<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-AEG25297-T29-L9-6JF"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1683 IS: Promoting Employment and Lifelong Learning Act of 2025 </dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1683</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250508">May 8, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S417">Mr. Budd</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S153">Mr. Grassley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S423">Mr. Ricketts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S433">Mr. McCormick</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S437">Mr. Justice</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to provide for Workforce Pell Grants.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="id8c2023a1fc11440a8a45139eca14b005" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Promoting Employment and Lifelong Learning Act of 2025 </short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>PELL Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="S1" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Workforce pell grants</header><subsection id="HF75F8EDB4D5941C39D495375111890C5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 401 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070a">20 U.S.C. 1070a</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block id="H9B5278B302D14E1FA08B1C8EDF5BD293" style="OLC"><subsection id="H1FB86DDED48041B5B8336120AA085958" commented="no"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Workforce pell grant program</header><paragraph id="H85F0C361EDDF4BF6B8F19B316C6EA9FF" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For the award year beginning on July 1, 2026, and each subsequent award year, the Secretary shall award grants (to be known as <quote>Workforce Pell Grants</quote>) to eligible students under paragraph (2) in accordance with this subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1ED3934F10EA4C86AFCB0840E9D2271B" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible students</header><text>To be eligible to receive a Workforce Pell Grant under this subsection for any period of enrollment, a student shall meet the eligibility requirements for a Federal Pell Grant under this section, except that the student—</text><subparagraph id="HC6CF0E12B07F4615870F5284FBB7227F" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall be enrolled, or accepted for enrollment, in an eligible program under section 481(b)(3) (hereinafter referred to as an <quote>eligible workforce program</quote>); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8D300215E43D4645BA493F978070E1F1" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may not—</text><clause id="H707FF9FFFD65481D91B53BCD0985E839" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>be enrolled, or accepted for enrollment, in a program of study that leads to a graduate credential; or</text></clause><clause id="H0A5894E10CD8483F922A1063F93845F7" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>have attained such a credential.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBD6715D1E1764700BD65A104F6481FB1" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Terms and conditions of awards</header><text>The Secretary shall award Workforce Pell Grants under this subsection in the same manner and with the same terms and conditions as the Secretary awards Federal Pell Grants under this section, except that—</text><subparagraph id="H7EDD9D64989449B79FCD0DF9AF0E93F4" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>each use of the term <term>eligible program</term> (except in subsections (b)(9)(A) and (d)(2)) shall be substituted by <quote>eligible workforce program under section 481(b)(3)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0CDD2638740743B8B3CA2D1E62CE182E" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a student who is eligible for a grant equal to less than the amount of the minimum Federal Pell Grant because the eligible workforce program in which the student is enrolled or accepted for enrollment is less than an academic year (in hours of instruction or weeks of duration) may still be eligible for a Workforce Pell Grant in an amount that is prorated based on the length of the program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1E18DE9F1837404891426CC73D812553" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Prevention of double benefits</header><text>No eligible student described in paragraph (2) may concurrently receive a grant under both this subsection and—</text><subparagraph id="H9710B81F211A465C909EACB6D2DBE5A3" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>subsection (b); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H50004DBC4F70423297EB6FFFB01944D8" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>subsection (c).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC7ADB86996364D8D8964DC9CD8D5A9BA" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Duration limit</header><text>Any period of study covered by a Workforce Pell Grant awarded under this subsection shall be included in determining a student’s duration limit under subsection (d)(5).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H0E1439DDD06545DA81364874DBF26ED0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Program eligibility for workforce pell grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 481(b) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1088">20 U.S.C. 1088(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HE360763C52B447C6A56245B46BF7D8D3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (3) and (4) as paragraphs (4) and (5), respectively;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAAE3E87E24344190A7A522DD7A290609"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (2) the following:</text><quoted-block id="H999CBCC128D9448388B693013B0027EC" style="OLC"><paragraph id="HBD69C75103444607951737937CBB8ABD"><enum>(3)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H10ADEF9CA4CC41059716AA272AB06208"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A program is an eligible program for purposes of the Workforce Pell Grant program under section 401(k) only if—</text><clause indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf32449f475594b4b8f43e82e9fdb8402"><enum>(i)</enum><text>it is a program of at least 150 clock hours of instruction, but less than 600 clock hours of instruction, or an equivalent number of credit hours, offered by an eligible institution during a minimum of 8 weeks, but less than 15 weeks;</text></clause><clause indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb1f066611b7f4ed7adbcd49a6e8b7a50"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>it is not offered as a correspondence course, as defined in 600.2 of title 34, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on September 20, 2020);</text></clause><clause indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id22cdfb5477d2482fb7864477e08be065"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the Governor of a State, after consultation with the State board, makes a determination that the program—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc48e9155b01e46adad7e1f2796009e84"><enum>(I)</enum><text>provides an education aligned with the requirements of high-skill, high-wage (as identified by the State pursuant to section 122 of the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/2342">20 U.S.C. 2342</external-xref>)), or in-demand industry sectors or occupations;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ideee1a03e078a47c1928aef6cb2bf9632"><enum>(II)</enum><text>meets the hiring requirements of potential employers in the sectors or occupations described in subclause (I);</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id27f4a8c39a4a406da0e560065db339a4"><enum>(III)</enum><text>either—</text><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id658a2128aa87473184ed934ba3eaffac"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>leads to a recognized postsecondary credential that is stackable and portable across more than one employer; or</text></item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3f3fc132097746779c3958ec280f9526"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>with respect to students enrolled in the program—</text><subitem commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7dd682e5fe8c4749aa714ca441ea9cf8"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>prepares such students for employment in an occupation for which there is only one recognized postsecondary credential; and</text></subitem><subitem commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id71ebdebffe854443b39e856e60979df9"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>provides such students with such a credential upon completion of such program; and</text></subitem></item></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id13ea2c4179c84887bc99a81d1f28ecc2"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>prepares students to pursue 1 or more certificate or degree programs at 1 or more institutions of higher education (which may include the eligible institution providing the program), including by ensuring—</text><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idca0615fdcec04aa3b8b35f964425e8fb"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>that a student, upon completion of the program and enrollment in such a related certificate or degree program, will receive academic credit for the program that will be accepted toward meeting such certificate or degree program requirements; and</text></item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7a4fa45baa60489a889b96fde70ff2e5"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the acceptability of such credit toward meeting such certificate or degree program requirements;</text></item></subclause></clause><clause indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1d9430048a2f498682a19f6037a6bc61"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">after the Governor of such State makes the determination that the program meets the requirements under clause (iii), the Secretary determines that—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idca4e5ce7e76f4bb1a8c246bba456f662"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the program has been offered by the eligible institution for not less than 1 year prior to the date on which the Secretary makes a determination under this clause; </text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id11f26ed5aee14ac4bf4f054a3fa2431c"><enum>(II)</enum><text>for each award year, the program has a verified completion rate of at least 70 percent, within 150 percent of the normal time for completion; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id61f707a01df14a6cb3e44912e5305c31"><enum>(III)</enum><text>for each award year, the program has a verified job placement rate of at least 70 percent, measured 180 days after completion; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id00f7019e4133483fba3098a90a07ee93" indent="up1"><enum>(v)</enum><text>for each award year, the total amount of the published tuition and fees of the program for such year is an amount that does not exceed the value-added earnings of students who received Federal financial aid under this title and who completed the program 3 years prior to the award year, as such earnings are determined by calculating the difference between—</text><subclause id="ideb2299abe17c409a9abb0c04cec0d733"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the median earnings of such students, as adjusted by the State and metropolitan area regional price parities of the Bureau of Economic Analysis based on the location of such program; and</text></subclause><subclause id="idcb9162823d574da681d8a2f4917911e7"><enum>(II)</enum><text>150 percent of the poverty line applicable to a single individual as determined under section 673(2) of the Community Services Block Grant Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9902">42 U.S.C. 9902(2)</external-xref>) for such year.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc14f50386156442b84e8a46c8e55f8cb"><enum>(B)</enum><text>In the case of a program that has not previously participated in programs under this title and is being determined eligible for the first time under this paragraph, the Secretary may consider such program to be an eligible program for purposes of the Workforce Pell Grants program under section 401(k) for a provisional eligibility period that may not exceed 3 years, if such program—</text><clause id="id3fe75d1564f549549b1c7108f2f5b45d"><enum>(i)</enum><text>subject to clause (ii), meets the requirements of subparagraph (A); and</text></clause><clause id="id5e8b0de3a7b741308cb2c02e00e15a83"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in lieu of the determination of median earnings under subclause (I) of subparagraph (A)(v), provides to the Secretary for purposes of meeting the requirements of subparagraph (A)(v), alternate earnings of students who complete the program, which are statistically rigorous, accurate, comparable, and representative of students who complete such program.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id730bb700cc6849f38f2e705e49189c91"><enum>(C)</enum><text>In this paragraph:</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida32116bf739f48c0849d3d4418f9a5ba"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible institution</term> means an institution of higher education (as defined in section 102), or any other entity that has entered into a program participation agreement with the Secretary under section 487(a) (without regard to whether that entity is accredited by a national recognized accrediting agency or association), which has not been subject, during any of the preceding 3 years, to—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5f5b9b22a88f4f738e1f8456da1c374e"><enum>(I)</enum><text>any suspension, emergency action, or termination under this title;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0c33c68392f14c85ad11865c84664f9f"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in the case of an institution of higher education, any adverse action by the institution’s accrediting agency or association that revokes or denies accreditation for the institution of higher education; or</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8442c692efcf4178949940d0dd537baa"><enum>(III)</enum><text>any final action by the State in which the institution or other entity holds its legal domicile, authorization, or accreditation that revokes the institution’s or entity’s license or other authority to operate in such State.</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id43914e36b8494969ba1090160da7c8af"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Governor</term> means the chief executive of a State. </text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id324abcacf24f449f8239b5ba1d2e4ec5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The terms <term>industry or sector partnership</term>, <term>in-demand industry sector or occupation</term>, <term>recognized postsecondary credential</term>, and <term>State board</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 3 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H1955351516F0422585F8AC0F0E029180" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Student eligibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 484(a)(1) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1091">20 U.S.C. 1091(a)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>or, for purposes of section 401(k), at an entity (other than an institution of higher education) that meets the requirements of section 481(b)(3)(B)(i),</quote> after <quote>section 487</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF260E94191454C74AB5F4042FA09AC29"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Effective date; applicability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this section shall take effect on July 1, 2026, and shall apply with respect to award year 2026–2027 and each succeeding award year. </text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

