<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HEEA2EE1200814A7CAC5BE97F3EE4B2CD" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4871 IH: COVID–19 Military Backpay Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4871</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250801">August 1, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="Z000018">Mr. Zinke</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001218">Mr. McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000565">Mr. Gosar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001115">Mr. Cloud</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000622">Mr. Patronis</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide remedies to members of the uniformed services discharged for not complying with the COVID–19 vaccination mandate.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H4CC2D48C7B8C43128509EFA5B5E44C6C" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HCBF3D2F3571A4FB6A1A750701EC05770" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>COVID–19 Military Backpay Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H65D619A4A13A4DCC81C4271B1D848F19"><enum>2.</enum><header>Remedies for members of uniformed services discharged for not complying with COVID–19 vaccination mandate</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H17749BD0147D4BC1A8CE2190554E77E4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="HFCEA078DEF7B45389D316845C61C71F2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Benefit</header><text>The term <term>benefit</term> means any benefit available under title 10 or 37, United States Code, including retirement points earned as described in section 12732 of title 10, United States Code, medical and dental care under chapter 55 of that title, and educational assistance programs under part IV of subtitle E of that title.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFC132CA8262448219E7DA58ED4B0083D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered discharge</header><text>The term <term>covered discharge</term>, with respect to a covered member, means any the following, resulting, in whole or in part, from the noncompliance of the member with the COVID–19 vaccination mandate or from the COVID–19 vaccination status of the member:</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA8521F6298BC4BF5A2CCC45916CA57D1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Discharge or separation (including any separation that may be considered to be voluntary) of the member from a uniformed service.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H65D4ED4A6BF1441DA6606947CB5726CC"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any cancellation or curtailment of active-duty orders issued to the member.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5F8D46E3248B4E159820ECA73CB9294D" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Transfer of the member from an active to inactive status.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD20923AC0CC5497E9DDB38A6C1EFA705"><enum>(3)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Covered member</header><text>The term <term>covered member</term> means any individual who—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H02674DF22CE84E64A2A53EE579B13BA4"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is or was a member of an active or reserve component of a uniformed service or the National Guard; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB64AB83BDDD94E20A61D1B59726112CA"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">was at any time subject to the COVID–19 vaccination mandate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H898C3E17C8594A4F8FFE8F363D1B6B15"><enum>(4)</enum><header>COVID–19 vaccination mandate</header><text>The term <term>COVID–19 vaccination mandate</term> means—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD0A18608077C4D06BB7B4C1638017CED"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the requirement of the Secretary of Defense to receive a COVID–19 vaccination pursuant to the memorandum dated August 24, 2021, and entitled <quote>Mandatory Coronavirus Disease 2019 Vaccination of Department of Defense Service Members</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE06208042C0443CBB5C75906CC1D185E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any order or other requirement issued by any uniformed service to implement the requirement described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA1A0D1227DF24906A8AAFF2748DF0086"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Pay</header><text>The term <term>pay</term> has the meaning given that term in section 101 of title 37, United States Code.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCC06632E201244E2AFD76F9E11EE2EB7"><enum>(6)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Uniformed services</header><text>The term <term>uniformed services</term> has the meaning given that term in section 101 of title 37, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H7187EFD684324BBA95A75F50ABF65DCA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Civil actions</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1CF971E859F74A5993EF522D096E56E8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A covered member may file a civil action in the Court of Federal Claims for a determination that the covered discharge of the member was involuntary or unlawful.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H204BFCDED7F1446BACE395A08B883B11"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Special rules for claims of involuntary discharge</header><text>In a claim that the covered discharge of a covered member was involuntary—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA770B92404044E8BBF08D231BCA03343"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">it shall not be a defense that the discharge was voluntary if the discharge resulted solely from the noncompliance of the member with the COVID–19 vaccination mandate or the COVID–19 vaccination status of the member; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4E5A1480BC02458385E28D85CA4673CF" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text>it shall be conclusive evidence that the discharge was involuntary if the discharge documentation of the member states that the member was discharged for the convenience of the Government, for failure to be world-wide deployable, or for misconduct.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H5469AD603F3842EEA36CD189A7A74DB6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Remedies</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4C21FF9B0A414D169C47419FA63D2985"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>If the Court of Federal Claims determines that the covered discharge of a covered member was involuntary or unlawful, the Court shall award the member the remedies specified in this subsection and such other remedies as may be available at law or in equity from the Court.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H38F6C51C014A4C1C87AE0A72028C8B1F"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Monetary remedies</header> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0BC88642D8DD4FF19CD1FA5FCE0A646B"><enum>(A)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Compensation for inactive-duty training</header><text>In the case of a covered member who is or was a member of a reserve component of a uniformed service or the National Guard, upon a determination by the Court of Federal Claims that the covered discharge of the member was involuntary or unlawful, the member is entitled to compensation under section 206 of title 37, United States Code, for inactive-duty training the member did not perform if the member did not perform such training as a result, in whole or in part, of the covered discharge.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEB944CAD7A7C43D892460CBD44DC5999"><enum>(B)</enum><header>No reduction of claim for other compensation</header><text>The amount paid to a covered member under subparagraph (A) shall not be reduced or offset by any amounts received by the member from civilian employment after the covered discharge.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE30DEEB3253346B4A5A8CACFFD398CBE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Other remedies</header><text>In addition to the other remedies provided for under this subsection, the Court of Federal Claims shall award the following to a covered member if the Court determines that the covered discharge of the member was involuntary or unlawful:</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H93CDD45034BF453C811C0ECEB422CCE2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The member shall be deemed to have served for the period beginning on the date of the covered discharge of the member and ending at the end of the member's term of service or enlistment contract, plus the term of reenlistment or extension of service under subparagraph (D).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9AEB391AD6314240BFB3A24D448B2F64"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the member would have completed 20 years of service during the term of service or enlistment contract during which the covered discharge occurred, or during the term of reenlistment or extension of service under subparagraph (D), the member shall—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H196C81CC51A54A0992A20B116B9A7FCF"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be deemed—</text> 
<subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9B71F174237046A3ADCD5DAD104CEFA1"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to have completed 20 years of service; and</text></subclause> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFB50246E3B9C447BAA7341F94B1FA03A"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to have requested and received the approval of the Secretary of Defense for a retirement date commencing on the first day of the calendar month following the completion of 20 years of service; and</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H13CB1DE1B42C4070857A9A33D201030D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be paid retired pay or retainer pay and other retirement benefits commensurate with the member's rank and years of service.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD590A36854794E3A9BFE4BF1F0427BBF"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the member would have completed 18 years of service during the term of service or enlistment contract during which the covered discharge occurred, or during the term of reenlistment or extension of service under subparagraph (D), the member shall be deemed—</text> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H76077E13CAAF411E8B221AD33901B315"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to have completed 18 years of service;</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDAD498650EB145CBAE0ED909CE71DD52"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to have requested and received the approval of the Secretary of Defense for a retirement date commencing on the first day of the calendar month following the completion of 20 years of service; and</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9285B1A6146C46F48C9F737BEFC0C6F9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of an enlisted member, to be eligible for retention in accordance with section 1176 of title 10, United States Code.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF9995A6107BC4AF1B9BF92BBBA3A95EA"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The member shall, notwithstanding any reentry or reenlistment code on the discharge documentation of the member—</text> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0C13D6F406CF48D2A62E5DDF56399BBB"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be eligible to reenlist or otherwise extend the service of the member; and</text></clause> <clause id="HF560E348F2734C38A6021A6F25D667D9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>be deemed to have reenlisted or extended the service of the member for an additional term of two years commencing on the day after the end of the term of service or enlistment contract of the member during which the covered discharge occurred.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H13B651176F9A4B0F8D900A9F4FEC9A85"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The member shall be awarded involuntary separation pay under section 1174 of title 10, United States Code, and the time in service and time in rank for such pay shall be calculated to include service through the end of the term of service or enlistment contract during which the covered discharge occurred, plus the term of reenlistment or extension of service under subparagraph (D).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H56BC090DDD6F493E8F8F17030A3AE261"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Jurisdiction</header><text>Notwithstanding section 1500 of title 28, United States Code, the Court of Federal Claims shall have jurisdiction over any civil action brought by a covered member relating to a covered discharge.</text></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBC7D6305429647C3A84FAA42F22F7C4B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Coordination with Executive Order 14184</header><text>The remedies available under this section are in addition to any remedies available pursuant to Executive Order 14184 (90 Fed. Reg. 8761; relating to reinstating service members discharged under the military’s COVID–19 vaccination mandate).</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H10F51DB0421347B49E0C27B8E06C77A9"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>This section applies with respect to claims relating to covered discharges pending before the Court of Federal Claims on or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

