<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-TAM25539-X7G-PY-S8K"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1482 IS: National Nursing Workforce Center Act of 2025 </dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1482</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250410">April 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S430">Ms. Blunt Rochester</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S384">Mr. Tillis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S398">Mr. Cramer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Public Health Service Act to support and stabilize the existing nursing workforce, establish programs to increase the number of nurses, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HD648D7BF7B9D4D2F81D3EFB0F79411D6"><section section-type="section-one" id="HC6559EA5A4FA4FBCB613E44E6E22E73D"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>National Nursing Workforce Center Act of 2025 </short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H4826A4F617124918B80963D54FB659B8"><enum>2.</enum><header>State nursing workforce centers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title VII of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/292">42 U.S.C. 292 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HDA1416C9F0DD49E1822357FA1E21CED9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating part G (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/295j">42 U.S.C. 295j et seq.</external-xref>) as part H; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF89C589070A34ABCBB5B4C9C710646F1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after part F the following new part:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC1436CE474C54BCE87304E91417036A8"><part id="H54FC9462814B4A37BB05A5A8CC7C20FD"><enum>G</enum><header>Nursing workforce centers</header><section id="H24FA359E43CC44DDA195E4B09A73CAAE"><enum>785.</enum><header>State and regional nursing workforce center data collection pilot program</header><subsection id="H9A9556BDD99C49E29D7D1BB8C293A2C6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may carry out a 2-year pilot program to establish new or enhance existing State-based nursing workforce centers, evaluate the impact of State-based nursing workforce centers on outcomes, and assess the feasibility of nursing workforce public-private partnerships. The Secretary shall begin implementation of such pilot program not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of the <short-title>National Nursing Workforce Center Act of 2025 </short-title>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HCC729A38DD954428A79C40F1DBE33A4C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grant terms</header><paragraph id="H182001F0E4A6418A830C2B6AE8E29921"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Term</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term of a grant awarded under the pilot program under subsection (a) shall be 2 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1FFDD659EA3740A6B1FCF653B99D5386"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Matching requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As a condition on receipt of a grant under the pilot program under subsection (a), the Secretary shall require the applicant to agree, with respect to costs to be incurred by the applicant in carrying out the activities funded through the grant, to make available non-Federal contributions (in cash or in kind) toward such costs in an amount that is equal to not less than $1 for each $4 of Federal funds provided through the grant. Such contributions may be made directly or through donations from public or private entities.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H11F3793D5E984076B757E8D76ED2421F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, an entity shall be—</text><paragraph id="HC8AEAF8869D843CD987515D7C1346828"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a State agency;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8993D6CCF6A541378FD647986A50EBB7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a State board of nursing;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEA5EE38C84104DA1B2AD481848576CC7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an organization that is exempt from taxation under section 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Act of 1986;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF9B0E046E15E4F4C84C5B47B68604C5B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a community-based organization; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEF65AE9C218643A89D3CEBD7FCCF2D0B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>a school of nursing (as defined in section 801); or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H51C45069D48642D8BDFC25BF4BADBC8B"><enum>(6)</enum><text>another type of school or program determined by the Secretary to be an eligible entity for purposes of this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBBBE42970F2940B2BF89C7EC0C26BCE2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Equitable distribution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall ensure, to the greatest extent possible, that such grants are equitably distributed among the geographical regions of the United States.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HCFDEB5C1FC6C477084BF36AB84F9898F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In selecting the eligible entity to be awarded a grant under this section for a nursing workforce center in a particular State, the Secretary shall give priority to eligible entities that—</text><paragraph commented="no" id="HB449104F72F641DD803D9F222DF88192"><enum>(1)</enum><text>propose to provide statewide services;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H405879F8704C40CDB9C5DD6E83E055AE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>have expertise in the State’s nursing workforce issues;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H5ACC45495A2548559D16FC7306C5A5A1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>have a history of convening entities to address nursing workforce issues; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H4D2EBF380EE541C19080886CD5446C19"><enum>(4)</enum><text>have partnerships with entities that traditionally educate and employ the State’s nurses.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC467C8FBDF864C9CBC95E44D11844109"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>A nursing workforce center supported under this section may use funds provided under this section for the following statewide activities:</text><paragraph commented="no" id="HC4AA199E92164B50AD05B6167B83026C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Conducting comprehensive analysis of and research on—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H9C8FF94A81C74B17A9C6E22242229968"><enum>(A)</enum><text>existing State nursing workforce data and gaps in such data;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H7223449A67154396B117DAC148EF1AEF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>2- and 4-year nursing education programs, including with respect to—</text><clause commented="no" id="HA8B4021DC7874B0A9435E7ED26639ABF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>faculty capacity and pay;</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H653074842E1E48EC943240956992127B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>enrollment, retention, and graduation;</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H6AB172C1F0664492A2E1796C8D19BAC1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>services for nursing students and the outcomes of such services;</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H95945FBEFA8F43C692C249CCF0A96D96"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>facility needs; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H19721C4D29834E728F1AD069D403E6E6"><enum>(v)</enum><text>clinical placement capacity;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H3C10550C799A458493EC7133947320EA"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">State-specific scholarships, grants, and financial aid; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H507C39A0D01E41AD8ACAFE1D1D69A741"><enum>(D)</enum><text>factors contributing to retention and recruitment challenges and to nurses leaving the workplace or profession.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H05501E01A2054656A571B4EF657B75A5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Conducting strategic nursing workforce planning with employers across all work settings and nursing education.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5075212EEECA4D94BD6DE9EEBAC47D4A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Conducting focused research on trends in nursing shortages, including the fiscal and clinical outcomes of contract nursing.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H225FF25DD344482B8726221A04FECE6E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Establishing and implementing programs to—</text><subparagraph id="H86498E72C1974DB1831EA753E66204D9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>support and retain faculty to increase enrollment in schools of nursing;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H14B7749797C043099CEE24A927A66ED8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>recruit and retain nurses in all settings where nurses practice;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCDE85C84B5B14A5492ACBD76AD39F847"><enum>(C)</enum><text>support leadership development;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC9082D9BA76643969663AE6418E601ED"><enum>(D)</enum><text>prepare the nursing workforce to address social determinants of health and health inequities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEB1C9DA2501E42C291D302EAB1AFE84B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>prepare nurses for public health crisis and pandemic response; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE729305A1A7147AC82C42F618C9194BC"><enum>(F)</enum><text>assist individuals in obtaining education and training required to enter the nursing profession, and advance within such profession, such as by providing career counseling and mentoring.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4E773261B6314BFDB099E48C1AFD7C0B"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date on which the first grant is awarded under the pilot program under subsection (a), and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the grants awarded under such pilot program during the year covered by the report. Each such report shall include—</text><paragraph id="HDF6246FD3AF940B396218DBC48FC9D9B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a description of initiatives to study the unique characteristics of State nursing workforces, and efforts to increase the number of new nurses, recruit nurses to the nursing profession, and retain nurses in the workplace;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE6D8F233553D480995D04B7989417550"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">impact data on nurses served by nursing workforce centers, including demographic information of the individuals served, the number of such individuals, and the types of services provided;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8F77EBE871E64FEC88AFCF2EC1068561"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the effectiveness of establishing formal public-private relationships for purposes of understanding the national nursing workforce through improved data collection and standardization;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0EABCFD24FF24B569019DE9933850E64"><enum>(4)</enum><text>data on continuous evaluation and quality improvement, and other relevant data as determined by the Secretary; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H88B4297E4C3F4BE189CB375F0B2E3688"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the Secretary’s recommendations and best practices for—</text><subparagraph id="HAB74FCEF572D4070BB94589295FB2531"><enum>(A)</enum><text>reducing shortages among different nursing specialties;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB279018893C643E2917A67F4ACBD30D1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>reducing shortages in rural and underserved areas;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE96613B04B064BF0BBD5B1A27F7716AC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>improving geographical distribution of the nursing workforce; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9EE7719AA0794249B1AFC51B3A7118DD"><enum>(D)</enum><text>reducing shortages among different types of nursing employers.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H7418F5EBC9334BC5B2052A1D1894A0F4"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">From the amounts appropriated to the Health Resources and Services Administration for workforce initiatives, the Secretary may use up to $1,500,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 and 2027 for purposes of carrying out this section.</text></subsection></section></part><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="HEA7F24D7216E4DD8B12D28FE3842C901"><enum>3.</enum><header>State and regional centers for health workforce analysis</header><subsection id="H8D07878FF12F433C810A56C0BF9A76CE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Expansion of covered programs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 761(c)(1)(A) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/294n">42 U.S.C. 294n(c)(1)(A)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>under this title</quote> and inserting <quote>under this Act</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE5F815FEE662454082B3C6F8F510E60D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Analysis and technical assistance</header><text>Section 761(c) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/294n">42 U.S.C. 294n(c)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5355C3FFF2DD49F5AC209403C914B197"><paragraph id="HAD25794982714D0B8D843FA25648E720"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Minimum requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At least one grant or contract awarded under this subsection may be awarded to an eligible entity that demonstrates—</text><subparagraph id="HF78D2068865A4FB6B913289711983411"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a mission to advance and support the nursing workforce;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4A7DD58E844444DE81147481CFACF1E8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>experience and expertise in guiding State-level nursing workforce centers;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2BC81ECA766D4F6A940665B303245ED8"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">experience in working with nursing workforce data;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H78AB1291E86C405B8ACBAF3FD5C7B7CA"><enum>(D)</enum><text>expertise in analytical methods and tools appropriate for nursing workforce research; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAE16C3BFCB254D24912AFF4022E4EBE5"><enum>(E)</enum><text>awareness of emerging topics, issues, and trends related to the nursing workforce.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC3AFB1F927224C6EB0F02EA23755BCEE"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Analysis and reporting</header><text>Analysis and reporting carried out pursuant to a grant or contract under this subsection may include—</text><subparagraph id="H2FDD9DAE88834023AC5566AFD4301513"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">collaborating with nursing workforce centers to produce or deliver, with respect to the supply of nurses, the demand for nurses, and the capacity to educate and train the nursing workforce—</text><clause id="HB7C36FBDB53F41268F31A33059EFE907"><enum>(i)</enum><text>regional and national reports;</text></clause><clause id="H2496D34B07A84427AF51A3DB7A6C5560"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>articles in peer-reviewed journals;</text></clause><clause id="H427E9D8903B243658140F9C5B8D4FB84"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>presentations at national and international conferences and meetings; and</text></clause><clause id="H15B7DD6F533B4DFEA5347AEEEAFE1C78"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>policy briefs, fact sheets, articles, blogs, and other publications available in the public domain;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9BA6C674595D494F86E9D204DD4F86B6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>evaluating the programs and activities of the nursing workforce centers overall;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5499E8FB97204260A5EF126E5F97B4F2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>developing evidence-based or evidence-informed strategies and best practices to alleviate nursing workforce shortages across States and regions; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8C3E723CAE594DD9A1B57F4E7558BE0B"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conducting rapid data analysis and short-term, issue-specific research.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4B97916A6E524F94A2A9171C12F3A6DE"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Technical Assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Technical assistance provided pursuant to this subsection may include—</text><subparagraph id="H0B829405F332431594EBBDFBEC805586"><enum>(A)</enum><text>providing technical assistance to nursing workforce centers on the collection, analysis, and reporting of standardized supply, demand, and education and training data to inform analysis conducted pursuant to this subsection;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8B29F17D8DF949B4B1A888696B025C1A"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">collaborating with nursing workforce centers to identify and deliver evidence-based or evidence-informed strategies to alleviate nursing shortages and the maldistribution of nurses;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8259332E79384971B2DC85826BFDB65A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>providing online and in-person training opportunities for nurses and other staff at nursing workforce centers; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H191402F87798438C84187528196CA77B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>developing and maintaining a website that—</text><clause id="H6F796CFCDA6C4D25BDD1C0EFE952268A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is accessible to grant and contract recipients under section 785 and this section;</text></clause><clause id="H3B2B1D93E3A84CF38A3795262FBBE97F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>supports resources for the provision of technical assistance under this section, such as—</text><subclause id="H70DF4B1B056D4E7CBC580F38D28E1DE8"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">evidence-based or evidence-informed educational materials, tools, recent findings of interest, and links to relevant resources; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H488E98805B6946A6A58655675B7DB6A2"><enum>(II)</enum><text>logistical and administrative information, such as online trainings, webinars, and publications; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H7F93973125EA4170BDD9C0734AD4AEF6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes a publicly accessible repository of webinars, tools, and resources.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCB62B794FB8E4A08BF4FF06FB8F14F8D"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>nursing workforce center</term> means a nursing workforce center funded under section 785.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

