<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" dms-id="H13FCEF05F7DA4F81B3002817841D3578" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 260 EH: No Tax Dollars for Terrorists Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 260</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To require a strategy to oppose foreign assistance by foreign countries and nongovernmental organizations to the Taliban, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H80621D3A2D38440E9892E6144E46998F" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HD3541467FE5D451FB9F10A62E9CAFFDC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No Tax Dollars for Terrorists Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section> <section id="H7EF3EDDD661F42E881FE27A6203383D1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Strategy to oppose foreign assistance by foreign countries and nongovernmental organizations to the Taliban</header> <subsection id="HCFC642B9DE7F4133AC29B1423CE1ABE8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the policy of the United States—</text> 
<paragraph id="H62FA81029F62407EAA82F90C493A46BD"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to oppose the provision of foreign assistance by foreign countries and nongovernmental organizations to the Taliban, particularly those countries and organizations that receive United States-provided foreign assistance; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEE4CA9DB91D045E598C2CE07B4152C7C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to review United States-provided foreign assistance to such foreign countries and nongovernmental organizations that have provided foreign assistance to the Taliban.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H236154FAB3C5409196EC7FB87C358F24"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report identifying, to the extent possible—</text> <paragraph id="H71307AFA98594883A2D49865B344EC20"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">foreign countries and nongovernmental organizations that have provided foreign assistance to the Taliban, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H033F860EF13549C7B1E42070C25DD571"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the amount of United States-provided foreign assistance each country or organization receives, if any; </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9133A6F6844446F1ABBD0E03C4A2435F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the amount of foreign assistance each country or organization has provided to the Taliban; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC5219E02DEFC47BF87B2673DE6680E32"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a description of how the Taliban has utilized such foreign assistance; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8CAB0E60B0F14C37A2713E85C80B3334"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">efforts the United States has taken since August 2021 to oppose foreign countries and nongovernmental organizations from providing foreign assistance to the Taliban, particularly those foreign countries and organizations that receive United States-provided foreign assistance.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H867FF349521843ED9DD1B80F200AF71D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Strategy and reports</header> 
<paragraph id="H5512F86D76F34649B5965EE5B7CA7F06"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall develop and implement a strategy to discourage foreign countries and nongovernmental organizations from providing foreign assistance to the Taliban. The strategy shall include efforts to support Afghan women and girls who are suffering under Taliban edicts, in a way that does not support the Taliban, and efforts to relocate eligible, fully vetted, at-risk Afghans and Afghan allies located inside and outside of Afghanistan to the United States or third countries. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF4B1BCA6215E450D8B50353ABD77368F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reports</header> <subparagraph id="H63DF35173B9143868CAACF22DCB92E62"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Initial report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than the date on which the strategy required by paragraph (1) is completed, the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report detailing the strategy and a plan for its implementation. </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2FCED2BDE9AA4FD6BE432C0BF4B45BE7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Subsequent reports</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date on which the strategy required by paragraph (1) is completed, and every 180 days thereafter for 5 years, the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the implementation of the strategy, including the impact of the strategy in discouraging foreign countries and nongovernmental organizations from providing financial or material support to the Taliban.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCB228E09B35E430F9DBFC86887CA6D04"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Additional report</header> <clause id="H1C941A9D1C834859832051327E7265B0"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the decision to terminate the bounty on Sirajuddin Haqqani and other key members of the Haqqani Network under the Rewards for Justice program.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H803894BD759B44E5BFF717320297BA1F"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Matters to be included</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report required by this subparagraph shall include the following:</text> <subclause id="H0536DF42F17847E9AD9C4302655EAD4D"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The status of the bounty on Sirajuddin Haqqani, Abdul Aziz Haqqani, and Yahya Haqqani under the Rewards for Justice program and the rationale for any changes made since September 1, 2021. </text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HE22D49FFD8E1487382D86035B5ABBC7E"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An identification of members of the Haqqani Network who are Specially Designated Global Terrorists and the status of the designation of the Haqqani Network as a foreign terrorist organization. </text></subclause> <subclause id="H3FC5CBD79EF0485CBDAE9E263D810624"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of any United States Government engagements with Sirajuddin Haqqani, Abdul Aziz Haqqani, Yahya Haqqani, or the Haqqani Network since September 1, 2021. </text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HCDC0A73E28324E17A2793A848B47F2A6"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether new information has emerged relating to the involvement of the Haqqani Network in terrorist attacks targeting the United States Military or United States civilians.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HB047577EF1E742A69A942FBE34B53874"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Form</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report required by this subparagraph shall be submitted in unclassified form but may include a classified annex. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H72B23AA883864FF38375E9E1D43E2808"><enum>3.</enum><header>Report on direct cash assistance programs in Afghanistan</header> 
<subsection id="H73C34F6AF7AA48E6AB4DF242AA6CDB12"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on United States Government-funded direct cash assistance programs in Afghanistan during the period beginning on August 1, 2021, and ending on the date that is 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act. </text></subsection> <subsection id="H45FF6F197DC14868A716F388C933AF17"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Matters to be included</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall, with respect to such direct cash assistance programs, include—</text> 
<paragraph id="H72DC9DC45A76479DB1A79404D9FE8429"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a general description of the types of implementing partners and recipients; </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE1DAC49622F240BF8078CFC19ED3A0E4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of method of payments; </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7573506D556C4DE88C5A17890B111D7B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a description of how and where currency exchanges occur; </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAC016E79807448AAA38F5EE46A770DB3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a description of how hawalas are used and the oversight mechanism in place regarding use of hawalas to transfer funds; and </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H781B257A922240059F98E13968CB3CD7"><enum>(5)</enum><text>a description of how oversight is conducted, including information on how the Department of State prevents the Taliban from accessing cash assistance under such programs. </text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC53CA5F91F2546F0A6E682ECA8BBC08A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Hawala defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>hawala’</term> means a system of transferring money through a network of money lending brokers.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HB5066FBFCAFB4F9D8430FB3E8EEEB92E"><enum>4.</enum><header>Report on status of Afghan Fund</header> 
<subsection id="HB74BAA6E6A7441238222519799BAFDC1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and every 180 days thereafter for 5 years, the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the status of the Afghan Fund.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H0428F4D4975D41E3BDC029B5E7289DA2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Matters to be included</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall, to the extent possible, include—</text> 
<paragraph id="H83FC304D30EF4988BA28D556486D4673"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a list of Taliban members working at Da Afghanistan Bank or serving on the Bank’s board; and </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9955C0FFB99F4C848FB36EC51AB6C766"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H7D54209B8DE54C57BB0224247A67BF27"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Taliban’s influence over Da Afghanistan Bank;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5E1A5A581C734FD0896E6E419CBCEB53"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Afghan Fund’s board of trustees, including how the Fund’s trustees were vetted and selected, and what United States agencies were involved in the vetting and selection process; </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H77B30775A17540CC8DA0313C240BC267"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the conditions necessary for funds in the Afghan Fund to be released to Da Afghanistan Bank;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7487780CB88C459496507328E9B73860"><enum>(D)</enum><text>how the Afghan Fund’s board of trustees will decide on the type and appropriateness of the Fund’s activities, including what kind of information will inform the board’s decisions and how the board will collect and verify this information; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H49CBDA8AB00C480A926CC93DEC9081C4"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a description of what controls have been put into place to ensure funds are not diverted to or misused by the Taliban or other actors when the Fund begins making disbursements.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H1C73F1ED8B17492F952671ED2FB40209"><enum>5.</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees’</term> means—</text> 
<paragraph id="HD6D1746D9D514D92B6812C7F9EEAD3E0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives; and </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H26DCC18540E24562A41AC08185B0C5CB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate.</text></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20250623" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives June 23, 2025.</attestation-date><attestor display="no">Kevin F. McCumber,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation>
<endorsement display="yes"></endorsement>
</bill> 


