<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1663B660126349379998354FC51A216F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4359 IH: Public Housing Fire Safety Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4359</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250710">July 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="R000609">Mr. Rutherford</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a grant program to provide amounts to public housing agencies to install automatic sprinkler systems in public housing, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD0B2EE96FA384F6CA96393D67B545C6D" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="H6E6D115306214E94821E28B195E35ED0"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Public Housing Fire Safety Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H698B99ADE3424A01B58EDE443A28DC68"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act—</text><paragraph id="H50678F663CDF481FBBC4ECBE3E5EC483"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>automatic sprinkler system</term> has the meaning given the term in section 31(a) of the Federal Fire Prevention and Control Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/2227">15 U.S.C. 2227(a)</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H19B049C8BFF34466AC02ABFCFF3D7751"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>Capital Fund</term> means the Capital Fund established under section 9(d) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437g">42 U.S.C. 1437g(d)</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H81F865C2ADA3406581A646F76EED1DC2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>exempted public housing project</term> means a public housing project that—</text><subparagraph id="H723F3DC53B14407AB37CD5715BC79581"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is not a newly constructed multifamily property, as defined in section 31(c)(2)(A)(ii) of the Federal Fire Prevention and Control Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/2227">15 U.S.C. 2227(c)(2)(A)(ii)</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEDACD654B07E4D79B9FB0313226C2C00"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is not subject to the requirements under section 31(c) of the Federal Fire Prevention and Control Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/2227">15 U.S.C. 2227(c)</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC905CEC7AC114E77A3F7E4536475A779"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the terms <term>public housing</term> and <term>public housing agency</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 3(b) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437a">42 U.S.C. 1437a(b)</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFEB086FF4AB6471E91934DD2E9FE77C9"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HC7B424A3F6104EF6864C84316120BCC7"><enum>3.</enum><header>Inspections of public housing</header><subsection id="H6B4D0491BB2B45378966EBB3333DA6D6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>With respect to inspections of public housing conducted by the Secretary, including through the Real Estate Assessment Center, the Secretary shall report on the presence or absence of automatic sprinkler systems in public housing.</text></subsection><subsection id="H9DFE1384E5414633ABD9260723C51C23"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall, based on inspections of public housing conducted during the 3-year period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act, submit to Congress a report on the presence or absence of automatic sprinkler systems in public housing, in particular in exempted public housing projects, which shall include recommendations to improve fire safety in exempted public housing projects.</text></subsection><subsection id="H871DA2653391411B9EE9245BD507DE10"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to require a public housing agency to install an automatic sprinkler system in an exempted public housing project.</text></subsection></section><section id="HB7377399AFFA4E1B925EA62C89E07C59"><enum>4.</enum><header>Grant program to retrofit public housing with automatic sprinkler systems</header><subsection id="H7E6ED13873D7461BBAAE57B4A7B20C67"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a competitive grant program under which the Secretary shall award grants to public housing agencies to install automatic sprinkler systems in exempted public housing projects.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC12D201AFB6B4C439FD59199FE7DCA20"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>A public housing agency may not use amounts received under this section to install automatic sprinkler systems in a rebuilt multifamily property, as defined in section 31(c)(2)(B)(iii) of the Federal Fire Prevention and Control Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/2227">15 U.S.C. 2227(c)(2)(B)(iii)</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection id="HD65FE4875EAE4332855B797EB61ADEFF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>In addition to amounts appropriated to the Capital Fund under any other provision of law, there is authorized to be appropriated to the Capital Fund $25,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2025 through 2034 to carry out this section.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

