<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-LIP25228-5LR-0N-YXL"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S954 IS: Boosting Innovation, Technology, and Competitiveness through Optimized Investment Nationwide Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 954</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250311" legis-day="20250310">March 11 (legislative day, March 10), 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S410">Ms. Lummis</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S437">Mr. Justice</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S412">Mr. Tuberville</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S434">Mr. Moreno</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S411">Mr. Marshall</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To establish a Strategic Bitcoin Reserve and other programs to ensure the transparent management of Bitcoin holdings of the Federal Government, to offset costs utilizing certain resources of the Federal Reserve System, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Boosting Innovation, Technology, and Competitiveness through Optimized Investment Nationwide Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>BITCOIN Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id7b626ee3390549ab81f03b5f7eb0f825"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="idc639c1c6c307400ab0a44e5fb066e432"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The global financial landscape is rapidly evolving, with digital assets playing an increasingly significant role in the world economy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id604052bfd6db42ee9375b7d64d8b0cd6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Bitcoin has demonstrated resilience, widespread adoption, and served as a medium of exchange and a store of value for more than a decade.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id564a303ac5c3466f8241b01dfbad0db7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Just as gold reserves have historically served as a cornerstone of national financial security, Bitcoin represents a digital-age asset capable of enhancing the financial leadership and security of the United States in the 21st century global economy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idccfa5c939fa24176b02189075cbb8267"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The acquisition and long-term storage of substantial quantities of Bitcoin by the United States can strengthen the financial condition of the United States, providing a hedge against economic uncertainty and monetary instability.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7c42d0acdd284a05bd14e6bcac8a47bb"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Bitcoin, as a decentralized and finitely scarce digital asset, offers unique properties that complement existing national reserves, strengthening the position of the United States dollar in the global financial system.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida1b3cd70a560484d90171648108f23c6"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Diversification of the national assets of the United States to include Bitcoin can enhance financial resilience and position the United States at the forefront of global financial innovation. </text></paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="id256dc725e0c14760bb1899b44edbbd89"><enum>3.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="idb3580960641b48debeaa3e216c280ff2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Airdrop</header><text>The term <term>airdrop</term> means a gratuitous distribution of digital assets to holders of Bitcoin in a broad, equitable, and non-discretionary manner. </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida3b79051bd8f48b3a2fbdae9ca3b13fd"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Bitcoin Purchase Program</header><text>The term <term>Bitcoin Purchase Program</term> means the program established under section 5(a).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idb1f63867c6154ddfb125faa25dfcde94"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Cold storage</header><text>The term <term>cold storage</term> means a method of storing private keys required to transact in Bitcoin, with a nexus to a secure physical location, protected from unauthorized access and isolated from any network connections.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc5ec0c50e31c4bc7bc70b050d8c85cd8"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Fork</header><text>The term <term>fork</term> means a change to the consensus mechanism of a distributed ledger that creates a separate ledger, resulting in a new digital asset that shares a common transaction history with Bitcoin up to the point of the change. </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id69d182772fa94bcfa687f02d61089aab"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Treasury.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddad4cf2888fd472e8f6e186c1d61e316"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Strategic Bitcoin Reserve</header><text>The term <term>Strategic Bitcoin Reserve</term> means the decentralized network of secure Bitcoin storage facilities established pursuant to section 4(a).</text></paragraph></section><section id="id1ef068e417894de3bf741b430380a181"><enum>4.</enum><header>Establishment of Strategic Bitcoin Reserve</header><subsection id="id8f71797f05f74a26ab71f3f6306482a8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish a decentralized network of secure Bitcoin storage facilities distributed across the United States, collectively to be known as the Strategic Bitcoin Reserve for the cold storage of Government Bitcoin holdings.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7c38724cb22b4fb98a2943cab1a6fc77"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The Strategic Bitcoin Reserve shall be used for the generation, safekeeping, and management of Bitcoin private keys associated with Government Bitcoin holdings.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id73095d81a21145e2aee7ab1890a92440"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Oversight</header><text>The Secretary shall be responsible for the ongoing monitoring and auditing of the holdings of the Strategic Bitcoin Reserve.</text></subsection><subsection id="idee77d4f6052d4e5bafa31428f57d10f3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Decentralization</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaa12dccc2a844b16bd836aa5772362c5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall ensure that the facilities of the Strategic Bitcoin Reserve are geographically dispersed throughout the United States, to minimize the risk of simultaneous compromise and to enhance the resilience of the Strategic Bitcoin Reserve.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9365548440504b66a25fc6b9e6a9077e"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Location selection</header><text>The Secretary shall select the locations for the facilities described in paragraph (1) based on a comprehensive risk assessment, prioritizing geographic diversity, security, and accessibility.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id423ea0486a0c430faa378ab4a398f380"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Security measures</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idce440beff82941379ac540416ee53d88"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall implement state-of-the-art physical and digital security measures to protect the Strategic Bitcoin Reserve.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc585f525937740c9985aceed4f802c58"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>The Secretary shall consult and collaborate with the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and industry experts to ensure the highest level of physical and digital security for the Strategic Bitcoin Reserve.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id7d62eedc766e4a7abc41f8e33398d3db"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Retention of forks and airdrops</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1a3f355ac03f45f790a620853b19ac3f"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall ensure that, with respect to Bitcoins controlled by the Strategic Bitcoin Reserve, all digital assets resulting from forks of the Bitcoin distributed ledger and digital assets distributed via airdrops to Bitcoin addresses are accounted for and reasonably stored in the Strategic Bitcoin Reserve.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ided00fd64b02e43979c2bd635400731cb"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prohibition on immediate sale</header><text>No digital asset stored in the Strategic Bitcoin Reserve that is the result of a fork or airdrop may be sold or otherwise disposed of during the 5-year period beginning on the date of the fork or airdrop, unless explicitly authorized by law. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbfab27612d8f4473a515854d6096c45d"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Evaluation and disposition after the holding period</header><subparagraph id="idf79c12cc2e8a42f29c15534905381259"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Market capitalization assessment</header><text>Upon the expiration of the 5-year holding period described in paragraph (2), the Secretary shall conduct an assessment to determine which digital asset resulting from a fork has the highest publicly traded market capitalization.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idad6c7b4806304fb290acc815aea357c9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Retention of dominant asset</header><text>The Secretary shall retain the digital asset with the highest publicly traded market capitalization that resulted from the fork.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2443d178a97a4c8cbbd5a60b6c3b42e9"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Disposition of non-dominant assets</header><text>The Secretary may sell, auction, or otherwise dispose of any digital assets resulting from the fork other than the asset identified pursuant to subparagraph (B), with the proceeds from such disposition to be deposited in the general fund of the Treasury.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id086c3dba409840d8b8ce10d4b67fc511"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Exception for novel utility</header><text>If the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Commerce and industry experts, determines that a non-dominant forked asset possesses novel technological utility or strategic value to the United States distinct from the dominant asset, the Secretary may recommend to Congress the retention of such asset, notwithstanding subparagraph (C). </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id3c328ce0e3644ceaa48469693632d5e0"><enum>5.</enum><header>Bitcoin Purchase Program</header><subsection id="id13fe21eeabc9458fa7a3c71d19943b6b"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id990222e858d34f239468d76ed6fc0cd3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish a Bitcoin Purchase Program which shall—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf2d7515ce7a94a79bc50fea7f93d15dc"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">purchase 200,000 Bitcoins per year over a 5-year period, for a total acquisition of 1,000,000 Bitcoins;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5cc8476bd0b24c3fb7fa1a3b277ebbaf"><enum>(B)</enum><text>conduct purchases in a transparent and strategic manner to minimize market disruption; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbe27a7d9bfd24622a22cdc5503030847"><enum>(C)</enum><text>hold Bitcoin acquired under this section in trust for the United States, as provided in this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id74eae6c0fd6042d9907ddaeec483025d"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Flexibility relating to purchases</header><text>The Secretary shall, by rule, establish a procedure to adjust the purchase schedule set forth under paragraph (1), if necessary, based on prevailing market conditions.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id26b6f585dbca41108283ff27a4d29ff9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Transfer offset</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any Bitcoin transferred to the Strategic Bitcoin Reserve under section 7 may offset the purchase requirements under paragraph (1). </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id67c4473c8f5848f9971e029b9f550fe8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Deposit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">All Bitcoins purchased under the Bitcoin Purchase Program shall be placed in the Strategic Bitcoin Reserve.</text></subsection><subsection id="id1db7caa64b0b41d99f7393485a8bd98a"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Minimum Holding Period</header><paragraph id="id1fef501e3da645e781f5b7bb70df5216"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To ensure the long-term stability and security of the Strategic Bitcoin Reserve, the Secretary shall hold all Bitcoin acquired by the United States and deposited in the Strategic Bitcoin Reserve, regardless of acquisition method, for not less than 20 years from the date of acquisition.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfd4e3b5e51e04fc586d30fb15c411c88"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Retention of Bitcoin</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the minimum holding period under paragraph (1), no Bitcoin held in the Strategic Bitcoin Reserve may be sold, swapped, auctioned, encumbered, or otherwise disposed of for any purpose. </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7422f4f59d4247f8bd71eaa5735f4e2c"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Recommendations after holding period</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id597f37f098f04c96b54aa304fcb27abd"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On the date that is 2 years before the end of the minimum holding period under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall submit to Congress recommendations on whether to continue to voluntarily hold or to allow for the gradual and controlled release of a portion of the holdings of the Strategic Bitcoin Reserve for the sole purpose of reducing the national debt. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaf53d824c5784d988762bca991b3b9b5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Recommendation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon the expiration of the minimum holding period, the Secretary shall not recommend selling more than 10 percent of the assets of the Strategic Bitcoin Reserve during any 2-year period. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id74cdbbd6f74749e8b7a9be67ef3766fe"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Public reports</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter for a period of 20 years, the Secretary shall publish an annual public report on the status of the Bitcoin Purchase Program.</text></subsection><subsection id="idf193db0647fd43c780b42644e251c6de"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Additional Bitcoin acquisitions</header><paragraph id="idc2a04e0bbff94cf3ba9024a8302ac4ff"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding the purchase limit established in subsection (a)(1)(A), the United States may acquire and hold Bitcoin in excess of 1,000,000 Bitcoins if such Bitcoin is acquired through—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id12b34f8dbfaa47c8ad2da50c97fe06db"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">transfers from Federal agencies pursuant to section 7;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0c481b1d0212402cbe6d8581a79a65f3"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">civil or criminal forfeitures; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id479bc1b885004035823fa954eb288860"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">gifts or bequests made to the United States; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id56004966130a4aaca0e4c36bb424bb9c"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other lawful means other than direct purchase under subsection (a)(1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ida09ab5cf740949e7818a73e6e607915c"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Treatment of additional holdings</header><text>Any Bitcoin acquired pursuant to paragraph (1) shall—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfaacc7bd1e9c41c58ca8683f44f9c833"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be placed in the Strategic Bitcoin Reserve;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id040f8b1989c24bc7bd624d3f056fc4bf"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be subject to the same security, auditing, and reporting requirements as Bitcoin acquired through the Bitcoin Purchase Program; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5cc551065be248d9b409e4c9b9971c0e"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be subject to the minimum holding period established in subsection (c)(1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9bcb05bd26ab4ac184461cd7697b4a21"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to authorize the Secretary to purchase Bitcoin in excess of the limits established in subsection (a)(1)(A) through the Bitcoin Purchase Program. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id8a64f34472fd49068060202af99de585"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Coordination with Exchange Stabilization Fund</header><text>The Secretary shall coordinate Bitcoin purchases made through the Bitcoin Purchase Program with any Bitcoin purchases made through the Exchange Stabilization Fund under section 5302 of title 31, United States Code, as amended by section 11 of this Act. </text></subsection></section><section id="idd8e38608edc845df91ba22b50ac5a376"><enum>6.</enum><header>Proof of Reserve System</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">To ensure transparency and accountability in the management of the Strategic Bitcoin Reserve, the Secretary shall establish an ongoing Proof of Reserve system of public cryptographic attestation under which—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide797c6e86ccc4cf692e4f0daf6bdab2f"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary shall—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3e87a3d87be4443baf0a7429e1db16e7"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">publish quarterly reports on the Strategic Bitcoin Reserve that include detailed information on the total holdings, transactions, and demonstrated control of private keys relating to the Strategic Bitcoin Reserve, including a public cryptographic attestation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id53db1fae6b644dca94f94805c085e3c7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>make the quarterly reports available to the public on an official website of the Department of Treasury; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idcc882e0a0f4c49c49172df1bcd9dfbb4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>select an independent, third-party auditor with expertise in cryptographic attestations to verify the accuracy and integrity of the quarterly reports; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id71b0f28e46784daca8c578022466fb73"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Comptroller General of the United States shall, to ensure compliance with this Act, conduct regular oversight of—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id411419a3c16b48d8bfe1cef4e4f0bd74"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Strategic Bitcoin Reserve;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id42f080261c4d46ec88937700dd99acc6"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the quarterly reports under paragraph (1)(A); and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2ee835aa08f54047aec3a0f2a629e0f9"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the audits under paragraph (1)(C).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="ida52543750d73433d80264cd56cff7b5d"><enum>7.</enum><header>Consolidation of Government Bitcoin Holdings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Beginning on the date of enactment of this Act, any Bitcoin under the control of any Federal agency, including the United States Marshal Service, shall—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id10b711aeaa8641daa3fb2865c095b918"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not be sold, swapped, auctioned, or otherwise encumbered; and </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd8810b53fd0e40318ab817c8d72ed46f"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">upon the acquisition of legal title to such Bitcoin (including after a final, unappealable judgment is entered in a criminal or civil forfeiture action in favor of the Federal agency), be transferred by the head of such Federal agency to the Strategic Bitcoin Reserve. </text></paragraph></section><section id="idfe913f168f834a3b98592593be394662"><enum>8.</enum><header>Voluntary State Participation and Segregated Accounts</header><subsection id="idf46ac512ccad49409ab9284ed0f8c001"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Voluntary State participation</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a program that allows a State to voluntarily participate in storing the Bitcoin holdings of the State in the Strategic Bitcoin Reserve in a segregated account.</text></subsection><subsection id="id81b175c28b24492d830ef2c11541e1fc"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Participation requirements</header><text>A State choosing to participate in the program established under subsection (a) shall sign a contractual agreement outlining the terms and conditions of participation, which shall include—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida5043aaf321d435b8367cff9fedb2adf"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the responsibilities of both the State and the Strategic Bitcoin Reserve in managing and securing the Bitcoin holdings of the State in the segregated account of the State;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id21936871913c488f8df37af3d2bad652"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a requirement that the State, in coordination with the Secretary, develop and implement appropriate security protocols and access controls to ensure the integrity and confidentiality of the segregated account of the State; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id944a9ac8e129481ba4f2f1008cec14f0"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">retention of title, and all attendant legal interests, by the State in the Bitcoin held in the segregated account, including title to any digital asset that is the result of a fork or airdrop relating to such Bitcoin.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id78a6ba97c198442ea6708496772e0f3a"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Withdraw or transfer</header><text>Each State participating in the program established under subsection (a) shall have the right to withdraw or transfer the contents of the segregated account of the State within the Strategic Bitcoin Reserve, subject to the terms and conditions in the signed contractual agreement under subsection (b) and any applicable Federal regulations.</text></subsection><subsection id="id3793fb52b70141f1afe5f7e381c773b0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limitation of liability</header><text>Any agreement entered into under subsection (b) shall include an explicit acknowledgment by the State that digital asset custody carries inherent risks that cannot be eliminated completely, and that the State assumes all risks associated with the voluntary placement of its digital assets in the Strategic Bitcoin Reserve. </text></subsection></section><section id="id1018b897c51d436085716a9557cfa758"><enum>9.</enum><header>Offsetting the cost of the strategic Bitcoin reserve</header><subsection id="id1073be422de64e479ef75bad1b53d152"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Discretionary surplus funds of federal reserve banks</header><text>Section 7(a)(3)(A) of the Federal Reserve Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/289">12 U.S.C. 289(a)(3)(A)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>$6,825,000,000</quote> and inserting <quote>$2,400,000,000</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="id1c88fead72484434b3c47700e3bb154d"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of remittances to Treasury</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id80002dc46c5742e4830f7556fc9c19af"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding the second subsection (b) of section 7 of the Federal Reserve Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/290">12 U.S.C. 290</external-xref>), for fiscal years 2025 through 2029, if the Federal reserve banks remit net earnings to the general fund of the Treasury during that period, the first $6,000,000,000 of these remittances (before repayment of any deferred asset) in a fiscal year shall be utilized by the Secretary for the implementation of the Bitcoin Purchase Program, pursuant to the purposes set forth under section 5. </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8ed333a73d8b4fd1a6881ef478c68f20"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (1) shall not apply if the Federal Reserve banks do not remit net earnings in any given fiscal year during the period of fiscal years 2025 through 2029.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id28c383bd2ad148e68d6f7c759c9dbb41"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Federal reserve system gold certificates</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Federal reserve banks shall tender all outstanding gold certificates in their custody to the Secretary. Not later than 90 days after the tender of the last such certificate, the Secretary shall issue new gold certificates to the Federal reserve banks that reflect the fair market value price of the gold held against such certificates by the Treasury, as of the date specified by the Secretary on each new gold certificate. Upon issue by the Secretary, each Federal reserve bank that receives a new gold certificate shall remit the difference in cash value between the old and new gold certificates to the Secretary for deposit in the general fund within 90 days.</text></subsection><subsection id="idf728e3b3232246fe96a95e24ad2fcf57"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Use of gold certificate remittances</header><paragraph id="id7bc42db0b5de4ac791b83578d8abd86e"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Funds remitted to the Secretary under subsection (c) shall be allocated as follows:</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id408de2a0871942268acc4edc87bd4cf1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An amount necessary to fund the Bitcoin Purchase Program, as established in section 5, shall be reserved for that purpose, up to the full amount required to purchase 1,000,000 Bitcoins under the program.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide3cdbb101fa64f318e9af96789346455"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any funds in excess of the amount necessary to fully fund the Bitcoin Purchase Program shall be deposited in the general fund of the Treasury to reduce the public debt.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id95975594da6f4fb59701046ffad985f6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Priority use</header><text>Funds allocated under paragraph (1)(A) shall be used for Bitcoin purchases under the Bitcoin Purchase Program before utilizing the remittances described in subsection (b) for such purchases.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6e56f4013b1d4734a1ae7ab3052aeb7a"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>The Secretary shall include in the annual report required under section 5(d) an accounting of all funds received under subsection (c) and their allocation pursuant to this subsection. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idfef675592b6c42ae872385b0c8a9fd54"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 5117(b) of title 31, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>(for the purpose of issuing those certificates, of 42 and two-ninths dollars a fine troy ounce)</quote>. </text></subsection></section><section id="id79cb86aebb2f464c80597eca3e2d4b7a"><enum>10.</enum><header>Protection of Private Property Rights</header><subsection id="id48aa352402ae4fba99f96762611b36b3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Rules of construction</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0a1642dc04fc4c428045609627e9dde7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">authorize the Federal Government to seize, confiscate, or otherwise impair any property right in the lawfully acquired Bitcoin holdings of any person; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc9d85ebdfa0c4e63a403ce8fbf72470c"><enum>(2)</enum><text>infringe upon the rights of individuals, businesses, or organizations to purchase, hold, transfer, or dispose of Bitcoin in accordance with the law.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id3f2245bd62324855bb316db6b3d6b08a"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Affirmation of rights</header><text>This Act affirms and protects the rights of persons to maintain full lawful control over the Bitcoin and other digital assets of those individuals, recognizing that the ability to maintain self-custody of private keys is fundamental to the principles of financial sovereignty, privacy, and personal liberty in the digital age.</text></subsection></section><section id="id4f6cf4a78e5f4af597617f4762124693"><enum>11.</enum><header>Modification of Exchange Stabilization fund</header><subsection id="id3fdddf94bee94e1db638a2556eb9ac25"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 5302 of title 31, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="idfb9122d122ac4bfb8eededc108f8d8c7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(1), by inserting <quote>section 5 of the BITCOIN Act of 2025,</quote> after <quote>section 3 of the Special Drawing Rights Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/286o">22 U.S.C. 286o</external-xref>),</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8d9bc1f14535409d9537d554fb4bb0b7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b), in the first sentence, by striking <quote>gold, foreign exchange, and other instruments of credit and securities</quote> and inserting <quote>gold, Bitcoin, foreign exchange, and other instruments of credit and securities</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id3cf875837a4d4d90bbff22e6026f0edc"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Transparency and accountability</header><text>Section 5302(c) of title 31, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="idd0f2603db5d14e59a3285d292a946a96"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by inserting <quote>, including a detailed accounting of any Bitcoin transactions and holdings</quote> after <quote>all projected liabilities</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf034c1ea270d4010918827a78cc5f610"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by inserting <quote>, including a specific accounting of any Bitcoin purchased, sold, or held by the fund during the year preceding the report</quote> after <quote>on the operation of the fund</quote>. </text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

