<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="H7FC2591B7CCA4A8BBC5664049E60389D" key="H">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2785 IH: New Mexico Land Grant-Mercedes Historical or Traditional Use Cooperation and Coordination Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2785</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20250409">April 9, 2025</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000273">Ms. Leger Fernandez</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To provide for greater cooperation and coordination between the
      Federal Government and the governing bodies and community users of land grant-mercedes in New
      Mexico relating to historical or traditional uses of certain land grant-mercedes on Federal
      public land, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H9B70171C5FB6452480AF689ADED60A2D">
<section section-type="section-one" id="H3FD8684BCDBB40A48C1A8DC41D60F5F0"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>New Mexico Land Grant-Mercedes Historical or Traditional Use Cooperation and Coordination Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H3D0C24D103CE44639AB3A17450A8F81D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
<paragraph id="H7ABC40A77B1E43038F4B9E0F8C485DA1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Community user</header><text>The term <term>community user</term> means an heir (as defined under the laws of the State) of a qualified land grant-merced.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC0BCACE353AB48BC9C4C3DA391EF627C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federal land</header> <subparagraph id="H7B86AC2552E94A7A93167651D8650D73"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>Federal land</term> means any land or interest in land owned by the United States.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H69886C7803AE440AA961C901D35286FF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusions</header><text>The term <term>Federal land</term> does not include—</text> <clause id="HE054D9FF5BA14A80AE9EF96B6B341404"><enum>(i)</enum><text>land within the boundary of an Indian reservation;</text></clause>
<clause id="H904FF20ED63A4D3E808794628033410E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>land held in trust or in restricted status by the United States for the benefit of—</text> <subclause id="H507AD7DD389547D8942EE9B792AC3C3F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>an Indian Tribe; or</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H2BEAFDCF748E454B87ABD22036935DFF"><enum>(II)</enum><text>an individual Indian; or</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H270F2A41DA8C48A3ABBE15E32DD98AB5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>land held in fee by an Indian or Indian Tribe that is subject to restrictions on alienation by the United States.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA5C67F3B84D6433DBCC714CD8476CA95"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Governing body</header><text>The term <term>governing body</term> means the board of trustees authorized under State law with the control, care, and management of a qualified land grant-merced.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA5702EAA78B24CBCA8E6D1A5A4323E6F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Historical or traditional use</header><text>The term <term>historical or traditional use</term> means the following long-established and habitual uses conducted by a qualified land grant-merced on Federal land for noncommercial benefit and for the benefit of the qualified land grant-merced:</text>
<subparagraph id="H613806F3AD264D6AAAB11A8E4F09B2BF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The use of water in accordance with all applicable Federal and State laws (including regulations).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA0FCF19AF7894ACB8DF5A96B4491BD70"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Gathering herbs in small quantities.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HC0F36BB09FEA4E4CAE7EFCF95DF37CDB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Gathering wood products in small quantities.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBFBF7205C49141E5866DB281A2D5E9E6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Gathering flora or botanical products in small quantities.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE2ECC8F7F822493E954A86FF3FB5D43E"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Grazing, to the extent that grazing has traditionally been carried out on Federal land, as determined by the Secretary concerned, in coordination with the New Mexico Land Grant Council.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H93C8CEE2395D4E208DFCE069F2964C4D"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Subsistence hunting or fishing that is conducted in accordance with State law.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE56069517B884511B9EB36CB0944BE47"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Soil or rock gathering in small quantities.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H014F4A2FB3EE46A8883358CA3B5A6832"><enum>(H)</enum><text>The use and maintenance of an existing monument or shrine.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE438CBCB41244D9FA820935B6D5F1E4C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The use and maintenance of an existing cemetery by a qualified land grant-merced.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4F250DAD98A943AD81F031487E91AED4"><enum>(J)</enum><text>Any other long-established and habitual use conducted by a qualified land grant-merced for noncommercial benefit that—</text>
<clause id="HE114362710324A9BA7874AA696C27804"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has a sustainable use by the qualified land grant-merced, as determined by the Secretary concerned, in coordination with the New Mexico Land Grant Council;</text></clause> <clause id="H4CF1A3D7D6384B088313B9D213034B1C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>supports the long-term integrity of the qualified land grant-merced, as determined by the Secretary concerned, in coordination with the New Mexico Land Grant Council; and</text></clause>
<clause id="HEC3C5D4C1F544E099C36DA5E9508AF57"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>is agreed to in writing by the Secretary concerned and the New Mexico Land Grant Council.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDCE2654EEA6B4CBAAE66CC94610792E8"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Indian tribe</header><text>The term <term>Indian Tribe</term> means the governing body of any individually identified and federally recognized Indian or Alaska Native tribe, band, nation, pueblo, village, community, affiliated Tribal group, or component reservation included on the most recent list published pursuant to section 104(a) of the Federally Recognized Indian Tribe List Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5131">25 U.S.C. 5131(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0EA001F29CBF4F3797AF81FB8127C4B6"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Memorandum of understanding</header><text>The term <term>memorandum of understanding</term> means a memorandum of understanding entered into or extended, renewed, or revised under section 3(a)(1).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD63396CE9FD6474AA9771430E909AB40"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Noncommercial benefit</header><text>The term <term>noncommercial benefit</term> means a benefit from a use, the primary purpose of which is not the sale of a good or service.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE11DB946087B4855B9781EFF39BB3346"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Qualified land grant-merced</header><text>The term <term>qualified land grant-merced</term> means a community land grant issued under the laws or customs of the Government of Spain or Mexico that—</text> <subparagraph id="HB891C98E70544A299088B477404B6DBC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is recognized under New Mexico Statutes Chapter 49, Articles 1 and 4 (or a successor statute); and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H7F8FED64E90A48F9AF4AFDA50445855B"><enum>(B)</enum>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H26227961E97F4BAE990D3890F17A0338"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has a record of historical or traditional use on Federal land under the jurisdiction of the Secretary concerned; or</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="H182ECD1056AF4B8C95131894FA543FD8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has a patented exterior boundary that is or was previously located on or adjacent to Federal land under the jurisdiction of the Secretary concerned.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0FF5A7181F734C74AD3DEBBF65243907"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Secretary concerned</header><text>The term <term>Secretary concerned</term> means the Secretary of Agriculture or the Secretary of the Interior, with respect to Federal land under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of Agriculture or the Secretary of the Interior, respectively.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1F97860331584715AFA4E63D114A5B83"><enum>(10)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means the State of New Mexico.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="HD2F5E732C5B04078BE57FF9A4DAFEF71"><enum>3.</enum><header>Memorandum of understanding on permit requirements and other land use authorizations for historical or traditional uses of qualified land grant-mercedes; reduction or waiver of certain fees</header>
<subsection id="HE38B4EE88BEE4E4AA5FA2AD5D34C2BE6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Memorandum of understanding</header>
<paragraph id="H6CB2E96089074951A593525627D901F2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary concerned, acting through the appropriate officials of the Department of Agriculture and the Department of the Interior in the State, in consultation with Indian Tribes, shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HB5BEBDBBC9E14249BDE1A14C05230393"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, enter into an initial memorandum of understanding with the New Mexico Land Grant Council; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H0FB32F5BF69842348342318D007A202A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>subject to the requirements of this section, on the expiration of the initial memorandum of understanding entered into under subparagraph (A) or any successor memorandum of understanding entered into under this subparagraph—</text> <clause id="H4AF2D3A79C8B477A9A4D6FC672D9B577"><enum>(i)</enum><text>enter into a successor memorandum of understanding with the New Mexico Land Grant Council; or</text></clause>
<clause id="HCC72C13528944389A53EC3AC1CB78854"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>extend or renew, with any revisions determined to be appropriate by the Secretary concerned and the New Mexico Land Grant Council, the expired memorandum of understanding.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H75181AB8966E4F8E822ED0E81943F8E6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applicable requirements and authorizations</header> <subparagraph id="H1233143E09CC4EAAB44F6EB3F55EAC36"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A memorandum of understanding shall—</text>
<clause id="HAD703295E63C4E3CAC65233D317A0E22">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>provide for enhanced cooperation and coordination between the Secretary concerned and qualified land grant-mercedes;</text>
            </clause>
<clause id="H210206F73E04429DAE64B6F8848BF1D2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provide for the Secretary concerned, acting through the appropriate officials of the Department of Agriculture and the Department of the Interior, to enter into subsidiary agreements with qualified land grant-mercedes for specific projects consistent with the memorandum of understanding; and</text></clause> <clause id="H79DBB4E3D2364AB99AD4A7996AA6DC42"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>be consistent with, and subject to—</text>
<subclause id="H18C45019799B4701AE4A81A44757AC00"><enum>(I)</enum><text>applicable Federal laws (including regulations);</text></subclause> <subclause id="HDB65920AE4874BDF9692E7883EA10249"><enum>(II)</enum><text>applicable land use plans; and</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H37463C167C264EF2A9AA8FD237EB5DFB"><enum>(III)</enum><text>valid existing rights.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6955220F8F1143BF972C493892DFAA26"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Permits and other land use authorizations</header><text>A memorandum of understanding shall include—</text>
<clause id="HB849D504B6AF4098AB22A49335E8BFD7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a description of the types of historical or traditional uses that—</text> <subclause id="H8FDFD220381F40EA966C19BD7BFECA41"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a community user or a governing body of a qualified land grant-merced may conduct for noncommercial benefit on Federal land under the jurisdiction of the Secretary concerned; and</text></subclause>
<subclause id="HE24D40333D554D6897E6E6D51303C844"><enum>(II)</enum><text>require a permit or other land use authorization from the Secretary concerned;</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H0A72B65B05B04594A3EDD1492D6698E1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a citation to, and description of, any administrative procedures for obtaining the permit or other land use authorization under clause (i);</text></clause>
<clause id="HC45186DAB277489B8DF62B24C5D12579"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a description of—</text> <subclause id="H97A4291B360349FFA57BE0C820B7ADAD"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the types of fees, including cost recovery fees and land use fees, that may be associated with a permit or other land use authorization under clause (i); and</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H7937C5D0AB82455AB8CC4E4846D6F23A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>if applicable, the process to request a reduction or waiver of the fees described in subclause (I) under regulations promulgated by the Secretary concerned;</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H14637D34BB06440087F33E072F7F7983"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a description of the process for determining the permissible use of motorized and nonmotorized vehicles and equipment by a community user or the governing body of a qualified land grant-merced for noncommercial historical or traditional use on Federal land under the jurisdiction of the Secretary concerned;</text></clause>
<clause id="H31D4744CD2844C0D8E3A9087396708D7"><enum>(v)</enum><text>a description of the process for determining the permissible use of mechanized vehicles or equipment by a community user or governing body of a qualified land grant-merced for historical or traditional use on Federal land under the jurisdiction of the Secretary concerned;</text></clause> <clause id="HFD7F5E4F509F4D278E5190DC295DEE8B"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>a description of the process for determining the permissible use of nonnative material by a community user or the governing body of a qualified land grant-merced for any of the uses described in subparagraphs (C) and (D) on Federal land under the jurisdiction of the Secretary concerned;</text></clause>
<clause id="H39C17598B40541AB82FB2ECBC17B8BD2"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>a description of any applicable restrictions and prohibitions on historical or traditional uses conducted by a qualified land grant-merced on Federal land under the jurisdiction of the Secretary concerned; and</text></clause> <clause id="HB818101C099148A584611095E4537EDB"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>a description of the process, in accordance with applicable law, for consulting with 1 or more Indian Tribes that would be directly affected by a proposed historical or traditional use on Federal land by a qualified land grant-merced.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H14144B402697414E99005139665A3667"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Routine maintenance and minor improvements</header><text>A memorandum of understanding shall address authorization of routine maintenance and minor improvements of infrastructure used by a qualified land grant-merced in connection with a historical or traditional use on Federal land under the jurisdiction of the Secretary concerned, including—</text> <clause id="H8C1667809C8D409285867E4806C9B825"><enum>(i)</enum><text>cleaning, repair, or replacement-in-kind of infrastructure;</text></clause>
<clause id="HED4DC4969D62401C88C19E74C0759B0C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>maintenance of a trail, road, cattle guard, culvert, or fence;</text></clause> <clause id="H8C35436D03194DA19B1DA7497D13AB6E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>maintenance of a monument or shrine;</text></clause>
<clause id="H638634CE7CB84CE595EE9BA69BB116CB"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>maintenance of a community cemetery by a qualified land grant-merced;</text></clause> <clause id="H90F86C5D19DB4DAEBB8D7685DAE51087"><enum>(v)</enum><text>maintenance of a livestock well, water line, water storage container, or water tank; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H20CB66AFA24F4D348D3B9FF7EB5E7C40"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>any other routine maintenance or minor improvement associated with historical or traditional uses identified by the New Mexico Land Grant Council during the development of the memorandum of understanding.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3AD25336028B49A39CFAFD896B210B74"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Major improvements</header><text>A memorandum of understanding may describe the process for authorizing major improvements of infrastructure of a qualified land grant-merced in connection with a historical or traditional use on Federal land under the jurisdiction of the Secretary concerned, including—</text>
<clause id="H1633AFD1DCE04B8CA0D5EF83CE5F951C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>construction or expansion of a community water or wastewater system of a qualified land grant-merced;</text></clause> <clause id="H5D1813B545F44023BF2DE3B4D3F04B77"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>construction or major repair of a livestock well, water line, water storage container, or water tank of a qualified land grant-merced;</text></clause>
<clause id="H0B6F94C848E5401D99D779B3CA9A63AA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>major repair of a monument or shrine of a qualified land grant-merced;</text></clause> <clause id="H597E22016EDF47AE95468F4D4C1EBEC2"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>installation of a cattle guard;</text></clause>
<clause id="H7C99B0F3920745008FC5462005986FFE"><enum>(v)</enum><text>construction of a trail, road, or fence;</text></clause> <clause id="H46CFD72BDE2C41C5AFED5EAF6C8753DB"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>construction or expansion of a community cemetery by a qualified land grant-merced; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H512D03A7471B4E35964A930EBCF5F4C9"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>any other major improvement associated with historical or traditional uses, as determined by the Secretary concerned.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H165C1DDCD8FF4923B274C922CC1E0009"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Notice and comment</header><text>A memorandum of understanding shall describe the policies and procedures for notice and comment on land management planning decisions and major Federal actions that could affect historical or traditional uses of Federal land by a qualified land grant-merced, and methods of providing the notice, including notice—</text>
<clause id="H75B5DC85DCD042DC8E6BF83CF10B86C3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>online;</text></clause> <clause id="H9F7CD38E77474185B807299052821BCC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in print; and</text></clause>
<clause id="HA66AC9E07538425FB78C267B7681579D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by mail or email to the New Mexico Land Grant Council and Indian Tribes, including through a listserv that would include qualified land grant-mercedes, the New Mexico Land Grant Council, and Indian Tribes.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H69E6C1B148C34E948D55BB43BFEA30E6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Development, execution, and implementation of memorandum of understanding</header> <subparagraph id="H63E2B6E2C09D4A5991B5D70E9181AF01"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Role of the new mexico land grant council</header><text>The New Mexico Land Grant Council may represent qualified land grant-mercedes in developing, executing, and implementing a memorandum of understanding.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HDA3638BCA780449A998DBD410951932B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Role of governing bodies of qualified land grant-mercedes</header><text>The Secretary concerned may invite representatives of governing bodies of qualified land grant-mercedes to participate in meetings and provide input during the development of a memorandum of understanding.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H31BC945F184840279C3D32D8B816F5E0"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>A memorandum of understanding—</text>
<subparagraph id="H5A5BD527C043482EA312E47A59ED1347"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall describe the process for a qualified land grant-merced to obtain authorizations for historical or traditional uses through existing authorities, subject to existing Federal laws (including regulations) and applicable permit and land use authorization requirements; but</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H97A04A8542DB4424ADED2644497937B2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall not directly approve or authorize a historical or traditional use described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HA11623081F7745FFAA03FB726FA7C0F7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Fees for qualified land grant-Mercedes</header><text>Where the Secretary concerned is authorized to reduce or waive land use fees or consider the fiscal capacity of the applicant in determining whether to reduce or waive a fee for a land use permit, the Secretary shall consider—</text> <paragraph id="HB21CC897DA264F0792D3E69AC799B7E9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the socioeconomic conditions of community users of a qualified land grant-merced; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6D76F28D65C248A59BDA4642AF33B450"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the annual operating budget of the governing body of the qualified land grant-merced.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HEB7C64487028498A92C4CB16C3AB007C"><enum>4.</enum><header>Consideration and inclusion of provisions with respect to historical or traditional uses in land use planning</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In developing, maintaining, and revising land use plans pursuant to section 202 of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1712">43 U.S.C. 1712</external-xref>) and section 6 of the National Forest Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1604">16 U.S.C. 1604</external-xref>), as applicable, the Secretary concerned shall, in accordance with applicable law, and, as determined to be appropriate by the Secretary concerned, include a section in the applicable land use plan that considers and evaluates the impact of other uses in the land use plan on historical or traditional uses by qualified land grant-mercedes.</text></section>
<section id="HB4ED75DD9D754D7FBCA166F3D6C377EF"><enum>5.</enum><header>Effect</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act—</text> <paragraph id="H0BAF336867B84BB2BF323AAFE52D188D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>modifies, limits, expands, or otherwise affects any treaty-reserved right, or any other right of, or obligation to, any Indian Tribe, including treaties or agreements with the United States, Executive orders, statutes, regulations, or case law, that is recognized on or after the date of enactment of this Act by any other means;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H10141FC56965465EB61831BDAE9F4F8A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>affects the authority of the State to regulate water use in accordance with all Federal and State laws (including regulations);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5A7300F147A4420BB05AB67599752F69"><enum>(3)</enum><text>affects the authority of the State to regulate the management of game and fish, in accordance with all Federal and State laws (including regulations);</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H71BED30A5A38474DA7E4269C9719A09C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>affects any valid existing rights, or valid permitted authorized uses of, Federal land; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H57E9167FCA064FA49A3BA4B155757664"><enum>(5)</enum><text>creates any implicit or explicit right to any type of use of Federal land.</text></paragraph></section>
</legis-body>
</bill>

