<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4AEFFA224948495A87C483DACF1C9871" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4263 IH: 123 GO Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4263</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250630">June 30, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001224">Mr. Self</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001309">Mr. Burchett</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001322">Mr. Baumgartner</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To enhance the competitiveness of the nuclear sector of the United States in foreign countries, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9065EB0D554C43F6932F6E2D64F6D8C7" style="OLC"><section id="H7F7D33AF76E84553BF20043D8B8DCCBF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>123 GO Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H723E0FA2F52542C8B7D58E617886AD96"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that Executive Order 14299 (90 Fed. Reg. 22581; relating to deploying advanced nuclear reactor technologies for national security) reflects the interests of the United States. </text></section><section id="H8BB1B1D29689470FA5E82C908F938FB0"><enum>3.</enum><header>Negotiation of 123 agreements</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of State shall—</text><paragraph id="H2CDE4F59170D4D24874BB507E42F50FC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>lead diplomatic engagement and negotiations for agreements for cooperation pursuant to section 123 of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2153">42 U.S.C. 2153</external-xref>) (hereafter referred to as <quote>123 agreements</quote>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF973FAF6F9FB4E73A545AD3C745C1001"><enum>(2)</enum><text>seek to enter into not fewer than 20 new 123 agreements before January 3, 2029; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7C96EFF76D9347A192DC3E87D08EEBA2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>seek to renegotiate or renew 123 agreements that are scheduled to expire before the date that is 10 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HB33DECFD4F5C47398F384F571396B562"><enum>4.</enum><header>Program to enhance global competitiveness</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of Commerce and the Secretary of Energy, and after review by the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy and the Assistant to the President for Economic Policy, shall implement a program to enhance the global competitiveness of United States persons (as such term is defined in section 1637(d) of the Carl Levin and Howard P. “Buck” McKeon National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal year 2015 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1708">50 U.S.C. 1708(d)</external-xref>) who are nuclear suppliers, investors, or lenders to compete for nuclear projects in foreign countries, including—</text><paragraph id="H483C1A4E52CA45EE8953E39E88FC0366"><enum>(1)</enum><text>expediting the conclusion of intergovernmental agreements on nuclear energy and the fuel supply chain with potential export countries;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1ABAF6278298475CBDBCE2E04687DD74"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">promoting broad adherence to the Convention on Supplementary Compensation for Nuclear Damage, with Annex, done at Vienna September 12, 1997 (TIAS 15–415);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC0EA4B74310F4433BD5E5064184F2852"><enum>(3)</enum><text>identifying statutory and regulatory burdens on exports of nuclear technology, fuel supplies, equipment, and services from the United States and recommending action to relieve such burdens; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9B0833A10A454BFE859C46D371E09A20"><enum>(4)</enum><text>encouraging favorable decisions by potential import countries on the use of nuclear technology, fuel supplies, equipment, and services from the United States.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

