<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB0BCDF7518844834BC2C1E389DC7248E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4347 IH: To amend the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 to provide employment and training data grants, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4347</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250710">July 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001226">Ms. Salinas</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 to provide employment and training data grants, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA07FC6E0CF75459BB750EDA83419B866" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HBE71A1F4CD494930878B99192E55F05B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>SNAP E&amp;T Data And Technical Assistance (DATA) Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H3F90799BD1744159B334EE1BBCC1F48D" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Amendment</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 5 of the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2014">7 U.S.C. 2014</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H2A2FD07252A94516833B28DBE12A2777" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="HEE69082EC06E4D23A97DDA89D3A32163"><enum>(o)</enum><header>Employment and training data grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary is authorized to award grants to State agencies, on a competitive basis, for the purpose of creating and strengthening longitudinal administrative databases and associated resources for the purpose of strengthening program quality, reducing burden, advancing equity, protecting privacy, and improving transparency in supplemental nutrition and assistance program employment and training programs.</text> <paragraph id="H241A54E2E27246BBA40900EDF32D2CB0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Award basis</header><text>The Secretary shall award grants on a competitive basis and in a manner consistent with the following priorities:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H20FB741B29BB417A9AF16F36B3A12458"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Encouraging participation among States that have not yet received such grants and among those with the greatest needs in terms of data infrastructure.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE17B3D329217494A924DF43AB4009E9B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Strengthening effectiveness in meeting the purposes of section 6(d)(4)(A)(i).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD6550D632B84463EA8D44740014EA2A4">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>Facilitating co-enrollment and coordination of services between employment and training programs offered under this Act and other federally-supported workforce development programs, such as those authorized under the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3101">29 U.S.C. 3101 et seq.</external-xref>) and the Strengthening Career and Technical Education for the 21st Century Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/224">Public Law 115–224</external-xref>; 132 Stat. 1563) and the amendments made by that Act.</text>
            </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0FFD587987604F60B61851F8B6616F4C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Participating in and contributing data to the State’s linked longitudinal data system, including submitting data that when linked with K–12, postsecondary, and workforce development data, provides the State with the ability to create more robust tools and analytics.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9187644346F3443D9572B266DA920F32"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Encouraging the use of non-Federal contributions to improve State data infrastructure and related resources.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBD65E3A18A434260AC1B97A3060396F5"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Enabling research and program improvement activities.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDE416FC9ACCF49E1B2DF69BE73DBA694"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Other priorities as determined by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H97045F9A804B4412971B5E6BB56387FA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Privacy and security standards</header><text>Data supported by this subsection shall be—</text> <subparagraph id="H51D0B8BC92FC454CB9501DBA3E3B5B77"><enum>(A)</enum><text>used only for the purpose described in this subsection;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD8276E54EB3941FAB11E76F0D9E38377"><enum>(B)</enum><text>exempted from the disclosure requirements of section 552(a) of title 5 of the United States Code pursuant to section 552(b)(3) of such title, to the extent such information is obtained or received by the Secretary;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H15BFF0F98DFD431AB9585350EC065A16"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">used in a manner that protects the identity and location of an individual that is an applicant for, or recipient of, supplemental nutrition assistance program benefits; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA05605A411884483BDCAB512B49009E3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>shall meet security standards as determined by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD298C057B0304E7D89118B9F11EE9BE7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Supplement not supplant</header><text>Funds made available under this subsection shall be used to supplement, and not supplant, other State or local funds used for developing State data systems.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H68CCAC3C960246BA9570DA2495F565FB"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the funds available under section 18, the Secretary shall use to carry out this subsection $15,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2026 through 2030.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7CD4C20D9B574850BBB8C3445D3CF8BB"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Administrative costs</header><text>The Secretary shall reserve not more than 20 percent of the funds made available under paragraph (4) for the provision of technical assistance to support the implementation of these Grants.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H35C146C83EDB4AF89CF00A96969EDE79"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 3 years after the effective date of this subsection, and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate, a report regarding implementation of this subsection that, includes the following information.</text> <subparagraph id="H9BB961D9B4D34F65A3D00670CEA20BB4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The number of grants awarded, a list of recipients, and the amount of funds awarded.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H42DD817C4A324BE8A7161A0F5BF195A3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A description of recipients’ use of the grant funds.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H49F287027BD14396BF5DE7CB2CE5133E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>An analysis of the impact of receiving such grants on improving the effectiveness of State employment and training programs in meeting the purposes of section 6(d)(4)(A)(i).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
<section id="HFF8F2039A3994843810B3229F2AF121F"><enum>3.</enum><header>GAO report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after funds are made available to carry out section 5(o) of the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2014">7 U.S.C. 2014(o)</external-xref>), the Comptroller General of the United States shall—</text> <paragraph id="H8580897FE4D14D22AAD537607CBC7288"><enum>(1)</enum><text>examine and review the implementation of such section, including an examination of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H0DE5B849DFCE40E5AD13857E2A577A68"><enum>(A)</enum><text>co-enrollment strategies and related best practices that maximize participant eligibility using linked and integrated data;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB4CD13FF41414FD7BEA7332A2FEA8CCA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an examination and distillation of best practices related to the coordination and braiding of funds that improve the quality of employment and training programs implemented under the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H198B7203F44A43F7AF01B9FE5BF5E31E"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">additional issues and impact that access to linked and integrated databases and the development of data exchange agreements have on the participant and provider outcomes within employment and training programs implemented under the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H659B732A99404AC88EDE8D81C9F07935"><enum>(2)</enum><text>develop recommendations to the Secretary of Agriculture on any changes that should be made to improve such data grants; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H42ADF1D59E394944AC4734F7A17168D7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>prepare and submit a report on the findings and recommendations based on the examination made under paragraph (1), and recommendations received, under paragraph (2), to—</text> <subparagraph id="H2F1525B291CA4C0C9FA3FC56E1A2EC4A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H792B54ABE2EA4386BFA4B06F3743BBBC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

