<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC2F85A0E5B81447A9567293E53F47EF8" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4281 IH: Bunker Buster Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4281</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250702">July 2, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001217">Mr. Moskowitz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001201">Mr. Suozzi</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the President to take actions to ensure Israel is prepared for all contingencies if Iran seeks to develop a nuclear weapon, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA8F131DE225B4C16B7E6BEB8552F0283" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H2CB7A0759B8A4E619274013CBEC3D454" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Bunker Buster Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H4E677D48C6F84EC78C7F363523CF6B21"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H5A6358262ADB47549D3E262FF78FF9A1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The United States Nuclear Regulatory Commission defines <quote>high-enriched uranium</quote> as uranium enriched to at least 20 percent uranium-235.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA42C12130EEC4B76AF267FFBB9AEBD59"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Under the 2015 Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action, Iran agreed to refrain from producing enriched uranium containing more than 3.67 percent uranium-235 for 15 years.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE5FACA27D5044AA99031E5ACF7397C53"><enum>(3)</enum><text>On January 13, 2019, the head of the Atomic Energy Organization of Iran, Dr. Ali Akbar Salehi, told the Fars News Agency, <quote>If we want to come out of the nuclear deal and produce, within four days we could start our 20 percent.</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H291718CB558F451896716278347799E7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>On April 16, 2021, Dr. Salehi told the state television that Iran had begun enriching uranium to 60 percent.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H85C9849DA97041F682304B86E00F1FF4"><enum>(5)</enum><text>On July 14, 2021, the former President of Iran, President Hassan Rouhani, said during a press conference that Iran has the knowledge and ability to enrich weapons-grade uranium at 90 percent.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H58C45912501747B49BE627598840784B"><enum>(6)</enum><text>According to an International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA) report, as of May 11, 2024, Iran has 142.1 kilograms (313.2 pounds) of uranium enriched up to 60 percent, an increase of 20.6 kilograms (45.4 pounds) since the last report by the United Nations watchdog in February. Uranium enriched at 60 percent purity is just a short, technical step away from weapons-grade levels of 90 percent. Iran’s overall stockpile of enriched uranium stands at 6,201.3 kilograms (1,3671.5 pounds), which represents an increase of 675.8 kilograms (1,489.8 pounds) since the IAEA’s previous report.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H24DABDFC6E414AACAA14440E8A33338C"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The current stockpile is enough to make several nuclear bombs according to the criteria the IAEA uses to make such determinations.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9AA7EF3907E842389E759F4CCC1113F3"> <enum>(8)</enum> <text>Reports indicate the Iran may be constructing new facilities to help expand its nuclear program.</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H19BC164BA74C43A5AE5A34A4A48C6070"><enum>(9)</enum><text>In June 2024, the IAEA elected to censure Iran for its violation of international responsibilities under its nuclear agreement and demanded its cooperation, including the readmittance of inspectors and the restoration of camera surveillance at nuclear sites.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE92B9BEF6F4D433DA5F5E1C1F73E3F26"><enum>(10)</enum><text>In June the IAEA announced Iran is installing 1,400 new advanced centrifuges at its Fordow facility.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA514C547115541F391F14417B501CC5E"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Since October 7, 2023, Israel has been at war with Hamas in the Gaza strip, which has used Iranian funding and direction to target the Jewish state.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2DD8A71524BA49488C3AD00CC033072A"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Hamas continues to hide within civilian infrastructure, fire rockets at humanitarian crossings, and steal international aid and resources that are only further hurting the Palestinian civilians. Hamas has built tunnels under United Nations Relief and Works Agency for Palestine Refugees in the Near East (UNRWA) buildings, including a large data center under UNRWA’s Gaza base, and stores weapons in UNRWA schools.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H31346B3A0085416290B618BBC5264E15"><enum>(13)</enum><text>As of June 2024, Ansarullah, or otherwise known as the Houthis, have launched at least 60 attacks at ships. They have seized 1 vessel, killed 4 sailors, and sunk 2 ships since November 2023. The Houthis have also launched drones, missiles, and mortars toward Israel and at United States and its allies. The Houthis operate with Iranian funds.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEAA9B769B11947EBB3A39B742FFCBAEC"><enum>(14)</enum><text>Since October 7, 2023, Hezbollah has launched over 5,000 rockets, missiles, and drones at Israel. Iran has, provided Hezbollah with more than 100,000 missiles and rockets.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H58FFC956A9CC4C759E04F4C8477B86E5"><enum>(15)</enum><text>Iran is expanding its missile capacity and weaponization program to further assist their proxies across the region.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC2D6A085D86C474088854EBE7B0D91B7"><enum>(16)</enum><text>On June 12, 2025, 60 days had lapsed without an agreement in diplomatic negotiations to prevent Iran from attaining a nuclear weapon.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H863E96580BA24607B3C86E2E2437B980"><enum>(17)</enum><text>On June 12, 2025, IAEA board declared Iran in violation of its non-proliferation obligations.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2F5F45CD7E67458A8FBD93F39CAE05B9"><enum>(18)</enum><text>On June 13, 2025, Israel launched a coordinated series of strikes against Iranian military and government targets in efforts to disrupt Iran’s development of a nuclear weapon based on Israeli intelligence assessment that Iran had taken steps putting them closer to achieving nuclear latency.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HAF558C6BB79F4C5A8F262275101DD9FC"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that the United States should—</text> <paragraph id="HC0DC3EDC32FB4F0693078A7E9D9C24AA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>seek to extend the limitations on Iran’s enriched uranium, including through engagement in multilateral diplomatic initiatives;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7DFC05FBBD6747F58FDE4D4425571F31"><enum>(2)</enum><text>ensure that Israel and other allies are prepared for all contingencies if Iran pursues development of a nuclear weapon;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8121B1F36F744D358E92D09A9179FB60"><enum>(3)</enum><text>send a clear signal to Iran that development of a nuclear weapon will never be tolerated; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5DED6BDF78984EE59348F405B68A7142"><enum>(4)</enum><text>reaffirm the United States commitment to deter Iranian nuclear development with a credible military threat.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H4A325726947A45CA8A3083FC4A3535F0"><enum>4.</enum><header>Actions to ensure Israel is prepared for all contingencies if Iran seeks to develop a nuclear weapon</header> <subsection id="H69FB18AA430F40AF9311EDA6D8D06B5F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to the preliminary conditions described in subsection (b), the President is authorized to take the actions described in subsection (c), upon the request of the Government of Israel, to ensure Israel is prepared for all contingencies if Iran seeks to develop a nuclear weapon.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H48049F3C21C54E3C8815583486996E97"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Preliminary conditions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may exercise the authority of subsection (a) only if the President first determines and certifies to Congress that it is vital to the national security interests of the United States to do so and the conditions in subsection (c)(2)(B) are met.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="HEDF77C74D53F4174A48358F778054A53"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Actions described</header><text>The actions described in this subsection are the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HFDB7024E45E64E47B4B0B7D0CFF90872"><enum>(1)</enum><text>To provide for the construction of infrastructure in Israel to accommodate large ordnance systems that are designed to destroy underground nuclear infrastructure, including—</text> <subparagraph id="H95F1E06258D44E3CBB411DD6A17AAB8B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>construction of extended runways for aircraft that carry the Massive Ordnance Penetrator (MOP);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE62B0488140246FCBACF7B9C6018DEBD"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">aircraft to carry and deliver the MOP;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6FE4FC9ADEBE49918D77F7AAAF35C502"><enum>(C)</enum><text>basing options for such aircraft; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA1A7DD2B79A1459BADB0432BE7A8FADF"><enum>(D)</enum><text>munition storage facilities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE3A2EB66881146D39FC430C9F8B6CD68"><enum>(2)</enum> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H0559BA14EF97445DB31AC27A3951ABA8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>To store in the territory of Israel the MOP or related munitions described in paragraph (1), to be used by the United States except as provided in subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H819393F04E304701ABAAE669CF22E4EE" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>To transfer the MOP or related munitions described in paragraph (1) to Israeli custody if the President determines and certifies to Congress that—</text> <clause id="H358AC1CFC0DB45229A815127EB4F5BCA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Iran—</text> 
<subclause id="HAE8A01C0BB304D2C8EC91000C6CA86E1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is in noncompliance with the NPT Safeguards Agreement;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H44496312C3F6479EB963C32DAF4DA0DB"><enum>(II)</enum><text>has modified its implementation of the NPT Safeguards Agreement (including modified Code 3.1); or</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H32EE7578DBB84013B6F4AB54AAC7BE16"><enum>(III)</enum><text>as determined by the President, has reduced access of inspectors of the IAEA in such a manner so as to be prejudicial to the IAEA’s ability to provide confidence as to the non-diversion of declared nuclear material and absence of undeclared nuclear activities;</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H9BDD81F3C4784FCA877D16357DACE873"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>it is vital to the national security of the United States to do so;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H1A9BBF5E8E5841C6AC6316273C71B7EC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Israel has no other means to achieve a mutual national security objective of destroying Iran’s underground nuclear infrastructure or facilities; and</text></clause> <clause id="HD10C07301FDE4233A4BF0B63F4867E1E"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a dual key control system is in place requiring approval by the President, acting through the Secretary of Defense (which may not be further delegated) for deployment of the MOP or related munitions described in paragraph (1) prior to Israeli deployment of such munitions.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H70CFD4A3F18D45F9BD46C716CCF453B8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>To provide for training of Israeli personnel with respect to the MOP or related munitions described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H817F67391BFB41BD851C81D82B890372"><enum>(4)</enum><text>To conduct joint research and development with Israel to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H4D2B25BB6683486FB768FD8192C36F5F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>enhance United States ordnance; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H923F20AD0754457E8BB765A90A77E394"><enum>(B)</enum><text>develop Israeli capability for ordnance to destroy underground infrastructure, including Hezbollah rocket storage and manufacturing facilities and underground Iranian nuclear facilities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4A8516761D974F4DB4C8B81C8397D05C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>NPT safeguards agreement defined</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>NPT Safeguards Agreement</quote> means the Agreement between Iran and the International Atomic Energy Agency for the Application of Safeguards in Connection with the Treaty on the Non-Proliferation of Nuclear Weapons, which entered into force on May 15, 1974.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H4C37C14C68F3440199E5F4C62B97E01A"><enum>5.</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act may be construed to serve as an authorization for the use of military force against Iran.</text></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

