<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Enrolled-Bill" dms-id="H40088C2C202843699566F26B1E3AB839" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-joint" star-print="no-star-print" key="H" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title> HJ 105 ENR: Providing for congressional disapproval under chapter 8 of title 5, United States Code, of the rule submitted by the Bureau of Land Management relating to “North Dakota Field Office Record of Decision and Approved Resource Management Plan”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">IA</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">One Hundred Nineteenth Congress of the United States of America</congress> 
<session display="yes">At the First Session</session><enrolled-dateline>Begun and held at the City of Washington on Friday, the third day of January, two thousand and twenty-five</enrolled-dateline> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. J. RES. 105</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no"></current-chamber> 
<legis-type>JOINT RESOLUTION</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">Providing for congressional disapproval under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/8">chapter 8</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, of the rule submitted by the Bureau of Land Management relating to <quote>North Dakota Field Office Record of Decision and Approved Resource Management Plan</quote>.</official-title> 
</form> 
<resolution-body style="traditional" id="HC6674DD3C9A54C9CBF8D6E1F5B92B8D4"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HF8730FE0028242FA93E49423A0A90346"><enum/><text>That Congress disapproves the rule submitted by the Bureau of Land Management relating to <quote>North Dakota Field Office Record of Decision and Approved Resource Management Plan</quote> (issued January 14, 2025, as a record of decision and approved resource management plan, and a letter of opinion from the Government Accountability Office dated June 25, 2025, printed in the Congressional Record on June 26, 2025, on pages S3556–S3558, concluding that such record of decision and approved resource management plan is a rule under the Congressional Review Act), and such rule shall have no force or effect. </text></section> </resolution-body> <attestation><attestation-group><role>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</role></attestation-group><attestation-group><role>Vice President of the United States and President of the Senate.</role></attestation-group></attestation> </resolution> 

