<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H71A90DADA06E4DBDB93D96E4331CC7F5" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 901 IH: Research Security and Accountability in DHS Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 901</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250131">January 31, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001220">Mr. Strong</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000590">Mr. Green of Tennessee</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="E000300">Mr. Evans of Colorado</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Under Secretary of the Science and Technology Directorate of the Department of Homeland Security to develop a Department-wide policy and process to safeguard research and development from unauthorized access to or disclosure of sensitive information in research and development acquisitions, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8D17601DF0CA4B928C8100FB7507FABC" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H9CB6EE65091C45E8A4C4E1D179F3356F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Research Security and Accountability in DHS Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H0733BA0EBF4649A68AA34DCC78127B77"><enum>2.</enum><header>Safeguarding sensitive research in the Department of Homeland Security</header> <subsection id="H740C84C319C149E797E024607D1F05F0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 302 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/182">6 U.S.C. 182</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="HA33C63335E154950B5BFAA201DE227A2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (13), by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFFCC30E9F68740959D47506E3476D06C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (14), by striking the period and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8F7C5D7C5A2A4A3493D1A96C7D47D6B9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HAB300788BCC94F2897057AFDB730615A" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="H2940CA1EC97A49FF97EC764D6B67084B"><enum>(15)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">developing, in coordination with appropriate agency officials, a Department-wide policy and process to safeguard research and development from unauthorized access to or disclosure of sensitive information in research and development acquisitions.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H84BA600D27014FDFADFFE51134ABA4F2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>GAO report</header>
<paragraph id="H6BAFE983E36346E7AD30D87CE68E5414"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a report on how the Department of Homeland Security has complied with National Security Presidential Memorandum–33 (NSPM–33) and adopted the National Science and Technology Council’s 2022 implementation guidance.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5F9868CB041B4AD79478E42537E78361"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The report required under paragraph (1) shall address the following:</text>
<subparagraph id="HDCEA27CC68D94AD89BFCABA6971CFB55"><enum>(A)</enum><text>How the Department of Homeland Security has complied with disclosure requirements outlined in NSPM–33, and how violations are reported to the relevant executive agencies, including in the intelligence community (as such term is defined in section 3(4) of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3003">50 U.S.C. 3003(4)</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H31691871B473459B8116788CBAEDA226"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Coordination and compliance with guidelines established by the National Science Foundation, the National Science Technology Council, the Office of Science and Technology Policy, and other executive agencies regarding Federal research security.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H1FEC4D15230E482FA7FD14E4F3A3B852"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The role of the Science and Technology Directorate of the Department regarding establishing a research security framework for research and development projects across the Department.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HAB311312D1B247968487B156706058E2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Congressional briefing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall provide to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a briefing addressing the development of policies and processes to safeguard Department of Homeland Security research and development in accordance with paragraph (15) of section 302 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/182">6 U.S.C. 182</external-xref>), as added by subsection (a).</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

