<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-RIL25363-X1D-DT-FV0"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 232 ATS: Designating May 2025 as “National Brain Tumor Awareness Month”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 232</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250515">May 15, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S375">Mr. Daines</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Designating May 2025 as <quote>National Brain Tumor Awareness Month</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas it is estimated that more than 93,000 individuals in the United States will be diagnosed with a primary brain tumor each year;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas it is estimated that more than 1,000,000 individuals are living with a brain tumor in the United States; </text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas, in the United States, brain tumors are— </text><paragraph id="idcce8ea40b30b4698a36ac2d084bb70f2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the leading cause of death from cancer in children who are under 14 years of age and teens who are under 19 years of age; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id77fb4c4eecfd4fd79610ef50c942090b"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"> the second-leading cause of death from cancer in young adults who are between 15 and 39 years of age; </text></paragraph></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas the average 5-year survival rate for an individual in the United States following the diagnosis of a primary malignant brain tumor is only 35.7 percent; </text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas it is estimated that 18,330 individuals in the United States will die as a result of a malignant brain tumor in 2025; </text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas brain tumors may be malignant or benign but can be life-threatening in either case; </text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas treatment of brain tumors is complicated by the fact that more than 100 types of brain tumors exist; </text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas the treatment and removal of brain tumors present significant challenges due to the uniquely complex and fragile nature of the brain; </text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas brain tumors affect the primary organ in the human body that controls not only cognitive ability, but the actions of every other organ and limb in the body, leading to brain tumors being described as a disease that affects the whole individual; </text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas brain tumor research is supported by several private, nonprofit research foundations and by Federal medical research institutions; </text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas basic research may fuel advancements and the development of new treatments for brain tumors; </text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas obstacles to the development of new treatments for brain tumors remain, and there are limited strategies for the screening or early detection of brain tumors; </text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas, despite the high number of individuals diagnosed with a brain tumor every year and the devastating prognosis for those individuals, only a few treatments have been approved for malignant brain tumors since the 1980s;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas none of the treatments for malignant brain tumors extend survival by more than 2 years on average or are considered to be curative; </text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas the mortality rates associated with brain tumors have changed little during the 30 years preceding the date of introduction of this resolution; </text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas there is a need for greater public awareness of brain tumors, including the difficulties associated with research on brain tumors and the opportunities for advances in brain tumor research and treatment; and </text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas May 2025, during which brain tumor advocates nationwide unite in awareness, outreach, and advocacy activities, is an appropriate month to recognize as <quote>National Brain Tumor Awareness Month</quote>: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id889692127fa246fbb37f786c263db6cf"><enum>(1)</enum><text>designates May 2025 as <quote>National Brain Tumor Awareness Month</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id51060a7eea064d9187bc67efc111b89c"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">encourages increased public awareness of brain tumors to honor the individuals who have lost their lives to a brain tumor or currently live with a brain tumor diagnosis; </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id53b4f23cf20f447aae540ab198508198"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supports efforts to develop better treatments for brain tumors that will improve the quality of life and the long-term prognosis of individuals diagnosed with a brain tumor;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id49b15de507594248ae0d945909c94acd"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">expresses its support for individuals who are battling brain tumors, as well as the families, friends, and caregivers of those individuals; and </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7278510bb4c948ad9d953553ab402b61"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">urges a collaborative approach to brain tumor research, which is a promising means of advancing understanding of, and treatment for, brain tumors.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

