<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5CC5F12BA8F548CDBA355F0B8B7D9192" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4788 IH: To require the District of Columbia to permit Members of Congress who have a valid license or permit which is issued pursuant to the law of a State which permits the Member to carry a concealed firearm, or who is otherwise entitled to carry a concealed firearm in the State in which the Member resides, to carry a concealed firearm in the District of Columbia, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4788</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250729">July 29, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001116">Mr. Clyde</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="H001052">Mr. Harris of Maryland</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001132">Mr. Crane</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001224">Mr. Self</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000175">Mr. Ogles</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000369">Mr. Amodei of Nevada</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001077">Mr. Higgins of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001316">Mr. Burlison</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001086">Mrs. Harshbarger</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000605">Mr. Perry</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the District of Columbia to permit Members of Congress who have a valid license or permit which is issued pursuant to the law of a State which permits the Member to carry a concealed firearm, or who is otherwise entitled to carry a concealed firearm in the State in which the Member resides, to carry a concealed firearm in the District of Columbia, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HAD9E9C155131477E8FF8E2D37203A76D" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H547CAC4BBB364F889F39E9929F7F6301" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Requiring District of Columbia to permit Members of Congress with valid concealed carry licenses from other jurisdictions to carry concealed firearms in District of Columbia</header> 
<subsection id="HFE48C6E1800147BF99BE7C99135BA4CD">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Requirement</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 5 of the Act of July 8, 1932 (sec. 22–4505, D.C. Official Code) is amended—</text>
        <paragraph id="H9945EC28A8EB414AAB62643B65408B71">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>by redesignating subsection (c) as subsection (d); and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HE06EBE94644742338558168E069F7735"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>by inserting after subsection (b) the following new subsection:</text>
          <quoted-block style="traditional" id="H17036F332D00486FAF12DAA71FD916C0"
            display-inline="no-display-inline">
            <subsection id="H59CB732D5610455DBD4B3B2FB98A748F">
              <enum>(c)</enum>
              <paragraph id="HF2B2BD5221F140FABD8441FB2DC7535C" display-inline="yes-display-inline">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>The provisions of section 4(a) with respect to pistols shall not apply to a Member of Congress who—</text>
                <subparagraph id="HCDF072988C9B4825B3E654FAF78A633F" indent="up1">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is not prohibited by Federal law from possessing, transporting, shipping, or receiving a firearm (as defined in section 921(a)(3) of title 18, United States Code);</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H147847119DF14F218D0FD7C6A0A9BB36" indent="up1">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is carrying a valid license or permit which is issued pursuant to the law of a State and which permits the individual to carry a concealed firearm (as so defined), or is otherwise entitled to carry a concealed firearm in the State in which the person resides; and</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H7E8957A879CC4246AB83C68BFCBE37AB" indent="up1">
                  <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>is carrying a valid identification document containing a photograph of the individual.</text>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H31D78E042106491BA80CC34B66DD31F5" indent="up1">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>In this subsection, the term <term>Member of Congress</term> means a Senator or Representative in, or Delegate or Resident Commissioner to, the Congress.</text>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
          </quoted-block>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H3E5091781BF04AE7BC88C8DE88F205E5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This Act and the amendments made by this Act shall take effect upon the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

