<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H288124F66F22491C8676B6EBE4580EA8" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 266 IH: Expressing support for the designation of March 27, 2025, as “Tuskegee Airmen Commemoration Day”, and calling on each State, the District of Columbia, and each territory to recognize the Tuskegee Airmen for their heroism, valor, and exemplary service to the Nation.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 266</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250327">March 27, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of March 27, 2025, as <quote>Tuskegee Airmen Commemoration Day</quote>, and calling on each State, the District of Columbia, and each territory to recognize the Tuskegee Airmen for their heroism, valor, and exemplary service to the Nation.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Tuskegee Airmen were Black pilots, aircrew, ground crew, and support personnel who served in the Army Air Corps from 1941 to 1949;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas 992 Tuskegee Airmen graduated flight training at the Tuskegee Army Air Field in Tuskegee, Alabama, and 450 pilots deployed into combat overseas;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Tuskegee Airmen faced enormous adversity, from overcrowded classrooms to bigoted officers and segregated facilities;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, during World War II, the Tuskegee Airmen flew over 15,000 combat sorties and saw extensive action in the European and North African theaters;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas 84 Tuskegee Airmen were killed in action, 12 died during training and noncombat missions, and 32 were taken prisoners of war after their planes were shot down;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Tuskegee Airmen earned 744 Air Medals, 14 Bronze Stars, and 8 Purple Hearts;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, in 1945, Tuskegee Airmen in the 477th Bombardment Group staged a nonviolent demonstration to desegregate the officers’ club at Freeman Field, Indiana, and their nonviolent direct action would inspire later civil rights protesters;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Tuskegee Airmen’s battle against fascism abroad and racism at home has been called a <quote>Double Victory</quote> and led President Truman to issue Executive Order 9981, integrating the Armed Forces;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas four Tuskegee Airmen, Benjamin O. Davis, Jr., Daniel <quote>Chappie</quote> James, Lucius Theus, and Charles McGee, later became generals in the Air Force;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, in 2006, a bill to award the Congressional Gold Medal to the Tuskegee Airmen <quote>in recognition of their unique military record, which inspired revolutionary reform in the Armed Forces</quote> was signed into law (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/109/213">Public Law 109–213</external-xref>);</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, in 2008, the Tuskegee Airmen National Historic Site opened at Moton Field in Tuskegee, Alabama, to commemorate and interpret the heroic actions of the Tuskegee Airmen; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas very few Tuskegee Airmen are still alive today to share their story of courage and bravery with younger Americans: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H113D39BFD7534019B94EEDC640FC5B62"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H78FC5CFC528E4B31AF296D0782EF8C45"><text>That the House of Representatives supports the designation of <quote>Tuskegee Airmen Commemoration Day</quote>.</text></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

