<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-BUR25124-DNY-RK-H99"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S676 IS: Stop Funding Religiously Oppressive Regimes Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 676</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250220">February 20, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S348">Mr. Paul</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To prohibit assistance to foreign governments that violate human rights with respect to religious freedom.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="id4AF38F4F7F9041F39723F5EF04BAEE1F"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop Funding Religiously Oppressive Regimes Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section section-type="subsequent-section" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id18ba54c918af43b0ba0a414879613462"><enum>2.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Identification of countries with laws imposing severe criminal penalties for apostasy, blasphemy, or interfaith</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall submit a report to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate</committee-name> and the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives</committee-name> that lists each foreign government that the President determines, based on credible information, imposes a death sentence or life imprisonment on the basis of—</text><paragraph id="id5fd86bcc9a044271aa9f949a33824caf"><enum>(1)</enum><text>anti-apostasy laws that explicitly prohibit disaffiliation from a particular religion;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id68c29917e99a431c93b99686cb0e859a"><enum>(2)</enum><text>anti-blasphemy laws; or</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2cd7940107c94f1695988d37f39c7f47"><enum>(3)</enum><text>laws prohibiting marriage between individuals of different religious faiths. </text></paragraph></section><section id="idE38F1AFEA16D4197AF8A50F914307E37"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibition on assistance to foreign governments that violate human rights with respect to religion</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The United States Government is prohibited from obligating or expending any Federal funds to provide assistance to the government of any country identified in the report submitted by the President pursuant to section 2.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

