<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE851BC66B9744ED9AD65F54E9677315A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2056 IH: District of Columbia Federal Immigration Compliance Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2056</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250311">March 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001077">Mr. Higgins of Louisiana</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the District of Columbia to comply with federal immigration laws.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H71160AC04F4C43489EBE607FE1CAAA4F" style="OLC"><section id="HE6678A97D98D4187B6527B894FA691A6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>District of Columbia Federal Immigration Compliance Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H216409005C4C47F8A66139F48FD7D311" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on District of Columbia serving as sanctuary jurisdiction</header><subsection id="HE471AD4878174A81B6CF2BDFD2C3C88B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided under subsection (b), the District of Columbia may not have in effect a statute, ordinance, policy, or practice that prohibits or restricts any entity or official of the District government from—</text><paragraph id="HA1A6C66CA319465A96686D7F6FEE8401"><enum>(1)</enum><text>sending, receiving, maintaining, or exchanging with any Federal, State, or local government entity information regarding the citizenship or immigration status (lawful or unlawful) of any individual; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H16066F803CBD41329C6599728DA1D78C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>complying with a request lawfully made by the Department of Homeland Security under section 236 or 287 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (8 U.S.C. 1226 and 1357) to comply with a detainer for, or notify about the release of, an individual.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0C6A105E5D104F89B53BB58273092231"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The District of Columbia is not in violation of subsection (a) solely because it has a policy whereby its officials will not share information regarding an individual who comes forward as a victim or a witness to a criminal offense, or comply with a request made by the Department of Homeland Security under section 236 or 287 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (8 U.S.C. 1226 and 1357) to comply with a detainer regarding an individual who comes forward as a victim or a witness to a criminal offense.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

