<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-GAI25351-JVF-1D-SXX"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1427 IS: Audit the IRS Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1427</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250410">April 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S376">Ms. Ernst</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S404">Mr. Scott of Florida</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To provide that persons having seriously delinquent tax debts shall be ineligible for employment by the Internal Revenue Service.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="HD700FAE7B9734AB0AEAD19BB125057F4"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Audit the IRS Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd150e82ba8b44875b1713feadccafc57" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Ineligibility of persons having seriously delinquent tax debts for employment by Internal Revenue Service</header><subsection id="H522346C1248242FF946302F3113DA9E6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section—</text><paragraph id="H130CB2F375DF4A3180A660E79D728790"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>seriously delinquent tax debt</term> means an outstanding debt under the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 for which a notice of lien has been filed in public records pursuant to section 6323 of such Code, except that such term does not include—</text><subparagraph id="HEDA261A240834A1A842308FF119C7C26"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a debt that is being paid in a timely manner pursuant to an agreement under section 6159 or section 7122 of such Code; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H09DE7B950A43415483FBA75547507AE8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a debt with respect to which a collection due process hearing under section 6330 of such Code, or relief under subsection (a), (b), or (f) of section 6015 of such Code, is requested or pending; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H75A8F7A57A45459C866DB1EB7F9D9E3D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>applicable employee</term> means an officer, employee, or contract employee of the Internal Revenue Service.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H98DED5F2CCE0495397AAA4B86E2D6DC4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Ineligibility for employment by IRS</header><text>An individual who has a seriously delinquent tax debt shall be ineligible to be appointed, or to continue serving, as an applicable employee.</text></subsection><subsection id="H966DC5C6AB6649A183E501BC6EF687F7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Verification</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc6cd4ed0e24f422688776bcc035c16c2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Commissioner of Internal Revenue shall verify that each applicable employee is not in violation of the requirement described in subsection (b).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0767f4ad3281496aaf34843b4ccf11b8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applicants</header><text>In the case of any individual who is applying for a position with the Internal Revenue Service as an applicable employee, the Commissioner of Internal Revenue shall verify that such individual is not in violation of the requirement described in subsection (b) prior to such individual being appointed as an applicable employee.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida7c81ef8a5854a139e87a6704d614a29"><enum>(d)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Regulations</header><text>The Office of Personnel Management shall, for purposes of carrying out this section with respect to the Internal Revenue Service, prescribe any regulations which the Office considers necessary.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

