<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ROS25F40-CS0-D3-5X9">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2722 IS: Taiwan Energy Security and Anti-Embargo Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>II</distribution-code>
        <congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session>1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. 2722</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action>
            <action-date date="20250904">September 4, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S423">Mr. Ricketts</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was
                read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on
                    Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title>To promote the energy security of Taiwan, and for other
            purposes.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body>
        <section id="S1" section-type="section-one">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Taiwan Energy Security and Anti-Embargo Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section id="idceb9014c8df444e3b5462daf85067795">
            <enum>2.</enum>
            <header>Findings</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text> <paragraph id="id9d349ddbcb8f4940bce8e34b2ad513d7"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>Taiwan is a vital democratic partner the energy security of which is critical to the strategic interests of the United States in the Indo-Pacific region.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="id34fa729e13ca43b0be940dc24d6024bd">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>Enhancing Taiwan’s energy resilience through diversified and reliable sources reduces vulnerability to coercion, disruption, or attack by authoritarian regimes.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="id2b5ce82fd5e941eb8b572f6430a7175b">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>The United States possesses abundant supplies of liquefied natural gas and other energy resources that support economic growth, job creation, and the national security interests of the United States.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="id44881be9499d4f03bcc4ed55b307df90">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>Promoting United States energy exports to and partnerships with Taiwan aligns with United States energy diplomacy objectives, strengthens bilateral economic and security ties, and contributes to regional stability.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="id9c26e3fe3d8448d09ef0158b34392813">
                <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text>The Alaska Liquefied Natural Gas Project, which has received pledged support from Taiwan’s state energy firm CPC Corp, would enhance the ability of the United States to supply Taiwan and other allies and partners of the United States in the Indo-Pacific with a cost-effective, reliable supply of energy.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="id723b2e8b26334eeda601be30522588ab">
                <enum>(6)</enum>
 <text>Taiwan’s energy infrastructure, including electric grid systems and liquefied natural gas import facilities, is vulnerable to asymmetric and kinetic threats from the People’s Republic of China.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="id4343f3548b574520bb16d2c0ac48fa49">
                <enum>(7)</enum>
 <text>Supporting Taiwan’s efforts to improve the resilience and security of its energy infrastructure advances deterrence and promotes continuity of government operations in the event of a crisis.</text>
            </paragraph>
        </section>
        <section id="id925816d12a4245158fe4ef9ad936f4cd">
            <enum>3.</enum>
            <header>Promotion of liquefied natural gas exports and energy infrastructure resilience
                for Taiwan</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Taiwan Enhanced Resilience Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/3351">22 U.S.C. 3351 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
            <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfc2de4a3a4ad459a9d03973fe9fbe989">
                <part id="idb0e8e26fb3d24ff08b2be52fd9d27b20" style="OLC">
                    <enum>8<?LEXA-Enum 8?></enum>
                    <header>Promotion of liquefied natural gas exports and energy infrastructure
                        resilience for Taiwan</header>
                    <section id="id2f27661b6ab24d6c989dc8dd8b1fc04f">
                        <enum>5540A.</enum>
                        <header>Definitions</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this part:</text> <paragraph id="id8818d3322a1a471eb2366bcfee356a6f"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>Appropriate congressional committees</header> <text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text>
                            <subparagraph id="idfd5f996a1e25431887bd8b2d9f988ec4">
                                <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation, and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate; and</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <subparagraph id="id507ee34621a74597b0d7239d0c609558">
                                <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives.</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                        </paragraph>
                        <paragraph id="idf96cfabcee79469190618875f8c3a61d" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline">
                            <enum>(2)</enum>
                            <header>Asymmetric threat</header>
 <text>The term <term>asymmetric threat</term> means a threat posed by unconventional means, including a cyberattack, sabotage, or economic coercion, designed to undermine or disrupt the operation of critical infrastructure.</text>
                        </paragraph>
                    </section>
                    <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="id62810d893c5042f887c2194f4cccca29">
                        <enum>5540B.</enum>
                        <header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Promotion of liquefied natural
                            gas exports to Taiwan</header>
                        <subsection id="id607cf483efe24e179bf46b49fe379a65">
                            <enum>(a)</enum>
                            <header>In general</header>
 <text>The Secretary of State, in coordination with the Secretary of Commerce and the Secretary of Energy, shall prioritize efforts to support and facilitate increased exportation to Taiwan of liquefied natural gas produced in the United States.</text>
                        </subsection>
                        <subsection id="id342832a018f74530b2dce3b84ff0065d">
                            <enum>(b)</enum>
                            <header>Required activities</header>
 <text>In carrying out subsection (a), the Secretaries shall—</text> <paragraph id="ida78f9cfb0c3c40cb87af2194e8b06eb0"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>engage with United States liquefied natural gas producers, exporters, and infrastructure entities to identify and address barriers to liquefied natural gas exports and storage projects intended for the market of Taiwan;</text>
                            </paragraph>
                            <paragraph id="idf81aac98b88e4627bbe4a8062d17bc6f">
                                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>facilitate coordination between United States private sector entities and relevant government and private sector stakeholders in Taiwan;</text>
                            </paragraph>
                            <paragraph id="id8360a3d846e943aa86a2cdc699acbcf5">
                                <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>provide diplomatic and technical support to streamline regulatory processes and expedite permitting for liquefied natural gas export and storage infrastructure projects linked to Taiwan;</text>
                            </paragraph>
                            <paragraph id="id9811521e0f7e4ceca431fdeb7185e862">
                                <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>consult with the Government of Taiwan to assess and strengthen liquefied natural gas import and storage capabilities; and</text>
                            </paragraph>
                            <paragraph id="id293e5c06eb3b465c8e54af50e31740e3">
                                <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text>coordinate interagency efforts to ensure cohesive and sustained United States support for liquefied natural gas exports to Taiwan.</text>
                            </paragraph>
                        </subsection>
                    </section>
                    <section id="idab78555b5bd247ba8bfcc68f2e5b9462">
                        <enum>5540C.</enum>
                        <header>Energy infrastructure resilience capacity building</header>
                        <subsection id="idad2bfd6b7d3a47d08779d2597fac488a">
                            <enum>(a)</enum>
                            <header>Requirement</header>
 <text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Taiwan Energy Security and Anti-Embargo Act of 2025</short-title>, the Secretary of State, in coordination with the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Energy, shall seek to engage with appropriate officials of Taiwan for the purpose of cooperating with the Ministry of Foreign Affairs, the Ministry of the Interior, the Ministry of Defense, and the head of any other applicable ministry of Taiwan for capacity building to enhance energy infrastructure resilience, including defensive military cybersecurity activities.</text>
                        </subsection>
                        <subsection id="ide716c3aa45bb47d29181bb7a00d9ec17">
                            <enum>(b)</enum>
                            <header>Identification of activities</header>
 <text>In carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary of State may identify cooperative activities—</text>
                            <paragraph id="iddccef8a83c9c48aea40419334d11e10e">
                                <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>to enhance cybersecurity programs to protect grid operating systems, liquefied natural gas terminals, and supervisory control and data acquisition systems;</text>
                            </paragraph>
                            <paragraph id="ide2ced0e1abe84dcc8b9430d199a6657d">
                                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>to support physical security improvements, operational redundancy, and continuity-of-operations planning;</text>
                            </paragraph>
                            <paragraph id="idb584521303184f71a4dbd280222cce74">
                                <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>to engage in joint training exercises and scenario-based planning with relevant agencies in Taiwan; and</text>
                            </paragraph>
                            <paragraph id="id5702d0c6f1ac4cb3b314d1f7ef84febc">
                                <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>to support workforce development, emergency response planning, and institutional modernization of energy sector operators.</text>
                            </paragraph>
                        </subsection>
                        <subsection id="id7376173879ff49239ae1f624cf0b5cf8">
                            <enum>(c)</enum>
                            <header>United States-Taiwan energy security center</header>
 <text>The Secretary of State may establish a joint United States-Taiwan Energy Security Center in the United States, leveraging the expertise of institutions of higher education and private sector entities to foster dialogue and collaboration for academic cooperation in energy security and resilience.</text>
                        </subsection>
                        <subsection id="ideb98eb6275be464e962898d5533ee25e">
                            <enum>(d)</enum>
                            <header>Authorization of assistance</header>
 <text>The Secretary of State, in coordination with the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Energy, may provide technical assistance to support the activities described in subsection (b) or the center described in subsection (c).</text>
                        </subsection>
                        <subsection id="id3bffb8dcb04e47ac983f2097c150be03">
                            <enum>(e)</enum>
                            <header>Implementation</header>
                            <paragraph id="id312836f740fa4ce5a5b09c2e42f17580">
                                <enum>(1)</enum>
                                <header>In general</header>
 <text>Assistance under this section shall be provided through the American Institute in Taiwan and in consultation with relevant authorities in Taiwan, consistent with the Taiwan Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/3301">22 U.S.C. 3301 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
                            </paragraph>
                            <paragraph id="ida683e846e11d4a55b60801dfdcd81573">
                                <enum>(2)</enum>
                                <header>Notification</header>
 <text>Any assistance provided by the Department of State pursuant this section shall be subject to the regular notification requirements of section 634A of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2394-1">22 U.S.C. 2394–1</external-xref>).</text>
                            </paragraph>
                        </subsection>
                        <subsection id="id026c862c925f45c2a99787f890601cdf">
                            <enum>(f)</enum>
                            <header>Briefings</header>
 <text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Taiwan Energy Security and Anti-Embargo Act of 2025</short-title>, the Secretary of State, in coordination with the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Energy, shall provide to the appropriate congressional committees a briefing on the implementation of this section.</text>
                        </subsection>
                    </section>
                    <section id="idc98074707f7349d09ccc928f97d54bcb">
                        <enum>5540D.</enum>
                        <header>Annual report</header>
                        <subsection id="id18b71832dbab4a6386b932fbfa6b43d2">
                            <enum>(a)</enum>
                            <header>In general</header>
 <text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Taiwan Energy Security and Anti-Embargo Act of 2025</short-title>, and annually thereafter for 3 years, the Secretary of State, in coordination with the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of Energy, and the Secretary of Defense, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that—</text>
                            <paragraph id="id8b82ebed383a4a5fa0b4ceeb9d428e8f">
                                <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>describes actions taken under this part;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="idba1b36586ed146bf90273be3aac2e184"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>identifies barriers to—</text>
                                <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd8b7394b619744118fa8e3ce1dbbd68a">
                                    <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">increased exportation of liquefied natural gas to Taiwan; and</text>
                                </subparagraph>
                                <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id381ecd33da844dd2a0a79052c521c331">
                                    <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">energy infrastructure security cooperation;</text>
                                </subparagraph>
                            </paragraph>
                            <paragraph id="idece8a0076b624a3aa08a1694f2e25fc9">
                                <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>evaluates the effectiveness of capacity building and technical assistance activities carried out under section 5540C; and</text>
                            </paragraph>
                            <paragraph id="idab054d4a2d594d11a9294a71a9faa461">
                                <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>provides recommendations to expand and improve future bilateral energy cooperation between the United States and Taiwan.</text>
                            </paragraph>
                        </subsection>
                        <subsection id="idc317c4137373474187431dd2a0400a91">
                            <enum>(b)</enum>
                            <header>Form</header>
 <text>Each report required by subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form but may include a classified annex.</text>
                        </subsection>
                    </section>
                </part>
                <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
            </quoted-block>
        </section>
        <section id="idddbde608e4a04474b6ce7546f68a5040">
            <enum>4.</enum>
            <header>Training to improve Taiwan's critical energy infrastructure protection</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 5504(a)(3) of the Taiwan Enhanced Resilience Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/3353">22 U.S.C. 3353(a)(3)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after <quote>capabilities</quote> the following: <quote>and critical energy infrastructure protection</quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section id="id95ca4d5f7b004e1986e110b6514f0f00">
            <enum>5.</enum>
            <header>Findings and sense of Congress regarding Taiwan’s use of nuclear energy</header>
            <subsection id="id06ebdd3462a140cb8ac01d15e7d57a30">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>Findings</header>
 <text>Congress makes the following findings:</text> <paragraph id="idef56ca95cc364fa09c9ab71c11f2bf59"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>According to the International Atomic Energy Agency, nuclear energy—</text>
                    <subparagraph id="id1a8089f863f342a786c367ed4ed6223b">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>is the second safest source of energy;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id67b49585d85f46c2ba7456424f8f14da"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>is one of only 2 clean energies that offer non-stop baseload power required for sustainable economic growth and improved human welfare; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id9bdd2c654d774f3c875548381cfc63fb">
                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>when compared with other sources of electricity from cradle to grave, has the lowest carbon footprint, uses fewer materials, and takes up less land.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="idf0ba71220ae34dd0b4ba89b02b20f42e">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>A nuclear fuel assembly lasts up to 6 years, making supply more resistant to maritime disruption.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id48ec2957bb2b45038127a0fd7dffccb4">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>Taiwan has built a robust civilian nuclear capability over previous decades that has shown the potential to provide clean, reliable power to Taiwan.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id16aff480f67c458aa168741ea894b8ad">
                    <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>On May 17, 2025, the Maanshan-2, Taiwan’s last operating nuclear power plant, was shut down after its 40-year operating license expired.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id4b422f03d95a495aa06716355ae5be38">
                    <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text>There are compelling economic and security reasons to evaluate placing existing infrastructure back in service to ensure Taiwan has clean, reliable power that is more resilient in a contingency.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="ideee6978631f4498db6fe41b118449a37">
                    <enum>(6)</enum>
 <text>As a result of Taiwan’s substantial use of energy in industrial manufacturing and production, and emerging energy requirements for electrification, artificial intelligence, and data center support, there is considerable benefit for Taiwan to evaluate new small modular reactors technology to augment its energy capacity and resilience.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id37a56f6746f045cfbc051e2f7aeeb304">
                    <enum>(7)</enum>
 <text>As Taiwan modernizes its military, the power demand from command-and-control systems, intelligence platforms, drone operations, and joint battlespace integration will continue to increase.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id899192e11ceb440ba705fafc83607fcd">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Sense of Congress</header>
 <text>It is the sense of Congress that—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5c1bd760de8a497681d2cdebb4f30934"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">it is in the interests of both the United States and Taiwan for the Government of Taiwan to consider—</text>
                    <subparagraph id="id41abff4a2aef461383243a4d1150801b">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>maintaining nuclear power as an energy source; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idcaa68d8d52774dd084756e5bbf091ae1"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>utilizing new nuclear technologies, including Gen III+ nuclear reactors and small modular reactor technology; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="idfdf13e8990994d4da2bd359b67963af6">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>the United States should prioritize assistance and cooperation with Taiwan on nuclear energy to improve technology exports and job creation in the United States and energy security and resilience in Taiwan.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
        </section>
        <section id="id6cd22ad9a06548ca894cf98ae324d8f1">
            <enum>6.</enum>
            <header>Insurance for vessels transporting vital goods to strategic partners</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 53902 of title 46, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
            <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id89a79d410c984c79b532c4a45c653225">
                <subsection id="id745505f751d6452e85297805f4401afb">
                    <enum>(d)</enum>
                    <header>Vessels transporting vital goods to strategic partners</header>
                    <paragraph id="idb5346af71caa44e386e75c81810c091b">
                        <enum>(1)</enum>
                        <header>In general</header>
 <text>The Secretary of Transportation may provide insurance and reinsurance under this chapter for any vessel engaged in commerce transporting critical energy, humanitarian, or other goods to Taiwan or another strategic partner of the United States that is facing coercive maritime threats if the Secretary determines, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of State, and the Director of National Intelligence, that providing such insurance or reinsurance is necessary to support vital strategic commerce or to deter coercive maritime behavior that undermines regional security.</text>
                    </paragraph>
                    <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcc9fa86b0f404c5983983fc6af8060ee">
                        <enum>(2)</enum>
                        <header>Nonapplicability of certain condition</header>
 <text>The condition under section 53902(c) shall not apply with respect to a vessel described in paragraph (1).</text>
                    </paragraph>
                </subsection>
                <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
            </quoted-block>
        </section>
    </legis-body>
</bill>

