<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-REI25168-CMG-KS-HS5">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2393 IS: Fiscal Year 2025 Veterans Affairs Major Medical Facility Authorization Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>II</distribution-code>
        <congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session>1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. 2393</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action>
            <action-date date="20250723">July 23, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S347">Mr. Moran</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which
                was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSVA00">Committee
                    on Veterans’ Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title>To authorize a major medical facility project for the Department of Veterans
            Affairs for fiscal year 2026 in St. Louis, Missouri, and for other
            purposes.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HBF830BD55B81442CBB71FE983BDB4907">
        <section section-type="section-one" id="H7EC95DB95E824A81A6F892632DCC39FB">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Fiscal Year 2025 Veterans Affairs Major Medical Facility Authorization Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section id="H139328ACEB714F23BAB05C98D54B40D6">
            <enum>2.</enum>
            <header>Authorization of major medical facility project of Department of Veterans
                Affairs for fiscal year 2026 in St. Louis, Missouri</header>
            <subsection id="HBCC2785707744D38989E3589FDE0497D">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
 <text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs may carry out a major medical facility project in fiscal year 2026 in St. Louis, Missouri, that consists of the construction of a new bed tower, clinical building expansion, consolidated administrative building and warehouse, utility plant, and parking garages, in an amount not to exceed $1,762,668,000.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H743DF4D081EA48BE9C8A55925EFC93F8">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
 <text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs for fiscal year 2026 or the year in which funds are appropriated for the Construction, Major Projects account, $1,762,668,000 for the project authorized in subsection (a).</text>
            </subsection>
        </section>
    </legis-body>
</bill>

