<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCFB6C2A628CB47C18D7CE0E2A94DC8B2" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1876 IH: Keeping Our Field Offices Open Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1876</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250305">March 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000557">Mr. Larson of Connecticut</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="N000015">Mr. Neal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001066">Mr. Horsford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000490">Mr. Bishop</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000530">Mr. Deluzio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000305">Ms. Jacobs</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000309">Mr. Jackson of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001315">Ms. Budzinski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001156">Ms. Sánchez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001296">Mr. Boyle of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001190">Mr. Schneider</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="I000058">Mr. Ivey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001127">Mrs. Cherfilus-McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001229">Mrs. McIver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001081">Mrs. Hayes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000216">Ms. DeLauro</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000301">Ms. Elfreth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001201">Mr. Suozzi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001211">Mr. Stanton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000148">Mr. Auchincloss</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001225">Mr. Sorensen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000601">Mr. Landsman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000380">Mr. Amo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="U000040">Ms. Underwood</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000622">Mr. Riley of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000610">Ms. Plaskett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000621">Ms. Randall</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001313">Ms. Brown</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000620">Ms. Pettersen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000687">Mr. Mfume</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001206">Mr. Morelle</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001220">Mr. McGarvey</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prevent closure of social security field and hearing offices and resident stations.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD223589EEB8842DAA41730B8CB449252" style="OLC"><section id="H774C079DC6CE4F6FA5ABAF27F0C986C9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Keeping Our Field Offices Open Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H4761359558E94DB9AC099392CF2050D2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Preventing closure of field and hearing offices and resident stations</header><subsection id="H12FA95D82DD241DB9D99208E5589930D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Moratorium on closure or consolidation of field or hearing offices or new limitations on access to such offices</header><paragraph id="HD3B208E2A40847B79B6EFE23A729C424"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3), the Commissioner of Social Security shall take no action on or after the date of enactment of this Act to close or consolidate field or hearing offices or resident stations of the Social Security Administration or to otherwise impose any new limitation on access to such offices or stations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2EDFA3AC70744E0D997A990C1F83059E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception for emergency closures</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (1) shall not apply with respect to any temporary action by the Commissioner to close or otherwise limit access to field or hearing offices or resident stations in response to an emergency.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7B9A267514654C018205098D3E11A8FA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Cessation of moratorium upon report to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (1) shall cease to be effective on the date that is 180 days after the report described in paragraph (4) is submitted.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0E72853AC94E4242864032B311AADDFF"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Report required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not earlier than January 21, 2029, the Commissioner shall submit to the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate a report outlining and justifying the process for selecting field or hearing offices or resident stations to be closed or consolidated or otherwise to have limited access. Such report shall include—</text><subparagraph id="HA550630E510F4AE4A6A41C279160B9DB"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an analysis of the criteria used for selecting field or hearing offices and resident stations for closure, consolidation, or limited access;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBF73B1DBE33044E5B9B4E92B346C806C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of how the Commissioner has analyzed and considered relevant factors, including transportation and communication burdens faced by individuals serviced by the offices and stations, including elderly and disabled individuals; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4BA68B512A71461A930CDDB01DBCAE67"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a description of any method of cost-benefit analysis applied by the Commissioner in connection with closures and consolidations of such offices and stations, and other limitations on access the offices and stations, including any analysis that takes into account—</text><clause id="HD702ED21433940699E7641F4D3C56D05"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the anticipated savings resulting from the closure, consolidation, or limitation on access;</text></clause><clause id="HAE93F28CFDAE43458D44AE364AF753A8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the anticipated costs associated with replacing services lost by the closure, consolidation, or limitation on access;</text></clause><clause id="H5BED1F59485F4C939F8EDA64D17E55F9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the anticipated effects on employees of the offices or stations affected; </text></clause><clause id="H8A542141BB614DF08C5454FB63E99AC1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>how the loss of access resulting from the closure, consolidation, or limitation on access will be replaced by the establishment of a new field or hearing office or resident station, increased access at a different office or station, or some other means, and the factors considered by the Commissioner in determining how to replace such lost access; and</text></clause><clause id="HB93CADDDC53841B5B098A4BCDA716FAC"><enum>(v)</enum><text>such other relevant factors as may be determined by the Commissioner, including but not limited to transportation and communication burdens faced by individuals serviced by the offices and stations, including elderly and disabled individuals. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA148098DC2B543FCBA63394DB9F63062"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements for future closures, consolidations, and new limitations on access</header><paragraph id="H27A8DDEE82B648AB9B767B616E2134FA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 704 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/904">42 U.S.C. 904</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2A9077D89E1643C0AF30272FB1F25611" other-style="archaic" style="other"><subsection id="HB04534E1892346EA9446A88CFF6ACB6B"><enum>(f)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H5CFF82EDD5C0438AA5715912696D864A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Field and hearing offices and resident stations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to paragraph (6), the Commissioner may not close a field or hearing office or a resident station of the Administration, consolidate two or more such offices or stations, or otherwise impose any new limitation on public access to any such office or station, unless the Commissioner complies with the requirements of paragraphs (2), (3), (4), and (5) in connection with the closure, consolidation, or limitation on public access.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HED765688B15B41A38F3376AF975C36CF" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HC9A35A4DCF6A486EA461C67EE14F39A2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The requirements of this paragraph are met in connection with a closure, consolidation, or new limitation on access referred to in paragraph (1) only if—</text><clause id="H5086393795CC4AF5B67A16505B7AC2FE" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>not later than 120 days before the date of the closure, consolidation, or limitation on access, the Commissioner provides effective public notice of the proposed closure, consolidation, or limitation on access (including, to the extent practicable, notice by direct mailing and through community outlets such as newspapers and posting in heavily frequented public spaces) to individuals residing in the area serviced by the affected offices or stations;</text></clause><clause id="H50ECAC6FC9FB4C369274C036D94ACA3B" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the public notice issued pursuant to clause (i) includes information on—</text><subclause id="H82D47CB3319741D9A667A3D2DCD3A318"><enum>(I)</enum><text>how the Commissioner will, not later than 30 days after the date of the closure, consolidation, or limitation on access, replace the loss in access resulting from the closure, consolidation, or limitation on access by establishing a new office or station, increasing public access to a different office or station, or some other means; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HB04A9B90D1A34EF3AEE6E4947B7D37DA"><enum>(II)</enum><text>how to contact the Administration if an individual experiences service delays or problems as a result of the closure, consolidation, or limitation on access; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HC3A82A9E280D46788CCB608653E667E6" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not earlier than 30 days after the issuance of public notice pursuant to clause (i) and not later than 45 days before the date of the proposed closure, consolidation, or limitation on access, the Commissioner conducts at least 2 public hearings (scheduled so that the first and last such hearings are separated by at least 10 days), at which the Commissioner presents the justifications for the closure, consolidation, or limitation on access described in subparagraph (B) and provides for attendees an opportunity to present their views regarding the proposed closure, consolidation, or limitation on access.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC16320C42FF1400BA694679F7FF856E6" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The justifications referred to in subparagraph (A)(iii) shall consist of the following:</text><clause id="HD84F1458A7044771BB0AB92F287A2632"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an analysis of the criteria used for selecting the field or hearing office or offices, or the resident station or stations, for closure, consolidation, or limited access;</text></clause><clause id="HE591363ADE2C478B827FFA63B1838DEA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a description of how the Commissioner has analyzed and considered relevant factors, including but not limited to transportation and communication burdens faced by individuals serviced by the offices or stations, including elderly and disabled individuals; and</text></clause><clause display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H38A41D72A12E4071BC38B301845003AC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of a method of cost-benefit analysis which shall be applied by the Commissioner in connection with the closure, consolidation, or limitation on access, and which shall take into account—</text><subclause id="HCF923605943B4E98AF59D7019795D8A0"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the anticipated savings resulting from the closure, consolidation, or limitation on access;</text></subclause><subclause id="HE16C1AD4A1F04B118737E6F945F07579"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the anticipated costs associated with replacing services lost by the closure, consolidation, or limitation on access;</text></subclause><subclause id="H0492ABD0E22043149581092394D9EE65"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the anticipated effects on employees of the offices or stations affected; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HDE590EA5B04E4E228603E2D9C7EE1E64"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such other relevant factors as may be determined by the Commissioner, including but not limited to transportation and communication burdens faced by individuals serviced by the offices and stations, including elderly and disabled individuals.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H53E5CA01075A430E8FD9F5D840F8C807" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The notice provided pursuant to subparagraph (A)(i) shall include notice of the time and place of the public hearings to be conducted pursuant to clause (A)(iii) and of the right of aggrieved individuals to appeal to the Commissioner regarding the proposed closure, consolidation, or limitation on access pursuant to paragraph (4).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3C778B5870304945B1306EE2059D8570" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The requirements of this paragraph are met in connection with a closure, consolidation, or limitation on access referred to in paragraph (1) only if, not later than 30 days before the date of the proposed closure, consolidation, or limitation on access, the Commissioner submits to the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Finance of the Senate, and each Member of the Congress representing a State or congressional district in which the affected office or offices, or station or stations, are located a detailed final report in support of the closure, consolidation, or limitation on access. Such report shall include—</text><subparagraph id="H6659DAD335F543B0A28314932C3DE2E1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the justifications described in paragraph (2)(B), (including any amendments made to such justifications after the public hearings conducted pursuant to paragraph (2)(A));</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB6832DDF03DE468B87453FBF41588632"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any findings made by the Commissioner pursuant to the public hearings;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H60FAA2264A0F4A43A3E3CB30FBEA89E3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the status of any appeals regarding the closure, consolidation, or new limitation on access which were commenced pursuant to paragraph (4) before the date of the report;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBCD6E52A3271442081F8B8004F1FD824"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the final decision of the Commissioner regarding the closure, consolidation, or new limitation on access; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7C33186DE0C24FCE9C224264CED8FEC4"><enum>(E)</enum><text>such other information as the Commissioner considers relevant.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0032A150EFB64C41B2A62515F33800D2" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HFF159EE3C56643779421CE90521002A7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Upon timely request by any individual who makes a showing in writing described in subparagraph (B) in connection with a proposed closure, consolidation, or limitation on access referred to in subparagraph (A), the Commissioner shall give such individual an opportunity for a hearing with respect to the closure, consolidation, or limitation on access. The request for the hearing shall be considered timely only if it is made not later than 30 days before the proposed date of the closure, consolidation, or limitation on access. The Commissioner shall submit to the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Finance of the Senate, and each Member of the Congress representing a State or congressional district in which the affected office or offices, or station or stations, are located the Commissioner’s findings based on the hearing and a description of any action taken or to be taken by the Commissioner on the basis of such findings.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0133C6B256124ECBAAF838F2CFD42E71" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A showing described in subparagraph (A) shall consist of a showing that—</text><clause id="H8FABA9BAE25F49DE8DE330885BE7EAA1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the determination of the Commissioner to close a field or hearing office or resident station, consolidate field or hearing offices or resident stations, or impose a new limitation on access to such offices or stations is arbitrary, capricious, an abuse of discretion, not in accordance with law, or not based on substantial evidence; or</text></clause><clause id="HE64C453112DB45958D16C8E250E43014"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Commissioner has failed to observe procedures required by law in connection with the closure, consolidation, or new limitation on access.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4AAEA65FEC764D69A3745F4D84F7EA13" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The requirement of this paragraph is met in connection with a closure, consolidation, or limitation on access referred to in paragraph (1) only if such closure, consolidation, or limitation on access will not result in the total number of field or hearing offices and resident stations of the Administration falling below the total number of such offices and stations that were in operation on January 20, 2025.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBDA2C54F04E549B28DAE31C1DF2564F8" indent="up1"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (1) shall not apply with respect to any temporary action by the Commissioner to close or otherwise limit access to field or hearing offices or resident stations in response to an emergency.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE927A61DFDC44824941A0B716DAB639E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by paragraph (1) of this subsection shall apply with respect to closures and consolidations of field or hearing offices and resident stations and impositions of new limitations on access to such offices and stations occurring after the cessation of the moratorium under subsection (a) of this section.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

