<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA0C06077048D469CBD6A45F1C44A3082" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 740 IH: Congratulating Seattle Sounders FC on becoming the first Major League Soccer team to win all 5 major North American soccer trophies.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 740</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250918">September 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="L000560">Mr. Larsen of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000510">Mr. Smith of Washington</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001159">Ms. Strickland</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Congratulating Seattle Sounders FC on becoming the first Major League Soccer team to win all 5 major North American soccer trophies.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, on August 31, 2025, Seattle Sounders FC won Leagues Cup 2025, becoming the first Major League Soccer team to win all 5 major North American soccer trophies;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Seattle Sounders FC won the Lamar Hunt United States Open Cup in 2009, 2010, 2011, and 2014;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Seattle Sounders FC won the Supporters’ Shield in 2014;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Seattle Sounders FC won MLS Cup in 2016 and 2019;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Seattle Sounders FC won the CONCACAF Champions Cup in 2022;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, since its inaugural season as a Major League Soccer team in 2009, Seattle Sounders FC has won 9 major North American soccer trophies;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, since the inaugural season of Major League Soccer in 1996, no Major League Soccer team had won all five major North American soccer trophies prior to Seattle Sounders FC;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Seattle Sounders FC beat Inter Miami CF 3–0 in the Leagues Cup 2025 Final on August 31, 2025;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Osaze De Rosario scored a goal in the 26th minute, Alex Roldan scored a penalty goal in the 84th minute, and Paul Rothrock scored a goal in the 89th minute of the Leagues Cup 2025 Final;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Pedro de la Vega earned the Best Player Award and Andrew Thomas earned the Best Goalkeeper Award for their performances in Leagues Cup 2025;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 69,314 fans packed Lumen Field, home of Seattle Sounders FC, to watch the Leagues Cup 2025 Final, making it the highest attended soccer match in the history of Washington State;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Seattle Sounders FC Leagues Cup 2025 team exhibited remarkable teamwork from its players who include Andrew Thomas, Jackson Ragen, Obed Vargas, Alex Roldan, Jesús Ferreira, Cristian Roldan, Yeimar Gómez Andrade, Nouhou, Paul Rothrock, Osaze De Rosario, Pedro de la Vega, Albert Rusnák, Danny Musovski, Reed Baker-Whiting, Danny Leyva, Ryan Kent, Kim Kee-hee, Kalani Kossa-Rienzi, Georgi Minoungou, and Snyder Brunell;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Seattle Sounders FC has been led during the 2025 season by Head Coach Brian Schmetzer, Assistant Coach Preki, Assistant Coach Freddy Juarez, Assistant Coach Andy Rose, Club Director of Goalkeeping Tom Dutra, and General Manager and Chief Soccer Officer Craig Waibel;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Seattle Sounders FC has been supported during the 2025 season by a robust operational and medical staff;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the 20 partner families in the ownership contingent have provided unparalleled support to the team and greatly contributed to its successes during the 2025 season;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Seattle Sounders FC has exhibited dedication to positive social impacts by strengthening communities through the RAVE Foundation partnership that furthers play equity statewide; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Seattle Sounders FC and the RAVE Foundation use soccer as a vehicle to inspire people of all ages, abilities, and backgrounds: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HCE6E4101C3FE46A698949BCC2D9A3194"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HEA23D2BBEBDF4E28B303FF7E7FE5DB3B"><enum/><text>That the House of Representatives recognizes—</text><paragraph id="H628A3799B21B435991CAA22E361A1AF4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Seattle Sounders FC for becoming the first Major League Soccer team to win all 5 major North American soccer trophies;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC3DA2E82975B42CBA0B5A10BCDB39909"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the people of the State of Washington and the city of Seattle for their enthusiastic support of Seattle Sounders FC; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF8A4D6A1C7044F7DBE865F114C3B6538"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the continuing progress toward ensuring equity in men’s and women’s professional sports.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

