<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MIR25485-895-HT-6G9"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1499 IS: New Start Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1499</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250428">April 28, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSSB00">Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To establish a program awarding competitive grants to organizations administering entrepreneurial development programming to currently incarcerated and formerly incarcerated individuals, and other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>New Start Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id072C8FB452BA4CD9ABC2C8AA94F988DF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text><paragraph id="idbd6139bf4f374ca192f2b2d5fb334f94"><enum>(1)</enum><text>according to the Department of Justice, every year, around 600,000 individuals are released from prison and return home to their communities, and almost 77 percent of those individuals will reoffend within 5 years;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idba4cd8c6adef4b158c231b551b29f185"><enum>(2)</enum><text>according to the Brookings Institution, an estimated 48.5 percent of formerly incarcerated individuals will remain unemployed or earn a negligible income for a period of 1 year post-incarceration, increasing the risk for recidivism; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb033ed3b01544c8d82b58ac100dd06a5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>according to the Florida State University Institute for Justice Research and Development, formerly incarcerated individuals see a reduction in earnings of 25 percent since criminal records make it difficult to find stable employment; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="idcd6991bae91348b1a27f5508b89d946f"><enum>(4)</enum><text>self-employment can provide economic stability for those who are otherwise locked out of the labor market; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2ebc8ebb7dc1430b83c4a43ccaa33113"><enum>(5)</enum><text>according to a paper entitled <quote>Entrepreneurship as a Response to Labor Market Discrimination for Formerly Incarcerated People</quote>—</text><subparagraph id="id57711c9f05ae4328b084be95fa4f8cc7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the average individual without a criminal record has a 7.09 percent likelihood of becoming an entrepreneur, but justice-impacted individuals were found to be more than 50 percent likely to choose entrepreneurship with a 12.49 percent likelihood of becoming an entrepreneur;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id005082a7725d4850b7ef185397bca001"><enum>(B)</enum><text>entrepreneurship reduces the likelihood of recidivism by 5.3 percent, which was a 32.5 percent decrease from average recidivism rates for regular employees who have been previously incarcerated; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3ddeb3a3abce49bbab098fb7e4160210"><enum>(C)</enum><text>formerly incarcerated individuals who choose entrepreneurship make $2,700 more annually than formerly incarcerated employees and that the income gap between formerly incarcerated entrepreneurs and entrepreneurs with no criminal record was 38 percent lower than the income gap between formerly incarcerated employees and employees with no criminal record.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="idE5912CDB0B8E4078A5B2FD0A6EE451E1"><enum>3.</enum><header>Entrepreneurship counseling and training for justice-impacted individuals</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/631">15 U.S.C. 631 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2cd627acd69e41a3b2e425ecfda7ea86"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating section 49 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/631">15 U.S.C. 631</external-xref> note) as section 50; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8562ac10d5c34cf08b3af4901fc49da5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after section 48 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/657u">15 U.S.C. 657u</external-xref>) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfb980d04b88a477cbcbbb6add74bca7e"><section id="id939bb7a83c4f4f2f9c9e32eec2e7e1e4"><enum>49.</enum><header>New Start Program</header><subsection id="id61039EB2C69D464C8270D6F0390DC66E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="id1688CF1FB294419783D7EF4471FA7B91"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of Congress</header><text>The term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="idD3D0F0D67E15404FA36BA1E039D69096"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id77D7134958D44AD2AE72DEC733D51BFA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Small Business of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id941762c1a46d40b3aff5831d58396f9d"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Community Advantage Small Business Lending Company</header><text>The term <term>Community Advantage Small Business Lending Company</term> has the meaning given the term in section 120.10 of title 13, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor regulation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1726c4e3b8a848d19457c3d329a7a83b"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Currently incarcerated individual</header><text>The term <term>currently incarcerated individual</term> means an individual who—</text><subparagraph id="id69cd1896b2a04d389dd716d618d2eb2b"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is incarcerated in a Federal prison designated as a minimum, low, or medium security prison by the Director of the Bureau of Prisons or is under the jurisdiction of the Bureau of Prisons and is housed in a Residential Reentry Center operated under a contract with the Bureau of Prisons; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide1fb9342863e46dc9f12a5b4dc127687"><enum>(B)</enum><text>meets the offense eligibility requirements set forth in any applicable policy notice or other guidance issued by the Administration for the program established under section 7(m).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id72a5f97341164fe4b9fc7f7dedd6e696"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Entrepreneurial development program</header><text>The term <term>entrepreneurial development program</term> includes programming that provides—</text><subparagraph id="idefe018f6fc084fb7a11c33f8869aa160"><enum>(A)</enum><text>assistance and in-depth training on how to start or expand a small business concern, including—</text><clause id="id89f5b7ad7adf45a583dd463a1e43a774"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a self-study course manual focused on the basic skills of entrepreneurship, financial literacy, the language of business, and the considerations and life skills relevant to self-employment and ownership of a small business concern;</text></clause><clause id="ideb9a0a2f1f004c5ea12ec40460383c51"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in-depth classroom instruction introducing the foundations of self-employment and ownership of small business concerns; or</text></clause><clause id="idbf29c798dff243478d81bac15efab943"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>one-on-one training, including individual support in the development of a business plan, entrepreneurial skills, and strategies for starting a small business concern;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb3624790292c42b7945aab63b3448293"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the tools, skills, and knowledge necessary to identify a business opportunity, including how to—</text><clause id="id055e3d44d5394e048b6a006f3c13a6ff"><enum>(i)</enum><text>draft a resume, business plan, or succession plan;</text></clause><clause id="idefaa42454a9d4b5aa5915581e464bc12"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>identify sources of capital and contracting opportunities; or</text></clause><clause id="idf4fbe2b3d74d47dabe050cedf069bd8d"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>connect with local resources for small business concerns;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf0f103e2d468458da2a6a0dee9dc442a"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a mentorship program for over a predetermined or open-ended period; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id105d93ee43c84796ab9fb7319b09f18b"><enum>(D)</enum><text>seed investment in exchange for a small amount of equity, as well as startup capital, or the opportunity to raise capital from outside investors.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id8C8BE26AA120472094532C15A573924E"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Formerly incarcerated individual</header><text>The term <term>formerly incarcerated individual</term> means an individual who—</text><subparagraph id="id26155A3868184C929B91130BB66AF108"><enum>(A)</enum><text>completed a term of imprisonment in Federal, State, or local jail or prison; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6573D83B36CE4091A6139ADB1CBAE3D6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>meets the offense eligibility requirements set forth in any applicable policy notice or other guidance issued by the Administration for the program established under section 7(m).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9D04D11E8E4D4759B4A30E8A3F332FB6"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Microloan intermediary</header><text>The term <term>microloan intermediary</term> means an intermediary (as defined in section 7(m)(11)) that is eligible to participate in the program established under section 7(m).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7E28C4E0E52244B5B888C02640998239"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Program</header><text>The term <term>Program</term> means the New Start Program established under subsection (b).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id33e5168633924d7fa85900e17fda5d4c"><enum>(8)</enum><header>SCORE</header><text>The term <term>SCORE</term> means the Service Corps of Retired Executives described in section 8(b)(1)(B).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id91cf22f6faf040cc83db9fc61f1cd5f7"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Women's business center</header><text>The term <term>women's business center</term> means a women's business center described in section 29.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idE61E351E136849DFA550057FF0DFC1E2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id78c47f7b460c44e69b49db05f1fa40f7"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>New Start Act of 2025</short-title>, the Administrator shall establish the New Start Program to award grants to organizations over a 5-year period to create or support existing entrepreneurial development programs for formerly incarcerated individuals or currently incarcerated individuals.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfe3bf9fc42034b5db3a927a965bdc51c"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>In carrying out the Program, the Administrator shall—</text><subparagraph id="id1fc1924645524de5a87d552f1134b2f6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>coordinate with the Director of the Bureau of Prisons to allow organizations, including small business development centers, women's business centers, and SCORE chapters, that receive a grant under this section to provide entrepreneurial development assistance to currently incarcerated individuals;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb01d7e6e6c734e9396e7f6e7a1eceadc"><enum>(B)</enum><text>develop a plan, which shall be updated annually and made in consultation with associations that represent small business development centers, women's business centers, and SCORE chapters, to match organizations with formerly incarcerated individuals and currently incarcerated individuals; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2c313222ff924d68b545134837ce4f8e"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to the extent possible, ensure an equitable share of grants between organizations that provide entrepreneurial development programs targeted to formerly incarcerated individuals and organizations that provide entrepreneurial development programs to currently incarcerated individuals.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id3827a18568ab47eeafa5439916d5b36a"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Grant requirements</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idca840ce723534c6dbaf539a9d8a680b0"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>The Administrator shall—</text><subparagraph id="idFAEFFD7D0BC34829B8A4420BBC00F42B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>award grants under the Program to organizations, or partnerships of organizations, including small business development centers, women's business centers, and SCORE chapters, which shall each receive a grant in an amount greater than $100,000 and less than $500,000 annually over the 5-year period in which the Program is in existence; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id23f6e06b680a40e6a2ba4885ecbbe75d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>allocate grants under the Program to ensure that the recipients are geographically varied throughout the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id79f1d785718a43b285af2878aa1145a4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Cap on women's business center grants</header><text>The amount of an award granted to a women's business center under the Program shall not count toward the maximum grant award amount allowable under section 29.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idF02922E408EA46ADBC35F62ECF8A0193"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Partnerships</header><text>An applicant for a grant under the Program may form partnerships with other organizations for the purposes of the application submitted under subsection (e) and for conducting entrepreneurial development programs.</text></subsection><subsection id="id051E8A04F88043E58F22CF708108A812"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Application</header><paragraph id="idB79F047FF3EF4AD1AA4DB28EA946DF24"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An organization or partnership of organizations desiring a grant under the Program shall submit an application to the Administrator in such form, in such manner, and containing such information as the Administrator may reasonably require.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idBD59A95CCBCF47CBA093B0D5AFDB7F22"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>An application submitted under paragraph (1) shall—</text><subparagraph id="id28596ba4df9d41208ff574552320913d"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for the purposes of entrepreneurial development programming targeted at formerly incarcerated individuals, demonstrate that the applicant is a microloan intermediary or a Community Advantage Small Business Lending Company, or has a partnership with such a microloan intermediary, Community Advantage Small Business Lending Company, or other lender that may provide capital to qualified formerly incarcerated individuals;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbbeb5aeb474a41c087b225b4ad13b398"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">demonstrate strong community ties, including those with the justice-impacted community, local businesses, and political leaders;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id863018f437964838a47b6b05c93d5b21"><enum>(C)</enum><text>demonstrate an ability to provide a full range of entrepreneurial development programming on an ongoing basis;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idec23d44920534c30a42e820b22a11597"><enum>(D)</enum><text>include a plan for reaching formerly incarcerated individuals or currently incarcerated individuals, including by identifying particular target populations within the community;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id45b3f5b92d144e059541e4d3bf042eff"><enum>(E)</enum><text>clearly define entrepreneurial development capabilities, including coordination with existing local resource partners of the Administration for additional training as necessary;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id92dbc16d98434d6abed12fde1cab8864"><enum>(F)</enum><text>present an entrepreneurial development curriculum, which may be a nationally recognized model or based upon such a model;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8c25fca8c77342d880ae2be0989fce28"><enum>(G)</enum><text>include a list of each partner organization; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4aa013cb3d994978a27d2d47c28bc0e0"><enum>(H)</enum><text>include a comprehensive plan for the use of grant funds, including estimates for administrative and outreach costs of running and evaluating the entrepreneurial development program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idD6B4A65C9138407786A1810A05C9689E"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In determining whether to award a grant under the Program, the Administrator may give priority to applicants based on—</text><paragraph id="idb971553e4e0d45e4aa8fd4f974b8238d"><enum>(1)</enum><text>whether the application includes a commitment from an existing or new non-Federal funding source;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idF03242FA0B05425FA7AD34A718733E9A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>whether the application takes into account local economies and markets as a part of the educational component of the entrepreneurial development program; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="idD2B66224677B4CEE8D2946A3BFAA078E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the ability or plan of the applicant to provide entrepreneurial development services concurrent with employment or job training services; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0FEBA45F937A43C287E389372E99B86E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>whether the applicant has a history of effectively providing entrepreneurial development training or access to capital to formerly incarcerated individuals or currently incarcerated individuals; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida3f27944faf849e4b56332e011bb3b0f"><enum>(5)</enum><text>whether the applicant will be providing entrepreneurial development training to currently incarcerated individuals who will be released from Federal custody not later than 18 months after the date on which those currently incarcerated individuals begin to receive those services.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idDCB0F25E93704382999E231730409A2E"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text>A recipient of a grant under the Program shall, to the maximum extent possible, connect formerly incarcerated individuals to a range of Federal resources, including—</text><paragraph id="id82224BB5E52B47A7AFF82C27390E8A0D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the program established under section 7(m);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idAA000ACCC02843C087DE3D1F1D050333"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Community Advantage Small Business Lending Companies;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5d1231a5639748b4a82985bcd04d5d7e"><enum>(3)</enum><text>small business development centers;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id609f9d3501374c8c9a6e1a76991b969e"><enum>(4)</enum><text>women’s business centers;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id373eae9b3f004ed091f048e27eda9597"><enum>(5)</enum><text>SCORE chapters;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id514b51cdb35a43289f0d87e9fde1b003"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Veteran Business Outreach Centers described in section 32 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/657b">15 U.S.C. 657b</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8D5FD00B38E54DE9B3B3CD3BC119221A"><enum>(7)</enum><text>business centers established by the Minority Business Development Agency of the Department of Commerce.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idFB33C271802D4FA38AA666A63D78420C"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Reports</header><paragraph id="id46D09D679259497CA91A85A9B724F443"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date on which the Administrator establishes the Program, and every year thereafter until the Program terminates, the Administrator shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report on the activities of the Program, including—</text><subparagraph id="id2C8BA5C1F415427BA122D577D90AB633"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a list of each grantee organization and each partner organization;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7EDFD7C2F8274F81829DAA5392289026"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the characteristics of formerly incarcerated individuals and currently incarcerated individuals assisted under the entrepreneurial development programs, including race and ethnicity, gender, age, marital status, parental status, employment status, income, and prior business experience;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id672D88CF285447CD9928FA4C2DD657EE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the participation and attendance rates for all components of the entrepreneurial development programs;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4E5626E75F1A4327AEE19BFF014AFEEF"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the entrepreneurial development program retention rate;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb0aa9de9ee0e46af84fd4c610ba0ac4f"><enum>(E)</enum><text>to the greatest extent practicable, the most common reasons why participants do not complete an entrepreneurial development program;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idAE9E96E4E0A84F36AE4C0EFB6B56CF1F"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the percentage of formerly incarcerated individuals who remain non-justice involved during the calendar year of an entrepreneurial development program;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1AF9FA6B2DDA41B7B0DE1AEB5CF799A2"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the experiences and perceptions of entrepreneurial development program participants;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9E846D7C82EF46EFA5FDE00EC5163591"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the number and dollar amount of loans made to formerly incarcerated individuals;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id91B6B5D43C7F4BA5AA8F9EA09A705B8B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the number and dollar amount of loans made or guaranteed by the Administration to formerly incarcerated individuals; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idF26CE35273924585BAC381676A118FA4"><enum>(J)</enum><text>such additional information as the Administrator may require.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idF16AE9DD23AF4303A362F4F2ABFBAD63"><enum>(2)</enum><header>GAO report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date on which the Program terminates, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report that evaluates—</text><subparagraph id="id6A577346D82743D0A17F773DE7837F27"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the services that grant recipients provided to formerly incarcerated individuals and currently incarcerated individuals assisted under entrepreneurial development programs;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id40C896A8D3454A16AAAB0D26B00767BE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>oversight of the Program by the Administrator, including policies and procedures for monitoring the compliance by grant recipients with Program requirements and an assessment of the effectiveness of the Program; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB0D2E26AA2FD4B6789DACA5A61CEE636"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the overall performance of the Program and the impacts of the Program on grant recipients.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id8B0CC3BD442D4F2186D5B8B6C91AD6F4"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to affect the program established under section 7(m), including—</text><paragraph id="id9A15EA8B7C0E419CA21F5A5682FF6311"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the requirements of that program;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idAF34D49D12E046F6A4A63B548370EFA3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the manner in which that program is carried out; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idD2B35E6DBE7B490F8E174107600C0079"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the use or availability of any amounts that have been made available to carry out that program.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idCB4DA73BC8B04B9D9E1343120F86C73F"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Administrator such sums as are necessary to carry out the Program.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

