<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H420BEF28D2054D1DB83AAECC1EFE9E6A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4936 IH: Taskforce for Recognizing and Averting Payment Scams Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4936</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250808">August 8, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000193">Mr. Nunn of Iowa</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="H001047">Mr. Himes</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a Task Force for Recognizing and Averting Payment Scams, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HAC1CF73C573E49348EF0ED7224B6B1FC" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HD5B8EDF7A3904D8589023FE58BCB0DB0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Taskforce for Recognizing and Averting Payment Scams Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>TRAPS Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H1EC210AB23EF4E428F88760D4A540221"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC87699274A624944BB25F196ED5F787E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Payment</header><text>The term <term>payment</term> means any mechanism through which an individual can electronically transfer funds to another individual via a platform or intermediary.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8E0E7C2597874F139BF77AC863669E3A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Treasury.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3EC91F1583B4481DA448DF57AB9BC79D" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Task Force</header><text>The term <term>Task Force</term> means the Task Force on Payment Scams established under section 3(a).</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HF01DD5D1437944699B79EAA5EFF1D81F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Task Force on Payment Scams</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H34A711190F3E4442877F135848D8AE48"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Establishment</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall establish a task force, to be known as the Task Force for Recognizing and Averting Payment Scams.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HCCB9EC5291AC4A1CAEF6CA6E27626543"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership</header> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBCCA0080B10B4106BF31ADAB937FBA82"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Composition</header><text>The Task Force shall be chaired by the Secretary or a designee thereof, and shall consist of representatives from the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HC141F2F020794457ADBA9E0EB9F96799"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFA38EC5E0F004C06A9FACB642A47E9C6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Federal Communications Commission.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0ADB724431F844ECAF700FF4C9E7B17D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Federal Trade Commission.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H10AA6A3B8CC143E98BDA18C43980629A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The Department of Justice.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H81916A6D2BD04682827EE03000075687"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The Office of the Comptroller of the Currency.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB4FC59F1054D4F2C9677D7D055CF9966"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE0CF45DBF2094AB8A08B9F16E6BB14D0"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The National Credit Union Administration.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE9A7D425F58141ED9119D49E55AC9ABD"><enum>(H)</enum><text>The Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0B0617B5179C4F9884B3995AF740357D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The Financial Crimes Enforcement Network.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8E74EB6601A147CF956457CFAE738620"><enum>(J)</enum><text>A representative, appointed by the Secretary in consultation with the Task Force, from a financial institution with expertise in identifying, preventing, and combating payment scams.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H04833E7A1AC14EBC97FC1F7698595255"><enum>(K)</enum><text>A representative, appointed by the Secretary in consultation with the Task Force, from a credit union with expertise in identifying, preventing, and combating payment scams.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE015A5B491F04F0BBC52EF9EF29ED9F2"><enum>(L)</enum><text>A representative, appointed by the Secretary in consultation with the Task Force, from a digital payment network with expertise in identifying, preventing, and combating payment scams.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAF4BB953FF1A4DB68E7911298CFAB8C6"><enum>(M)</enum><text>A representative, appointed by the Secretary in consultation with the Task Force, from a community bank.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4473018A37BA424D86086C8BAF3EB3B2"><enum>(N)</enum><text>A representative, appointed by the Secretary in consultation with the Task Force, from a consumer group.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H361F967289CF469093696976F9624DE3" commented="no"><enum>(O)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A representative, appointed by the Secretary in consultation with the Task Force, from an industry association representing technology or online platforms.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAE748C22C98247F891DA05C8A794AB90" commented="no"><enum>(P)</enum><text>Not more than 5 representatives appointed by the Secretary to represent victims, scam support networks, and other relevant stakeholders in order to better assist consumers and stakeholders.</text></subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H1B7E56EB0F3B4A7C87DCBE685BB00D2B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Term of appointment</header><text>The term of a member of the Task Force shall continue until the termination of the Task Force.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBED7A3F225CB4E8787D0927D4072D55D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Vacancy</header><text>Any vacancy occurring in the membership of the Task Force shall be filled in the same manner in which the original appointment was made.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD1FDD57AFCA84B7EA73242824FABA468"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The Task Force shall—</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF8345412194E44FCBB4000454F6F39D4"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">examine current trends and developments in payment scams, identify effective methods for preventing such scams, and issue recommendations to enhance efforts to identify and prevent such activities;</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD3643DE653B1498E8C7383D88BBABE4A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">adopt a cross-sector approach to ensure its recommendations reflect the full scope of the issue, given that scams impact individuals across a wide range of industries, including financial services, telecommunications, and technology; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H94C44C2F0A444E3AAD303765A7BE6E5C"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include representation from stakeholders with direct experience supporting victims of scams, as well as industry participants with insight into scam tactics and prevention strategies.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H74D3E3C35E674AB684627F3951E731E0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text>The Task Force shall meet not less than 3 times during the 1-year period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act, and thereafter at such times and places, and by such means, as the Chair of the Task Force determines to be appropriate, which may include the use of remote conference technology.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HBCAC0085FCA94B7C91823F3B758C8D37"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The duties of the Task Force shall include—</text> <paragraph id="HBA766FF22EDC4959AC5382F95FCEEA1E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>evaluating best practices for combating methods used by scammers, including spoofed calls, scam text messages, and malicious advertisements, pop-ups, and websites;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H45D8A2EA8A254D63897E38A74C40F134"><enum>(2)</enum><text>assessing how international jurisdictions have tried to prevent payment scams;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2B05E60AFD6F4676BFF970C48723635F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>identifying and reviewing current methods used to scam a consumer through payment platforms;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H177AEC152BC14A01953190472DFA4CE1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>determining a strategy for education programs that better equip consumers to identify, avoid, and report payment scam attempts to the appropriate authorities;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H157E0F4BEE904A4889992243FD3BD561"><enum>(5)</enum><text>coordinating efforts to ensure perpetrators of payment scams can be identified and pursued by law enforcement;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE0D378D24A554507827F650118DB8128"><enum>(6)</enum><text>consulting with other relevant stakeholders, including State, local, and Tribal agencies and financial services providers;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA1EE13F4E08B4A47A0BCA815571AE7E7"><enum>(7)</enum><text>determining whether any additional Federal legislation would be beneficial for law enforcement and industry in mitigating payment scams; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD66D7793F9FD423796F8C2B52DB8FAD5"><enum>(8)</enum><text>identifying potential solutions to payment scams involving business email compromise.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H38FFEB0B372145E4B6E41D59D5E7FAAF"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Compensation</header><text>Each member of the Task Force who is a civilian or employee of the United States shall serve without compensation, other than compensation to which entitled as an employee of the United States, as the case may be.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H562BFD8883C94E0AAF5E5FB938B1FA5C"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Report</header> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE8ABA541C17F4E49AC20463EDDFD6B13"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date on which the Secretary establishes the Task Force, the Task Force shall submit to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and make publicly available online a report detailing—</text> <subparagraph id="H18D52F7522CD4112973B4CC1F9B4495F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the results of the reviews and evaluations of the Task Force under subsection (e);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF775ED1FF69E470FAD8F3914752ED9DF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the strategy identified under subsection (e);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC64CF848F0A4402DA05750A37B14DA4A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any legislative or regulatory recommendations that would enhance the ability to detect and prevent payment scams described in subsection (e); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE3D3286A770F4ED6ADEF4B527D605A7B">
                        <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>recommendations to enhance cooperation among Federal, State, local, and Tribal authorities in the investigation and prosecution of scams and other financial crimes, including harmonizing data collection, improving reporting mechanisms and streams, estimating the number of complaints and consumers affected, and evaluating the effectiveness of anti-scam training programs.</text>
                    </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3506526F8D7C4FC39914E9DBB83DDCA8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Annual updates</header><text>After submitting an initial report required under paragraph (1), the Task Force shall, on an annual basis, submit to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and make publicly available online an updated version of the report.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF3794C32FADB4AE59381E3B43FF7742E"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Applicable law</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/4">Chapter 4</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, shall not apply to the Task Force.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2DCB8D6525844844B936CB6855F4C1F6"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>The Task Force shall terminate on the date that is 3 years after the date on which the Task Force submits the report required under subsection (h)(1).</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

