<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-LIP25341-97P-YM-087"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2399 IS: Loggers Economic Assistance and Relief Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2399</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250723">July 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S252">Ms. Collins</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S363">Mr. King</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S422">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAF00">Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To establish a payment program for unexpected loss of markets and revenues to timber harvesting and timber hauling businesses due to major disasters, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H6D35FB6A2B6A4A88B367A8FF02747D71"><section section-type="section-one" id="H51C70BE56B5C482588BDB0A35A9E3364"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Loggers Economic Assistance and Relief Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HE1C6E106FB934903B52150893D2A3E5E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Payment program for timber harvesting and timber hauling businesses</header><subsection id="H30EBBA150332425C8E229990717AA7A9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HC193C2EDDBE4497295871D1CC6934231"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means any timber harvesting business or timber hauling business that harvested or hauled unrefined timber products in the previous calendar year.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HC1CF21768C3C46F790E40CBE878DAD31"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Major disaster</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>major disaster</term>—</text><subparagraph id="H44C42C911A404792BF660E8E744EE205"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has the meaning given the term in section 102(2) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5122">42 U.S.C. 5122(2)</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3F7AC95339014F6194DBE0C334A55907"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes an insect infestation declared a major disaster pursuant to such Act. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8151BA8FA8AF44FC9F112595CF0F4FFC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Gross revenue</header><text>The term <term>gross revenue</term> means the gross revenue generated by an eligible entity from timber harvesting or timber hauling services within the normal range of operation of the eligible entity, as determined by the Secretary.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0D0BA0EB665D4CA8983E34C9219CA465"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Administrator of the Farm Service Agency.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFD1F6F0018424E9289BF908205CF9F59"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Payments</header><text>The Secretary shall make payments in accordance with this section to eligible entities that as a result of a major disaster experienced a loss of not less than 10 percent in gross revenue in a 30-day period or quarter of a calendar year, as compared to the gross revenue of the eligible entity during the same 30-day period or quarter of the previous calendar year.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2A8275EE92C047A98A25590C046459CE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Amount of payment</header><text>The amount of a payment made to an eligible entity under subsection (b) shall be equal to 10 percent of the gross revenue of the eligible entity during the applicable period under subsection (b).</text></subsection><subsection id="H1C079D631AF041DCB0AEB9D23C06E49B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Allowable use</header><text>The Secretary shall only make a payment under subsection (b) to an eligible entity that certifies to the Secretary that the payment will be used only for operating expenses.</text></subsection><subsection id="H246123AE06DE49F7979B0CAFFD0556E7"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate and the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives a report describing the payments made under this section, including—</text><paragraph id="HDDC616C9B1DD4060813B1E75D6826A8A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the identity of each recipient of a payment; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7D7255EB35BE463B9E0BC9724E319915"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the amount of each payment provided to each recipient described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3D02614BC414421BA71CF884538D275A"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Regulations</header><paragraph id="H5315B7A4703E4BB8B4BD180FD3FEEB68"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as otherwise provided in this section, not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall prescribe such regulations as are necessary to carry out this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H778A485661F74D7B8CEBB8E665978C78"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Procedure</header><text>The promulgation of regulations under, and administration of, this section shall be made without regard to—</text><subparagraph id="HC4F5721637EA47328CCC0DBE979BB0C9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the notice and comment provisions of section 553 of title 5, United States Code; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFA6FFC03A7A246099FB68A33907A59D1"><enum>(B)</enum><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/44/35">chapter 35</external-xref> of title 44, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Paperwork Reduction Act</quote>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF741BCBEC07D4BA2A7B49BA05D1DE544"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $50,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2025 through 2029.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

