<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7C057AB7DEC84A23AFE68026DDDC4BD4" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 523 IH: Expressing support for the designation of June 21, 2025, as National ASK (Asking Saves Kids) Day to promote children’s health and secure storage of guns in the home.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 523</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250620">June 20, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001121">Mr. Crow</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="A000380">Mr. Amo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001127">Mrs. Cherfilus-McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000400">Ms. Kamlager-Dove</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001208">Mrs. McBath</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001227">Ms. McClellan</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of June 21, 2025, as National ASK (Asking Saves Kids) Day to promote children’s health and secure storage of guns in the home.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas firearm-related deaths are now the leading cause of death in United States children;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to estimates from the Healthcare Cost and Utilization Project, on average, 22 children and teens per day were injured or killed from the discharge of a firearm;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 4.6 million children in the United States live in homes with loaded and unlocked guns;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in States that collect data through the National Violent Death Reporting System, on average, 80 percent of unintentional firearm deaths of children under 15 occurred in a home;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in approximately 76 percent of school shootings by a student, the gun was brought from their home or the home of a family member and owned by an adult family member;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the ASK Campaign encourages parents to add a question to a conversation before their child visits other homes, <quote>Is there a gun in your house?</quote>, and follow affirmative answers with, <quote>Is it locked and unloaded?</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas asking these simple questions about gun safety before sending your child to visit or play at another home could help save your child’s life;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas asking these questions will raise awareness of the need for secure storage of guns in the home as a proven effective preventative safety measure;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas asking these questions will prevent incidents of family fire, in which an improperly stored or misused gun results in injury or death;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the ASK Campaign was first established with the American Academy of Pediatrics (AAP) in 2000 and is currently administered by the Brady Campaign;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the president of the AAP has said, <quote>Keeping children and teens safe from preventable injuries is one of the most important things we do as pediatricians.</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, a November 2017 Government Accountability Office report, <quote>Personal Firearms: Programs that Promote Safe Storage and Research on Their Effectiveness</quote>, identified 16 public or nonprofit programs that promote secure gun storage, including the ASK program, and reported that the ASK program was the only national program to be evaluated and validated as effective;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas June 21, the first day of summer, the season in which kids typically spend more time at a friend’s or family member’s home, has traditionally been designated as National ASK Day;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Brady Center and Campaign, its more than 100 chapters in a majority of States throughout the Nation, and its many local, State, and national partners come together to highlight the ASK Campaign each year in communities across the Nation; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas June 21 is designated by national organizations, as well as various local and State governments, including State legislatures, as the 20th annual National ASK Day: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H17C5BE6A2AB34F03A199FDCDDFD8CC5F"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H2797A4207C19419DA68A93107A106A31"><enum/><text>That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="H3DEA104026A44C9496E842563C47339F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the designation of National ASK (Asking Saves Kids) Day to encourage parents to begin asking this life-saving question;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5260FDC7F7A6476DB09830DFFA866097"><enum>(2)</enum><text>encourages public health, medical, and other professionals to discuss gun ownership, gun safety, and safe storage in the home with their patients and parents and guardians of minors; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H30B0A77067914E8391BEE4F17FDC3D7C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>supports the goals and ideals of National ASK Day.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

