<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2D05CCA17823494B8EBF5924A52FD2F2" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 343 IH: Supporting the goals and ideals of San Jacinto Day in recognition of April 21, 1836, the date on which General Sam Houston and the Texan Army defeated the Mexican Army winning Texas independence from Mexico.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 343</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250421">April 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000816">Mr. Williams of Texas</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001291">Mr. Babin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001224">Mr. Self</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Supporting the goals and ideals of San Jacinto Day in recognition of April 21, 1836, the date on which General Sam Houston and the Texan Army defeated the Mexican Army winning Texas independence from Mexico.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, 189 years ago, General Sam Houston launched an attack against Santa Anna and his Mexican Army achieving the deciding victory over Mexico securing Texas independence;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas General Sam Houston said, <quote>We must now act or abandon all hope. Rally to the standard and be no longer the scoff of mercenary tongues. Be men, be free men, that your children may bless their father’s name</quote>;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the battle lasted only 18 minutes before the Texan Army claimed their victory;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the victory at San Jacinto led to the independence of Texas from Mexico, giving Texas the autonomy needed for its eventual admission into the United States nine years later; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the legacy of the Texan Army, remembered for its courage and sacrifice continues to inspire national pride in Texans and Americans alike: Now therefore be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HDF37B7195BBA45E5AB60DD9EFA519B0F"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HE4E81C8B339C4F1A98496F7A2932A76E"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> 
<paragraph id="H108A48B6DA9E4097ADCCBA48C864A872"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the goals and ideals of San Jacinto Day, marking the 189th anniversary of the Battle of San Jacinto, the day outnumbered Texan soldiers defeated the Mexican Army and solidified Texas independence;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC7AB5893140E48A8A1DAE6F6297E2D0E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>honors the bravery and honor of those who fought in the Texas revolution for their commitment to freedom and liberty; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1E77DD8B59C749FA893A7E074C61FF9C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>encourages all Americans to reflect on the importance of freedom and the spirit of those who fight to uphold freedom and American ideals.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

