<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-OTT25274-00W-WV-T76"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1842 IS: Wildfire Reduction and Carbon Removal Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code>II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1842</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250521">May 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S316">Mr. Whitehouse</sponsor> (for himself and
                    <cosponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill;
                which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to create a credit for carbon
 removal and storage for forest residues from wildfire management.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="idf362506390894839a141d2747cacb8d7"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Wildfire Reduction and Carbon Removal Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section section-type="subsequent-section" id="id98ae70a772824e8ea029359cadb52c7f"><enum>2.</enum><header>Credit for forest residue carbon removal and storage</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf7314b34b7e942989c9b8f5da96465e8"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subpart D of part IV of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id11DC80FCE85D45FC95EDE2CEECB70F77"><section id="id3af0236cdf274eaab9ab401fdda316d0"><enum>45BB.<?LEXA-Enum 45BB.?></enum><header>Forest residue carbon removal and storage</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3493cfbe624046f4bcfb66c034f784fa"><enum>(a)</enum><header>General rule</header><text>For purposes of section 38, the forest residue carbon removal and storage credit for any taxable year is an amount equal to the applicable dollar amount per metric ton of qualified carbon dioxide equivalent which is—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7b78c1e46d3c416a955ceba5dd94b25a"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">captured by the taxpayer from qualified forest residue biomass using biomass equipment which was originally placed in service at a qualified forest residue biomass carbon removal and storage project on or after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Wildfire Reduction and Carbon Removal Act of 2025</short-title>, and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide099d6f802ce427d83b845ad345ed28b"><enum>(2)</enum><text>stored by the taxpayer in secure geological storage or via long-duration utilization.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id339fb7beb9644f389cc62201b1480b0a"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicable dollar amount</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida560b1452b744b0689c152c1984e2c64"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The applicable dollar amount is—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6fc11523ea5d4685b14a57c33ab70dcf"><enum>(A)</enum><text>$36, in the case of qualified carbon dioxide equivalent stored in secure geological storage, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf923d799558f4f719a973cc0fc391245"><enum>(B)</enum><text>$12, in the case of qualified carbon dioxide equivalent stored via long-duration utilization.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3fc25a3b9a7e40b096a8e7c16f5e0bd2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Adjustment for inflation</header><text>In the case of any taxable year beginning in a calendar year after 2026, the $36 and $12 amounts under paragraph (1) shall each be multiplied by the inflation adjustment factor determined under section 43(b)(3)(B) for such calendar year, determined by substituting <quote>2025</quote> for <quote>1990</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf32ad374b0e24a96abc1ff2f6a8c2057" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Increased credit amount
 for certain facilities</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idedf1052dfbfc4dfe9d1ca3170c726632"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of qualified carbon dioxide equivalent which is described in subsection (a)(1) and which meets the requirements of paragraphs (3) and (4) of section 45Q(h) (determined after application of the modifications described in subparagraph (B)), the amount applicable shall be equal to such amount (determined without regard to this paragraph) multiplied by 5.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id28f82f88e87d41b8bb32a05ac245266c"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Modifications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The modifications described in this subparagraph are as follows:</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbdd42f3c0d94487f93405c59c7db36ba"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In section 45Q(h)(3)(A), the term <quote>qualified forest residue biomass carbon removal and storage project</quote> shall be substituted for <quote>qualified facility</quote> each place it appears, and <quote>such project</quote> shall be substituted for <quote>such facility</quote> each place it appears.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id37757120c74a482a9a013eee1b9b3465"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In section 45Q(h)(3)(A), the term <quote>biomass equipment</quote> shall be substituted for <quote>carbon capture equipment</quote> in the matter before subparagraph (A).</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd975d96688364408ac9ff5dc7a893f65"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>In section 45Q(h)(3)(A)(ii), by disregarding the phrase <quote>for any portion of such taxable year which is within the period described in paragraph (3)(A) or (4)(A) of subsection (a)</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6f180a874b5742de88a034b8a84382c6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Installation of additional biomass system equipment at existing
 project</header><text>In the case of a qualified forest residue biomass carbon removal and storage project placed in service before the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Wildfire Reduction and Carbon Removal Act of 2025</short-title> at which additional biomass equipment is placed in service on or after the date of the enactment of such Act, the amount of captured qualified carbon dioxide equivalent taken into account for purposes of subsection (a) is an amount (not less than zero) equal to the excess of—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id55f8b58937564fdf9c717f156646f5b0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the total amount of qualified carbon dioxide equivalent captured at such project for the taxable year, over</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb6e67b51ae324bf8b10f2a1692c2f579"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the total amount of the carbon dioxide equivalent capture capacity of the qualified forest residue biomass project in service at such project on the day before the date of the enactment of such Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id773a114edf0e492aa100d333983514cf"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Qualified carbon dioxide equivalent</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>qualified carbon dioxide equivalent</term> means the net metric tons of carbon dioxide equivalent which—</text><paragraph id="id7992a48cd0574a169f65c4865e0bced5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is captured through the disposal or utilization of the carbon embodied in qualified forest residue biomass, and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0b0bf1f241aa42729baad2158af3b5d8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is measured and verified at the point of disposal or utilization based on, in accordance with the rules of subsection (f)—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf70157a3cc164c2e9dbd59f0339f1a25"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">project-level lifecycle analysis of greenhouse gas emissions, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id00a0d6d349544b6fa03d1b0d85886d6c"><enum>(B)</enum><text>project-level monitoring, reporting, and verification.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idafdaed99bbff42468301d7420ea8fa27"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Qualified forest residue biomass carbon removal and storage
 project</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb7e7610d419c41c19d35de40570f9094"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id33ed0938c8394395bcebf0978fa04ffb"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>qualified forest residue biomass carbon removal and storage project</term> means any project which—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id629f8c44af764a5c82fe95de87bf6023"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">uses biomass equipment to store qualified carbon dioxide equivalent in secure geological storage or via long-duration utilization, and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id34cd017158f548b99a94021f491c5925"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>stores not less than 1,000 metric tons of qualified carbon dioxide equivalent as described in clause (i) during the taxable year.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc9fae77653894cdf8e7b762f0a51a6ad"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Aggregation of facilities</header><text>The term <term>qualified forest residue biomass carbon removal and storage project</term> may include multiple facilities which may be aggregated in order to meet the requirement of subparagraph (A)(ii).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idCB34D311728D4265BD0485A96099ED16"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualified forest residue biomass</header><text>The term <term>qualified forest residue biomass</term> means forest residues from the thinning of trees no greater than 8 inches in diameter at breast height and other residues (such as limbs and bark) which—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf1e951b7016a42ee8fc3d20a22c165ad"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">meet sustainability standards issued pursuant to section 2(f) of the <short-title>Wildfire Reduction and Carbon Removal Act of 2025</short-title>, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida3a84b1d53ad43cb8ecc19ba954e5d42"><enum>(B)</enum><text>are produced from wildfire hazard reduction or ecological restoration activities identified—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3754d9c8eb8e481ab54b58fa0ef287d0"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in a final United States Forest Service Land Management Plan or Bureau of Land Management Resource Management Plan, or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id927b9dee9308428592a6bc706686e206"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by the United States Forest Service as occurring in firesheds with significant wildfire hazard potential and vegetation departure.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id18233575cb6d450e85df10ca7ddd1e6a"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Other definitions and special rules</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6C78DBC9D7814CE3ACF50F681BDBCB4D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Secure geological storage</header><text>Carbon dioxide equivalent shall be treated as stored in secure geological storage only if such carbon dioxide equivalent is stored in such wells or underground storage mechanisms, including injection of bio-liquids or bio-solids or engineered burial of biomass, appropriate to the type of biomass carbon removal as the Secretary shall identify in consultation with the Secretary of Energy and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency as having demonstrated the capability to store such carbon dioxide equivalent securely for at least a 1,000-year period.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idAD86AC734ABB4E7BA2AD916C094A135E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Long-duration utilization</header><text>Carbon dioxide equivalent shall be treated as stored via long-duration utilization if such carbon dioxide equivalent is stored in the form of biochar, durable building materials, or other products which remove carbon, which are determined by the Secretary in collaboration with the entities described in paragraph (1) to have demonstrated the capability to store such carbon dioxide equivalent securely for at least a 100-year period, as calculated based on a lifecycle analysis.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb0ebf8d96b1540e8b00b59f4c0685b26"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Biomass equipment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>biomass equipment</term> means any equipment used at a qualified forest residue biomass carbon removal and storage project to dispose of qualified forest residue biomass.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id01897daddf7848b8be1fd4d93a3b283d"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Credit not allowed for enhanced recovery operations</header><text>No credit shall be allowed under subsection (a) with respect to qualified carbon dioxide equivalent which is used by the taxpayer as a tertiary injectant in an enhanced oil or natural gas recovery project.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id70c5e57e7b49465ba2dcfdf831f225ef"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Coordination with other credits</header><subparagraph id="id617da832b4374cbc97ef1048f8b7ff53"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>No credit shall be allowed under this section with respect to any qualifying carbon dioxide removal project for any taxable year for which a credit determined under section 45Q or 48C is allowed for such taxable year.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ideda2045dde304770aab407518adfd09a"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Special rule for qualified carbon dioxide removal
 projects integrated with clean energy generation</header><clause id="id69c07e7a4b494f0c83d6eed31e9e907d"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of any qualifying carbon dioxide removal project which produces electricity, hydrogen, or fuel as an output of its qualifying carbon dioxide removal approach, no credit shall be allowed with respect to the production of such electricity, hydrogen, or fuel under section 40B, 45, 45V, 45Y, or 45Z unless such electricity, hydrogen, or fuel is consumed by such qualifying carbon dioxide removal project.</text></clause><clause id="id4ea93ea6ebad46e3b8e68c6aae843b8b"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Energy credit and clean electricity investment
 credit</header><text>In the case of any qualifying carbon dioxide removal project which includes—</text><subclause id="ideac018b91568406e8335eddcd651f1b7"><enum>(I)</enum><text>any energy property (as defined in section 48(a)(3)) which produces electricity or hydrogen from the process of carbon dioxide removal, or</text></subclause><subclause id="id81e2d736910f4f9b9b0dbf3a2259215e"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any qualified facility (as defined in section 48E(b)(3)) which produces electricity or hydrogen from the process of carbon dioxide removal,</text></subclause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="clause">no
                                            credit shall be allowed under section 48 or 48E with
                                            respect to such energy property or qualified
                                            facility.</continuation-text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id73402a7363ec4e32b59a3be37353a86d"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Only qualified carbon dioxide equivalent captured and
                                    disposed of or used within the United States taken into
 account</header><text>The credit under this section shall apply only with respect to qualified carbon dioxide equivalent the capture and storage or disposal of which is within—</text><subparagraph id="idf816e12c6083459eb6ed4dc8b1684456"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the United States (within the meaning of section 638(1)), or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf5bc88a3fe714d8095ed40cc532874cd"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a possession of the United States (within the meaning of section 638(2)).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idd79728d772cb436dabf63cc946faf65d"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Credit attributable to taxpayer</header><subparagraph id="idffd513dacb314fb49b69cb4573183ab8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B) or in any regulations prescribed by the Secretary, any credit under this section shall be attributable to the person that owns the biomass equipment and physically or contractually ensures the capture and storage or disposal of the qualified carbon dioxide equivalent.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id760fc4fe04ee4074b24cc2f528b17db6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Election</header><text>If the person described in subparagraph (A) makes an election under this subparagraph in such time and manner as the Secretary may prescribe by regulations, the credit under this section—</text><clause id="idff2292b298bd4628971acd384f5a64da"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall be allowable to the person that stores or disposes of the qualified carbon dioxide equivalent, and</text></clause><clause id="id2d515f2098b542f0ace1a67368229015"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>shall not be allowable to the person described in subparagraph (A).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idd60662552860440888fe53d0f8c09054"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Recapture</header><text>The Secretary shall, by regulations, provide for recapturing the benefit of any credit allowable under subsection (a) with respect to any qualified carbon dioxide equivalent which ceases to be stored or disposed of in a manner consistent with the requirements of this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida0a1519dc624400187e038ee7809f389"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Credit reduced for tax-exempt bonds</header><text>Rules similar to the rule under section 45(b)(3) shall apply for purposes of this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4df8415e77324bbe82ae603aef712950"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Guidance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than January 1, 2026, the Secretary shall issue guidance regarding implementation of this section, including standards on qualified forest residue biomass and determination of net qualified dioxide equivalent removals under this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide0b08d87352d4b3482321871aa35f6d5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Credit To be part of general business credit</header><text>Subsection (b) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/38">section 38</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking <quote>plus</quote> at the end of paragraph (40), by striking the period at the end of paragraph (41) and inserting <quote>, plus</quote>, and by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id962463C10EE1439CB2460330BA5ABC7C"><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd0a69cefbb0442ee89d1a84b3cda0779"><enum>(42)</enum><text>the forest residue carbon removal and storage credit determined under section 45BB(a).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2c5bc28fbad84009953b90471494bbaa"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Elective payment and transfer of credit</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id83d0548275d948bf8a3e46d88e248446"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Elective payment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (b) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6417">section 6417</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id96801cf5601e408995641889b385dd11"><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idff402af8b090469d9f0ca5dddee02764"><enum>(13)</enum><text>The forest residue carbon removal and storage credit determined under section 45BB(a).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="idfeaa971c63b44b049e4dec4a6b79246b"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Transfer</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6418">Section 6418(f)(1)(A)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idceae2fc5110348219dc5f033427769fa"><clause id="idd089a505a2d144ad89c4fe85adfde0ae"><enum>(xii)</enum><text>The forest residue carbon removal and storage credit determined under section 45BB(a).</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc96b286b363545d29f628c2507c750b5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for subpart D of part IV of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="idaec91e53-7cdf-4aa0-8b60-e076a5d0b897"><toc><toc-entry level="section" idref="id3af0236cdf274eaab9ab401fdda316d0">Sec.
 45BB. Forest residue carbon removal and storage.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id70778830e510406a867df8cd38e7040f"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2025.</text></subsection><subsection id="id4be89952bf5842b4add9f15f3c59e1a6"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Sustainability standards rulemaking and public comment period</header><paragraph id="id13b03e244f0e439995e4199e1b4959f3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Rulemaking authority</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Interior, shall issue regulations to establish sustainability standards for the identification of qualified forest residue biomass for purposes of the forest residue carbon removal and storage tax credit established by this section. Such regulations shall—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id08ff9d22fcbf46c687980cc7481ae19e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>using the best available science, including the 2023 Wildfire Hazard Potential map produced by the Forest Service Fire Modeling Institute and the 2023 Vegetation Condition Class categorization produced by the Landscape Fire and Resource Management Planning Tools program, identify firesheds with significant wildfire hazard potential and vegetation departure from a fire-adapted historical baseline from which qualified forest residue biomass can be sourced;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6bc6f6ee8ae349b5bf37e4df5bcbe381"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identify regional and ecosystem-specific requirements to limit eligibility to practices and sites which—</text><clause id="idbb03edec6e1642af82c6e0f30f457f64"><enum>(i)</enum><text>have minimal negative impacts on soil quality, soil fertility, soil erosion, soil carbon sequestration, and site productivity;</text></clause><clause id="id5e03e104d95a4463b6730f3b84ac5fe6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>have minimal negative impacts on biodiversity, including soil microbiota, plants, and animals;</text></clause><clause id="id138d9eb9078745b1a78473614af4c5da"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>have minimal negative impacts on water quality and hydrological functioning;</text></clause><clause id="id91f76a28b2924441b2499d5c60bde15c"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>have minimal impacts on reducing or displacing food production; and</text></clause><clause id="ida999ed24e7454852825e2783cf35f1ca"><enum>(v)</enum><text>have minimal substitution for existing economic uses of forest products, including considering reducing the maximum diameter of thinned trees considered to be qualified forest residue biomass; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idde2c5d078abc44e19220a704566a94c5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>consider direct and indirect impacts of biomass sourcing and harvest.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id8ebc9ade81a74b27b973cbaed525d38a"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Public comment requirement</header><text>Not later than 6 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Treasury shall publish in the Federal Register proposed regulations that include sustainability standards for the forest residue carbon removal and storage tax credit.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4f9e2620f95e45f8b971e353457b64ca"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public comment period</header><subparagraph id="idaa97c092fa904ddbaacb9e825920964c"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>The Secretary shall provide for a period of not less than 60 days after the date of publication of the proposed regulations during which the public may submit comments on the proposed regulations.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idae6070dd36aa4eb6a9ac10ca22385517"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Consideration of comments</header><text>The Secretary shall consider all comments received during the public comment period before issuing final regulations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5977b29a128a47ae8fedd975044b809e"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Final regulations</header><text>The Secretary shall issue final regulations and establish sustainability standards for the carbon removal tax credit established under this section not later than 90 days after the close of the public comment period, taking into account feedback from the public and stakeholders.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5211ff20904042549d142557f7b41071"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Consideration of revision</header><text>Every 5 years, the Secretary shall provide for a public comment period to consider whether the sustainability standards should be updated to reflect latest science. The Secretary shall consider all comments received during the public comment period before determining whether to update the regulations under the same procedures as used to issue the original standards.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id6cfa80daa2f14305ad5083b5229b65e1"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Carbon determination rulemaking and public comment period</header><paragraph id="id5c82f697555f431c861dd7483c9ec752"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Rulemaking authority</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of Energy and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, shall issue regulations to establish greenhouse gas lifecycle analysis requirements and monitoring, reporting, and verification requirements to determine qualified carbon dioxide equivalent for the implementation of the forest residue carbon removal and storage tax credit established by this section. These regulations shall seek to—</text><subparagraph id="id7574f07095314ee8b691994163cbe156"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to the greatest extent possible, identify best available tools, models, or default values for embodied or lifecycle emissions in order to facilitate consistency and comparability across qualified carbon dioxide removal approaches with respect to—</text><clause id="id37b8bc7d010d4ec298b1f4d712019d02"><enum>(i)</enum><text>project-level greenhouse gas lifecycle analysis;</text></clause><clause id="id9c363418fa14408b9d821d05f575d9ef"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>project-level monitoring, reporting, and verification; and</text></clause><clause id="ide5e0ebd14e0345f0ba4cd2c11d240c42"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>determination of net carbon dioxide removal;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id702cf142e5f74c91b547433f556ac4ba"><enum>(B)</enum><text>include reporting and verification requirements which facilitate transparency and evaluation of the net carbon dioxide removal claimed by the taxpayer; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide0350b4bf2b64b6187f36a52aed62cb6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>take into account best practices and requirements from other carbon dioxide removal accounting programs in order to minimize inefficiencies and conflicting procedures.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idb56a477b6e594095bb8175c3b1de9745"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Lifecycle analysis</header><text>Under the proposed regulations, the project-level greenhouse gas lifecycle analysis shall—</text><subparagraph id="id13b39e0325804b78b14248ed13306b2a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>include all processes, activities, and greenhouse gas emissions associated with the capture, storage, and utilization of carbon dioxide equivalent, including—</text><clause id="id2cf6832f90de440a890161e3004c1f5e"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any mass and energy inputs and outputs from raw or processed materials, including biomass feedstock production, manufacture, processing, transport, storage, use, and disposal;</text></clause><clause id="id9f3758e597bc40d1ba7a689b1e652391"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>direct land use change, estimated indirect land use change, and other ecosystem perturbations that affect carbon uptake of forests; and</text></clause><clause id="id3fefcc3c84544f6cb41862b726c7b9aa"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>long-term retention of carbon dioxide;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf636c7f71a5444dc81bfdda220737ee5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>only exclude any process from such analysis if such process does not significantly change the outcome of such analysis, with such exclusion to be noted and justified;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id47c5f33d03d34ebcb795ded48ecc9e69"><enum>(C)</enum><text>calculate net carbon dioxide equivalent removal, including accounting for uncertainty associated with the estimate of net carbon dioxide removal and taking into account any estimated losses during carbon storage over a 100-year period; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9f56fbd5658a45fa979df19d9747e6e1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>be consistent with the Best Practices for Life Cycle Assessment of Biomass Carbon Removal and Storage Technologies issued by the Department of Energy on January 17, 2025.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id53fc095d02104468a0fdbad98856a117"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Monitoring, reporting, and verification</header><text>Under the proposed regulations, the project-level monitoring, reporting, and verification shall—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf82f2b78c7f5451abf64f9109536769c"><enum>(A)</enum><text>develop traceability requirements to verify the source and proportion of qualified forest residue biomass used in a project;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb5edb2ff09a448569df4061f35f70744"><enum>(B)</enum><text>utilize independent third-party verifiers and protocols for monitoring, reporting, and verification;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id25d8c420992d4d1d9bde5c4c7d1a2939"><enum>(C)</enum><text>quantify uncertainty associated with measurements and the resulting estimate of net carbon dioxide removal; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id54737ed5047442938d312780323cdf02"><enum>(D)</enum><text>include requirements for continued monitoring of the qualified project for a period determined by the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Energy and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, to be appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id97e00945fc10407e9cdd049a8b72899c"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Public comment requirement</header><text>Not later than 6 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Treasury shall publish in the Federal Register proposed regulations that include lifecycle analysis and monitoring, reporting, and verification requirements for the forest residue carbon removal and storage tax credit.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc79ec64e2af143d793c7f4fb3747f335"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Public comment period</header><subparagraph id="idc42d5771bce14b9c972725d76f4a60ae"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>The Secretary shall provide for a period of not less than 60 days after the date of publication of the proposed regulations during which the public may submit comments on the proposed regulations.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id055af7dec04a43f998d7040c2c02f171"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Consideration of comments</header><text>The Secretary shall consider all comments received during the public comment period before issuing final regulations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id4e6997b397714e1bb09667d89e4d7655"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Final regulations</header><text>The Secretary shall issue final regulations and establish lifecycle analysis and monitoring, reporting, and verification for the carbon removal tax credit established under this section not later than 90 days after the close of the public comment period, taking into account feedback from the public and stakeholders.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3d3c5b89148145eb9f8c98e7e174579d" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Consideration of revision</header><text>Every 5 years, the Secretary shall provide for a public comment period to consider whether the lifecycle analysis and monitoring, reporting, and verification requirements should be updated to reflect latest science. The Secretary shall consider all comments received during the public comment period before determining whether to update the regulations under the same procedures as used to issue the original requirements.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ide1ba82bc5786408ba9e5e6553d442bab"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Secure geological storage regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency and the Secretary of Energy, shall establish regulations for determining adequate security measures for the geological storage of qualified carbon dioxide equivalent in the form of injection of bio-liquids or bio-solids or engineered burial of biomass for purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/45BB">section 45BB</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 such that the qualified carbon dioxide equivalent does not escape into the atmosphere over a 1,000-year period.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


