<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-LYN25097-TR5-DP-J4X"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S523 IS: Protect Medicaid Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 523</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250211">February 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S373">Mr. Cassidy</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S317">Mr. Barrasso</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S318">Mr. Wicker</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S395">Mrs. Hyde-Smith</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to prohibit Federal Medicaid funding for the administrative costs of providing health benefits to individuals who are unauthorized immigrants.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protect Medicaid Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id1B61E5A1E2404DB88A2A8BF346E52CD2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibiting Federal Medicaid funding for the administrative costs of providing health benefits to individuals who are unauthorized immigrants</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1903(i) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396b">42 U.S.C. 1396b(i)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="id3CDFC103ADBA4C72924153B7EB5FE079"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (26), by striking <quote>; or</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id658E21513FBB413EB24D7099B1B51455"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (27), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5F109138E1DB49C1B75F6DB5F9E3EEF0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (27) the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="traditional" act-name="" id="idB8EDB39354CD4F89B8ECBA8E05EF7C5C"><paragraph id="id5C4FA91035E04376AA1F682661EDE326"><enum>(28)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to any amounts expended for the administration of a State program that provides health benefits to noncitizens who are ineligible for medical assistance under this title on the basis of not having a satisfactory immigration status (as defined in section 1137(d)(1)(B)(iii)) (except that such prohibition shall not be construed as prohibiting payment under the preceding provisions of this section for costs attributable to the establishment or operation of a system designed to ensure compliance with such prohibition).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="id05584B558A4748759C70433BF2BE6255"><enum>3.</enum><header>Inspector General report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Inspector General of the Department of Health and Human Services shall submit to Congress a report that includes the following information with respect to States that provide health benefits to noncitizens who are ineligible on the basis of immigration status for medical assistance under title XIX of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396">42 U.S.C. 1396 et seq.</external-xref>):</text><paragraph id="idE0C4ADCD8E5146008C8575F526072E3E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>How such States separate amounts expended on the administrative costs related to the State's Medicaid program and amounts expended on administrative costs related to providing health benefits to such noncitizens.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idE3A36DA6316E4525B1984EEC2EED554A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The types of procedures, protocols, or systems that such States employ to ensure that they are in full compliance with prohibitions on the use of Federal funding to provide health benefits to such noncitizens and how effective they are at ensuring compliance.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9D6CC84E3EE94F6A9902193E87794298"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A description of States' methods of financing State programs that provide health benefits to noncitizens who are ineligible for medical assistance due to not having a satisfactory immigration status, including through the increased use of provider taxes and intergovernmental transfers to finance the non-Federal share of expenditures under the State Medicaid program for medical assistance provided to individuals who are not so ineligible.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idBA850CC4096C489391EDB258B78F5B14"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An analysis of—</text><subparagraph id="id1B38961BEE2C4B72AC63C5E1D1FC1001"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the extent to which such noncitizens are provided covered outpatient drugs purchased under—</text><clause id="id3B8E8C1FB6D74C0A9BF2E87CD40983CA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Medicaid Drug Rebate Program under section 1927 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396r-8">42 U.S.C. 1396r–8</external-xref>); or</text></clause><clause id="idC66EAC94B36647B880EE499A19AE7719"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the drug discount program under section 340B of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/256b">42 U.S.C. 256b</external-xref>); and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idCF08B3968E2743958DA21A858B438BA7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the effect that the provision to such noncitizens of covered outpatient drugs purchased under the programs described in subparagraph (A) has on the average manufacturer price (as defined in section 1927(k)(1) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396r-8">42 U.S.C. 1396r–8(k)(1)</external-xref>)) of such drugs, including whether the average manufacturer price for such drugs would be lower if no drugs purchased under such programs were provided to such noncitizens.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

