<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4E58ECECED65431C9ECC6EAE1E7C2570" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 647 IH: Condemning remarks made by Representative Delia Ramirez of Illinois declaring her allegiance to the Republic of Guatemala before the United States of America.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
        <congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session display="yes">1st Session</session>
        <legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 647</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
        <action display="yes">
            <action-date date="20250812">August 12, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</sponsor> submitted the
                following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSO00">Committee on Ethics</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
        <official-title display="yes">Condemning remarks made by Representative Delia Ramirez of
            Illinois declaring her allegiance to the Republic of Guatemala before the United States
            of America.</official-title>
    </form>
    <preamble>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas Representative Delia Ramirez of Illinois declared <quote>I’m a proud Guatemalan before I’m an American</quote>;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas members of Congress are elected to represent constituents residing in their district in the United States of America, not foreign nations;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas Americans place their trust in elected members of Congress to represent their interests in the Federal Government;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas members of Congress take an oath to <quote>support and defend the Constitution of the United States of America against all enemies, foreign and domestic; that I will bear true faith and allegiance to the same</quote>; and</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas Representative Ramirez’s comments have cast doubt on whether she puts the interests of her constituents before those of the people of the Republic of Guatemala: Now, therefore, be it</text>
        </whereas>
    </preamble>
    <resolution-body style="traditional" id="H3F8B117B51C74C9DB570AD88FBF36D28">
        <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H1A4DB54AA5AB4C8187CCE072C8F8F56C">
 <text>That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="HF8F0A9A65FBD4A7E82794C5878FE4AB6"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>condemns the anti-American comments made by Representative Delia Ramirez of Illinois;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HB94918E76D454517A974345F75CE019E">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>affirms its allegiance to always put the interests of American citizens before those of other nations;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HB54F4F1948024CB89DEB8FE715816C47">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>condemns comments that put the interests of foreign nations above those of the United States; and</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H21E83F2D1CE74916AAF5AE062C87A98A">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>affirms its commitment to always put the safety, prosperity, and overall well-being of the American people first before those of other nations.</text>
            </paragraph>
        </section>
    </resolution-body>
</resolution>

