<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-BOM25571-SML-H9-WDP"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2696 IS: Foundation for Enabling Biotechnology Innovation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2696</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250903">September 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S391">Mr. Young</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To establish a Foundation for Enabling Biotechnology Innovation.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Foundation for Enabling Biotechnology Innovation Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id887cbdb424cc4f57a3b770479ebb4fbf"><enum>2.</enum><header>Foundation for Enabling Biotechnology Innovation</header><subsection id="id49530af7f728443e9332335dddc3d68b"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Director of the National Science Foundation shall establish a nonprofit foundation to be known as the <quote>Foundation for Enabling Biotechnology Innovation</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="id25bb861f23cb450bb542d3a6db71c83b"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Mission</header><text>The mission of the Foundation for Enabling Biotechnology Innovation (referred to in this Act as the <quote>Foundation</quote>) shall be to accelerate commercialization of biotechnology products in the United States by supporting and enhancing the capacity of Federal agencies and fostering collaboration across sectors.</text></subsection><subsection id="id3ecf2efb2b5e4c4ea1340983551716a4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Activities</header><text>In carrying out its mission under subsection (b), the Foundation may carry out the following:</text><paragraph id="id15f91a4a084c4fd79b4cb0efef3f036e"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Promote public-private partnerships that leverage expertise and resources across sectors to foster innovation and address challenges in commercialization of biotechnology products.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8357aa0cfd96424b9c09e77149912768"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Convene relevant stakeholders to develop expert recommendations on biotechnology commercialization, including horizon scanning for emerging technologies and regulation of novel products that may be commercialized in the future.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id68206c3bdec14b5b9ab236f84dee8010"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Advance collaboration and dialogue between Federal agencies that contribute to commercialization of biotechnology and relevant stakeholders, including industry, institutions of higher education, and nonprofit and philanthropic organizations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id069eae5e378448a190c8215e2d108e3d"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Support and conduct public engagement, education, and outreach activities about innovation, regulation, commercialization, and use of biotechnology products, including to evaluate efficacy of communication methods.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide962970ee5b24a1d80e686fba7524d79"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Facilitate market access for United States biotechnology products, including through international engagement, commercial and regulatory diplomacy, and development of shared norms and standards.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id05cc849ba30e4c8c8ce2c1026dd639af"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Support studies, projects, and research on topics such as market acceptance and regulatory process improvement, including through direct funding, grants, competitions, and other methods.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida39be539f80a41be8a0a02968f06be14"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Develop and implement education and fellowship programs, which may include—</text><subparagraph id="idad1b05d384bd421bb85a2fe0f375e877"><enum>(A)</enum><text>short courses on biotechnology product commercialization;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3d87bfb2ce7d4a48825399017fd17191"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shadowing experiences with relevant Federal agencies;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0f6bc93b723f482284afd9e32550cf9c"><enum>(C)</enum><text>capstone projects, in which participants develop ideas to advance biotechnology commercialization; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddc341a54686140219f7b4ba84d04485a"><enum>(D)</enum><text>support for participants such as stipends, travel, health insurance, professional development, and other appropriate expenditures as determined appropriate by the Foundation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ida423ab0611df44e0a3d8490740b1a088"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Provide direct support to Federal agencies for discrete or ongoing projects.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3b2c521403ab451c9e621d80b869d511"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Conduct other activities as determined necessary by the Foundation to carry out its mission.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idcdc337f1f3ea4bec9d745ec0f4a45c6c"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The Foundation shall not be an agency or instrumentality of the Federal Government and the Foundation shall not conduct any regulation of biotechnology products or any other products.</text></subsection><subsection id="id3d770583ca8d465da9c9944f753df26d"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Support</header><text>The Foundation may receive, administer, solicit, accept, and use funds, gifts, devises, or bequests, either absolutely or in trust of real or personal property or any income therefrom or other interest therein to support activities under subsection (c), except that this subsection shall not apply if any of such is from a foreign country of concern or a foreign entity of concern.</text></subsection><subsection id="id77191edc87c246dba831c7df21246ed6"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Tax exempt status</header><text>The Board of the Foundation for Enabling Biotechnology Innovation shall take all necessary and appropriate steps to ensure the Foundation is an organization described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, and exempt from taxation under section 501(a) of such Code.</text></subsection><subsection id="ida7c34869d20b40f88ff66c03ad9261c8"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Board of directors</header><paragraph id="id6a79c54e9b3c457f9a37c9c329f6594e"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Foundation for Enabling Biotechnology Innovation shall be governed by a Board of Directors (referred to in this section as the <quote>Board</quote>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida604e237db40490ca1c9a2a9c7ab52dd"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Composition</header><text>The Board shall be composed of the following:</text><subparagraph id="id700df423ffd04e37a29f55b24a98f15a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Not fewer than 5 voting members described in paragraph (4).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6da190d6734d4025921c15c17bf74fd8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Ex officio nonvoting members described in paragraph (5).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idb52259e18449479fb1990dfd678dc340"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Initial members</header><text>The Director of the National Science Foundation shall—</text><subparagraph id="id77b5929bf9a040fb8bf574318bdce1f5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>seek to enter into an agreement with the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine to develop a list of individuals to serve as members of the Board who are well-qualified and meet the requirements in paragraph (4); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id074d41e3b3d34bc283ae92879abc43ca"><enum>(B)</enum><text>appoint the initial members of the Board from such list not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idb25a0d7d0fee4da8857e0f734deee21d"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Voting members</header><subparagraph id="idc7398acf61844299adb7f2a42c79475d"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Representation</header><text>The voting members of the Board shall be drawn from a broad cross-section of stakeholders across sectors, regions, and communities, including from institutions of higher education, industry, and nonprofit and philanthropic organizations.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id847ab26a98064d7595dc0e5a61fdeae6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Experience</header><text>The voting members of the Board shall have the experience and qualifications to provide advice and information to advance the mission of the Foundation for Enabling Biotechnology Innovation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7dad3706f1964316831c4a344f57f1b8"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Federal employees</header><text>No employee of the Federal Government may be appointed as a voting member of the Board.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id0743d36905754cbca5ffd71bc424c38c"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Nonvoting members</header><subparagraph id="idde24c3de5c804bed9e2c2e8ac71b7976"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Ex officio members</header><text>The ex officio members of the Board shall be designated by—</text><clause id="ida79842b8decc47aea0e516ae3f7c3b31"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Director of the National Science Foundation;</text></clause><clause id="id23da979eb4884a52a86aeeabff78dfc5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Secretary of Defense;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd727ecb42e3e4643b718845baf7eab88"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary of Agriculture;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf67aad31877c43b38331f780886b6d10"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary of Health and Human Services;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb7d1f73ad10c4d0f958b92322232ee36"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency; and</text></clause><clause id="id5563db9ab34a4fff923b7b2c64ca0dfb"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the heads of other agencies, as agreed upon by the Board.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5ce0669483c547f39f76910359060b89"><enum>(B)</enum><header>No voting power</header><text>The ex officio members described in subparagraph (A) shall not have voting power on the Board.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id3800003816e94950ae09f3e4ffd72011"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Chair and vice chair</header><subparagraph id="id3aee337d82704de79b8c3b20dd86d4d3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Board shall designate, from among its voting members—</text><clause id="id5aacac74f2854068a67d72b37303b507"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an individual to serve as the Chair of the Board; and</text></clause><clause id="id35579cc9b78a4117857ae64b18d83f6a"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an individual to serve as the Vice Chair of the Board.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idee51e72e9109454486a40e4032398de2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Terms</header><text>The term of service of the Chair and Vice Chair of the Board shall end on the earlier of—</text><clause id="ida57602bf67ab40ffa0d76dda9c06e76c"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the date that is 3 years after the date on which the Chair or Vice Chair of the Board is designated for the respective position; or</text></clause><clause id="ide7a83314c2864b6992e936b8dd4572d0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the last day of the term of service of the member, as determined under paragraph (7), who is designated to be Chair or Vice Chair of the Board.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc5641ca3d4394db38ed3237c0f96bf46"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Representation</header><text>The Chair and Vice Chair of the Board may not be representatives of the same area of subject matter expertise or entity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide12ae18f84d44e478ad2dc0e89e6ddfe"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Terms and vacancies</header><subparagraph id="idda5b13322b8a4452be52f781bd157845"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Term limits</header><text>The term of office of each voting member of the Board shall be not more than 5 years, except that a member of the Board may continue to serve after the expiration of their term, if no new member is appointed to replace the departing Board member.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8c087e5bf4f54a62add42d739f17312a"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Initial members</header><text>Of the initial members of the Board appointed under paragraph (3), half of such members shall serve for 4 years and half of such members shall serve for 5 years, as determined by the Chair of the Board.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbaeb15eeb8a843c390bb7b76d8723767"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Vacancies</header><text>Any vacancy in the voting membership of the Board—</text><clause id="id025d986f576a4312aa0db4c2c3c03183"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall be filled in accordance with the bylaws of the Foundation by individuals who are well qualified and meet the requirements in paragraph (4);</text></clause><clause id="idf706536c42a8436abb0460ae1fee91d3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>shall not affect the power of the remaining members to carry out the duties of the Board; and</text></clause><clause id="id3d1e0e7cb91c4108994ff58f5826f24a"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>shall be filled by an individual selected by the Board.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc7f0b0d8f8bb40f79e8d92da3b35092b"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Renewal</header><text>Board members may be renewed for additional terms, as long as the individual continues to meet the requirements in paragraph (4).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id2f791956ba6d450fa64e8712b1136045"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Quorum</header><text>A majority of the voting members of the Board shall constitute a quorum for the purposes of conducting the business of the Board.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id91c261205f4f4d418f143745992578ac"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Board shall carry out the following:</text><subparagraph id="idf56835fe01f04c3398224a8cf9c2cacf"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Establish bylaws for the Foundation in accordance with paragraph (10).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id744ec729a49f4b81aec0cce658a670f8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Provide overall direction for the activities of the Foundation and establish priority activities.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idee35bc99c43b4cbcaa0fe5879ef96939"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Coordinate with the Director of the National Science Foundation regarding the activities of the Foundation for Enabling Biotechnology Innovation to ensure consistency with the programs and policies of the National Science Foundation and other Federal agencies.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4409a9c7c264452f9278db1d9dddd353"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Evaluate the performance of the Chief Executive Officer of the Foundation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id891d1f1b4dcb45289df5c0362e1eaffe"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Actively solicit and accept funds, gifts, grants, devises, or bequests of real or personal property to the Foundation, including from private entities.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7be7937b34e740fca151c60d8a00fcc8"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Carry out any other necessary activities of the Foundation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id57fff9d04e7c416dbd63fab0e42c0fe1"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Bylaws</header><text>The Board shall establish bylaws for the Foundation, ensuring that—</text><subparagraph id="id5cc0990d250b415abcd35b09c11ab036"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the bylaws of the Foundation shall include—</text><clause id="id46cad4017a2149df86ea34c264290d03"><enum>(i)</enum><text>policies for the selection of the Board members, officers, employees, agents, and contractors of the Foundation;</text></clause><clause id="ideeb43fd747f84751a8545ea13c804fe9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>policies, including ethical and disclosure standards, including—</text><subclause id="id0aba72e189524b279c0f83da4c950827"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the acceptance, solicitation, and disposition of donations and grants to the Foundation, including appropriate limits on the ability of donors to designate, by stipulation or restriction, the use or recipient of donated funds; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id8e68f7fe800744dfb54d0e41fbbee5a3"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the disposition of assets of the Foundation;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="idcdb1e8a8a620449fa884ea51c79b44ea"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>policies that subject all employees, fellows, trainees, and other agents of the Foundation (including appointed voting members and ex officio members of the Board) to conflict-of-interest standards; and</text></clause><clause id="id84773b28d02140049d949292621b9a5c"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the specific duties of the Chief Executive Officer of the Foundation; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb062cdc55f3348d78ee7f38af51d9475"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the bylaws of the Foundation and activities carried out under such bylaws do not—</text><clause id="id1f558ca9c39e47929dfb8d218127d58a"><enum>(i)</enum><text>reflect unfavorably upon the ability of the Foundation to carry out its responsibilities or official duties in a fair and objective manner; or</text></clause><clause id="id105f9dbe1c9b4659863d6ba3a34dca40"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>compromise, or appear to compromise, the integrity of any Federal Governmental agency or program, or any officer or employee employed by, or involved in a Federal Governmental agency or program.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ida6cbef46d2c54cf6b56e888783b931dd"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Compensation</header><subparagraph id="idbcae897612574941a32bf06e02b0ef2d"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Members of the Board may not receive compensation for serving on the Board.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id111bcc59a54b44c3b297a0551090ca48"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Certain expenses</header><text>In accordance with the bylaws of the Foundation, members of the Board may be reimbursed for travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence and other necessary expenses incurred in carrying out the duties of the Board.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id316e03e95798493b859d265dee1ea04e"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Personal liability</header><text>The members of the Board shall not be personally liable for carrying out the duties of the Board, except for malfeasance.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id73d18e1a72ad47889cfccbc9bbe12e78"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Administration</header><paragraph id="idf1e9ac3014074b77a33efc37ea2d321f"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Chief executive officer</header><subparagraph id="idd3ef92e20de94ba0a83d145e857dff8f"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Foundation shall have a Chief Executive Officer who shall be appointed by the Board, and who shall serve at the pleasure of the Board, and for whom the Board shall establish the rate of compensation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2d057905f50347cd83427f6fb45cb047"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>Subject to the bylaws established under subsection (g)(10), the Chief Executive Officer shall be responsible for—</text><clause id="id18bfc8709c9a46cdaf06091f04ac682a"><enum>(i)</enum><text>carrying out the activities of the Foundation under subsection (c);</text></clause><clause id="idc7cc0a788d704961aefdc73febde8a27"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>hiring, promoting, compensating, and discharging officers and employees of the Foundation and defining the duties of such officers and employees;</text></clause><clause id="idf266bc3092734e7492e0b81a3cb5a72d"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>accepting and administering donations to the Foundation and administering the assets of the Foundation;</text></clause><clause id="idc4b94eef39844ca69981d60c860bb6de"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>entering into contracts and executing legal instruments as appropriate in carrying out the activities of the Foundation; and</text></clause><clause id="id9a8ebc5881164c279b9cad22c7346f3c"><enum>(v)</enum><text>performing other functions as necessary to operate the Foundation.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id34181b0d15af40bda4ce461acf203eb5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Strategic plan</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the appointment of the Chief Executive Officer, the Foundation shall submit to the Director of the National Science Foundation, the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate, and the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives a strategic plan that contains the following:</text><subparagraph id="id966e5885e45d4910b0cda3f0195d2b15"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A plan for the Foundation to become financially self-sustaining not later than 5 years after the submission of the strategic plan, aside from regular appropriations.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id47382b3e13624b63aa54aa13f880fef8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Short- and long-term objectives of the Foundation, as identified by the Board.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id23b5e05e0a34453ebc676db2cd888b33"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The efforts the Foundation will take to be transparent in the processes of the Foundation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbfcae91051724e5e94ac34165c521805"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The financial goals and benchmarks of the Foundation for the 10 years following the submission of the strategic plan.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0850361302a1432db2bce979ac32a36a"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The efforts the Foundation will make to ensure maximum complementarity and minimum redundancy with Federal activities related to biotechnology commercialization.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idfcdf215220c64c56a3fb45658bc0d36d"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8cc33c5e7b64429aa2fd337e36ede149"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the appointment of the Chief Executive Officer, and not later than February 1 of each year thereafter, the Foundation shall publish a report describing the activities of the Foundation during the immediately preceding fiscal year that includes the accomplishments, operations, activities, and financial condition of the Foundation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idec7a15c846da47dca8e8d40a6a1ff08f"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Financial condition</header><text>Each such report shall include a comprehensive statement of all support provided to the Foundation, including funds, gifts, grants, devises, or bequests of real or personal property, and describing the amount of support from each person or entity, the persons or entities from which such support is received, and any restrictions on the purposes for which such support may be used.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id278d15da6b3c4620a8d54a0cfc1373a8"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>The Foundation shall make copies of each report submitted under this paragraph available—</text><clause id="id78180121c87e46939aee29c7aa849328"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to the Director of the National Science Foundation, the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate, and the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives; and</text></clause><clause id="id316873806ee0448ea59e5603a524325f"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for public inspection, and shall upon request, provide a copy of the report to any individual for a charge not to exceed the cost of providing such copy.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id0cd30546f6564f2bbf5064f9c2a64f84"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Audits and disclosure</header><text>The Foundation shall—</text><subparagraph id="idc7ce8fa1ec2c4a3cbcdd214ab8a6e091"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide for annual audits of the financial condition of the Foundation, including a full list of the Foundation’s donors and any restrictions on the purposes for which gifts to the Foundation may be used; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id77f1d840c3db48e7ab0963559222b90e"><enum>(B)</enum><text>make such audits, and all other records, documents, and other papers of the Foundation, available to the Director of the National Science Foundation and the Comptroller General of the United States for examination or audit.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id2f3fbbe35a3f475e9c45d59033b14c99"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Transfer of funds</header><text>The Foundation may transfer funds and property to Federal agencies that contribute to commercialization of biotechnology, which those agencies may accept and use to further the mission of the Foundation as described in subsection (b).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id73446ebe7269411990dbc6e8257981ce"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Integrity</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id45dc233d59a8444c949b7ad900a60d19"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To ensure integrity in the operations of the Foundation, the Board shall develop and enforce procedures relating to standards of conduct, financial disclosure statements, conflicts of interest (including recusal and waiver rules), audits, and any other matters determined appropriate by the Board.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida3125a52f6604d8a8448e5efc73d338f"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conflicts of interest</header><text>To mitigate conflicts of interest, any individual who is an officer, employee, or member of the Board is prohibited from any participation in deliberations by the Foundation of a matter that would directly or predictably affect any financial interest of any of the following:</text><subparagraph id="id6c240a07154c428ea8e5e384031e0f52"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Such individual.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4ecb895236354724ae8ea523c1b452a4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A relative of such individual.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8c9652b60e6a4148a0e2e9173241b0f9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A business organization or other entity in which such individual has an interest, including an organization or other entity with which such individual is negotiating employment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idb8b39618d429411fa4d82ac25c1212c0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Citizenship</header><text>To mitigate risks from malign foreign influence, any individual who is an officer, employee, or member of the Board shall be—</text><subparagraph id="idb5e8d503781247af870e3ca58c7db833"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a citizen or national (as defined in section 101 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)</external-xref>)) of the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida8edc4af38cc4bcfa8085d4825636bcc"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an alien admitted to the United States as a refugee under section 207 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1157">8 U.S.C. 1157</external-xref>); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddbfd5b65e5fe40eabf03146da35b5d1d"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence (as defined in section 101 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)</external-xref>)).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0a9ffc0e247d4e33bb687bbbfbe0cef3"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Intellectual property</header><text>The Board shall adopt written standards to govern the ownership and licensing of any intellectual property rights developed by the Foundation or derived from the collaborative efforts of the Foundation.</text></subsection><subsection id="id8e511fef32554256859eb20e8e11868f"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Full faith and credit</header><text>The United States shall not be liable for any debts, defaults, acts, or omissions of the Foundation. The full faith and credit of the United States shall not extend to any obligations of the Foundation.</text></subsection><subsection id="id85d2efc7db5947bd8d8d72bfd3694bf4"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Support services</header><text>The Director of the National Science Foundation may provide facilities, utilities, and support services to the Foundation.</text></subsection><subsection id="ide37870353b39459798717786c13ff6b2"> <enum>(m)</enum> <header>Non-Applicability</header> <text>Chapters 5 and 10 of title 5, United States Code, shall not apply to the Foundation.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id39ac67522abd451da68900ac63d0ae0e"><enum>(n)</enum><header>Separate fund accounts</header><text>The Board shall ensure that amounts received pursuant to the authorization of appropriations under subsection (o) are held in a separate account from any other funds received by the Foundation.</text></subsection><subsection id="id3cad05059fd849f994ef34f7f6ac9c7f"><enum>(o)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><paragraph id="idd0e3839dd48941c792fa1bee2d1b1b59"><enum>(1)</enum><header>National Science Foundation</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Director of the National Science Foundation $4,000,000 for fiscal year 2026, and every subsequent year to carry out this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8fcd27d6b9324d1f9c034fcd236b378d"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Foundation for enabling biotechnology innovation</header><text>From amounts appropriated to the National Science Foundation for each fiscal year, the Director of the National Science Foundation shall transfer not less than $4,000,000 per year to the Foundation.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idc1fda0df775641b6a0ef645af8ffd1a6"><enum>(p)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="id25dc0849f8834c28916d54cacde76905"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Board</header><text>The term <term>Board</term> means the Board of Directors of the Foundation, established pursuant to subsection (g).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id12a453fa3b13429488d82bba249f543a"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Foreign country of concern</header><text>The term <term>foreign country of concern</term> has the meaning given such term in section 10638 of the Research and Development, Competition, and Innovation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/19237">42 U.S.C. 19237</external-xref>; enacted as part of division B of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/167">Public Law 117–167</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id68a9ab72b0b8498abf1ab62d664dee39"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Foreign entity of concern</header><text>The term <term>foreign entity of concern</term> has the meaning given such term in section 10638 of the Research and Development, Competition, and Innovation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/19237">42 U.S.C. 19237</external-xref>; enacted as part of division B of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/167">Public Law 117–167</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id771bb1b3666940019d0a67bc5865a782"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Foundation</header><text>The term <term>Foundation</term> means the Foundation for Enabling Biotechnology Innovation established pursuant to subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbf7614380e9f443f98451e0b9783d491"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text>The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given such term in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfbcc334528994c8dbdeab0d31e9a4c6d"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Relative</header><text>The term <term>relative</term> has the meaning given such term in section 13101 of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

