<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC61278E5680542908678BB712316AF52" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 488 IH: Combating Cartels on Social Media Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 488</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250116">January 16, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001133">Mr. Ciscomani</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="H001085">Ms. Houlahan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Homeland Security and the Secretary of State to implement a strategy to combat the efforts of transnational criminal organizations to recruit individuals in the United States via social media platforms and other online services and assess their use of such platforms and services for illicit activities.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H709C9069F5A746CDA5ED8202DFDF445E" style="OLC"><section id="H2C216EEF53674F74B9680B1BE96D5E87" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Combating Cartels on Social Media Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H25D03F06ECAB4975B7A43AD1CEB3D586"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H676F6EC4C0AD4FC28F0B34FBFDA34E41"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="HB2534EDE70124FD7822B9C743B6F2E4B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs, the Committee on the Judiciary, and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3B7C12E75F00463BA1B9665F531EEF26"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Homeland Security, the Committee on the Judiciary, and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H01447A4850554FE394EEF74044D7AB8A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered operator</header><text>The term <term>covered operator</term> means the operator, developer, or publisher of a covered service.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H32647CF0EF704599A9D5354FF7431D3C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered service</header><text>The term <term>covered service</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H8E12C3EBF0D442E69F39A0F21E666D2C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a social media platform;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H081BB1D011CC40EEB75CB33E520CAF7E" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a mobile or desktop service with direct or group messaging capabilities, but not including text messaging services without other substantial social functionalities or electronic mail services, that the Secretary of Homeland Security determines is being or has been used by transnational criminal organizations in connection with matters described in section 3; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H08C947FD3DE6423FB101C332CFC095AF" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a digital platform, or an electronic application utilizing the digital platform, involving real-time interactive communication between multiple individuals, including multi-player gaming services and immersive technology platforms or applications, that the Secretary of Homeland Security determines is being or has been used by transnational criminal organizations in connection with matters described in section 3.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H10C7A6F1694B467AA10C328D1D8C464B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Criminal enterprise</header><text>The term <term>criminal enterprise</term> has the meaning given the term <term>continuing criminal enterprise</term> in section 408 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/848">21 U.S.C. 848</external-xref>). </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0FE99094A653407AA339BC6302FC1643"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Illicit activities</header><text>The term <term>illicit activities</term> means the following criminal activities that transcend national borders:</text><subparagraph id="H8E0E7211E24A43B6A74D1B127B5F4936"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A violation of section 401 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/841">21 U.S.C. 841</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6DA9045F6D9C4EEE847D8D5C01C29797"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Narcotics trafficking, as defined in section 808 of the Foreign Narcotics Kingpin Designation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/1907">21 U.S.C. 1907</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9C1663A5258D44DEA774D24D0BC5654A" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Weapons trafficking.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF1D6AD39617E44BE8D8F12772F3F9B74"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Migrant smuggling, defined as a violation of section 274(a)(1)(A)(ii) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1324">8 U.S.C. 1324(a)(1)(A)(ii)</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3609ACB8DC7D450EBE09BD7AE20B1E30"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Human trafficking, defined as—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H23B90704BFE0401097B13A700D718471"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a violation of section 1590, 1591, or 1592 of title 18, United States Code; or </text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC69136B22B4347168975998D8A9A00BA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">engaging in severe forms of trafficking in persons, as defined in section 103 of the Victims of Trafficking and Violence Protection Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7102">22 U.S.C. 7102</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H16D0D26896CE4E4E84180C680E6441D0"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Cyber crime, defined as a violation of section 1030 of title 18, United States Code.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H19DBCB5A89374C6AA2C602E583946786"><enum>(G)</enum><text>A violation of any provision that is subject to intellectual property enforcement, as defined in section 302 of the Prioritizing Resources and Organization for Intellectual Property Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/8112">15 U.S.C. 8112</external-xref>). </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1D0AFF6825944628882604E961526596"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Bulk cash smuggling of currency, defined as a violation of section 5332 of title 31, United States Code.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H22BC3D4B74764DC4A81531BFBDE9549B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Laundering the proceeds of the criminal activities described in subparagraphs (A) through (H). </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H48A0A247CA2B45678FAEDD482A958816" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Transnational criminal organization</header><text>The term <term>transnational criminal organization</term> means a group, or network, and associated individuals, that operate transnationally for the purposes of obtaining power, influence, or monetary or commercial gain, wholly or in part by certain unlawful means, while advancing their activities through a pattern of crime, corruption, or violence, and while protecting their unlawful activities through a transnational organizational structure and the exploitation of public corruption or transnational logistics, financial, or communication mechanisms. </text></paragraph></section><section id="H85C5853CB42D4F36A87D15BF087323E8" commented="no"><enum>3.</enum><header>Assessment of illicit usage</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Attorney General, and the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a joint assessment describing—</text><paragraph id="H0ED57E8FD5D7461B9AFEC4DCC0F677B4" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the use of covered services by transnational criminal organizations, or criminal enterprises acting on behalf of transnational criminal organizations, to engage in recruitment efforts, including the recruitment of individuals located in the United States, to engage in or provide support with respect to illicit activities occurring in the United States, Mexico, or otherwise in proximity to an international border of the United States; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEEE3480B631A42F19CC3D748274E95AA" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the use of covered services by transnational criminal organizations, or criminal enterprises acting on behalf of transnational criminal organizations, to engage in illicit activities or conduct in support of illicit activities, including—</text><subparagraph id="H29C84F61E1C945FB963838661A0F2469" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>smuggling or trafficking involving narcotics, other controlled substances, precursors thereof, or other items prohibited under the laws of the United States, Mexico, or another relevant jurisdiction, including firearms;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB76388BBD04B4472B7896995254A862A" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">human smuggling or trafficking, with a particular focus on the exploitation of children; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4B09D04C50704C25A0161F61B6C3AC20" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">transportation of bulk currency or monetary instruments in furtherance of smuggling or trafficking; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H78226CDF28FE431AA975D06FF60B8F4B" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the existing efforts of the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Attorney General, the Secretary of State, and relevant government and law enforcement entities to counter, monitor, or otherwise respond to the usage of covered services described in paragraphs (1) and (2). </text></paragraph></section><section id="H74BEF94762DD49F6AFE93424B39BDF47"><enum>4.</enum><header>Strategy to combat cartel recruitment on social media and online platforms</header><subsection id="HEF5C199BB7864D02BACF1040B14DF883" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Attorney General, and the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a joint strategy, to be known as the <quote>National Strategy to Combat Illicit Recruitment Activity by Transnational Criminal Organizations on Social Media and Online Platforms</quote>, to combat the use of covered services by transnational criminal organizations, or criminal enterprises acting on behalf of transnational criminal organizations, to recruit individuals located in the United States to engage in or provide support for illicit activities occurring in the United States, Mexico, or otherwise in proximity to an international border of the United States. </text></subsection><subsection id="HADDAB58E693547C7A80287490E8E1369"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><paragraph id="HD1EDC1A8C00E4332BA796A7591C15D06"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The strategy required under subsection (a) shall, at a minimum, include the following:</text><subparagraph id="H9A53732A46F14E5DBF9B45B818048F09" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A proposal to improve cooperation between the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Attorney General, the Secretary of State, and relevant government and law enforcement entities.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFDA801E0A672413EB2F554E4A26300C6" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Recommendations to implement a process for the voluntary reporting of information regarding the recruitment efforts of transnational criminal organizations, or criminal enterprises acting on behalf of transnational criminal organizations, in the United States involving covered services. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5CE3F397A56D4E2BA9F9EB7430897271"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A proposal to improve intragovernmental coordination with respect to the matters described in subsection (a), including between the Department of Homeland Security, the Department of Justice, the Department of State, and State, Tribal, and local governments.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H656481D40E844847A16B23C0E3F9C367"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A proposal to improve coordination within the Department of Homeland Security, the Department of Justice, and the Department of State and between the components of those Departments with respect to the matters described in subsection (a).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8F757E3A842B48CE928703F862EA3B32" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Activities to facilitate increased intelligence analysis for law enforcement purposes of efforts of transnational criminal organizations, or criminal enterprises acting on behalf of transnational criminal organizations, to utilize covered services for recruitment to engage in or provide support with respect to illicit activities.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H49974496062040D697FF18A89F25800E"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Activities to foster international partnerships and enhance collaboration with foreign governments and, as applicable, multilateral institutions, with respect to the matters described in subsection (a). </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H930A37D571E84C4C82A4E39169115E25" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Activities to specifically increase engagement and outreach with youth in border communities, including regarding the recruitment tactics of transnational criminal organizations, or criminal enterprises acting on behalf of transnational criminal organizations, and the consequences of participation in illicit activities.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H60ED79592E804DB2AEB7A2E5551DCE72"><enum>(H)</enum><text>A detailed description of the measures used to ensure—</text><clause id="H8DF0773D8FA248A0A7B67663EB1BC4C6" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">law enforcement and intelligence activities focus on the recruitment activities of transnational criminal organizations, or criminal enterprises acting on behalf of transnational criminal organizations, rather than individuals the transnational criminal organizations or enterprises, as the case may be, attempt to or successfully recruit; and</text></clause><clause id="H3571A09532ED413DB00C97F877129214"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the protection of privacy rights, civil rights, and civil liberties in carrying out the activities described in clause (i), with a particular focus on the protections in place to protect minors and constitutionally protected activities. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF95B6BDFB7A147B5A40FBD18FF6B214F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The strategy required under subsection (a) shall not include legislative recommendations or elements predicated on the passage of legislation that is not enacted as of the date on which the strategy is submitted under subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB5B10EBB61194A378343350797C25549" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In drafting and implementing the strategy required under subsection (a), the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Attorney General, and the Secretary of State shall, at a minimum, consult and engage with—</text><paragraph id="HD7020DE60D8A4F4BB8AE5D3C0812E482"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the heads of relevant components of the Department of Homeland Security, including—</text><subparagraph id="HB74D963FC5FE4B3F89309BBCDDF74D69"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Under Secretary for Intelligence and Analysis;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7D7388E89DC040F4A06CD064BB083F31"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Under Secretary for Strategy, Policy, and Plans;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2818A154D62E4323B612EC9AF554E675"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Under Secretary for Science and Technology;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1DF28B4A46DF4EDB90A1B003D97D7985"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H47137443D231465EBCA60C05198A5DE5"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the Director of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5BC8118C8684466486D23919B797A030"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the Officer for Civil Rights and Civil Liberties;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H32FB36711A2B477ABB6A3C0CE9E7C1E4"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the Privacy Officer; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4F20381D45D04AF9B53369E55BCD7879"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the Assistant Secretary of the Office for State and Local Law Enforcement;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1D1881ADC69F4B32B4EC4C2FABB16ABB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the heads of relevant components of the Department of Justice, including—</text><subparagraph id="HEEEFC99198BC4D2B83298D9C4CD1B934"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Assistant Attorney General for the Criminal Division;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1CC2FB15BA6E4073BEC49841A30F5474"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Assistant Attorney General for National Security;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8EF17C5FBD1847ADBBDCF043A93EB88A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Assistant Attorney General for the Civil Rights Division;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1C92A8EE6680458DA0859A48DBDACA38"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Chief Privacy and Civil Liberties Officer;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC4DCE7FFF90C45BE9C0AC6406963211C"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the Director of the Organized Crime Drug Enforcement Task Forces;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H742105DF96DD410A90C619D7855ADCDD"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA4BD31F7C6F046B4AF1434D3B7330618"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the Director of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives; </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEB53F89B3922457687720B2D425648F1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the heads of relevant components of the Department of State, including—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC021B2F8C9A34775B9D59A0B5FC2D26F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Assistant Secretary for International Narcotics and Law Enforcement Affairs;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H032B26DDF93446108925941B9E84BC86"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Assistant Secretary for Western Hemisphere Affairs; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBA4E9EE58ACC4CDB9B7705AE0998A36B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Coordinator of the Global Engagement Center;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB09B3C42F7DC4505B08104A9C7EC0482" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the Secretary of Health and Human Services;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA1B86717F2F942A6A73B40D20FC9832C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the Secretary of Education; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDB4DE70BCB514DA8AF8E7A32F6807571"><enum>(6)</enum><text>as selected by the Secretary of Homeland Security, or his or her designee in the Office of Public Engagement, representatives of border communities, including representatives of—</text><subparagraph id="HFB08BBF906674EE599FBF8EE19A81C87"><enum>(A)</enum><text>State, Tribal, and local governments, including school districts and local law enforcement; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1FCE22F24EDC48E6B10428397A2FA159"><enum>(B)</enum><text>nongovernmental experts in the fields of—</text><clause id="H633AF88B445440BFB5550D1E577B266E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>civil rights and civil liberties;</text></clause><clause id="H97F931DCB2E146E698A82135288E45EA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>online privacy;</text></clause><clause id="H059869BCD8B0404692D35AEFD666D411"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>humanitarian assistance for migrants; and</text></clause><clause id="H3E47B8BB49D740AABBD6F1557310F2C1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>youth outreach and rehabilitation.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF2802917BE6F41138D2A20F1A462D3BF"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Implementation</header><paragraph id="H76CC37C33A2C45DDB7A6812BD0A31CD5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date on which the strategy required under subsection (a) is submitted to the appropriate congressional committees, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Attorney General, and the Secretary of State shall commence implementation of the strategy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5C14CE5A8E714FC690DD17F2F5A11899"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><subparagraph id="HC94387875AE34336856554DEFCED1DB0" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date on which the strategy required under subsection (a) is implemented under paragraph (1), and semiannually thereafter for 5 years, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Attorney General, and the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a joint report describing the efforts of the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Attorney General, and the Secretary of State, respectively, to implement the strategy required under subsection (a) and the progress of those efforts, which shall include a description of—</text><clause id="H5A80DC2D35B9455282FD26D7D6B4F7FA" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the recommendations, and corresponding implementation of those recommendations, with respect to the matters described in subsection (b)(1)(B);</text></clause><clause id="H288375F7A4D943BC9385FA54B7D1787F" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the interagency posture with respect to the matters covered by the strategy required under subsection (a), which shall include a description of collaboration between the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Attorney General, the Secretary of State, other Federal entities, State, local, and Tribal entities, foreign governments and, as applicable, multilateral institutions,; and</text></clause><clause id="H570438BAE41F4A7F9B7D9B14FE6C8F9E" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the threat landscape, including new developments related to the recruitment efforts of transnational criminal organizations, or criminal enterprises acting on behalf of transnational criminal organizations, and the use by such organizations or enterprises, as the case may be, of new or emergent covered services and recruitment methods.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H85B0385A5C2C42E6B6F45A58F809399B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Form</header><text>Each report required under subparagraph (A) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may contain a classified annex.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0AC69C1E5DD6408FBFC581947A7CF347"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Civil rights, civil liberties, and privacy assessment</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date on which the strategy required under subsection (a) is implemented under paragraph (1), the Office for Civil Rights and Civil Liberties and the Privacy Office of the Department of Homeland Security, in consultation with the Assistant Attorney General for the Civil Rights Division and the Chief Privacy and Civil Liberties Officer of the Department of Justice, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a joint report that includes—</text><subparagraph id="HB7D1B6E950474E1AB3E3ECAEFA462576"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a detailed assessment of the measures used to ensure the protection of civil rights, civil liberties, and privacy rights in carrying out this section; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0838B150666D4681B22B66ACF8176C78"><enum>(B)</enum><text>recommendations to improve the implementation of the strategy required under subsection (a).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H71389438D83B420C8003261A41A8F9ED"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text>Prior to implementation of the strategy required under subsection (a) at the Department of Homeland Security, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall issue rules to carry out this section in accordance with section 553 of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H5985C0D7D8C240A38BB5E31BE6B66237"><enum>5.</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act may be construed to expand the statutory law enforcement or regulatory authority of the Department of Homeland Security, the Department of Justice, or the Department of State.</text></section><section id="H01536B1A9AF8460FB80F5B75325F80CC" commented="no"><enum>6.</enum><header>No additional funds</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No additional funds are authorized to be appropriated for the purpose of carrying out this Act.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

