<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-TAM25875-64S-7T-R93"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2507 IS: Defending Against Imitations and Replacements of Yogurt, milk, and cheese to Promote Regular Intake of Dairy Everyday Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code>II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2507</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250729">July 29, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S354">Ms. Baldwin</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S323">Mr. Risch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S252">Ms.
                    Collins</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S422">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S363">Mr.
                    King</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S418">Mr. Fetterman</cosponsor>,
                    <cosponsor name-id="S331">Mrs. Gillibrand</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S266">Mr. Crapo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S381">Mr. Rounds</cosponsor>,
                    <cosponsor name-id="S423">Mr. Ricketts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S411">Mr. Marshall</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S394">Ms. Smith</cosponsor>)
                introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the
                    <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and
                    Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require enforcement against misbranded milk
 alternatives.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H2CDE35E55CF345379FCC7083C7116C83"><section section-type="section-one" id="H2BDEF54657F2448597050BF1D8EFBAEB"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Defending Against Imitations and Replacements of Yogurt, milk, and cheese to Promote Regular Intake of Dairy Everyday Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>DAIRY PRIDE Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H9E2F7CAB840E4DC9927C0765B1762A58"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the purpose of this Act to establish that no food may be introduced or delivered for introduction into interstate commerce using a name for a standardized dairy product if the food does not meet the criterion set forth for dairy products under paragraph (z)(2) of section 403 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/343">21 U.S.C. 343</external-xref>) (as added by section 3(a)) or the requirements for imitation of another food under paragraph (c) of section 403 of such Act.</text></section><section id="H46ADBAFDF0F04D4B9867AF10EC46D89F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Enforcement of definition</header><subsection id="H860F378FCC314769A886F9632AE01D41"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 403 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/343">21 U.S.C. 343</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9C35728CA34B435999C94768E7EF351F"><subsection commented="no" id="H591594E7824C4917A323063782A3FDE7"><enum>(z)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H27330509847240F0862D48CA6442FB65"><enum>(1)</enum><text>If it uses the name for a standardized dairy product described in subparagraph (3) and the food does not meet—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf125be82c5574acd8d254a6dfcb63c24" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the criterion for being a dairy product, as described in subparagraph (2); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id215e7389912c4bcda4db0651bceb59b1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the requirements for imitation of another food under paragraph (c).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HC599DD9BEB994AC29BE0F85DC7253A1C" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>For purposes of this paragraph, a food is a dairy product only if the food is, contains as a primary ingredient, or is derived from, the lacteal secretion, practically free from colostrum, obtained by the complete milking of one or more hooved mammals.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H53E464583D8841528D4A917505544449" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A name for a standardized dairy product described in this subparagraph means the dairy product terms described in parts 131 and 133 of subchapter B of chapter I of title 21, Code of Federal Regulations, and sections 135.110, 135.115, and 135.140 of title 21, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulations), or any other term for which the Secretary has promulgated a standard of identity with respect to a food that is formulated with a dairy product (as described in subparagraph (2)) as the primary ingredient.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H720AA3DA5C894DE1B8332AD28F5F4C9F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Guidance</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idedb94708fa5d4da987b0b0600fd50984"><enum>(1)</enum><header>New guidance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Commissioner of Food and Drugs, shall—</text><subparagraph id="H2D206568E3CD43CB80A780455907A119"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, issue draft guidance on how enforcement of the amendment made by subsection (a) will be carried out; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4C69341C2AF94B7DB7F126C38EBA77C5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, issue final guidance on such enforcement.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4dabc4bbc4c340a6ba38a4fc882913b2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effect on certain previous guidance</header><text>Effective on the date of enactment of this Act, any guidance issued by the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Commissioner of Food and Drugs, that is not consistent with paragraph (z) of section 403 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/343">21 U.S.C. 343</external-xref>), as added by subsection (a), shall have no force or effect.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H197964627B834D258A2CE53196F13782"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Commissioner of Food and Drugs, shall report to Congress on enforcement actions taken under paragraph (z) of section 403 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/343">21 U.S.C. 343</external-xref>), as added by subsection (a), including warnings issued pursuant to such paragraph and penalties assessed under section 303 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/333">21 U.S.C. 333</external-xref>) with respect to such paragraph. If food that is misbranded under section 403(z) of such Act is offered for sale in interstate commerce at the time of such report, the Commissioner of Food and Drugs shall include in such report an updated plan for enforcement with respect to such food.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


