<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-NEW25864-7XY-SN-3LS"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 383 ATS: Commemorating the 80th anniversary of the conclusion of World War II with the surrender of Imperial Japan and honoring veterans of both the Pacific and European theaters.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 383</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250910">September 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S381">Mr. Rounds</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Commemorating the 80th anniversary of the conclusion of World War II with the surrender of Imperial Japan and honoring veterans of both the Pacific and European theaters.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, after the attack on Pearl Harbor by the Japanese on December 7, 1941, the United States declared war on Japan, and later declared war on Germany and Italy after their declarations of war on the United States, fully entering the United States into World War II and joining the Allies to fight the Axis Powers in a war in which over 16,300,000 citizens of the United States served in the military;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, during World War II, approximately 415,000 United States servicemembers were killed, another 670,000 were seriously wounded, and 130,000 were held as prisoners of war; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas September 2, 1945, marked the official end of World War II, with representatives of the Allied and Japanese governments signing the Instrument of Surrender, prepared by the Department of War and approved by President Harry S. Truman: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id89acdb3536914b07aeb1a1add880bec4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>honors all veterans, living and deceased, of the Pacific and European theaters of World War II on the 80th anniversary of the conclusion of World War II;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8fb0695c3c8b42e18c57003844f34846"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">expresses the deep appreciation and gratitude of the United States for the valor and selfless service of the veterans of World War II;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1ba53ef8a2494c3ba7e0890c60bd731b"><enum>(3)</enum><text>calls on the people of the United States to commemorate the 80th anniversary of the signing of the Instrument of Surrender aboard the USS Missouri (BB–63) on September 2, 1945, as a day of appreciation for the members of the <quote>Greatest Generation</quote> who, through their sacrifices both in the Armed Forces and on the home front, preserved liberty for future generations;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0c6a7ac273eb4ffbbcd3759472a79e98"><enum>(4)</enum><text>mourns the more than 200,000 people, including more than 12,000 United States servicemembers and up to 150,000 Japanese civilians, who died from April 1 to June 22, 1945, in the Battle of Okinawa, which was the only land battle on the home islands of Japan and the costliest ground combat of the Asia-Pacific War, and which led President Harry S. Truman to re-examine the costs of invading mainland Japan;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5111af2be2b34c8ca631dfad68589bf1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>reaffirms the Treaty of Peace with Japan, done at San Francisco September 8, 1951 (commonly known as the <quote>Treaty of San Francisco</quote>), which formally ended the <quote>state of war</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb157ffd70aaa4213b0cc0b42825c70da"><enum>(6)</enum><text>recognizes the alliances and partnerships formed in the Indo-Pacific region following World War II, including those with Japan, Australia, the Philippines, Singapore, the Republic of Korea, and Thailand, as well as critical defense sites developed on Okinawa, Guam, Wake Island, the Northern Mariana Islands, the Republic of the Marshall Islands, the Federated States of Micronesia, the Republic of Palau, and elsewhere, have contributed immeasurably to the continued peace and prosperity enjoyed throughout the Indo-Pacific region.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

