<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-BUR25393-R26-0G-CG7"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1583 IS: AUSSOM Funding Restriction Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1583</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250501">May 1, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S323">Mr. Risch</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S355">Mr. Cruz</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S404">Mr. Scott of Florida</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To restrict the use of United States Assessed Contributions to the United Nations under United Nations Security Council Resolution 2719 (2023) to support the African Union’s peacekeeping mission in Somalia.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>AUSSOM Funding Restriction Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id9699484a2aac4135a60c4ad33ac4de10"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="id0a43f63dc093467082b950b5c1570c39"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf980ed3b9fbf4324b4d3547f1c34b17d"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2804d98b0328468a8586dfc59da01929"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="iddb16ee5b73974a80b0583ac23198b1dd"><enum>(2)</enum><header>AUSSOM</header><text>The term <term>AUSSOM</term> means the African Union Support and Stabilisation Mission in Somalia, established as the successor mission to the African Union Transition Mission in Somalia under United Nations Security Council Resolution 2767 (2024). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9c00e56108cc4820aa7ff67275d84e2a" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Resolution 2719</header><text>The term <term>Resolution 2719</term> means United Nations Security Council Resolution 2719, adopted on December 21, 2023. </text></paragraph></section><section id="id0f96c4a88b4e4d94a88ea0fad3b2a8fc"><enum>3.</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the policy of the United States—</text><paragraph id="id5bba46548e7647a0aab3bc90eb53f1c7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to support Somali- and African partner-led initiatives—</text><subparagraph id="id2fc0cd3ca4e74148910ce88d8584ed63"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to contain and defeat al-Shabaab and ISIS-Somalia;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id68ad2d7bfb6a42cb8b966ad1ceacdafd"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to foster peace, security, stability, and economic development within Somalia; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idec72920d5abb453d8d19c42cee0c24bb"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to support the development of functional Somali state institutions at the national and federal member state level;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id6babdb5312ae44d09a876f468eec9def"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to ensure appropriate and fair burden sharing at the United Nations, including for United Nations peacekeeping missions and United Nations support to African Union peace support operations;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id438f3e4f931a43bea66599ca17399273"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to uphold the conditions set forth in Resolution 2719 for the application of United Nations assessed contributions to African Union peace support operations on a case-by-case basis, including conditions that require—</text><subparagraph id="id7b5179af945442e3839e66956f889e5e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that funding from assessed contributions cannot exceed 75 percent of the annual budget of an African Union peace support operation under a <quote>one mission, one budget</quote> model, with the remaining 25 percent mobilized by the African Union and United Nations <quote>from the international community as extra-budgetary resources</quote>; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idea19f27bcb5e4cc39fc9922a6ee727ff"><enum>(B)</enum><text>compliance with—</text><clause id="id3b5763f172aa4203a6638cd16bc40500"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Human Rights Due Diligence Policy on United Nations support to non-United Nations security forces;</text></clause><clause id="id3cff3ad7e94b47f28265e7d2e21d8809"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the African Union Compliance Framework on International Human Rights Law;</text></clause><clause id="idb98f6e76ded944c48b5a888308a0d6d5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the African Union Policy on Conduct and Discipline for Peace Support Operations; and</text></clause><clause id="id4f18bd977c3c4854a41a245eeb5be751"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the African Union Policy on Prevention and Response to Sexual Exploitation and Abuse;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfaf438006843412b94e0a45cd20c4484"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the prioritization of protection of civilians; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id87330f9a8f2e400a889fcd94cf56c7ab"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the existence and application of appropriate accountability mechanisms of African Union-led peace support operations to member states of the United Nations;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idc1fd88d7b7294748b34371770beea042"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to judiciously consider United States support for the application of United Nations assessed contributions to African Union peace support operations, including the selection of an appropriate first application of Resolution 2719 that—</text><subparagraph id="id6320e3ffe3d440b58fddf37db71f96bf"><enum>(A)</enum><text>responds to a new crisis or threat with the demonstrable need for a multi-lateral response led by the African Union; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0aa01a9cfa60481ca053c0e576b07e0c"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has clear and achievable objectives; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id4f056fb6cca24035a8448f590be4a8bd"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to encourage the exploration and utilization of alternative funding mechanisms for AUSSOM that do not rely on United Nations assessed contributions to diversify AUSSOM’s financial burden and promote international responsibility-sharing.</text></paragraph></section><section id="id2e49eef854754999aa9295e771b82221"><enum>4.</enum><header>Restriction on funding</header><subsection id="id181a6564bbeb4ab0b8bfa46f29140597"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>None of the funds appropriated or otherwise made available for assessed contributions of the United States to the United Nations, including any organ, agency, or entity of the United Nations, may be obligated or expended for—</text><paragraph id="id8718f7c750e449458f837329d2e6a1ab"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any activity related to the implementation of Resolution 2719 in support of AUSSOM or any other African Union-led peace support mission in Somalia; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3f4ef7d6e5794156939957f02605e296"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any program, project, or initiative for Somalia directly linked to the mandate outlined in Resolution 2719.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idf5288030cedb41ffb8f6361657d824f3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Direction to United States Ambassador to the United Nations</header><text>The United States Ambassador to the United Nations, or their designee shall use the voice, vote, and influence of the United States at the United Nations— </text><paragraph id="id49937574bec640eea88e6f376f38b8ce"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to oppose any United Nations Security Council resolution that would authorize funding prohibited under subsection (a); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idffa17d04f9ca44958e7bd6984d30ec61"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to decline to join in consensus on any United Nations Security Council product, including letters from the United Nations Security Council President, that authorizes funding prohibited under subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id2be4bfa3752e484eb6e81f0043ed451f"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>This restriction under subsection (a) shall not apply to—</text><paragraph id="id859f43859efa47f6bd73628cfb1356a3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the use of United Nations assessed contributions to fund the United Nations Support Office in Somalia (UNSOS) as approved by the United Nations Security Council;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9b7d662e4ee447a89f4787bc425adc6e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the use of voluntary contributions of the United States to the United Nations or funds expressly appropriated by Congress to support AUSSOM;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idceb5b7f7f39b4137b890b4b3adf4f674"><enum>(3)</enum><text>humanitarian assistance funded with United Nations assessed or voluntary contributions delivered through nongovernmental organizations or United Nations agencies that operate independently of AUSSOM; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idcd03e5447d1a477fb2796e874910eb2d"><enum>(4)</enum><text>expenditures for salaries of United States personnel, administrative costs, or other support services directly associated with the oversight or monitoring of assessed contributions of the United States to the United Nations to ensure compliance with this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idad7196d62cfb44cfb1626408a2eb453f"><enum>5.</enum><header>Annual assessment</header><subsection id="id31c93fca53794e8784daa03258a7e976"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Secretary of State shall conduct an annual assessment of the African Union’s ability to meet the terms and conditions outlined in Resolution 2719 paragraphs 3 to 13 for African Union-led peace support operations to receive United Nations Security Council authorization to have access to United Nations assessed contributions.</text></subsection><subsection id="idab146ce2c0ce49d7a2b5363d6166929e"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Independent assessment</header><text>The assessment required under subsection (a) shall be conducted independently of any assessment of the same conducted by the United Nations Secretary General and reported to the United Nations Security Council under paragraphs 15 and 16 of Resolution 2719.</text></subsection></section><section id="id6077efab432642bc8836fee923a24236"><enum>6.</enum><header>Reporting requirement</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that includes—</text><paragraph id="id991556c00544494a90ccef8efc8cb610"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the findings of the assessment required under section 5;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida8009f8bb36e44ec809212ef59d04a4e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the total assessed contributions of the United States to the United Nations for peacekeeping;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1db8a8308b144f4bbdc41b1d606081f7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the allocations and expenditures for assessed contributions to the United Nations under Resolution 2719;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd4e1f2c2638e42aaa38bbbf36a0d39b5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>an assessment of how United Nations assessed contributions are being used to implement Resolution 2719;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id87dc7748abe24765853fbd626f337460"><enum>(5)</enum><text>an analysis of the performance and effectiveness of AUSSOM, including the types and impact of United States support to Somalia directly or indirectly impacting the mission and objectives of AUSSOM;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd0094034b786492f964fd79a6dc10afc"><enum>(6)</enum><text>a breakdown of financial and other support for AUSSOM provided by the United Nations, African Union, European Union, and other international and regional actors, including both bilateral and multilateral contributions;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idad8a796fe63e417591e85cdb37e7e7e7"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the status of and progress made toward finding alternative funding mechanisms for AUSSOM; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9071c9c246bb4ccab96802a12844fbc4"><enum>(8)</enum><text>a description of measures taken to ensure compliance with section 4. </text></paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf3f8c08c3cfc40f2aaa01e624e37232d"><enum>7.</enum><header>Consultations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 4(d)(2) of the United Nations Participation Act of 1945 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/287b">22 U.S.C. 287b(d)(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida33cca8a9983436184a0e3335962699a"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6f485363837b41838d69c47ab00b2ed7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the matter preceding clause (i), by inserting <quote>and African Union peace support operations receiving United Nations assessed contributions under United Nations Security Council Resolution 2719 (2023)(referred to in this paragraph as <term>Resolution 2719</term>)</quote> after <quote>peacekeeping operations</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9fce911cefec4172beceebcd53d228e3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in clause (i), by inserting <quote>or African Union peace support operation receiving United Nations assessed contributions under Resolution 2719</quote> after <quote>peacekeeping operation</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb4fced2fff6745a1979d7567a08b1476"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc3c43b71d13c4c17bd7716f627c3b82b"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the matter preceding clause (i), by inserting <quote>and African Union peace support operation receiving United Nations assessed contributions under Resolution 2719</quote> after <quote>peacekeeping operation</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9de96d487ce14d24b313fe854b1652dd"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in clause (v), by inserting <quote>or African Union peace support operation receiving United Nations assessed contributions under Resolution 2719, as the case may be</quote> after <quote>peacekeeping operation</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

