<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-FLO25775-DSC-52-WS9"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2708 IS: Appalachian Trail Centennial Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2708</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250904">September 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S384">Mr. Tillis</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To enhance the preservation, maintenance, and management of national historic trails and national scenic trails, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Appalachian Trail Centennial Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id0eb3dffa50d3468bbb7205a28540b87e"><enum>2.</enum><header>Congressional declaration of policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress declares that—</text><paragraph id="idad74990850e94131b8749e411e37e6ad"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the large landscape conservation work relating to national historic trails and national scenic trails is built on partnership, collaboration, and community engagement;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id64c86af39029448a863fc8d9ec697955"><enum>(2)</enum><text>national historic trails and national scenic trails—</text><subparagraph id="id4eaefed6267d48df87a7c0dfc7f51a61"><enum>(A)</enum><text>are landscape conservation tools; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id710c207601194963ba5961e153437b12"><enum>(B)</enum><text>are federally designated areas, but may include portions of non-Federal land under the National Trails System Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1241">16 U.S.C. 1241 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id83592448cb7c46efbde1a41fd8d1666a"><enum>(3)</enum><text>national historic trails and national scenic trails are intended to be developed and preserved over time, collaboratively and cooperatively, to further the purposes of the National Trails System Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1241">16 U.S.C. 1241 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2d3ce8fe37514727a5fbd7bd3e3227ae"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the Appalachian National Scenic Trail, 1 of the first 2 components of the National Trails System—</text><subparagraph id="idfe72a5f8f6ce43ef995a960a0d2da0c8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is a realm of natural, scenic, historical, and cultural wonder available to all; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idff3e6bc9495a40df9a82b71f184b57c0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is a model for cooperative management and public-private partnership;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id85eafb8366754a5db9f8ff63ae0bcd03"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the centennial of the Appalachian Trail Conservancy in 2025 is an opportunity to strengthen the precepts of the cooperative management model—</text><subparagraph id="ide25822cf40a44429ab18879573bedd48"><enum>(A)</enum><text>pioneered on the Appalachian National Scenic Trail; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd6fdfbe86c7b41c7b195d7c9c549e77a"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to be replicated as appropriate throughout the National Trails System;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id877eb4da0a024ab7afb446692084f525"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the development of the Appalachian National Scenic Trail is in large part due to the efforts of volunteer organizations (commonly referred to as <quote>Appalachian Trail Maintaining Clubs</quote>) that—</text><subparagraph id="id2f5fcffa96a1411aaad0a747d4e5b84f"><enum>(A)</enum><text>directly or through subdivisions or subsidiary organizations, have coordinated the participation of tens of thousands of volunteers for the planning, construction, development, maintenance, operation, and stewardship of the Appalachian National Scenic Trail, which inspired the establishment of the National Trails System; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id866bfdf3c3134795a202fcd878737536"><enum>(B)</enum><text>are the expert, dispersed corps of volunteers who provide much of the day-to-day cooperative operation of the Appalachian National Scenic Trail;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id4209b88f20ce4ac98fffb5560725647e"><enum>(7)</enum><text>there are inherently governmental functions referred to in the National Trails System Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1241">16 U.S.C. 1241 et seq.</external-xref>) relating to the administration of national historic trails and national scenic trails, which is distinct from the management and operation of those trails;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5f5c5cf48b534d95bf2fcb61ddff524a"><enum>(8)</enum><text>the Federal Government is responsible for—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0a9020e9ee4a4b68b972a30490d613f1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the administration of national historic trails and national scenic trails; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id292778dca79f44d7915ee07615b2547a"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in cases in which the United States is the landowner, the management of national historic trails and national scenic trails;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd00b74e6ae8b487198184347068f91b5"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">volunteers, volunteer organizations, and other cooperating individuals or entities are empowered to undertake non-inherently governmental and delegable roles in the management and operation of national historic trails and national scenic trails;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id00c0c4a89806431bbd04c39cb3daaba1"><enum>(10)</enum><text>the operation of a national historic trail or national scenic trail does not require land management authority over the land on which the national historic trail or national scenic trail is located; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf60869a63f3b4023a6e8e370ca3f4cb8"><enum>(11)</enum><text>it is the policy of the Federal Government that national historic trails and national scenic trails—</text><subparagraph id="idbc5e4373227b409db4d42222af13de35"><enum>(A)</enum><text>are conservation units managed and operated in partnership with governmental and nongovernmental entities; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idaf8328b9d3fe414a8c762af7fb5dba46"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>while administered by Federal agencies, are intended to be cooperatively developed with appropriate non-Federal Governmental and nongovernmental partners.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="id264dae582f9446caaf71c55b0382599f"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="id7ed98a028de04f6680c40c6c32a78ab1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>The term <term>administration</term>, with respect to a covered trail, means the roles and responsibilities of the Secretary concerned with respect to the covered trail that may not be shared with any other individual or entity.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8e23e20163dd43f48f5d59c6be66a553"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Comprehensive plan</header><text>The term <term>comprehensive plan</term> means a comprehensive plan for a covered trail submitted under subsection (e) or (f) of section 5 of the National Trails System Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1244">16 U.S.C. 1244</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddc7a582a05364274aaec6e6e937fdcb2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Cooperative management</header><text>The term <term>cooperative management</term>, with respect to a covered trail, means the negotiated division of roles and responsibilities relating to the stewardship and development of the covered trail that are—</text><subparagraph id="idf5ecb92d1f9e466394674323b5fc6445"><enum>(A)</enum><text>permissible under law; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6b50dd491b414c0980e2fd99e108363f"><enum>(B)</enum><text>within the categories of—</text><clause id="id34e9dd61f23346febb8ee1effaa24dd3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>administration;</text></clause><clause id="idf6079dc7709b41ddb881a76d418e50b6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>management; and</text></clause><clause id="idb4a378ccbf2c44f49738ad3eab755bbe"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>operation.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id787e46982d0848cc8ee32a3c9c294b81"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Cooperative management system</header><text>The term <term>cooperative management system</term>, with respect to a covered trail, means the negotiated management structure for cooperative management of the covered trail, including—</text><subparagraph id="id38cf0ddc18764148a9081a86f23d14a7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Federal and State trust resource managers;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id91c561e1416e45738058279ad0e41e8e"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Tribal governments;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5d9076ab37ef4dd69ad600d002724ee1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>nongovernmental organizations; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id33123d8c52574cae8d33c390a468573b"><enum>(D)</enum><text>volunteers organized by entities described in subparagraphs (A) through (C).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id93303e2e6c504576b1788f811bb5b22e"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Covered trail</header><text>The term <term>covered trail</term> means a national historic trail or national scenic trail designated by section 5(a) of the National Trails System Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1244">16 U.S.C. 1244(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd273baba00524b0ba63a4b9788ff59fe"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Designated operational partner</header><text>The term <term>Designated Operational Partner</term>, with respect to a covered trail, means the 1 or more entities designated for the covered trail under subparagraph (A) or (B) of section 4(b)(1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide25ff7d8b7624527a959aeb8f38b097d"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Gateway community</header><text>The term <term>gateway community</term> means a municipality or unincorporated settlement in the vicinity of a covered trail.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb698dedeaef9409ca716d7e1482eb123"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Management</header><text>The term <term>management</term>, with respect to a covered trail, means the roles and responsibilities under applicable law of the owner of the land, or any interest in land, on which the covered trail is located with respect to the covered trail.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6f8bfbfe58b5472493d313c7962e338d"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Operation</header><subparagraph id="id61d51142904e4b0f9f85ff8003eb7aa7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>operation</term>, with respect to a covered trail, means any activity permissible under law that—</text><clause id="idaa7b941ff33a4f67a6a6530daa92261e"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is carried out pursuant to a cooperative agreement on land on which the covered trail is located;</text></clause><clause id="id90bdae8f9afd4837833de881218239fe"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is not an activity of administration; and</text></clause><clause id="idf470ded50f744383891ec9dbbe7b7af6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>does not infringe on any management or ownership authority of the applicable land manager, if the land manager is not the individual or entity carrying out the activity.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide09e59fc7fa14ada9dfa4f01680a4baa"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text>The term <term>operation</term> includes—</text><clause id="idd2a30b0277e3493396fa2db7c1704893"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the identification and acquisition of land for a covered trail;</text></clause><clause id="id6e2f5582d58646aa81dba30e28f9f1a6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the planning, construction, and maintenance of a facility or other improvement on, across, or along a covered trail;</text></clause><clause id="id536e2e69f5b04852bdcc3dd28e686914"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the provision of services for a covered trail;</text></clause><clause id="idb80b55dc7882467eb0bb7bd431f90cef"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the conceptual development of a covered trail;</text></clause><clause id="id14981ba17f4843609c5beeb91bc9fe1b"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the maintenance of the treadway of a covered trail;</text></clause><clause id="id83ca853ec95e4d1f93e07eaf1b8b2fef"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>conducting a research project relating to a covered trail;</text></clause><clause id="id193d5fc3a571447ca916b1f29b2540ae"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>the provision to volunteers of education and training relating to methods of planning for, construction of, and maintenance of a covered trail; and</text></clause><clause id="idf409ba39036347dbb534a45f8420e646"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>the conservation of natural, cultural, or other resources associated with a covered trail.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idec1dfdb6eb76477d8fcce60473dd2e42"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Proposed priority list</header><text>The term <term>proposed priority list</term> means a proposed priority list for a covered trail developed under section 4(b)(3).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9ace2c1ecbe4417fb1843b275908fb37"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id51e5e69acc7c42c4a07f7230f288b0fe"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Secretary concerned</header><text>The term <term>Secretary concerned</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="id9e1a40fc409f4cabbd5afa5533e0561a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary, with respect to a covered trail administered by the Secretary; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfc607ddaa0b747a698aabc24eb70bc7e"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary of Agriculture, with respect to a covered trail administered by the Secretary of Agriculture.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf88701d9ef5746beb175c36fd5ea2514"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Visitor capacity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>visitor capacity</term> means, with respect to a covered trail, the maximum number and types of visitor use that the covered trail can accommodate while achieving and maintaining the desired resource conditions and visitor experiences that are consistent with the purposes for which the covered trail was established, which may vary for different segments of a covered trail.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc6d4152a59dc4b4f87417b3905321aad"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Volunteer organization</header><text>The term <term>volunteer organization</term> means any organization providing operation or management support to a covered trail administrator or land manager, including by organizing volunteers.</text></paragraph></section><section id="id81efd59f12944260bd511b8180bffbaf"><enum>4.</enum><header>Strengthening administration, management, and operation for national historic trails and national scenic trails</header><subsection id="id3b9a9338672a4080a474ed5d7d65dad4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Status</header><text>Each covered trail shall be—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcef86546e5db4e5a84ff21e1658dbca6"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a unit of the National Trails System; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3d6a0a63612f4d6b81283711557ef0c8"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a unit of the federally administered area to which the Secretary concerned assigns the covered trail.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idbfb05c73f0054c6ebe1793591d9e5594"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Operation</header><paragraph id="id14ba160fbd3c40a599ce7db20d0304e7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Designated Operational Partners</header><subparagraph id="id99067de402634b4c81452401f3d1b9cf"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Appalachian trail conservancy</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary concerned shall designate the Appalachian Trail Conservancy as the Designated Operational Partner for the Appalachian National Scenic Trail.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc572791a0b784749bd7a5ca1fe21be5c"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Additional designations</header><clause id="id2851342654ae4f79bd0ce3de084ad506"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In addition to the designation under subparagraph (A), the Secretary concerned may designate to serve as the Designated Operational Partner for any other covered trail 1 or more eligible entities described in clause (ii) that the Secretary concerned determines—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id546853bae62242a6b28e0761d1167fe6"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are capable of supporting the partnership nature of the covered trail as a mechanism for conservation, volunteer mobilization, and land and facility management; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfb40ef33bf344dc9a06abf41e66797e3"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">would be successful partners for the applicable covered trail.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id48d79ef295b74233a6398a61cc72e281"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Description of eligible entities</header><text>An eligible entity referred to in clause (i) is an organization, institution, corporation, or other entity that, as determined by the Secretary concerned—</text><subclause id="id6e3fdce3208644e4915807247c3432b2"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and exempt from tax under section 501(a) of that Code;</text></subclause><subclause id="idc4d7bd5b502d4d3ebf5cf28a35dbfcab"><enum>(II)</enum><text>has demonstrated experience in the operation, maintenance, and preservation of the resources of the covered trail, regardless of whether the experience was before or after the designation of the covered trail under the National Trails System Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1241">16 U.S.C. 1241 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></subclause><subclause id="idc8c176bcb81e4e06890d3a07d81415d1"><enum>(III)</enum><text>has a plan for providing, facilitating, and coordinating the services of volunteers to contribute to the stewardship of the covered trail;</text></subclause><subclause id="ideed22d5668d442d8b783f5a0632f26e7"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>has a record, including through a predecessor organization, of engagement with the establishment, management, maintenance, or operation of the covered trail;</text></subclause><subclause id="ide5dbdef345e84968aee072ccea851691"><enum>(V)</enum><text>adheres to reasonable financial, accounting, and risk management practices;</text></subclause><subclause id="id3a96e969d14a4b5582884936ea49bc28"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>adheres to applicable requirements of Federal agreements, grants, and contracts; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id1baa66df7c6a4f4fa8b778b49bcd5d82"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>would not supplant an organization already serving a substantial operational role trail-wide for the covered trail or across a significant portion of the covered trail, unless the Secretary concerned has determined that the organization being supplanted has failed to perform the responsibilities of the organization under a management agreement with respect to the covered trail.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id4a840dfbd59a4644a8c71e83ffa6b437"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Qualifications</header><subclause id="idbec5f9a8867d4a0c96af5eb98d89199e"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An eligible entity designated as a Designated Operational Partner under clause (i) shall be considered to possesses unique expertise, location capacity, cost-sharing ability, or other unique qualities relevant to the designation as a Designated Operational Partner for the covered trail.</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3895a81153bb4d4bba5566f05a1e6aaa"><enum>(II)</enum><header>No competitive process</header><text>An eligible entity designated as a Designated Operational Partner under clause (i) may be a direct beneficiary or recipient of appropriated funds without competition.</text></subclause><subclause id="id8116538046194e1fbdbc0a107e0e3874"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Present-funded activity</header><text>Designation of a Designated Operational Partner for a covered trail shall be considered to be a continuation or completion of a present-funded activity.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id952d07a1fc024b249d95952db80219e6"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Rescission</header><text>The Secretary concerned may rescind the designation of an eligible entity as a Designated Operational Partner under subparagraph (B) if the Secretary concerned determines that the eligible entity has ceased to meet 1 or more of the criteria described in clause (ii) of that subparagraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id02bcbd22c94a4c319a7b49c1043d609d"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Protection of Property Rights</header><subparagraph id="idff3cfd3e47c147139f268592892fda37"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the Designated Operational Partner for a covered trail becomes aware of an allegation of trespass or other infringement or violation of a property right held by the Federal Government that adversely affects the identified cultural, natural, scenic, recreational, or historical resources of the covered trail, the Designated Operational Partner may submit to the Secretary concerned and the United States Attorney for the Federal district court in which the alleged violation occurred a written request—</text><clause id="idc619fde3403e4f43b802a4b05d7a477d"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to investigate the allegation; and</text></clause><clause id="id2c80c607a5e441609e1909233d5fac86"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to enforce the rights of the United States by preventing, reducing, mitigating, or remediating the adverse effects of the alleged violation.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idba41c4e9ecea49fab6dc650373cea475"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Notice</header><clause id="idede327dce9464ef09b3ba9520e5de173"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A request under subparagraph (A) shall include, to the maximum extent practicable, detailed information relating to the alleged trespass, infringement, or violation, including—</text><subclause id="id92ae1cd4db834ca8afe57d9dc7add61f"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the nature, location, duration, and known identity of any alleged offender;</text></subclause><subclause id="idd0553ac8042c40a7a1d6fcea57c4f360"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any efforts carried out to address the alleged violation;</text></subclause><subclause id="idc2b8b272079c45a29bdf82f562254eb7"><enum>(III)</enum><text>any impacts of the alleged violation on the applicable covered trail or resources of the covered trail; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id8b80be5349104a5d89667b2ef463df1f"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>any requested remedy.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id0f684467aff949e89bf0f05639594d61"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Submission requirements</header><text>A request under subparagraph (A) shall be—</text><subclause id="id5981149d50f54384aa42e1ca3de7752a"><enum>(I)</enum><text>submitted to the Secretary concerned and appropriate United States Attorney by—</text><item id="id8b998a56e0de4979b105bcc0117206f6"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>electronic means; or</text></item><item id="idfa99ff986fc5416d9018b879a39b29a2"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>delivery to the address on file for official correspondence; and</text></item></subclause><subclause id="id9381acfdf1bf4c898bdaff4f225d00cf"><enum>(II)</enum><text>clearly identified as a <quote>Designated Operational Partner Request for Redress</quote>.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id0854307289d34035ae38b43e4a1cfb98"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Signatures</header><text>A request under subparagraph (A) may be signed by—</text><subclause id="id1a8f8e702543442e8fdefee0deed9cbc"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the applicable Designated Operational Partner; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id43b130ecb16441b4ba452e2af953ad33"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any other individual or entity that is a part of the cooperative management system of the applicable covered trail.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id08db7d29222f4ff8b1dc6a789ddc1df0"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Response</header><clause id="idf24aab37c40e4fd99f2e2c3d9c5036af"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Assessment</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date on which a request is submitted under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall submit to the United States Attorney for the Federal district court in which the applicable alleged trespass, infringement, or violation occurred and the Designated Operational Partner an assessment of the alleged violation.</text></clause><clause id="id24350dacf253484fb71cb5e92e2587ac"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Additional information from designated operational partner</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date on which the Designated Operational Partner receives an assessment under clause (i), the Designated Operational Partner may provide to the Secretary concerned and the relevant United States Attorney additional information relating to the alleged violation.</text></clause><clause id="ideaec0dc84e3c4ffbb85b24b51dd28952"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Response from United States attorney</header><text>Not later than 150 days after the date on which a request is submitted to a United States Attorney under subparagraph (A), and not later than 60 days after the date on which a Designated Operational Partner provides additional information under clause (ii) to the United States Attorney, if applicable, the United States Attorney shall submit to the Secretary concerned and the Designated Operational Partner information regarding whether the United States Attorney is pursuing redress for the alleged violation.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8c2c5212d7e0459db051d8d2ff5056ae"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Litigation costs</header><text>In issuing any final order with respect to a petition brought under this subsection, the relevant Federal district court may award to a Designated Operational Partner the costs of petitioning (including reasonable attorney and expert witness fees) if the Secretary or United States Attorney takes action to address the alleged violation of the rights of the United States.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8310ebc0e7c64e988924bd966ab58682"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Effect</header><text>Nothing in this paragraph—</text><clause id="id2b459c9466874e8ca078d1ad09f9f5b3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>limits any cause of action that the Federal Government may have under any other law;</text></clause><clause id="idfa482f24c0ef4540af01a9f823680e35"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>obligates—</text><subclause id="id828861e0725e41b3a51e7c9721fd9f97"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a Designated Operational Partner to participate, or to present claims or defenses, in any civil action relating to the property rights of the Federal Government; or</text></subclause><subclause id="id92373870ceb749809808efe2f6ea6bd2"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the Federal Government to participate, or to present claims or defenses, in any civil action relating to the property rights of the Designated Operational Partner; or</text></subclause></clause><clause id="idcb39f52b0234426e9ab0c479aac9089c"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>makes—</text><subclause id="idb7437bca8ae04a4d8cc6d3011cb4f033"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a Designated Operational Partner a necessary party in any action relating to the property rights of the Federal Government; or</text></subclause><subclause id="id98e6cdf44a2f4db191ab1e6252974469"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the Federal Government a necessary party in any action relating to the property rights of the Designated Operational Partner.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idb0c2fbaa06024ea59ce477ee510ad16b"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Land and resource protection proposed priority lists</header><subparagraph id="id70d29d36ad7c40cea1f4fcd6340acbf3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each Designated Operational Partner shall periodically develop and submit to the Secretary concerned and the heads of any other appropriate Federal land management agencies a proposed priority list for land and resource protection for the applicable covered trail.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7e6c7d9e18eb491f9f6c4020039e0bb4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Applicable law</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf72cd1289c3c4b0c8398be5fbec8428b"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A proposed priority list shall be considered to advance the planning and development of the applicable covered trail in accordance with section 2(c) of the National Trails System Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1241">16 U.S.C. 1241(c)</external-xref>).</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id91469430066545a7a0a32964a5165350"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Effect</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide52268d6ce08421c8b0cb3abf34ff1ea"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conveys any land protection authority not included in the National Trails System Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1241">16 U.S.C. 1241 et seq.</external-xref>); or</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd0422e2f7e364980b11333fe6b6bd6e9"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prioritizes the use of funds for land protection projects on covered trails over funds for other land protection projects.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id05b76e03647944989f06c1db969cb736"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>A Designated Operational Partner shall include on a proposed priority list—</text><clause id="idbc5e2677f5cb4cefb4c2ee3aa3d1d0aa"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the location and current ownership of each parcel of land identified for inclusion in the applicable covered trail;</text></clause><clause id="id7362e89df54c46cda49dbf835341ead8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the desired nature of ownership of each parcel of land identified for inclusion in the covered trail, including a partial or fee ownership;</text></clause><clause id="id1fe2189c87ed457d9c7d9e46ac803549"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the name of the owner of each identified parcel of land;</text></clause><clause id="id3032422c70034bb7a875d3dda1edcd5a"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a description of the benefit to the covered trail in the preservation of scenic, recreational, historical, natural, or cultural values for which the covered trail was designated; and</text></clause><clause id="idf1f16171b1854e3e9be39dd02a071fab"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the name of any nongovernmental partner committed to advancing the protection of parcels of land identified on the proposed priority list for inclusion in the covered trail.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3fa98d44c02243c091aa7bafaafa46cc"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Input; criteria</header><text>In developing a proposed priority list, a Designated Operational Partner shall—</text><clause id="iddbcc3e603aea4d439496a341241ec50a"><enum>(i)</enum><text>solicit input from a variety of governmental, nongovernmental, Federal, and State partners, the scope of which shall be limited to a landscape or physiographic region agreed to by the Designated Operational Partner and the Secretary concerned; and</text></clause><clause id="idee91ef440dfc4deb9183de22108fd12e"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>establish criteria to prioritize land and resource protection recommendations included on the proposed priority list.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id97ad964ddd4d43abb8b35334322f68a6"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Use of Federal funds</header><clause id="id2bc1e7f3b6e1444585badd7888562db8"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In using Federal funds to protect land for a covered trail—</text><subclause id="id5ba2a2a7c3274f859f031c7af5333dee"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the Secretary concerned shall prioritize the use of funds for land identified for Federal protection in the applicable proposed priority list, except to the extent that the Secretary concerned determines, based on considerations set forth in the National Trails System Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1241">16 U.S.C. 1241 et seq.</external-xref>) and the comprehensive plan for the covered trail, and subject to clause (ii), that—</text><item id="id0f074657044f4cb6a83cb539d050bfce"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>a parcel of land included on the proposed priority list should not be prioritized; or</text></item><item id="idef6b6c41588c4016a4425e5c6fd9473b"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>a parcel of land not included on the proposed priority list should be prioritized; and</text></item></subclause><subclause id="id2ba7e422a9ba4bc6a5890dbdc95a1534"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a State is encouraged to incorporate land identified for State protection in the applicable land and resource conservation plan of the State, as appropriate, in accordance with State law.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id836865abd64641dbb3366a0b4381754d"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>If the Secretary concerned determines under clause (i)(I) that a parcel of land included on the proposed priority list should not be prioritized or that a parcel of land not included on the proposed priority list should be prioritized instead of a parcel of land included on the proposed priority list, the Secretary concerned shall submit to the Designated Operational Partner notice of the determination, including a detailed explanation of the reason for the determination.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id20eae58242044c9da0199525ba05646b"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Reports</header><text>Not less frequently than once every 5 years, the Secretaries concerned shall submit to Congress a report that describes any progress or lack of progress of the Secretaries concerned with respect to advancing land and resource conservation objectives under proposed priority lists.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1b14099b7d2c44bd9c36fbe7e6d0a9b6"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to each of the Secretary and the Secretary of Agriculture such sums as are necessary to carry out planning activities relating to the development, updating, and implementation of proposed priority lists under this paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id49f8a14ccef04868b0c7e10639cb52ed"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Acceptance or rejection of comprehensive plans</header><subparagraph id="idfe79d84453904a30931b70deeca883bb"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding subsections (e) and (f) of section 5 of the National Trails System Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1244">16 U.S.C. 1244</external-xref>), a Designated Operational Partner may accept or reject—</text><clause id="id9b9f52c5142e4aff9d84b72638a159a7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a proposed comprehensive plan for the applicable covered trail; and</text></clause><clause id="id7857cf37a1034fa4bb24e7e87233c84a"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any amendments or revisions to the comprehensive plan for the applicable covered trail (other than an addendum to a comprehensive plan for the applicable covered trail prepared in accordance with the process established under subsection (g)(3)).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id26b7f3190cb94f4cac69f814684644e0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Report</header><text>If a comprehensive plan or amendment or revision to a comprehensive plan rejected by a Designated Operational Partner under subparagraph (A) is subsequently submitted to Congress, the Secretary concerned shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives a report that describes the basis for the submission of the rejected comprehensive plan or amendment or revision to the comprehensive plan by the Secretary concerned.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id2899c8d8d27f436ab92558b65d5b1c4e"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Surplus personal property</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id385519a4bb20486aae2874ccfcc43516"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding subchapter III of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/40/5">chapter 5</external-xref> of title 40, United States Code, a Federal agency may dispose of surplus personal property by transferring the property to a Designated Operational Partner, to be used by the Designated Operational Partner for purposes of carrying out a cooperative agreement entered into under section 7(h) of the National Trails System Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1246">16 U.S.C. 1246(h)</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id157847fc4c644a7e8c8036d62ff89159"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A transfer of surplus personal property under subparagraph (A) shall be subject to the condition that the Designated Operational Partner to whom the property is transferred (including any subsidiary or subdivision of the Designated Operational Partner) may not—</text><clause id="idf1b18aab6f494b919704e4f2752d8df1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>use the transferred property for purposes other than carrying out the duties and authorities of the Designated Operational Partner under the cooperative agreement; or</text></clause><clause id="idd9b4b0129d96429b9aac6e33c7fc524e"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>transfer the transferred property to a recipient that is not a part of the cooperative management system of the covered trail.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id2857bbaa4cab49bbb28bc6af8aefa5c7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Management</header><text>Nothing in this Act or the National Trails System Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1241">16 U.S.C. 1241 et seq.</external-xref>)—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idffb7acb1e81a49eaa7f4a29aae70a872"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provides any authority to a Designated Operational Partner, other volunteer organization, volunteer, or other individual or entity any authority to issue, amend, or revoke any land use authorization unless provided for explicitly by statute;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id42dc6316cfb24063b5bb213d96ab799e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>except as specifically provided in this Act or the National Trails System Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1241">16 U.S.C. 1241 et seq.</external-xref>), removes or transfers any authority otherwise provided by law; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id72c83c0c729841eba4828e4ffbfa8e1f"><enum>(3)</enum><text>except as authorized by the processes established under this Act or the National Trails System Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1241">16 U.S.C. 1241 et seq.</external-xref>), provides any Designated Operational Partner, other volunteer organization, volunteer, or any other individual or entity authority over the property, holdings, or possessory or other interest of any other partner to a covered trail.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id8cf903c739704a32bd17b68715646244"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Administration</header><paragraph id="id23799df91e444573afd0e0934a4e4175"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In making administration, management, or operational decisions that would impact the ability of volunteers or a volunteer organization to serve a substantial role on covered trails, the Secretary concerned shall—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id941b6b8c0b144e438fbab2235925af90"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">rather than presuming absolute control over the covered trail by the Federal Government, encourage the participation of volunteers and volunteer organizations; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1512052077b34fa9b36273829bca7113"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to the extent practicable, remedy constraints on supporting the role of volunteers and volunteer organizations on covered trails.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide42885a3ea8f4ef0a44df19d4cb42b22"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary and the Secretary of Agriculture shall use the rulemaking authority of section 7(i) of the National Trails System Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1246">16 U.S.C. 1246(i)</external-xref>), the Federal Lands Recreation Enhancement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/6801">16 U.S.C. 6801 et seq.</external-xref>), and any other applicable law to establish, by regulation, a fee collection and distribution system under which the administrator of a covered trail may collect all permits and fees levied by federally administered areas and State-administered areas traversed by a covered trail, to be remitted to the applicable federally administered area or State-administered area levying the permits and fees.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ided61bdfa9f564078922ec0b6487eaae9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Applicable law</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/10">Chapter 10</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, shall not apply to the cooperative management of a covered trail.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id2a4ad75a396a4b1d81ad0210d6deaf9a"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Availability of funds</header><paragraph id="ided92554fbd5c4f199965bc93613fc1b3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A covered trail shall be eligible for funds made available for—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfd485f2ae9dd4d0f8d5ca3493693e9f8"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a unit of the National Trails System;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id72c853b24bf243a5a4da4dde7bca73b2"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any federally administered area to which the covered trail is assigned; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd2176f2be3ad4ce6840402946fb9faaf"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any federally administered area traversed by the covered trail.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idae102dad2ca6487eb00f2e6215803206"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Multiple agencies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The location of a covered trail on land managed by 1 Federal agency shall have no impact on the eligibility of the covered trail for funding for any project, planning, volunteer or visitor support effort, or any other component of administering a covered trail by any other Federal agency.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id10338d85fcad4caa8b08987e8086c487"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Land and water conservation fund</header><text>A covered trail shall be eligible for amounts made available from the Land and Water Conservation Fund established under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/54/2003">chapter 2003</external-xref> of title 54, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8d0b606f9d6248ea8087be9ac9abdaf0"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Partnerships</header><text>The Secretary concerned shall use interagency and intergovernmental partnerships to ensure the maximum recreational and conservation potential of a covered trail is achieved.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0e3675579a5e4cedae6d016c7b98bc86"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Cooperative agreements</header><text>To the maximum extent practicable, the administrator of a covered trail shall enter into a cooperative agreement under the National Trails System Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1244">16 U.S.C. 1244 et seq.</external-xref>), for a term of not longer than 20 years, with a volunteer organization partner, under which—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd2e0468ad44e457b884465199f8e21b0"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the administrator of the covered trail shall delegate to the volunteer organization partner the authority to operate the covered trail (including the provision of financial assistance for such purpose);</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id896a821fc46948a99f6a537a450abd10"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">operational and management responsibilities with respect to the covered trail shall be shared between the administrator of the covered trail and volunteer organization partner, including subsidiaries or delegees of the volunteer organization partner; or</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc4f395f7c68a468b9e650d05174a40ba"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other appropriate arrangement between the administrator of the covered trail and the volunteer organization partner authorized by the National Trails System Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1244">16 U.S.C. 1244 et seq.</external-xref>) shall be carried out.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id47053bf99cb546698a20c931283dddc8" commented="no"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Comprehensive plans</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id82d8f70edbca4ceb8bbf7c276e2a013e"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The applicable comprehensive plan—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8fea1bd1a0144f34acb9fec77b84e40a"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall be incorporated into the management of each federally administered area traversed by the covered trail; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddbcb4fda70f549cfb1188bd0ccb74355"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">should be appropriately considered by State-administered areas that are traversed by a covered trail.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc04bf50f2de740d1b554715ad3f5d622"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Incorporation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In updating a general management plan or similar unit-level plan applicable to a federally administered area traversed by a covered trail, the Secretary concerned shall incorporate the requirements of any applicable comprehensive plan.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idaa3654129f9d4c6a8adaf4c546c4c032" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4a9dff2a9a744d49bb3f62b7e44bb35c"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary concerned shall use the rulemaking authority of section 7(i) of the National Trails System Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1246">16 U.S.C. 1246(i)</external-xref>) to establish, by regulation, a process for addenda to comprehensive plans, as appropriate, to address location-or topic-specific administration, management, or operation issues.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ided88abd52f46433db04476b6cb009865"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The process established under subparagraph (A) shall require that any addendum to a comprehensive plan shall be developed after consultation with the applicable land manager and Designated Operational Partner, as applicable.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idffa150d68ba04b8e8578158cfabfa478" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Visitor capacity</header><text>For a covered trail that is subject to subsection (e) or (f) of section 5 of the National Trails System Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1244">16 U.S.C. 1244</external-xref>), the applicable comprehensive plan shall ensure that the visitor capacity requirement for the covered trail is determined based on visitor capacities for targeted sites, trail segments, or areas of the covered trail.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idcc28b969a3ca4a35afd7954077820475"><enum>5.</enum><header>Improving covered trail planning and development</header><subsection id="id6dc3c9c9375d4ee5804ac5c85424e562"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Visitor capacity</header><text>The Secretary concerned shall determine the visitor capacity of a covered trail that is subject to subsection (e) or (f) of section 5 of the National Trails System Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1244">16 U.S.C. 1244</external-xref>)—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id45d027b5b3ab4bdf867a0f64329c2ed8"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">based on the desired conditions of the specific portion or segment of a covered trail rather than the entire covered trail; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbf887ffc917c441e83d444214081a623"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in accordance with applicable laws and agency policies, including the applicable comprehensive plan.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ida65b3ff604f44d04be0781f2cb900a2f"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Economic impact assessment</header><paragraph id="idaf5e7c45b5284e4fb4852f3aed17f7e6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, and not less frequently than once every 5 years thereafter, the Secretary and the Secretary of Agriculture shall identify 1 or more methods to assess the economic impact of covered trails on gateway communities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id19d5afbc6ae44c4b88b28901bd0e885e"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>In identifying methods under paragraph (1), the Secretary and the Secretary of Agriculture shall, to the maximum extent practicable—</text><subparagraph id="id895a96b4c1644a4186e591c2fe05c9ef"><enum>(A)</enum><text>aggregate and extrapolate economic impact information from existing data, such as data from land units on which covered trails are located;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id62e405d37970474db094e2dc17c26f32"><enum>(B)</enum><text>use State and county economic impact information;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2c60705ad6da4a2fa7f6937dc29b8abe"><enum>(C)</enum><text>partner with State and local governments; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5ba81ca550c644a18c68c81b19a40060"><enum>(D)</enum><text>leverage the cooperative management systems of the covered trails and local and landscape-wide partnerships to obtain and process relevant information and report any relevant findings.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id967ca4e823df41d89bd36dc49119921c"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Advancing covered trail planning</header><paragraph id="idd0318afa188645469d041d9aa03a6464"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds that—</text><subparagraph id="id751814d5024341f8aa95304127b6e69d"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the designation of a covered trail is the onset of the long-term development and planning for the covered trail, rather than the conclusion of those activities; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf25b8cddef894c9d938d38f363bf8341"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the cultivation of partnerships, the acquisition of land, including interests in land and land use agreements, the conduct of accessible and inclusive interpretation, and the development of recreational facilities, as appropriate for covered trails, are needed to advance the purposes of the National Trails System Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1241">16 U.S.C. 1241 et seq.</external-xref>) to meet the ever-expanding outdoor recreation needs of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id186783f8a04c45a48096b4e730644688"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reports</header><text>The Secretary and the Secretary of Agriculture, acting jointly, shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives—</text><subparagraph id="id326127ca9b55419492ca7c7df8c20207"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, a report that describes the successes and challenges in developing and planning covered trails; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc4c8756a71c04226998c747f1e50731e"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not later than 5 years after the date of enactment of this Act, a report that assesses the desired conditions and use of facilities on each covered trail with respect to—</text><clause id="id0e97e17a05324366b3cdf9844b4e6ca2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>visitor usage of specific segments or sites of the covered trail, including the extent to which visitors use the covered trail in groups of not fewer than 10 individuals;</text></clause><clause id="idf7902b3f2890437e8426510a0b185dc3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>proposed priority segments or sites for additional facilities or protection of additional land or resources identified by relevant cooperative management partners; and</text></clause><clause id="id85d461732dea4eadab598220332f7ddf"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any activities that the Secretary and the Secretary of Agriculture determine are necessary to advance the development of and planning for the covered trail consistent with the partnership nature of covered trails.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idfb1b7e0bae4640469a39bf2ae974d581"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Community engagement</header><text>In preparing the reports under paragraph (2), the Secretary and the Secretary of Agriculture shall consult with—</text><subparagraph id="id9854cf4d4da44644938a9d288018b297"><enum>(A)</enum><text>communities located in the vicinity of the proposed segments and sites described in paragraph (2)(B)(ii);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddd214438b3fd400c97b2ff0ac88bb050"><enum>(B)</enum><text>federally recognized Indian Tribes;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide53148a1eb8e496eab83536c144fa965"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any Federal and State agencies that manage land traversed by covered trails; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7df349b0db834b70bbb7bcd7bb3f931b"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Designated Operational Partners and other cooperative management partners of covered trails.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id5735c0eab791443090432080b4be90d6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary and the Secretary of Agriculture—</text><paragraph id="id30c1c17ea0184888a548c5b989a4558e"><enum>(1)</enum><text>for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2031, such sums as are necessary—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id07db2f0833ac45edacfb81ec77884522"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to carry out subsection (a);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfc1c360694ea4bb7944e44e6dfddf168"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to identify the methods under subsection (b); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id24ca7671c7214fe08e07cb2dea6381a6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to prepare the reports required under subsection (c); and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5faaa32473544ad3abc4788dc9996f06"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2031, through programs determined to be appropriate by the Secretary and the Secretary, such sums as are necessary for the acquisition, construction, and development of facilities (including the acquisition of land or interests in land) for covered trails.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

