<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCF23EE39C93B41EC984FD42B9B72B6D1" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3148 IH: Supporting America’s Leaders Undergoing Tough Expenses Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3148</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250501">May 1, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000311">Mr. Jack</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001189">Mr. Austin Scott of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000481">Mr. Figures</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001327">Mr. Bresnahan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001218">Mr. McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001212">Mr. Moore of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001129">Mr. Collins</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000603">Mr. Gill of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000490">Mr. Bishop</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001235">Mr. Moore of West Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000484">Mr. Fine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000812">Mrs. Wagner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001093">Mrs. Houchin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001220">Mr. Strong</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000601">Mr. Goldman of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001239">Mr. McGuire</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000055">Mr. Aderholt</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Defense to carry out a pilot program to assist certain members of the Armed Forces and dependents with additional supplemental coverage relating to cancer.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0DC5671BA661450FB8F7C2CCBB4CD11E" style="OLC"><section id="H281C8B6042AD45AC92794D85C62972F6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Supporting America’s Leaders Undergoing Tough Expenses Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SALUTE Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HF9CD6A645ABC457B9013BCB78B7D9E3C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Pilot program to assist certain members of the Armed Forces and dependents with additional supplemental coverage relating to cancer</header><subsection id="H53BA4E1686F3402484CE12F279CF6D12"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than September 30, 2026, the Secretary of Defense shall establish a pilot program under which a covered individual may obtain supplemental insurance for noncovered expenses under a fixed indemnity supplemental benefit plan described in subsection (b)(1).</text></subsection><subsection id="H98A948F47A6A4FFF8D7384C71B911D0B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Agreement</header><paragraph id="H7C601CC353D24F7A896F536072E34105"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In carrying out the pilot program under subsection (a), the Secretary shall enter into an agreement with not more than two companies to each offer one or more fixed indemnity supplemental benefit plans that—</text><subparagraph id="HC2746518E3004F38856878ACE4F4329D" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">meet the requirements for a supplemental insurance plan under section 199.2 of title 32, Code of Federal Regulations, and the exception in section 199.8(b)(4) of such title, as in effect on the date of the enactment of this Act;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H88795BCA743E4A0E89749A75B9346CB0" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>are provided under a separate policy, certificate, or contract;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H77A154A182E74CC981F9B7104C1B2E50" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>provide no coordination with any other health benefit plan; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H531E85D0F73C4C4FBFA3C0B21C8F130E" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>are designed to help participants pay noncovered expenses.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0DF8C2A1009D48E2B00249AF9D665A1F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>An agreement entered into under paragraph (1) shall be for a period of at least three years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF3249D5F31784763AEB199E8995574DC" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>In entering an agreement under paragraph (1) with a company, the Secretary—</text><subparagraph id="H393B330DEFFC436D9E8AC9D24A037FB4" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may not select the company unless the company is licensed in each State;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA6DADA004F524A0D85AC14388C40E1AC" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall award the contract based on the expertise of the company;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD36C3E7AD5924BBA8A0DF012E3C4E055" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>shall negotiate the terms and conditions of the fixed indemnity supplemental benefit plan provided under the contract, including with respect to the ability of the company to communicate with individuals not enrolled in the plan and whether such communication may include information on other insurance products;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H95682E01BD3C4CF78FB88205C280E7AF" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>shall negotiate the cost of coverage with the company that will cover the participants who elect to enroll in such plan;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H63C90F717C374B6A850D5CAE67FAE556" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>shall provide a method for verification of the eligibility of applicants and procedures for determination of eligibility; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H13AECFDB79A04AC283A264ED1C4F56BA"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall provide a method for payroll deduction of premiums.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAB933C716B4141F8B908216478B92565" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Provision of information</header><text>The Secretary shall provide information to covered individuals regarding the pilot program under subsection (a) by making available on the online portal of the TRICARE program the following information:</text><subparagraph id="H31142467238C4708BEFF1C3B66BD925E" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A notice of availability of a fixed indemnity supplemental benefit plan provided under the pilot program.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB79D7029F9E749EEB4B14BFDD23F875F" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A description of how to enroll in such plan.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H77216FA452B64D4D8E9CB73FA09505E3" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A description and explanation of the benefits provided under such plan.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H02D43A5D875D49F7BBD09DD25A8D32F9" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A description of the costs to the individual through premiums and remittances to a company providing such plan.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBE464ACC0F8440E099620D8642BF76B6" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Election To enroll</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A covered individual may elect to enroll in a fixed indemnity supplemental benefit plan provided under the pilot program under subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="HEBE1D337789F49A8B993D0EBD832B41C" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limitations on authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the amounts authorized to be appropriated by this Act to carry out the pilot program may be used to subsidize the cost of a fixed indemnity supplemental benefit plan provided under the pilot program under subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="H526890CAB2F5408D90EB8DAF1E66B230" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Treatment of companies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of the pilot program under subsection (a), companies selected to carry out the activities in subsection (b) shall not be considered contractors of the Federal Government.</text></subsection><subsection id="H31FB46F36B0D496C841017C5BE21D471" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Preemption</header><text>The provisions of this section shall supersede the laws of any State except with respect to State laws relating to licensing of an insurance company or plan solvency of such a company.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA427D06BB95E43A1B849107367B30713" commented="no"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than three years after the date on which the pilot program under subsection (a) commences, the Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives a report regarding such pilot program, including the following:</text><paragraph id="H9EB3677800B34E32AFC3CACF3445CCEE" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A description of the insurance products provided through a fixed indemnity supplemental benefit plan provided under the pilot program under subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0028E69AF07D4660BA91D007E3ED4DFC" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The number of covered individuals who enrolled in such a plan.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8635563AC0BC4A038CB644E98869B37D" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Feedback and examples of use cases by such individuals.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H902DC98B0E714A76913E86B9A347E5A4" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A determination by the Secretary with respect to whether such pilot program should be made permanent.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H922219ECF10245EC8363EF747439E0CD" commented="no"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>Unless the Secretary makes a determination under subsection (g)(4) to make the pilot program under subsection (a) permanent, the pilot program under subsection (a) shall terminate on the day that is five years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H0A3E5D30A6F044D08F0BA550516B79D6" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H3F05A1D8254F4A4790EB177AC0A56B35" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>covered individual</term> means the following:</text><subparagraph id="H049D9F22847C42358D75DEBE751171AD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A member of the Army, Navy, Marine Corps, Air Force, or Space Force.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0920E2BD003844CF825741E47F5E8C7E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A dependent (as defined in section 1072 of title 10, United States Code) of such a member who is enrolled in the TRICARE program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE5E3CE6AE70648DA8E41978D140840F0" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>noncovered expense</term> means, with respect to a covered individual, any expenses relating to the screening for and diagnosis and treatment of cancer that are not otherwise covered by the health care benefits the individuals receives under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/55">chapter 55</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC83CD027845F4FFB837DEC7655353A29" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <term>State</term> has the meaning given such term in section 901 of title 32, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H872378D6147E4E36AF062B865CA6BF0A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The term <term>TRICARE program</term> has the meaning given that term in section 1072 of title 10, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

