<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MCC25732-38H-5V-YWN">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1980 IS: To establish the Senate NATO Observer Group, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>II</distribution-code>
        <congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session>1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. 1980</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action>
            <action-date date="20250605">June 5, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S384">Mr. Tillis</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which
                was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSRA00">Committee
                    on Rules and Administration</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title>To establish the Senate NATO Observer Group, and for other
            purposes.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body>
        <section id="id4d3d5cc7270142b0bb0e425b711896f6" section-type="section-one">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>United States Senate NATO Observer Group</header>
            <subsection id="idf70c0d59da8241fbb84975569b2ebcd1">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>Establishment</header>
 <text>There is established within the Senate a group of Senators to address and advise on matters relating to the North Atlantic Treaty Organization, to be known as the <quote>Senate NATO Observer Group</quote>.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id01006a1f19664fdf96d43fac1021b322">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Functions</header>
 <text>The Senate NATO Observer Group shall—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id36f95a286cb7458494d57eddb6952d6f"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">serve as a forum for addressing matters relating to the North Atlantic Treaty Organization that fall within the jurisdictions of 2 or more committees of the Senate;</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3678403f11094fa1a9cc16a2c674fc0e">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">advise the Senate on issues relating to the North Atlantic Treaty Organization, including North Atlantic Treaty Organization enlargement; and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id910088294ad3414ba53738ca23c1d7d4">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to any matter involving the North Atlantic Treaty Organization and the United States Government, particularly during negotiations on North Atlantic Treaty Organization enlargement, engage in close interactions between and among the executive branch, the Senate, the North Atlantic Treaty Organization, any other member country of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization, and any country that is a candidate for membership in the North Atlantic Treaty Organization.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id264c4a19b3f04d3fbc70c3b63fd2ead9">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Appointment of members</header>
                <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaf60b683d1a34bc88b8c0a3404b4fd15">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                    <header>119th Congress</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the 119th Congress, the Senate NATO Observer Group shall exist in the manner established by the majority leader and the minority leader of the Senate in the Congressional Record at the beginning of first session of the 119th Congress.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4195d4b9977e4c2286930560c8fc8817">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Subsequent Congresses</header>
                    <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id19925f6a5dbe4e7387015408eb015051">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
                        <header>Appointment</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning in the 120th Congress, not later than 60 days after the date on which of the first session of each Congress convenes, the majority leader and the minority leader of the Senate shall each appoint to the Senate NATO Observer Group not more than 7 Senators.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3fbb9ab628d24a72928fc96fa52e3b3a">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
                        <header>Co-chairs</header>
 <text>Of the members appointed under subparagraph (A), the majority leader and the minority leader of the Senate shall each appoint 1 co-chairperson of the Senate NATO Observer Group.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="idba2ea4b0319b4dcc930cfbe1f7526df6">
                <enum>(d)</enum>
                <header>Foreign travel</header>
 <text>Each co-chair of the Senate NATO Observer Group and 1 designated staff member may engage in foreign travel for official purposes if such travel is authorized by the other co-chair of the Senate NATO Observer Group.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id969a748c98f84f55931758e0dd1bfa4c">
                <enum>(e)</enum>
                <header>Interparliamentary services</header>
 <text>The Office of Interparliamentary Services of the Senate shall be designated to provide administrative support and protocol functions to the Senate NATO Observer Group, and for special delegations or travel authorized by the majority leader or the minority leader of the Senate.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7e04a38b90564bb186709f058fd1d282">
                <enum>(f)</enum>
                <header>Use of foreign currencies</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, the co-chairs of the Senate NATO Observer Group are authorized to use funds in accordance with the provisions of law relating to foreign currencies, as codified in section 1754 of title 22, United States Code, for activities critical to carrying out the functions of the Senate NATO Observer Group.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id9e60cb7a83a840feba3f169f96805194">
                <enum>(g)</enum>
                <header>Report</header>
 <text>Not less frequently than annually, the Senate NATO Observer Group shall submit to the majority leader and minority leader of the Senate and the chairperson and ranking member of the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate a report on the activities undertaken by the Senate NATO Observer Group during the preceding fiscal year, including with respect to travel, legislative efforts, and public diplomacy initiatives.</text>
            </subsection>
        </section>
    </legis-body>
</bill>

