<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-RIL25591-03T-Y0-4FD">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 261 IS: Honoring the life of Sarah Lynn Milgrim and condemning the recent extremist attacks.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>III</distribution-code>
        <congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session display="yes">1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. RES. 261</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action display="yes">
            <action-date date="20250604">June 4, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S411">Mr. Marshall</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S347">Mr. Moran</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which
                was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the
                    Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
        <official-title display="yes">Honoring the life of Sarah Lynn Milgrim and condemning the
            recent extremist attacks.</official-title>
    </form>
    <preamble>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas Sarah Lynn Milgrim was born on December 29, 1998;</text> </whereas> <whereas> <text>Whereas Sarah excelled academically and in the arts, partaking in and loving music and theater;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas, at Shawnee Mission East High School in Prairie Village, Kansas, she played in the orchestra and sang in the choir and chamber choir;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas, in the greater Kansas City region, she performed in community show choirs and the KC Lyric Opera children’s choir;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas, while growing up, Sarah cultivated her faith as an integral part of her being, attending Sunday school at Congregation Kol Ami;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas, after graduating from Shawnee Mission East High School, Sarah enrolled in and graduated from the University of Kansas in Lawrence, Kansas, earning a Bachelor of Science in environmental science;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas, at the University of Kansas, Sarah continued to strengthen her faith as an active member of Hillel and Chabad;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas, following her achievements at the University of Kansas, Sarah pursued and earned Master’s degrees in International Affairs from American University and Resource Development and Sustainability from the United Nations University for Peace in Costa Rica;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas, in the fall of 2023, Sarah began working as the Director of Civil Society Affairs at the Embassy of Israel in Washington, DC;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas, in this capacity, Sarah worked day and night to fight the scourge of religious discrimination and violence;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas, while working at the Embassy of Israel, Sarah met and fell in love with Yaron Lischinsky;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas, following a panel discussion promoting peace and conflict resolution, a gunman, in a targeted attack, killed Yaron and Sarah; and</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas this horrific act of violence represents another direct attack on the Jewish population of the United States: Now, therefore, be it</text>
        </whereas>
    </preamble>
    <resolution-body>
        <section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section">
 <text>That the Senate—</text> <paragraph id="id9ad7676d8bfd42e7a331342f3da7f244"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>strongly condemns violence targeted at religious groups;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="id85bc42a223894584a28c0786bc030e27">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>remembers the life of Sarah Milgrim and celebrates her work;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="id0eb98423f2ff405092579aa456fae0e6"> <enum>(3)</enum> <text>denounces the senseless violence that resulted in the deaths of Sarah Milgrim and Yaron Lischinsky; and</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="idf361c87e5f25404e8ea8df127ffd740d">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>supports the full prosecution of the individual who committed this extremist attack.</text>
            </paragraph>
        </section>
    </resolution-body>
</resolution>

