<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H496E226D987147D0A149A526708441D7" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5438 IH: Incentivize Savings Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5438</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250917">September 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001218">Mr. McCormick</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001317">Mr. Brecheen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000246">Mr. Edwards</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001307">Mr. Baird</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001118">Mr. Cline</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HBU00">the Budget</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To incentivize Federal agencies to create savings for the American people, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H2F26DDC6A5284FD29FB1604A30274E76" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H9551016B34B841FEB4263F839A3BF9D0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Incentivize Savings Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H9540D5446BF74958BB4EA8601E5EA866"><enum>2.</enum><header>Special rules for Federal agency budgets and bonuses</header> <subsection id="HA6CCADCB0B644E74B1358B13DC810189"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/13">chapter 13</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code, is amended by inserting at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="H29091FC8A758443A979C6C435D515B8B" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="H10213253AD944078B3ED81497DD37C67"><enum>1311.</enum><header>Special rules for unexpended Federal agency appropriations</header> 
<subsection id="H53AF8C21F9AA4167AB2B7983826095D5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If a Federal agency does not expend funds appropriated or otherwise made available to the agency for a definite period during the period of availability of such funds—</text> <paragraph id="HA5286CCABE114147865B971A9F62196F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>49 percent of such total funds shall remain available for an additional fiscal year;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H565723C09B07424CAB2AAADEEC50608B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>49 percent of such total funds shall be used for payments of principal and interest on the public debt; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEFA669E3C9234F9382E91DED24BDB7B3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>2 percent of such total funds shall be used, not later than the date that is 30 days after the last day of the applicable period of availability, for retention bonuses within such Federal agency under section 5754 of title 5.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5CE1C47C44F9477E900B8C01EAE36948"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text>In carrying out subsection (a)(3)—</text> <paragraph id="H4F394D6D3B1B49EEAE3F65EEB5CE69A1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>notwithstanding such section 5754, any retention bonus paid under such subsection may not exceed an amount equal to 10 percent of the applicable employee’s basic pay; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9EA7AC383B574A208F69A89F9380DDB8"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any amounts remaining of such total funds after paying all bonuses under such subsection shall be used for payments of principal and interest on the public debt.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HDC0FBB02C3B747CD94E7D1F3FF33B089"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Budget request</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If subsection (a) is applied to the funds of a Federal agency, with respect to the fiscal year following the fiscal year in which the availability of such funds expired, the budget submission of the agency to the Office of Management and Budget, and the budget request for the agency in the President’s annual budget submission to Congress under section 1105(a) of this title, may not be greater than the total amount of the budget request for the agency for the fiscal year in which the availability of such funds expired, adjusted by the percentage change in the Consumer Price Index (all items—United States city average) between such fiscal years.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB3C636A928CB49DDA4FD99E0D051F29E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definition of Federal agency</header><text>As used in this section, the term <term>Federal agency</term> means an Executive agency (as that term is defined in section 105 of title 5) or any other agency of the executive branch of the Federal Government, including the United States Postal Service and the Postal Regulatory Commission, but does not include the American National Red Cross.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HF86747B265D54CA98625A62939AB5765"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents for such subchapter is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 1310 the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="HFB9FA3C7D59F484B92EC94112B8ECDF7" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry level="section">1311. Special rules for unexpended Federal agency appropriations.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

