<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0A6789103154488CBA452EEE68E4CF88" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 318 IH: Expressing support for the designation of the week of April 24–29, 2025, as “Small Businesses in For-Hire Transportation Week”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 318</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250409">April 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001205">Mrs. Miller of West Virginia</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSM00">Committee on Small Business</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of the week of April 24–29, 2025, as <quote>Small Businesses in For-Hire Transportation Week</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas small business in the for-hire transportation industry is made up of over 18,300 locally owned and operated companies in the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas small business in the for-hire transportation industry employs 276,250 drivers and nearly a million other workers (mechanics, call center personnel, administrative staff, and management teams) in the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas small business in the for-hire transportation industry employs a workforce that is approximately 50 percent minority in the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas nonemergency medical transportation, taxicab, limousine, livery, paratransit, and shuttle small businesses transport over 2,000,000,000 people annually in the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas small businesses in the for-hire transportation industry continue to be critical to helping small businesses, families, hospital personnel, patients, COVID patients, shut-ins, and working families, those in food deserts, and others through the transitions needed during COVID–19 and the future variants;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas small businesses in the for-hire transportation industry continue to be essential in providing public transportation to those in our communities who need it the most;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Transportation Alliance is a critical nonprofit organization that provides small business entrepreneurs with the support to build their own successful businesses in their local community through education, training, and mentoring opportunities;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Congress should support riding local, as small businesses are the economic drivers in every community and a healthy for-hire transportation industry benefits the local economy, creates more jobs, and keeps investment in the community; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas small businesses in the for-hire transportation industry continue to be a critical resource to local, State, and Federal agencies, providing necessary transportation options for every citizen: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H2C3EF31A66414CC580898E89C336E232"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H833DA9D858FA461ABE90A4FE35B03B3E"><enum/><text>That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="H15D32A872A574915A9DADA0DF52EEEA2" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">expresses support for the designation of <quote>Small Businesses in For-Hire Transportation Week</quote> in honor of the commitment and essential services provided by the for-hire transportation industry; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEEFB0D49BFCC46E0BBBA499F44C564B9"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recognizes the efforts of small business in the for-hire transportation industry to promote safety and support for our communities.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

