<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-TAM25879-9NT-9C-SRS"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2531 IS: Uterine Fibroid Intervention and Gynecological Health Treatment Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2531</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250730">July 30, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S428">Ms. Alsobrooks</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S410">Ms. Lummis</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To authorize the Secretary of Health and Human Services to award grants to increase early detection of and intervention for uterine fibroids, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H4545CADAA81E4EB6AF93630F0BE296AF"><section section-type="section-one" id="HC1FF584AE633454095078E0EEAFFC210"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Uterine Fibroid Intervention and Gynecological Health Treatment Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H7FC693FD69F54F84A392734840654B2A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Research on uterine fibroid early detection and intervention</header><subsection id="HCAE91138D5464035B1E8F109D1DF033B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services (referred to in this Act as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall—</text><paragraph id="H5EAB749B4FAB445080C8D09B6E0B90BD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct or support research on increasing early detection of, and intervention for, uterine fibroids; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8AAC7E6ABC254DD4B4E60C118CD23FE6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>based on the results of such research and other relevant information, formulate evidence-based or evidence-informed strategies to increase early detection in health care settings.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7419EFEC5ED34420B6493FBF34F1113A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Timeline</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall finalize the evidence-based or evidence-informed strategies required by subsection (a)(2) as expeditiously as possible in order to make such strategies available to grantees under section 3 to implement such strategies pursuant to section 3(b)(3).</text></subsection></section><section id="H5C3EAE3578784812B054FEE771D21012"><enum>3.</enum><header>Grants with respect to uterine fibroid early detection and intervention</header><subsection id="H21AAD38E22B54BCA81C1504764D8D7AB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may award grants to States for carrying out programs—</text><paragraph id="H2BCFEE9DBA7E4780807E2A83F85D615F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to increase early detection of, and intervention for, uterine fibroids; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6A9BCE71939A40EBA6CC912F75D36144"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to develop and implement public awareness and education campaigns for the early detection of, and intervention for, uterine fibroids.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE062BF2BF3BC42E3B6D4A1E6B3872700"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>A State receiving a grant under this section may use the grant for the following activities, with respect to increasing early detection of, and intervention for, uterine fibroids:</text><paragraph id="H30DFDE3746634872AA355CD4C0A7C47E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Screening procedures, including advanced gynecological imaging, including payment for such procedures.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H97211E9D149F4758B7D7F94D8485AF08"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Patient navigation services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H84B2A4035166413C9F24E0746185B100"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Implementation of evidence-based or evidence-informed strategies formulated under section 2(a)(2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC16B809C97E34ED2B0959FC827A54701"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Facilitating access to health care settings.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H165B91D718A24C72A1CB0D69EC99A42E"><enum>4.</enum><header>Research with respect to uterine fibroid early detection and intervention</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary may award grants to States for the purpose of conducting research, which may include clinical trials, related to—</text><paragraph id="H2903665B6AAE4739B40420198E5D05E7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>disparities in pain control and management in uterine fibroid surgical treatment; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7B48623324D0476A939A7C88CCFD5516"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Asherman’s Syndrome, intrauterine adhesions, and other intrauterine conditions, as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HEBCF66B151EF4878A027E78AACB9A9C5"><enum>5.</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header><subsection id="H1647FF0DCF95405B82A492C857C6D4C5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reports on grants</header><text>Not later 2 years after the initial award of grants under section 2 or 3, and every 2 years thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to Congress, and make publicly available on the website of the Department of Health and Human Services—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7c4a724afb2447f89b3bbd64073fc870"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a report summarizing the findings and results of programs and activities funded through grants awarded under this Act; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id90ba1a3784b84f568761fc8ae5acc45d"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a report outlining research developments and findings related to—</text><subparagraph id="HC4336714CFE54ABA9AB94CF8CD50ECE0" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>disparities in pain control and management in uterine fibroid surgical treatment; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA29DED0465AC4A8FAC3BB0D4EB2A16A7" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Asherman’s Syndrome, intrauterine adhesions, and other intrauterine conditions, as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

