<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-HEN25040-0WY-93-NDK"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S360 IS: To provide for across-the-board rescissions of nonsecurity discretionary spending.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 360</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250203">February 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAP00">Committee on Appropriations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To provide for across-the-board rescissions of nonsecurity discretionary spending.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="id57a9ffdf77e84962b2f74206ed5f76e3"><enum>1.</enum><header>Across-the-board rescissions</header><subsection id="id880ead104ece4b06a5df5d5fb84411d2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide7838dad96e444a8971766aa2076d619"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Budget authority</header><text>The term <term>budget authority</term> has the meaning given that term in section 3 of the Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/622">2 U.S.C. 622</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4f8f729912594393bea50cfdf1d8461d"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Discretionary appropriations; security category</header><text>The terms <term>discretionary appropriations</term> and <term>security category</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 250(c) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/900">2 U.S.C. 900(c)</external-xref>). </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3845fcb79a25460582cf85f8db57615b"><enum>(3)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nonsecurity discretionary appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>nonsecurity discretionary appropriations</term> means discretionary appropriations provided in a regular appropriation Act that are not included in the security category.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idcf2fc54434da4126be353eee88245f7b"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Regular appropriation act</header><text>The term <term>regular appropriation Act</term>—</text><subparagraph id="id1bbed904363e4c0688c379add553aafb"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means an annual appropriation Act (as described in section 105 of title 1, United States Code) providing new budget authority for the programs, projects, and activities under the jurisdiction of a subcommittee of the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idccd2d3ce756b4b659d963d37f5046c7d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes—</text><clause id="ide7f1df6509ae464ea344cead2c1eca1a"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a title, division, or other subdivision of an Act or resolution that, if it were a separate Act, would be an Act described in subparagraph (A); and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb99f2fdcf4d7496e9ae6ac07e543d212"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a resolution or Act, or a title, division, or other subdivision of a resolution or Act, making continuing appropriations for a fiscal year. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfd7cac31401f4c6fb13ae0dabe88cfc7"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Rescissions</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbdefc3f34af94ae9b19f6074dc3e7a1c"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Fiscal year 2026</header><text>For fiscal year 2026, effective on the day after the date on which appropriations are made available through the end of fiscal year 2026 for the entire Federal Government, there is rescinded, on a pro rata basis, 1 percent of the nonsecurity discretionary appropriations made available for fiscal year 2026.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id48923D3AF30C4154B7127895C456605D"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Fiscal year 2027</header><text>For fiscal year 2027, effective on the day after the date on which appropriations are made available through the end of fiscal year 2027 for the entire Federal Government, there is rescinded, on a pro rata basis, 2 percent of the nonsecurity discretionary appropriations made available for such fiscal year. </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5E00B6532F22497F8C2FA493DA814925"><enum>(3)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsequent fiscal years</header><text>For fiscal year 2028, and each fiscal year thereafter, effective on the day after the date on which appropriations are made available through the end of the applicable fiscal year for the entire Federal Government, there is rescinded, on a pro rata basis, 5 percent of the nonsecurity discretionary appropriations made available for such fiscal year. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id8a62e0c2796e4b769d7b4a648e94202c"><enum>(c)</enum><header>OMB reports</header><text>For fiscal year 2026, and each fiscal year thereafter, not later than 30 days after the date on which appropriations are made available through the end of such fiscal year for the entire Federal Government, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall submit to the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives a report specifying the account and amount of each rescission made pursuant to subsection (b). </text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

