<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-HEY25054-33D-NY-CLW"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S95 IS: Parris Island Protection Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 95</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250115">January 15, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S293">Mr. Graham</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S365">Mr. Scott of South Carolina</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To prohibit the use of Federal funds to close or realign the Marine Corps Recruit Depot located at Parris Island, South Carolina.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Parris Island Protection Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idc45ade10723e4627a39ca59956c43212"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="id31fc3221ee5b43e99f566cd55bfc2043"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Marine Corps Recruit Depot located at Parris Island, South Carolina (in this section referred to as <quote>Parris Island</quote>), has served the United States as a home to the Marine Corps since 1891.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idec7984b9a3e649f086dc524cc09d278b"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Parris Island stands as a site of cultural and historical significance to the Marine Corps and the fighting spirit of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id392d7fce695948e8a17ccbceb14e144e"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Parris Island offers various and challenging conditions that have prepared members of the Marine Corps for every major conflict since World War I.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1dcc2152fcbd4deb9872e9d2115bc65f"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Parris Island has cultivated a legacy of excellence and faithful service to the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4782b2d406774e77a653e163cdc99a57"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Parris Island is and shall remain the physical home of the Eastern Recruiting Region of the Marine Corps.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id93321703507642359eeb7e5e2c0288c9"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Continued investments are needed to ensure that Parris Island continues to serve the United States for years to come.</text></paragraph></section><section id="ida68d62d66f4a40fa98dd02d60720c639"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibition of closing or realignment of Marine Corps Recruit Depot located at Parris Island, South Carolina</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No Federal funds may be used to close or realign Marine Corps Recruit Depot, Parris Island, South Carolina, or to conduct any planning or other activity related to such closure or realignment.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

