<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9FF82C578C704E909AACF3B96B34595E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1574 IH: Realizing Engineering, Science, and Technology Opportunities by Restoring Exclusive Patent Rights Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1574</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250225">February 25, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001224">Mr. Moran</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="D000631">Ms. Dean of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000614">Mr. Roy</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 35, United States Code, to establish a rebuttable presumption that a permanent injunction should be granted in certain circumstances, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H063F9876E07E4EF59D41888943A6A6E3" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H2E3201496CA8438C8DBE853F07C8EF4A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Realizing Engineering, Science, and Technology Opportunities by Restoring Exclusive Patent Rights Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>RESTORE Patent Rights Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H8BAF0FE9C80149FCB0ADFEA59247CCA4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
<paragraph id="HE0A4C0FA0DA444EF896805E17C275A66"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Securing effective and reliable patent protection for new technologies is critical to maintaining the competitive advantage of the United States in the global innovation economy.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF78708D64C72400AB2FEDE33D92C8EE2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Constitution of the United States empowers Congress to grant inventors the <quote>exclusive Right</quote> to their inventions in order to <quote>promote the Progress of Science and the useful Arts</quote>.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9F7F28700DAD4422BB652AA32AC73D8F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The right to prevent others from making, using, offering to sell, selling, or importing a patented invention without authority from the inventor is the core of the patent right, ensuring that an inventor enjoys, for a limited time, the sole benefit of the inventor’s invention or discovery.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8F227D63F7B84A4C8B529C8F293927DA"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Congress and the courts of the United States have long secured the constitutionally protected patent right through the traditional equitable remedy of an injunction.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H58A9F9481B1B4D0899B732D6FC95DD6D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Given the irreparable harm that is caused by multiple acts of infringement or willful infringement of a patent, courts historically presumed that an injunction should be granted to prevent such acts, with a burden on defendants to rebut such a presumption with standard equitable defenses.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6ED9B449E7C0455EB2E628F1ED626F2E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Recently, courts have ended the approach described in paragraph (5), which contradicts the traditional, historical practice governing the equitable remedy described in that paragraph.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H34530EA234404484A63FD33F2EBFC979"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Eliminating the traditional, historical equitable practice of applying a rebuttable presumption of injunctive relief in the case of continuing acts of infringement or willful infringement of a patent has—</text> <subparagraph id="H1B40B4DFB6E743588B729BD7E353D47C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>substantially reduced the ability of patent owners to obtain injunctions to stop continuing or willful infringement of patents; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H3C87EF734EBE4FE185A0305434020D34"><enum>(B)</enum><text>created incentives for large, multinational companies to commit predatory acts of infringement, especially with respect to patents owned by undercapitalized entities, such as individual inventors, institutions of higher education, startups, and small or medium-sized enterprises.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> <section id="HC2A24AC0F77147B9883A2C06AD7643DB"><enum>3.</enum><header>Rebuttable presumption that injunctive relief is warranted</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 283 of title 35, United States Code, is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="HFE906CB18A8B40B282192D32FAC75EFE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>The several</quote> and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H04DB1B6C724C40E5927EF2CCF93B0D01" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H223F4D6A703D49C3A92CBD955544118E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The several</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE1966CEE469A4507BAB428D85429BA66"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H477611927CD84A8096E5CEBE0041FC41" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HCD9901A31F02459E9EC649049C527C1D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rebuttable presumption</header><text>If, in a case under this title, the court enters a final judgment finding infringement of a right secured by patent, the patent owner shall be entitled to a rebuttable presumption that the court should grant a permanent injunction with respect to that infringing conduct.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

