<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ELL25381-MF7-D4-5NW"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2533 IS: Pick Up After Your DOGE Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2533</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250730">July 30, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S316">Mr. Whitehouse</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S366">Ms. Warren</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require performance and security audits of certain agency computer systems, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Pick Up After Your DOGE Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id0cd46001297648529ee13a72c9abae2e"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <term>appropriate congressional committee</term> means any committee with jurisdiction over an agency that is the subject of an audit under this Act.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="idaa7640ef4b1c496486793235e76dca7b"><enum>3.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">United States DOGE service access to data</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the United States DOGE Service shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees and the Comptroller General of the United States a full accounting of all Federal agencies where agency DOGE teams, as defined in Executive Order 14158 (90 Fed. Reg. 8441; relating to establishing and implementing the President's Department of Government Efficiency), or individuals acting on behalf of, or at the instruction of, the United States DOGE Service or agency DOGE teams, accessed Federal agency computer systems, networks, data, or information.</text></section><section id="id09a9567552504d82840fe1c0146199c6"><enum>4.</enum><header>Comptroller General studies</header><subsection id="id131820f12e0c4d719ad6624020286d42"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall commence a comprehensive audit of Federal agency computer systems and networks accessed by the United States DOGE Service, the U.S. DOGE Service Temporary Organization, or any employees or volunteers affiliated with those agencies, or, if applicable, associated agency DOGE teams, to identify security vulnerabilities or bugs in software installed, created, or modified by the United States DOGE Service, the U.S. DOGE Service Temporary Organization, or any employees or volunteers affiliated with those agencies, or, if applicable, associated agency DOGE teams.</text></subsection><subsection id="id01b63353cd5b467891a948020768fe6b"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Priority review</header><text>In conducting the audits described in subsection (a), the Comptroller General shall give priority to reviews of the systems, networks, and databases of the Social Security Administration, the Department of Health and Human Services and the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services, and the Department of the Treasury and the Internal Revenue Service.</text></subsection><subsection id="id7bc0b837e7864391b66193f0eb202fcb"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Initial Audit Results</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees and agency heads a report or reports describing the results of the comprehensive systems audits performed under subsection (a) for the Social Security Administration, the Department of Health and Human Services and the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services, and the Department of the Treasury and the Internal Revenue Service, including recommendations for legislation and administrative action as the Comptroller General determines appropriate.</text></subsection><subsection id="idf9901d5315ed4adaa35053d6de8d2fd6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Final audit results</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees and agency heads a report or reports describing the results of the comprehensive systems audits performed under subsection (a) for other Federal agencies selected for review by the Comptroller General, in consultation with the appropriate congressional committees, including recommendations for legislation and administrative actions as the Comptroller General determines appropriate.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9b22ea73fe3d4bf297de15acaeac8887"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Agency action</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after receipt of an audit report by an agency head under subsections (c) or (d), the agency head shall—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id353d64392afe440c9f6447ed989a7e63"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">fix any vulnerabilities or bugs identified in the report; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idae936863a04240edb7718cdad249e671"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submit to the appropriate committee of jurisdiction a report on the status of those vulnerabilities or bugs.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

