<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2F5C0AABB84F4FD490DBACEAD8FE6A14" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5059 IH: Specialty Crop Domestic Market Promotion and Development Program Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5059</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250826">August 26, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000129">Mr. Valadao</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="H001090">Mr. Harder of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000578">Mr. LaMalfa</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Specialty Crops Competitiveness Act of 2004 to direct the Secretary of Agriculture to establish a program under which the Secretary will award grants to eligible organizations to encourage the development, maintenance, and expansion of commercial domestic market for domestically produced specialty crop commodities.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H268D800EEE424674921BB2315C9B33E8" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H3DB92B209FA041B4B676FF187C69619E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Specialty Crop Domestic Market Promotion and Development Program Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H8163961D2857424E9E0EB06AE44C3508"><enum>2.</enum><header>Specialty crop domestic market promotion and development program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title II of the Specialty Crops Competitiveness Act of 2004 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/7712a">7 U.S.C. 7712a et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H0FF9C0102A9C46A8BA228EBDB7B67AB0" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="HB4B34590D0074632A92BF06815D9FB19"><enum>204.</enum><header>Specialty crop domestic market promotion and development program</header> 
<subsection id="H7D863886C5B64EC4A3AE298C39C13716"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of encouraging the development, maintenance, and expansion of the commercial domestic market for domestically produced specialty crop commodities, the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Administrator of the Agricultural Marketing Service, shall establish a program under which the Secretary will award grants to eligible organizations to implement a domestic market development program for specialty crops.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H01FD93A6DA044B88830DAD90E36F15A1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible organization seeking a grant under this section shall submit to the Secretary—</text> 
<paragraph id="HE1A34BE91FCD4FA1AF9C60AFCF5A3F83"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB4895DF70A524283BA60473DA7668E77"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a marketing plan that meets the requirements of subsection (c); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8369FA371B944B9C9685BE8CACE9D4F6"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a certification that any Federal funds received by such organization under this section will supplement, but not supplant, funds from non-Federal sources (including a private entity) to carry out a domestic market development program for specialty crops.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H1CA9E5FDBD374C9BB4329F5311E15C7C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Marketing plan</header> <paragraph id="H5D38806FC1C74BE38D70979F3BD6FD3C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A marketing plan submitted under subsection (b) shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HDF0A6E162695445F9F893228DAA38133"><enum>(A)</enum><text>describe the advertising or other demand-oriented, generic domestic promotion activities to be carried out by the eligible organization using funds awarded through a grant under this section; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE121CBBDC092432C9E1E044FAE1C7D4B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>contain—</text> 
<clause id="H379773A3F78A401BB882318AF2383C8F"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of the manner in which funds received by the eligible organization through a grant under this section, in conjunction with funds and services provided by the eligible organization, will be expended in implementing the marketing plan;</text></clause> <clause id="H9931E960A4374B35A324C8E849CCD594"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the market goals to be achieved under the marketing plan; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H8EE7D2F036854B8CB1CDB579B135CB5B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>such additional information as may be required by the Secretary.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7AE8A60147BB410E8181ECE2617A148A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Amendments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A marketing plan approved under this section may be amended by the eligible organization submitting such plan at any time, subject to the approval of the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA091C081E5B54967B980519865F0CC28"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Amount of grant</header> 
<paragraph id="H978F258BF4504B44AAFB161C48CF7375"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall justify, in writing, the level of funds awarded through a grant to an eligible organization and the level of matching funds to be required of the organization.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4BF423386275424D9DAE6E560FF3D2CE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Matching funds</header><text>The recipient of a grant under this section shall provide non-Federal matching funds equal to not less than 25 percent of the amount of the grant, or such other amount determined by the Secretary pursuant to paragraph (1).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC5F03E88A43541558F6FBDBC51FBF9A6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>In-kind support</header><text>Non-Federal matching funds described in paragraph (2) may include in-kind support.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H22488874470B4B30B0157588C3BB8833"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Multiyear basis</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may provide assistance under this section on a multiyear basis. The Secretary shall conduct an annual review of any grant awarded on a multiyear basis to ensure that the eligible organization has complied with the marketing plan submitted under subsection (c).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF73CC6C0BB8B4CC89FE817CAD9CD8F79"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Termination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may terminate any grant made, or to be made, under this section if the Secretary determines that the eligible organization receiving such grant—</text> <paragraph id="H1A47D79472C447338F597CFA9D9A0686"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is not adhering to the terms and conditions applicable to the grant;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF952A5F2A5B144D491F9045BA011DF0B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is not implementing the marketing plan submitted under subsection (b) or is not adequately meeting the established goals of the plan; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1BD925C191D74914AEF2096712D7E1E1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>is not adequately contributing its own resources to the implementation of the plan.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC91E1AC5F419486EA132DB30ED0F5602"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Evaluations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning not later than 15 months after the first grant is awarded under this section to an eligible organization, the Secretary shall monitor the expenditures by eligible organizations made using grant funds, including the following:</text> <paragraph id="H3BF3CCC8A0094E3E96D887E2FDF38068"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A thorough accounting of such expenditures.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H376CAA5E8F25404E805A9DB643156671"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An evaluation of the effectiveness of the marketing plan of the eligible organization in developing, maintaining, or expanding the commercial domestic market for specialty crops.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H4268732484FD41DB8C8381D7C17751AA"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Limitation on use of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Funds received through a grant under this section may not be used—</text> 
<paragraph id="H81EDD5D8BCFA41BBAF3B2B0B6B5C6C45"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to provide direct assistance to any domestic or foreign for-profit corporation for the corporation’s use in promoting foreign-produced products; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE89D75D023F444DA8DECE1C3D46D1E14"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to provide direct assistance to any for-profit corporation that is not recognized as a small business concern (as described in section 3(a) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/632">15 U.S.C. 632(a)</external-xref>)), other than—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H7850185DF4594372B2C0F1AB086D8CC7">
                                <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>a cooperative;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H853BE9F3EBBD4A58893FA3F2E61A6AC3"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>an association described in the Act of February 18, 1922 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/291">7 U.S.C. 291</external-xref>); or</text>
              </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1E0DD9E9E29A49FB939EFBADCFC94BAC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a nonprofit trade association.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H5F6B726F5CFB4DDCA08A0215CDD3B910"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Audits</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If, as a result of an evaluation or audit of activities of an eligible organization using funds made available through a grant under this section, the Secretary determines that a further review is justified in order to ensure compliance with the requirements of this section, the Secretary shall require the eligible organization to contract for an independent audit of the activities carried out using funds awarded under a grant under this section, including activities of any subcontractor of an eligible organization.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H94E388184EBF4B74B23663AD0DB6A32A"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Eligible organization defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <quote>eligible organization</quote> means—</text> <paragraph id="HDA10909145454CCBA531E9375B7E2FFE"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a United States agricultural trade organization or regional State-related organization that promotes the sale of United States produced and grown specialty crops and that does not profit directly from specific sales of United States specialty crops;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H51BF1DC70CAE4AF8A462779E50F714F0"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a cooperative organization or State agency that promotes the sale of United States produced and grown specialty crops;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6139B36075684519B249CE837E5A140D"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a private organization that promotes the sale of United States produced and grown specialty crop commodities if the Secretary determines that such organization would significantly contribute to increased domestic purchases of United States produced specialty crop commodities; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H633AAADE94284B038A5BDEB7FB1D75BA"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a specialty crop organization operating under Federal marketing orders.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H75D35E6B8CAE4077ACDCAC82295C76F6"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Funding</header> <paragraph id="H6210DDA85E8C41558C66BC3B9E63D93C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $75,000,000 for fiscal year 2026 and each fiscal year thereafter.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H06F4D7859214449293DE581B4625099E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administrative expenses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may use funds made available under paragraph (1) to carry out this section for a fiscal year for expenses related to administering the program under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> </legis-body></bill>

