<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-RIL25616-N4T-L4-CYF">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2010 IS: Transparency in Enforcement, Restricting, and Monitoring of Services Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
<congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>S. 2010</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
<action>
<action-date date="20250610">June 10, 2025</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S355">Mr. Cruz</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S416">Mrs. Britt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S374">Mr. Cotton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S266">Mr. Crapo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S410">Ms. Lummis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S411">Mr. Marshall</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S323">Mr. Risch</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S420">Mr. Schmitt</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title>To require online service providers to disclose their acceptable use policies, provide users with written notice before the termination of a user’s account, and publish an annual report detailing actions taken to enforce their acceptable use policies, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H2D4144A8762B4918A908E98D7EBBD50F">
<section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Transparency in Enforcement, Restricting, and Monitoring of Services Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>TERMS Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="idff4ee71bc2134ace812d4216316b4dca"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purpose of this Act is to ensure that consumers, businesses, and organizations seeking to use the products or services of an online service provider have sufficient information regarding the online service provider’s commercial business standards, processes, and policies with respect to the unilateral termination, suspension, or cancellation of user accounts or ability to use the online service provider’s products or services. Such information allows consumers to make informed choices regarding their decision to use or purchase the services or products of an online service provider and promotes a competitive marketplace for such products or services.</text></section>
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="id405710cb462c4e8fb39dc0bd7e01fe8d"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="id5be94c7ad2084a96a657f4e31b183475"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Federal Trade Commission.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id564d1aa0db694cdf9b99957085d67e39"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Nonprofit organization</header><text>The term <term>nonprofit organization</term> has the meaning given such term in section 201(i) of title 35, United States Code.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4ae6da4cdb154e82a2b17579f0690c07"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Online service provider</header><text>The term <term>online service provider</term>—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id070904dd7f7c4b4ba40a630774aa8af5"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means the provider of a public-facing website, online service, or online application directed to a consumer or organization that—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1a5bd40be13246bcaed2ee11c9d9dc3c"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">requires any person who wishes to use the website, online service, or online application to create a unique account or profile for such website, service, or application;</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5282bef77c0649c6a6bb7f37b1ccf80a"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provides an internet-based product or service that is accessible through the website, online service, or online application; and</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6372cbdceb3f480aa04098a8ade5efcf"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>is engaged in interstate or foreign commerce; and</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ideba33aacf38b410f9959a995867fa535"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes any entity described in subparagraph (A), regardless of whether—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbe3d734118e045a39f98bbc4195b688f"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">offering a product or service to the general public is the sole source of income or principal business of such entity; or</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc8c874c634da4974b4ee1712af52f9df"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the entity earns a profit on a product or service.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id50583aaa07e7459d8bae25b2247cddd3"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Restrict</header><text>The term <term>restrict</term>, with respect to a user, means an online service provider’s termination or suspension of a user’s account or profile on the online service provider’s website, online service, or online application, or limitation of the user’s access thereto based on a determination that the user violated the online service provider’s acceptable use policy.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc979c50c7c244e279aab35fb3a09719f"><enum>(5)</enum><header>User</header><text>The term <term>user</term> means, with respect to an online service provider, a person who registers an account or creates a profile on the website, online service, or online application of the online service provider.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="id11fdfc50798c4ddaa3775a500f721349"><enum>4.</enum><header>Disclosure of acceptable use policies</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id46629ebd6b3443dd95d26246a8c3173c"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act and subject to subsection (b), an online service provider shall publicly disclose in an easily accessible manner, such as within terms of service available on the online service provider’s website, an acceptable use policy that concisely and accurately describes, in clear language, information regarding the standards, processes, and policies of the online service provider with respect to any decision by the online service provider to restrict a user.</text></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3a0cec1fbb0b4b258581554e399cbbdf"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Required information</header><text>For purposes of subsection (a), an online service provider shall include the following information in an acceptable use policy:</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4fa4351083334c7295215e7335e0e0b0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An explanation of what specific acts or practices are prohibited by the online service provider that could lead to a decision by the online service provider to restrict a user.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcad0b59888104e8783d1c35d04d01f76"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An explanation of how the online service provider enforces the acceptable use policy, including any third party the online service provider relies upon, in whole or in part, to assist in the enforcement of the acceptable use policy by the online service provider.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id343e52670fb148de91ca24ec19168d47"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Either—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd3f0db0fc7ba4a86ab0954f43065d219"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an explanation of how a user can appeal, if applicable, a decision by an online service provider to restrict a user; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id575c30a15e7045b780d9372b2acee091"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if the online service provider does not permit an appeal or reconsideration of a decision to restrict a user, a statement that such decision is not appealable or subject to reconsideration.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide05615852e0540c8b1342a1d6f7c8442"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An explanation of whether acts or practices a user commits entirely outside of the website, online service, or online application of the online service provider, such as social media posts, public statements, media publications, and third-party resources, may be a sufficient basis alone or in combination with other information to restrict a user.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idff97e6849ab840d9a6dae03571dc59da"><enum>(5)</enum><text>An explanation of the online service provider’s standards, processes, and policies with respect to the notice requirement described in section 5.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id394c701ca18041a1b5f782490f8654b9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Changes to acceptable use policies</header><text>If an online service provider makes a material change to its acceptable use policy that would result in a material change to any information described in subsection (b), the online service provider shall, taking into account available technology, provide advance notice to each user.</text></subsection></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="idbdb81870671f4d1fb6d8ccaa91678892"><enum>5.</enum><header>Advance written notice prior to termination or suspension</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7711749dcb3b4f61a1faeb4cc6dae174"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notice requirement</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id17e67820b7f44ffb83c16e50edabe8ef"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>Except as described in subsection (b), an online service provider shall provide advance written notice to a user in violation of the online service provider’s acceptable use policy prior to restricting the user.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8f991648a9e44abc9da0936778461e72"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Required information</header><text>The advance written notice required under paragraph (1) shall include the following information:</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2971557b92be45d5a840d125f3feaf2a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The specific act or practice of the user that led to the decision to restrict the user.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7ee84403cb60448483f8d61869daa4fc"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A description of how the act or practice identified in subparagraph (A) violated the acceptable use policy.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd5875233c56346b9a0441768853838a1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether the user has an option to appeal the decision, and, if so, a description of the process for how the user can appeal the online service provider’s decision, consistent with the acceptable use policy.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2dd5f1dca42a402e82bac312e3620c7e"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A description of the option for the user to elect that the online service provider publicly disclose such written notice as described in paragraph (4).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idce63f53fccde40a3888838f1b6ed8caf"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Advance written notice</header> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idff56b59958514f73baf4f4eb02577809"><enum>(A)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>For the purposes of this section, an online service provider will be deemed to have provided an advance written notice to a user if such provider makes a good faith effort to notify the user not later than 7 days prior to restricting the user.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc15dc82a1a2d491687e85fae95f8a981"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Good faith effort</header><text>For the purposes of subparagraph (A), a good faith effort may include—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0fe60aeb3c7b43bf83e037cdb556f220"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a notification to the most recent email address or other contact information the user provided to the online service provider; or</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id813ca288ca0c450abc331c7571da0ca2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if the online service provider does not have any contact information for the user, a prominent notice that is displayed to the user on the online service provider’s website, service, or application when the user next accesses the user’s account or profile on such website, service, or application.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd138e7beb6874697a9e2c3002e44c401"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Public disclosure</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An online service provider shall—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4f8dfebc10c74b5f9af730f1b25a632c"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide to any user issued a written notice under paragraph (1) an option for the online service provider to publicly disclose such notice; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id03c19c4a748647e090e722440e0ef5ff"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if such user chooses to have such notice publicly disclosed, publish such notice on the website of the online service provider.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idba2adf94f9ef4654837cdee5b0dbde7f"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exceptions for court action or imminent risk of harm</header><text>An online service provider may restrict a user without advance written notice if—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8e69589571c8465eb8a9f93a3038032e"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such restriction was done to—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9d9823fb4bd2430c9b30fa9fdf7df257"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">comply with a lawful order of a court of competent jurisdiction;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbaf19eff379e4b9fbb94ab10c3d553d8"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">comply with Federal law; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9cb79d7ce1334a8eafa7dab77439095d"><enum>(C)</enum><text>protect against an imminent risk of—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id17f44182ae0c470f91b62bb67c5c397d"><enum>(i)</enum><text>death;</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3581622d766e4d67ada7af429c54496a"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a serious physical injury; or</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id86cd5285f2e04218accd5a966db56e42"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a serious health risk; and</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6f809fc09da5489d8da539cb4854a6c2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the online service provider provides the user the information required by subsection (a)(2) and publicly discloses the written notice at the same time that the provider restricts the user or as soon as practicable thereafter.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2eb33f5a8c814b6b8a126abf10c16eda"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The requirements of this section shall take effect on the date that is 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section>
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="id24d7f6a99e064b54aa474fabc1e225fb"><enum>6.</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idea0d66ec8f7e40cba3e2b4cec7fe70d7"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>Annual report</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act and annually thereafter on a date to be determined by each online service provider, an online service provider shall publish, with an open license, in both a format easily read by humans and a machine-readable format, in a location on its public website that is easily accessible to users and visitors of such website, and consistent with the requirements described in subsections (b) and (c), a report detailing actions taken to enforce the online service provider’s acceptable use policy.</text> </subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8708ba2f7e9b4327b95a544078f0ed93"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report required under subsection (a) shall include the following information with respect to the applicable reporting period:</text>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id606f06d8b9804be1910623a4ef6197f7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The total number of instances in which the online service provider was alerted of a potential violation of the acceptable use policy by—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6fd99519185a4f6ea3bf026fd29e0281"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a user complaint;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0e78814e30b94fd9b4f16edf17fa790b"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an employee of, or a person contracting with, the online service provider;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id35fe6d96be9f4a34a2ab9d2ffc4132d4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an internal automated detection tool of the online service provider;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7a89ecd182474bfe85511281b91bb74d"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a government entity, including the specific office or entity that alerted the online service provider;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id071dd70125434bd6be0920519600dab9"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a nonprofit organization; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide29958f1f3aa4fbc92dbbcd554fe1489"><enum>(F)</enum><text>any other person.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide1d4364d2df94fe891f63cb20efb80a7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Subject to subsection (c), the number of instances in which the online service provider took steps to restrict a user, including the number of instances in which the online service provider—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idef92cc79e8de425ca7022a8f0550f7a3"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">terminated a user’s account or profile on the online service provider’s website, online service, or online application or otherwise permanently limited access to or use of the product or service of the online service provider;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idda07e637b850445a98dd03596b37dcc3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>suspended a user’s account or profile on the online service provider’s website, online service, or online application;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id949e6ff846da4b428aba73b25c36bafb"><enum>(C)</enum><text>limited a user’s access to the online service provider’s website, online service, or online application; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb2aca72e14ba41668f720c7209a71eaf"><enum>(D)</enum><text>took any other action, such as issuing a warning, in response to a violation of the acceptable use policy.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd32c339c3cdb4bcaaba78ad5351ad1f1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The number of instances in which a user appealed the online service provider’s decision.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida6683a71f00347c3801069a20613d97b"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The number of appeals that resulted in a reversal of the online service provider’s decision.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id069313da9eff4881832acf8d42a3100a"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Categorization of actions taken</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The information described in subsection (b)(2) shall be categorized by—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7baee7891ceb4ad6aebc4101e402f0e1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the exact provision of the acceptable use policy that was violated by a user; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id98564cdaacb04b7f9b6bbab50d6b9847"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the source of the alert of the potential violation of the acceptable use policy as described in subsection (b)(1).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="idf0f4d1894903463bbb02ef639a1768cf"><enum>7.</enum><header>Enforcement</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaa4dab787a1346fbbd7a751ac52ea4cf"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Enforcement by the Commission</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida2ce0f3be4b246aaad3bf3284ae3e555"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Unfair or deceptive acts or practices</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A violation of this Act shall be treated as a violation of a rule defining an unfair or deceptive act or practice under section 18(a)(1)(B) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/57a">15 U.S.C. 57a(a)(1)(B)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf8b6359a48f2417d9e87c39eea4668b6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Powers of the Commission</header>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddf7c5d4285054bcf89a461d25ec067c6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subparagraph (C), the Commission shall enforce this Act in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though all applicable terms and provisions of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>) were incorporated into and made a part of this Act.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9381b6ac080d4df1bcd97018dea00f9b"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Privileges and immunities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subparagraph (C), any online service provider who violates this Act or a regulation promulgated under this Act shall be subject to the penalties and entitled to the privileges and immunities provided in the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id05901d4d36aa4d2ca4fb10e8d979a9fb"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Nonprofit organizations</header><text>Notwithstanding section 4, 5(a)(2), or 6 of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/44">15 U.S.C. 44</external-xref>, 45(a)(2), 46) or any jurisdictional limitation of the Commission, the Commission shall also enforce this Act, in the same manner provided in subparagraphs (A) and (B), with respect to organizations not organized to carry on business for their own profit or that of their members.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id672cff93ed2a4655b5366e52bbb2eeba"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Authority preserved</header><text>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to limit the authority of the Commission under any other provision of law.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb7fe394e94944433a16d8422450bad61"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Commission guidance</header>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcb62524b97e643238e7d13b1eb1d6ec6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Commission shall issue guidance to assist online service providers in complying with the requirements of this Act, which shall include the provision of best practices and examples.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8c8412e81cd341dbb47501bbd56036c0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation on guidance</header><text>No guidance issued by the Commission with respect to this Act shall—</text>
<subparagraph id="idaba673fbd89f468fadf7597b921a4edf"><enum>(A)</enum><text>confer any rights on any person, State, or locality; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id558b8d5edb194125abf6e4f90e65efdc"><enum>(B)</enum><text>operate to bind the Commission or any person to the approach recommended in such guidance.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id76b76f0720c04a12b3b447c0237d60d3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Use in enforcement actions</header><text>In any enforcement action brought pursuant to this Act—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4a1f8f715ea74cc5a10822b4fa2048a8"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Commission—</text>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcb19b5d5415b44b090f27803beda38cf"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall allege a specific violation of a provision of this Act; and</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id595c3eea93164c659c9c65a6f2ba410a"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>may not base such enforcement on, or execute a consent order based on, practices that are alleged to be inconsistent with any guidance issued by the Commission with respect to this Act, unless the practices are alleged to violate a provision of this Act; and</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9a14008ab4cd4dc1846459827b3e861a"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a person may use compliance with any such guidance as evidence of compliance with this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

