<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H781DBB36853C4BC7A2D962CEFC0B118D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1289 IH: Veterans Nutrition and Wellness Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1289</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250213">February 13, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001260">Mr. Buchanan</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to establish and carry out a pilot program to administer to eligible veterans medically-tailored meals and groceries, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H99005FE4100C46B9A3333F867500EE7F" style="OLC"><section id="HEC98AAAD13634CBAAAD5B70888F2B86D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Veterans Nutrition and Wellness Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H27B8115DEFDA4571996DCDB77F3AA539"><enum>2.</enum><header>Department of Veterans Affairs pilot program to administer medically-tailored meals and groceries to certain eligible veterans</header><subsection id="H5802AC0FBA6F40239720E6BEE2AE8583"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall establish and carry out a pilot program (to be known as the <quote>Food is Medicine program</quote>).</text></subsection><subsection id="H9367B2E44AD74C60AB0ABD718B0F3A83"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Functions</header><text>Under the Food is Medicine program, the Secretary shall,</text><paragraph id="H47BB2816793F4AE4A32DF26FE3CE3FF4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>with respect to eligible veterans described in subsection (c)—</text><subparagraph id="H47316A825F034EAF918C522258043C24"><enum>(A)</enum><text>administer medically-tailored meals and medically-tailored groceries; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAB9B8ADC47A74CE69444FF631438A6DD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>furnish nutrition education and cooking classes through a registered dieticians, nutritionists, and community health workers;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H26BD8ACDC3DB4397B9CD49E05EB1C13B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>develop and seek to implement training programs for health care providers employed by the Department of Veterans Affairs with respect to the integration of the Food is Medicine program in the treatment plans of veterans receiving health care under the laws administered by the Secretary; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H52639895C82F4C65B2FEAF4CBC59B042"><enum>(3)</enum><text>seek to collaborate with community-based organizations, including food banks and local agriculture programs, to—</text><subparagraph id="H744CBDE148D94A6698A9643F82210646"><enum>(A)</enum><text>procure fresh and locally-sourced produce; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBA5DEE383FF54BDA943C35EDE146CA86"><enum>(B)</enum><text>expand the availability of medically-tailored meals and medically-tailored groceries.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9E74E4230C7440D6AD4B838E42CCD91B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible veteran described in this subsection is a veteran (as defined in section 101 of title 38, United States Code) who is enrolled in the system of annual patient enrollment established and operated under section 1705 of such section and—</text><paragraph id="H170A90C182734F2E8816518B220E44CA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">receives health care furnished by the Department with respect to multiple chronic conditions, including diabetes, cancer, or heart failure; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4CFD5B81CB96491981DE849EDE3B4C7F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>receives such health care with respect to maternal health, including prenatal care, labor and delivery care, postpartum care, and is at risk of preeclampsia or gestational diabetes. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB1DBE41EFDCC4605A9DE2AE95751E170"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Regional balance</header><text>In carrying out the Food is Medicine program, the Secretary shall, to the maximum extent practicable ensure geographic diversity of the pilot program offices of the Food is Medicine program.</text></subsection><subsection id="H863B7DB405CF40D5AE1BD8C7682F1440"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report</header><text>During the period the authority to carry out the Food is Medicine program is effective, the Secretary shall submit to Congress an annual report on such program that includes—</text><paragraph id="HC31F58F6788D4820A19DB17472E96577"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the number of eligible veterans participating in such program;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9C3393FD76774F50A5289FDBC863679E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>with respect to such eligible veterans, a summary of—</text><subparagraph id="H32CA56A9A09B4F60B7813CAB3ECB730C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>health outcomes;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3938BF6231AA4D0585B70081F2010AC5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>effects on physical and mental health;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEF1170E36B364D04BE8F1689EDD46E9A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>quality of life; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB3DF37A5194A43B68E7D95CC8E2D5283"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the extent of utilization of health care under the laws administered by the Secretary;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0EE4C092576F438C8097A89DA6B0DE4D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an evaluation of the effectiveness of such program, including estimated cost savings to the Department of Veterans Affairs; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4DB90E39F3FE453B948A55F57EF47629"><enum>(4)</enum><text>recommendations of the Secretary with respect to potential improvements to such program. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2DCDFCB3EEFB49A8BDA060A3C98C9076"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><paragraph id="H528E83B0D3704508AA0490D9294EFCF8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2), there are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary for fiscal years 2025 through 2028 such sums as may be necessary to carry out the Food is Medicine program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB100D602E1F44D7B87D61645886E75AB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>Any amounts appropriated pursuant to paragraph (1) shall be used for—</text><subparagraph id="H11593B83BB84450FB7FE91E8CF918960"><enum>(A)</enum><text>developing and operating the Food is Medicine program;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFB728FFF3D4F46858FD8E659296CF453"><enum>(B)</enum><text>hiring registered dieticians and nutrition specialists;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF3A0ECC4BC06449DA481BD7CD87C73E4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>conducting research and evaluations; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEDABC9733CFA4F03B8994759136FD894"><enum>(D)</enum><text>establishing partnerships with local organizations pursuant to subsection (b)(3).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF0488B4D34D043F5888D0CBFB0B8C1D0"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Termination date</header><text>The authority of the Secretary to carry out the Food is Medicine program shall terminate on the date that is three years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1D9CFD499FAD4B049873887091C22B4E"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H768C3B3862A346B39A88ADE87EF4459C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <quote>medically-tailored groceries</quote> means nutritious food for an individual with a diet-sensitive condition curated to the treatment plan of such individual.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD495DFEE1C5A4FD997A3EBDFDD042DBA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <quote>medically-tailored meals</quote> means nutritious meals customized for an individual with a severe chronic condition or limitation in activities of daily living.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

