<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ERN25317-L4K-WK-MT3"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1985 IS: Safe Operations of Shared Airspace Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code>II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1985</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250605">June 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S275">Ms. Cantwell</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S327">Mr. Warner</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S415">Mr. Warnock</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To improve aviation safety, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7def21a1bd7944019195058762933217"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Safe Operations of Shared Airspace Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id95f3e409ab3940e0b6a19de3c29de2e8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text><toc><toc-entry level="section" idref="S1">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id779e9ad65ad446e5af2b481a66f4ce6e">Sec. 2. Definitions.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id43673bca645b495e8aae2bce3d27c657">Sec. 3. Expert compliance review of FAA Safety Management System.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idfb6c7ed9be654b40a5313339085961d9">Sec. 4. ADS–B Out Reforms.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id3827b87325444655a9d1ec38aa59f2ed">Sec. 5. ADS–B In requirement to enhance safety.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idcc1fcdbb831b4521a899b2b415f9de98">Sec. 6. Safety reviews of airspace.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id95c519c12ff44448ac975b2ba08f251a">Sec. 7. FAA-Department of Defense Safety Information Sharing.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idabdd530fd4f64939b6d8c0f3adcd7427">Sec. 8. No disruptions to FAA workforce.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id41ce2f73048e44889dc47fa2d37b8426">Sec. 9. Extension of FAA air traffic controller max hiring requirement.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="ide10e0b020bfb4d3ca6b80c5c5a8b2cb4">Sec. 10. Air traffic controller training improvements.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id7f485d2e15b641c2974ab666008613d9">Sec. 11. TARAM analyses.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id18344cb276de453c8aa26cc16ab61446">Sec. 12. Employee reporting.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id0c2b00e907b04c9fb7607db52dd3cf26">Sec. 13. Conflicts of interest.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id779e9ad65ad446e5af2b481a66f4ce6e"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddc895a13c7664aab94c6db83c715fb00"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the FAA.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id20fede39c8734052920c57f9a7858154"> <enum>(2)</enum> <header>ADS–B in</header> <text>The term <term>ADS–B In</term> means onboard avionics technology that periodically receives ADS–B Out broadcasts of an aircraft's state vector (3-dimensional position and 3-dimensional velocity) and other required information as described in part 91.277 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation).</text>
            </paragraph><paragraph id="idf5971258e1dd4b53a3f3fc4d3ee956c5">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
                <header>ADS–B out</header>
 <text>The term <term>ADS–B Out</term> has the meaning given such term in section 91.227 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ida2fba0acb1784969acd45ca17965faf0"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Air carrier; foreign air carrier</header><text>The terms <term>air carrier</term> and <term>foreign air carrier</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 40102 of title 49, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id98230746fed6457580cd2650c2ea58de"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of congress</header><text>The term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbd37e59c59f24321840dae90033d7f20" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Cabinet member</header><text>The term <term>Cabinet Member</term> means an individual who is the head (including an acting head) of the Department of Agriculture, Department of Commerce, Department of Defense, Department of Education, Department of Energy, Department of Health and Human Services, Department of Homeland Security, Department of Housing and Urban Development, Department of the Interior, Department of Justice, Department of Labor, Department of State, Department of Transportation, Department of the Treasury, or Department of Veterans Affairs, or any other individual who occupies a position designated by the President as a Cabinet-level position.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id83d7d48714d741f199c53dd3b66dd647"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Comptroller General</header><text>The term <term>Comptroller General</term> means the Comptroller General of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb4c949ababe84103b18a4564c0f17c26"><enum>(8)</enum><header>FAA</header><text>The term <term>FAA</term> means the Federal Aviation Administration.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7efb2c0eb3d84a17a0ca6bf4ae84f1e5"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Powered-lift</header><text>The term <term>powered-lift</term> has the meaning given such term in section 1.1 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id492281be1a964ac9a1f7ed54cea00d5a"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Rotorcraft</header><text>The term <term>rotorcraft</term> has the meaning given such term in section 1.1 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1f6d877a553444a0851a5f90ba696fd9"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Transportation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2a6d15094b6e4b47b711291348422f9e"><enum>(12)</enum><header>SMS</header><text>The term <term>SMS</term> means a safety management system.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id91bf3c2c23d94bd1ba4978f96e9decb5"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Transport airplane</header><text>The term <term>transport airplane</term> means a transport category airplane designed for operation by an air carrier or foreign air carrier type-certificated with a passenger seating capacity of 30 or more or an all-cargo or combi derivative.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id64615172c2154c8fa7993ecf5b7f6c0d"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Unmanned aircraft system</header><text>The term <term><quote>unmanned aircraft system</quote></term> has the meaning given such term in section 44801 of title 49, United States Code.</text></paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id43673bca645b495e8aae2bce3d27c657">
            <enum>3.</enum>
            <header>Expert compliance review of FAA Safety Management System</header>
            <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                id="ide6237bfa8e53465ebb10eb213126ce4d">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Expert compliance review</header>
                <paragraph id="id2302b03be71f4b8f858899fbdf65f5b1">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                    <header>Establishment</header>
                    <subparagraph id="id53ba4f9e1090411da5237d5bcce23012">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
                        <header>In general</header>
 <text>Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this section, the Administrator shall convene an independent expert panel (in this section referred to as the <quote>review panel</quote>) to review and make findings and recommendations on the matters listed in paragraph (2).</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="idff4645a2bdb7412c889b2a917202d215">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
                        <header>Purpose</header>
 <text>The purpose of the review panel is to review and evaluate FAA orders and policies to inform the FAA’s implementation of a comprehensive and integrated SMS for all lines of business within the FAA.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id9f3ba134b7c04bdfbaff18abd60e130e">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Contents of review</header>
 <text>The review panel shall review the following:</text> <subparagraph id="id76e89ac7a363468ea45ce747d602c59c"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>The extent to which the FAA’s SMS complies with relevant FAA orders and policies.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id0de1608969f64e30bcde33421542989a">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>The actual and projected safety enhancements achieved through the FAA’s prior implementation of SMS.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id153fd54d959f464d8944765cf8ac45d6">
                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>The effectiveness of SMS, including with respect to the implementation of the following 4 components:</text>
                        <clause id="ida171bd335eac4f23812d98f79e34a966">
                            <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>Safety policy.</text> </clause> <clause id="id22e12b754d614091873cdec899b8c528"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>Safety risk management.</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="id3ab09225164549f99eb9bb444ce19f58">
                            <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>Safety assurance.</text> </clause> <clause id="id0f5f95f23922490bbfaacad9dc3e692a"> <enum>(iv)</enum> <text>Safety promotion.</text>
                        </clause>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id6ca32317ba4240c2b41c5bdd0e7f2fb1">
                        <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>The extent to which SMS and each of the 4 components described in subparagraph (C) are integrated among and across all lines of business of the FAA.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id2ceb44df2ebe45f1afa1bf0801786799">
                        <enum>(E)</enum>
 <text>The extent to which SMS and each of the 4 components so described are understood, communicated, and trained to personnel at the FAA.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id64cb232fcb9a40808da2d62bb42ca703">
                        <enum>(F)</enum>
 <text>The efficacy of the FAA’s Voluntary Safety Reporting Programs as part of SMS, including any actions taken by the FAA in response to reports filed under such program.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id98ef966031d14d42860e8c10f20a3adf">
                        <enum>(G)</enum>
 <text>Whether the Federal Government should advocate for changes to Annex 19–Safety Management of the International Civil Aviation Organization (in this section referred to as <quote>ICAO</quote>) to ensure appropriate updates to the State Safety Program standards and recommended practices, including—</text>
                        <clause id="id892d6cba4b62474085ad037e2881f65b">
                            <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>a systems-level approach to evaluating and improving SMS for air navigation service providers; and</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="idba8b313b807f4220aff912c499986728">
                            <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>the implementation of SMS for civil aviation regulators.</text> </clause> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idf5b0ccc23cb645cab3d2c1c8d4034591"> <enum>(H)</enum> <text>Any other matter determined by the Administrator for which review by the review panel would be consistent with the public interest in aviation safety.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id6e9adaf08361451bbdee4a0b868642ed">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
                    <header>Composition of review panel</header>
                    <subparagraph id="id0913673838d242a6b6cdec4bc1fe7a24">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
                        <header>Appointed members</header>
 <text>The review panel shall consist of the following members appointed by the Administrator:</text>
                        <clause id="id596c2e36f33e4abb8001da00132663f1">
                            <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>Two representatives of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration with expertise in SMSs.</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="id8d28a167fe9546c583a0e4deb2b14a52">
                            <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>Three appropriately qualified representatives of aviation labor organizations (designated by the applicable represented organization), including—</text>
                            <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                                id="id4c47225d48f7417f82005ac5a2c7573a">
                                <enum>(I)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the principal organization representing the largest certified collective bargaining representative of airline pilots; and</text>
                            </subclause>
                            <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                                id="id32d0e5df79a34bb6be00c801e4e6fa68">
                                <enum>(II)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the exclusive bargaining representatives of FAA air traffic controllers certified under section 7111 of title 5, United States Code.</text>
                            </subclause>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="id16516ce84c6d408eb8cb8be60b5a25d2">
                            <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>Not less than 5 independent subject matter experts in safety management systems who—</text>
                            <subclause id="id5a35bb02ad114354aa99990273275ec4">
                                <enum>(I)</enum>
 <text>have not served as a political appointee in the FAA; and</text>
                            </subclause>
                            <subclause id="id7622f7b116da44598c1d08641f6f4944">
                                <enum>(II)</enum>
 <text>have a minimum of 10 years of relevant applied experience.</text>
                            </subclause>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="id31a69750ab4d4948bcda3c10d0717c9e">
                            <enum>(iv)</enum>
 <text>Three representatives from the aviation industry with expertise in SMS.</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="id4ad6cde9a912413da6b1cc62048618b5">
                            <enum>(v)</enum>
 <text>A representative of the United States Mission to the ICAO.</text> </clause> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id8c022ffcfabf4961bcdb6e60fa357c96"> <enum>(B)</enum> <header>Advisory members</header> <clause id="id74b083e77c6d4764a91eb2bd552c9d7b"> <enum>(i)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text>In addition to the appointed members described in subparagraph (A), the review panel shall be advised by up to 5 employees of the FAA, at least 3 of whom shall be subject matter experts in implementing SMS at the FAA.</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="idaf90792830b1485e87d3bbd73e532a71">
                            <enum>(ii)</enum>
                            <header>Duties</header>
 <text>The advisory members may take part in deliberations of the review panel and provide subject matter expertise with respect to the review panel’s work.</text>
                        </clause>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="idb64d9575124d440d954411853c987405">
                    <enum>(4)</enum>
                    <header>Recommendations</header>
 <text>The review panel shall issue recommendations to the Administrator based on the review of the matters listed in paragraph (2) in order to inform the FAA’s implementation of a comprehensive and integrated SMS for all lines of business within the FAA.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="ida4135f2dc01c4aa680ca4ce71380bdd6">
                    <enum>(5)</enum>
                    <header>Report</header>
                    <subparagraph id="id2da5912f92e94ee8b7f5c8392bd04ac8">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
                        <header>Submission</header>
 <text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the first meeting of the review panel, the review panel shall submit to the Administrator and the appropriate committees of Congress a report containing the findings and recommendations regarding the matters listed in paragraph (2) that are endorsed by a majority of the review panel.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="ida042f10c666246cc9d9917f619ae91b8">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
                        <header>Dissenting views</header>
 <text>In submitting the report under subparagraph (A), the review panel shall append to such report the dissenting views of any individual member or group of members of the review panel regarding the findings or recommendations of the review panel.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id915f50da505e4bf9911d4facb94e7719">
                        <enum>(C)</enum>
                        <header>Publication</header>
 <text>Not later than 5 days after receiving the report under subparagraph (A), the Administrator shall publish such report, including any dissenting views appended to the report, on the website of the FAA.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id4d15c56c9038486b9970ed415f076801">
                        <enum>(D)</enum>
                        <header>Termination</header>
 <text>The review panel shall terminate upon the submission of the report under subparagraph (A).</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id1c1a21dea8ab40e7add6ae0595ac8215">
                    <enum>(6)</enum>
                    <header>Administrative provisions</header>
                    <subparagraph id="id000be443cffe490fb63f7979935dd09e">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
                        <header>Access to information</header>
                        <clause id="id4551a8b19f5b4d6581e7b00ff2bb40b6">
                            <enum>(i)</enum>
                            <header>In general</header>
 <text>The review panel shall have the authority to perform the following actions if a majority of the review panel members consider each action necessary and appropriate:</text>
                            <subclause id="idc497f2fdaaf8408cb0f15a024a3efe48">
                                <enum>(I)</enum>
 <text>Entering onto the premises of the FAA for access to and inspection of records or other purposes.</text>
                            </subclause>
                            <subclause id="ida5de72f44f234f7da26b94e44bda6663">
                                <enum>(II)</enum>
 <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, except as provided in clause (ii), accessing and inspecting de-identified, but otherwise unredacted, records directly necessary for the completion of the review panel’s work under this section that are in the possession of the FAA.</text>
                            </subclause>
                            <subclause id="id157776a59bc446d8a0c9585819a01499">
                                <enum>(III)</enum>
 <text>Interviewing employees of the FAA as necessary for the review panel to complete its work.</text>
                            </subclause>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="id787df3a4d6ea43849a570a8a7a3fd9a6">
                            <enum>(ii)</enum>
                            <header>Non-federal government members</header>
 <text>Members of the review panel who are not officers or employees of the Federal Government shall only have access to, and be allowed to inspect, information provided to the FAA pursuant to section 40123 of title 49, United States Code, and part 193 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, in a de-identified form.</text>
                        </clause>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id851557d1de0f49f2b8c32716200e85b1">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
                        <header>Nondisclosure of confidential information</header>
                        <clause id="idd0478362afa9408c96905e62279c4ee5">
                            <enum>(i)</enum>
                            <header>Nondisclosure for non-federal government members</header>
                            <subclause id="idd5ea8f9e7a67446d97dfe074cd0c9da1">
                                <enum>(I)</enum>
                                <header>Non-federal government participants</header>
 <text>Prior to participating on the review panel, each individual serving on the review panel representing a non-Federal entity shall execute an agreement with the Administrator in which the individual shall be prohibited from disclosing at any time, except as required by law, to any person, foreign or domestic, any non-public information made available to the panel under subparagraph (A).</text>
                            </subclause>
                            <subclause id="idbc0ee9078add4409bd3ec14e4d983c13">
                                <enum>(II)</enum>
                                <header>Federal Government participants</header>
 <text>Federal officers or employees serving on the review panel as representatives of the Federal Government and subject to the requirement to protect confidential information (including proprietary information and trade secrets under section 1905 of title 18, United States Code) shall not be required to execute agreements under this clause.</text>
                            </subclause>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="ide71486e9c5c341e3b18d5a9638b06f85">
                            <enum>(ii)</enum>
                            <header>Protection of information</header>
 <text>Information that is obtained or reviewed by the review panel shall not constitute a waiver of the protections applicable to the information under section 552 of title 5, United States Code (commonly referred to as the <quote>Freedom of Information Act</quote>). Members of the review panel shall protect such information to the extent required under applicable law.</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="id72048bc4f7904cc08f12c5884a8c4b61">
                            <enum>(iii)</enum>
                            <header>Protection of proprietary information and trade secrets</header>
 <text>Members of the review panel shall protect proprietary information, trade secrets, and other information otherwise exempt under section 552 of title 5, United States Code, to the extent permitted under applicable law.</text>
                        </clause>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id9335d1a5e92b475dba80448a3c91c010">
                    <enum>(7)</enum>
                    <header>Inapplicability of FACA</header>
 <text>The review panel shall not be subject to <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/10">chapter 10</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code (commonly referred to as the <quote>Federal Advisory Committee Act</quote>).</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="idbf6ef64bdf03487a8d11e5f1cfee1dc5">
                    <enum>(8)</enum>
                    <header>Process improvements</header>
 <text>Not later than 1 year after the submission of the recommendations under paragraph (4), the Administrator shall report to the appropriate committees of Congress on the status of any ongoing actions in response to such recommendations, including the status of implementation of each of the recommendations of the review panel, if any, with which the Administrator concurs.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id765d86c799114c379c518fb33c9f8183">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Non-Concurrence with recommendations</header>
 <text>Not later than 6 months after submission of the recommendations under subsection (a)(4), with respect to each recommendation of the review panel with which the Administrator does not concur, if any, the Administrator shall publish on the website of the FAA and submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a detailed explanation for such determination.</text>
            </subsection>
 </section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfb6c7ed9be654b40a5313339085961d9"><enum>4.</enum><header>ADS–B Out Reforms</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcb41cb4213ee450ba60f83666979fa33"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Applicability of certain exceptions</header><text>For purposes of applying section 91.225(f) of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation), the term <term>sensitive government mission</term> shall be strictly construed and shall not include training flights, flights of Federal officials below the rank of Cabinet Member, or any routine flights.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6f57c77cf1694e538b72d93d819c5953"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 1046(e)(3) of the John S. McCain National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2019 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/40101">49 U.S.C. 40101</external-xref> note) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8cf3a329773b4028931a8d6ef9ba0b91"><paragraph id="id66eed74097f44df8af702f0a22e7ac72">
                        <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>The term <term>special mission aircraft</term> means an aircraft the Secretary of Defense designates, in coordination with the Federal Aviation Administration, for a unique mission to which operating with ADS–B Out equipment installed and activated creates a unique risk when weighed against any risk to the safety of the national airspace system posed by non-equipage and deactivation of ADS–B Out equipment.</text>
 </paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="id758dd743bc1f4d73b263c2ec1f3acdcb"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Administrative action</header><text>The Administrator shall modify section 91.225(f) of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation), and any pertinent Memorandum of Agreement, to conform with the requirements of this section.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id309281e523e84eed8ca369f4bd7c4050"><enum>(d)</enum><header>GAO review and report</header><text>Not later than the date that is 1 year after the date of enactment of this section, the Comptroller General shall—</text><paragraph id="idc13e96c9b8414d8898c4890fb7abf716"><enum>(1)</enum><text>review the utilization of exceptions specified in section 91.225(f) of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation), as modified to conform with the requirements of this section, and section 1046(e)(3) of the John S. McCain National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2019 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/40101">49 U.S.C. 40101</external-xref> note), as amended by subsection (b), to determine whether the Department of Defense and other relevant Federal agencies, or other applicable operators, have utilized those exceptions in accordance with relevant law and regulation and the extent of such utilization; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddc64eeb15d494ec4958d4cb912fe7f25"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report on the findings of the review conducted under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id2ff233089db64e3a9a6de96440404a7f"><enum>(e)</enum><header>FAA review</header><text>Upon submission of the report specified in subsection (d)(2), the Administrator shall determine whether any Federal agencies that have been found to have not utilized exceptions in accordance with relevant laws and regulations shall be permitted to continue to utilize those exceptions. The Administrator shall brief the appropriate committees of Congress on such determination.</text></subsection><subsection id="id8a91727c64394c8186d6f1e1a6b6181a">
                <enum>(f)</enum>
                <header>Joint council</header>
 <text>The Administrator, through the Office of FAA–DOD Coordination established or designated under section 6, and the Secretary of Defense, shall establish a joint council to regularly review all operations, including those operated by Federal agencies, that utilize the exceptions to the ADS–B Out equipage and transmission requirements to ensure compliance with relevant laws and regulations. The joint council shall brief the appropriate committees of Congress on an annual basis.</text>
            </subsection></section><section id="id3827b87325444655a9d1ec38aa59f2ed">
            <enum>5.</enum>
            <header>ADS–B In requirement to enhance safety</header>
            <subsection id="id84c2514610e14858b326cada71fd5159">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>Deadline for compliance</header>
 <text>Not later than the date that is 4 years after the date of enactment of this section, an air carrier operating under part 121 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations or providing service under part 135 of title 14 of such Code pursuant to a schedule or in conjunction with part 380 of title 14 of such Code may not operate an aircraft unless the aircraft has Automatic Dependent Surveillance-Broadcast In (ADS–B In) equipment installed and operational at all times unless otherwise authorized by air traffic control, regardless of whether the Administrator has issued regulations to implement such requirement.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="idc86b2dc5dcd44b8090c596917a7ecde9">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Performance requirements</header>
 <text>The Administrator shall determine appropriate performance requirements for the ADS–B In equipment referenced in subsection (a) for the purposes of providing safety-enhancing capabilities for flight crews, including but not limited to increasing situational awareness, receiving indications and alerts of air traffic conflicts, and facilitating aircraft collision avoidance. The Administrator shall issue relevant guidance to operators and other appropriate stakeholders on the types of equipment that satisfy the requirements of this section.</text>
            </subsection>
        </section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcc1fcdbb831b4521a899b2b415f9de98"><enum>6.</enum><header>Safety reviews of airspace</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                id="idc5ff759d3b5a420f974c27a5ee856a11">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header display-inline="yes-display-inline">FAA–DOD Coordination </header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this section, the Administrator shall establish or designate an office within the FAA as the Office of FAA–DOD Coordination (in this section referred to as the <term>Office</term>), which shall—</text>
                <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                    id="id84f37d3190814941b6da4d4c1f311909">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">coordinate airspace usage of military aircraft and rotorcraft with relevant FAA lines of business including the Air Traffic Organization; and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                    id="id47972abebe9e4bc1834d920ddbbd4139">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">carry out the safety review required by subsection (b).</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id57f6e2c4761241e988c56377ddd667d4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Safety reviews</header><paragraph id="idcb96346c484540fd98ddca3a5086a3f1">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                    <header>Review of Ronald Reagan Washington National Airport</header>
 <text>Not later than 30 days after the date on which the Office is established or designated, the Administrator, in coordination with the Secretary of Defense and the heads of any other Federal agencies determined appropriate by the Administrator, shall initiate a safety review (in this subsection referred to as the <quote>review</quote>) of all military, law enforcement, and civilian rotary wing, powered lift, and unmanned aircraft system flight operations and flight routes in the Washington DC Metropolitan Area Special Flight Rules Area, including but not limited to flight operations conducted by the Department of Defense and emergency response providers, to evaluate any associated safety risk on commercial transport airplane operations at Ronald Reagan Washington National Airport.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id4569f27d41ca4f3e8a902e517b7e97d9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Other airport reviews</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfe63979f86ae4d9e905115d4079b6219"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator, in coordination with the Secretary of Defense and the heads of any Federal agencies determined appropriate by the Administrator, shall conduct safety reviews of all military, law enforcement and civilian rotary wing, powered lift, and unmanned aircraft system flight operations and flight routes at other Class B airports (as listed in section 1 of Appendix D to part 91 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation)) in Class B airspace in the national airspace system, including flight operations conducted by the Department of Defense and emergency response providers, to evaluate any associated safety risk on commercial transport airplane operations.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddca1db2d6c3f44ce810ec0558842d2e9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Prioritization</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7a039d5b14634a94900ec35771c3fd0d"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this section, for the sole purpose of carrying out the safety reviews required by subparagraph (A), the Administrator shall classify Class B airports into the following categories based on the volume of mixed air traffic at each airport, as determined by the Administrator:</text><subclause id="id05d3a66ddab74bdf86602e87e594b7d3" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Class B airports with higher volumes of mixed air traffic.</text></subclause><subclause id="idc2309457ed314ae4a61d4e107557f09c" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>Class B airports with lower volumes of mixed air traffic.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="idf82e3bc9fc8d4b48a8df9eade2832c3c" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In conducting the safety reviews required by subparagraph (A), the Administrator shall prioritize the evaluation of Class B airports in the category under clause (i)(I).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9d1b385e01cf4caab3c29e332855ba79"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Deadline of initiation of reviews</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1c2ca1b7e0154905bb27c97a1dcca9f3"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Class B airports with higher volumes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall initiate the review under subparagraph (A) of Class B airports in the category under subparagraph (B)(i)(I) no later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this section.</text></clause><clause id="iddaf98aa449934f91961de8503b7241aa" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Class B airports with lower volumes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall initiate the review under subparagraph (A) of Class B airports in the category under subparagraph (B)(i)(II) no later than 90 days after the deadline for completion of the reviews under paragraph (4)(B)(i).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0512f97616be4a02b47c5104c383404b"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>In conducting the safety reviews required by paragraphs (1) and (2), the Office shall do the following:</text><subparagraph id="idea710dba5fb94d118bf29e87538e86a6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Analyze air traffic and airspace management.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0753986918254f28b15caca49852dfe7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Evaluate the level of coordination the Administrator exercises with the Secretary of Defense and the heads of any other Federal agencies, and emergency response providers as appropriate, to inform the designation and approval of airspace use and flight routes for non-transport airplane operations.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddfed69b81b004513b73472e26e84a5ef"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Assess any risks posed to transport airplanes from military aircraft, civil rotorcraft, powered lift aircraft, and unmanned aircraft systems operating in Class B airspace in proximity to Class B airports.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide82455e2d87945f1949147225c2b6e95">
                        <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>Review relevant incidents submitted to the Administrator through Air Traffic Mandatory Occurrence reports (as documented via FAA Form 7210–13), Aviation Safety Reporting System reports, and Aviation Safety Action Program reports, and relevant reports submitted to the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration through the Aviation Safety Reporting System, to identify any safety trends regarding the operation of military aircraft, civil rotorcraft, powered lift aircraft, and unmanned aircraft systems in Class B airspace near Class B airports.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9823842c50284593b74b61ba268bbf71"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Select appropriately qualified representatives of aviation labor organizations (designated by the applicable represented organization) as participants in the reviews, including, at a minimum—</text><clause id="idf23658b3abc54efb9f16886a575b8f5c"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the principal organization representing the largest certified collective bargaining representative of airline pilots; and</text></clause><clause id="idd4f5d4d5cb8d41a880910b6e227f73cc"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the exclusive bargaining representative of air traffic controllers of the FAA certified under section 7111 of title 5, United States Code.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd19530b7e72a4abd8c301b687dd92a2d"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Deadlines for completion of safety reviews</header><subparagraph id="id62ca61bc6ef04d5b83d112496d2698b5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Ronald Reagan Washington National Airport</header><text>The Administrator shall complete the safety review required by paragraphs (1) not later than 120 days after the date on which such review is initiated.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ideae97498cf5047cab0867cda5caf051a" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Other airports</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0914cfe92fe841ed8cf963baa0a844ec"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Class B airports with higher volumes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall complete the safety reviews required by paragraphs (2) of Class B airports in the category under subparagraph (B)(i)(I) of such paragraph no later than 2 years after the date on which the first of such reviews is initiated.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide1ccd5d92b9c47219e073cced8c615bb"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Class B airports with lower volumes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall complete the safety review required by paragraphs (2) of Class B airports in the category under subparagraph (B)(i)(II) of such paragraph no later than 2 years after the deadline for completion of the reviews under clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id28ac01a6a8914edb94c0f1ad34f3b05a"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the safety reviews required by paragraphs (1) and (2) are completed, the Administrator shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report detailing the analysis and results of the review, together with relevant findings and recommendations, including any recommendations for legislative or administrative action determined appropriate by the Administrator.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id95c519c12ff44448ac975b2ba08f251a"><enum>7.</enum><header>FAA-Department of Defense Safety Information Sharing</header><subsection id="id272b1f084ad44bf4b6d26b23b1f152df"><enum>(a)</enum><header>MOU with the Department of the Army</header><text>Not later than the date that is 60 days after the date of enactment of this section, the Federal Aviation Administration and the Department of the Army shall establish a Memorandum of Understanding to permit, as appropriate, the sharing of information from the Army’s Safety Management Information System with the FAA to facilitate communications and analysis of any applicable impacts to the safety and efficiency of civil aviation operations and to mitigate risk in the national airspace system.</text></subsection><subsection id="id2aa3af4d1af04047827a809322b92fd3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Other Department of Defense MOUs</header><text>Not later than the date that is 90 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Federal Aviation Administration shall establish a Memorandum of Understanding with the following military departments to permit, as appropriate, the sharing of information from applicable aviation safety information systems to facilitate communications and analysis of any applicable impacts to the safety and efficiency of civil aviation operations and to mitigate risk in the national airspace system:</text><paragraph id="id2b4b2e7f9b6e4578a6b6b4fd9cd7869e"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Department of the Navy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id676a954764e446c79338d038713a925e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Department of the Air Force.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8d9d7cc3f642438a9be36ab496eabf14"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Coast Guard.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idabdd530fd4f64939b6d8c0f3adcd7427"><enum>8.</enum><header>No disruptions to FAA workforce</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8fea438142984b35a97410bf3e7d57b7"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Hiring freeze exclusion</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc23e87e57d504097aa5d9d0adfa52aef"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any action by the President, the Secretary, the Administrator, the Director of the Office of Personnel Management, or other head, officer, or employee of a Federal executive entity to halt appointment activities in the Federal service on or after the date of enactment of this section shall exclude the FAA workforce.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id74797f62b72c4947b88ca3e6add0dc3f"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Retroactive application</header><text>Each action by the President, the Secretary, the Administrator, the Director of the Office of Personnel Management, or other head, officer, or employee of a Federal executive entity to halt appointment activities at the FAA during the period beginning on January 20, 2025, and ending on the date of enactment of this section is reversed.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0a314b4b06e340d79d454a3ecae5b917"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Deferred Resignation Program and Voluntary Furlough Exclusion</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1c7ca9fc5e3541699d2b51cff0bb2ea2"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>Any action on or after the date of enactment of this section by the President, the Secretary, the Administrator, the Director of the Office of Personnel Management, or other head, officer, or employee of a Federal executive entity to offer a deferred resignation program or voluntary furlough opportunity to Federal employees shall exclude the FAA workforce.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd1d4fbf52286436d90c77470685029ad"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Savings clause</header><text>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to affect the Voluntary Separation Incentive Payments program carried out under part 576 of title 5, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on January 1, 2025).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id28c6b4135e924e698db3b00c02554d96"><enum>(c)</enum><header>GAO review of FAA probationary personnel terminations</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id42aa18dbf0fd4427acfeb830e6fbd4f1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this section, the Comptroller General shall initiate a review of each action by the President, the Secretary, the Administrator, the Director of the Office of Personnel Management, and other head, officer, or employee of a Federal executive entity during the period beginning on February 14, 2025, and ending on the date of enactment of this section to terminate an employee in a probationary period of employment of the FAA.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id734e6e01948f497291f0801924a1e0c4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>In conducting the review, the Comptroller General shall evaluate—</text><subparagraph id="id817ebf08b7c44074a30175b45340685d"><enum>(A)</enum><text>whether a comprehensive safety risk management analysis evaluating the impacts of the proposed workforce reduction on the safety and efficiency of the national airspace system was performed by the Secretary or Administrator prior to the terminations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6389b359354d428ba6b79466c4ab8b4b"><enum>(B)</enum><text>whether the President, the Secretary, the Administrator, the Director of the Office of Personnel Management, or other head, officer, or employee of a Federal executive entity made efforts to notify congressional committees of jurisdiction of the proposed and confirmed workforce reductions; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf281c6088fdf43e0a0879138af7727f5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>whether the workforce reductions resulted in a detrimental impact to the safety and efficiency of the national airspace system.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id3d0aec5ed2a14116a6eb195ab9737b5f"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Deadline</header><text>The Comptroller General shall complete the review required by this subsection not later than 180 days after the date on which the review is initiated.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idabb14af6c94a4bc7980824ed0a0226bf"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after the date on which the review is completed, the Comptroller General shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report detailing the results of the review together with relevant findings and recommendations, including any recommendations for legislative or administrative action.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2c704dcbdb3e41028e419379bafa3b63"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Prohibition on FAA staffing reductions</header><text>The Secretary and the Administrator shall not—</text><paragraph id="id7873c5c2abec43ccb0c54f54347c7e2b"><enum>(1)</enum><text>carry out a reduction in force for employees of the FAA; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6db0b94d1ef947f9a3d64e188c93d4d9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>reduce the number of full-time equivalent positions at the FAA.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id41ce2f73048e44889dc47fa2d37b8426"><enum>9.</enum><header>Extension of FAA air traffic controller max hiring requirement</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 437(a) of the FAA Reauthorization Act of 2024 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/44506">49 U.S.C. 44506</external-xref> note) is amended by striking <quote>2028</quote> and inserting <quote>2033</quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide10e0b020bfb4d3ca6b80c5c5a8b2cb4"><enum>10.</enum><header>Air traffic controller training improvements</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf6c0f9a2dc9948f69618fffe6e141a77"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Enhanced Air Traffic Collegiate Training Initiative program</header><paragraph id="ida24df5d7fd574f88a4179b35d0d1fad8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator shall leverage the Collegiate Training Initiative program described in section 44506(c) of title 49, United States Code, to maintain an Enhanced Air Traffic Collegiate Training Initiative program (in this section referred to as the <quote>Enhanced Initiative</quote>) to support the recruitment, education, and hiring of well-qualified developmental air traffic controllers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idea2d6b7b4cb4409ea2780bb34fa2d2f7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>In maintaining the Enhanced Initiative under paragraph (1), the Administrator shall, at a minimum, include the following criteria:</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0f8f55884f794e3f8b08840b69f5f341"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Selecting and leveraging partnerships with accredited institutions of higher education (as defined in section 61.1 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations) that administer an accredited air traffic curriculum to undergraduate students.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbc491954e18c431a86f2e71db254d01a"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Determining criteria for accredited institutions of higher education to participate in the Enhanced Initiative.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida693220157754a46b611dee6642afb7e"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Soliciting applications from, and provide guidance to, interested accredited institutions of higher education that administer an accredited air traffic curriculum to undergraduate students, including accredited institutions that participate in the Collegiate Training Initiative, to help increase qualified accredited institutions participating in the Enhanced Initiative.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idd3a22a75ef774f2bb9ec258ff1f81bfa"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Selection criteria</header><text>Prior to selecting an accredited institution of higher education for participation in the Enhanced Initiative, the Administrator shall—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddde7fbff83024e2f85e574967373c5a9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">evaluate the institution’s air traffic curriculum, including the institution’s—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2d1e431fa5a040289d48ce04519e64ba"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">access to air traffic educational resources; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2b43d253dce444a6be31f318093e186d"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">proximity and access to air traffic facilities and equipment;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1ce2581d6b9e4fb8a57062bd41aeb600"><enum>(B)</enum><text>certify that each institution of higher education seeking to participate in the Enhanced Initiative has a qualified air traffic curriculum that provides, at a minimum, an equivalent level of education and training for air traffic controller trainees to that provided at the FAA Academy; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id62ec8b2cef8740029b072e3dce4cf1ee"><enum>(C)</enum><text>certify that all evaluations of students at accredited institutions of higher education seeking to participate in the Enhanced Initiative shall be conducted by FAA-approved and certified evaluators.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id10560205f6f94a50a73fc87a431cf990"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Program expansion</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall establish a minimum target of certifying 15 qualified institutions of higher education that meet the criteria described in this section for selection to participate in the Enhanced Initiative. The qualified institutions of higher education selected for such minimum target shall include any institution of higher education selected and certified by the Administrator for participation in the Enhanced Initiative as of January 20, 2025.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idec35a02339d342f8809c4e8816b5f8df"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Hiring qualified graduates</header><text>The Administrator may appoint qualified individuals who have successively completed an air traffic curriculum certified by the Administrator under paragraph (3) at a participating institution of higher education selected by the Administrator and received at least a well-qualified score on the Air Traffic Skills Assessment, or successor air traffic entrance exam, on a non-competitive basis for the position of Air Traffic Control Specialist in the excepted service (as defined in section 2103 of title 5, United States Code).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idcdf596539a274a6c8b1f7f51d01ba9ef"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Supporting the hiring of qualified instructors</header><text>Using amounts made available under section 106(k)(1) of title 49, United States Code, the Administrator may award funds to support the recruitment and hiring of qualified faculty and FAA-approved and certified evaluators at accredited institutions of higher education that administer an accredited air traffic curriculum to undergraduate students that either—</text><subparagraph id="ide1395f8083ce486da4d8ec3b10daa533"><enum>(A)</enum><text>participate in the Collegiate Training Initiative and are interested and qualified applicants for participation in the Enhanced Initiative; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id604eeff886f84b39b7c6f380c9fce578"><enum>(B)</enum><text>have been selected by the Administrator for participation in the Enhanced Initiative.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id4eab8d7edf5842358ad4f80f0ffe4b55">
                    <enum>(7)</enum>
                    <header>Review of enhanced AT–CTI program</header>
                    <subparagraph id="id6ec22f72575c4be4a12b91a9a943254d">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
                        <header>In general</header>
 <text>Not later than 5 years after the date of the enactment of this section, the Comptroller General shall initiate a study to examine the effectiveness of the Enhanced Initiative in increasing FAA air traffic controller education and training capacity and throughput to grow the FAA air traffic controller workforce.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="idb7304b69443f4c908557aeb23e7ad5a3">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
                        <header>Contents</header>
 <text>In conducting the study under subparagraph (A), the Comptroller General shall, at a minimum, evaluate the effectiveness of the program in producing—</text>
                        <clause id="id933a928eab59407184c5535c8e473c00">
                            <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>students that score at least a well-qualified score on the Air Traffic Skills Assessment or successor air traffic entrance exam;</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="id5bfc2eb6d58a4bdf9eb887eaf8b4293d">
                            <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>developmental controllers that enter en route and terminal air traffic environments after completing the Enhanced Initiative; and</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="idcf8709e38c764574ad7429031947ba7b">
                            <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>developmental controllers that become Certified Professional Controllers.</text>
                        </clause>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id80b06f4171974422a8eeeb5e25017746">
                        <enum>(C)</enum>
                        <header>Consultation</header>
 <text>In conducting the study required under subparagraph (A), the Comptroller General shall consult with the FAA and appropriate stakeholders involved in overseeing, operating, and administering the Enhanced Initiative.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id944b630d3d7c402181e34948468adeec">
                        <enum>(D)</enum>
                        <header>Report</header>
 <text>Not later than 1 year after the date the Comptroller General initiates the study under subparagraph (A), the Comptroller General shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress and the Administrator a report describing the results of the study, together with any appropriate recommendations for legislative or administrative action.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4f4669629c9f481c813d1a43f00d9dfe"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Improving Aviation Medical Examiner staffing</header><text>Using amounts made available under section 106(k)(1) of title 49, United States Code, the Administrator shall exercise all actions necessary to hire qualified licensed medical physicians with knowledge of or a background in aerospace medicine, psychiatry, psychology, neurology, cardiology, or internal medicine in order to—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id37a06b008d7b4e1293c815e26c81801f"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">increase the Aviation Medical Examiner (as described in section 183.21 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations) workforce; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4194408ea657427993afd7053b16c635"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">achieve maximum staffing capacity within the FAA Office of Aerospace Medicine.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5f1b6165078849e2b5602bc44776a328"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Air traffic control instructor recruitment program</header><paragraph id="ide9b371a6320c44898fe1da649a28276c"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this section, the Administrator shall develop and execute an air traffic control instructor outreach and engagement program to assist with the recruitment, hiring, and retention of air traffic control instructors at the FAA Academy and at FAA air traffic control facilities with a demonstrated shortage of air traffic control personnel to provide classroom instruction or on-the-job training.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id31eb7b1661194bce98fe6c522f679573"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>In executing the program under paragraph (1), the Administrator shall conduct outreach and engagement activities relating to air traffic control instructor career opportunities to air traffic controllers who are within 1 year of—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2d53c380501d423ab905e95eec48fbe4"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">meeting the age and service requirements for an annuity under sections 8336(e) and 8412(e) of title 5, United States Code; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfecddc8aea5f48f4b1ac60d738a716b2"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">attaining the mandatory separation age for air traffic controllers described in sections 8335(a) and 8425(a) of title 5, United States Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id7de540680fb74d71b97144a0a2987f63"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Consideration</header><text>In developing the outreach and engagement program, the Administrator may consider the results of the study conducted in section 416 of the FAA Reauthorization Act of 2024 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/118/63">Public Law 118–63</external-xref>, 138 Stat. 1161).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf3cc48b9e62c4b7c8fecb2265af51ce4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Publication</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In executing the program under paragraph (1), the Administrator shall make publicly available on the website of the FAA, in a conspicuous manner, qualification criteria and hiring materials relating to air traffic control instructor careers, including active job postings for air traffic control instructors.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7f485d2e15b641c2974ab666008613d9"><enum>11.</enum><header>TARAM analyses</header><subsection id="id30A39E2D6DFD465AA7C8D93FCD6D7405"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Assessment</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id58e87184eeb643b2968376b436aeb942"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall conduct a Transport Airplane Risk Assessment Methodology (in this section referred to as <quote>TARAM</quote>) analysis with respect to any transport airplane accidents in the United States that result in a fatality, regardless of whether an aircraft design or a manufacturing issue is believed to have contributed to the accident.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id92f1f9f310a948c78c46662091de1736"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 30 days after conducting a TARAM analysis in accordance with paragraph (1), the Administrator shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report containing the results of the analysis, together with recommendations for such legislation and administrative action as the Administrator determines appropriate.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7aaafc1991b840a79544bb77d8de9456">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
                    <header>Employee designation</header>
 <text>Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this section, the Administrator shall designate multiple employees of the FAA as experts for the TARAM analysis process who shall be responsible for the advocacy, maintenance, and training of TARAM guidance and processes, including updating FAA Policy Statement PS–ANM–25–05, Risk Assessment Methodology for Transport Category Airplanes (dated November 4, 2011) to reflect, among other things, current National Transportation Safety Board accident rates.</text>
                </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                id="id8d7b3107280147888a39f086ecc71261">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Required updates</header>
 <text>Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this section, the Administrator shall revise FAA Policy Statement PS–ANM–25–05, Risk Assessment Methodology for Transport Category Airplanes (dated November 4, 2011) and any successor policy statement in accordance with the requirements of this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5dbcf2033cac43f686c8f8033d6cf17c"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 130(c) of the Aircraft Certification, Safety, and Accountability Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/260">Public Law 116–260</external-xref>; 134 Stat. 2349) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idE3882ED86B46460689BFD95499D48595"><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="PH2E7D48553C334EB78D198B49808D8C39"><enum>(c)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Required notice</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall provide notice to the congressional committees of jurisdiction on the findings and recommendations of a TARAM conducted following a transport airplane accident in which a loss of life occurred.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id18344cb276de453c8aa26cc16ab61446"><enum>12.</enum><header>Employee reporting</header><subsection id="id99EF174296344E98A6AAD3DAE56AFD1C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Whistleblower audit</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id550ebef957874fbb9015383fd37ac33b"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Inspector General of the Department of Transportation shall initiate an audit of the FAA, including the FAA Whistleblower Protection Program, to review whether the FAA is appropriately processing and acting on submitted complaints.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id46a873b9949a46c6bf47bc2997fb5392"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The audit conducted under paragraph (1) shall not compromise the identity of any individual who submitted a report through the Whistleblower Protection Program or the FAA Hotline of the FAA Office of Audit and Evaluation.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idF9606C1FB1144F8DB29E0FED905B0C1E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this section, the Inspector General of the Department of Transportation shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report containing the results of the audit conducted under subsection (a), together with recommendations for such legislation and administrative action as the Inspector General determines appropriate.</text></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0c2b00e907b04c9fb7607db52dd3cf26"><enum>13.</enum><header>Conflicts of interest</header><subsection id="id10fadd01132c44f6aa94600e42727ec9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Interim final rule</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary of Transportation shall issue an interim final rule to require strict adherence to the requirements described in section 208 of title 18, United States Code.</text></subsection><subsection id="idf7c9434dbc24441a98522f42c808ee85"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Compliance review and briefing</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section, the Inspector General of the Department of Transportation shall review the Department of Transportation’s compliance with the requirements of this section and identify any applicable conflict of interest waivers granted by the Federal Government for the Department of Transportation relating to Department of Transportation and FAA employees, contracting, acquisition, and procurement, and shall brief the appropriate committees of Congress about the findings of such review.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

