<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HADBE5F7852A24C9DA8B1C2D71EBBDA10" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1293 IH: Vehicle Energy Performance Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1293</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250213">February 13, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001117">Mr. Casten</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide tax incentives and fees for increasing motor vehicle fuel economy, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9F353C139115466186B86225A4EB6A03" style="OLC"><section id="H5B0DAEED12834CB4A01158AD29E6CC62" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><subsection id="HE25DA82E0BCE4F139126A346061A1872"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Vehicle Energy Performance Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H21E2B965B4DC4921ACCD1F81FE13207C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Amendment of 1986 Code</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as otherwise expressly provided, whenever in this Act an amendment or repeal is expressed in terms of an amendment to, or repeal of, a section or other provision, the reference shall be considered to be made to a section or other provision of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986. </text></subsection></section><section id="HD1EE40A7BD7A4D05B8A2146948C679E6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Tax credit for vehicle energy performance</header><subsection id="H0D756B235A3246D7929338DFD7F1A16B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subpart B of part IV of subchapter A of chapter 1 (relating to other credits) is amended by inserting after section 30D the following new section:</text><quoted-block id="H110F2CACCAE04B56BDE156A84918E1AE" style="OLC"><section id="H3F720BCFF61D47889C353A72383999B6"><enum>30E.</enum><header>Vehicle energy performance rebate</header><subsection id="H3DDA8CD9D03040C895356EB639E5F921"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Allowance of credit</header><paragraph id="H2D5F4AACA72248D9AB7A922479D35804"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There shall be allowed as a credit against the tax imposed by this chapter for the taxable year an amount equal to the amount determined under paragraph (2) with respect to any new qualified high energy performance motor vehicle placed in service by the taxpayer during the taxable year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H98A79F5C7B0C48828070F107C56351F9" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Credit amount</header><text>With respect to each new qualified high energy performance motor vehicle, the amount determined under this paragraph shall be equal to the amount (not greater than $5,000) that bears the same ratio to $5,000 as—</text><subparagraph id="H9917B8F699934E7298A7857D66A27CFF" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the excess of—</text><clause id="H2DF62DB777614F64939D2A665C3CCCA8" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the vehicle energy performance of such vehicle, over</text></clause><clause id="H2C9A1AEBAFB444EABE56DA513694AA97" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the median vehicle energy performance for the model year immediately preceding the model year of such vehicle, bears to</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7D51423BAEC84121BE668075013170B6" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the excess of—</text><clause id="HF315F89913F4435B9736784F84CCBD54" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the best vehicle energy performance for the model year immediately preceding the model year of such vehicle, over</text></clause><clause id="H0FADCB2E2CC243CCA0C88C31E585E3B9" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the median vehicle energy performance for the model year immediately preceding the model year of such vehicle.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBB931E89DAFE416D93D7D246558A557C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>New qualified high energy performance motor vehicle</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <quote>new qualified high energy performance motor vehicle</quote> means a passenger automobile or light truck—</text><paragraph id="H425ECD1D77F84D96B3F8FA6E76B8E0F0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>which is treated as a motor vehicle for purposes of title II of the Clean Air Act,</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7D7B2277173441AB942628B458482A8D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>which achieves vehicle energy performance that is greater than the median vehicle energy performance for the model year immediately preceding the model year of such vehicle,</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC7BE6988AA704E3785D2CBBD83D98223"><enum>(3)</enum><text>for which standards are prescribed pursuant to section 32902 of title 49, United States Code,</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H45C480D8303C4EA09C37FAEC68B50D44"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the original use of which commences with the taxpayer,</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCE90E5709AB14CFDA8AC4E2E60E6089C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>which is acquired for use or lease by the taxpayer and not for resale, and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDFCCD22955C24C55864A1093EE8A756A"><enum>(6)</enum><text>which is made by a manufacturer beginning with model year 2027.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H223DB699B9A34F85B72C4CD95D821D17"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application with other credits</header><paragraph id="H1948D64EEDC64D2CA0F663A9F9A65FCE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Business credit treated as part of general business credit</header><text>So much of the credit which would be allowed under subsection (a) for any taxable year (determined without regard to this subsection) that is attributable to property of a character subject to an allowance for depreciation shall be treated as a credit listed in section 38(b) for such taxable year (and not allowed under subsection (a)).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8418BF76750E404F81AC66C735F553CE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Refundable personal credit</header><subparagraph id="H1DAA827DFF8F46D690D769E817F772CB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of this title, the credit allowed under subsection (a) for any taxable year (determined after application of paragraph (1)) shall be treated as a credit allowable under subpart C for such taxable year (and not allowed under subsection (a)).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBA70DC74488945A2A3309FF3B0E3415C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Refundable credit may be transferred</header><clause id="H82EB326F239944F5AEA4C04BD950E60F"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A taxpayer may, in connection with the purchase of a new qualified high energy performance motor vehicle, transfer any refundable credit described in subparagraph (A) to any person who is in the trade or business of selling new qualified high energy performance motor vehicles and who sold such vehicle to the taxpayer, but only if such person clearly discloses to such taxpayer, through the use of a window sticker attached to the new qualified high energy performance vehicle—</text><subclause id="H725CACFE1A5A4643B3BAB89B75AE651C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the amount of the refundable credit described in subparagraph (A) with respect to such vehicle, and</text></subclause><subclause id="H48FF4E0D9823464A8BEF9ADD61B40B92"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a notification that the taxpayer will not be eligible for any credit under section 30D with respect to such vehicle unless the taxpayer elects not to have this section apply with respect to such vehicle.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HD95F09D1522C486183219E01BDF1145F"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Certification</header><text>A transferee of a refundable credit described in subparagraph (A) may not claim such credit unless such claim is accompanied by a certification to the Secretary that the transferee reduced the price the taxpayer paid for the new qualified high energy performance motor vehicle by the entire amount of such refundable credit.</text></clause><clause id="H05FB2C88E5394BF8A1B66ED0D550D6F8"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Consent required for revocation</header><text>Any transfer under clause (i) may be revoked only with the consent of the Secretary.</text></clause><clause id="H11D32033ECDB463BACA5423FC3938A55"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary may prescribe such regulations as necessary to ensure that any refundable credit described in clause (i) is claimed once and not retransferred by a transferee.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF8629C02A0EF4975A4A0C7A1ADB8F2A0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Other definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section:</text><paragraph id="H8347F7038C724AF1A859303EB362164C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Vehicle energy performance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>vehicle energy performance</quote> means, with respect to any vehicle, the combined fuel-economy rating determined for the model and model year of such vehicle.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAE63115B1EFA41D3B862283DA74E40F0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Median vehicle energy performance</header><text>The term <quote>median vehicle energy performance</quote> means, with respect to any model year, the median combined fuel-economy rating for all new motor vehicles of such model year sold in the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAE7BE7BF8D5345B5BF0BE889E4D71F1C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Best vehicle energy performance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>best vehicle energy performance</quote> means, with respect to any model year, the highest combined fuel-economy rating of any model of motor vehicle of such model year sold the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD229C14F5C2847B1AD6957DE81B495FB"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Combined fuel-economy rating</header><text>The term <quote>combined fuel-economy rating</quote> means the combined fuel-economy rating determined in accordance with section 32908 of title 49, United States Code, and expressed in miles per gallon of gasoline equivalent.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF6D4858036194CC3AB9190EAF0D63E7E"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Model year</header><text>The term <quote>model year</quote> has the meaning given such term under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/32901">section 32901(a)</external-xref> of such title 49.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD1798A2E17CB40E7AC44B2F4A8D717F4"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Motor vehicle</header><text>The term <quote>motor vehicle</quote> means any vehicle which is manufactured primarily for use on public streets, roads, and highways (not including a vehicle operated exclusively on a rail or rails) and which has at least 4 wheels.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H08F025AC6D5641DF886968A130157334"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Other terms</header><text>The terms <quote>automobile</quote>, <quote>passenger automobile</quote>, <quote>light truck</quote>, and <quote>manufacturer</quote> have the meanings given such terms in regulations prescribed by the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency for purposes of the administration of title II of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7521">42 U.S.C. 7521 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1C27B9941A7249D9BCB5DF71B9F6F745"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Special rules</header><paragraph id="HBD050BA0C4564B0AA73A7B699EB42ACB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Basis reduction</header><text>For purposes of this subtitle, the basis of any property for which a credit is allowable under subsection (a) shall be reduced by the amount of such credit so allowed (determined without regard to subsection (c)).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H93BDD88597AC487FB32EC993E42217C6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Property used by tax-exempt entity</header><text>In the case of a vehicle whose use is described in paragraph (3) or (4) of section 50(b) and which is not subject to a lease, the person who sold such vehicle to the person or entity using such vehicle shall be treated as the taxpayer that placed such vehicle in service, but only if such person clearly discloses to such person or entity in a document the amount of any credit allowable under subsection (a) with respect to such vehicle (determined without regard to subsection (c)). For purposes of subsection (c), property to which this paragraph applies shall be treated as of a character subject to an allowance for depreciation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4B284F1F295448FEB079F6C4D0A847DF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Property used outside United States, etc., not qualified</header><text>No credit shall be allowable under subsection (a) with respect to any property referred to in section 50(b)(1) or with respect to the portion of the cost of any property taken into account under section 179.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H99E60DC2F5A34DF4A16DE21A7470ACF4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Recapture</header><text>The Secretary shall, by regulations, provide for recapturing the benefit of any credit allowable under subsection (a) with respect to any property which ceases to be property eligible for such credit.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7E04FCDC34C7477B923D994524D275D5"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Election not to take credit</header><text>No credit shall be allowed under subsection (a) for any vehicle if the taxpayer elects to not have this section apply to such vehicle.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0A53BF1DF8DE467190146BB743C099FA"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Interaction with air quality and motor vehicle safety standards</header><text>A motor vehicle shall not be considered eligible for a credit under this section unless such vehicle is in compliance with—</text><subparagraph id="H6D9BA4DA76D34D36A8526A9BD77C0EAD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the applicable provisions of the Clean Air Act for the applicable make and model year of the vehicle (or applicable air quality provisions of State law in the case of a State which has adopted such provisions under a waiver under section 209(b) of the Clean Air Act), and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5F82A20828CA4F1DA9B0C575AA64A527"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the motor vehicle safety provisions of sections 30101 through 30169 of title 49, United States Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H30323BE803EF490AB7758582EB677922"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Inflation adjustment</header><text>In the case of any model year beginning in a calendar year after 2027, each dollar amount in subsection (a)(2) shall be increased by an amount equal to—</text><subparagraph id="H503D91D5985540A79BD5B53B69B40FBD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such dollar amount, multiplied by</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9AA2E54D81B04A51A8EA7DDDEA593093"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the cost-of-living adjustment determined under section 1(f)(3) for the calendar year in which the model year begins, determined by substituting <quote>2026</quote> for <quote>2016</quote> in subparagraph (A)(ii) thereof.</text></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">Any increase determined under the preceding sentence shall be rounded to the nearest multiple of $100.</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5565B82EAADA44A4B167BEB958EA6E9A"><enum>(8)</enum><header>One credit per vehicle</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any vehicle, the credit described in subsection (a) shall only be allowed once with respect to such vehicle, as determined based upon the vehicle identification number of such vehicle.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H93C9792F5E5745109BC81DD9FDBAE6EA"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Reporting of vehicle energy performance</header><paragraph id="HA5A9FB88392F40559EB74508C5A8A0B0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Vehicle manufacturers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than November 1 of each calendar year (beginning with calendar year 2026), each vehicle manufacturer shall submit to the Secretary a report that includes—</text><subparagraph id="H4C3177AEAB554AA4842221C4AED9600F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the vehicle energy performance for each model of that model year which was manufactured by such manufacturer and sold in the United States, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAB55945D6F4945639F74E3E4B3EEF16E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to each such model of such model year, the number of vehicles of such model and model year sold in the United States during the 1-year period beginning on October 1 of the preceding year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAC19630E7F0047D0B4F2746DAC31427E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Publication by Treasury</header><text>Not later than December 1 of each calendar year (beginning with calendar year 2026), the Secretary shall publish the median vehicle energy performance and the best vehicle energy performance for that model year.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEDA5FEC7156846DEAFC59A4605738ABF"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Regulations</header><paragraph id="HF1924F7C959746728EBF2AB2FC6A43A3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the Secretary shall promulgate such regulations as necessary to carry out the provisions of this section not later than 1 year after the date of enactment.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD052BA7CA7E448BC8F09F4B362B20E77"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Coordination in prescription of certain regulations</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury, in coordination with the Secretary of Transportation and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, shall prescribe such regulations as necessary to determine whether a motor vehicle meets the requirements to be eligible for a credit under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H3150F875D6774CF5B05600FA30B81E4E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Credit allowed against alternative minimum tax</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/38">Section 38(c)(4)(B)</external-xref> is amended by redesignating clauses (i) through (xii) as clauses (ii) through (xiii), respectively, and by inserting before clause (ii) (as so redesignated) the following new clause:</text><quoted-block id="H01A0A96C59824240998E8E28B3F838CF" style="OLC"><clause id="HD88B268941684536AF98684A38FBE539"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the credit determined under section 30E,</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H4713D27CE5064C7DB1A1DBD848D7D44C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Display of credit</header><text>Section 32908(b) of title 49, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="H24F35121CFA34D0B975AED6AABE617B6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text><subparagraph id="H9D6A1FAABF254898A39F44720D83FB2C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (E) and (F) as subparagraphs (F) and (G), and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB1C6D5C0DBDB45059CEA91C64950E976"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (D) the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block id="HF453D7218F5E4405A66AEC7630D49D8D" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="H9BFEA92DBB0B4B40BC49E53BB44C4650" indent="up1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the amount of the vehicle energy performance credit allowable with respect to the sale of the automobile under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/30E">section 30E</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/30E">26 U.S.C. 30E</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>, and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF9AAC22B5422465F933E914F95A015E3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>paragraph (1)(E)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraph (1)(F)</quote>. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0BADA63C410342908E126E7B0555A0D1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><paragraph id="H0AFFABE1394C4447B39B73867703262B"><enum>(1)</enum><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/38">Section 38(b)</external-xref> is amended by striking <quote>plus</quote> at the end of paragraph (40), by striking the period at the end of paragraph (41) and inserting <quote>, plus</quote>, and by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block id="H209AC00CAD9A415EA80B98A5FB156519" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H54207D2F8316439D8FFD0E057661C4CD"><enum>(42)</enum><text>the portion of the vehicle energy performance rebate to which section 30E(c)(1) applies.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H0B5DEF2CEB3549F3BB2B5F0A6F5BAA11"><enum>(2)</enum><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/1016">Section 1016(a)</external-xref> is amended by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of paragraph (37), by striking the period at the end of paragraph (38) and inserting <quote>, and</quote>, and by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block id="HDAD490BE10514621B95A6B14ECAED7C8" style="OLC"><paragraph id="HE5768B7462A14D5683C0B42BE8E3D7CB"><enum>(39)</enum><text>to the extent provided in section 30E(e)(1).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="HAE201875E2A6455A8DABC07801713197"><enum>(3)</enum><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6501">Section 6501(m)</external-xref> is amended by inserting <quote>30E(e)(6),</quote> after <quote>30D(e)(4),</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFA8EAAC8030F48B2B94F956E5F6FAF7F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The table of section for subpart C of part IV of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 30D the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HC6BED0B7404E49BA81E7750D927E7203" display-inline="no-display-inline"><toc container-level="quoted-block-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" idref="H110F2CACCAE04B56BDE156A84918E1AE" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"><toc-entry idref="H3F720BCFF61D47889C353A72383999B6" level="section">Sec. 30E. Vehicle energy performance rebate.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H5392C8BB11094E3D94F849C303F8922B"><enum>3.</enum><header>Low vehicle energy performance fee</header><subsection id="HA805BC8B8E5A405E868252AB92A93DF1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/4064">Section 4064</external-xref> is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block id="H5F96577406284314BA442B3818407840" style="OLC"><section id="HA2F30A6012B2495EAB5CAA384BE153D9"><enum>4064.</enum><header>Low vehicle energy performance fee</header><subsection id="HAF53C9753DAA4916940E3A17EA2329E7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Imposition of tax</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is hereby imposed on the sale by the manufacturer of each low energy performance vehicle a tax equal to the product of $5,000, multiplied by the quotient of—</text><paragraph id="HCA0A0EAA999B4B9E91EDDBBF8028AC32"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the excess of—</text><subparagraph id="HB72409C5C09648D0862155E7C181EEC8"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the median vehicle energy performance for the model year immediately preceding the model year of such vehicle, over</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEC4EA365C84047658F41E6ABB83C9135"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the vehicle energy performance of such vehicle, divided by</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H88E37DCA84384F599039CD77A894AB5F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the excess of—</text><subparagraph id="H9B4916770D7C4E428246A8660307B2F4"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the best vehicle energy performance for the model year immediately preceding the model year of such vehicle, over</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD924823853934EA0B0855B9CAF1372DB"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the median vehicle energy performance for the model year immediately preceding the model year of such vehicle.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD958148042234B89814D2C0F8E8866E8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Low energy performance vehicle</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text><paragraph id="H41769F046F924C74983B7215D5AD94BE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <quote>low energy performance vehicle</quote> means a passenger automobile or light truck—</text><subparagraph id="HE7DF87AEE78647AAA55B6F12996AEFD2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>which is treated as a motor vehicle for purposes of title II of the Clean Air Act,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF6ED2C9A28034C82B6A2F0E186EA896A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>which achieves vehicle energy performance that is lower than the median vehicle energy performance, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H32C1DECF6FA34FF4BC8995E55DD68685"><enum>(C)</enum><text>which is made by a manufacturer beginning with model year 2029.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9308F2B0999C43A897FB11B7D49A6909"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception for certain vehicles</header><text>The term <quote>low energy performance vehicle</quote> does not include any vehicle—</text><subparagraph id="HD31A7EAE9B0E437FA9DD4D8D45E735C7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>which—</text><clause id="H25EB027D3A564CF88C720F3644823545"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has a gross vehicle weight rating of more than 8,500 pounds, and</text></clause><clause id="H5CD7069918DC427EB049EF21F9044764"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is determined by the Secretary to be a vehicle which is designed for commercial use, or</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAC258354DD9C44BDBEDCAD550B435342"><enum>(B)</enum><text>sold for use and used—</text><clause id="H8AC5A934EB8F4A648E66020DFE10BDC9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>as an ambulance or combination ambulance-hearse,</text></clause><clause id="H019B9F4547704834B5131546E667AB86"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by the United States or by a State or local government for police or other law enforcement purposes, or</text></clause><clause id="H939A1F920E994ED7A0C463840B519D17"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>for other emergency uses prescribed by the Secretary by regulations.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5DEB3FD80FC14FB7BCC9169358DFC580"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Other Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section:</text><paragraph id="H04B61A75EBBF4782B6EBDD2EB9D43607" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Vehicle energy performance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>vehicle energy performance</quote> means, with respect to any vehicle, the combined fuel-economy rating determined for the model and model year of such vehicle.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5238427E1FE6455D8FAE1A533BB08BD9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Median vehicle energy performance</header><text>The term <quote>median vehicle energy performance</quote> means, with respect to any model year, the median combined fuel-economy rating for all new motor vehicles of such model year sold in the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0F4106911C5149C1A118796D34AE7471" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Best vehicle energy performance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>best vehicle energy performance</quote> means, with respect to any model year, the highest combined fuel-economy rating of any model of motor vehicle of such model year sold the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H16FC312CADC94616BE3FCF8D9BBD3E91"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Combined fuel-economy rating</header><text>The term <quote>combined fuel-economy rating</quote> means the combined fuel-economy rating determined in accordance with section 32908 of title 49, United States Code, and expressed in miles per gallon of gasoline equivalent.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0B24A83B952440E9BD0A5C3FAF204365"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Model year</header><text>The term <quote>model year</quote> has the meaning given such term under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/32901">section 32901(a)</external-xref> of such title 49.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF1E936EEF59A4DABBB0DB67F71B69511"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Motor vehicle</header><text>The term <quote>motor vehicle</quote> means any vehicle which is manufactured primarily for use on public streets, roads, and highways (not including a vehicle operated exclusively on a rail or rails) and which has at least 4 wheels.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H00B37385CBB04ECA90D83715198F841A"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Other terms</header><text>The terms <quote>automobile</quote>, <quote>passenger automobile</quote>, <quote>light truck</quote>, and <quote>manufacturer</quote> have the meanings given such terms in regulations prescribed by the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency for purposes of the administration of title II of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7521">42 U.S.C. 7521 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA90FC313F485465BAD98BF846D32C7D2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Inflation adjustment</header><text>In the case of any model year beginning in a calendar year after 2029, each dollar amount in subsection (a)(2) shall be increased by an amount equal to—</text><paragraph id="H1740C1AA017F410B9D0C76EF34C922E1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>such dollar amount, multiplied by</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H032199A0AF0C414FA358CE8FCC78DAE5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the cost-of-living adjustment determined under section 1(f)(3) for the calendar year in which the model year begins, determined by substituting <quote>2028</quote> for <quote>2016</quote> in subparagraph (A)(ii) thereof.</text></paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">Any increase determined under the preceding sentence shall be rounded to the nearest multiple of $100.</continuation-text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H897DDC1AD156458D887266FBD50FF0BF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><paragraph id="H486B94F9F4A64E019BE2DE0FD74E0CB3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The heading for part I of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/32">chapter 32</external-xref> is amended by striking <quote><header-in-text level="part" style="OLC">Gas</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="part" style="OLC">Fuel</header-in-text></quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0B10003BFA0F41C9B1252F2C38617D25"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The table of parts for subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/32">chapter 32</external-xref> is amended by striking <quote>Gas</quote> in the item relating to part I and inserting <quote>Fuel</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAD67C4F82A0C43F696A7B1931DE841E3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The table of sections for part I of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/32">chapter 32</external-xref> is amended by striking <quote>Gas</quote> in the item relating to section 4064 and inserting <quote>Fuel</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5E3643027316475DA612400FFA5E9492"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The heading for subsection (d) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/1016">section 1016</external-xref> is amended by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">gas guzzler tax</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">low vehicle energy performance fee</header-in-text></quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCFDB5D35AC444107BE5BED4AFAA44353"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The heading for subsection (e) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/4217">section 4217</external-xref> is amended by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">gas guzzler tax</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">low vehicle energy performance fee</header-in-text></quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0D70F29FDA6D457B84A029182C5E4736"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The heading for subparagraph (B) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/4217">section 4217(e)(3)</external-xref> is amended by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subparagraph" style="OLC">gas guzzler tax</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subparagraph" style="OLC">low vehicle energy performance fee</header-in-text></quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H29E8B70C1CD644FAA748BD5C9855B26B"><enum>(7)</enum><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/4217">Section 4217(e)</external-xref> is amended by striking <quote>gas guzzler tax</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>low vehicle energy performance fee</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HF7B6D5A7562043C69CBEE403DF2B4A64"><enum>4.</enum><header>Fuel economy of dual fueled automobiles</header><subsection id="HBCC5081074BF472D8BE29D3A5FF18323"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Measurement of fuel economy for electric dual fueled automobiles</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 32905(e) of title 49, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="H229DE05136544652A468F3715FE12B90"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), in the matter preceding subparagraph (A)—</text><subparagraph id="H3F3954B4EE6D43F693F46F2009A47458"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>At the request of the manufacturer, the Administrator may</quote> and inserting <quote>The Administrator shall</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0E65683E6F034DF28498C5DEA80147E6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>model year 2015</quote> and inserting <quote>model year 2026</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE3821472726348B2A45CDF189CEDD288"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by amending paragraph (2) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="HA3DC9BF8F336464D9B4C01265658BAE6" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H8FFE2B4220FA4FE3B371FC780A5C4997"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Review and updating of formula</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 3 years after the date of the enactment of this paragraph, and every 3 years thereafter, the Administrator shall, using real-world data if possible, review and update the formula for determining under paragraph (1) percentage utilization on gasoline or diesel fuel and percentage utilization on electricity. </text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD04EB2148CB846CFB4065D9003B7CD1D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Fuel economy information for dual fueled automobiles</header><paragraph id="HCF245845A9464AB5A1B28DF31AF613FD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Labeling requirements and contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 32908(b)(3) of title 49, United States Code, is amended—</text><subparagraph id="H3D44A7F6F8C540CFBDF83FE4C16996F9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (B), (C), and (D) as subparagraphs (D), (E), and (F), respectively; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H67FB698E77A14C5ABE36239D22C639AF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (A) the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H3F30990B9C6A451DAC476F62FFCBD081" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="HA7BBE9390A6843BB9B55059D536C8DF7" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">indicate the fuel economy of the automobile when operated primarily on alternative fuel;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE48F627D870049BAA0EA8AD7F6ABCB9B" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>indicate the multi-day average fuel economy of the automobile when operated on a combination of alternative fuel and gasoline or diesel fuel, with the percentage utilization of alternative fuel and the percentage utilization of gasoline or diesel fuel being determined by a formula based on real-world data and updated not less frequently than every 3 years;</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H96B2AA8DB07C41A1A9FED6E13DDC76E3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Fuel economy information booklet</header><text>Section 32908(c)(2)(B) of title 49, United States Code, is amended—</text><subparagraph id="HDA128A2909614451BB3EA21335008A6B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in clause (i), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H63FC63F24BF1497EAFBDFE9A258C3DE4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating clause (ii) as clause (iii); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5F2216C8172D461B9D400DDAE56423BA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after clause (i) the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="HF55CB974D7FE480F883CF6B0AB82B9DC" display-inline="no-display-inline"><clause id="H23F13B1F8BE443BDA361BEAD8BE97EE0" indent="up2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information on the multi-day average fuel economy of the automobile when operated on a combination of alternative fuel and gasoline or diesel fuel, as indicated under subsection (b)(3)(C); and</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H474D75E2948D4F979A316910B5F02DD8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply with respect to automobiles of model year 2027 or later.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

