<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD2C91FBE2CD043B3A4A0B23834AF8006" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1270 IH: To suspend the production of the penny and nickel, to require the Comptroller General of the United States to carry out a study on pennies and nickels, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1270</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250212">February 12, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001183">Mr. Schweikert</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To suspend the production of the penny and nickel, to require the Comptroller General of the United States to carry out a study on pennies and nickels, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H7BD6B13E1CB2422DBDACC0D12CFFE062" style="OLC"><section id="HB7C6D10043BE41099ED1E00A0F6E1500" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Saving taxpayers money by suspending production of the penny and nickel</header><subsection id="HA18DE283D1744C8AA268068FD751CD8D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Temporary suspension of production</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subsection (b) and notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary of the Treasury shall cease production of one-cent and five-cent coins during the 10-year period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H9C5D4D5A11A14E6392B92EDABB182325"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exception</header><paragraph id="HB26597C1A8FE4620865962D034B89AD7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury shall continue to produce one-cent and five-cent coins as appropriate solely to meet the needs of numismatic collectors of that denomination.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H35A0518448AC419FA5076D6B5A985819"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sale</header><text>The coins produced under paragraph (1) shall be sold in accordance with other general provisions governing numismatic coins (as opposed to circulating coins).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HADB13F998DE24CF885091C971CED00B5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Net receipts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The net receipts from the sale of one-cent and five-cent coins produced under this subsection shall equal the total cost of production, including variable costs and the appropriate share of fix costs of production, of the one-cent and five-cent coins, respectively, as determined by the Secretary of the Treasury.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H845ED758CC7A4EE39A5D72FCEDF60D1C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>No effect on legal tender</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, one-cent and five-cent coins are legal tender in the United States for all debts, public and private, public charges, taxes, and duties, regardless of the date of minting or issue.</text></subsection></section><section id="H6BD2F411433947ECB931BEB4AF728EF3"><enum>2.</enum><header>GAO study on the effects of the suspension of production of the penny and nickel</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury, Director of the United States Mint, and the Commissioner of the Internal Revenue Service, shall—</text><paragraph id="HF4B4CA8FFEB649A9B1FCC039FE0DB18A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>study the effect of the suspension of production of the one-cent and five-cent coins under this Act; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H66C25DF703834B589E35B3228E676667"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submit to the Committee on the Budget and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on the Budget and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives a report—</text><subparagraph id="H11C8680C787946C7B8285C1BA309D027"><enum>(A)</enum><text>on whether production should remain suspended, be permanently ended, or be reinstated; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF7EEB36D96D340B2A9AA3D17E1FA68B0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that considers—</text><clause id="H94C2D5D62DBA47C285F41EEC2A46550C"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the net savings from the suspension of production of the one-cent and five-cent coins; and</text></clause><clause id="H07B67205F98444EEA8E8CEEBC9C36315"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the effect of rounding cash purchases up or down to the nearest ten-cents.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

