<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB87741ABA5D448118C317336542A1F9E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4161 IH: Fair Calculations in Civil Damages Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4161</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250626">June 26, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001117">Mr. Casten</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit a court from awarding damages based on race, ethnicity, gender, or actual or perceived sexual orientation, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H7B5DF98347CF4619B4DD18E5A40F8968" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H2941AFB3C001411A847B8051B067F887" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Fair Calculations in Civil Damages Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HCD97801D78EB45C0A84CBF36D6D562D8" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act—</text> 
<paragraph id="HB5F484B36F3A47EAABB7474279A188EA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>future earnings table</term> includes any table or compilation of economic data used to determine, taking into account the median earnings in a geographic region—</text> <subparagraph id="H175A462297474E018060BF3991107513"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how many years an individual would have worked in the future; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H430C37C49BB04CB1B6D74F7CC51C6278"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the average wage an individual would have earned in the future; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H678B644F3B5147D1A50AA96264DC7A96"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>protected class</term> means a group of individuals sharing a common characteristic or identity who are legally protected against discrimination.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HAF605833557C41FD95D8B02118F0AC6E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Calculations of damages</header> 
<subsection id="H05906DBDA58C4CF4A75A31C559BFB0B9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no court of the United States may award damages to a plaintiff in a civil action using a calculation for the projected future earning potential of that plaintiff that takes into account the actual or perceived race, ethnicity, or sex (including gender, gender identity, sexual orientation, and sex characteristics including intersex traits).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H1305941984F74F3DAA72B9FBC69F0289"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall be construed to deny a court from ordering damages based on the fact that the plaintiff is a member of a protected class or for the purposes of Federal civil rights laws.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H16DF4AF66952426182A3CA2D4D776547"><enum>4.</enum><header>Inclusive future earnings tables</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act—</text> <paragraph id="HBA326C926DD64B41AA6BC219336F93E7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary of Labor shall develop guidance for forensic economists to develop inclusive future earnings tables that do not rely on race, ethnicity, gender, or actual or perceived sexual orientation; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE63DB4875B594FA1903D8864BED5376A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary of Labor and the Attorney General shall develop guidance for States on how to make calculations of future earnings in State tort proceedings free of bias on the basis of actual or perceived race, ethnicity, and sex (including gender, gender identity, sexual orientation, and sex characteristics including intersex traits).</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HDDE2971896044223B542E86857C93D05"><enum>5.</enum><header>Study and report</header> <subsection id="H4B6DB0186BCA4691B1F66F167F3899C7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Judicial Conference of the United States</header> <paragraph id="HED9F5A665AF244C1ADA36CE3E82DBA94"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Judicial Conference of the United States shall conduct a study on—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HA49CE5E04DBA4894836A8529F6CEE3DE"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">damages awarded under Federal law for personal injury; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H34F7DAE8CB324F4DA29AF0C1552871AA"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the aggregate data described in paragraph (1)—</text> 
<clause id="H97CB01E038BD414981F7A275A4CB0BEB">
                            <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by case type, including employment discrimination and tort damages; or</text>
                        </clause> 
<clause id="H3ACC5A8DB7F84B88BBBDCF8D21602355"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by protected classes, including actual or perceived race, ethnicity, and sex (including gender, gender identity, sexual orientation, and sex characteristics including intersex traits).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8358A6DA9E594A9B9B696F928CA86EE0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Judicial Conference of the United States shall submit to Congress a report on the study conducted under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA3D41DF770F943D1A096BF6BAF93CC12"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Administrative Office of the United States Courts</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrative Office of the United States Courts shall conduct a study and submit to Congress recommendations resulting from the study on how to ensure that calculations of future earning potential of plaintiffs that take into account age and disability without conflicting with Federal equal protection laws.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HAA26E1048BE6475DBA9003F0698E7D4C"><enum>6.</enum><header>Training</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Federal Judicial Center shall conduct training for Federal judges on how to implement this Act, including instructions on how to use tables on future earnings in evidence that comply with this Act.</text></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

