<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" slc-id="S1-RIL25161-S3L-V5-K53"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 89 ATS: Expressing support for the designation of February 15 through February 22, 2025, as “National FFA Week”, recognizing the important role of the National FFA Organization in developing the next generation of leaders who will change the world, and celebrating the 90th anniversary of New Farmers of America and the 75th anniversary of the Future Farmers of America Federal charter.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 89</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250221" legis-day="20250220">February 21 (legislative day, February 20), 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S391">Mr. Young</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S407">Mr. Hagerty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S437">Mr. Justice</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S375">Mr. Daines</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S430">Ms. Blunt Rochester</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S384">Mr. Tillis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S385">Ms. Cortez Masto</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S323">Mr. Risch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S252">Ms. Collins</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S418">Mr. Fetterman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S378">Mr. Lankford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S432">Mr. Gallego</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S317">Mr. Barrasso</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S388">Ms. Hassan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S372">Mrs. Capito</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S408">Mr. Hickenlooper</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S411">Mr. Marshall</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S318">Mr. Wicker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S363">Mr. King</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S410">Ms. Lummis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S406">Mr. Kelly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S153">Mr. Grassley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S409">Mr. Luján</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S416">Mrs. Britt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S395">Mrs. Hyde-Smith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S414">Mr. Ossoff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S404">Mr. Scott of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S174">Mr. McConnell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S415">Mr. Warnock</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S423">Mr. Ricketts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S343">Mr. Boozman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S376">Ms. Ernst</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S303">Mr. Thune</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S429">Mr. Banks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S435">Mr. Sheehy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S357">Mrs. Fischer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S374">Mr. Cotton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S419">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S420">Mr. Schmitt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S417">Mr. Budd</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S344">Mr. Hoeven</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S381">Mr. Rounds</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S398">Mr. Cramer</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of February 15 through February 22, 2025, as <quote>National FFA Week</quote>, recognizing the important role of the National FFA Organization in developing the next generation of leaders who will change the world, and celebrating the 90th anniversary of New Farmers of America and the 75th anniversary of the Future Farmers of America Federal charter.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the National FFA Organization (referred to in this preamble as <quote>FFA</quote>) was established in 1928;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the mission of FFA is to make a positive difference in the lives of students by developing their potential for premier leadership, personal growth, and career success through agricultural education;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the FFA has more than 1,000,000 members in 9,235 chapters in all 50 States, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the United States Virgin Islands, and the District of Columbia;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas FFA welcomes all students;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas more than 13,000 FFA advisors and agricultural education teachers deliver an integrated model of agricultural education, providing students with an innovative and cutting-edge education;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas FFA facilitates formative experiences, altering the course of students’ lives for the better;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas FFA members develop the necessary career-readiness skills to continue their education in college or to enter the workforce immediately;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas FFA prepares members to be globally conscious citizens of their community, their State, their country, and the world;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas FFA provides opportunities to demonstrate literacy, advocacy, and technical skills in agriculture, food, and natural resources; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas FFA members will celebrate <quote>National FFA Week</quote> during the week of February 15 through February 22, 2025: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H44534B960BE24AF1BC99D6A94F8A6AAB"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H5733742F05A74586949DECC4395CA1E7"><enum/><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="H56181D31D3524D628AF1DE23B21918A6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the designation of February 15 through February 22, 2025, as <quote>National FFA Week</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD3064A63FEB54EA688549B66402E4A45"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the important role of the National FFA Organization in developing the next generation of leaders who will change the world; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE713A10A1EFE427388FB0F690C1A9E5F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>celebrates the 90th anniversary of New Farmers of America which served Black vocational agriculture students in segregated public schools, until NFA and FFA became one organization in 1965; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4A8E5D94D75349E487AAEE38677C71C0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>commemorates the 75th anniversary of President Harry S. Truman signing into law the bill that provided the Federal charter for the Future Farmers of America on August 30, 1950.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

