<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ROS25469-3YK-H5-DCY"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1265 IS: USTR Inspector General Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1265</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250402">April 2, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S432">Mr. Gallego</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend title 5, United States Code, to establish an Inspector General of the Office of the United States Trade Representative, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>USTR Inspector General Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idec53368d892946169313294607dcbbb8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text><paragraph id="id70e1d198baab46018b382c26dc91acb1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Section 8 of article I of the Constitution of the United States provides that Congress has the sole power to regulate international trade.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc57bcfaa21254b7389e5a936e20ea47e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Congress established the Office of the United States Trade Representative in the Executive Office of the President under section 141 of the Trade Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/2171">19 U.S.C. 2171</external-xref>) with the primary responsibility for developing, and coordinating implementation of, the international trade policy of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbd8d3faf06cb48aa9c1f1faddb24dee2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The United States Trade Representative has primary responsibility for administering a variety of trade statutes and for monitoring the implementation and enforcement of trade agreements.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id852fe2afb3bb47e6939b2c57cf8a983e"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Section 141(c)(1)(F) of the Trade Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/2171">19 U.S.C. 2171(c)(1)(F)</external-xref>) states that the United States Trade Representative shall <quote>report directly to the President and the Congress regarding, and be responsible to the President and the Congress for the administration of, trade agreements programs</quote>. </text></paragraph></section><section id="id90C09B14DD804BB6BF2EB1772F5E487B"><enum>3.</enum><header>Establishment of Inspector General of the Office of the United States Trade Representative</header><subsection id="id6B1C7EBDB76346219AF684C24AA3111C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>Section 401 of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3D7E361AC5FD4784BD8A631D3C360AF0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>or the National Reconnaissance Office,</quote> and inserting <quote>the National Reconnaissance Office, or the Office of the United States Trade Representative,</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idD5699539119B46D596ADD0A1E267FD55"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>or the Director of the National Reconnaissance Office;</quote> and inserting <quote>the Director of the National Reconnaissance Office; or the United States Trade Representative;</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4624D618FB22494395632B66771288B0" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Appointment of Inspector General</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall appoint an individual to serve as the Inspector General of the Office for the United States Trade Representative in accordance with section 403(a) of title 5, United States Code. </text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

