<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6B289B5E5FC74BE68EDA4B17220B95A1" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3585 IH: Capacity Building for Business Districts Pilot Program Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3585</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250523">May 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000235">Mr. Ezell</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Public Works and Economic Development Act of 1965 to establish the Capacity Building for Business Districts Pilot Program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H09F253466E2C4276A2A983007524B5FA" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HA3F4D72B452B4A18AA40E6C8D808A949" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Capacity Building for Business Districts Pilot Program Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H6F5DDBE669FC44259A673321BF88C4D0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
<paragraph id="H647CFE4D8B1F4F0FA63E4C02E59FDAC1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Vibrant and prosperous business districts are vital components of thriving communities, providing critical commercial goods and services to community residents.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1CD53FA8184649D396878A15BB4A338B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Business districts contribute to the vitality, character, and identity of urban neighborhoods, small towns, and rural and Native communities.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H070A990402C34ED1B5563EEDAD8C502A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Business districts drive entrepreneurship, local business ownership, economic growth, and job creation.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD5FE074DCED24A0FAEB3BA9CE17ADBCC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Business districts are an essential part of the economic development ecosystem for towns, cities and rural communities, helping to attract consumers, visitors, new residents and new businesses to those communities and neighborhoods.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H96CB0D9FF1E049D8ACF70A5B04C08636"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Locally based business district organizations are well positioned to provide technical assistance and support to small and underserved businesses, while also helping to attract customers for those businesses by shaping and nurturing the physical environment of the business districts.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB3112B6E2C944C5AB7D3EA6B42A750E7"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Locally based business district organizations need technical assistance and flexible capital to support their ongoing operations, and cannot readily access these funds from existing programs at the Economic Development Administration due to the relatively small scale and highly local scope of their operations.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9BBF1F3C006941FA9A4A8230BAF700C8"><enum>(7)</enum><text>There exists a substantial number of intermediary organizations that are well positioned to receive and responsibly deploy funding from the Economic Development Administration to currently unserved or underserved business district organizations for capacity building grants, technical assistance, training, and dissemination of best practices.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HD70A9AF6F4564027B07D60A89700C4A0"><enum>3.</enum><header>Capacity building for business districts pilot program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 207 of the Public Works and Economic Development Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3147">42 U.S.C. 3147</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="H53028B792961462DAFD53C63A5A8B020"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(2)—</text> <subparagraph id="HAA0BD2FD481A44E49C85659E7531F4AE"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>by redesignating subparagraph (I) as subparagraph (J); and</text>
                </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H7F2DA6DFDC5A4ADCB8DB632DDACCC10F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (H) by striking the <quote>and</quote> at the end and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HFE766EA7176E4C8EAD7585EA343D60CB" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subparagraph id="H23C5492472834325A75B6845E6E22A0F"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">carrying out the pilot program established under subsection (c); and</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0149411B749D4E3BB2F9002C21769E99"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H301DA11B58D3489E9CF51CCED4BC9252" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="H7ED03AF66E874EB889FA9A2F690EEC29"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Capacity building for business districts pilot program</header> <paragraph id="H539ED24C1056477E99CEC6554A48A79B" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Within the program authorized under subsection (a), the Secretary shall establish a pilot program, to be known as the <quote>Capacity Building for Business Districts Pilot Program</quote>.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H65F9927D9CE24181B5F256A22B360CCA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Grants</header><text>The Secretary may award to specified recipients Capacity Building for Business Districts Pilot Program grants, on a competitive basis, to carry out place-based initiatives that provide specialized technical assistance, capacity building, and related services to eligible subrecipients that support business district revitalization in low-income, rural, minority and Native communities.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H007541BCEB4645C2A58ACD61F12FB551"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Multiple awards</header><text>In providing assistance under this subsection, the Secretary shall make multiple awards to multiple organizations.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB2F36B5CE82340088F33383FB1758FC4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Administration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may not carry out this subsection through a regional office.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H60194AFBC3C7491AAC037557E2C6D374"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Prioritization</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure a broad geographic distribution of award activities, and give priority to an applicant—</text>
<subparagraph id="HEFCBB01841924682897225BAA3790C8C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that would serve a distressed community in an area described under section 301(a), including rural communities and Indian Tribes; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9FBC7C200247460895EB1919B04767C0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that has the demonstrated capacity to serve multiple States or multiple geographies within a State.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1A401930BB5F49C489A11B3AABF3F719"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text>Specified recipients shall submit to the Secretary (at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may prescribe, but no more frequently than annually) a report specifying—</text> <subparagraph id="HC9D66A487DB542A6A5B4D73876B172AA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the names and addresses of eligible subrecipients receiving services and support from the specified recipient;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE5CD7E319F56431FB864EB1B5CB04F63"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the use of funds by the specified recipient, including direct technical assistance and pass-through grant funds;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8F45A3187D604C26B1BDD80C5B9985EE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the use of funds by the eligible subrecipients, including internal operations, direct services to businesses, and district revitalization activities;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HCE2BBE54C3B54FEEB1626986C2106388"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the specific geographic areas served by the eligible subrecipients;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE560759BED04428C941574DB4F5A13A5"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the name, address, and industry as determined by the North American Industry Classification System, of each entity receiving assistance from eligible subrecipients;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H4606B9D2AC534EB5B937A67D1365F892"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the total number of jobs created and retained during the reporting period; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H605A29BCB37C462EA44BC3FA6CC52211"><enum>(G)</enum><text>any other information as the Secretary considers appropriate consistent with the findings under section 2 of the <short-title>Capacity Building for Business Districts Pilot Program Act of 2025</short-title>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0C282C98857F473A817A1423E999EF1A"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Term</header><text>The term of an initial grant shall be for a period that the Secretary determines appropriate for the proposed activities but not less than 2 years.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H002677DB18C7428BB64EF60B239B332B"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection:</text>
<subparagraph id="HDD82495E7CE74AA58FA65940143554E8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Business district</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>business district</term> means a geographic area, which may have been designated as a business district by a State, county, regional or local unit of government, that is characterized by dense development, efficient land use, and a concentration of small businesses, economic activity, and employment opportunities or an area that could contain such concentration, including a rural main street or neighborhood commercial corridor.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB52AFD646F724838992945DE5B1900A1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Business district organization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>business district organization</term> means a public or nonprofit entity located in a business district and established to provide services to the business district to promote the district, attract private investment and create jobs, and enhance the physical environment through property development and planning activities.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H9B12B03DE68B4A88955A043F3631B782"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Capacity building</header><text>The term <term>capacity building</term> means training, education, support, advice, and the provision of operating grants to enhance the technical and administrative capabilities of business district organizations.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE9F6F10C4BA04A70977E6814F4695B80"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Eligible subrecipient</header><text>The term <term>eligible subrecipient</term> means a business district organization that—</text>
<clause id="H46C99DD964274DA3A7BF956779F6FE2E" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is an organization that—</text> <subclause id="H4F7A117A99F44EB3B8B76EFD3CC48840" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is described in paragraph (3), (4), (5), or (6) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and is exempt from taxation under section 501(a) of such Code; or</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H3554A84B98EA450B9E65C06F16C67939" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is a public entity; and</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HDC4946D282CE4774A8D50A54F9562F05"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provides services to a business district located in an area described under section 301(a) to support economic development, including providing business support services and physical space enhancements to such district.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H76424C913FFC452395E8E80F8CA51475"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Specified recipient</header><text>The term <term>specified recipient</term> means an organization that—</text> <clause id="HBD5DE74AAF384D5FB42947119E531190"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is described in paragraph (3), (4), (5), or (6) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and is exempt from taxation under section 501(a) of such Code;</text></clause>
<clause id="H9B0CA38FCB1F4029A575DE11BB475C17"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>operates, including through affiliates, membership networks or partnerships with third party entities, in multiple geographic areas served by multiple regional offices of the Economic Development Administration; and</text></clause> <clause id="HE610704A84584227928E9A8D3DDC7F98"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>has experience and expertise in providing technical assistance and executing capacity building programs in support of business district organizations and similar community-based organizations that focus on revitalizing business districts and commercial corridors, including through support of underserved small businesses.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

