<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="first-star-print" slc-id="S1-REI25083-CN3-25-WF9" key="G"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 312 IS: Recognizing June 2025, as “LGBTQ Pride Month”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 312</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250630">June 30, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S394">Ms. Smith</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S428">Ms. Alsobrooks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S354">Ms. Baldwin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S330">Mr. Bennet</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S430">Ms. Blunt Rochester</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S275">Ms. Cantwell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S385">Ms. Cortez Masto</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S418">Mr. Fetterman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S432">Mr. Gallego</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S331">Mrs. Gillibrand</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S388">Ms. Hassan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S359">Mr. Heinrich</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S408">Mr. Hickenlooper</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S406">Mr. Kelly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S426">Mr. Kim</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S363">Mr. King</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S409">Mr. Luján</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S364">Mr. Murphy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S229">Mrs. Murray</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S414">Mr. Ossoff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S380">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S259">Mr. Reed</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S402">Ms. Rosen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S313">Mr. Sanders</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S353">Mr. Schatz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S436">Ms. Slotkin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S327">Mr. Warner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S415">Mr. Warnock</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S422">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S316">Mr. Whitehouse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S366">Ms. Warren</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing June 2025, as <quote>LGBTQ Pride Month</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the story of the lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, and queer (referred to in this preamble as <quote>LGBTQ</quote>) community in the United States is one of courage rising from marginalization, of joy forged in the crucible of injustice, and of progress built by generations who refused to be silent, invisible, or erased;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas LGBTQ individuals live and thrive in every corner of the United States—from Alabama to Alaska, from barrios to boardrooms—bringing with them a diversity of race, religion, ability, origin, political belief, and lived experience that enriches the soul of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas LGBTQ individuals have made indelible contributions across every sector of society, including education, science, law, public service, the arts, technology, business, and the ongoing struggle for civil rights, helping to shape a more equitable and vibrant United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the persistent failure of Federal and State officials to collect full and accurate data on sexual orientation and gender identity causes tremendous harm to LGBTQ individuals in the United States, who remain largely invisible to the government entities entrusted with ensuring their health, safety, and well-being;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas LGBTQ individuals in the United States serve, and have served, in the United States Army, Coast Guard, Navy, Air Force, Marines, and Space Force honorably and with distinction and bravery;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas a decades-long Federal policy, known as the <quote>Lavender Scare</quote>, threatened and intimidated Federal public servants from employment due to their sexual orientation by alleging LGBTQ individuals posed a threat to national security, preventing many more from entering the workforce;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas an estimated number of more than 100,000 brave service members were discharged from the Armed Forces between the beginning of World War II and 2011 because of their sexual orientation, including the discharge of more than 13,000 service members under the <quote>Don’t Ask, Don’t Tell</quote> policy that was in place between 1994 and 2011;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas transgender people had been able to serve openly in the military since 2016, but were arbitrarily banned from service in 2025;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas LGBTQ individuals in the United States serve, and have served, in positions in the Federal Government and State and local governments, including as members of Congress, Cabinet Secretaries, Governors, mayors, and city council members;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the demonstrators who protested on June 28, 1969, following a law enforcement raid of the Stonewall Inn, an LGBTQ club in New York City, are pioneers of the LGBTQ movement for equality;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, throughout much of the history of the United States, same-sex relationships were criminalized in many States, and many LGBTQ individuals in the United States were forced to hide their LGBTQ identities while living in secrecy and fear;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on June 26, 2015, the Supreme Court of the United States ruled in Obergefell v. Hodges, 576 U.S. 644 (2015), that same-sex couples have a constitutional right to marry and acknowledged that <quote>[n]o union is more profound than marriage, for it embodies the highest ideals of love, fidelity, devotion, sacrifice, and family</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the HIV epidemic, worsened by government inaction and social stigma, decimated LGBTQ communities—especially among Black and Brown gay men and transgender women—and yet, the community responded not with despair but with determination, launching a global movement for health justice;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas people living with HIV continue to face discrimination in the United States and, in certain States, may be subject to greater criminal punishment than individuals without HIV;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the LGBTQ community maintains its unwavering commitment to ending the HIV and AIDS epidemic;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas LGBTQ individuals in the United States face disparities in employment, healthcare, education, housing, and many other areas central to the pursuit of happiness in the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 17 States have no explicit ban on discrimination based on sexual orientation and gender identity in the workplace;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 19 States have no explicit ban on discrimination based on sexual orientation or gender identity in housing;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 22 States have no explicit ban on discrimination based on sexual orientation or gender identity in public accommodations;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 30 States have no explicit ban on discrimination against LGBTQ individuals in credit and lending services;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, as a result of discrimination, LGBTQ youth are at increased risk of—</text><paragraph id="ida4b9f8a63c6948079a1dc20e5be3a17c"><enum>(1)</enum><text>suicidality;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf72836b1fad64d1f9d73d9e0d1f1a0d8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>homelessness;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfdb7811692ed4ea99fa3b620cb634c2a"><enum>(3)</enum><text>becoming victims of bullying, violence, or human trafficking; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id63e51fee93794fa4916c937d3fadeb87"><enum>(4)</enum><text>developing mental health conditions, including anxiety and depression;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas LGBTQ youth of color are overrepresented in child welfare and juvenile justice systems;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the LGBTQ community has faced discrimination, inequality, and violence throughout the history of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, at both the State and Federal levels, the LGBTQ community has been repeatedly targeted by politically motivated legislation and executive actions aimed at restricting LGBTQ rights, limiting access to essential services, and erasing the visibility and recognition of LGBTQ individuals;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas LGBTQ individuals in the United States, in particular transgender individuals, face a disproportionately high risk of becoming victims of violent hate crimes;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas members of the LGBTQ community have been targeted in acts of mass violence, including—</text><paragraph id="id54ca7b94b1734bf7b05974cd167c2adb"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Club Q nightclub shooting in Colorado Springs, Colorado, on November 19, 2022, where 5 people were killed and 25 people were wounded;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6edd4baace0d480d8f318af371fae5e1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Pulse nightclub shooting in Orlando, Florida, on June 12, 2016, where 49 people were killed and 53 people were wounded; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id22a5148128024c60b1cb987637c4a5ff"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the arson attack at the UpStairs Lounge in New Orleans, Louisiana, on June 24, 1973, where 32 people died;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas LGBTQ individuals face persecution, violence, and death in many parts of the world, including State-sponsored violence like in Uganda, where LGBTQ people live under threat of the death penalty;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in the several years preceding 2019, hundreds of LGBTQ individuals around the world were arrested and, in some cases, tortured or even executed because of their actual or perceived sexual orientation or gender identity in countries and territories such as Chechnya, Egypt, Indonesia, and Tanzania;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the global movement for marriage equality continues to gain momentum, with—</text><paragraph id="id4f3cd0c65d3a4d0089f36a01d3ae85fc"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Thailand becoming the first Southeast Asian country to legalize same-sex marriage in January 2025;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8fc8608de31841a595708638b5ab4d5b"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Liechtenstein recently enacting its own marriage equality law; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id761bfd5c1f8141a8a0356440cbad1947"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Taiwan, in 2019, making history as the first place in Asia to extend marriage rights to same-sex couples;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, since June 2019, Ecuador, Costa Rica, Northern Ireland, Switzerland, Chile, Slovenia, Andorra, Cuba, Greece, and Estonia have extended marriage rights to same-sex couples;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the LGBTQ community holds Pride festivals and marches in some of the most dangerous places in the world, despite threats of violence and arrest;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2009, President Barack Obama signed the Matthew Shepard and James Byrd, Jr. Hate Crimes Prevention Act (division E of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/84">Public Law 111–84</external-xref>; 123 Stat. 2835) into law to protect all individuals in the United States from crimes motivated by their actual or perceived sexual orientation or gender identity;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas LGBTQ individuals in the United States have fought for equal treatment, dignity, and respect;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas LGBTQ individuals in the United States have achieved significant milestones, ensuring that future generations of LGBTQ individuals in the United States will enjoy a more equal and just society;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, despite being marginalized throughout the history of the United States, LGBTQ individuals in the United States continue to celebrate their identities, love, and contributions to the United States in various expressions of Pride;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in June 2020, in Bostock v. Clayton County, 140 S. Ct. 1731 (2020), the Supreme Court of the United States affirmed that existing civil rights laws prohibit employment discrimination on the basis of sexual orientation and gender identity, a landmark victory for the LGBTQ community;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in December 2022, Congress enacted the Respect for Marriage Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/228">Public Law 117–228</external-xref>; 136 Stat. 2305), which repealed the discriminatory legal definition of marriage as limited to a relationship between a man and a woman, and the discriminatory definition of a spouse as a person of the opposite sex; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas LGBTQ individuals in the United States remain determined to pursue full equality, respect, and inclusion for all individuals regardless of sexual orientation or gender identity: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id8fefd6dc04bb43ca88ec830572da2c91"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the rights, freedoms, and equal treatment of lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, and queer (referred to in this resolution as <quote>LGBTQ</quote>) individuals in the United States and around the world;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc4dc0a87d673413f81de1bfd7707be7a"><enum>(2)</enum><text>acknowledges that LGBTQ rights are human rights that are to be protected by the laws of the United States and numerous international treaties and conventions;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8725007f04b248c7877a21deb67c3211"><enum>(3)</enum><text>supports efforts to ensure the equal treatment of all individuals in the United States, regardless of sexual orientation and gender identity;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8d37106ed400467c92ed620693e4fe2c"><enum>(4)</enum><text>supports efforts to ensure that the United States remains a beacon of hope for the equal treatment of individuals around the world, including LGBTQ individuals; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida0a6301f9e40425d87d417784c619a94"><enum>(5)</enum><text>encourages the celebration of June as <quote>LGBTQ Pride Month</quote> in order to provide a lasting opportunity for all individuals in the United States—</text><subparagraph id="id6a8c4bc5c9c142e698917d2513c7549e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to learn about the discrimination and inequality that the LGBTQ community endured and continues to endure; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id17a026a6c8fd4e6994dbcf8933177a6c"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to celebrate the contributions of the LGBTQ community throughout the history of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

