<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB88CF4BB042B45B386CFA9A6B5E69FC3" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 320 IH: Encouraging the Department of State and civil society to further the Abraham Accords by encouraging peace and tolerance in education.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 320</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250409">April 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001190">Mr. Schneider</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="W000812">Mrs. Wagner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000601">Mr. Goldman of Texas</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Encouraging the Department of State and civil society to further the Abraham Accords by encouraging peace and tolerance in education.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the Abraham Accords shattered barriers, improved ties between Israel and neighboring countries, and advanced the cause of achieving lasting peace in the Middle East, including through a negotiated solution to the Israeli-Palestinian conflict that ensures mutual recognition and guarantees that Israelis and Palestinians live side by side with freedom, security, and prosperity, and this negotiated solution must include recognition of the State of Israel’s right to exist;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas it is the policy of the United States to develop and implement a regional security strategy that recognizes the shared threat posed by Iran and violent extremist organizations, ensures sufficient United States deterrence in the region, builds partner capacity to address shared threats, and explores multilateral security arrangements built around like-minded partners;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Abraham Accords created formal diplomatic ties between Israel and the United Arab Emirates, Bahrain, and Morocco, deepening understanding, cooperation, and friendship among the countries;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the leadership and success of prior accords between Egypt and Israel paved the way for creating formal diplomatic ties with other Arab and Muslim-majority countries;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Congress supports the expansion of the Abraham Accords across the world, in particular to Saudi Arabia and Indonesia;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Congress is committed to fostering education abroad with the values of peace and tolerance while encouraging other countries to do the same;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas peace and tolerance in national curricula and education is critical to mitigate extremist influences to create a peaceful world and tolerant societies of the future;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Israel Relations Normalization Act of 2021 maintains that antisemitism education is a critical component of a peace and tolerance curriculum;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Egypt, the United Arab Emirates, Bahrain, and Morocco have made transformative and positive changes in their national curriculum, and these changes include the reduction or removal of antisemitic content, the elimination of hate speech, and the insertion of new educational material promoting respect, tolerance, and peace with others;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas there have been similar positive changes in the national curriculum of Saudi Arabia and Indonesia, who are actively implementing educational reforms that foster inclusivity, respect, and understanding; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas civil society reports on reforms of national curriculum in the region, which apply methodological standards on education for peace and tolerance, have been instrumental in encouraging positive change throughout the Arab and Muslim world: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H5422D36C7B6740A09DBF52B32AE0DC94"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H13898E5C265748BDA30649754C607268"><enum/><text>That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="H0FA731FE72E94D63B6DC6767E1F6598F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">encourages Israel and its Arab and Muslim-majority neighbors to continue to deepen and expand cooperation across the full spectrum of economic, security, and civilian issues, emphasizing collaborative efforts in peace and tolerance education;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H99BCB3E6940C46E7AD5C39334D81D8BB"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">encourages international organizations, including the United Nations, to improve and prioritize counter-incitement in its educational work throughout the region, as well as take steps to eliminate antisemitism across all United Nations bodies;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC661C13194B743A6B87576839C484EB1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>supports the expansion and strengthening of the Abraham Accords to urge other countries to normalize relations with Israel and ensure that existing agreements reap tangible security and economic benefits for the citizens of those countries and all peoples in the region;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5BB05B53E547465D8D0F76A35225E7BD"><enum>(4)</enum><text>encourages the Department of State to proactively engage with countries in the region, supporting the goals of this resolution and the Israel Relations Normalization Act of 2021, to press for curricula reform in bilateral dialogues as a key agenda item to help facilitate the implementation of positive changes that promote regional stability, peace, and tolerance based on international standards; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC1E9CAB537F742D4A1EBDA774200CA56"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">encourages civil society and partners across the United States to continue working together with governments across the world to make sure the next generation of children receives a quality, comprehensive peace and tolerance education.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

