<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H04AEB375E4D048F59DB6B780A1310E38" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 277 IH: Supporting the designation of May 2025 as “National Myositis Awareness Month”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 277</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250331">March 31, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001218">Mr. McCormick</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Supporting the designation of May 2025 as <quote>National Myositis Awareness Month</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas residents of the United States of America are among those affected by myositis and other rare diseases, with nearly 1 in 10 Americans having rare diseases;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas idiopathic inflammatory myopathies (collectively referred to as myositis) are rare, chronic, autoimmune muscle-wasting diseases that often feature debilitating muscle inflammation and other symptoms, such as pain, fatigue, and trouble swallowing, and can result in myositis-associated interstitial lung disease;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas more research is needed to identify the causes of and modes of treatments for the myositis group of diseases, which includes anti-MDA5 autoantibody-positive myositis, antisynthetase syndrome, dermatomyositis, juvenile dermatomyositis, immune-mediated necrotizing myopathy, inclusion body myositis, and polymyositis;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas myositis is difficult to diagnose which leads myositis patients to frequently experience delayed treatment and difficulty finding a health care provider with expertise in their condition;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas all who suffer with myositis experience reduced quality of life, particularly since no cure has been found and life expectancy is shortened, especially for those with inclusion body myositis, and women and people of color with all forms of myositis experience particularly pronounced health disparities; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas public awareness and education campaigns on myositis detection and treatment are held during the month of May: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HEB76FB8959B5438794B70D08332E9CFC"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HD70B7F1FC5614D2C84E322D775717158"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="HC8E93613031B4EFA9C45C4ABAA73F2DE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the designation of <quote>National Myositis Awareness Month</quote>;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAC73E5B48F1A4C4BA0B67EC96F28929F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the importance of raising awareness about myositis and its impact on United States veterans and citizens; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H259968C5200C4D69B5683730E3550189"><enum>(3)</enum><text>encourages all people in the United States to become more informed about myositis and to support the individuals and families who are affected by these conditions.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

