<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HFC09AE1367174968A61EE2BD8B762BAA" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4066 IH: Countering White Supremacist Extremism Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4066</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250620">June 20, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000788">Ms. Williams of Georgia</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Under Secretary for Intelligence and Analysis of the Department of Homeland Security to develop and disseminate a threat assessment regarding threats to the United States associated with foreign violent white supremacist extremist organizations, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H55348AC1B98440558C2151C9B3B71F36" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H710BA38D1BB3465BB54D0C331CAA4D04" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Countering White Supremacist Extremism Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H0317FE644D6540E2B8BC4205A18A951C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Threat assessment</header> 
<subsection id="H327D03130160484D835A908B2202B77B">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Under Secretary for Intelligence and Analysis of the Department of Homeland Security shall, in coordination with appropriate Federal partners, develop a terrorism threat assessment and reference aid regarding threats to the United States associated with foreign violent white supremacist extremist organizations. Consistent with the protection of classified and confidential unclassified information, the Under Secretary shall share the threat assessment developed under this section with State, local, and Tribal law enforcement officials, including officials who operate within State, local, and regional fusion centers through the Department of Homeland Security State, Local, and Regional Fusion Center Initiative established in accordance with section 210A of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/124h">6 U.S.C. 124h</external-xref>).</text>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="H6B6411F5F6DE469E980CBC4126DF57D5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Foundation, incorporation, and coordination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The threat assessment and reference aid developed pursuant to subsection (a)—</text> <paragraph id="H63153B4EE1EA4EA893821CE19841A558"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall be—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF62985C2B84F4067B4FDBF8CE0377D8B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">based on and incorporate appropriate elements of the Department of State Strategy for Countering White Identity Terrorism Globally required under section 1299F of the William M. (Mac) Thornberry National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/283">Public Law 116–283</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2656j">22 U.S.C. 2656j</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H808C2EF0068B4DF1AC5D7785B722DCF1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>developed in coordination with the Office of Civil Rights and Civil Liberties of the Department of Homeland Security and other appropriate Federal agencies; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF787076FBE0A4C74A9C38D7FA9A9975D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may be informed by existing products developed by such Office and agencies, as appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE0615357EEB14E6D80A86DC823A979D8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Overview</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The threat assessment and reference aid shall include an overview of symbols, flags, or other references utilized by adherents of foreign violent white supremacist extremist organizations.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HCBA19D7A9DA94521880C1522E47E7A96"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Distribution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Consistent with the protection of classified and confidential unclassified information, the Under Secretary for Intelligence and Analysis of the Department of Homeland Security shall share the threat assessment and reference aid with the following:</text> <paragraph id="H01FF4C579055486EBCF10EAE91A28E48"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">State, local, and Tribal law enforcement officials, including officials who operate within State, local, and regional fusion centers through the Department of Homeland Security State, Local, and Regional Fusion Center Initiative established in accordance with section 210A of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/124h">6 U.S.C. 124h</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3F40998CBEDA431C8DB800144AF36765"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Appropriate owners and operators of online platforms to assist in identifying content that may be associated with a foreign violent white supremacist extremist organization that may violate the terms of service of such online platforms, upon request from such online platforms and in consultation with the Office of Civil Rights and Civil Liberties of the Department.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H0F4C56A99FB1424FB035F9A5F287E8BB"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="HA607EB9301844A8287C552E8956DEBF2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Foreign violent white supremacist extremist organization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>foreign violent white supremacist extremist organization</quote> means an organization based outside the United States that seeks, wholly or in part, through unlawful acts of force or violence, to support a belief in the intellectual and moral superiority of the white race over other races.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H59F7F6AFE08944C88C5275AA107A4833"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Online platform</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>online platform</quote> means internet-based information services consisting of the storage and processing of information by and at the request of a content provider and the dissemination of such content to third parties.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H366178DDCF7949AC873D3183A7872DEE"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Under Secretary for Intelligence and Analysis of the Department of Homeland Security shall ensure that the threat assessment and reference aid does not contain the name or other identifiable information of any individual or organization engaged in lawful political or public discourse in the United States protected under the United States Constitution.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

