<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-HEN25889-0G9-HM-N4Y"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2639 IS: Military Spouse Entrepreneurship Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2639</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250731">July 31, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S384">Mr. Tillis</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSSB00">Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Administrator of the Small Business Administration to establish and carry out a program that assists military spouses in establishing small business concerns, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="ide7a08a9fe56648adbb082549525d0c97"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Military Spouse Entrepreneurship Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id9BE9A9FD62214A7883BD3793C39DFE93"><enum>2.</enum><header>Entrepreneurship assistance for military spouses</header><subsection id="id2A70936527EF48F3876B26080C433E3F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="id5BE3B0DF275E45C7A47800F39268DA27"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Small Business Administration.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idD834635AF10E4B79956FD39E4B1A8D67"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Small business concern</header><text>The term <term>small business concern</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/632">15 U.S.C. 632</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id8F37FF5F6DA8488A9D5054A251BC0E19"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Program</header><paragraph id="idB7B7EA9BDEDA4D56A6BE19F1A264FC32"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2), the Administrator shall establish a program within the Small Business Administration—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfb3d0930cee8459493f77b534dd4a716"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the purpose of which shall be to assist military spouses in forming, operating, and growing small business concerns; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3d049b320f05415fa0b6b5e09f7d5906"><enum>(B)</enum><text>which shall include providing such assistance through remotely accessible online services.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idA5E1B88F3B554466AB890A50FC692073"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Extension of existing program</header><text>In lieu of establishing a new program, the Administrator may carry out the purpose described in paragraph (1) through an extension of a program that is in existence, as of the date of enactment of this Act, if that extension is tailored to military spouses and otherwise achieves that purpose and satisfies the requirements of this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id1A284F2EFC574ECA86432630B60F7B3D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Assistance</header><text>The assistance provided by the Administrator under the program described in subsection (b) shall include the following:</text><paragraph id="id1DF15B517DCC4EB1A00B2A1F2240AAD3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Assistance for military spouses in identifying and understanding the requirements with respect to forming and operating a small business concern, including assistance relating to relocating the operations of a small business concern.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idFF9D3149DC0B47E2B08727559BCEF1D6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Assistance for military spouses in strengthening the expertise and skills necessary for the formation and operation of a small business concern, including the expertise and skills necessary to create a sustainable small business concern throughout the uniquely challenging requirements of life as a military spouse, which arise as a result of—</text><subparagraph id="id3471DF241B3D43F18D8376BAB1593727"><enum>(A)</enum><text>military deployments;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6A54CBA6BD5E4506B3F5D99907D01780"><enum>(B)</enum><text>military-related absences from the workforce; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9D46F4E37DE7468E97B7F8392646114A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>multiple permanent changes of duty station or other long-term relocations for military reasons.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idDB6390F70D9C43F8AC9B10EB77D71B63"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Through partnerships with organizations supporting military spouse entrepreneurship and business volunteer entities (including by entering into cooperative agreements with those organizations and entities), providing mentorship to military spouses with respect to entrepreneurship.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0F2A11ADE08F494C98B7E7348ADAD1F0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Any other assistance that the Administrator determines to be appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id35DE5D8DBB404173B0F422F0204D9629"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Survey; report</header><paragraph id="id94F73A8A4B2B44BBAAF4EE519BBD1BC9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Survey</header><subparagraph id="id609719A11BCF45F4B9260D55F45B2A7B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator, in consultation with such nonprofit organizations and other stakeholders determined appropriate by the Administrator, shall conduct a survey to identify the barriers to forming, operating, and growing small business concerns that are faced by military spouses as a result of life as a military spouse, including as a result of the conditions described in subparagraphs (A), (B), and (C) of subsection (c)(2).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idDA61810809F942618AB54CA0FAD04345"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Analysis required</header><text>The survey conducted under subparagraph (A) shall include an analysis of the challenges that military spouses face in accessing capital and other critical resources with respect to forming, operating, and growing small business concerns, including the education, mentoring, and training that is required to form, operate, and grow a small business concern.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idC61FE6ACC56F4B6F9CD92086268475FD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall submit to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship of the Senate and the Committee on Small Business of the House of Representatives a report containing the results of the survey conducted under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id56B3A97A20D04C7FA7AFC1DECBCF5DE6"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Use of results; outreach</header><text>In carrying out the program described in subsection (b), the Administrator shall—</text><paragraph id="idACB8B31CC0484264B70F2EE0B9BCB77A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>take into consideration the results of the survey conducted under subsection (d)(1); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id76CB1C638AFF49CA91D249EA0D7BA6B5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>develop an outreach program to ensure that the program becomes well-known.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id6943FD8363DA4EED8D6CDDDC1CBC036C"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Consultation permitted</header><text>In carrying out this section, the Administrator may consult with the Secretary of Defense, as determined necessary by the Administrator.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

