<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB539676DEAA342D0A4DD46D109568F3A" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 375 IH: Expressing support for the designation of May 2025 as “Renewable Fuels Month” to recognize the important role that renewable fuels play in reducing carbon impacts, lowering fuel prices for consumers, supporting rural communities, and lessening reliance on foreign adversaries.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 375</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250501">May 1, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000193">Mr. Nunn of Iowa</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001119">Ms. Craig</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001091">Mrs. Hinson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000474">Mr. Flood</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001315">Ms. Budzinski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001172">Mr. Smith of Nebraska</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000475">Mr. Finstad</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001215">Mrs. Miller-Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001212">Mr. Stauber</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001225">Mr. Sorensen</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000446">Mr. Feenstra</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of May 2025 as <quote>Renewable Fuels Month</quote> to recognize the important role that renewable fuels play in reducing carbon impacts, lowering fuel prices for consumers, supporting rural communities, and lessening reliance on foreign adversaries.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the United States is the largest producer of biofuels in the world, which contributes to the domestic economy, creates jobs, and reduces greenhouse gas emissions;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas ethanol is a renewable fuel made of biomass from plant materials;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2024, more than 55,810 jobs in the United States were directly associated with the ethanol industry, with an additional 258,089 indirect and induced jobs supported across all sectors of the economy;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the ethanol industry created $28,300,000,000 in household income and contributed more than $53,000,000,000 to the gross domestic product of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas ethanol and feed co-product production provide a valuable market for United States corn, as a typical dry mill ethanol plant adds nearly $2 of additional value, or 55 percent, to every bushel of corn processed;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas ethanol use reduces greenhouse gas emissions by between 44 and 52 percent compared to gasoline, and by displacing hydrocarbon substances like aromatics in gasoline, ethanol also helps reduce emissions of air toxins, particulate matter, carbon monoxide, nitrous oxides, and exhaust hydrocarbons;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2024, ethanol played a vital role in bolstering the energy independence of the United States by supplementing nearly 630,000,000 barrels of imported crude oil;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2024, ethanol exports reached a record 1,930,000,000 gallons, an increase of over 500,000,000 gallons compared to 2023;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas <fraction>1/3</fraction> of every bushel processed by an ethanol plant is used to make distillers grains, one of the most efficient and desirable animal feeds available;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas biodiesel is a drop-in replacement for petroleum-based diesel fuel that is produced from renewable resources such as recycled cooking oil, soybean oil, distillers corn oil, canola oil, and animal fats;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas renewable diesel is an advanced biofuel, made from the same feedstocks as biodiesel, that reduces greenhouse gas emissions, while meeting the same standard specification for diesel fuels as petroleum-based diesel;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas biofuel production uses more than 1,000,000,000 pounds of soybean oil per month and generates increasing amounts of soybean meal for feed markets, driving a 30 percent increase in crush capacity across the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the biodiesel and renewable diesel sectors generated a total economic impact of $23,300,000,000, supporting 75,200 United States jobs and contributing $3,600,000,000 in wages;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas biodiesel and renewable diesel can be used in existing diesel engines without modification and are available throughout the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas advanced biofuels like biodiesel and renewable diesel reduce greenhouse gas emissions by at least 50 percent compared to petroleum-based diesel;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas biodiesel emits up to 80 percent less particulate matter than petroleum-based diesel, improving air quality and health outcomes;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the production of biodiesel and renewable diesel adds to the total domestic fuel supply, reducing the price of all diesel fuel at the pump;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, without the renewable fuel standard helping to drive production of biodiesel and renewable diesel, the value of soybeans grown by farmers in the United States would decrease by 8 percent;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas sustainable aviation fuel is made from renewable biomass and waste resources and can deliver the performance of petroleum-based jet fuel; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas sustainable aviation fuel can be blended with conventional jet fuel and the use of sustainable or blended aviation fuel requires no infrastructure or equipment changes: Now, therefore, be it </text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="OLC" id="H4842B11679E5456D9A588485265526A4"><section id="H2DB15D11240E4F83AD9982CD58946AA0" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="HFE38A02AF27643458CC0A1416D192D9C" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the designation of <quote>Renewable Fuels Month</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE1EBADE235C54B0281C83A7EE99FBF46"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes—</text><subparagraph id="HCC32504A0BFB41D78019C31851E43322"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the important role renewable fuels play in reducing the carbon impact of the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H36D2F23E2C9A4B90BC6D79F2FCE7D8E4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the ability of renewable fuels to lower fuel prices for consumers;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H84BDC9B4C9C94BDD8DF27E68BBB27249"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the support to rural communities that renewable fuel industries provide; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD79D051B6BC1487DB0DA02953ACBA0E6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the opportunity that the production of renewable fuels provides to lessen the reliance of the United States on foreign adversaries.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

