<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H45A0D959F0A241FDA1CD09B1547DB8F4" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 661 IH: Expressing support for the designation of August 22, 2025, as “Chuck Brown Day”, and honoring Chuck Brown’s contributions to music and to the District of Columbia.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 661</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250822">August 22, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of August 22, 2025, as <quote>Chuck Brown Day</quote>, and honoring Chuck Brown’s contributions to music and to the District of Columbia.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Chuck Brown is known as the <quote>Godfather of Go-Go</quote> because he was the major architect of the musical genre known as <quote>go-go</quote>, a unique mix of funk, soul, and Latin party sounds, whose popularity continues today;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Chuck Brown, who was born on August 22, 1936, and passed away at the age of 75 on May 16, 2012, was a resident of the District of Columbia most of his life;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Chuck Brown, who taught himself to play guitar, became a virtuoso singer, songwriter, guitarist, and bandleader;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Chuck Brown’s go-go beat gave the District of Columbia a musical identity of its own and reminds the Nation that the District of Columbia has always been the hometown of talented artists;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Chuck Brown’s musical catalog spans 22 studio albums over 3 decades;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Chuck Brown’s hit <quote>Bustin’ Loose</quote>, with his group, the Soul Searchers, was the top song on the Billboard Top 100 R&amp;B Chart for 4 weeks in 1979;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Chuck Brown earned a Grammy nomination in 2010 for the song <quote>Love</quote>, from his album entitled <quote>We Got This</quote>, and was awarded a National Endowment for the Arts National Heritage Fellowship in 2005;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Chuck Brown’s go-go has been passed from generation to generation with undiminished popularity;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Chuck Brown influenced jazz, rap, and go-go musicians, such as the bands Trouble Funk, Rare Essence, and Experience Unlimited (also known as <quote>E.U.</quote>);</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Chuck Brown was so committed to securing statehood and equal voting rights for the residents of the District of Columbia that he played a concert on a very hot, humid day on the United States Capitol Grounds in 2010;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the District of Columbia has named a street located near the historic Howard Theatre for Chuck Brown;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the District of Columbia has named a park located at 2901 20th Street NE, for Chuck Brown;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas go-go is the official music of the District of Columbia;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Chuck Brown is admired for having risen from humble beginnings and overcoming time in prison to become a devoted father and family man;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Chuck Brown was a great, multitalented musician who brought joy through his music, never stopping until his death; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas August 22, 2025, is Chuck Brown’s birthday: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HE9AB60570E9847CBB316B98ED0BDC095"> 
<section id="H35442DDA24A946CBA09039596CD1A470" section-type="undesignated-section" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives supports the designation of <quote>Chuck Brown Day</quote>, and honors Chuck Brown’s contributions to music and to the District of Columbia.</text></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

