<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-SIL25121-GJL-RV-LX5"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S464 IS: No Central Bank Digital Currency Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 464</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250206" legis-day="20250205">February 6 (legislative day, February 5), 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S346">Mr. Lee</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S355">Mr. Cruz</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S404">Mr. Scott of Florida</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Federal Reserve Act to limit the ability of Federal Reserve banks to issue central bank digital currency.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No Central Bank Digital Currency Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>No CBDC Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id6B85E88FD6BD414A973A17E510450A7D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Central bank digital currency</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 13 of the Federal Reserve Act is amended by adding after the 14th undesignated paragraph (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/347d">12 U.S.C. 347d</external-xref>) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3bb56b107d044587a8d04d1d6d506e82"><paragraph id="idd0ea394a3511439c94b7c82cfba9de11"><enum/><text>No Federal reserve bank, the Board, the Secretary of the Treasury, any other agency, or any entity directed to act on behalf of the Federal reserve bank, the Board, the Secretary, or other agency, may mint or issue a central bank digital currency directly to an individual (including central bank digital currency issued to an individual through a custodial intermediary) or a digital currency intermediary, offer related products or services directly to an individual, or maintain an account on behalf of an individual (including an account in a specially designated account at a digital currency intermediary or supervised commercial bank). No Federal reserve bank may hold digital currencies minted or issued by the United States Government as assets or liabilities on a balance sheet of the bank or use such digital currencies as part of fulfilling the requirements under section 2A.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

