<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H40CA9164EA4245B59C772A8E0B042D62" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 46 IH: Rural Broadband Window of Opportunity Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 46</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250103">January 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001301">Mr. Bergman</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Federal Communications Commission to prioritize the timely processing of certain long-form applications in the Rural Digital Opportunity Fund Phase II auction.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H3EE57EB480FE49A488BC9ED914744B21" style="OLC"><section id="HD7AA59A44EA348D2926256BD27ADA9D2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Rural Broadband Window of Opportunity Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H3F0B29A5EDCE40A2AF4A23BA4D1C05EB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purpose of this Act is to level the playing field for service providers participating in the Rural Digital Opportunity Fund that are disadvantaged by short construction seasons.</text></section><section id="H8A79C79265C34F4D8C3F4DA7BFAE8FE0"><enum>3.</enum><header>Application Processing Prioritization</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">With respect to the long-form applicants of the Rural Digital Opportunity Fund Phase II auction provided for in the Report and Order in the matter of Rural Digital Opportunity Fund and Connect America Fund adopted by the Federal Communications Commission (in this section referred to as the <quote>Commission</quote>) on January 30, 2020 (FCC 20–5), the Commission shall prioritize the timely processing of long-form applications and any subsequent paperwork (in this section referred to as the <quote>applications</quote>) submitted by the long-form applicants as follows: The Commission shall prioritize the timely processing of applications which are proposing to provide service in geographic areas which the Commission determines to have the shortest construction seasons (such as in areas characterized by long winters with heavy snowfall). </text></section></legis-body></bill> 

