<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H22DEB5F16B60474C895EF1CDE769F45D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 661 IH: Maximizing Israel-U.S. Research Advancement and Collaborative Leadership in Emerging Medical Technology Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 661</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250123">January 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001260">Mr. Buchanan</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001200">Mr. Soto</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001215">Mrs. Miller-Meeks</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Health and Human Services, in consultation with the Secretary of Commerce, the Council for Technology and Innovation of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services, and the Commissioner of Food and Drugs, to carry out a program to facilitate and coordinate efforts between the United States and Israel to expand and enhance collaboration on the development and delivery of health care products and services.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H2EC2C227042945DBB9668501230AC610" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HA3CFE4FE7BD64C07B571DBC937EBC53C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Maximizing Israel-U.S. Research Advancement and Collaborative Leadership in Emerging Medical Technology Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>MIRACLE Medical Technology Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H7598C394C43941D4888FE527CE20BF1C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Program for facilitation and coordination of United States-Israel efforts on the development and delivery of health care products and services</header> <subsection id="H700F91148486431FB9085D451E8F081A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to the availability of appropriations, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, in consultation with the Secretary of Commerce, the Council for Technology and Innovation of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services, and the Commissioner of Food and Drugs, shall carry out a program to facilitate and coordinate efforts between the United States and Israel to expand and enhance collaboration on—</text> 
<paragraph id="H63298AB8A09E41B9A72CCCE10F3EE109"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the development of health care products and services; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAC9EBB99304543D8914B552B6BE0366A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the delivery of such products and services to those in need.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE6F52F1B51EB438890DAE3054137485F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Program components</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The program under subsection (a) shall include facilitation and coordination of efforts including each of the following:</text> <paragraph id="HBA5ADCAEF7F74AABB1773939E9480E8E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Research and development</header> <subparagraph id="H9D102D31BE5840669C6C53373BE6BA8D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Joint research projects between United States and Israeli institutions and companies.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H87D17915676B4A3B98CFE5DE3CE4B16B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Promoting collaboration in areas such as medical device technology, pharmaceuticals (including biological products, genomics, and innovative digital health care solutions), and health care systems management, including a special focus on early-stage clinical trials.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEE1D0465756E4F6DBB33ABF7C6FC8924"><enum>(C)</enum><text>With respect to biological products, supporting—</text> 
<clause id="H8887BAFC647C4B7F828140D64C184ADE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>innovation;</text></clause> <clause id="H1962815CCEC1456FA9DCDE355AB571DD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>process optimization; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HD82BE0CB95884339B41794A5BF04983D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the development of advanced manufacturing techniques that can enhance productivity, reduce costs, and improve product quality.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEDDC8EE62DAF4EA4B3980D6A9128D32E"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Work toward developing a framework for sharing health data for research purposes with the Ministry of Health of Israel.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H45BEE2A311A14E48A8F896E66567ED21"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Innovation and start-up ecosystem</header> 
<subparagraph id="H222B4A914FDE4E7BA235808E1B07DA68"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Fostering collaboration between United States and Israeli start-up and other companies in the health care sector.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H82176FF2A7C54337B0A6A1E223F48CDC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Facilitating innovative technology acceptance by the marketplace.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H16D6150FCC1C4344A4795EC5B38EAE13"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Facilitating mechanisms for technology transfer and joint venture opportunities.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H57AA24CD3F144FF99EC4E4FF9FA4F98F"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Supporting innovation hubs to accelerate the development and commercialization of United States health care technologies in the Israeli market, including by encouraging cybersecurity standards for sharing data, promoting patient privacy, and encouraging research.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H591E7EB5345A495EAAA2BB1DA41DB96E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Regulatory harmonization and intellectual property protection</header><text>Establishing joint efforts—</text> <subparagraph id="HF8402BE269F244E6B43CF73DF934D1DE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to ensure intellectual property protection;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0BFA12AEF4474E47B92EAB51F6EF65CE"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to increase regulatory harmonization, including with respect to regulatory data protection for biological products;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC4480D398FB34F8B977AA42F94AF4F1B"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to formulate plans for a commercialization framework for medical device technologies;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H00FF68F388D243348D38955004477DAB"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to encourage a potential mutual recognition agreement for pharmaceutical good manufacturing Practices between the Food and Drug Administration and Israeli regulators;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAE2D86CB240645418B9078F8B052271C"><enum>(E)</enum><text>to strengthen and reaffirm the confidentiality commitment with the Food and Drug Administration and the Pharmaceutical Division, the Medical Devices Department, and the National Food Services and Nutrition Division of the Ministry of Health of Israel;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD6AB5354E32B4F3BB47D7F2B4AF25A0D"><enum>(F)</enum><text>to encourage Israel’s participation in regulatory harmonization and cooperation organizations; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA159C54F0C844434993B45E62D9C413E"><enum>(G)</enum><text>to expand international collaboration under Project Orbis for concurrent submission and review of oncology products.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4BCB691EDFC14ECF91628FC6CCF770B0"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Health care system strengthening</header><text>Facilitating the sharing of best practices, knowledge, and skills in areas such as clinical care and health care management.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H65D594DBE1E64189BCDA6BA9B5860FDB"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Telemedicine and digital health cooperation</header><text>Establishing initiatives—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H40F2DFEE017948E98D7E4FE57B82ECB3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to enhance telemedicine infrastructure;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H92CB976F49A04E5FB56B2A13051F3DAF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to promote interoperability between United States and Israeli health care systems; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE0EC6A3171A346D889EDE0A34F3F1FF1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to facilitate collaboration on digital health technologies, data analytics, and cybersecurity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H006141DFB263406EAC8E136240AF6745"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Disease prevention initiatives</header><text>Collaborating in disease prevention, including joint efforts to combat infectious diseases, develop vaccines, and share epidemiological data.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF25110039D0642CF9B93474CB8F8ED4B"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Biological product manufacturing</header> 
<subparagraph id="H63B55905C69A4914BCF0B4B2B102FDC4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Promoting biological product manufacturing.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8356FA2D78A64BD88956BEAF5429CD38"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Establishing joint manufacturing facilities for biological products in facilities in the United States that leverage the strengths and expertise of both countries.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H90F5D0A494A64037B34D4F45D4823FA3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Pursuing accelerated development of life-saving treatments and new sources of nutrition that are both healthier and more available at an affordable cost.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3F9007385D35453E94463699D4C00F7E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Workforce training and skill development, including promoting exchange programs and training initiatives to develop a skilled workforce in biological product manufacturing.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB6699D711D4B44859DAFF67ABECBB79B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Supply chain resilience through strategic collaboration to identify and develop contingency plans to mitigate biological product supply disruptions.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H029C26FA182C43BB8A2EBAB366DF2C7C"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Facilitating public-private partnerships to support the development and scale-up of biological product manufacturing capabilities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H853E1A15C8A647CBB140C1559FB46544"><enum>(c)</enum><header>United States-Israel Health Care Collaboration Center</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the program under subsection (a), the Secretary of Health and Human Services may establish a joint United States-Israel Health Care Collaboration Center in the United States leveraging the experience, knowledge, and expertise of institutions of higher education, national laboratories, entities in the private sector, and others in the development and delivery of health care products and services.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H01131E0F3E0F4402A7729FB2F3B5B392"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Commencement of implementation</header><text>Not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall commence implementation of the program under this section.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8BB8765D768740B89F55A1546B3DE995"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>To carry out this Act, there is authorized to be appropriated $8,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

