<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-NEW25534-663-K7-LVW"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 215 IS: Expressing support for the designation of the week of May 12, 2025, through May 16, 2025, as “Veterans Affairs Research Week” to celebrate the research, innovation, and significant contributions of the Department of Veterans Affairs to improving the lives of countless veterans, people in the United States, and individuals around the world.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 215</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250512">May 12, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S229">Mrs. Murray</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSVA00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of the week of May 12, 2025, through May 16, 2025, as <quote>Veterans Affairs Research Week</quote> to celebrate the research, innovation, and significant contributions of the Department of Veterans Affairs to improving the lives of countless veterans, people in the United States, and individuals around the world.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, in 1925, the Veterans’ Bureau, the predecessor to the Department of Veterans Affairs (referred to in this preamble as the <quote>VA</quote>), established the Medical Research Section, marking 2025 as the 100-year anniversary of VA research;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Dr. Philip B. Matz served as the first Research Chief of the Veterans' Bureau, advocating for hospital-based research directly related to improving the clinical conditions of veterans;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 1925, a system of diagnostic clinics with links to outside consultants was established by the Veterans’ Bureau, evidencing the long connection that VA research has had to industry and innovation;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas VA-affiliated nonprofit research and education corporations play a critical role in facilitating collaborations between VA research and industry, enabling VA investigators to participate in public-private partnerships to amplify their groundbreaking research efforts;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 1933, the Tumor Research Laboratory at the Hines Veteran Affairs Medical Center in Chicago, Illinois, became the first research laboratory to receive designated funds from the VA Central Office, leading to Dr. Robert Schrek identifying the connection between sun exposure and skin cancer;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas VA research has led to medical breakthroughs and lifesaving procedures used by veterans and non-veterans across the United States and around the world, including the development of the concept of computed tomography scanning, the first effective treatments for tuberculosis, development of an implantable cardiac pacemaker, the first large clinical trials of hearing aids, the first successful transplantation of a liver, and many others;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas research on Gila monster metabolism at the Bronx VA Medical Center created breakthroughs leading to the development of GLP–1 agonist medications, which is broadly considered 1 of the most consequential health advances of the 21st century;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas VA research in the field of mental health and the 10 Mental Illness Research, Education and Clinical Centers of the VA have revolutionized the treatment of several mental, behavioral, and neuropsychological conditions, including leading research in fields like post-traumatic stress, substance use, major depressive disorder, serious mental illness, and many others;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas VA research facilities across the United States employ thousands of top-tier researchers and innovators who, as of 2024, conduct over 7,000 active research projects in numerous disciplines;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas VA Puget Sound and their nonprofit affiliate, the Seattle Institute for Biomedical and Clinical Research, has been a nationally renowned research facility for over 75 years, housing over 750 continuing research projects in 2024 in numerous disciplines;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Nobel Prize in Physiology or Medicine has been awarded to VA researchers, including Dr. Andrew Schally, Dr. Rosalyn Yalow, and Dr. Ferid Murad, for their vital contributions to scientific knowledge;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2025, during the 100-year anniversary of VA Research, the VA Office of Research and Development is recognizing researchers for their scholarly excellence and commitment to improving the lives of Veterans, including—</text><paragraph id="id68dbd99c4b794af4820067409a63bd59"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Dr. Jean Beckham, VA Durham Health Care System;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaef74205c3214959974a8e9bbf089c63"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Dr. Robert Clark, South Texas Veterans Health Care System in San Antonio, TX;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9d96df1d98124da1bc989996f2960a1c"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Dr. Daniel Hall, VA Pittsburgh Health Care System;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3ca7120a18b64f98aad9209e2ce4dd4d"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Dr. Robert Kirsch, Louis Stokes Cleveland VA Medical Center;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4f42dfa1d5ef4af89a26c05d4ef680e3"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Dr. Vincent Marconi, Joseph Maxwell Cleland Atlanta VA Medical Center; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id232c0a80d7b14cfc9aa9c7813d0af458"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Dr. Arlan Richardson, Oklahoma City VA Health Care System; and</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas May 12, 2025, through May 16, 2025, is the appropriate week to celebrate 100 years of VA research through <quote>Veteran Affairs Research Week</quote>: Now, therefore be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="idb0a58d29ddf54af9a23d6885aa3313a0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>honors and celebrates the 100-year anniversary of Department of Veterans Affairs (referred to in this resolution as the <quote>VA</quote>) research, representing a century of lifesaving and cutting-edge research conducted by the VA which improves the lives of veterans, people in the United States, and individuals around the world;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida7cddfe82c5c43bdb0e65a93795660a4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>applauds the spirit of inquiry and commitment to scientific excellence of VA researchers and their affiliates, who ensure that veterans receive the most up-to-date, effective care and maintain the leadership and competitiveness of the United States in scientific research and healthcare;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb28813ad9b19458ba6af02312246d053"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recognizes the critical importance of supporting VA research through robust funding, public support, and Federal cooperation;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1e9544f7f91446eaa98d15eedb59f016"><enum>(4)</enum><text>acknowledges that VA research facilities and their affiliates contribute significantly to the economies of their local communities; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1f0fda0a7d5b40b7bcd9980403c037df"><enum>(5)</enum><text>supports the designation of the week of May 12, 2025, through May 16, 2025, as <quote>Veteran Affairs Research Week</quote>.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

