<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-REI25169-G9J-81-YDF"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 335 IS: Calling on Federal and State courts to provide full transparency to the people of the United States by unsealing materials concerning Mr. Jeffrey Epstein.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 335</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250724">July 24, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S419">Mr. Mullin</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Calling on Federal and State courts to provide full transparency to the people of the United States by unsealing materials concerning Mr. Jeffrey Epstein.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas Mr. Jeffrey Epstein pled guilty to charges of soliciting a child for prostitution and soliciting a prostitute in Florida in 2008;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2008, following a lengthy Federal investigation, Mr. Epstein secured a Federal non-prosecution agreement from the Office of the United States Attorney for the Southern District of Florida;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Mr. Epstein was arrested on July 6, 2019, by Federal authorities, accused of sexually exploiting and abusing dozens of underage girls as young as 14 by enticing them to engage in sex acts with him in exchange for money, and charged with sex trafficking of minors and conspiracy to engage in sex trafficking of minors;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Chief Medical Examiner of New York City ruled that the death of Mr. Epstein on August 10, 2019, while in Federal custody at the Metropolitan Correctional Center in New York City, was a suicide;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on June 28, 2022, Ms. Ghislaine Maxwell was sentenced to 20 years in prison for conspiring with Mr. Epstein to sexually abuse minors;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the circumstances surrounding the life of Mr. Epstein and the death of Mr. Epstein while in Federal custody have sparked a firestorm of public interest in the case relating to Mr. Epstein;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, as the Department of Justice has noted, <quote>[m]uch of the material [relating to Mr. Epstein] is subject to court-ordered sealing</quote>; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the public interest in the materials relating to Mr. Epstein that are sealed by a court order greatly outweighs any privacy interests, including those of the deceased Mr. Epstein and his associate, Ms. Maxwell: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—-</text><paragraph id="iddbad102a6d6a4df58ebb66fb9d36e6e2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>calls upon applicable Federal and State courts to immediately unseal all materials, including grand jury materials, sealed as part of any criminal investigation, proceeding, or prosecution of Mr. Jeffrey Epstein or Ms. Ghislaine Maxwell, subject only to continuing redactions to protect victims and preserve ongoing prosecutions; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5035531c244742cca543a7b2dd22e5e8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>supports full transparency and public access to these materials.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

