<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H864A40A1A53F4DCBA59CC9C4168EB892" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2256 IH: National Rosie the Riveter Day Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2256</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250321">March 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001225">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 36, United States Code, to designate <quote>National Rosie the Riveter Day</quote> and request the President to issue an annual proclamation.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HDCA691DC355F45ABAE2F2D9EE5E31A5A" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H0331FEA520C245ADA2BBFD361F6B0868" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>National Rosie the Riveter Day Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H6CBEE6E03C274EFEB43105E21C6FAF13"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HB06C16D74B514147A0D5BAFCE39E5F04"><enum>(1)</enum><text>National Rosie the Riveter Day is a collective national effort to raise awareness of the more than 6,000,000 American women who joined the workforce during World War II.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA6F20153A0F048DCB07E621EA0E89044"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The people of the United States have chosen to honor women workers who contributed to the home front during World War II, including through the award of a Congressional Gold Medal.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC041E420AD75442EAE2AAC7C3F99EA94"><enum>(3)</enum><text>These women left their homes to work or volunteer full-time in factories, farms, shipyards, airplane factories, banks, and other institutions in support of the war effort.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H45FCB0C003A94CDA98C21F84B9DA30CC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>These women worked with the United Service Organizations and the American Red Cross, drove trucks, riveted airplane parts, collected critical materials, rolled bandages, and served on rationing boards.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4F8EBC60DE6A45908CEF6B2F24DD02DE"><enum>(5)</enum><text>These women in the workforce persevered often in the face of harassment, discrimination, and prejudice to support their country and families in a time of great need.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE8ECB94C8EF14A6AA4C6BD3E421A7EE0"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Women of color overcame long-held policies of discrimination and racial segregation to make significant contributions to the war effort and workforce.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H21355912E3364D369B821E2D19CA3163"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Our <quote>Rosie the Riveters,</quote> the American women who worked and sacrificed during World War II, are a testament to women’s empowerment and invaluable contribution to the war effort, inspiring future generations of women and girls.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF34BD5B0D0904592B323A94FC96D5A9A"><enum>(8)</enum><text>It is fitting and proper to recognize and preserve the history and legacy of working women, including volunteer women, during World War II to promote cooperation and fellowship among such women and their descendants.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6CB2DBFB9162433AA2B6CBAC924FA99F"><enum>(9)</enum><text>These women and their descendants wish to further the advancement of patriotic ideas, excellence in the workplace, and loyalty to the United States of America.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H793497710B4648749B7E0725CE8C3FD0"><enum>(10)</enum><text>March 21, during Women’s History Month, would be an appropriate date to designate as <quote>National Rosie the Riveter Day</quote>.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H4AD4AF51EA64429EB6E7A484ED635421"><enum>3.</enum><header>Designation of National Rosie the Riveter Day</header> 
<subsection id="H8512614E679D4059A1B1D8847441B37D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/36/1">Chapter 1</external-xref> of title 36, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> <quoted-block id="H659234D345FB4E3990B0979C45163AD7" style="OLC"> <section id="H4EEEDC8434A44468832A8FED3A97849D"><enum>149.</enum><header>National Rosie the Riveter Day</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The President is requested to issue each year a proclamation—</text> 
<paragraph id="H77B1BCA3751740F6980199DFAF8698E5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>calling on the people of the United States to observe National Rosie the Riveter Day with appropriate ceremonies and activities; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7695ADC321734B818D96594858C3F002"><enum>(2)</enum><text>urging civil and educational authorities of States, territorial, tribal, and local governments to observe National Rosie the Riveter Day through appropriate programs and activities.</text></paragraph></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H142736EE9426403B8A602A8F5087E537"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>The table of sections for such chapter is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text> <quoted-block id="H4CE5C40184124A59B6D08476DADF5711" style="OLC"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">149. National Rosie the Riveter Day.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

