<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H11A58F4BC7E7452B8C02F10B057A804E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1499 IH: To amend the Grand Ronde Reservation Act to address the hunting, fishing, trapping, and animal gathering rights of the Confederated Tribes of the Grand Ronde Community, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1499</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250221">February 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001226">Ms. Salinas</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="B001326">Ms. Bynum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001094">Ms. Hoyle of Oregon</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Grand Ronde Reservation Act to address the hunting, fishing, trapping, and animal gathering rights of the Confederated Tribes of the Grand Ronde Community, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6EA0E3134FDA4A229F6697F44FE837CA" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="HB6BE34CEBAE744A09DE47DD9A69E2CEC"><enum>1.</enum><header>Grand Ronde Reservation Act amendment</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2 of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/100/425">Public Law 100–425</external-xref> (commonly known as the <quote>Grand Ronde Reservation Act</quote>) (102 Stat. 1595) is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2276369057C74438A959757E40B950A4"> <section id="HECDE4071BABE4353B8482102EABD5AEF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Hunting, fishing, trapping, and animal gathering</header> <subsection id="H346B64BBC3044272970AFDECA7B7EEC0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H3F41AFED8EBC47E89A7C010EA3236EE3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Consent decree</header><text>The term <term>Consent Decree</term> means the final judgment and decree of the United States District Court for the District of Oregon, in the action entitled <quote>Confederated Tribes of the Grand Ronde Community of Oregon against the State of Oregon</quote>, entered on January 12, 1987. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H61AFC65AC45F4F1282CF10AED3C46731"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Grand Ronde Hunting and Fishing Agreement</header><text>The term <term>Grand Ronde Hunting and Fishing Agreement</term> means the agreement entitled <quote>Agreement Among the State of Oregon, the United States of America and the Confederated Tribes of the Grand Ronde Community of Oregon to Permanently Define Tribal Hunting, Fishing, Trapping, and Animal Gathering Rights of the Tribe and its Members</quote> and entered into by the United States on December 2, 1986.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H52E451E0E0924C74A69B8763DA21011A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Indian Tribe</header><text>The term <term>Indian Tribe</term> has the meaning given the term in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H9D4CF6F30CF540199188BC87D89A29DC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Hunting, fishing, trapping, and animal gathering agreements</header> <paragraph id="HBFB25E4FD98543498C6A56C7A32178DB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Grand Ronde Hunting and Fishing Agreement shall remain in effect until and unless replaced, amended, or otherwise modified by 1 or more successor government-to-government agreements between the Confederated Tribes of the Grand Ronde Community and the State of Oregon relating to the hunting, fishing, trapping, and animal gathering rights of the Confederated Tribes of the Grand Ronde Community.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H34A3F8858265445695ADA0C33B8423B8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Amendments</header><text>The Grand Ronde Hunting and Fishing Agreement or any successor agreement entered into under paragraph (1) may be amended from time to time by mutual consent of the Confederated Tribes of the Grand Ronde Community and the State of Oregon.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H243B383852F04F98BE5B23C7AD284DA5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Contents of new agreement or future amendments</header><text>No successor agreement or amended agreement entered into under paragraph (1) shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H1D816CB7067E406E9B48539FCE02BCBE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>purport to affirm, recognize, establish, expand, adjudicate, waive, limit, abrogate or otherwise affect the ancestral, aboriginal, treaty, statutory, equitable, or other applicable rights of the Confederated Tribes of the Grand Ronde Community or any other Indian Tribe;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4B96FA4ABB7145E6820F6F2C38239812"><enum>(B)</enum><text>limit the State of Oregon from entering into separate agreements with other Indian Tribes that address the authority to take species within the geographic scope of the agreement; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H16465B75B9814AE4AF2D721B51E1F4BD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>be used in a civil or criminal action in a court of competent jurisdiction to enlarge, confirm, adjudicate, affect, or modify any treaty or other right of an Indian Tribe.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE40F6243B4F940CCBB34E90AD9B32FFD"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Source of Authority</header><text>All hunting, fishing, trapping, and animal gathering rights of the Confederated Tribes of the Grand Ronde Community in any successor agreement or amended agreement entered into under paragraph (1) after the date of enactment of this paragraph shall derive solely from the authority of the State of Oregon.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF2AA1750670240F3ABE7DFB5D1EC6254"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Judicial review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In any action brought in the United States District Court for the District of Oregon to rescind, overturn, modify, or provide relief under Federal law from the Consent Decree, the United States District Court for the District of Oregon shall review the application of the parties on the merits without regard to the defense of res judicata or collateral estoppel. </text></subsection> <subsection id="HDA05F079BFE443D7AF0CFE9D04F7C932"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effect</header><text>Nothing in this section, or in any successor agreement or amended agreement entered into under paragraph (1), shall have the force or effect of determining, defining, affirming, recognizing, abrogating, limiting, or affecting the rights or claims of any Indian Tribe, including any treaty and other sovereign rights.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

