<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H50B1E753BC724E50BA105398220FD5E4" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3734 IH: Stop Millionaires Using Service for Kickbacks Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3734</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250604">June 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000579">Mr. Ryan</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="N000191">Mr. Neguse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000530">Mr. Deluzio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001221">Ms. Scholten</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001119">Ms. Craig</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001223">Mrs. Sykes</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 18, United States Code, to provide that officers and employees of the executive branch are required to recuse themselves in matters affecting the financial interests of their previous employers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB175A91487D54CE6A95C0BF834F4C8D7" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H99EA1795B3924D869ECC2221E3AB3F17" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop Millionaires Using Service for Kickbacks Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Stop MUSK Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HFD19ED1044314076ADCAADFF5CBB74AB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Recusal of executive branch officers and employees in matters affecting financial interests of previous employers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 208(a) of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HA7DD047952964A8880F01988D0D0FB29"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>an officer or employee of the executive branch of the United States Government, or of any independent agency of the United States, a Federal Reserve bank director, officer, or employee, or an officer or employee of the District of Columbia, including a special Government employee</quote> and inserting <quote>an officer or employee in any position listed under the Executive Schedule (sections 5312 through 5316 of title 5), a special Government employee, or an officer or employee of the Executive Office of the President</quote>; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H00E25E91F19344D698D189E3F276BCC0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after <quote>organization in which he is serving as officer, director, trustee, general partner or employee,</quote> the following: <quote>organization for which he, during the 4-year period preceding such participation, served as an officer, director, trustee, general partner, agent, attorney, consultant, contractor, employee, or direct competitor, organization (other than a political organization described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/527">section 527(e)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986) in which he is an active participant,</quote>.</text></paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

