<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF6F03196EB354E05A773E9D1746BA536" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5308 IH: Service Starts At Home Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5308</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250911">September 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001136">Mr. Conaway</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Education to carry out grant programs to encourage student participation in local government and volunteer service, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD1843D7F9518432FBE4FFD4BE8AD8E38" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="HB0360373C75D4FF991E667B15C92542B"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Service Starts At Home Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="HCCA2814E15244B9592B7E3C5F1B1B325"><enum>2.</enum><header>Grants to support internships in local government</header> <subsection id="H2B48568CAF024B75B078C687BD01358C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall carry out a program under which the Secretary makes grants, on a competitive basis, to eligible entities to support paid internships within units of local government for secondary school students and students who are qualified undergraduates at institutions of higher education in the State in which the entity is located.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HB0F9B4171A874883AA0587F0B0ED6AA6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be considered for a grant under subsection (a), an eligible entity shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HC87CB5EBA3A942BBA6D8ABC63F624597"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Local government internship program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each eligible entity that receives a grant under subsection (a) shall use such grant to carry out a program under which the entity—</text>
<paragraph id="H331F37BFAB6A462F90FC77F8F7345EE3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identifies appropriate paid internship opportunities within units of local government for secondary school students and students who are undergraduates at institutions of higher education in the State in which the entity is located;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H457926B195D14340B69B1C8993E9F21F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>establishes a process for the selection of students to fill such internships;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD0704B687A8A47F5A2082C31444D6E5F"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">determines hourly rates of pay and other terms and conditions applicable to such internships; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2C792C83BA934BBAB099CC55CBF2D64A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>pays the costs incurred in providing such internships.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H1CBE44EF6CD74423993ED891965F3084"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Accommodations and educational standards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the internship program under subsection (c), an eligible entity shall—</text> <paragraph id="H542AB24DC77E4D61A1AB58C77A04E481"><enum>(1)</enum><text>work with institutions of higher education to ensure that the work performed by interns has educational value and meets applicable educational standards; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD02E19ADAC6A4420896A230581906576"><enum>(2)</enum><text>seek to provide reasonable employment-related accommodations to interns who have childcare needs, transportation difficulties, or other such challenges, which may include accommodations such as flexible work schedules for interns and allowing interns to telework to the extent determined practicable by the eligibility entity concerned.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H51ADF623C1C04996A1B925EC47695CEA"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $50,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="HE5855AD311854BEBB8EB9116F496BD38"><enum>3.</enum><header>Scholarship for volunteer service programs</header>
<subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8166E6974D2944D4891FDA2A37108C63"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Funding</header>
<paragraph id="H4EFB653C321447AA995529EC1B4320DE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>State programs</header>
<subparagraph id="H8654938A58874EC0BB6AD4EE5EFF748B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall carry out a program under which the Secretary makes allocations to States, in accordance with subparagraph (B), to carry out the scholarship program under subsection (b).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0B85698FA6254360AD9D9F92A49B2230"> <enum>(B)</enum> <header>Allocations to States</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">From the amount appropriated to carry out this section for each fiscal year and not reserved under paragraph (2), each State that has an application approved by the Secretary under subparagraph (C) shall be allocated an amount in proportion to number of students enrolled in the public elementary schools and secondary schools in the State for the previous school year relative to the total number of students enrolled in the public elementary schools and secondary schools for such school year in every State that has an application approved by the Secretary under such subparagraph.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
<subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBFF331359B0B4BBAA3BAA209079BE9A0"><enum>(C)</enum><header>State application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible to receive an allocation under subparagraph (B), a State shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7381AFA929F54F3B8A533AE12656DD86"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federal program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">From the amount appropriated to carry out this section for each fiscal, the Secretary may reserve not more than 20 percent to carry out the Federal supplemental scholarship program under subsection (c).</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H80EC0DD0A5964538B6B8251B6FA2B6D2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>State administered scholarship program</header>
<paragraph id="H97A448C98C0F4355B566706D3C946029"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each State that receives an allocation under subsection (a)(2) shall use such allocation to carry out a program under which the State awards scholarships, on a competitive basis, to eligible students who demonstrate a commitment to volunteer service work.</text></paragraph> <paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H01DCB8F0F1064937AB0BD3874A8F90F6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application</header><text>A student who seeks a scholarship under this subsection shall submit an application to the State at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the State may require.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H865FBD2EAE374EA7BD2DD0EB162FF0A8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Student eligibility</header><text>To be eligible to receive a scholarship under this subsection a student shall meet the following criteria:</text> <subparagraph id="H0B8F5D0428F84FFB8F8929B0F70ADA84"><enum>(A)</enum><header>First-time applicant</header><text>In the case of a first-time applicant for a scholarship under this subsection, the student shall—</text>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA5AAEC85A0B94A249F97B4CD0E6C2136"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be enrolled—</text> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC981506211E145AD8E48DE436A5FD303"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in a secondary school and be in the final year of a program of study leading to a regular high school diploma; or</text></subclause>
<subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDE6E7A105FE34BC2AEA33EE43F32FD4F"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in an institution of higher education; and</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H6ECCFDAE04A94F818AE7F9E165C73259"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have completed at least 100 hours of volunteer service work in the preceding school year (or another one-year period determined by the Secretary).</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H5753B1D00A5746549EED0E8E94CF6699"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Renewal applicant</header><text>In the case of a student who received a scholarship under this subsection for an academic year and is seeking a scholarship for a subsequent academic year, the student shall—</text> <clause id="H44D12E31AF6F4E038F201BDF533213FD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>be enrolled in an institution of higher education;</text></clause>
<clause id="HCD9C2846673D4C6D9B826E2AD962EAF5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>be in good academic standing (as determined by the institution); and</text></clause> <clause id="H6DBFC3DA85814946ACBAC182159D9DA6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have completed at least 100 hours of volunteer service work in the preceding school year (or another one-year period determined by the Secretary).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" id="H2B09A44A6F424433BFD2E75AFE0E7A6E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Renewal process</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to the availability of funds for such purpose, a State that receives an allocation under subsection (a) shall—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H149D5E4B7DED4B7E9DE3C07CC6DF46D5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>award a scholarship to each renewal applicant who meets the requirements described in paragraph (3)(B); and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HC145B76554A5456AA3AE76B268FE59A6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>establish a streamlined process under which renewal applicants can apply for such scholarships with minimal documentation required.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H621D906D561B4AD8823F65097FF4C694"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding scholarships under this subsection, a State shall—</text>
<subparagraph id="H06F7F1D006CE4823AE46B28076C7A385"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in accordance with paragraph (4), first award scholarships to renewal applicants described in paragraph (3)(B); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H057DB0A3201B4F44B3E9F5F0C27080B9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>from any funds remaining after awarding such scholarships, award scholarships to first-time applicants described in paragraph (3)(A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H86890539661D47EFA846C5966150DB85"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>A scholarship received by a student under this subsection may be used by such student only to pay the student’s costs of attendance at an institution of higher education.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H65C88698291E46638E357279E78F0DF5"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Duration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each scholarship under this subsection shall be awarded for a period of one academic year. A student may receive a scholarship under this subsection for a total period of not more than 4 academic years.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HEA90A57B32F944C5A29DCFF0B5E02C93"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Amount</header><text>The amount of each scholarship under this subsection shall be—</text> <subparagraph id="H73EB6E1515A8450F8C1009EB385366DA"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$1,000, for a student who completed at least 100 hours, but less than 138 hours, of volunteer service work in the preceding school year (or another one-year period determined by the Secretary);</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H76B0BFA19A8C4947BEE83E010751D47D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>$1,500, for a student who completed at least 138 hours, but less than 175 hours, of volunteer service work in the preceding school year (or another one-year period determined by the Secretary);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H07B31E1D09CF43AC869913B632F208D9"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$2,000, for a student who completed at least 175 hours, but less than 213 hours, of volunteer service work in such period;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC1A1C171696B4768A317E89771F81AC2"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$2,500, for a student who completed at least 213 hours, but less than 250 hours, of volunteer service work in such period; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H54063B48776841FDB57948A65345B417"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$3,000, for a student who completed at least 250 hours of volunteer service work in such period.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" id="HC5FD74904E6F4246AFAD0EC4AED28112"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Federal supplemental scholarship program</header>
<paragraph commented="no" id="HF93E7B9FE51F443DB6F6199A02B9EBC9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>From amounts reserved under subsection (a)(2), the Secretary may carry out a program under which the Secretary awards supplementary funds, on a competitive basis, directly to eligible students for volunteer service work.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE71B340D06CE4D7391CAF774EAE4A746"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Amount</header><text>The amount of supplementary funds awarded to each student under paragraph (1) shall be determined by the Secretary.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H57C3BC0BA26A4AB2937CFAD11690C666"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Priority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In awarding scholarships under this subsection, the Secretary shall prioritize the award of funds to students who have not received a scholarship under subsection (b).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBF323E69EBB14B37808820CECE34D42E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $100,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030.</text></subsection></section>
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7BE77BC3B5304BB68D9FEA48A5C16EDC"><enum>4.</enum><header>Recognition of achievement in community service</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary shall carry out a program to recognize elementary schools, secondary schools, local educational agencies, and institutions of higher education based on their overall volunteer achievement and contributions to community service.</text></section> <section id="HC5991FCA6914489D8B082BA6ED8463DF"><enum>5.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
<paragraph id="H8230EB2983F7493C9BAD50766BB59807"><enum>(1)</enum><header>ESEA definitions</header><text>The terms <term>elementary school</term>, <term>local educational agency</term>, <term>regular high school diploma</term>, <term>secondary school</term>, <term>Secretary</term>, and <term>State</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAE8474A133EF44A498F86ABA75B433E1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Cost of attendance</header><text>The term <term>cost of attendance</term> has the meaning given that term in section 472 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087ll">20 U.S.C. 1087ll</external-xref>).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H34537D358B9340AD8E21364B701C8ECD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means a State or a unit of local government.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE118055C484847E1B37D18C6653BF3D3"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given that term in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC6D3F80D403340D89A1ACC1EBD95C734"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Unit of local government</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>unit of local government</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H7BD72E8E0FEB42C283C26CD55E36FE77"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a county, municipality, town, township, village, parish, borough, or other unit of general government below the State level; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H099D077D5CA844FFB3852CF12AA9C0DB"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a governing body of an Indian Tribe or Tribal organization.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H95922207135848019F865497A60C854E"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Volunteer service work</header><text>The term <term>volunteer service work</term>—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9A604A1B876743D2B8B842323E2E2CCE"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means unpaid acts of volunteer service conducted for or on behalf of a government or other nonprofit organization, which may include a community-based organization, faith-based organization, school, national service program, civic or fraternal service organization, local government agency, or other such organization; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFEE5363897BB4824AE263E37913EE1E5"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not include acts of proselytizing, conducting worship services, religious instruction, political lobbying, court ordered service, or service conducted primarily for the benefit of the family of a student eligible for a scholarship under section 3.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

