<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MIR25762-TVD-CV-5YP"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2349 IS: Incorporating National Support for Unprecedented Risks and Emergencies Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2349</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250717">July 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Secretary of the Treasury to establish a catastrophic property loss reinsurance program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HEEB8B3DF88584F54BC97B4CA1DFCD388"><section section-type="section-one" id="H8B94D2FC810C4C1E88FB4FED826B6148"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Incorporating National Support for Unprecedented Risks and Emergencies Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>INSURE Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H8029C155205246F4BDE3A341B8717349"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H967FD6B1D9664A82B9AEE425550D4C6E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>All-perils property insurance policy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>all-perils property insurance policy</term> means a property insurance policy approved by a State which includes coverage for catastrophe perils as those perils are added to the Program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2AC7D62D93FF429ABA1F9929B1978683"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Catastrophe peril</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>catastrophe peril</term> means the damage caused by—</text><subparagraph id="H67CFF4798C244F9EBAFF8EA1B3F13181"><enum>(A)</enum><text>wind, hurricane, wildfire, severe convective storm, and flood as they are added to the Program under section 3(d);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA7CB5CE1B53D4FC1997B8ED50DE53E8F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>earthquake, conditioned on the report under section 4(2); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H62A6BB6627BE4B309F2E5BAF956A5726"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any other peril as determined by the Secretary and added to the Program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H7B7EFB6A08064B0BB525DEADCFBA6A7D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Engaged in the business of insurance</header><text>The term <term>engaged in the business of insurance</term> means a person or entity that is subject to oversight by a State insurance department.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf0db9acd33c644fd9ad62ae33c6082ff"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Fund</header><text>The term <term>Fund</term> means the Federal Catastrophe Reinsurance Fund established under section 3(i).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H72E5356839CD4546BF84D1A4E2503150"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Insurer</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>insurer</term>—</text><subparagraph id="HF8F7B0C904BF4E9A988C4992FAD57734"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means an admitted or non-admitted insurance company licensed or authorized to sell primary property insurance by State insurance regulators; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9B8272B31A36420EAA2CF6E5E9AD5959"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include a reinsurance company or a captive insurance company.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3C4A1AF675D34D7797DBF8313409121D"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Participating insurer</header><text>The term <term>participating insurer</term> means an insurer that is participating in the Program.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida60d3def568d47a088b6502e331575de"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Program</header><text>The term <term>Program</term> means the catastrophic property loss reinsurance program established under section 3(a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE83154DA6BB8496D8999D8D4077863C0"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Property insurance policy</header><text>The term <term>property insurance policy</term> means a contract of insurance, through a policy form approved by a State insurance department, that provides, among other coverages, coverage for physical damage to residential or commercial property.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE3ED57FABDC844D881FE44EAACE775E9"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Treasury.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2EF3758C22224B86B8C1631C979E6F0C"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Statistical plan</header><text>The term <term>statistical plan</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H6B0AE909FA504398A74D4BA119BEC07E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of the data elements to be reported; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC906DE3D1EB349F8AB5C7A71DDE95FAE" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the instructions and procedures for accurately reporting data. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB99751BCD76D43708BA1F22869314376"><enum>3.</enum><header>Catastrophic property loss reinsurance program</header><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6967C138DE0949B6A2BEDD75DABB457A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 4 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall establish a catastrophic property loss reinsurance program to provide reinsurance for qualifying primary insurance companies.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC49612BD17A7438FA461858616469CBA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>An insurer is qualified to participate in the Program if such insurer—</text><paragraph id="H5F421041113A4260AD0C38FD80377FC9"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">offers an all-perils property insurance policy, as perils are phased in under subsection (d), for—</text><subparagraph id="H11810400BE124A4583E4AE5B3EA65E09"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">residential property insurance policies; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H48FFAD5F6D434198B09E38C2EB934E4C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">commercial property insurance policies; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE8BDF9A43DA345889E921EB311CCE029"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">offers a loss prevention partnership with the policyholder to encourage investments and activities that reduce insured and economic losses from a catastrophe peril.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA8A47CD919684F398BC6F9EB4D7AB89D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>The Secretary may contract with reinsurance brokers and consultants to assist the Secretary in the design and management of the Program. </text></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H77E26F6DB4EF4AFDACB22EF9C0A72432"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Program phase-In timeline</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text><paragraph commented="no" id="H5B6FD8D3D21F4C2C9601CB15336D2E80"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not later than January 1 of the year beginning 4 years after the date of enactment of this Act, operate the Program for the perils of wind and hurricane;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HE99DE29E6E7244CFAE6CDC254E7EF573"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not later than January 1 of the year beginning 5 years after the date of enactment of this Act, operate the Program for the perils of severe convective storm and wildfire;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H812E2608B8F7467E9E6065DC041768BD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>not later than January 1 of the year beginning 6 years after the date of enactment of this Act, operate the Program for the peril of flood; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H1764935ABCCA4A99BA22E852916CD8D7"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than the earlier of January 1 of the year beginning 8 years after the date of enactment of this Act or the date on which the feasibility report described in section 4(2) is submitted, operate the Program for the peril of earthquake.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC483DB1A5F504C5396C5FACE10FD035D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Threshold for payment</header><paragraph id="HCC55A966E957473896C7405B63458399"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall, after consulting with the advisory committee established under subsection (h), establish a financial threshold at which a participating insurer may receive amounts from the fund established under subsection (i).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H5D3DA61941384199B458571D16CC0FD2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Threshold calculation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The threshold established under paragraph (1) shall be an amount that is not greater than 40 percent of the probable maximum loss of an individual participating insurer for each catastrophe peril included in the Program.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HA2EC2B61E5794E559B4EDEB1D8539F8C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In establishing the threshold described in paragraph (1), the Secretary shall consider—</text><subparagraph id="HE40450A9DF53458C9D6721EB8A8E2F66"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the amount of reinsurance necessary to meaningfully reduce the cost to the participating insurer to—</text><clause commented="no" id="HADF9AA4D31F44D2B9A1589F6807CB6D9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>provide coverage for catastrophe perils covered by the Program; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="HD5E5F2B7536949B0AB77F4E22F7D5251"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>encourage States to require participating insurers to offer an all-perils property insurance policy;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H0AB08D74945C491D91F7BD42595AA2A0"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the levels of primary insurer retention and private reinsurance market capacity necessary to—</text><clause id="H70991A63AC7044B785D03985C35AC3EC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>promote stable and competitive markets for catastrophe reinsurance; and </text></clause><clause id="HD86E8957B0074D59834C6278276F22FD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>incentivize the establishment by private parties of capital market alternatives to reinsurance, for example the creation of a market for catastrophe bonds; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H8AD00F91C5854B4F8817DD7424695D07"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the role of the Program in promoting investments by participating insurers that would be aimed at decreasing losses.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9890C5C3705C4AAA9AAED038A0A87642"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Premiums</header><paragraph id="HCDA6C84D6296494DB3BE7061FCB2FEB7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall require participating insurers to pay a premium to the Secretary each quarter.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAE76D20EBEE84C259B542380634A3C8E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Premium amount considerations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount of the premium required under paragraph (1) shall reflect only the following considerations:</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H786D0E9B4215423FAFEA927F2948614A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The expected average annual losses for the participating insurer under the specific terms of the reinsurance coverage, as calculated by the Secretary based on the exposure of the participating insurer. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7C100E5142334672BA1E93A0A278A3B5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The administrative costs to administer and manage the Program.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd9d2fa37486c4032b6eeda9ed33800d2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A trend factor to account for increases over time in the cost of average annual losses for participating insurers, as determined by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H71465A47033F4543A3EE5C2EC1EF143B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall consult with the advisory committee established under subsection (i) when establishing premium amounts and may contract for services to assist in the establishment of premium amounts.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1CD21B4D8A0B452AB3BE1652059D5232"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Minimum premium required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may not establish any premium that is less than 50 percent of the amount equal to the sum of the—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H9D6295C5D25E47358F8D2C8BE61CB505"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">expected average annual losses for the participating insurer, as calculated by the Secretary based on the exposure of the participating insurer; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H974397C8C0F844889FC09A8BCC552CDB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>administrative costs to administer and manage the Program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0338AD2F6D18479590872ABE7D153B04"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Premium adjustments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall adjust premiums each quarter for each participating insurer to reflect material changes in the exposure of the participating insurer. </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HFD2673F4C9BC4642A07351CFE6E064FC"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Premium increases</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Excluding any adjustment made under paragraph (5), the Secretary may increase premiums for a participating insurer not more than 7 percent annually.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H44534BFEC78940A681860EED9F560AF2"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Loss prevention partnerships</header><paragraph id="HB934D059A47944F896D765F992A24CD9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, in coordination with the advisory committee established under subsection (h), State insurance agencies, and State and Federal emergency management agencies, shall develop a list of activities that qualify as loss prevention partnerships for purposes of this section, which may include the following activities:</text><subparagraph id="H02963DB2B9B24546A28F6ECA09B0E9A5"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Participating insurers identifying loss prevention steps that make properties eligible for coverage or renewal.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA1882C3C78F84A55A705BAC747F21BFC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Participating insurers making coverage contingent upon the implementation of a loss prevention activity by a potential insured party.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFFD274F1C4E34D47A7327E1D7D542AAF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Activities excluded from loss prevention partnerships</header><text>The Secretary, State insurance agencies, and State and Federal emergency management agencies may not include the following activities as loss prevention partnerships for purposes of this section:</text><subparagraph id="H8894E0A2F5AB42839069F502746B304D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The provision of an insurance premium discount for an investment by an insured party or potential insured party in an activity designed to reduce the losses of the participating insurer, absent an investment by the participating insurer.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H41E86324FE3C4AFEA690C02235B5B073"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The provision of general information about loss prevention.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD5CF71D987354F169767B56BDC6CFB9D"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Advisory committee</header><paragraph id="HA4D45634B66D46F4B57F7D63D3A8F57B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish an advisory committee to advise the Secretary with respect to the Program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H46C1C58F2D524FD7A0C92211FFE04758"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>The committee established under paragraph (1) shall include the following members:</text><subparagraph id="H8FA1619AF68C44E7B9DBF94187AF79BA"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">5 members representing consumer organizations engaged in fair housing, insurance, environmental, climate, and technology advocacy.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H355C5F546D084954A77900CE336A58DE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>3 members selected from individual primary insurance companies selling property insurance policies, including one large national insurer, 1 medium sized regional insurer, and 1 small insurer. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H78E46B1DBF4046A3AE4B4410FFA9CA50"><enum>(C)</enum><text>1 global reinsurer active in United States property insurance markets.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H61F541E08A634FB386340EA6FD67FA21"><enum>(D)</enum><text>1 domestic-focused reinsurer active in United States property insurance markets.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEBF59D5EDE9F4DF2968283AD951E2A03"><enum>(E)</enum><text>2 insurance regulators from a State of the United States, a territory or possession of the United States, or the District of Colombia. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H900053ABAE9E4E7988BB26279E5A0F1D"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">2 State legislators who—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4c4ed51359d34ea0b67cc661b1d2b009"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">serve on State legislative committees with oversight over insurance matters; and </text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddbf597cbd40b4b22a8e9c819ace608e2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are not employed directly or indirectly by any person or organization engaged in the business of insurance.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9A03E0B6BB054A01B30AB4D0803ECB47"><enum>(G)</enum><text>2 members selected from independent insurance agents who serve traditionally underserved areas.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4037F316B0B34CB7A27F637EE650C06A"><enum>(H)</enum><text>1 representative from a mortgage lender.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0C58B478E31544639C5DCC5FCDCCE877"><enum>(I)</enum><text>1 representative from a bank.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H72AE9D75EAE045DCB71DDDB9C8AD18EA"><enum>(J)</enum><text>1 representative from each of the following agencies:</text><clause id="H06A20A9BE0D34902B5521799D3C6BE78"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The Department of Housing and Urban Development.</text></clause><clause id="H9B9953FC502E4843BFDA153223F802E3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The Department of Health and Human Services.</text></clause><clause id="HAA049176AB6E4ABE942B7628290F9B80"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The Federal Housing Finance Agency.</text></clause><clause id="H1AEB2D12249E47568021DEFE56CBA193"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The Department of Veterans Affairs.</text></clause><clause id="HAEA2B48179544D19A4B378362378A94C"><enum>(v)</enum><text>The Department of Agriculture.</text></clause><clause id="H056F8F63391D414387E7AF99CBB0F2FB"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>The Federal Emergency Management Agency.</text></clause><clause id="H05CBD24D15F44C8EBD71F1518A919F43"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>The Office of Management and Budget.</text></clause><clause id="H2A1A7FC03A694469853C2AA240F00984"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>The Environmental Protection Agency.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA58E73840D3146FF85722551767D3F7E"><enum>(K)</enum><text>1 representative from the Financial Stability Oversight Council. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H41A4F1CBEC51446D94044B989DA98F6D"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Federal Catastrophe Reinsurance Fund</header><paragraph commented="no" id="H56AE19A3EC6342D59D8258A40624E759"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall establish the Federal Catastrophe Reinsurance Fund to hold and invest premiums paid by participating insurers.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H0B450486A40B40EA8171DE5E16DFBA5F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Issuance of notes and bonds</header><subparagraph id="H1BFDC8BCD1864F5D9B3650D8F9C94760"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If amounts in the Fund are insufficient to pay obligations to participating insurers, the Secretary shall issue notes and bonds under this paragraph, the proceeds of which shall be used for payment obligations to participating insurers. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1FC683D8A2B04FFC82585CFB7D455DB8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Terms</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notes and bonds issued under this paragraph shall be—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcce787a3727e4cf3978ba9559cf4e8fe"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in such form and denominations, and shall be subject to such terms and conditions of issue, conversion, redemption, maturation, and payment as the Secretary may prescribe; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2cdac5b617c54e98af273eb9dead00c2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">fully and unconditionally guaranteed both as to interest and principal by the United States, and that guaranty shall be expressed on the face of each bond.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H20B33D3E1CF641AAAD193D74894DE4B6"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Interest</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notes and bonds issued under this paragraph shall bear interest at a rate not less than the current average yield on outstanding market obligations of the United States of comparable maturity during the month preceding the issuance of the obligation as determined by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC39A37F3AEB840A1B7713237B8DBF182"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Treatment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">All notes and bonds issued under this paragraph, and the interest on credits with respect to those obligations, shall not be subject to taxation by any State, county, municipality, or local taxing authority.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H058EFB0B07F049328D53CF7B0904D5D4"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Satisfaction</header><text>The Secretary shall utilize investment revenue from the Fund to satisfy any notes or bonds issued under this paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA44F2AEBBB254F5B9FD783D3A661F2C7"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Data collection</header><paragraph id="H7793F8C5BBD54993B0C1B35272BE7835"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text><subparagraph id="H745E0576E00C4518B2DC2B30085C4E82"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish a statistical plan for quarterly reporting by participating insurers of policy-level claim transaction data;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1F30B654E5224C3295A88EEC79B88E9D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>consult with the advisory committee established under subsection (h) and the National Association of Insurance Commissioners with respect to—</text><clause id="H622A7078177B4234BC46FEE180FDB6E5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the contents of the statistical plan; and</text></clause><clause id="H41D52BE20F33461A8D84B482E6C6B9DB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the method of data collection;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7142C3C9FD3C47809119179D36C9F173"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">collect quarterly reports from each participating insurer that include—</text><clause commented="no" id="H895E75A31ABF42F9950BC17A69FA72CD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a description of all exposures covered by the Program at the time of the submission of the report; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="HF0A8EAA33A214B63AF09B43594038ED0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a list of the type and amount of all claims made in the previous quarter;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAD32D1A22FBC476E8D35F4899F020EEC"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in a manner that does not risk public disclosure of personally identifiable information of policyholders, provide the quarterly reports received under subparagraph (C) to—</text><clause id="H863E5C12F2B946BF9DB50A67DBD0ACAE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Director of the Office of Financial Research to assess risk to—</text><subclause id="HBAC013BE74FF4A7AAC5FC2B36AE5CFA3"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the financial stability of the United States; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HADD370A42D6040F88A8F9343A060F202"><enum>(II)</enum><text>international financial systems arising from United States property insurance markets, including lack of available property insurance or inadequate coverage from property insurance;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H4C550B5F8B824EC78D8DFF00DBBEF9E1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Director of the Federal Insurance Office to assess the risks to the financial stability arising from under-insurance of property insurance policies covering catastrophe perils, including in traditionally underserved insurance markets;</text></clause><clause id="HF693055DA1DD491EB92142B64A0D646D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the head of the department of insurance in each State; and</text></clause><clause id="H06C43995B0D641A6B2779B37EE52B950"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>any other Federal, State, or local government entity that, as determined by the Secretary, is related to—</text><subclause id="H2147E7D564CE441E966A06073A61374A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>catastrophe loss prevention, mitigation, or recovery; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H2BF0A886008843418B33AB45E7B97E58"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the promotion of competitive property insurance markets; and</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF2138992B5B740E5A679F86B43050FFB"><enum>(E)</enum><text>make the data collected under this paragraph available online in a manner that does not risk public disclosure of personally identifiable information of policyholders.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H05193E039D8F4E49B3C1B02C7067EA6D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contracting with a statistical agent</header><subparagraph id="H16EBAAB8FC63437A8A4B1D4AA4A5625D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall contract with a statistical agent via a competitive bidding process to collect and review the data under this subsection for accuracy and completeness.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB42D52F13F3C4D99A062CB8A30A7A335"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Office of Financial Research as the statistical agent</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary is unable to identify a qualified statistical agent for collection of data under this subsection, the Director of the Office of Financial Research shall establish a data collection infrastructure for collection of such data.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H636157E1658943CDA064A7C5AF249512"><enum>4.</enum><header>Reports on relocation fund and earthquake coverage</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="H11467D78C3A14E8B9BDBD1002F67612C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, submit to Congress a report on the feasibility of establishing a fund to relocate homes and businesses that have become uninsurable due to catastrophe perils; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA37E80369C1A4FD79182B93A57DA7819"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, submit to Congress a report on the feasibility of including earthquakes as a peril covered under the all-perils property insurance policy.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H9F94A13128304DCF80071789FF60F373"><enum>5.</enum><header>Long-term policy pilot program</header><subsection id="H3490E24C3D9D4989BDD63FFA2CC4AE2A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall, in consultation with States and the National Association of Insurance Commissioners, establish a pilot program for all-perils property insurance policies, as perils are phased in under section 3(d), with a policy term of at least 5 years (in this section referred to as a <quote>multi-year policy</quote>). </text></subsection><subsection id="HD99E1B6F1B4C44A08F46299F3D5E5AFC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Premium and policy conditions</header><text>An insurer who participates in the pilot program established under this section may—</text><paragraph id="H85A187036D3544E08F594ABBA69C03D8"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">increase premiums based on—</text><subparagraph id="H5E98F14E005949AE91177DB53AA70437"><enum>(A)</enum><text>price indexes of construction costs;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCBBEA621B8424D009524126AF86F6216"><enum>(B)</enum><text>changes in home value; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H022FA25CC9284A6C9E052437FCCD6363"><enum>(C)</enum><text>optional coverages selected by the policyholder;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5D50D6D0073F4CA0B9C5960DD9B8114E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not increase premiums based on a change in the assessment by the insurer of the catastrophe peril risks associated with the insured property;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD80AF3DA78864BBCA9A93CF0ED27F108"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">require property maintenance consistent with the condition of the property at time of initial policy issuance; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H16AC83D563894965B5B6B669A22EAD3E"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">require loss mitigation investment partnerships as a condition for the multi-year policy.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HDFC71D8ED2A74B5DBA597246693873EA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Actions by the policyholder</header><paragraph commented="no" id="H54CB8C532A534720A815767163395B88"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Policy continuation</header><text>With the agreement of the insurer, a consumer purchasing the property during the term of the multi-year policy may continue the policy for the remainder of the term.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H2852A989307C4A599F9E0CCC4A6F78E2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Election to new insurer</header><text>If the policyholder elects to move to a new insurer during the term of the multi-year policy, the new insurer may take into account loss mitigation investment partnerships with the prior insurers in rate setting. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7351C227A4404EC594CA86427748A238"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Cancellation by policyholder</header><text>If the policyholder is the recipient of any funds for loss prevention property improvements from the insurer, Federal, State, local government, or other source and the policyholder cancels the policy before the end of the multi-year policy term, the policyholder shall return a pro-rata share of such improvement to the source of the funds.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

