<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-EHF25467-FKS-90-V47"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1553 IS: Promoting and Respecting Economically Vital American Innovation Leadership Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1553</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250501">May 1, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S384">Mr. Tillis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend title 35, United States Code, to invest in inventors in the United States, maintain the United States as the leading innovation economy in the world, and protect the property rights of the inventors that grow the economy of the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="not-changed"><section section-type="section-one" id="id6e04d225-10ad-47a4-95dd-f94fea9ca7d4" changed="not-changed"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Promoting and Respecting Economically Vital American Innovation Leadership Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>PREVAIL Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id8e150aa1-2dfd-4907-9a60-88f0316e6643" changed="not-changed"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="ida4c1b703-ec69-460d-a40b-f93ce3d53ee3" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The patent property rights enshrined in the Constitution of the United States provide the foundation for the exceptional innovation environment in the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc8608fc5-d087-4008-9818-ce5155d3a840" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Reliable and effective patent protection encourages United States inventors to invest their resources in creating new inventions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id86526daf-fbc9-4735-8a11-b3fc2a80abef" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><text>United States inventors have made discoveries leading to patient cures, positive changes to the standard of living for all people in the United States, and improvements to the agricultural, telecommunications, and electronics industries, among others.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id78a77b44-1bbf-4cd3-82af-23e14193e9ed" changed="not-changed"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The United States patent system is an essential part of the economic success of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id51d7770a-4185-435f-8f5c-d9f017f97607" changed="not-changed"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Reliable and effective patent protection improves the chances of success for individual inventors and small companies and increases the chances of securing investments for those inventors and companies.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id92f0ba0e-1602-4c40-b796-24467d78da8a" changed="not-changed"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Intellectual property-intensive industries in the United States— </text><subparagraph id="idd50d57b3-e102-4c8d-b4fe-3b06b039eee9" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>generate tens of millions of jobs for individuals in the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id541950ba-1bf7-4877-b29e-af2537674c37" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>account for more than <fraction>1/3</fraction> of the gross domestic product of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id00d02250-a975-46a3-b1d0-296f7b6c468e" changed="not-changed"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The National Security Commission on Artificial Intelligence has emphasized that— </text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide4f25897-a3c4-46dc-8277-b1e13e73531f" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the People’s Republic of China is leveraging and exploiting intellectual property as a critical tool within its national strategies for emerging technologies; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id31dae7f6-5c43-459d-a6db-362cfa08911e" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the United States has failed to similarly recognize the importance of intellectual property in securing its own national security, economic interests, and technological competitiveness.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id38a44a04-48a9-4533-9795-da18e2223f91" changed="not-changed"><enum>(8)</enum><text>In the highly competitive global economy, the United States needs reliable and effective patent protections to safeguard national security interests and maintain its position as the most innovative country in the world. </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5ef887d3-de2b-4b14-a30d-ed240bf70cd1" changed="not-changed"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress last enacted comprehensive reforms of the patent system in 2011.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1cd58ca5-a530-4a69-838a-66b6328829fb" changed="not-changed"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Unintended consequences of the comprehensive 2011 reform of patent laws have become evident during the decade preceding the date of enactment of this Act, including the strategic filing of post-grant review proceedings to depress stock prices and extort settlements, the filing of repetitive petitions for inter partes and post-grant reviews that have the effect of harassing patent owners, and the unnecessary duplication of work by the district courts of the United States and the Patent Trial and Appeal Board, all of which drive down investment in innovation and frustrate the purpose of those patent reform laws.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6a7a1bac-2ca8-4c53-a15e-e399a5ca2046" changed="not-changed"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Efforts by Congress to reform the patent system without careful scrutiny create a serious risk of making it more costly and difficult for innovators to protect their patents from infringement, thereby— </text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5d6109dd-3eb3-4ca3-a19f-9bdddf7b2ab3" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">disincentivizing United States companies from innovating; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4b690f62-b70e-4e8b-a0be-e227c283ea76" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">weakening the economy of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="id42ba6164-8a9a-4a98-bcc5-5394489cbb83" changed="not-changed"><enum>3.</enum><header>Patent trial and appeal board</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 6 of title 35, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="id45169584-b704-4597-a315-0e280fd4f479" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (b), (c), and (d) as subsections (c), (d), and (e), respectively;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id81964793-0c8c-4eaf-8c99-ba506e769db3" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (a) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida7680f3e-2487-4133-ab79-33032d2ed25b" changed="not-changed"><subsection id="id4d3d05ae-d6a0-42ce-aa66-8ba54a53d34e" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Code of conduct</header><paragraph id="id92ff6c53-ea6a-40fc-a871-275196873330" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director shall prescribe regulations establishing a code of conduct for the members of the Patent Trial and Appeal Board. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id93785868-e5bf-44a7-b695-38906bef81ef" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In prescribing regulations under paragraph (1), the Director shall consider the Code of Conduct for United States Judges and how the provisions of that Code of Conduct may apply to the Patent Trial and Appeal Board.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="idcf1f63a0-64c3-4d40-a387-3033701052fd" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking subsection (d), as so redesignated, and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3b849c2f-686a-4657-83ce-5003cd7bca62" changed="not-changed"><subsection id="id21c61988-e964-4747-8ca7-85111121b4a8" changed="not-changed"><enum>(d)</enum><header>3-Member panels</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida4f700dd-cd12-4bb6-ad5c-cb9d1f89715a" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>Each appeal, derivation proceeding, post-grant review, and inter partes review shall be heard by at least 3 members of the Patent Trial and Appeal Board, who shall be designated by the Director. The Patent Trial and Appeal Board may grant rehearings. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="idabfc1636-e212-4874-92af-773365135adb" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Changes to constitution of panel</header><text>After the constitution of a panel of the Patent Trial and Appeal Board under this subsection has been made public, any changes to the constitution of that panel, including changes that were made before the constitution of the panel was made public, shall be noted in the record.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc4413a03-ab2e-49c4-b69d-8df5fa879d26" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><header>No direction or influence</header><text>An officer who has supervisory authority or disciplinary authority with respect to an administrative patent judge of the Patent Trial and Appeal Board (or a delegate of such an officer), and who is not a member of a panel described in this subsection, shall refrain from communications with the panel that direct or otherwise influence any merits decision of the panel.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6e79dd19-ffe7-4ecf-9bb5-77c65d8e96cc" changed="not-changed"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Ineligibility to hear review</header><text>A member of the Patent Trial and Appeal Board who participates in the decision to institute an inter partes review or a post-grant review of a patent shall be ineligible to hear the review.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="ided19b4cf-0467-4b32-b2b2-fc7b69f1b6e5" changed="not-changed"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (e), as so redesignated—</text><subparagraph id="id2ecd8025-394c-4fbf-b5cc-25eee51ec057" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the first sentence—</text><clause id="id2b10beac-f61d-4236-8670-3fb442583159" changed="not-changed"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>the date of the enactment of this subsection</quote> and inserting <quote>the date of enactment of the <short-title>Promoting and Respecting Economically Vital American Innovation Leadership Act</short-title></quote>;</text></clause><clause id="id751725c6-7c45-4799-98e6-3780c5d80eaa" changed="not-changed"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>by the Director</quote> and inserting <quote>by the Director or the Secretary</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="id4401ee11-3b1a-4639-8bd0-3649b135e402" changed="not-changed"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>or the Secretary, as applicable,</quote> after <quote>on which the Director</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbd6ccf73-f087-49c2-8f46-5222751b4588" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the second sentence—</text><clause id="id38c8475f-4668-4dcd-bdcd-d0097f099648" changed="not-changed"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by inserting after <quote>by the Director</quote> the following: <quote>, or, before the date of enactment of the <short-title>Promoting and Respecting Economically Vital American Innovation Leadership Act</short-title>, having performed duties no longer performed by administrative patent judges,</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="idf293d039-a400-4b19-9e31-cbea5b813327" changed="not-changed"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>that the administrative patent judge so appointed</quote> and inserting <quote>that the applicable administrative patent judge</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="id2c5dddbc-3c76-4fb6-8002-d91f5237c706" changed="not-changed"><enum>4.</enum><header>Inter partes review</header><subsection id="ide018972f-5dc0-4480-8f90-45cd494d733f" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Real parties in interest</header><text>Section 311 of title 35, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4f7c6b63-8424-49ca-8d59-18f4a6af4f63" changed="not-changed"><subsection id="id1423675b-3e5f-47d7-8359-65e8b6c56f45" changed="not-changed"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Real party in interest</header><text>For purposes of this chapter, a person that, directly or through an affiliate, subsidiary, or proxy, makes a financial contribution to the preparation for, or conduct during, an inter partes review on behalf of a petitioner shall be considered a real party in interest of that petitioner.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="idc403f83a-d0eb-457c-b9f8-16261b3a6021" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Petitioner certification and Director determination</header><text>Section 312(a) of title 35, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idca1c002bd79e477b8d35966a8bbc4d38" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (4), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id717d58cc75684ef9baad4e1a1ebb1f04" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (5), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id96030554d87e4d5299913391b1826409" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="id46275ED7E741483BBA9A6649EB7C4BDF" act-name="" changed="not-changed"><paragraph id="idCEDB44D803754FBA85E889B162BF8ED4" changed="not-changed"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the petitioner certifies, and the Director determines, that the petitioner—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id12f2cb3503de41c1b9c955c515df18c2" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is a nonprofit organization that—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ided16d027742141e8b06bf9e3150d4dd5" changed="not-changed"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is exempt from taxation under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(a)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, described in section 501(c)(3) of such Code, and described in section 170(b)(1)(A) of such Code, other than an organization described in section 509(a)(3) of such Code; </text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6c4696764fef405593d7d8b6a3617253" changed="not-changed"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not have any member, donor, or other funding source that is, or reasonably could be accused of, infringing 1 or more claims of the challenged patent; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4e88731d496e4bd8a532985c6c479152" changed="not-changed"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>is filing the petition for the sole purpose of ascertaining the patentability of the challenged claims of the patent and not to profit from or fund the operations of the petitioner;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc1dcaa6d248045ebb36ef57eb3ff0605" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is currently engaging in, or has a bona fide intent to engage in, conduct within the United States that reasonably could be accused of infringing 1 or more claims of the challenged patent;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7ab6c5ba773d455ab562c70897d207d2" changed="not-changed"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">would have standing to bring a civil action in a court of the United States seeking a declaratory judgment of invalidity with respect to 1 or more claims of the challenged patent; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd2f3053dd71541cd8fa75f6c10d382a1" changed="not-changed"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has been sued in a court of the United States for infringement of the challenged patent.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3ad74ce12ee74c9e810370d70e1f9353" changed="not-changed"><enum>(c)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Institution decision rehearing timing</header><text>Section 314 of title 35, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id725eba5f-38e3-46f4-81ad-82d7ceed6d4c" changed="not-changed"><subsection id="id26d5403e-876f-4ea3-8c36-d9184203a49d" changed="not-changed"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Rehearing</header><text>Not later than 45 days after the date on which a request for rehearing from a determination by the Director under subsection (b) is filed, the Director shall finally decide any request for reconsideration, rehearing, or review with respect to the determination, except that the Director may, for good cause shown, extend that 45-day period by not more than 30 days.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="id3597a4d5-0e4c-45ce-8b85-ea7acaddbc82" changed="not-changed"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Eliminating repetitive proceedings</header><paragraph id="id20126602-690b-4faa-a832-cd3f3fa3ce7e" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 315 of title 35, United States Code, is amended—</text><subparagraph id="idd6c9e1e6-77ed-4254-9b15-7e4b1b805932" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (b), by amending the second sentence to read as follows: <quote>The time limitation set forth in the preceding sentence shall not bar a request for joinder under subsection (d), but shall establish a rebuttable presumption against joinder for the requesting person.</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4ac63988-19fb-4c08-ab89-10b5a6643ab4" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (c), (d), and (e) as subsections (d), (e), and (f), respectively;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id069b0f10-9002-4ad5-869e-93633290ecc8" changed="not-changed"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (b) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idad95c1f1-0e83-4b1d-b43e-06e038984451" changed="not-changed"><subsection id="id54262074-c4f2-40b7-9c7e-a197334a01b2" changed="not-changed"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Single forum</header><paragraph id="id4cb75a78-db33-4ba9-acee-57832fb32ce2" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If an inter partes review is instituted challenging the validity of a patent, the petitioner, a real party in interest, or a privy of the petitioner may not file or maintain, in a civil action arising in whole or in part under section 1338 of title 28, or in a proceeding before the International Trade Commission under section 337 of the Tariff Act of 1930 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1337">19 U.S.C. 1337</external-xref>), a claim, a counterclaim, or an affirmative defense challenging the validity of any claim of the patent on any ground described in section 311(b).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0b4c6698-078a-4e05-a218-7653a4646858" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In determining whether to institute a proceeding under this chapter, subject to the provisions of subsections (a)(1) and (g), the Director may not reject a petition requesting an inter partes review on the basis of the petitioner, a real party in interest, or a privy of the petitioner filing or maintaining a claim, a counterclaim, or an affirmative defense challenging the validity of the applicable patent in any civil action arising in whole or in part under section 1338 of title 28, or in a proceeding before the International Trade Commission under section 337 of the Tariff Act of 1930 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1337">19 U.S.C. 1337</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id517cbf12-82ee-4d7a-b37f-09646caceea5" changed="not-changed"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by amending subsection (d), as so redesignated, to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idba21223a-0c7b-4853-8d6a-c2855ca59eb5" changed="not-changed"><subsection id="idd055bf20-8a72-43f2-bbf9-088bb9360c4b" changed="not-changed"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Joinder</header><paragraph id="id9bfcdb81-08af-4d71-a79f-fcb321e05c68" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the Director institutes an inter partes review, the Director, in the discretion of the Director, may join as a party to that inter partes review any person that properly files a request to join the inter partes review and a petition under section 311 that the Director, after receiving a preliminary response under section 313 or the expiration of the time for filing such a response, determines warrants the institution of an inter partes review under section 314.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id151753c7-a232-4d11-9de2-8c2aa6dbcfc0" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Time-barred person</header><text>Pursuant to paragraph (1), the Director, in the discretion of the Director, may join as a party to an inter partes review a person that did not satisfy the time limitation under subsection (b) that rebuts the presumption against joinder, except that any such person shall not be permitted to serve as the lead petitioner and shall not be permitted to maintain the inter partes review unless a petitioner that satisfied the time limitation under subsection (b) remains in the inter partes review.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3282caf4-f79a-4278-acc0-9a1bac044000" changed="not-changed"><enum>(E)</enum><text>by amending subsection (e), as so redesignated, to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcbc98172-407d-48e5-ad96-ddd0c99a5590" changed="not-changed"><subsection id="idf68851e2-65e8-4de0-ad91-7fc44ea4d797" changed="not-changed"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Multiple proceedings</header><paragraph id="id305b170f-c6cb-4f8d-89a8-68974a84f7cc" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding sections 135(a), 251, and 252, and chapter 30, after a petition to institute an inter partes review is filed, if another proceeding or matter involving the patent is before the Office—</text><subparagraph id="id1c48cc3c-3b07-49d4-b83e-32aec2c576dd" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the parties shall notify the Director of that other proceeding or matter—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9565e558-4044-46a7-8c51-c3f260104d51" changed="not-changed"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 30 days after the date of entry of the notice of filing date accorded to the petition; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcb535b84-20c4-4d35-a1c7-3c574c80ce71" changed="not-changed"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if the other proceeding or matter is filed after the date on which the petition to institute an inter partes review is filed, not later than 30 days after the date on which the other proceeding or matter is filed; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbde49f1b-e889-48a0-ba01-5faa79481667" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Director shall issue a decision determining the manner in which the inter partes review or other proceeding or matter may proceed, including providing for stay, transfer, consolidation, or termination of any such matter or proceeding.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ided730864-86b2-455c-b094-ac34923f214e" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In determining whether to institute a proceeding under this chapter, the Director shall, unless the Director determines that the petitioner has demonstrated exceptional circumstances, reject any petition that presents prior art or an argument that is the same or substantially the same as prior art or an argument that previously was presented to the Office.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5bb14bb7-c7cd-492d-8665-60d0293b51a7" changed="not-changed"><enum>(F)</enum><text>by amending subsection (f), as so redesignated, to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0ce324f0-4554-461e-9585-14cdba235aee" changed="not-changed"><subsection id="id276136d2-d314-4688-985a-04fada4bb034" changed="not-changed"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Estoppel</header><paragraph id="idaba1ca8a-ce39-4481-a049-ea487bc6facc" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A petitioner that has previously requested an inter partes review of a claim in a patent under this chapter, or a real party in interest or a privy of such a petitioner, may not request or maintain another proceeding before the Office with respect to that patent on any ground that the petitioner raised or reasonably could have raised in the petition requesting or during the prior inter partes review, unless—</text><subparagraph id="id74db3f42-c5db-43aa-82e3-7abe69b6ce42" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>after the filing of the initial petition, the petitioner, or a real party in interest or a privy of the petitioner, is charged with infringement of additional claims of the patent;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2f5fcfd9-b5c3-49f7-85f5-0afe6c6621ad" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a subsequent petition requests an inter partes review of only the additional claims of the patent that the petitioner, or a real party in interest or a privy of the petitioner, is later charged with infringing; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8a91e560-975a-4e33-b70d-9229a450a398" changed="not-changed"><enum>(C)</enum><text>that subsequent petition is accompanied by a request for joinder to the prior inter partes review, which overcomes the rebuttable presumption against joinder set forth in subsection (b), and which the Director shall grant if the Director authorizes an inter partes review to be instituted on the subsequent petition under section 314.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="iddf37f0a4-4c19-4f49-9357-b3332d57d425" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Joined party</header><text>Any person joined as a party to an inter partes review, and any real party in interest or any privy of such person, shall be estopped under this subsection and subsections (c)(1) and (e)(2) to the same extent as if that person, real party in interest, or privy had been the first petitioner in that inter partes review.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf340adf3-313a-42e7-9457-5fcfa62614d7" changed="not-changed"><enum>(G)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id85a98bb5-2dc0-4798-a2ad-6c8273355820" changed="not-changed"><subsection id="id30f275db-a1b2-4365-924a-3ae2307a91c9" changed="not-changed"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Federal court and International Trade Commission validity determinations</header><text>An inter partes review of a patent claim may not be instituted or maintained if, in a civil action arising in whole or in part under section 1338 of title 28, or in a proceeding before the International Trade Commission under section 337 of the Tariff Act of 1930 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1337">19 U.S.C. 1337</external-xref>), in which the petitioner, a real party in interest, or a privy of the petitioner is a party, the court, or the International Trade Commission, as applicable, has entered a final judgment that decides a challenge to the validity of the patent claim with respect to any ground described in section 311(b).</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id2e9d4480-3cef-4c46-821d-09d3bf4cddd7" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendments</header><text>Section 316(a) of title 35, United States Code, is amended—</text><subparagraph id="id0a11f0bd-a753-4aeb-8ac7-053c13df965b" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (11), by striking <quote>section 315(c)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 315(d)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id71dced5b-62c0-49ab-9acd-43e902f75839" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (12), by striking <quote>section 315(c)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 315(d)</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idf586c75c-7c23-41a5-be6d-31defddb7463" changed="not-changed"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Conduct of inter partes review</header><text>Section 316 of title 35, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id72c765f6-c40e-4007-809a-181e2390a570" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (a)—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbc23c0b6-863a-4494-9da0-0e9a8f76a822" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating paragraphs (2) through (13) as paragraphs (3) through (14), respectively;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3e40d4e3d5b14eea9b65b993766bfaa1" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (1) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="id464489A5BA0246B69E41C965B4BA3A6E" act-name="" changed="not-changed"><paragraph id="id66E42EBF2FEB4AA0A362A8D94877F6D5" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>establishing procedures for briefing and limited discovery, at the request and discretion of the Director, for assisting the Director in making a determination under section 312(a)(6);</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idff4c02b9d4c54e7f8fb13d4432077663" changed="not-changed"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by amending paragraph (6), as so redesignated, to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id61df0c58-1179-46bc-ac74-3b7e234309c6" changed="not-changed"><paragraph id="id60339388-d392-42c1-9c3a-17536ae241dd" changed="not-changed"><enum>(6)</enum><text>setting forth standards and procedures for discovery of relevant evidence, including that such discovery shall be limited to—</text><subparagraph id="id7c4820ef-beaa-4667-8893-4fc4d040862f" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the deposition of witnesses submitting affidavits or declarations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idba3e0c9c-104a-4801-ba06-23cf460abe1d" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>evidence identifying the real parties in interest of the petitioner; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idec62f1c9-00ed-4597-b870-211cb210eb9e" changed="not-changed"><enum>(C)</enum><text>what is otherwise necessary in the interest of justice;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide33351bb-7387-4a4b-bcaf-838ead98fa02" changed="not-changed"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by amending paragraph (10), as so redesignated, to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id03e1fdb8-4ca8-477c-bc45-8738dc2448f2" changed="not-changed"><paragraph id="ida344798f-355d-4914-947c-20e4d42487f1" changed="not-changed"><enum>(10)</enum><text>setting forth standards and procedures for—</text><subparagraph id="idec932517-981b-4821-a7f5-089bdb327cda" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>allowing the patent owner to move to amend the patent under subsection (d) to cancel a challenged claim or propose a reasonable number of substitute claims;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6b554cea-7cf6-44b8-bc6e-15f1736be8fd" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>allowing the Patent Trial and Appeal Board to provide guidance on substitute claims proposed by the patent owner; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idacf985e8-d606-4e70-ab49-ca94f3b08e6f" changed="not-changed"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">allowing the patent owner to further revise proposed substitute claims after the issuance of guidance described in subparagraph (B); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfcca007f-0e12-4ab9-97b3-74b7328ad0dd" changed="not-changed"><enum>(D)</enum><text>ensuring that any information submitted by the patent owner in support of any amendment entered under subsection (d), and any guidance issued by the Patent Trial and Appeal Board, is made available to the public as part of the prosecution history of the patent;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd835260d-0a65-4ea4-b29d-2f581f36e54a" changed="not-changed"><enum>(E)</enum><text>in paragraph (13), as so redesignated, by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ideca812c8-c8c8-40ff-b684-ea43e3eaec4e" changed="not-changed"><enum>(F)</enum><text>in paragraph (14), as so redesignated, by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id15fe07c5-645b-49e2-82bf-60d3969be41d" changed="not-changed"><enum>(G)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1c6cd23d-a8a3-4dc4-9a23-96865a70ba42" changed="not-changed"><paragraph id="idbbfa219e-4689-4d72-96b9-12a667f1ada3" changed="not-changed"><enum>(15)</enum><text>setting forth the standards for demonstrating exceptional circumstances under sections 303(e)(1) and 315(e)(2).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7379dd68-e6b8-4990-b374-bfdefbe605f1" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by amending subsection (e) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0ade43d0-f58c-4b2e-94ae-786d8c6a69d0" changed="not-changed"><subsection id="idc76cd17a-83a1-44d5-b2a5-6a827f295d3a" changed="not-changed"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Evidentiary standards</header><paragraph id="idafd2dfc3-fcbf-4c12-9945-5b0610869347" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Presumption of validity</header><text>The presumption of validity under section 282(a) shall apply to previously issued claims of a patent that is challenged in an inter partes review under this chapter.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb3a28210-515a-40ea-ad12-8d9e7ad461cc" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Burden of proof</header><text>In an inter partes review under this chapter—</text><subparagraph id="id2c2fc6e3-d816-4809-9793-89a8844bd26b" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the petitioner shall have the burden of proving a proposition of unpatentability of a previously issued claim of a patent by clear and convincing evidence; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb36048a4-3ea6-4f61-b188-329bd394372f" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the petitioner shall have the burden of persuasion, by a preponderance of the evidence, with respect to a proposition of unpatentability for any substitute claim proposed by the patent owner.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide732e161-f030-4132-8606-7fecef13564b" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ided578e6e-a497-4219-94f3-16d4623d782e" changed="not-changed"><subsection id="id627b2afe-479b-4118-9d47-04a859e954ca" changed="not-changed"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Claim construction</header><text>For the purposes of this chapter—</text><paragraph id="idc0931fe0-3787-488d-9e33-d317393a1dea" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>each challenged claim of a patent, and each substitute claim proposed in a motion to amend, shall be construed as the claim would be construed under section 282(b) in an action to invalidate a patent, including by construing each such claim in accordance with—</text><subparagraph id="id54f59fea-ca80-4242-a4a0-41a52f68cbc0" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the ordinary and customary meaning of the claim as understood by a person having ordinary skill in the art to which the claimed invention pertains; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id175d6232-b3cc-4de9-afa9-fb0d4980b357" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the prosecution history pertaining to the patent; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idd4ff25de-9867-449f-a34f-c05bd500b1b1" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>if a court has previously construed a challenged claim of a patent or a challenged claim term in a civil action to which the patent owner was a party, the Office shall consider that claim construction.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idd8a471e9-905e-4876-8f76-7625315734da" changed="not-changed"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Settlement</header><text>Section 317(a) of title 35, United States Code, is amended by striking the second sentence.</text></subsection><subsection id="idd2de8db2-46e7-4e10-93c0-fe96fe05e4e3" changed="not-changed"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Timing To issue trial certificate and decisions on rehearing</header><text>Section 318 of title 35, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="id231f0a75-be90-4e1c-837c-7153afa56730" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b), by inserting <quote>, not later than 60 days after the date on which the parties to the inter partes review have informed the Director that the time for appeal has expired or any appeal has terminated,</quote> after <quote>the Director shall</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3f30a96d-c570-4c73-9af1-9c13c3215813" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5176392f-c27e-4eda-87d3-f6517e7cf559" changed="not-changed"><subsection id="id436d4846-d2a9-4208-9d5a-aca6fad831b0" changed="not-changed"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Rehearing</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date on which a request for rehearing of a final written decision issued by the Patent and Trial Appeal Board under subsection (a) is filed, the Board or the Director shall finally decide any request for reconsideration, rehearing, or review that is submitted with respect to the decision, except that the Director may, for good cause shown, extend that 90-day period by not more than 60 days.</text></subsection><subsection id="id45bb8745-4220-4031-a641-10cdc6fe1a81" changed="not-changed"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Review by director</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id91a43a24-de1d-4db4-907d-82520a222299" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>The Director may grant rehearing, reconsideration, or review of a decision by the Patent Trial and Appeal Board issued under this chapter. </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc7fb9ab4-2402-46ed-8735-e86f845c1b56" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any reconsideration, rehearing, or review by the Director, as described in paragraph (1), shall be issued in a separate written opinion that—</text><subparagraph id="id3b72e4aa-5714-4eb4-a377-7c30506a42d4" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is made part of the public record; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5c6d4720-72f4-4169-8710-4f5e162515ca" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>sets forth the reasons for the reconsideration, rehearing, or review of the applicable decision by the Patent Trial and Appeal Board.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idfd17e21b-1793-4954-953f-c01c468e680e" changed="not-changed"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>For the purposes of an appeal permitted under section 141, any decision on rehearing, reconsideration, or review of a final written decision of the Patent Trial and Appeal Board under subsection (a) of this section that is issued by the Director shall be deemed to be a final written decision of the Patent Trial and Appeal Board.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id9d0a8430-056c-4d00-8b12-9988441049c2" changed="not-changed"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Timing To issue decisions on remand</header><text>Section 319 of title 35, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="iddb0397c0-34ab-4604-b85b-925c254d08e7" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>A party</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id35e1d53b-b06d-48f3-808b-1019c97d4eb2" changed="not-changed"><subsection id="idc2299638-0f34-414c-ba81-be8c7e528a64" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A party</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="ida4646531-546a-4296-92c1-9ed08c137e75" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id14abbda8-cf9d-4ced-91e0-b227149e69db" changed="not-changed"><subsection id="id727396a7-6b7d-4c0f-9d4f-23a178b82c3f" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Timing on remand after appeal</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date on which a mandate issues from the court remanding to the Patent Trial and Appeal Board after an appeal under subsection (a), the Board or the Director shall finally decide any issue on remand, except that the Director may, for good cause shown, extend that 120-day period by not more than 60 days.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idb16fe43f-6944-4d73-bb79-136026bdd2cf" changed="not-changed"><enum>5.</enum><header>Post-grant review</header><subsection id="idc8007dcd-c390-4425-8a27-5bd173c679a3" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Real parties in interest</header><text>Section 321 of title 35, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8cdf9370-ad0b-4170-928b-b0d09b989ebe" changed="not-changed"><subsection id="idc82de57c-1708-4352-bfc0-fd4190dd6abe" changed="not-changed"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Real party in interest</header><text>For purposes of this chapter, a person that, directly or through an affiliate, subsidiary, or proxy, makes a financial contribution to the preparation for, or conduct during, a post-grant review on behalf of a petitioner shall be considered a real party in interest of that petitioner.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="id85b018b2-0749-4591-8e5d-a70038a63344" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Timing To issue decisions on rehearing</header><text>Section 324 of title 35, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb79e677b-c6f2-48db-aaab-cd1942069ac9" changed="not-changed"><subsection id="id1a88060f-3c42-479c-9bca-ffac18ad994e" changed="not-changed"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Rehearing</header><text>Not later than 45 days after the date on which a request for rehearing from a determination by the Director under subsection (c) is filed, the Director shall finally decide any request for reconsideration, rehearing, or review with respect to the determination, except that the Director may, for good cause shown, extend that 45-day period by not more than 30 days.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="id5b9bbc1c-247b-4967-8ea7-26f9e1274336" changed="not-changed"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eliminating repetitive proceedings</header><text>Section 325 of title 35, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="idc9ce1cb8-2a85-458c-a125-edc380b4f70e" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (c) through (f) as subsections (d) through (g), respectively;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id670c22d1-2778-4d63-9425-af1836ad5d91" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (b) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idedff67e7-b75a-4bee-a053-0031082afd80" changed="not-changed"><subsection id="id8cdc71f1-c65a-4786-b565-3592f75f453f" changed="not-changed"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Single forum</header><paragraph id="id5093fd81-0d10-464e-84d3-6e965d904c41" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If a post-grant review is instituted challenging the validity of a patent, the petitioner, a real party in interest, or a privy of the petitioner may not file or maintain, in a civil action arising in whole or in part under section 1338 of title 28, or in a proceeding before the International Trade Commission under section 337 of the Tariff Act of 1930 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1337">19 U.S.C. 1337</external-xref>), a claim, a counterclaim, or an affirmative defense challenging the validity of any claim of the patent.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc2905850-3f6e-4357-9af5-e24dcf546b41" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In determining whether to institute a proceeding under this chapter, subject to the provisions of subsections (a)(1) and (h), the Director may not reject a petition requesting a post-grant review on the basis of the petitioner, a real party in interest, or a privy of the petitioner filing or maintaining a claim, a counterclaim, or an affirmative defense challenging the validity of the patent in any civil action arising in whole or in part under section 1338 of title 28, or in a proceeding before the International Trade Commission under section 337 of the Tariff Act of 1930 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1337">19 U.S.C. 1337</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="ideaa3040e-845e-4b08-8903-741f2e3adbcf" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by amending subsection (e), as so redesignated, to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id16a5adb9-a8e1-4046-8317-f9316bef9f4e" changed="not-changed"><subsection id="idb4259313-2b3c-4d32-82f2-a45076a08d5a" changed="not-changed"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Multiple proceedings</header><paragraph id="idfb879e77-45b2-4c58-acaf-f24f6382a2fb" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding sections 135(a), 251, and 252, and chapter 30, after a petition to institute a post-grant review is filed, if another proceeding or matter involving the patent is before the Office—</text><subparagraph id="id68d43be5-c017-4e88-8c5e-4677c67b7bc0" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the parties shall notify the Director of that other proceeding or matter—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id901d4a80-7e6d-48fa-9793-f1a5f62079e9" changed="not-changed"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 30 days after the date of entry of the notice of filing date accorded to the petition; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfa8e02eb-07c5-4680-aa74-6cb966f17a37" changed="not-changed"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if the other proceeding or matter is filed after the date on which the petition to institute an inter partes review is filed, not later than 30 days after the date on which the other proceeding or matter is filed; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4d5192fe-c244-45f8-9930-f80fa400f703" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Director shall issue a decision determining the manner in which the post-grant review or other proceeding or matter may proceed, including providing for stay, transfer, consolidation, or termination of any such matter or proceeding.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idfabb12ef-50ce-4df6-af92-5dea594252fc" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In determining whether to institute a proceeding under this chapter, the Director shall, unless the Director determines that the petitioner has demonstrated exceptional circumstances, reject any petition that presents prior art or an argument that is the same or substantially the same as prior art or an argument that previously was presented to the Office.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="idc1872d40-971f-46c9-8640-22b181b9834b" changed="not-changed"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by amending subsection (f), as so redesignated, to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide4443325-2135-49dc-adc6-657b0797e9cd" changed="not-changed"><subsection id="idafbd021d-c0b6-4e5e-b2e9-140fdccb1265" changed="not-changed"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Estoppel</header><paragraph id="id98c05a9d-cc58-42ae-b449-75f6426bd11e" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A petitioner that has previously requested a post-grant review of a claim in a patent under this chapter, or a real party in interest or a privy of a petitioner, may not request or maintain another proceeding before the Office with respect to that patent on any ground that the petitioner raised or reasonably could have raised in the petition requesting or during the prior post-grant review, unless—</text><subparagraph id="id48f8bae7-281b-44b9-ada7-ede9fec333ac" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>after the filing of the initial petition, the petitioner, or a real party in interest or a privy of the petitioner, is charged with infringement of additional claims of the patent;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6455b335-e4d1-4244-b341-d0bc738c7a22" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a subsequent petition requests an inter partes review of only the additional claims of the patent that the petitioner, or a real party in interest or a privy of the petitioner, is later charged with infringing; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7848373a-9273-4f5a-a192-2e2f40f4660a" changed="not-changed"><enum>(C)</enum><text>that subsequent petition is accompanied by a request for joinder to the prior post-grant review, which the Director shall grant if the Director authorizes a post-grant review to be instituted on the subsequent petition under section 324.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id09e45dbd-5c9d-4ea8-8e80-d2fd6cfc1dc3" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Joined party</header><text>Any person joined as a party to a post-grant review, and any real party in interest or any privy of such person, shall be estopped under this subsection and subsections (c)(1) and (e)(2) to the same extent as if that person, real party in interest, or privy had been the first petitioner in that post-grant review.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="id5b588866-01ec-4106-bd46-b92bb1803336" changed="not-changed"><enum>(5)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd6bb6fd8-1749-4dec-ab56-7c14267a7b7c" changed="not-changed"><subsection id="idff0877b7-0ee9-4a6b-aa75-c747a31ff1f5" changed="not-changed"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Federal court and International Trade Commission validity determinations</header><text>A post-grant review of a patent claim may not be instituted or maintained if, in a civil action arising in whole or in part under section 1338 of title 28, or in a proceeding before the International Trade Commission under section 337 of the Tariff Act of 1930 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1337">19 U.S.C. 1337</external-xref>), in which the petitioner, a real party in interest, or a privy of the petitioner is a party, the court, or the International Trade Commission, as applicable, has entered a final judgment that decides a challenge to the validity of the patent claim.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idc2e39765-56fa-4604-8101-416387b24fcd" changed="not-changed"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Conduct of post-Grant review</header><text>Section 326 of title 35, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide8145618-02f5-4d86-95ff-db4b9f7889ff" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (a)—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2836565a-8cfb-4e30-b9de-863bc3f26936" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by amending paragraph (5) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfc17f706-4e80-485a-8197-1a1d484ad471" changed="not-changed"><paragraph id="ideb5643ed-f912-4752-87eb-4879793533c2" changed="not-changed"><enum>(5)</enum><text>setting forth standards and procedures for discovery of relevant evidence, including that such discovery shall be limited to—</text><subparagraph id="id80af1ab6-360b-4d59-a7c3-1510afcfa0cd" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the deposition of witnesses submitting affidavits or declarations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idec01b966-4c3b-487f-880a-81afe5694154" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>evidence identifying the real parties in interest of the petitioner; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf3b10639-3ae6-4b18-9f4a-65b2fcd9c968" changed="not-changed"><enum>(C)</enum><text>what is otherwise necessary in the interest of justice;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0b6c6261-e469-4bc4-bcb0-9ac924feb5fb" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by amending paragraph (9) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ideb5616f8-88f7-4a58-9d99-10e46476b658" changed="not-changed"><paragraph id="id994d8c3c-75fa-4697-b085-5fb27cf7cb9f" changed="not-changed"><enum>(9)</enum><text>setting forth standards and procedures for—</text><subparagraph id="id9e39433d-cd72-432b-877f-3bf7f29751dc" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>allowing the patent owner to move to amend the patent under subsection (d) to cancel a challenged claim or propose a reasonable number of substitute claims;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf645403c-c6e0-49fe-afef-b133a76760c2" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>allowing the Patent Trial and Appeal Board to provide guidance on substitute claims proposed by the patent owner; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idada4828a-3205-407b-85a0-0e2b18293880" changed="not-changed"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">allowing the patent owner to further revise proposed substitute claims after the issuance of guidance described in subparagraph (B); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idaa8d373c-57b3-4872-a226-03a94cb81107" changed="not-changed"><enum>(D)</enum><text>ensuring that any information submitted by the patent owner in support of any amendment entered under subsection (d), and any guidance issued by the Patent Trial and Appeal Board, is made available to the public as part of the prosecution history of the patent;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3a4c595d-c660-4e6a-bf4d-8fe463dc5701" changed="not-changed"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (11)— </text><clause changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id036d0988fb214979b44f46dbcd4b421b"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>section 325(c)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 325(d)</quote>; and</text></clause><clause changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida25229b1c4c341a2957332f7a2b37aa4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id13dd8658-cde7-4f37-8d23-cd99730a9300" changed="not-changed"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in paragraph (12), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7d9f55b1-71f1-4cc9-96b5-76a54c6c4e64" changed="not-changed"><enum>(E)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6dec7d7d-cb9c-4d63-89f0-402f38257088" changed="not-changed"><paragraph id="id79fe407a-dec6-41c7-b8c6-9e58b53f93f8" changed="not-changed"><enum>(13)</enum><text>setting forth the standards for demonstrating exceptional circumstances under section 325(e)(2).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8822aa91-c290-4718-8f1a-510de400c7d1" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by amending subsection (e) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5ccac2f5-da50-45da-a455-b603d83479d8" changed="not-changed"><subsection id="id1b44bcad-f2f0-4c99-96ee-0c6939d159f3" changed="not-changed"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Evidentiary standards</header><paragraph id="id1568750a-ad15-44fa-965e-d5c76c2dd52b" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Presumption of validity</header><text>The presumption of validity under section 282(a) shall apply to previously issued claims of a patent that is challenged in a post-grant review under this chapter.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5c7a0663-aa86-4b56-847f-2926375e8c23" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Burden of proof</header><text>In a post-grant review under this chapter—</text><subparagraph id="id46e04673-7371-43c5-8e1e-401adb8feedc" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the petitioner shall have the burden of proving a proposition of unpatentability of a previously issued claim of a patent by clear and convincing evidence; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5b490d74-fba7-45a3-b6c3-880cdd899634" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the petitioner shall have the burden of persuasion, by a preponderance of the evidence, with respect to a proposition of unpatentability for any substitute claim proposed by the patent owner.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9c579123-6ee6-428b-ae2a-961af7ef65b7" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id843a13f9-48cc-4df3-8b38-0e5e7157efbc" changed="not-changed"><subsection id="idca4d5085-b0dc-4428-b30c-d344a4aa035d" changed="not-changed"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Claim construction</header><text>For the purposes of this chapter—</text><paragraph id="id7463954d-9854-4767-b4fc-599ec47a98c1" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>each challenged claim of a patent, and each substitute claim proposed in a motion to amend, shall be construed as the claim would be construed under section 282(b) in an action to invalidate a patent, including by construing each such claim in accordance with—</text><subparagraph id="id82cdc470-4c25-4de7-a9ef-ab65f8b87074" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the ordinary and customary meaning of the claim as understood by a person having ordinary skill in the art to which the claimed invention pertains; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idce4c85cc-d15f-4160-ac64-9038b7862d14" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the prosecution history pertaining to the patent; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idbd6aabc8-63f0-4eff-b318-05a8fe5fdfba" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>if a court has previously construed a challenged claim of a patent or a challenged claim term in a civil action to which the patent owner was a party, the Office shall consider that claim construction.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id865a33b5-65ee-4cd6-876d-ea0e9be116be" changed="not-changed"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Settlement</header><text>Section 327(a) of title 35, United States Code, is amended by striking the second sentence.</text></subsection><subsection id="id73ab155e-5f2a-4f40-9346-ad1ffeee8ddf" changed="not-changed"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Timing To issue trial certificates and decisions on rehearing</header><text>Section 328 of title 35, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="id60ec89d1-b756-4770-beda-883c8e21b33f" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b), by inserting <quote>, not later than 60 days after the date on which the parties to the post-grant review have informed the Director that the time for appeal has expired or any appeal has terminated,</quote> after <quote>the Director shall</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5f0a4f47-e0d6-48f8-8987-fe7f66bcb788" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide99537e6-e33c-4575-a4a8-00576013ed44" changed="not-changed"><subsection id="id7179fd45-6001-4c68-b966-bb3eacd1de7b" changed="not-changed"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Rehearing</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date on which a request for rehearing of a final written decision issued by the Patent and Trial Appeal Board under subsection (a) is filed, the Board or the Director shall finally decide any request for reconsideration, rehearing, or review that is submitted with respect to the decision, except that the Director may, for good cause shown, extend that 90-day period by not more than 60 days.</text></subsection><subsection id="ide0c0b616-e939-4411-a0de-61f5236b06d8" changed="not-changed"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Review by director</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5d226c55-2b1f-45c9-9fa7-7de8cb8bed55" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>The Director may grant rehearing, reconsideration, or review of a decision by the Patent Trial and Appeal Board issued under this chapter. </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8f391c3a-9d2a-48b8-a06c-16b34a47fbe5" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any reconsideration, rehearing, or review by the Director, as described in paragraph (1), shall be issued in a separate written opinion that—</text><subparagraph id="idf8160005-8c3d-408f-9a19-6be79ecea53d" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is made part of the public record; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7bb06694-aa17-4676-9c01-727247787d6d" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>sets forth the reasons for the reconsideration, rehearing, or review of the applicable decision by the Patent Trial and Appeal Board.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id2d553193-ac96-4a08-94c2-2d141b6b1869" changed="not-changed"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>For the purposes of an appeal permitted under section 141, any decision on rehearing, reconsideration, or review of a final written decision of the Patent Trial and Appeal Board under subsection (a) of this section that is issued by the Director shall be deemed to be a final written decision of the Patent Trial and Appeal Board.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id34d2d13d-336d-41b6-bb04-6dffb1653be0" changed="not-changed"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Timing To issue decisions on remand</header><text>Section 329 of title 35, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="idfdc9d271-477a-4117-ad68-0549edadd671" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>A party</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd29c86fd-5864-43a2-9051-dac8ff2abe04" changed="not-changed"><subsection id="ida845f6ad-303c-4402-b9ea-6df017ab343a" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A party</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="idd388c7ff-5cc3-4e6d-ac8d-75472372c2fe" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id24140ee8-ea41-40d3-91dd-dbe5e6b54ba8" changed="not-changed"><subsection id="id7323167f-8388-403d-842e-53393f4708a3" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Timing on remand after appeal</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date on which a mandate issues from the court remanding to the Patent Trial and Appeal Board after an appeal under subsection (a), the Board or the Director shall finally decide any issue on remand, except that the Director may, for good cause shown, extend that 120-day period by not more than 60 days.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idf00edf99-bacc-4d5a-aec0-5b12c1aabe1c" changed="not-changed"><enum>6.</enum><header>Reexamination of patents</header><subsection id="id826b870c-4dad-493e-80ed-3af3628aa86e" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Request for reexamination</header><text>Section 302 of title 35, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the second sentence the following: <quote>The request must identify all real parties in interest and certify that reexamination is not barred under section 303(d).</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="ide30df8f8-54d3-4265-b7b8-149d268a93d2" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reexamination barred</header><text>Section 303 of title 35, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="ide5355563-2f1a-485c-aa11-54036d19c944" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking the third sentence; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddb2a544d-e247-4435-bb02-1886446bfcf0" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida0851c3a-b2cf-4423-9674-031cf3978407" changed="not-changed"><subsection id="id4d283cdc-387f-49b8-8953-3de14b91104a" changed="not-changed"><enum>(d)</enum><text>An ex parte reexamination may not be ordered if the request for reexamination is filed more than 1 year after the date on which the requester or a real party in interest or a privy of the requester is served with a complaint alleging infringement of the patent. For purposes of this chapter, a person that directly or through an affiliate, subsidiary, or proxy makes a financial contribution to the preparation for, or conduct during, an ex parte reexamination on behalf of a requester shall be considered a real party in interest of the requester.</text></subsection><subsection id="id05a17fd7-08fc-4019-b08b-cb95e8e8fa5d" changed="not-changed"><enum>(e)</enum><text>In determining whether to order an ex parte reexamination, the Director—</text><paragraph id="id54026323-df99-4e1e-ac74-0459c2ef210a" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall, unless the Director determines that the requestor has demonstrated exceptional circumstances, reject any request that presents prior art or an argument that is the same or substantially the same as prior art or an argument that previously was presented to the Office; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id52f2a775-5057-4aab-ad37-869804263044" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may reject any request that the Director determines has used a prior Office decision as a guide to correct or bolster a previous deficient request filed under this chapter or a previous deficient petition filed under chapter 31 or 32.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ide9e86d4c-11b7-49b7-8848-6b4618cc991b" changed="not-changed"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reexamination order by Director</header><text>Section 304 of title 35, United States Code, is amended, in the first sentence, by inserting after <quote>resolution of the question</quote> the following: <quote>, unless the Director determines that the request for reexamination should be rejected under subsection (d) or (e) of section 303, in which case the Director shall issue an order denying reexamination</quote>.</text></subsection></section><section id="id09c052f7-f233-4741-8164-72e5ff6f132b" changed="not-changed"><enum>7.</enum><header>Elimination of USPTO fee diversion</header><subsection id="ide3ee6357-1447-4a7d-a2db-046d40cd58d3" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>Section 42 of title 35, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="idcfd3a7a8-f17c-4945-86ea-8df9909251ea" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>All fees</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="id51f5c0ad-ffb7-4e0b-961a-ad5fa401fa4c" act-name="" changed="not-changed"><subsection id="ida2666b5a-3519-4471-bf97-4d0e87d160c5" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Fees for service by PTO</header><text>All fees</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="idcff79dd9-db21-42e2-aa61-99248aadaae8" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text><subparagraph id="idd8fb2cd0-8083-4eb4-a819-6b89af70f4de" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>All fees paid to the Director and all appropriations</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="id98e4a300-8865-458a-8254-8fedc2a1ae4c" act-name="" changed="not-changed"><subsection id="id3f7b7594-588b-4593-969f-7439114a7657" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Innovation Promotion Fund</header><text>All fees paid to the Director</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbce9f7d7-1ad2-4dd8-b27f-707c1e837d78" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Patent and Trademark Office Appropriation Account</quote> and inserting <quote>United States Patent and Trademark Office Innovation Promotion Fund</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idb3dd2347-2861-4927-b8a7-4a5fd1278012" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking subsection (c) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="id9589496d-28b8-48e7-9e01-998323c83fb5" act-name="" changed="not-changed"><subsection id="idbc8bda5e-2456-410b-9d77-7c1c20b70e91" changed="not-changed"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Collection of funds for PTO activities</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaeea5287-9222-4309-8285-222f280039ad" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>Fees authorized in this title or any other Act to be charged or established by the Director shall be collected by the Director and shall be available to the Director until expended to carry out the activities of the Patent and Trademark Office.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9da96b20-e94e-43eb-8ce9-fbca072b4dcf" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of fees</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0ddfe055-c64e-423d-aa03-f7a05109dbf3" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Patent fees</header><text>Any fees that are collected under this title, and any surcharges on such fees, may only be used for expenses of the Office relating to the processing of patent applications and for other activities, services, and materials relating to patents and to cover a proportionate share of the administrative costs of the Office.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9323d73b-926c-431b-aef6-d38a4f8bdfc3" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Trademark fees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any fees that are collected under section 31 of the Trademark Act of 1946 (as defined in subsection (d)(1)) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1113">15 U.S.C. 1113</external-xref>), and any surcharges on such fees, may only be used for expenses of the Office relating to the processing of trademark registrations and for other activities, services, and materials relating to trademarks and to cover a proportionate share of the administrative costs of the Office.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="idbb1991ab-2d8c-4a26-ac16-a54c34cff528" changed="not-changed"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (d) and (e) as subsections (e) and (f), respectively;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idede9f11a-494a-432e-872e-c365285b2037" changed="not-changed"><enum>(5)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (c) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idadeee5a1-03df-400b-820e-71c1a832e546" changed="not-changed"><subsection id="id00ed808a-9a5f-4504-a6b5-e8bdf3b5d191" changed="not-changed"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Revolving fund</header><paragraph id="idb247f797-702d-45e2-80cb-e421b758113b" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection—</text><subparagraph id="ida4274058-89c4-4573-804c-0f4baeeb3d2b" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the term <term>Fund</term> means the United States Patent and Trademark Office Innovation Promotion Fund established under paragraph (2); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id47c8777d-f00b-4ea0-972f-c484bebb0df8" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the term <term>Trademark Act of 1946</term> means the Act entitled <quote>An Act to provide for the registration and protection of trademarks used in commerce, to carry out the provisions of certain international conventions, and for other purposes</quote>, approved July 5, 1946 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1051">15 U.S.C. 1051 et seq.</external-xref>) (commonly referred to as the <quote>Trademark Act of 1946</quote> or the <quote>Lanham Act</quote>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id0e138a7e-7237-4428-b567-7480f47d6ef6" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established in the Treasury a revolving fund to be known as the <quote>United States Patent and Trademark Office Innovation Promotion Fund</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id214de23b-6feb-4fd3-95a7-a7143e08052d" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Derivation of resources</header><text>There shall be deposited into the Fund any fees collected under—</text><subparagraph id="id59ba5a4e-39cb-4285-a906-2f98511a64d7" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>this title; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddc6d6d08-b766-4a07-b4bb-ec3bd5fe0c68" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Trademark Act of 1946.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idc908b977-b4d1-4e1a-981d-0e6a8cac6b72" changed="not-changed"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Expenses</header><text>Amounts deposited into the Fund under paragraph (3) shall be available, without fiscal year limitation, to cover—</text><subparagraph id="ide0754b9c-b5ca-428d-9e0f-feb5b99ff737" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to the extent consistent with the limitation on the use of fees under subsection (c), all expenses, including all administrative and operating expenses, determined by the Director to be ordinary and reasonable, incurred by the Director for the continued operation of all services, programs, activities, and duties of the Office relating to patents and trademarks, as such services, programs, activities, and duties are described under—</text><clause id="idfea9dd85-919f-46f9-ac3c-cfec069e48c7" changed="not-changed"><enum>(i)</enum><text>this title; and</text></clause><clause id="iddffdd5be-0f33-4010-b5bc-477757e1e986" changed="not-changed"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Trademark Act of 1946; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id92df1849-2427-401c-9295-da4dfdfb8521" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>all expenses incurred pursuant to any obligation, representation, or other commitment of the Office.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="idc156334a-5373-46d1-bb99-9f2a2293ded0" changed="not-changed"><enum>(6)</enum><text>in subsection (e), as so redesignated, by striking <quote>The Director</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="idae01d30d-9b85-4b2e-b341-8bfe0f312444" act-name="" changed="not-changed"><subsection id="ida3cd1029-95da-4176-97f5-e5abc59b8378" changed="not-changed"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Refunds</header><text>The Director</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="idf6ebc092-1e21-4889-99a6-0baf4fe3375b" changed="not-changed"><enum>(7)</enum><text>in subsection (f), as so redesignated, by striking <quote>The Secretary</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="idbfe08267-dd82-40ff-9ba3-fca7cd468f32" act-name="" changed="not-changed"><subsection id="id815aa7ed-9b96-4e77-9650-3d9c877f155b" changed="not-changed"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Report</header><text>The Secretary</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id68726d8e-3ba7-4ee4-8c55-58be2607062d" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date; transfer from and termination of obsolete funds</header><paragraph id="id78ecae65-6086-4253-8c02-e7d65c33042e" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by subsection (a) shall take effect on the first day of the first fiscal year that begins on or after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida68c034a-ef48-4bf1-adb1-013bb30f260a" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Remaining balances</header><text>On the effective date described in paragraph (1), there shall be deposited in the United States Patent and Trademark Office Innovation Promotion Fund established under section 42(d)(2) of title 35, United States Code (as added by subsection (a)), any available unobligated balances remaining in the Patent and Trademark Office Appropriation Account, and in the Patent and Trademark Fee Reserve Fund established under section 42(c)(2) of title 35, United States Code, as in effect on the day before that effective date.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1c03e5c4-a18d-4c02-8705-e494c43f4121" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Termination of reserve fund</header><text>Upon the payment of all obligated amounts in the Patent and Trademark Fee Reserve Fund under paragraph (2), the Patent and Trademark Fee Reserve Fund shall be terminated.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id7aaf8b34-cd8e-4b31-b537-a3325f5560d5" changed="not-changed"><enum>8.</enum><header>Institutions of higher education</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 123(d) of title 35, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6b8b2946-801c-4151-a436-87dcf8819f58" changed="not-changed"><subsection id="ide0526849-5a68-4a23-839e-4ae8b34bef9f" changed="not-changed"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Institutions of higher education</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id93be8b67-b6e1-4451-aa40-f5e0a287658a" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definition</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given the term in section 101(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb0ace5c5-c16d-49e5-9b9f-027cf3a4c3e4" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Inclusions</header><text>For purposes of this section, a micro entity shall include an applicant who certifies that—</text><subparagraph id="id446c19da-ee84-4259-97ae-6c99c09a6327" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the applicant’s employer, from which the applicant obtains the majority of the applicant’s income, is an institution of higher education;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida57bb6e0-a3b3-4891-93d6-db893b74fff7" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the applicant has assigned, granted, conveyed, or is under an obligation by contract or law to assign, grant, or convey, a license or other ownership interest in the particular applications to an institution of higher education;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id46ad72cb-b7af-4dde-944c-a18f9582dc6a" changed="not-changed"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the applicant is an institution of higher education; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida71a89c4-d8c5-443a-8faf-5d89310f19c7" changed="not-changed"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the applicant is an organization described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and exempt from taxation under section 501(a) of such Code that holds title to patents and patent applications on behalf of an institution of higher education for the purpose of facilitating commercialization of the technologies of the patents and patent applications.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="id4d7a8484-c4d6-4ce5-8330-580f38a9705f" changed="not-changed"><enum>9.</enum><header>Assisting small businesses in the United States patent system</header><subsection id="id03f86e9a-3d17-44d7-a180-510e4142df14" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <term>small business concern</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/632">15 U.S.C. 632</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection id="idfc41b647-d20f-4679-a5b4-ee57f65e4300" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Small business administration report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Small Business Administration, using existing resources, shall submit to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship of the Senate and the Committee on Small Business of the House of Representatives a report analyzing the impact of—</text><paragraph id="id90f55060-34f4-4a9d-9158-454fd822caa7" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>patent ownership by small business concerns; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide5751560-fb75-43c7-8d9f-05d0cd50830b" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>civil actions against small business concerns arising under title 35, United States Code, relating to patent infringement.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id1aaacdbe-5a19-4ae0-b570-58277a5f3376" changed="not-changed"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Free online availability of public search facility materials</header><text>Section 41(i) of title 35, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idba6125ee-e0e0-4008-ab66-c6309e914140" changed="not-changed"><paragraph id="id7c77a30c-2f5e-455a-8ba7-c3cb9c45cbb8" changed="not-changed"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Free online availability of public search facility materials</header><text>The Director shall make available online and at no charge all patent and trademark information that is available at the Public Search Facility of the Office located in Alexandria, Virginia, including, except to the extent that licenses with third-party contractors would make such provision financially unviable—</text><subparagraph id="id8ef6142c-b97a-4bf4-9e4e-d94c72488922" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>search tools and databases;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idab03dda6-a534-47ad-8631-04a2452d5db9" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>informational materials; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0aa6f54e-7534-453b-9b89-099a258fa43c" changed="not-changed"><enum>(C)</enum><text>training classes and materials.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

