<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H82F1CDCC883149A38A9B6073C87EF16B" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 814 IH: Recognizing and honoring the White House Medical Unit for its service to the Commander in Chief.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 814</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251017">October 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000304">Mr. Jackson of Texas</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing and honoring the White House Medical Unit for its service to the Commander in Chief.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the White House Medical Unit was established in 1945 to preserve the health and fitness of the Nation’s Chief Executive by providing immediate and high-quality medical care to the President of the United States and executive branch leadership;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the White House Medical Unit is staffed primarily by active-duty personnel from the United States Army, Navy, Air Force, and Coast Guard who deliver world-class medical support in both routine and emergency settings;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the White House Medical Unit provides comprehensive medical care to the President, the Vice President, their families, and White House staff at all times of the day, both at the White House and while traveling domestically and internationally;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the White House Medical Unit maintains constant readiness to respond to medical contingencies anywhere in the world and is a critical element in the Presidential Emergency Operations Plan;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the White House Medical Unit plays a vital role in the continuity of the office of the Presidency, integrating seamlessly with the United States Secret Service, White House Military Office, and National Security Council to ensure uninterrupted national leadership;</text></whereas> <whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas the White House Medical Unit operates a state-of-the-art medical clinic in the Executive Office of the President that provides emergency coverage and triage for over 1,000,000 annual White House visitors, staff, and guests, ensuring safety and rapid response capabilities;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the personnel of the White House Medical Unit perform their duties with professionalism and excellence, often under intense pressure and in highly classified or operationally sensitive environments; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the year 2025 marks the 80th anniversary of the White House Medical Unit’s founding and continuous service to the Nation: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H1005501915F14A68A73AB68A16F24546"> 
<section id="H063189B6E0CD4E5A9CD75C30E634367E" section-type="undesignated-section" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="H742C0485DA2F41648F97B78C40881FF6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognizes and honors the White House Medical Unit for its exemplary service, professionalism, and unwavering commitment to the health and safety of the President, Vice President, their families, and White House staff;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H73E2F84C3C094F348DC7E917411CDE62"><enum>(2)</enum><text>extends its sincere gratitude to the military medical personnel who have served or are currently serving within the White House Medical Unit and recognize their vital contributions to the security and continuity of the United States Government;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2DBF8D895EF846288F0A308A3FB398BE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>commends the leadership of the White House Medical Unit for maintaining operational excellence in one of the most demanding and high-visibility assignments in Federal service; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE65A8507751A4341873979F840BFB167"><enum>(4)</enum><text>celebrates the 80th anniversary of the White House Medical Unit and honors its eight decades of dedicated service to the United States.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

