<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-LIP25039-CJ1-H0-L64"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S142 IS: Wildland Firefighters Congressional Gold Medal Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 142</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250116">January 16, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S317">Mr. Barrasso</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S435">Mr. Sheehy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S323">Mr. Risch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S394">Ms. Smith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S410">Ms. Lummis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S415">Mr. Warnock</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S330">Mr. Bennet</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S266">Mr. Crapo</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To award a Congressional Gold Medal to wildland firefighters in recognition of their strength, resiliency, sacrifice, and service to protect the forests, grasslands, and communities of the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Wildland Firefighters Congressional Gold Medal Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id30b7a2728c69410f9eb55f9e5c92c332"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="ideb39319aecd94a67a3891834093b407b"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Wildland fires have increased in intensity and severity over the 30-year period preceding the date of enactment of this Act, causing catastrophic destruction to homes, infrastructure, and valuable Federal, State, and private lands. More than 1,000,000,000 acres of land across the United States are at risk of wildfire, including approximately 117,000,000 acres of Federal land that have been identified as high or very high risk for wildfire potential.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6ebfe4553b0d43289c3dd43bffee1336"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Forest Service, the Bureau of Land Management, the National Park Service, the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, and the Bureau of Indian Affairs collectively employ more than 18,700 wildland firefighters to combat wildfires across millions of acres of public and private lands each year, while thousands more workers and volunteers serve as State, local, and contract wildland firefighters.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide473839928024c8c91f26e5132591778"><enum>(3)</enum><text>As the wildland-urban interface expands, wildfires increasingly find their way out of the backcountry and into the backyards of communities across the United States. Wildland firefighters are evolving their skillsets, tactics, and strategies to address the growing threat of wildfire in the 21st century.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8442269603ba4f5da990ec5f53d09370"><enum>(4)</enum><text>While the protection of life and property remains a top priority, wildland firefighters also have an important role in responsible forest management and conservation. Wildland firefighters perform prescribed burns and other forest management activities, including timber harvests, contribute to healthy forests, and reduce catastrophic wildfire risk.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfecdda904b614794926a6f4da075a6bb"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Each wildland firefighter is specialized and trained to work in dynamic and extraordinarily dangerous environments. Wildland firefighters routinely work long days while on a 2-week rotation, often sleeping in inhospitable conditions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idca261a88d5f24fc2a0bc5cd39f2c54ef"><enum>(6)</enum><text>According to the Forest Service, firefighters generally work 16-hour days while fighting a fire, and they typically exceed 2,500 operational hours in a 6-month period.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id33985047a12e431eb64e4421b437b686"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Wildland firefighter crews are all-hazards frontline emergency responders that use any means necessary to protect life and property while responding to floods, hurricanes, pandemics, and acts of terrorism.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida15d9dcdeecd4a15b25116a7a3882f6e"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Engine and hand crews, the primary firefighting workforce, come in varying sizes and modules that can be tailored to fit the specific needs and terrain obstacles that each fire presents.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9094d5ff7d04474594b84f9c554d74e2"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Interagency hotshot crews are highly skilled mobile hand crews with elite knowledge about fire suppression tactics.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc55d887d04594e3da093179e30bd5224"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Pilots and aerial fire suppression crews take to the skies with air tankers and helicopters to drop water and fire retardant, supporting decision-makers on the ground.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7516cd10ee164f519e661b4339d1c8c2"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Aerially delivered firefighters, including helitack crews and smokejumpers, exit helicopters and jump from planes into remote and difficult-to-reach areas, providing quick and targeted fire suppression and emergency medical short-haul extraction. These fire personnel provide oversight and direct action on initial and extended attack incidents. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5764f414a2ce4b36844748dfe8ecc101"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Wildland firefighters in the United States also answer the call to fight wildfires internationally. During the record-setting fires in Australia in 2020, the United States sent 362 firefighters to help. During Canada’s historic 2023 fire season, more than 2,000 Federal wildland firefighters answered the call.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id46a08817aaf84a5db1fe90dc334b7c56"><enum>(13)</enum><text>As of the date of enactment of this Act, the United States maintains mutual assistance and cooperation agreements for wildland firefighting efforts with Canada, Mexico, Australia, New Zealand, and Portugal.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf32ccde78fc64d4b9d896fa4629ec2e6"><enum>(14)</enum><text>The increases in the severity of wildfires and in annual fire season active months have also increased the demand for wildland firefighters and associated employees. Recruitment and retention of wildland firefighters has been a national issue for many years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4c6936ca4076466a824e87c7d92a2d7b"><enum>(15)</enum><text>Wildland firefighters put their lives on the line to keep the people of the United States safe, and some pay the ultimate sacrifice to do so. Between January 1, 2019, and January 1, 2025, 98 wildland firefighters have lost their lives fighting fires. Acute and secondary effects from wildfire, such as wildfire smoke exposure, are directly linked to tens of thousands of firefighter and civilian deaths each year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id08ded41488cb4dfe9d9229ed51ab8ebe"><enum>(16)</enum><text>June 30 to July 6 of each year is recognized as a Week of Remembrance to honor the fallen wildland firefighters who sacrificed their lives to protect the wildlands of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd1ae6712d69a4d07967695726e14c127"><enum>(17)</enum><text>National Wildland Firefighter Day is held annually on July 2 to recognize all who are devoted to wildland firefighting.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2ec07172748b4262965e17e52c2fcad7"><enum>(18)</enum><text>The exemplary efforts of wildland firefighters are deserving of recognition, and it is appropriate and proper to honor those who have previously served, as well as current and future firefighters. Wildland firefighters showcase principles of duty, respect, and integrity in every aspect of service. Each firefighter exhibits strength, resiliency, and grit to protect the forests, grasslands, and communities of the United States. Wildland firefighters do not shy away from dangerous situations, but instead risk life and limb to help others. The outstanding accomplishments of these brave individuals continue an unparalleled legacy of public service. </text></paragraph></section><section id="id18fba0afd1044057874cde6c2c33cf5b"><enum>3.</enum><header>Congressional Gold Medal</header><subsection id="id42001f702e9a4f41bede326794b06209"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Presentation Authorized</header><text>The Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President pro tempore of the Senate shall make appropriate arrangements for the presentation, on behalf of Congress, of a single gold medal of appropriate design in honor of wildland firefighters, collectively, in recognition of their strength, resiliency, sacrifice, and service to protect the forests, grasslands, and communities of the United States.</text></subsection><subsection id="ida9d91f673dec4559a6e525cc47c8a4cb"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Design And Striking</header><text>For purposes of the presentation described in subsection (a), the Secretary of the Treasury (referred to in this Act as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall strike a gold medal with suitable emblems, devices, and inscriptions, to be determined by the Secretary, in consultation with the National Interagency Fire Center.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="id6e002519d5e6423e8594a947f3bb4359"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Disposition of Medal</header><paragraph id="id385cf7ea679e4e0bb69d68b26e4146bf"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In General</header><text>Following the presentation of the gold medal under subsection (a), the gold medal shall be given to the National Interagency Fire Center, where the gold medal shall be displayed, as appropriate, and made available for research.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6d033015b9c5415e8215475f14999b7c"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that the National Interagency Fire Center should ensure that the display and availability of the medal described in paragraph (1) be at appropriate locations, particularly locations associated with wildland firefighters.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcd1d3d8f7e0f4c4d9aee26104a64e4a5"><enum>4.</enum><header>Duplicate medals</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary may strike and sell duplicates in bronze of the gold medal struck under section 3, at a price sufficient to cover the costs thereof, including labor, materials, dies, use of machinery, and overhead expenses. </text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="idf0df83ace5c74a788728b94b76aa8e7d"><enum>5.</enum><header>Status of medals</header><subsection id="id0724e22e6611407bac15aa835fb46f56"><enum>(a)</enum><header>National Medals</header><text>The medals struck under this Act are national medals for purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/51">chapter 51</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code. </text></subsection><subsection id="idf6ec081ebd4e4350aefcd5b2ea5dd54d"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Numismatic Items</header><text>For purposes of sections 5134 and 5136 of title 31, United States Code, all medals struck under this Act shall be considered to be numismatic items.</text></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="id87823a0e3d4a4b47932dacc0ddaa3c0f"><enum>6.</enum><header>Authority to use fund amounts; proceeds of sale</header><subsection id="iddd31f993e3564a78b6bac06a596d7e14"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority To Use Fund Amounts</header><text>There is authorized to be charged against the United States Mint Public Enterprise Fund such amounts as may be necessary to pay for the costs of the medals struck under this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="id0534decbdfcb490a9da30409e07c460f"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Proceeds of Sales</header><text>Amounts received from the sale of duplicate bronze medals authorized under section 4 shall be deposited into the United States Mint Public Enterprise Fund.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

