<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-EHF25294-XG7-80-2GM"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1356 IS: Trading and Investing with Clear Knowledge and Expectations about Risk Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1356</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250408">April 8, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S404">Mr. Scott of Florida</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to require national securities exchanges to identify issuers that are consolidated variable interest entities, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Trading and Investing with Clear Knowledge and Expectations about Risk Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>TICKER Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idD01CFD77FD9C49018D3039CA08BD59B3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that— </text><paragraph id="idEBF11E464A4D4A0FA635B05E8BE12FFB"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">variable interest entities based in foreign jurisdictions, including the People’s Republic of China, pose a specific and significant risk to investors in the United States, including because investors that purchase shares of those entities— </text><subparagraph id="id0FFC5FC1506746039AABD4716CED73FB"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have no equity or direct ownership interest; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id76C59845AC3B4941B3FC6F106A0AC5ED"><enum>(B)</enum><text>lack legal recourse; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id49168C3073694CB19C893FA2B93DC012"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">investors in the United States should more clearly be made aware of the risk described in paragraph (1) in a transparent, easily accessible, and standardized manner that is recognizable to all persons that have invested, or seek to invest, in entities that are described in that paragraph and are listed on exchanges in the United States, such as through clearly visible warning indicators on ticker symbols and other company symbols used by those exchanges.</text></paragraph></section><section id="id18D9D9DB3C2A45BD8D8CADB623846614"><enum>3.</enum><header>Identification of risk with respect to certain entities</header><subsection id="idB75D312F93514592BD6B9739A01B7E9E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section— </text><paragraph id="idF07F9E29EE574967AFBD79845EB445E9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the terms <term>broker</term>, <term>dealer</term>, <term>exchange</term>, and <term>security</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 3(a) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78c">15 U.S.C. 78c(a)</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9086A7E0F3DC425BB35BCE2EA7023288"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>Commission</term> means the Securities and Exchange Commission;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7260866B27704C5181EBA54BF5FD620E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>covered entity</term> means a consolidated variable interest entity; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1FF180CFC16C47EC95DEB6E9F47C36B4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the term <term>national securities exchange</term> means an exchange that is registered as a national securities exchange pursuant to section 6 of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78f">15 U.S.C. 78f</external-xref>), as amended by subsection (b) of this section; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idF851DB4C329C495095EB5CA0C564E7F3"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the term <term>variable interest entity</term> has the meaning given the term under generally accepted accounting principles.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0C0F42BC8C9F4C72AD23C2BDB4043A08"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><paragraph id="id4AE6944D28444EB490CCD956837E834F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>National securities exchanges</header><subparagraph id="id0B7FEE870C87424E85A94070F25A0F41"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 6(b) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78f">15 U.S.C. 78f(b)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="id8FE40D2B901C491CB5AAA30DA4BA7501" act-name=""><paragraph id="idE9FB5FF731FF4B7F9B61CADFE544A89E"><enum>(11)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idF72B4C8E7E9A4CE4A37414C4CA99B247"><enum>(A)</enum><text>In this paragraph, the term <term>covered entity</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3(a) of the <short-title>Trading and Investing with Clear Knowledge and Expectations about Risk Act</short-title>.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id84ED0C0F76A54A5F904B60B37BE4F067" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The rules of the exchange require the identification of each covered entity, the securities of which are listed on the exchange, as a covered entity in the symbol for the covered entity used on the exchange.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id08BD80DD109E4FDEAE36B594C0F63F84"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Effective date; applicability</header><text>The amendment made by subparagraph (A) shall—</text><clause id="idE9240A9EAC5449279D8F040855EF7D72"><enum>(i)</enum><text>take effect on the date that is 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act; and</text></clause><clause id="id85F6E1B3E29E4A56A3248B1E5333A0D2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>apply with respect to a covered entity, the securities of which are listed on a national securities exchange on or after the date that is 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id3A8900B4AB274ED4BBCCBDBAE01E18F5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Brokers and dealers</header><text>Beginning not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Commission shall require brokers and dealers to provide warnings to investors investing in covered entities that those investors may lack legal recourse with respect to such an investment.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

