<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H827DCA7E21114A1E9A35A7B060FA565E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1275 IH: Focus on Learning Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1275</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250212">February 12, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000821">Mr. Westerman</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001212">Mr. Stauber</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001234">Ms. Morrison</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001121">Mr. Crow</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Surgeon General to conduct a study regarding the use of mobile devices in elementary and secondary schools, and to establish a pilot program of awarding grants to enable certain schools to create a school environment free of mobile devices.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H2DF248CB643F4155B48EAA2E49D1E7D5" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="H73AFC39028EF43D49306C4C2E051AE57"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Focus on Learning Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H780EEC1AD0F14A608A71E7255C53ADA5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H33B09DDA405942A8AC36CFF4585DE963"><enum>(1)</enum><header>ESEA terms</header><text>The terms <term>child with a disability</term>, <term>elementary school</term>, <term>English learner</term>, <term>local educational agency</term>, and <term>secondary school</term> have the meaning given those terms in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>). </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H5EC6E637CB4F44ACA1173FBCA8D50585"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Mobile device</header><text>The term <term>mobile device</term> means any personal mobile telephone or other portable electronic communication device with which a user engages in a call or writes or sends a message or any device in which the user plays a game or watches a video, except that such term does not include school-issued devices. </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD8BEDC0CDCD9476CA2FC0E409B151645"><enum>(3)</enum><header>School environment free of mobile devices</header><text>The term <term>school environment free of mobile devices</term> means an elementary school or secondary school in which mobile devices of students are kept in a secure container that is controlled by a school administrator.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H158E4025C9F74AAEB006B9651D5D5E69"><enum>(4)</enum><header>School hours</header><text>The term <term>school hours</term> means regular school hours for instruction, including lunch periods, free periods on school grounds, and time between classroom instruction.</text></paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="HB7AE5AFF8FD64606BC1B2C7E1A0B09A1"><enum>3.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Study</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2F1F93BBA9FE4AB98D129B5F36B80E7D"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Surgeon General, in consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, shall complete a study regarding the use of mobile devices in elementary schools and secondary schools nationwide, including—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE879AFF312D24F44821A12274AD6A166"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the impact of such use on—</text><subparagraph id="H8EC0206E1907486484C32236BB2D42F7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>student learning and academic achievement;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBDD5A1AD310447D3BB58C1931E316DEA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>student educational outcomes and engagement;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1A367A8493674EBEB362C7BFC36AA667"><enum>(C)</enum><text>student mental health;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H279367439FCF4F32B9BD86CCC43402FE"><enum>(D)</enum><text>classroom instruction; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H183DFC0E3CB54D00A426D4FD665DF4C1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>school climate and student behavior; and </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1E09A4675AEF4E88B7677DD631A322C3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an analysis of data collected from participating schools in the pilot program under section 4. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HF16EB19CEDD34C628AD308F90E9BA897"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>The Surgeon General, in consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, shall submit a report to Congress containing the results of the study conducted under subsection (a), and shall make such report publicly available. </text></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H323C5DDE636940CA9975A5F4EE43EAD8"><enum>4.</enum><header>Pilot program</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H399A54815AE14ACE9A68DE3F2CE7447C"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Program established</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Education, in consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, shall establish a pilot program, through which the Secretary of Education, in consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, shall award grants to local educational agencies to enable participating schools served by such agencies (referred to in this section as <quote>participating schools</quote>) to purchase secure containers and install lockers in order to create a school environment free of mobile devices.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H845AA85EAACE44199FAE4DF8C29805B4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text>A local educational agency desiring to participate in the program under this section shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may reasonably require, including—</text><paragraph id="HD17A2D38BCD84B11805305EC921F47A5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an assurance that such local educational agency will identify and select participating schools in a manner that engages the students, parents, educators, principal, school leaders, and specialized instructional support personnel, of such schools; </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE32B178DCA7B4C4395E82C9799F30416"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an assurance that each participating school will have a communication system (which may be mobile devices) allowing teachers, administrators, and staff to communicate with each other and with local emergency responders;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCA33698F4D3F47E6A13224C4701F7128"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an assurance that each participating school will have a clear process for students to be able to contact their parents;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF9EE0DC68E80402F84B74228091AF050"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the policy of each participating school on mobile device use during school hours as of the date of the application; and </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H33E851EEC15C4D7693BBC1ECDACA66B7"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of what each participating school's new policy on mobile device use during school hours will be upon beginning participation in the pilot program under this section. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H352644E88C1C441F83FAAD2BE784568A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Selection</header><text>The Secretary of Education, in consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, shall select local educational agency applicants for participation in the pilot program based on the Secretary of Education's determination that the applicant’s participation will likely yield helpful information relevant to testing a school environment free of mobile devices.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H73557322F4BC4BEEB31A0F5CEBD9E449"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Exemptions</header><text>Participating schools may, while maintaining a school environment free of mobile devices, allow exemptions such that mobile devices may be used during school hours—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H64198E632FA2408A8E093AD0FC7CB880"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to monitor or treat health conditions;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD83AF56B22D24A54AA9A5FE66DD51A39"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by students who are children with disabilities; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD89530C3FC37404C99563C01F833A42B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by students who are English learners for translation purposes.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H368F940C79F94BC481EDE71325DED43A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Parental notification</header><text>Each local educational agency that applies for participation in the pilot program under this section shall—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC151157E0A9346CFB68B42A6BAA2DDB1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">notify parents of students enrolled in elementary schools and secondary schools that are served by the agency and that may become participating schools—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA5F0302C91D14B09AEEE51E18CF2C1CE"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not less than 30 days before submitting an application under this section; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7F340351F98C47F096C2961B53DBA999"><enum>(B)</enum><text>upon receipt of a grant award under this section; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H44E299AFC5504FB78A1CF4E60809046C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>solicit feedback from such parents before applying for the grant about the local educational agency's desire to implement a school environment free of mobile devices.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2C3E1BAAEB5D4811BADEBBBC13385A9A"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Administrative expenses</header><text>The Secretary of Education and the Secretary of Health and Human Services may use not more than 2 percent of the amounts made available to carry out this section for administrative expenses, data collection, and carrying out the study required under section 3. </text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1F85A26568454A08898302F8B19139FF"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section, $5,000,000 for the period of fiscal years 2025 through 2029. </text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

