<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-RIL25317-HSJ-X0-KH1">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 155 ATS: Honoring the life and legacy of the Honorable Mia Bourdeau Love, former Representative for the State of Utah.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress>
<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num>S. RES. 155</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20250405" legis-day="20250404">April 5 (legislative day, April 4), 2025</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S431">Mr. Curtis</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S346">Mr. Lee</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">Honoring the life and legacy of the Honorable Mia Bourdeau Love, former Representative for the State of Utah.</official-title>
</form>
<preamble>
<whereas><text>Whereas Ludmya “Mia” Bourdeau was born in Brooklyn, New York, on December 6, 1975, to Haitian immigrant parents Jean Maxime and Marie Bourdeau and was raised in a family steeped in faith, freedom, compassion, and hard work;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the values instilled in Representative Love by her parents inspired a life of service, excellence, and courage;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas Representative Love graduated from the University of Hartford, and upon moving to Utah, began a lifetime of public service and civic leadership;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas she was elected to the Saratoga Springs City Council and then made history in 2009 as the first African-American woman elected mayor in the State of Utah;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas, in 2014, Representative Love was elected to the United States House of Representatives, becoming the first Black Republican woman ever elected to Congress;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, in Congress, she was a principled voice for the people of Utah, for fiscal responsibility, for opportunity, and for the enduring values of family, faith, and freedom;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas, throughout her life, she used her voice not only to shape policy and uplift civic discourse, but also to comfort friends, encourage family, and testify about her faith;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, after her time in Congress, Representative Love continued to serve the public as a political commentator, author, and national thought leader, fostering more honest, civil, and inclusive conversations on the pressing issues of the day;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas Representative Love’s deep faith as a member of the Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints was central to her life, and her leadership and commitment to discipleship shaped her every endeavor;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas she was a devoted wife to Jason Love, a loving mother to Alessa, Abigale, and Peyton, and a joyful grandmother to Mera, and built her life around strengthening her family, encouraging their dreams, and walking beside them with grace and strength;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas Representative Love inspired countless women, immigrants, public servants, and young leaders to find their voice, stand firm in their values, and believe they too could lead;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas even in the face of illness and adversity, Representative Love demonstrated faith, courage, authenticity, and resolve, recording her memoir <quote>Qualified</quote> after her cancer diagnosis to ensure her voice would continue to uplift her family and the people of the United States; and</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas Representative Love passed away on March 23, 2025, leaving behind a legacy of integrity, inspiration, and purpose that will resound for generations: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble> <resolution-body id="H2D11367FA28D4475A2B81EE4755F1335"> <section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That—</text>
<paragraph id="id8a3e0d6e9a304f60b85eb2167b058ef4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Senate—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id89100ff05e9e4e16a321eb0803c02786"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has heard with profound sorrow and deep respect the announcement of the death of the Honorable Mia Bourdeau Love, former Representative for the State of Utah; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="ida3681e6d37884ba2bdadf31ef0ca30f6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>respectfully requests that the Secretary of the Senate—</text> <clause id="id4ab37ef1fd0f4360aefdf10ff44dc4fe"><enum>(i)</enum><text>communicate this resolution to the House of Representatives; and</text></clause>
<clause id="id9b3aa1e33afd45a9854c63eb51571c83"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>transmit an enrolled copy of this resolution to the family of the Honorable Mia Bourdeau Love; and</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="id34e54e6bd87140988ea6814f3504c38f"><enum>(2)</enum><text>when the Senate adjourns on the date of the adoption of this resolution, it stands adjourned as a further mark of respect to the memory of the Honorable Mia Bourdeau Love.</text></paragraph></section>
</resolution-body>
</resolution> 


