<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB2B354544D9A4AE99F5DF4362A1FE0DB" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>106 HR 3525 IH: Regulatory Accountability Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3525</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250520">May 20, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000134">Ms. Van Duyne</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To improve agency rulemaking, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF23C973322804523B81697D1769EB88E" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="HCEDF7C6B5F9B42798E95E11989FD8CA6"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Regulatory Accountability Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H09B91CAB630B46A48CA75A85F36216E3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 551 of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="HCAF665813FFF42DC9C6768A3667A2AA3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (5), by striking <quote>rule making</quote> and inserting <quote>rulemaking</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H768C2E3ED3FA4FA889B54506FD73076D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (6), by striking <quote>rule making</quote> and inserting <quote>rulemaking</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3088A50129CD469BAEFE244DA575817A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (13), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4A1262AB80C143839DB167944C0F420C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in paragraph (14), by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H75FE36AEE1C94FA5ABD21A13A21166B7"><enum>(5)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H71C2E94513B24F169EC2126F8E905A34"><paragraph id="H31801C79C858448D91411E88F3DC1496"><enum>(15)</enum><text><term>guidance</term> means an agency statement of general applicability that—</text><subparagraph id="H2718C44D38B345E783C5055A178EAF81"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is not intended to have the force and effect of law; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD944675B608E413A86DB7E3A60B0EFDA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>sets forth a policy on a statutory, regulatory, or technical issue or an interpretation of a statutory or regulatory issue;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA661F2531A07446B82C654E04CE1F6A6"><enum>(16)</enum><text><term>major guidance</term> means guidance that the Administrator finds is—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H05D331F26F804B35AB427CCCAF3257B0"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">likely to lead to—</text><clause id="H444D5DDBF70D4F20ABE44D761348BD20"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any annual effect on the economy;</text></clause><clause id="HE501F6592C5D4E4DAF0CA8619D9B961E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a major increase in costs or prices for consumers, individual industries, Federal, State, local, or Tribal government agencies, or geographic regions; or</text></clause><clause id="H05B73AE93ED2432E855D866BAB948C6E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>significant adverse effects on competition, employment, investment, productivity, innovation, public health and safety, or the ability of United States-based enterprises to compete with foreign-based enterprises in domestic and export markets; or</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF513FF2ABBB545A994549973E3F3A110"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a departure from a prior statutory interpretation or agency policy;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFFEB45758C364BF3A243CDDCA567448B"><enum>(17)</enum><text><term>major rule</term> means any rule that the Administrator determines is likely to—</text><subparagraph id="HAFE57668042B474CB6820007AB433EFD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>cause an annual effect on the economy of $100,000,000 or more;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1C1051FCCD804DF18AC4213676A9281F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>cause a major increase in costs or prices for consumers, individual industries, Federal, State, local, or Tribal government agencies, or geographic regions; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBF0FDE15043345AB92E505B3685BBE53"><enum>(C)</enum><text>cause significant adverse effects on competition, employment, investment, productivity, innovation, public health and safety, or the ability of United States-based enterprises to compete with foreign-based enterprises in domestic and export markets; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8DDD7C3CAD504B2982846F9BA52B6F92"><enum>(D)</enum><text>raise novel legal or policy issues arising out of legal mandates;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD4AFA9AAD0C14C5281139F271848985F"><enum>(18)</enum><text><term>Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs</term> means the office established under section 3503 of title 44 and any successor to that office; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0C6406832F584A61A3DA87EC96081766"><enum>(19)</enum><text><term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="H0C7783E74D7B4D1B8AA4F25593CF5978"><enum>3.</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 553 of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="HCE36C424E6014233BD29A2B0366B7A33"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the section heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="USC">Rule making</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="USC">Rulemaking</header-in-text></quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA7150EBA9BAB42DD93ABD054E244D138"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>(a) This section applies</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H22B020E72AEF4762850DACC951C956EE"><subsection id="H98B280999B7C4234983688F48A02A0D2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>This section applies</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H0BEAD6FDEE1645EEA2A0BB9BCB3146B9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking subsections (b) through (e) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBED36B940B124563A981C2A3E51AAB9C"><subsection id="H35831DD6A871412EAD4D1EDF5AEF2AA5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rulemaking considerations</header><text>In a rulemaking, an agency shall consider, in addition to other applicable considerations, the following:</text><paragraph id="H6B7945482F5348E1BE9FA82AAE4D4936"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The legal authority under which a rule may be proposed, including whether rulemaking is required by statute or is within the discretion of the agency.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H347D18F442E84A6EBF33948AF38E9080"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The nature and significance of the problem the agency intends to address with a rule.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD01AFFE54983427C906FDAFF38E1450D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Whether existing Federal laws or rules have created or contributed to the problem the agency may address with a rule and, if so, whether those Federal laws or rules could be amended or rescinded to address the problem in whole or in part.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD873FAC43C354647BE952879772666E5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A reasonable number of alternatives for or to a new rule, with the consideration of 3 alternatives presumed to be reasonable, that—</text><subparagraph id="HCC9D328E3459466B98342A5C8298DE01"><enum>(A)</enum><text>meet the objectives of the statutory provision on which the rulemaking relies, including substantial alternatives or other responses identified by the agency or by interested persons; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H644FAB5FB3BD4A4A82C8BB54C4599A57"><enum>(B)</enum><text>consider not only mandating particular conduct or manners of compliance, but also—</text><clause id="H07B2647168494F14BB5ADB2E022F8203"><enum>(i)</enum><text>specifying performance objectives;</text></clause><clause id="H646E0C9BFB774ECAAF3DCB7092CBBF1E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>establishing economic incentives, including marketable permits, to encourage desired behavior;</text></clause><clause id="H6DD3F88F201846B8A784CD3CD3E82C6A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>establishing disclosure requirements that will provide information upon which choices can be made by the public; or</text></clause><clause id="HC23762309D774D13AB75605FC610BF76"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>adopting other means of meeting the objectives of the statutory provision on which the rulemaking relies without mandating particular conduct or manners of compliance.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3A5C592DE9B84FC4AB71A90C916AD6A6"><enum>(5)</enum><text>For any major rule, unless prohibited by law, the potential costs and benefits associated with potential alternative rules and other responses considered under paragraph (4), including quantitative and qualitative analyses of—</text><subparagraph id="H13FBC53B15FD45C6AE3BFBCAD044B015"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the direct costs and benefits, with costs and benefits measured over equal time periods;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5BD1196D50B0491790468D9ED0C377FD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the nature and degree of risks addressed by the rule and the countervailing risks that might be posed by agency action; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H83A3880FB39E4FE19AE95244FED2DC17"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to the extent practicable, the cumulative costs and benefits and the indirect costs and benefits, and an analysis of the effects that the rule is anticipated to have on entities that purchase products or services from, sell products or services to, or otherwise conduct business with entities to which the rule will apply.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H68DB4EEE3313427993EF4A91455F0B4B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Notice of proposed rulemaking</header><paragraph id="H7F9759FC872D4019B0BED09A6E64A58B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If an agency determines that the objectives of the agency require the agency to issue a rule, the agency shall—</text><subparagraph id="H77F52742A66741A093F698BFD8A4AC59"><enum>(A)</enum><text>submit a notice of proposed rulemaking to the Administrator for review;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB6F0B058C0BB4C30A8B3BCDDAE23D253"><enum>(B)</enum><text>refrain from publishing the notice until the Administrator concludes the review under subparagraph (A); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6724DA744D4E42A4B594FFE7236AFFA1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>at the conclusion of review by the Administrator, publish a notice of proposed rulemaking in the Federal Register, which shall include—</text><clause id="H70EF188546E1448A8CB0A11266F9542C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a statement of the time, place, and nature of any public rulemaking proceedings;</text></clause><clause id="H051D97B615D4467AB9E0B9EEAB06359A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a reference to the legal authority under which the rule is proposed, including the specific statutory provision on which the rulemaking relies;</text></clause><clause id="H74463E8E73A742E2A8BB2555EC3347F8"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the text of the proposed rule;</text></clause><clause id="H28E22F157F3C4862841ED67E163297B5"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a summary of information known to the agency concerning the considerations described in subsection (b); and</text></clause><clause id="HA2F296C7ED3B4F27810D38A816994624"><enum>(v)</enum><text>where otherwise consistent with applicable law, for any major rule—</text><subclause id="H440D2FDFB77B4D9B8932E3AC0896CF64"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a reasoned preliminary explanation regarding how—</text><item id="H36EED741848741EAABE2B5DB8FF79895"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the proposed rule meets the objectives of the statutory provision on which the rulemaking relies; and</text></item><item id="HC361E68E0A5B4D0D9E20E4F003207F8D"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the benefits of the proposed rule justify the costs;</text></item></subclause><subclause id="H7A7E7F51C98748B2A74CBF02821435AD"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a discussion of—</text><item id="HDA8108428A07402CADA6E4E6D8437EB9"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the costs and benefits of alternatives considered by the agency under subsection (b)(4);</text></item><item id="H1CFDD8740C6D41BF91814C3585430730"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>whether the alternatives considered by the agency under subsection (b)(4) meet the objectives of the statutory provision on which the rulemaking relies; and</text></item><item id="HED0381B14B274B95842C04E6220B23AD"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>the reasons why the agency did not propose an alternative considered by the agency under subsection (b)(4); and</text></item></subclause><subclause id="HAB5E6CF9C5E5428F83F22468F59E484D"><enum>(III)</enum><text>a solicitation of public comment, including on all issues and alternatives discussed under subclauses (I) and (II) and subsection (k)(1)(A).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDE996F435ABE4E8B83E0C5300D079A34"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Accessibility</header><subparagraph id="HB5465D2520014CC192EBE59F6146FAD7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than the date on which an agency publishes a notice of proposed rulemaking under paragraph (1), all studies, models, scientific literature, and other information developed or relied upon by the agency, and actions taken by the agency to obtain that information, in connection with the determination of the agency to propose the rule that is the subject of the rulemaking shall be placed in the docket for the proposed rule and made accessible to the public.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5E912D1A4C9A455998F620E5791A6FEE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Information controlled by nongovernmental person</header><text>With respect to any information to which a nongovernmental person holds a legal right to prohibit or limit reproduction, distribution, or public display, the information shall be—</text><clause id="H6E7CBC539E564F3F98493A448C2E1883"><enum>(i)</enum><text>placed in the docket through citation or incorporation by reference, including a specification of the identity of the nongovernmental person who holds a legal right to prohibit or limit reproduction, distribution, or public display of the information and the means by which a member of the public may request a full copy of the information from that holder; and</text></clause><clause id="H0B91C907964244BBA6C6B706E527A55D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>considered made accessible to the public after a placement described in clause (i), provided that the nongovernmental person who holds a legal right to prohibit or limit reproduction, distribution, or public display of the information makes the information reasonably available upon request in a timely manner to any member of the public who requests a copy of the information.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB9B549CDC80149BBAF1C67C9FAE7AA71"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Subparagraphs (A) and (B) shall not apply with respect to information that is exempt from disclosure under section 552(b).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7801F75F2C904464933916DF3E71F744"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Information quality</header><text>If an agency proposes a rule that rests upon scientific, technical, or economic information, the agency shall—</text><subparagraph id="H07026C3037E74C2285968D2D687FEE0D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>propose the rule on the basis of the best publicly available scientific, technical, or economic information; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H420AA1ECF6D34E6EA25BFB56F9E36CAB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to the maximum extent practicable, use that information in compliance with the guidelines issued under section 515 of the Treasury and General Government Appropriations Act, 2001 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/106/554">Public Law 106–554</external-xref>; 114 Stat. 2763A–154).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE2A7BC130DA748BB85500B1CFF066F79"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Public comment</header><subparagraph id="H2E8DCF1AB93B41DD8258F20E9EEB9FCA"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>After publishing a notice of proposed rulemaking under paragraph (1), an agency shall provide interested persons an opportunity to participate in the rulemaking through the submission of written material, data, views, or arguments with or without opportunity for oral presentation, except that when a rule is required by statute to be made on the record after opportunity for an agency hearing, sections 556 and 557 shall apply.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6CBC6BF0A9F9450E97C225337E56149B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Timeline</header><clause id="H260FC1C0A59A49BA86A0E0589374F6A4"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (C), an agency shall provide not less than 60 days, or, with respect to a proposed major rule, not less than 90 days, for interested persons to submit written material, data, views, or arguments under subparagraph (A).</text></clause><clause id="H390835E5931047F6BDDFFC842A787983"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Adequate review period</header><text>If a proposed rule relies on information placed in the docket through citation or incorporation by reference as described in paragraph (3)(B), the comment period required under clause (i) shall be adequate to allow interested persons to receive and review that information to inform their submission.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA59AE8F2ACA645588807044FA4B593C8"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Responsive comment period for major rules</header><text>With respect to a proposed major rule, an interested person who made a submission under subparagraph (A) during the comment period under subparagraph (B) with respect to the rule may, during the period beginning on the day after the date on which that comment period closes and ending on the date that is 30 days after that day, respond to any other submission made by any other interested person under subparagraph (A) during the initial comment period.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD051A9EB7697461380AA4B2D85089CA4"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Accessibility</header><text>All comments and responses submitted under this paragraph shall be promptly placed in the docket and made accessible to the public.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB67B10888F6743DBB8684ED98F0AF204"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Change of classification after publication of notice</header><text>If, after an agency submits for review and publishes the notice of proposed rulemaking required under paragraph (1), a proposed rule is determined to be a major rule, the agency shall—</text><subparagraph id="HA74F80D132AE43AEB77325A541F8FACA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>publish a notice in the Federal Register with respect to the change of the classification of the rule; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H257EEF6873164F2386CB582461A1400A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>allow interested persons an additional opportunity of not less than 30 days to comment on—</text><clause id="HCEC06C98CEB84EA592C8E93CDBBBF7EF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the rule; and</text></clause><clause id="HB2F5017E92FD4AAAA317CF549C177BB3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the change of the classification of the rule.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFCE96F781D674536BBEE4D52AFF64CD6"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Requirements for certain communications</header><subparagraph id="H2DDC6677123F44CE823C747B24C757F4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (C), after an agency publishes a notice of proposed rulemaking required under paragraph (1), or after an agency publishes a notice of initiation of rulemaking under subsection (d)(1)(B), the agency, and any individual acting in an official capacity on behalf of the agency, may not communicate, and a person who receives Federal funds from the agency may not use those funds to communicate, through written, oral, electronic, or other means, to the public with respect to the proposed rule in a manner that—</text><clause id="H1C8194460FFF4671888C700960E65CD8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>directly advocates, in support of or against the proposed rule, for the submission of information that will form part of the record for the proposed rule;</text></clause><clause id="HC671387DD82248C5A265D950111F86E0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>appeals to the public, or solicits a third party, to undertake advocacy in support of or against the proposed rule; or</text></clause><clause id="HC96633BB5C9A4898B8E2DA0DCD46F0CC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>is directly or indirectly for the purpose of publicity or propaganda within the United States in a manner that Congress has not authorized.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H07049C7816694B91867B37EC25BEE12E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Ex parte communications</header><text>All ex parte communications between an agency and any stakeholder that may benefit from a proposed rule of the agency shall be published in the Federal Register with the notice of proposed rulemaking for that rule.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2AC21C4EC8014752834BA049212D7815"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The prohibition under subparagraph (A) shall not apply to a communication that requests comments on, or provides information regarding, a proposed rule in an impartial manner.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC642B2B69EF14227AE58F33F161EC035"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Advanced notice of proposed rulemaking for major rules</header><paragraph id="H221318BD7C4F4C97B91AA765806DB707"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Notice for major rules</header><text>When an agency determines to initiate a rulemaking that may result in a major rule, the agency shall—</text><subparagraph id="HB60789150D914EFD99A858BF64880077"><enum>(A)</enum><text>establish an electronic docket for that rulemaking, which may have a physical counterpart; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H83F7988F613A4024AD8D41B06D27E062"><enum>(B)</enum><text>publish an advanced notice of proposed rulemaking in the Federal Register, which shall, at a minimum—</text><clause id="H4670CAACA11D48258A1526E34E90FD81"><enum>(i)</enum><text>briefly describe the nature and significance of the problem the agency may address with the rule, including any data or categories of data that the agency has identified as relevant or that the agency intends to consult for the rule; </text></clause><clause id="H65F80DE1ADCD434685D93AA1458B6476"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>refer to the legal authority under which the rule would be proposed, including the specific statutory provision that authorizes the rulemaking;</text></clause><clause id="H52B21293FCB348708CB5980CEB4F766D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>invite interested persons to propose alternatives and other ideas regarding how best to accomplish the objectives of the agency in the most effective manner;</text></clause><clause id="H0E792CF60B1F49B99CB67F93D7D3370B"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>solicit written data, views, and arguments from interested persons concerning the information and issues identified in the advanced notice; </text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H625BE201EAEA48A49796D98278CE7A9F"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide for a period of not less than 30 days for interested persons to submit written data, views, and arguments described in clause (iv) to the agency; and</text></clause><clause id="H167743D249F4441FB7105FAFC9CA153E"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>appear in the Federal Register not later than 90 days before the date on which the agency publishes a notice of proposed rulemaking for the rule.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFDEBF466DAD94918B5D59D8EE4498FC1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Accessibility</header><text>All information provided to the agency under paragraph (1) shall be promptly placed in the docket and made accessible to the public, unless the information—</text><subparagraph id="H5624B0EDBAA04059BAE898C502E68626"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is information to which the submitter does not hold a legal right to authorize disclosure; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBF5B88C8193248A3B5CA487E01AAF920"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is exempt from disclosure under section 552(b).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFE6176BCEF214CF58E6ECFE9F69EE461"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>With respect to the alternatives and other ideas proposed under paragraph (1)(B)(iii)—</text><subparagraph id="HE94B094FE1C743018871C7002D947A33"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the alternatives and other ideas are for the benefit of—</text><clause id="H3E3F76D1A3A54C89946B9FFAFDAC154E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the agency receiving the alternatives and other ideas; and</text></clause><clause id="HE31EF3391B7B4CDF870D35AA2D6A384C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the public; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC8E51966661142D99672A9B2585E1B02"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the agency receiving the alternatives and other ideas may respond to the alternatives and other ideas.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H41B739E3C3BF4D3382C3ABBCC0C0ABB0"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Timetable</header><subparagraph id="H63AC15B9DEBD467F897BFEC4592B5529"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>After considering any written material submitted by interested persons under paragraph (1), if an agency determines to proceed with a rulemaking for a major rule, the agency proposing the rule shall establish a timetable for the rulemaking that—</text><clause id="H3C6F9935A7B74E57AF7B7C70CC8083EA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>contains intermediate completion dates for actions of the agency, including—</text><subclause id="HD2688B6DA3BE4313A058C482E87FB207"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the anticipated date on which the agency shall publish the notice required under subsection (c)(1) with respect to the rule; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H7E109B38FB174459B1A32C330E8F52B6"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the duration of the comment period required under subsection (c)(4), including the date on which the comment period shall end; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HCF9699760F50490FA0D8559DEBF8C55D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>includes a final completion date for actions by the agency.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB1C47489DA544ABDBCE47D3E87D1F973"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>The timetable required under subparagraph (A) shall be published in the electronic docket established under paragraph (1)(A) with respect to the rulemaking.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H117866F330194D8C9E5A153E08141D08"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Consideration of factors</header><text>In establishing the timetable required under subparagraph (A), an agency shall consider relevant factors, including—</text><clause id="HFAD4325DD0154D108ACDA6A2D9230650"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the size and complexity of the rulemaking;</text></clause><clause id="H9E751A2ACA7F44C28167B183ED5F34DF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the resources available to the agency;</text></clause><clause id="HF24BA7614A5F432AB3A21B2135BBF67C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the national significance of the rulemaking; and</text></clause><clause id="H3E4F5F03AEE24C3CA0DCD3B671919F0E"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>all statutory requirements that govern the timing of the rulemaking.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H36326496B3DD4BFBAF2E8CB30D6A29C8"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Report required</header><clause id="HD978B9D4DD60435C88DB2BD48A8D9C8D"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An agency that fails to meet an intermediate or final completion date for an action established under subparagraph (A) shall submit to Congress and the Director of the Office of Management and Budget a report regarding why the agency failed to meet the completion date.</text></clause><clause id="H13E7C085757C43F49758D82043283440"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Contents; publication in Federal Register</header><text>A report submitted under clause (i) shall—</text><subclause id="H8E24D9532EC34C5E9AA42839A1ACCDB6"><enum>(I)</enum><text>include an amended timetable for the rulemaking; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HCEAB7463756444D2BB19A845CB0785F8"><enum>(II)</enum><text>be published—</text><item id="H2EB0B17AF773456E83C135486CA0E8E8"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>in the Federal Register; and</text></item><item id="HE163ED8F0811403C8852BAB09EBE2877"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>in the electronic docket established under paragraph (1)(A) with respect to the rulemaking.</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H97087EB4BE2448A3AEB85F6082192DDD"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Changes to intermediate dates published in electronic docket</header><text>If an agency changes an intermediate completion date for an action of the agency established under subparagraph (A)(i), the agency shall publish in the electronic docket established under paragraph (1)(A)—</text><clause id="H7E12B9C93B5C4BFC9658E6AB802C4867"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the updated completion date for the action; and</text></clause><clause id="HD9FF3F30C3F64B719265C3C8E6A10DC3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a brief explanation regarding the reason for the change to the completion date.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0EB4EFBC748A486EBF31B040CA1A5F5B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Notice of determination of other agency course</header><subparagraph id="H0890F32902DD4F6F844BA7E21EF23C9C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If, after publishing the notice required under paragraph (1), an agency determines not to issue a major rule, the agency shall—</text><clause id="HB44A0A77D3B1451F8C9EE63EA7F3B3F6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>publish a notice of determination of other agency course; and</text></clause><clause id="HE2063C9F85A4475C8CF523D9BCDAD7D0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if the agency intends to issue a rule, comply with the procedures required under subsection (c).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDB85C4525A6E4E8EB01261DF534E2D50"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>A notice of determination of other agency course published under subparagraph (A)(i) shall include—</text><clause id="HAB75281B351D442A940F1C61E95B34F9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a description of the alternative response the agency has determined to adopt; and</text></clause><clause id="H7BA0CA6822EA490EB6788747E5ADB471"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if the agency intends to issue a rule, any information required under subsection (c).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1835B3BC57F149E6B1F2397B1C04CAC5"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Final rules</header><paragraph id="H7D504BD1B12A4CC582E172B82CF744F9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Net benefits of major rule</header><subparagraph id="H79CB836E6AF34564BC4D54B48C41AEA2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), in a rulemaking for a major rule, an agency shall adopt the alternative considered under subsection (b)(5) that maximizes net benefits, taking into consideration—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5F8FFED4841440898E402A365765A1AC"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">cumulative regulatory cost burdens; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0F19809EDB93486C96B7F654C64A4385"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">only benefits that arise within the scope of the statutory provision that authorizes the rulemaking. </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD38B7E6F2FF74E48A4B5D75DCDFA1EFA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>In a rulemaking for a major rule, an agency may adopt an alternative other than as required under subparagraph (A) only if—</text><clause id="HD560C1BC24BC4A8C9B093778CAA575C5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Administrator approves the adoption by the agency of the alternative; and</text></clause><clause id="H441F4D236EBB48C084B545F180DBC78A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the alternative is adopted to—</text><subclause id="HD4570744B1C6479EA18FACED23BD44AA"><enum>(I)</enum><text>account for costs or benefits that cannot be quantified, including costs or benefits related to constitutional or civil rights, provided that the agency identifies all such costs and benefits and explains why those costs and benefits justify the adoption of the alternative; or</text></subclause><subclause id="HA3F789C6450F4B0FBF79C02236E55CC4"><enum>(II)</enum><text>achieve additional benefits or cost reductions, provided that the agency—</text><item id="H35BBE7C6690841568B610685082194B3"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>identifies—</text><subitem id="HC27327F7BD024C189BABD64CD010F4A5"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>all such additional benefits and the associated costs of those benefits; and</text></subitem><subitem id="H865C3352314D40E1A3A522E80724A5D1"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>all such cost reductions and the associated benefits of those cost reductions; and</text></subitem></item><item id="H78F58816F379472CA45E30729D7532BD"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>explains why—</text><subitem id="H966C413031C243E2B6EE687F6C56DBC0"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>the additional benefits justify the additional costs; or</text></subitem><subitem id="HC59E58C6224944F7A647A469BB81EDDB"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>the additional cost reductions justify any benefits foregone.</text></subitem></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7F74CBE531EF4E13A61BAA596781C1A4"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in subparagraph (A) may be construed to preclude an agency from including in an alternative adopted pursuant to such subparagraph changes made as a result of agency analysis or review performed under chapter 6 of this title.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4D144935C2F248C69AE91E523B7E0513"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Publication of notice of final rulemaking</header><text>After submitting a final rule to the Administrator for review and obtaining a certification from the Administrator that the review has concluded, the agency shall publish a notice of final rulemaking in the Federal Register, which shall include—</text><subparagraph id="H6EEAD867615143C3BD82301E559AE16D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a concise, general statement of the basis and purpose of the rule and a reference to the legal authority under which the rule is made, including the specific statutory provision on which the rulemaking relies;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H007F11D146644E1B911EC072C061D89A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a reasoned determination by the agency regarding the considerations described in subsection (b);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1E56CBB66DC14715B3096A9E60C3B808"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a response to each significant issue raised in the comments on the proposed rule; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H943A48A64C3548859F862055B00C7FA7"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the internet address of a summary of not more than 100 words in length of the proposed rule, in plain language, that shall be posted on the internet website under section 206(d) of the E-Government Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/44/3501">44 U.S.C. 3501</external-xref> note) (commonly known as regulations.gov); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDBA53395AC4F4EDDA1ACCE4561AA5B40"><enum>(E)</enum><text>with respect to a major rule, a reasoned determination by the agency that—</text><clause id="H9DCF6EC284AD4A2AAFCA8C9B0ECB1AA5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the benefits of the rule advance the relevant objectives of the statutory provision on which the rulemaking relies and justify the costs of the rule; and</text></clause><clause id="H9A3B807515B74BF38FCE562B14848203"><enum>(ii)</enum><subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H39207C56712247FBA3AA07D900CC8D77"><enum>(I)</enum><text>no other alternative considered would achieve the relevant objectives of the statutory provision on which the rulemaking relies in a manner that more greatly maximizes net benefits as required under paragraph (1)(A); or</text></subclause><subclause id="H13A3BB919C8645E18FEB1AEBD6C8E6CE" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the adoption by the agency of a more costly or less costly rule complies with paragraph (1)(B).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEAECE7A26AAA44C7A08D26A260CF832B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Information quality</header><text>If an agency rulemaking rests upon scientific, technical, or economic information, the agency shall—</text><subparagraph id="H7E9DC042F8B34652BDBEF89A8D073E32"><enum>(A)</enum><text>adopt a final rule on the basis of the best reasonably available scientific, technical, or economic information; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF961EF82195B4709BF62FD96D2625068"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to the maximum extent practicable, use that information in compliance with the guidelines issued under section 515 of the Treasury and General Government Appropriations Act, 2001 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/106/554">Public Law 106–554</external-xref>; 114 Stat. 2763A–154).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEC8685BD07874BF990FFCA370A9B8FA3"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Accessibility</header><subparagraph id="H2E5A9DCB9A934047B9754ABE29057ACA"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than the date on which an agency publishes a notice of final rulemaking under paragraph (2), all studies, models, scientific literature, and other information developed or relied upon by the agency, and actions taken by the agency to obtain that information, in connection with the determination of the agency to finalize the rule that is the subject of the rulemaking shall be placed in the docket for the rule and made accessible to the public.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H50C3D054E1D649EE8FB3A46A17CADFB6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Information controlled by nongovernmental person</header><text>With respect to any information to which a nongovernmental person holds a legal right to prohibit or limit reproduction, distribution, or public display, the information shall be—</text><clause id="H686A3E1730BC43FDB089512592E3E180"><enum>(i)</enum><text>placed in the docket through citation or incorporation by reference, including a specification of the identity of the nongovernmental person who holds a legal right to prohibit or limit reproduction, distribution, or public display of the information and the means by which a member of the public may request a full copy of the information from that holder; and</text></clause><clause id="H79A8F3C1C90C43339F45DCC2B5459687"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>considered made accessible to the public after a placement described in clause (i), provided that the nongovernmental person who holds a legal right to prohibit or limit reproduction, distribution, or public display of the information makes the information reasonably available upon request in a timely manner.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H277AB0322A1C4EA6B896D7D2C88C8377"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Subparagraphs (A) and (B) shall not apply with respect to information that is exempt from disclosure under section 552(b).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5AD84A9D1E8D4BE2BA028D18AEBB5807"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Rules adopted at the end of a Presidential administration</header><subparagraph id="HFA73B77F2CAF42B9AE0D388F95A46CC9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>During the 60-day period beginning on a transitional inauguration day (as defined in section 3349a), with respect to any final rule that had been placed on file for public inspection by the Office of the Federal Register or published in the Federal Register as of the date of the inauguration, but which had not become effective by the date of the transitional inauguration day, the agency issuing the rule may, by order, delay the effective date of the rule for not more than 90 days for the purpose of obtaining public comment on whether—</text><clause id="H1FD12D04BB2148E68D32C81C55D40600"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the rule should be amended or rescinded; or</text></clause><clause id="HAB3F65661450405DB642EF5E5692841F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the effective date of the rule should be further delayed.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3B4577D3C36F4CFCB619DD59A64DC196"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Opportunity for comment</header><text>If an agency delays the effective date of a rule under subparagraph (A), the agency shall give the public not less than 30 days to submit comments.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H91CF6651B9DA4950920D6714D227BE8C"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Citation to Congressional record</header><text>Not later than 30 days after a final rule described in subparagraph (A) goes into effect, or, in the case of a final rule described in subparagraph (A) that is a major rule, not later than the date on which the final rule goes into effect, the agency promulgating the rule shall publish in the Federal Register a citation to the Congressional Record for the submission required under section 801(a)(1)(A) of this title with respect to the final rule.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H079567003AE54CEC81BDF7EF4CA5506F"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Applicability</header><paragraph id="H0578EC61EFFB44B3855E4F56CDEE1774"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Primacy of certain rulemaking considerations and procedures in other federal laws</header><subparagraph id="H013AAC3EAD454979B1ABB13EB7198A6F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>If a rulemaking is authorized under a Federal law that requires an agency to consider, or prohibits an agency from considering, a factor in a manner that is inconsistent with, or that conflicts with, the requirements under this section, for the purposes of this section, the requirement or prohibition, as applicable, in that other Federal law shall apply to the agency in the rulemaking.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF05B3ED8DCB041F0BF24784FAB60CB81"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Procedural requirements</header><text>If a rulemaking is authorized under a Federal law that requires an agency to follow or use, or prohibits an agency from following or using, a procedure in a manner that is duplicative of, or that conflicts with, a procedural requirement under this section, for the purposes of this section, the requirement or prohibition, as applicable, in that other Federal law shall apply to the agency in the rulemaking.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H424D1F5F048C4FA996BF24D2892BF12B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Guidance and rules of organization</header><text>Except as otherwise provided by law, this section shall not apply to guidance or rules of agency organization, procedure, or practice.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H747966BC2D1446CB8475F7A1BF7B64B7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exceptions for good cause</header><subparagraph id="H82CD24C7708D48E9A254DFE16534CABA"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Finding of good cause</header><clause id="H9C66C20BCE404725BEDC9695DA8AE1AD"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If an agency for good cause finds that compliance with subsection (c), (d), or (e)(2)(B) before issuing a final rule is unnecessary, impracticable, or contrary to the public interest, that subsection shall not apply and the agency may issue the final rule or an interim final rule, as applicable, under subparagraph (B) or (C).</text></clause><clause id="HAA4D204B056A49E9B03160F07A4EC6A3"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Incorporation of good cause finding</header><text>If an agency makes a finding under clause (i), the agency shall include that finding and a detailed statement with respect to the reasons for that finding in the final rule or interim final rule, as applicable, issued by the agency.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF3D4AEB48B34449FB01D57BBC3D33C50"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Direct final rules</header><clause id="HFD1036CC6D2F48BEA1938B78B6FE7BA6"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in clause (ii), if an agency makes a finding under subparagraph (A)(i) that compliance with subsection (c), (d), or (e)(2)(B) before issuing a final rule is unnecessary, the agency shall, before issuing the final rule—</text><subclause id="H85F63846FE81466DB8900821A5D6DAF5"><enum>(I)</enum><text>publish in the Federal Register the text of the final rule, the brief statement required under subparagraph (A)(ii), and a notice of opportunity for public comment;</text></subclause><subclause id="HFFE24306C37F4443B5E5F6C49BAD56AA"><enum>(II)</enum><text>establish a comment period of not less than 30 days for any interested person to submit written material, data, views, or arguments with respect to the final rule; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HC4D8AC0DD8FF41D5B49B9717A18B2FE6"><enum>(III)</enum><text>provide notice of the date on which the rule will take effect.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H767416839735435BB832DC53E67B7A69"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>An agency that made a finding described in clause (i) may choose not to follow the requirements under that clause if the agency determines that following the requirements would not expedite the issuance of the final rule.</text></clause><clause id="H8A9154276C9C4ACA95971DDE52E7DC18"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Adverse comments</header><text>If an agency receives significant adverse comments with respect to a rule during the comment period established under clause (i)(II), the agency shall—</text><subclause id="HA14EB5514CBB4BA781CEA2ACED8C0594"><enum>(I)</enum><text>withdraw the notice of final rulemaking published by the agency with respect to the rule; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H6ECF66F484AA43259ACD53D51D36C06E"><enum>(II)</enum><text>complete rulemaking in accordance with subsections (c) through (e), as applicable.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H19A8C7586B174117AFA9153EDC1EEAC9"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Interim final rules</header><clause id="HF9B655756B684E0D903AB9F5A95C6D38"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If an agency for good cause finds that compliance with subsection (c), (d), or (e)(2)(B) before issuing a final rule is impracticable or contrary to the public interest, the agency shall issue an interim final rule by—</text><subclause id="H3A7321B5487941A1A9A24380D86E7F74"><enum>(I)</enum><text>publishing the interim final rule and a request for public comment in the portion of the Federal Register relating to final rules; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H558A233961F04440AE759A6236A4688B"><enum>(II)</enum><text>providing a cross-reference in the portion of the Federal Register relating to proposed rules that requests public comment with respect to the rule not later than 60 days after the rule is published under subclause (I).</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H06AC31459F8143A386E5273D57C9CA8A"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Interim period</header><subclause id="H30BC9269C2704797ADDFDA6882E49FD1"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date on which an agency issues an interim final rule under clause (i), the agency shall—</text><item id="H69F0BA01E1C14BA0849842B80A3AF51B"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>rescind the interim rule;</text></item><item id="HCF930013668D4103A00D0877ECAC4E30"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>initiate rulemaking in accordance with subsections (c) through (e); or</text></item><item id="H7022C3701F6C48558B950D3FB30D62FE"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>take final action to adopt a final rule.</text></item></subclause><subclause id="H8D0B9CAEAAF647E7BE295DC9D9F3BCF9"><enum>(II)</enum><header>No force or effect</header><text>If, as of the end of the 180-day period described in subclause (I), an agency fails to take an action described in item (aa), (bb), or (cc) of that subclause, the interim final rule issued by the agency shall have no force or effect.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0B0F080675044431BE2B618065E2FD39"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Exemption for monetary policy</header><text>This section shall not apply to a rulemaking or to guidance that concerns monetary policy proposed or implemented by the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System or the Federal Open Market Committee.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE2B1C98BABC24A10BAF4671070A1050B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to modify, alter, or abridge exclusive rights held pursuant to title 17.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H532A873EDD7F4ED8837E78A5D0294B64"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Date of publication</header><text>A final rule, a direct final rule described in subsection (f)(3)(B), or an interim final rule described in subsection (f)(3)(C) shall be published not later than 30 days (or, in the case of a major rule, not later than 60 days) before the effective date of the rule, except—</text><paragraph id="H0964804FC84F44B8BA4E7A9DE144EB27"><enum>(1)</enum><text>for guidance; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H581C94A6EC8946129DE29F0AEE65D1F5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>as otherwise provided by an agency for good cause and as published with the rule.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7C4CDF1877A34C539DD72C6F72CFD7EB"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Right To petition and review of rules</header><text>Each agency shall—</text><paragraph id="H06604D802E70490FBED5270B4EBB7F30"><enum>(1)</enum><text>give interested persons the right to petition for the issuance, amendment, or repeal of a rule; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HED5F6F1F00484D2D9BC26F861EBEE5A3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>on a continuing basis, invite interested persons to submit, by electronic means, suggestions for rules that warrant retrospective review and possible modification or repeal.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0E9CD667DE954F42B4374B8CD02C41A6"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Rulemaking guidelines</header><paragraph id="H80DEDA7D291B4D269392F0DBA267EB76"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Assessment of rules</header><subparagraph id="H382DA16EE1A84293AEDB5F03D0E7FCC3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator shall establish guidelines regarding rulemaking as follows:</text><clause id="HE93A7C8FECC74EFF96CBED9BBAB8F70B"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Identification of need for rules</header><text>Guidelines setting forth how needs for rulemaking should be identified, including—</text><subclause id="H578E994B536B40BEB9B0340E8A29F8A2"><enum>(I)</enum><text>whether rulemaking is made necessary by compelling public need, such as material failures of private markets or public institutions to protect or improve the health and safety of the public, the environment, or the well-being of the public; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H4B1BCE79967B4ECE89BA69EABD32D489"><enum>(II)</enum><text>whether rulemaking needs could be lessened by reliance on potential State, local, Tribal, or regional regulatory action or other responses that could be taken in lieu of agency action.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H6A068996A4124EDB8D6DF6B07C4294DF"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Assessment of rules</header><text>Guidelines setting forth how the assessment, including the quantitative and qualitative assessment, of proposed and final rules should occur, including how to determine—</text><subclause id="H65ED10208A884AAC9233C7D638E3A242"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the costs and benefits of proposed and final rules and alternatives to them, including quantifiable and non-quantifiable costs and benefits;</text></subclause><subclause id="H91F688F17AB747C3977BAE24A5C69250"><enum>(II)</enum><text>whether proposed and final rules maximize net benefits;</text></subclause><subclause id="HDC0EB2CD4FBA42D1BD6187A9747C3C20"><enum>(III)</enum><text>estimated impacts on jobs, wages, competition, innovation, rural populations, and low-income populations;</text></subclause><subclause id="H1AB3F41048704BB6BFC1E528E69979AF"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>other economic issues that are relevant to rulemaking under this section or other sections of this part; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H1BD17298DE864ABB80FD9124C56A7D1F"><enum>(V)</enum><text>risk assessments that are relevant to rulemaking under this section and other sections of this part.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H51F4AC81F94E43BF966CB8A4C96F4A31"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Numbers of alternatives</header><text>Guidelines regarding when it may be reasonable to consider in a rulemaking more alternatives than the number presumed to be reasonable under subsection (b)(4).</text></clause><clause id="H5CAB53968E9049D8A01CC2E5702B7046"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Adoption of alternatives for major rules</header><text>Guidelines regarding when it may be appropriate, in a rulemaking for a major rule, to adopt an alternative final rule under subsection (e)(1)(B).</text></clause><clause id="HF71894BB8F364053B7DA916C6A634D6B"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Administrator review</header><text>Guidelines regarding the efficient submission and review of proposed and final rules under subsections (c)(1) and (e)(2).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFD60BD44DF3549558F63A0415DC7C40F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Agency analysis of rules</header><clause id="HC3FAC8509F1242789D845E7552360CBF"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The rigor of the cost-benefit analysis required or recommended by the guidelines established under subparagraph (A) shall be commensurate, as determined by the Administrator, with the economic impact of a rule.</text></clause><clause id="HD28ED27D60DE43DE8E1D839CBF07B6A9"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Risk assessment guidelines</header><text>Guidelines for a risk assessment described in subparagraph (A)(iv) shall include criteria for—</text><subclause id="H5D07F250BCE046CCABB47975EBA00D85"><enum>(I)</enum><text>selecting studies and models;</text></subclause><subclause id="H61B58646D32A4B33AF172BD57899E994"><enum>(II)</enum><text>evaluating and weighing evidence; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H9D9F19C10A804A15A0F0FB11EA3271A1"><enum>(III)</enum><text>conducting peer reviews.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H72FDEB908B0B4240B74922D786953F7F"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Updating guidelines</header><text>Not less frequently than once every 10 years, the Administrator shall update the guidelines established under subparagraph (A) to enable each agency to use the best available techniques to identify, quantify, and evaluate the need for rulemaking and present and future benefits, costs, other economic issues, and risks as objectively and accurately as practicable.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAED790120C4347279F507C413FF0DA82"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Simplification of rules</header><subparagraph id="HD5467A1944914E8A91A490C62DCE820F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Issuance of guidelines</header><text>The Administrator shall issue guidelines to promote coordination, simplification, and harmonization of agency rules during the rulemaking process.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H564A18ACDD0B45719CD1172B6F5F6067"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The guidelines issued by the Administrator under subparagraph (A) shall advise each agency to—</text><clause id="HEF07715922B14DC4A150056AAD3E2C0C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>avoid rules that are inconsistent or incompatible with, or duplicative of, other regulations of the agency and those of other agencies; and</text></clause><clause id="H3EA3C53A06524176BC86B7B60EB58CAC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>draft the rules of the agency to be simple and easy to understand, with the goal of minimizing the potential for uncertainty and litigation arising from the uncertainty.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA3EABADC052445C7951FEBAF967497AC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Consistency in rulemaking</header><subparagraph id="H8E198519D86E46118A82F8A27CCF78DB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To promote consistency in rulemaking, the Administrator shall issue guidelines to ensure that rulemaking conducted in whole or in part under procedures specified in provisions of law other than those under this section conform with the procedures set forth in this section to the fullest extent allowed by law.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEFBC7734C1204A96A34740EBCD5E3191"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Agency adoption of regulations</header><text>Each agency shall adopt regulations for the conduct of hearings consistent with the guidelines issued under this paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCDE9398E4E8040E2A7F571F07C8DDB41"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Agency guidance; procedures To issue major guidance; authority To issue guidelines for issuance of guidance</header><paragraph id="H0C1E5354CE8D48BABFE8244483043CE8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Agency guidance shall—</text><subparagraph id="HC5A6F16AF12B44B58CC4513ECDCA8523"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not be used by an agency to foreclose consideration of issues as to which the guidance expresses a conclusion;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0C88C372908448689DB60480AE686DF5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>state that the guidance is not legally binding by including the phrase <quote>The contents of this document do not have the force and effect of law and do not, of themselves, bind the public or the agency. This document is intended only to provide clarity to the public regarding existing requirements under the law or agency policies.</quote> on the first page of the document; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0207D33239B4484B95C6F5CCFC588091"><enum>(C)</enum><text>be published in a single location on an internet website designated by the Director at the time the guidance is issued.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5941E980FF10423F9C56200FD28F24F7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Procedures to issue major guidance</header><text>Before issuing any major guidance, an agency shall make and document a reasoned determination that—</text><subparagraph id="H550CE02AA1E14081935D2A3F87D9D360"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such guidance is understandable and complies with relevant statutory objectives and regulatory provisions; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD08AE7CAC0D54FB09E0A7A2A6B3205D0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identifies the costs and benefits, including all costs and benefits to be considered during a rulemaking as required under subsection (b), of requiring conduct conforming to such guidance and assures that such benefits justify such costs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H646DE54DFBED4D678816C54D5528DB89"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Issuance of updated guidance</header><subparagraph id="H89F9ED1E40F94189A703DFCDE05886B4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator shall issue updated guidelines for use by agencies in the issuance of guidance documents.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7A0605B592FF4552A288CB889E45A12F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The guidelines issued by the Administrator under subparagraph (A) shall advise each agency—</text><clause id="H7FBEC1B31F6C4072B16CEB9A2B9FF8FA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>not to issue guidance documents that are inconsistent or incompatible with, or duplicative of, other rules of the agency and those of other agencies;</text></clause><clause id="H0CF3877D36A34008AE8FADEA60882416"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to draft the guidance documents of the agency to be simple and easy to understand, with the goal of minimizing the potential for uncertainty and litigation arising from the uncertainty; and</text></clause><clause id="HB2AAC820A44245AE9F587432BDF76872"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>how to develop and implement a strategy to ensure the proper use of guidance by the agency.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFC469440E8564C18A12463D5B79A65FC"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Major rule frameworks</header><paragraph id="HB880F577DC8D417F8C5508D9EB565D03"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Beginning on the date that is 180 days after the date of enactment of this subsection, when an agency publishes in the Federal Register—</text><subparagraph id="HFE4DB5F8F26541FABF498F7284D95C44"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a proposed major rule, the agency shall include a potential framework for assessing the rule, which shall include a general statement of how the agency intends to measure the effectiveness of the rule; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1F200B86CB0148B98FFD22B4C4599BE9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a final major rule, the agency shall include a framework for assessing the rule under paragraph (2), which shall include—</text><clause id="H27DAE8BB33504E1D9FF6B5F8A0EDB200"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a clear statement of the regulatory objectives of the rule, including a summary of the expected and predicted benefits and costs of the rule;</text></clause><clause id="HE0A0FF6B804D4AAC8A32F29531F02862"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the methodology by which the agency plans to analyze the rule, including metrics by which the agency can measure—</text><subclause id="H790B01AFC10F4085BA452E1556176709"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the effectiveness and benefits of the rule in producing the regulatory objectives of the rule; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HB36DCC87571C4B9AB3DFDB97567B78B8"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the impacts, including any costs, of the rule on regulated and other impacted entities;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H675815C6214A472AA7BC5F01CE30E096"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a plan for gathering data regarding the metrics described in clause (ii) on an ongoing basis, or at periodic times, including a method by which the agency will invite the public to participate in the review process and seek input from other agencies; and</text></clause><clause id="H4C25A3BE5FA14D7CB39BA920DA0FC27E"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a specific timeframe, as appropriate to measure the full impact of the rule but not more than 10 years after the effective date of the rule, under which the agency shall conduct the assessment of the rule in accordance with paragraph (2)(A).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD0836485734B4CC7B2E07D8EF0726B9C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Assessment</header><subparagraph id="HEDD8DE2A268649B2970B42C3D65F2A0A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each agency shall assess the data collected under paragraph (1)(B)(iii), using the methodology set forth in paragraph (1)(B)(ii) or any other appropriate methodology developed after the issuance of a final major rule to better determine whether the regulatory objective was achieved, with respect to the rule—</text><clause id="H4F745EAF52D2452D8965BCCB2FE9B8B8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to analyze how the actual benefits and costs of the rule may have varied from those anticipated at the time the rule was issued; and</text></clause><clause id="HF183D726DDCA4F6485A4FF638FA16197"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to determine whether—</text><subclause id="HF97C4E7C28C04F90AEC154176265CAB1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the rule is accomplishing the regulatory objective of the rule;</text></subclause><subclause id="HBF87814DA7EE40E5AD310B3B33024016"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the rule has been rendered unnecessary, taking into consideration—</text><item id="H301A45F5BBC849E683095009C603C406"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>changes in the subject area affected by the rule; and</text></item><item id="HEB816893855F4C4789AF16AEA9F2F7CF"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>whether the rule overlaps, duplicates, or conflicts with—</text><subitem id="H8819A24A8E7847059407E247DC28C20B"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>other rules; or</text></subitem><subitem id="H37C371FE62724B22B96BF09BE8F83BCE"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>to the extent feasible, State and local government regulations;</text></subitem></item></subclause><subclause id="HAA68547E76C44F9792FFE73A177EC878"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the rule needs to be modified in order to accomplish the regulatory objective; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HE87AC11939414EDC919AF3CED9D7663C"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>other alternatives to the rule or modification of the rule could better achieve the regulatory objective while imposing a smaller burden on society or increase cost-effectiveness, taking into consideration any cost already incurred.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H685BF65A23B644059C1130FA7512033E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Different methodology</header><text>If an agency uses a methodology other than the methodology under paragraph (1)(B)(ii) to assess data under subparagraph (A), the agency shall include as part of the notice required to be published under subparagraph (D) an explanation of the changes in circumstances that necessitated the use of that other methodology.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2261C602EF7B407E97E373D8204A53B4"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Subsequent assessments</header><clause id="H78BB5B8DD1F446AEA391079636F093A7"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in clause (ii), if, after an assessment of a major rule under subparagraph (A), an agency determines that the rule will remain in effect with or without modification, the agency shall—</text><subclause id="HC57C0D6741324CB1A5357BC442289CC8"><enum>(I)</enum><text>determine a specific time, as appropriate to the rule and not more than 10 years after the date on which the agency completes the assessment, under which the agency shall conduct another assessment of the rule in accordance with subparagraph (A); and</text></subclause><subclause id="H01FA78F28CD44657BDD0B4A8272CFF12"><enum>(II)</enum><text>if the assessment conducted under subclause (I) does not result in a repeal of the rule, periodically assess the rule in accordance with subparagraph (A) to ensure that the rule continues to meet the regulatory objective.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H9DBE2373BE3E467E83F53A6CA6B1CF70"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Exemption</header><text>The Administrator may exempt an agency from conducting a subsequent assessment of a rule under clause (i) if the Administrator determines that there is a foreseeable and apparent need for the rule beyond the timeframe required under clause (i)(I).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF5B08831AE92450CBD99A11542FFC6D4"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date on which an agency completes an assessment of a major rule under subparagraph (A), the agency shall publish a notice of availability of the results of the assessment in the Federal Register, including the specific time for any subsequent assessment of the rule under subparagraph (C)(i), if applicable.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H464594BEBB10418280867ED587B3BE5B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>OIRA oversight</header><text>The Administrator shall—</text><subparagraph id="H047988E1EF7B4B2B8C75DA0BF963B0B3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>issue guidance for agencies regarding the development of the framework under paragraph (1) and the conduct of the assessments under paragraph (2)(A);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6587F3977F4A45439218A530381F141B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>oversee the timely compliance of agencies with this subsection;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBE487315C4FE494DB063F3E767929882"><enum>(C)</enum><text>ensure that the results of each assessment conducted under paragraph (2)(A) are—</text><clause id="H156464947E6D4B5AAE6DF5891535507D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>published promptly on a centralized Federal website; and</text></clause><clause id="H64A24D506DB04502A72844EC43825269"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>noticed in the Federal Register in accordance with paragraph (2)(D);</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEB7D8BD6298549B8A441CA67C135F605"><enum>(D)</enum><text>ensure that agencies streamline and coordinate the assessment of major rules with similar or related regulatory objectives;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1306343D5C774759A39156F8FD5A0C38"><enum>(E)</enum><text>exempt an agency from including the framework required under paragraph (1)(B) when publishing a final major rule if the Administrator determines that compliance with paragraph (1)(B) is unnecessary, impracticable, or contrary to the public interest, as described in subsection (f)(3)(A)(i); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0881964398BE4834A1FCC15B776F0ECC"><enum>(F)</enum><text>extend the deadline specified by an agency for an assessment of a major rule under paragraph (1)(B)(iv) or paragraph (2)(C)(i)(I) for a period of not more than 90 days if the agency justifies why the agency is unable to complete the assessment by that deadline.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0C4FD4BB7F5D4484A7DA4797550F3DEE"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to affect—</text><subparagraph id="HE97E375156194770B6208B2A42FCC456"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the authority of an agency to assess or modify a major rule of the agency earlier than the end of the timeframe specified for the rule under paragraph (1)(B)(iv); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7861AB0C6EC74AA2A41FAE64877450B6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other provision of law that requires an agency to conduct retrospective reviews of rules issued by the agency.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H87DF43B16C024D0F97358E9D8E9E9D14"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Applicability</header><subparagraph id="H8198DBB599DA45E9B9046246938D479F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>This subsection shall not apply to—</text><clause id="H98F2D1E2539947BE8A691CA2EE8386AE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a major rule of an agency—</text><subclause id="H431582D0838A4135A968785EA7683D6E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>that the Administrator reviewed before the date of enactment of this subsection;</text></subclause><subclause id="HDA02A7E4861B430A8393D82D14D4A187"><enum>(II)</enum><text>for which the agency is required to conduct a retrospective review under any other provision of law that meets or exceeds the requirements of this subsection, as determined by the Administrator; or</text></subclause><subclause id="HCC051E3B55574332A11636F1475BDFEE"><enum>(III)</enum><text>for which the authorizing statute is subject to periodic reauthorization by Congress not less frequently than once every 10 years;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H951B32250D1741AD86DD0C552A559051"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>guidance;</text></clause><clause id="HD71794AA5B204919B5D03D61B1CF91D9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>routine and administrative rules; or</text></clause><clause id="HA5052048503E4235A6BAC4A0AE338A7E"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a rule that is reviewed under section 2222 of the Economic Growth and Regulatory Paperwork Reduction Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/3311">12 U.S.C. 3311</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCBA9B309146B4829996D9800F92392DE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Direct and interim final major rule</header><text>In the case of a major rule of an agency for which the agency is not required to issue a notice of proposed rulemaking in response to an emergency or a statutorily imposed deadline, the agency shall publish the framework required under paragraph (1)(B) in the Federal Register not later than 180 days after the date on which the agency publishes the rule.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC568B87219CE46328AC9D389BA88905C"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Recommendations to Congress</header><text>If, under an assessment conducted under paragraph (2), an agency determines that a major rule should be modified or repealed, the agency may submit to Congress recommendations for legislation to amend applicable provisions of law if the agency is prohibited from modifying or repealing the rule under another provision of law.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2807E30C31F347E0A2FC77A0F80A5BA5"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Judicial review</header><subparagraph id="H36EB0412267A4CA795C726B049F79DBD"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Judicial review of agency compliance with this subsection is limited to whether an agency—</text><clause id="H64A7527A3BC4434FAA17B24CBE52E0EA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>published the framework for assessment of a major rule in accordance with paragraph (1); or</text></clause><clause id="HEEB5186C5B0C49339DDA11D2709D4373"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>completed and published the required assessment of a major rule in accordance with subparagraphs (A) and (D) of paragraph (2).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1DBA9F5DD1A2409CB90C6589F00375F7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Remedy available</header><text>In granting relief in an action brought under subparagraph (A), a court may only issue an order remanding the major rule to the agency to comply with paragraph (1) or subparagraph (A) or (D) of paragraph (2), as applicable.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8B67D63D441D48338A01394756884048"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Effective date of major rule</header><text>If, in an action brought under subparagraph (A)(i), a court determines that the agency did not comply, the major rule shall take effect notwithstanding any order issued by the court.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H79D72A59346B4AB0A94D2031FB23CDF1"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Authorities and responsibilities of the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs</header><paragraph id="HB5326529C4CB40B1B541A4791843E158"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator shall provide meaningful guidance and oversight, which may include review by the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs, to ensure that each agency issues rules in accordance with the requirements under this section and other applicable law and do not conflict with the policies or actions of another agency.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9BDC3F092EB147C4A63FC30F3E4CE88A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notification</header><text>If the Administrator determines that a major rule of an agency does not comply with the principles and requirements of this section, is not consistent with other applicable laws, or conflicts with the policies or actions of another agency, the Administrator shall—</text><subparagraph id="HC08F324EBC5F4CACBF0D45F9B13268A5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identify areas of noncompliance;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBF5ED789BC6443398AC512D6CDE911E7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>notify the agency; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE4853BDD02304AD48C86B22B3DC84D64"><enum>(C)</enum><text>request that the agency comply before the agency finalizes the major rule concerned.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H582E7E051E29486289D08922AA74FC34"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Annual statement to Congress on agency compliance</header><text>The Administrator shall submit to Congress, including the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Oversight and Accountability of the House of Representatives, an annual written report that, for the 1-year period preceding the report—</text><subparagraph id="HD77D3EAA3E1C4518A33EF5352B147628"><enum>(A)</enum><text>details compliance by each agency with the requirements of this section that relate to major rules, including activities undertaken at the request of the Administrator to improve compliance; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDB3F0E2121384BBC967CB4477F670D94"><enum>(B)</enum><text>contains an appendix detailing compliance by each agency.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5D96AE92EE1A4D9ABDF7AFA66589A586"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit the scope of the authority of the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs under subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/44/35">chapter 35</external-xref> of title 44, section 515 of the Treasury and General Government Appropriations Act, 2001 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/106/554">Public Law 106–554</external-xref>; 114 Stat. 2763A–154), chapter 8 of this title, or any other law or Executive Order.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="HE64E19D4764A4597A584CC597D7180B8"><enum>4.</enum><header>Scope of review</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 706 of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="H0678BE6A86804E73897AFAEEF315EB48"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the first sentence of the matter preceding paragraph (1), by striking <quote>To the extent necessary</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD143154EBF534806A099A94ACEBA9663"><subsection id="H57FA2FE8367B430CAA45472E2C3A56A3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To the extent necessary</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H4CFF2DE62E924910AB264D31E23EE75C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (a), as so designated—</text><subparagraph id="HFADDE9391E2B43CB81DCAA582D4218BA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H85A5A9429A984DCEAA7EF696FD97C28F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by inserting <quote>, or, when appropriate, remand a matter to an agency without setting aside,</quote> after <quote>set aside</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H80F954090E314075A765A0B3437E2F0D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking the flush text following paragraph (2)(F) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4EBE7E919AC94B16919CC6143F16F4BA"><subsection id="HD998045E3BB54AB39C24F7B018756AF2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Review of entire record; prejudicial error</header><text>In making a determination under subsection (a), the court shall review the whole record or those parts of the record cited by a party, and due account shall be taken of the rule of prejudicial error.</text></subsection><subsection id="H8762802A464D44E9858F07854D1D4D6D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Preclusion of review</header><paragraph id="H5D9061FF56B94994B58832A6A3B59A22"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any action or inaction of the Administrator under subchapter II of chapter 5, except sections 552 and 552a, shall not be subject to judicial review.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFAD277CE7C55481FA8A698BB0FA6344C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>The preclusion of judicial review under this subsection shall not be construed or used to construe any other provision of law to provide any cause of action against the Administrator, except as explicitly provided by law.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9DF203C8950243A2B692785AF7BBFE86"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Review of certain guidance</header><text>Agency guidance that does not interpret a statute or rule may be reviewed only under subsection (a)(2)(D).</text></subsection><subsection id="HDF889FEBB9514D8EB80F9BAF16D07E3A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Agency interpretation of rules</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFE6EB55000C84EF29CF1DDEDBBCA8342"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Standard of review</header><text>Unless expressly required otherwise by statute, the reviewing court shall decide all questions of law de novo, with due regard for the views of the agency administering the statute and any other agency involved in the decision making process. </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H70F6D1C0B4F447AA8006A1DBAE481477"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Weight</header><text>The weight that a reviewing court gives an interpretation by an agency of a rule of that agency shall depend on the thoroughness evident in the consideration of the rule by the agency, the validity of the reasoning of the agency, and the consistency of the interpretation with earlier and later pronouncements.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H0DFEBD0CF27B416998DB2B59778AC4DB"><enum>5.</enum><header>Added definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 701(b) of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="H2011F4547B0645028D0EFDCB5566A56F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)(H), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAA927B8FAF6F4576A5E7A6813E0B9DBE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text><subparagraph id="H2245583A7C0243A7B6387C0394AA210E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting <quote><quote>guidance</quote>,</quote> after <quote><quote>relief</quote>,</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEDBFCB89D26C44A0AFA05C6CF1DC6143"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8BF82B5B7F50417FB2C7F49F97138440"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1AB102024A7A4358990A60AEE78BD3DE"><paragraph id="HBD0CBA8C80524CAE9DC2D5407FC96620"><enum>(3)</enum><text><quote>substantial evidence</quote> means such relevant evidence, including the quality, as a reasonable mind might accept as adequate to support a conclusion in light of the record considered as a whole.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="HF78B04C7A74046D88CB41167790F9010"><enum>6.</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The amendments made by this Act to sections 553, 701(b), and 706 of title 5, United States Code, shall not apply to any rulemaking, as defined in section 551 of title 5, United States Code, as amended by section 2 of this Act, that is pending or completed as of the date of enactment of this Act.</text></section><section id="H1BA26A207355413586F7254BEE19FDB7"><enum>7.</enum><header>Rule of construction with respect to copyrights</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act, or in the amendments made by this Act, may be construed as altering, modifying, or abridging an exclusive right granted under title 17, United States Code.</text></section><section commented="no" id="HC5665A016FAE4043855986D52B20066B"><enum>8.</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendments</header><subsection id="H3A9F7AAC30B642808ADBF8050FFF2B75"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Alaska national interest lands conservation act</header><text>Section 1002(g)(2) of the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/3142">16 U.S.C. 3142(g)(2)</external-xref>) is amended, in the third sentence, by striking <quote>section 706(2)(E)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 706(a)(2)(E)</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H67910DBE73CA4BDF9505F562D7F96DA8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Antarctic marine living resources convention act of 1984</header><text>The Antarctic Marine Living Resources Convention Act of 1984 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/2431">16 U.S.C. 2431 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4917F21FDF3B467CA1F052E4517117A5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 307(b)(1) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/2436">16 U.S.C. 2436(b)(1)</external-xref>), by striking <quote>subsections (b), (c), and (d)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsections (c) and (g)</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDED39BB2DF6441839D22E9F753BBDEE6"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 308(c), in the third sentence, by striking <quote>section 706(2)(E)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 706(a)(2)(E)</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7CD66D9D00BC411A8316663751DA1CE8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Atlantic Tunas Convention Act of 1975</header><text>Section 6(c)(2)(B) of the Atlantic Tunas Convention Act of 1975 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/971d">16 U.S.C. 971d(c)(2)(B)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>subsections (b) and (c) of section 553</quote> and inserting <quote>section 553(c)</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCFD0BD96D610441CA57A7CEE8877F1B1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>CARES Act</header><text>Section 1114 of the CARES Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9012">15 U.S.C. 9012</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>section 553(b)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 553(c)</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC891C1DF9C78480E84E44FE39C73CED3"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Clean Air Act</header><text>Section 307(d)(3) of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7607">42 U.S.C. 7607(d)(3)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>section 553(b)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 553(c)</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H38ADBD80F7FB46999A2BE0062D608CAA"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Congressional accountability act of 1995</header><text>The Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1301">2 U.S.C. 1301 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H31251961A4824097B69EA188A0EFEE46"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 303(b) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1383">2 U.S.C. 1383(b)</external-xref>), in the second sentence, by striking <quote>section 553(b)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 553(c)</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEFCF456CCD0F432DAA488EC3CC936C04"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 304 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1384">2 U.S.C. 1384</external-xref>)—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H782E6950E3B94443A0CD57ED7ADAA570"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (b)(1), by striking <quote>section 553(b)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 553(c)</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H00BA461B2BF64728BE8761540BEE5B6D"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (d)(3), by striking <quote>section 553(d)(3)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 553(g)(2)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8DF17E830DD34977B72F15C5FE85CC79"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subsection (e), by striking <quote>section 553(b)(B)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 553(f)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H572D83A87B8848EFBB4D789B870DD03E"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 409 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1409">2 U.S.C. 1409</external-xref>), in the first sentence—</text><subparagraph id="HA623EC4F21E14D97AA98DB88537C01C7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>section 706(2)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 706(a)(2)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA21804219367467A806D4BC3ABB6E0AF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>section 706(2)(B)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 706(a)(2)(B)</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H73EEA91721C54AF999F8677D7DC59B13"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Consumer product safety act</header><text>Section 9(i) of the Consumer Product Safety Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/2058">15 U.S.C. 2058(i)</external-xref>) is amended, in the first sentence, by striking <quote>section 553(e)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 553(h)</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HFDF2FBE2196C4891A7C1A6EFD2C89C2A"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Deep seabed hard mineral resources act</header><text>Section 302(b) of the Deep Seabed Hard Mineral Resources Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1462">30 U.S.C. 1462(b)</external-xref>) is amended, in the third sentence, by striking <quote>section 706(2)(E)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 706(a)(2)(E)</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF7DB3D23B2224D09B48CC6E549E70A09"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Defense production act of 1950</header><text>Section 709(b)(1) of the Defense Production Act of 1950 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4559">50 U.S.C. 4559(b)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>for not less than 30 days, consistent with the requirements of section 553(b)</quote> and inserting <quote>in a manner consistent with the requirements of section 553(c)</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF125CB3C7AF84E15861CE6ED8D933C57"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Endangered species act of 1973</header><text>Section 4(b)(3) of the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1533">16 U.S.C. 1533(b)(3)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H9E8B9127AD5A4E37918E8DB6266C5121"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), in the first sentence, by striking <quote>section 553(e)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 553(h)</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H297596ABB82D4A05A5B76B43606FDAEF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D)(i), in the first sentence, by striking <quote>section 553(e)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 553(h)</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6EE5EE4BA531419ABC9234781529587E"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Energy Policy Act of 1992</header><text>Section 106(e) of the Energy Policy Act of 1992 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12712">42 U.S.C. 12712</external-xref> note) is amended by striking <quote>(b)(B), and (d)(3)</quote> and inserting <quote>(f)(3), and (g)(2)</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H35C209ADF3DB4C08AACF0574605DA0D1"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Expedited funds availability act</header><text>Section 609(a) of the Expedited Funds Availability Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/4008">12 U.S.C. 4008(a)</external-xref>) is amended, in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by striking <quote>section 553(c)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 553</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8BAF12B5D31D4C3D906EA47BB06A3672"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993</header><text>Section 110(a)(3) of the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/2620">29 U.S.C. 2620(a)(3)</external-xref>) is amended, in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>sections 553(b)(B) and section 553(d)(3)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsections (f)(3) and (g)(2) of section 553</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H98E0564323264F4A81B41822FAD8FD38"><enum>(n)</enum><header>Fastener quality act</header><text>Section 6(b)(3) of the Fastener Quality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/5408">15 U.S.C. 5408(b)(3)</external-xref>) is amended, in the second sentence, by striking <quote>section 706(2)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 706(a)(2)</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2282FC161A5D43BC8BD91217E201EBFE"><enum>(o)</enum><header>Federal food, drug, and cosmetic act</header><text>Section 912(b) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/387l">21 U.S.C. 387l(b)</external-xref>) is amended, in the second sentence, by striking <quote>section 706(2)(A)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 706(a)(2)(A)</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H51652F9DE4C14E25969E9C242C6C84B4"><enum>(p)</enum><header>Federal hazardous substances act</header><text>Section 3 of the Federal Hazardous Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1262">15 U.S.C. 1262</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H6CEF0EF5137E473599737BFB07C9F6A3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (e)—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H987DA6C388D44F97A2DF3BEC7DC2C22D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (1), in the first sentence, by striking <quote>(other than clause (B) of the last sentence of subsection (b) of such section) of title 5 of the United States Code</quote> and inserting <quote>of title 5, United States Code, other than subsection (f)(3) of such section,</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2F1E0561394440EDBC5CD70D7AC11D5E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)(C), by striking <quote>paragraph (2) of section 706</quote> and inserting <quote>section 706(a)(2)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE9A3825082A24B729B2BF37952BF64C4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (j), in the first sentence, by striking <quote>section 553(e)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 553(h)</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF07B79E16F4749A5AEDDC0347AFCC092"><enum>(q)</enum><header>Federal trade commission act</header><text>Section 18(e) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/57a">15 U.S.C. 57a(e)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H3B41052F7A134F38B3CD08553CC15097"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), in the second sentence of the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>section 706(2)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 706(a)(2)</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7590849D143E4573BEBF02DBB41FF3AA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (5)(C), in the second sentence, by striking <quote>Section 706(2)(E)</quote> and inserting <quote>Section 706(a)(2)(E)</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC48E5A4C023B41EFBF2B3509950D8722"><enum>(r)</enum><header>Flammable fabrics act</header><text>The Flammable Fabrics Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1191">15 U.S.C. 1191 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H1EAEEB80AA14407EB6B52B6B45E694F2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 4(k) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1193">15 U.S.C. 1193(k)</external-xref>), in the first sentence, by striking <quote>section 553(e)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 553(h)</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7DA09A600B3E482FABAC612A4661A45E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 16(c)(2) (f<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1203">15 U.S.C. 1203(c)(2)</external-xref>), by striking <quote>section 553(b)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 553(c)</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF7D109E3B73F46A6BE05F7D347336C41"><enum>(s)</enum><header>General education provisions act</header><text>Section 411 of the General Education Provisions Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1221e-4">20 U.S.C. 1221e–4</external-xref>) is amended, in the second sentence, by striking <quote>Notwithstanding the exception provided under section 553(b) of title 5, such</quote> and inserting <quote>Such</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H94099021A6224909A799D4A9193A9954"><enum>(t)</enum><header>High seas fishing compliance act of 1995</header><text>Section 108(d) of the High Seas Fishing Compliance Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/5507">16 U.S.C. 5507(d)</external-xref>) is amended, in the third sentence, by striking <quote>section 706(2)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 706(a)(2)</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9674A266E28841E6878F4FA7663D2936"><enum>(u)</enum><header>Higher Education Act of 1965</header><text>Section 492(b)(2) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1098a">20 U.S.C. 1098a(b)(2)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>section 553(b)(3)(B)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 553(f)(3)</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H87365E370BFD4D3991BC11ECBF912535"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Housing and community development act of 1992</header><text>The Housing and Community Development Act of 1992 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/4501">12 U.S.C. 4501 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HF3E12D016774426884CB7DB80F4C9416"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 643(b)(3) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/13603">42 U.S.C. 13603(b)(3)</external-xref>), in the first sentence, by striking <quote>(notwithstanding subsections (a)(2), (b)(B), and (d)(3) of such section)</quote> and inserting <quote>(notwithstanding subsections (a)(2), (f)(3), and (g)(2) of such section)</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBBC707B4433842ED94A1F229B5763B33"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 685 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/13643">42 U.S.C. 13643</external-xref>), in the second sentence, by striking <quote>(notwithstanding subsections (a)(2), (b)(B), and (d)(3) of such section)</quote> and inserting <quote>(notwithstanding subsections (a)(2), (f)(3), and (g)(2) of such section)</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3666CA1D485A47318BFE18A1463498F7"><enum>(w)</enum><header>Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000</header><text>The Intercounty Adoption Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/14901">42 U.S.C. 14901 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6AB3C56A45484F7EB7928F6181D40C79"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 203(a)(3) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/14923">42 U.S.C. 14923(a)(3)</external-xref>), by striking <quote>Subsections (b), (c), and (d) of section</quote> and inserting <quote>Section 553</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6E5D47DBF9CA4D099CC941868F177CA2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 401(a)(2) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/14941">42 U.S.C. 14941(a)(2)</external-xref>), by striking <quote>Subsections (b), (c), and (d) of section</quote> and inserting <quote>Section 553</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2791E9350E574CFB9F15F440AF3BAD93"><enum>(x)</enum><header>International banking act of 1978</header><text>Section 7(f)(2) of the International Banking Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/3105">12 U.S.C. 3105(f)(2)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>paragraph (2)(F)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (a)(2)(F)</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HFA18E934F61B45328CCB3D3B7F1A4842"><enum>(y)</enum><header>Magnuson-Stevens fishery conservation and management act</header><text>Section 308(b) of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1858">16 U.S.C. 1858(b)</external-xref>) is amended, in the third sentence, by striking <quote>section 706(2)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 706(a)(2)</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2B7959C9AEA54F8689406D5C19B58CBF"><enum>(z)</enum><header>Marine mammal protection act of 1972</header><text>Section 109 of the Marine Mammal Protection Act of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1379">16 U.S.C. 1379</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H67054F1E804F4E2BB08D77E5BED0F5C0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (c)(4), in the first sentence, by striking <quote>section 706(2)(A) through (E) of Title</quote> and inserting <quote>subparagraphs (A) through (E) of section 706(a)(2) of title</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H239FAB6E80A14FB699D574F4E66F5B9D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (d)(2), in the second sentence—</text><subparagraph id="H814FBF0EC9134FD5AF3954EF55F23740"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Title</quote> and inserting <quote>title</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB3A1692DF5D9435FB8C5294C56072466"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>subsection (d) of such section 553</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (g) of such section 553</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC9377F01B5C94120BE2DA685074F6B2B"><enum>(aa)</enum><header>McKinney-Vento homeless assistance act</header><text>Section 433 of the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/11387">42 U.S.C. 11387</external-xref>) is amended, in the second sentence, by striking <quote>(notwithstanding subsections (a)(2), (b)(B), and (d)(3) of such section)</quote> and inserting <quote>(notwithstanding subsections (a)(2), (f)(3), and (g)(2) of such section)</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H41894D0E5F394EF0B349388F9C07970A"><enum>(bb)</enum><header>Migrant and seasonal agricultural worker protection act</header><text>The Migrant and Seasonal Agricultural Worker Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1801">29 U.S.C. 1801 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H828BD21E71B44378B8C4E808E507EE80"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 103(c) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1813">29 U.S.C. 1813(c)</external-xref>), in the third sentence, by striking <quote>section 706(2)(E)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 706(a)(2)(E)</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC9A059CAF5274B768D448E83B930F252"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 503(c) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1853">29 U.S.C. 1853(c)</external-xref>), in the third sentence, by striking <quote>section 706(2)(E)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 706(a)(2)(E)</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA048252131B4465FBC709328646FCAE8"><enum>(cc)</enum><header>Milwaukee railroad restructuring act</header><text>The Milwaukee Railroad Restructuring Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/45/901">45 U.S.C. 901 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H84A3543E41DE4A1D9F38E7E3FA2E6ED9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 5(b)(2) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/45/904">45 U.S.C. 904(b)(2)</external-xref>), in the second sentence, by striking <quote>sections 706(2)(A), 706(2)(B), 706(2)(C), and 706(2)(D) of title 5 of the United States Code</quote> and inserting <quote>subparagraphs (A), (B), (C), and (D) of section 706(a)(2) of title 5, United States Code</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8D2EDB6719344D38ABBEDA9A0DBF69D1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 17(<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/45/915">45 U.S.C. 915</external-xref>), by striking <quote>sections 706(2)(A), 706(2)(B), 706(2)(C), and 706(2)(D) of title 5 of the United States Code</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>subparagraphs (A), (B), (C), and (D) of section 706(a)(2) of title 5, United States Code</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H30715D91E4B04FD2BD0EAD5EF4011405"><enum>(dd)</enum><header>Native american programs act of 1974</header><text>Section 814 of the Native American Programs Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2992b-1">42 U.S.C. 2992b–1</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H48D8FE7E056D4BF8A938BF259DAEBA20"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text><subparagraph id="H744D1B6BA8D14B5FBC07AA374462CB08"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>Subparagraph (A) of the last sentence of section 553(b) of title 5, United States Code, shall not apply with respect to any interpretative rule or general statement of policy</quote> and inserting <quote>Section 553(c) of title 5, United States Code, shall apply with respect to guidance</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H545F5174C46247FABF47DC35BBD46BBF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text><clause id="H5781567CAA1C43A6B1327B9D9F94E5DA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>Subparagraph (B) of the last sentence of section 553(b)</quote> and inserting <quote>Section 553(f)(3)</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="HF6F363C92BCD489E932DE135FBA0F213"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>an interpretative rule or a general statement of policy</quote> and inserting <quote>guidance</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3DE087AE2E0345339249883DA317B3F7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), in the matter preceding subparagraph (A)—</text><clause id="H9145C9A3C51244A981153FEE57C8D32A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>The first 2 sentences of section 553(b)</quote> and inserting <quote>Section 553(c)</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="HF8E185C568D440D89003B74A6858B6A3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>an interpretative rule, a general statement of policy,</quote> and inserting <quote>guidance</quote>;</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC740458EC0804CB0B940C52A9EADF699"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text><subparagraph id="HC57D0849AB614CE08D9FDB8D383948E3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the matter preceding paragraph (1)—</text><clause id="HB35A85E6F8D1498890C5688F83A4A150"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>section 553(d)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 553(g)</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="H5547FF60E70B46B4B4B0CC7E29ECA214"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>an interpretative rule) or general statement of policy</quote> and inserting <quote>guidance)</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3DC00C20F9484B93A0BEB36F05B9F100"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the flush text following paragraph (2), by striking <quote>the first 2 sentences of section 553(b)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 553(c)</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC09B9F6F5C574F16995F4218B4BAA48B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (d), by striking <quote>an interpretative rule) and each general statement of policy</quote> and inserting <quote>guidance)</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7AEFDDACDEB8437C9B5C74A4FEB58E65"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (e)—</text><subparagraph id="HCFEEADCA05034DA19312CF11834519E9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>any interpretative rule) or a general statement of policy</quote> and inserting <quote>guidance)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H69433FDF2B484AA18F48B97A0DEF70D6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>or such general statement of policy</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBD3E62A7101F412FAF132E64DD34147F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in subsection (f)—</text><subparagraph id="HC623C3F2BFA04484B0A0D7ED00F5434D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>an interpretative rule) or a general statement of policy</quote> and inserting <quote>guidance)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9C4A2ECA01314196A135B359C360D226"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>or such general statement of policy</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCD049D3A7AE24E579F65C9FFD5C9C897"><enum>(6)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H73EDDB0CDE894CDC97984961316C0CE5"><subsection id="HEBC73446BEBA41418A40D30A00EFF4CC"><enum>(g)</enum><text>In this section, the term <term>guidance</term> has the meaning given the term in section 551 of title 5, United States Code.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H66D1FA9E32264E01BDC1611B9AB332EC"><enum>(ee)</enum><header>Natural gas policy act of 1978</header><text>Section 502(b) of the Natural Gas Policy Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/3412">15 U.S.C. 3412(b)</external-xref>) is amended, in the third sentence, by striking <quote>section 553(d)(3)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 553(g)(2)</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H794036B16E4F477C9F674BA587B61242"><enum>(ff)</enum><header>Noise control act of 1972</header><text>Section 6(c)(2) of the Noise Control Act of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4905">42 U.S.C. 4905(c)(2)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>the first sentence of section 553(c)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 553(c)(4)</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HCBE26EBDBC3648A3B15D90BCCF7E52AF"><enum>(gg)</enum><header>Northeast rail service act of 1981</header><text>Section 1152(c) of the Northeast Rail Service Act of 1981 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/45/1105">45 U.S.C. 1105(c)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>paragraphs (2) (A), (B), (C), and (D) of section 706, title 5</quote> and inserting <quote>subparagraphs (A) through (D) of section 706(a)(2) of title 5</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H40301A2E64A7434482B46508CAE1F31D"><enum>(hh)</enum><header>Northern pacific halibut act of 1982</header><text>Section 8(b) of the Northern Pacific Halibut Act of 1982 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/773f">16 U.S.C. 773f(b)</external-xref>) is amended, in the third sentence, by striking <quote>section 706(2)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 706(a)(2)</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0B6CD50CFAAE493F95CDE49E9F078D1A"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Ocean Thermal Energy Conversion Act of 1980</header><text>Section 302(c)(2) of the Ocean Thermal Energy Conversion Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9152">42 U.S.C. 9152(c)(2)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>section 706(2)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 706(a)(2)</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HFFE63F2725EE433C8D84E27FCB2FC8E6"><enum>(jj)</enum><header>Poison prevention packaging act of 1970</header><text>The Poison Prevention Packaging Act of 1970 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1471">15 U.S.C. 1471 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H401E0BDA727844DBAB82314D1C6829AB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 5 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1474">15 U.S.C. 1474</external-xref>)—</text><subparagraph id="H8D8696124F544DFBB49058F76E401394"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a), in the first sentence, by striking <quote>(other than paragraph (3)(B) of the last sentence of subsection (b) of such section) of title 5 of the United States Code</quote> and inserting <quote>of title 5, United States Code, other than subsection (f)(3) of such section,</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0DC460DBA6B34209BE3BC3CEEDCF065C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text><clause id="H19FD143E80CE499482EAB143B90854D8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>of the United States Code</quote> each place that term appears and inserting <quote>, United States Code</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="H02DB80169AD9418381D850C5634FA174"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), in the first sentence, by striking <quote>paragraph (2) of section 706</quote> and inserting <quote>section 706(a)(2)</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB5F62ECB663643A79FA8681B197D4337"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 7(c)(2) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1476">15 U.S.C. 1476(c)(2)</external-xref>), by striking <quote>section 553(b)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 553(c)</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H951C238488FC4089B3D3F76752F5F7AA"><enum>(kk)</enum><header>Poultry products inspection act</header><text>Section 14(c) of the Poultry Products Inspection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/463">21 U.S.C. 463(c)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>section 553(c) of title 5, United States Code</quote> and inserting <quote>section 553(c)(4) of title 5, United States Code,</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H64D2CE8FEE5542DEBE348C57A8610F76"><enum>(ll)</enum><header>Public health service act</header><text>Section 2723(b)(2)(E)(iii) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg-22">42 U.S.C. 300gg–22(b)(2)(E)(iii)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>section 706(2)(E)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 706(a)(2)(E)</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2EE7662A424946209956438DD0662423"><enum>(mm)</enum><header>Railway Labor Act</header><text>Section 10A(b) of the Railway Labor Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/45/160a">45 U.S.C. 160a(b)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>the third sentence of section 553(b)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraph (2) or (3) of section 553(f)</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H660B5FE6446347D08065B6E9525D1CD0"><enum>(nn)</enum><header>Regional rail reorganization act of 1973</header><text>Section 216(c)(3) of the Regional Rail Reorganization Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/45/726">45 U.S.C. 726(c)(3)</external-xref>) is amended, in the fourth sentence, by striking <quote>section 706(2)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 706(a)(2)</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBC95AAA82AC74580918DBC433B2F259C"><enum>(oo)</enum><header>Rehabilitation Act of 1973</header><text>Section 107(d)(3)(B) of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/727">29 U.S.C. 727(d)(3)(B)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>section 706</quote> and inserting <quote>section 706(a)</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCE984E7CB341429C985BC8DA2D7C6442"><enum>(pp)</enum><header>Reorganization Plan No. 1 of 1980</header><text>Section 1(a)(2) of the Reorganization Plan No. 1 of 1980 (94 Stat. 3585; 5 U.S.C. App.) is amended by striking <quote>section 553(a)(2) and (b)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsections (a)(2) and (c) of section 553</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3565A50C340647C182F14DB026D9B11C"><enum>(qq)</enum><header>Rural Development Act of 1972</header><text>Section 608(a) of the Rural Development Act of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2204b-2">7 U.S.C. 2204b–2</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>section 553(b)(3)(B)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 553(f)(3)</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HEEDA35CBF7B746D2AD42E22AA6B5B473"><enum>(rr)</enum><header>Social security act</header><text>The Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/301">42 U.S.C. 301 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HA532694651984F2D81CF7993D61A8B24"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 221(j) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/421">42 U.S.C. 421(j)</external-xref>), in the flush text following paragraph (3), by striking <quote>in accordance with section 553(b)(A) of title 5, United States Code</quote> and all that follows through <quote>and statements</quote> and inserting <quote>in accordance with section 553(f)(2) of title 5, United States Code, of guidance or rules of agency organization, procedure, or practice relating to consultative examinations if such guidance and rules</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H43D18707DEFF4B3A977ACE4BA7D1A158"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 410(c)(2) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/610">42 U.S.C. 610(c)(2)</external-xref>), by striking <quote>section 706(2)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 706(a)(2)</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H02EE53C9445B4A559602E97E947A636F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in section 1871(b)(2) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395hh">42 U.S.C. 1395hh(b)(2)</external-xref>), by striking subparagraph (C) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA04C751266EA4229BE877AFAA421AF6A"><subparagraph id="HA693D7CDEAE94871B1C511EC0B0E718E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>subsection (c) of section 553 of title 5, United States Code, does not apply pursuant to subsection (f)(3) of such section.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB81EFE8E914F460082755004C1145AA0"><enum>(ss)</enum><header>South pacific tuna act of 1988</header><text>Section 8(b) of the South Pacific Tuna Act of 1988 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/973f">16 U.S.C. 973f(b)</external-xref>) is amended, in the third sentence, by striking <quote>section 706(2)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 706(a)(2)</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H717C9853ED8D442E85011C57BEED7D0F"><enum>(tt)</enum><header>Tariff act of 1930</header><text>Section 777(f)(5) of the Tariff Act of 1930 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1677f">19 U.S.C. 1677f(f)(5)</external-xref>) is amended, in the third sentence, by striking <quote>section 706(2)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 706(a)(2)</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5DFC9BACE303474D812CD8A3655D72D7"><enum>(uu)</enum><header>Title 5, united states code</header><text>Title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDB2B0CFBD4754D91A12AB3A99EB17788"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 552a—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDD91031A1477413196B8E56037F63566"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (j)—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE3BE2B6584984444A7521911445D1A39"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by striking <quote>sections 553(b)(1), (2), and (3), (c), and (e)</quote> and inserting <quote>clauses (i), (ii), and (iii) of section 553(c)(1)(C), section 553(c)(4), and section 553(h)</quote>; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1C19BFB7BD094E04A6219852232500F0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the matter following paragraph (2), by striking <quote>section 553(c)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 553(c)(4)</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB920C4EA70BB42CEA2CB7A35C4431816"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (k)—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC8F6AF2B5AE748FEAAC203F2F298FF22"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by striking <quote>sections 553(b)(1), (2), and (3), (c), and (e)</quote> and inserting <quote>clauses (i), (ii), and (iii) of section 553(c)(1)(C), section 553(c)(4), and section 553(h)</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="HBD6E485B631C456BB97099A9CB34E1A6" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the matter following paragraph (7), by striking <quote>section 553(c)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 553(c)(4)</quote>;</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8B35BB39D1CA476BA9B7A3B8AD6E5581"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 556(d), in the sixth sentence, by striking <quote>rule making</quote> and inserting <quote>rulemaking</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2386F60E88874EC3BC8029FCD8287A67"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in section 557(b), in the fourth sentence of the matter preceding paragraph (1), by striking <quote>rule making</quote> and inserting <quote>rulemaking</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H98EBE599AAEB4F9B9D9D234E6A64220F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in section 562(11), by striking <quote>means <quote>rule making</quote> as that term is defined in section 551(5)</quote> and inserting <quote>has the meaning given the term in section 551</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H913F1520DD0C41FE8E815A34309A409D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in section 601(2), by striking <quote>section 553(b)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 553(c)</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8C0448CC2A444E8EBE9EBE97BADE822A"><enum>(6)</enum><text>in section 1103(b)(1), by striking <quote>section 553(b)(1), (2), and (3)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 553(c)</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD042D87DD79D4BA78C85B504D4E181CB"><enum>(7)</enum><text>in section 1105, by striking <quote>subsections (b), (c), and (d)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsections (b) through (g) and (i)</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB9EE027143374A78AB412FC238494221"><enum>(vv)</enum><header>Title 11, united states code</header><text>Section 1172(b) of title 11, United States Code, is amended, in the second sentence, by striking <quote>sections 706(2)(A), 706(2)(B), 706(2)(C), and 706(2)(D) of title 5</quote> and inserting <quote>subparagraphs (A), (B), (C), and (D) of section 706(a)(2) of title 5</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB0A3E7885F524BA4BC5F7C2A5F521929"><enum>(ww)</enum><header>Title 14, united states code</header><text>Section 2507(b)(2)(A) of title 14, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>section 706(1)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 706(a)(1)</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE26A8301B395451CBDD1CD1971870E07"><enum>(xx)</enum><header>Title 28, united states code</header><text>Section 3902 of title 28, United States Code, is amended, in the first sentence, by striking <quote>section 706(2)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 706(a)(2)</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC225AAC890FF4600BDB612DC437E097F"><enum>(yy)</enum><header>Title 41, united states code</header><text>Section 8503(a)(2) of title 41, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>section 553(b) to (e)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 553</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE0C21C9A75E94C77B6F45502902DF3DB"><enum>(zz)</enum><header>Title 46, united states code</header><text>Title 46, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="HFC64280754E24F00A10D3C105DDCE6F2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 14104(b), in the second sentence, by striking <quote>shall be considered to be an interpretive regulation for purposes of section 553 of title 5</quote> and inserting <quote>shall be subject to section 553 of title 5</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8F64C437215846B9B9076415AEAE4F3F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 70105(c)(3)(B), in the second sentence, by striking <quote>section 706(2)(E)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 706(a)(2)(E)</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBF7BB016DEAD469C8459151A4E9B910C"><enum>(aaa)</enum><header>Title 49, United States Code</header><text>Section 60102(b)(6)(C) of title 49, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>section 553(b)(3)(B)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 553(f)(3)</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H839CAC95830140AAA176540471A8F406"><enum>(bbb)</enum><header>Toxic substances control act</header><text>Section 19(c)(1)(B) of the Toxic Substances Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/2618">15 U.S.C. 2618(c)(1)(B)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H37EA07F79B5741A087A0DF08EE44F7BC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in clause (i)—</text><subparagraph id="H0B68C9A7CAE841D499486BC17DC02591"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subclause (I), by striking <quote>paragraph (2)(E)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (a)(2)(E)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB369D7A894A64C1FB899F6B980F818B8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subclause (II), by striking <quote>paragraph (2)(E)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (a)(2)(E)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H82E1A93941C3479CBFB8DC1494FBBD71"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in clause (ii), by striking <quote>section 553(c)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 553(e)(2)</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5677D912C9C045FC80785578C8055965"><enum>(ccc)</enum><header>Unfunded mandates reform act of 1995</header><text>Section 401(a)(2)(A) of the Unfunded Mandates Reform Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1571">2 U.S.C. 1571(a)(2)(A)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>section 706(1)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 706(a)(1)</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC7F64D9C231A45F6BED076AD5E4E74CE"><enum>(ddd)</enum><header>United States Housing Act of 1937</header><text>Section 31(d) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437z-3">42 U.S.C. 1437z–3(d)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>(b)(B), and (d)(3)</quote> and inserting <quote>(f)(3), and (g)(2)</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H276DE03F3FF44F8293E744CBDF8DF9F8"><enum>(eee)</enum><header>United states warehouse act</header><text>Section 13(d)(2) of the United States Warehouse Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/252">7 U.S.C. 252(d)(2)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>section 706(2)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 706(a)(2)</quote>.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

