<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-TAM25651-LF1-XY-L06"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2062 IS: Rolling Active Pharmaceutical Ingredient and Drug Reserve Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2062</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250612">June 12, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S380">Mr. Peters</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S417">Mr. Budd</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To improve supply chain resiliency for critical drug products with vulnerable supply chains and ensure that reserves of critical drugs and active pharmaceutical ingredients are maintained to prevent supply disruptions in the event of drug shortages or public health emergencies. </official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="id7F958974EDF54B64ADE2698A0E0CBB95"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Rolling Active Pharmaceutical Ingredient and Drug Reserve Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>RAPID Reserve Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section commented="no" id="id5443add2acd84195a6bfc9dc0d060105"><enum>2.</enum><header>Rolling active pharmaceutical ingredient and drug reserve</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id787cd1b277d845408cedc778c876be13"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services (referred to in this section as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall award contracts or cooperative agreements to eligible entities with respect to drugs and active pharmaceutical ingredients of such drugs that the Secretary determines to be critical and to have vulnerable supply chains. The Secretary shall publish the list of such drugs and active pharmaceutical ingredients of such drugs.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="id9493325a4421461b9292f4892bb8e8dc"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id09735fa5c9c2470280aa05f0a67a9186"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity, pursuant to a contract or cooperative agreement under subsection (a), shall agree to—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id131cd24d7a964ea0be60d344fe34232e"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">maintain, in a satisfactory domestic establishment registered under section 510(b) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/360">21 U.S.C. 360(b)</external-xref>) or in a satisfactory foreign establishment registered under section 510(i) of such Act that is located in a country that is a member of the Organisation for Economic Cooperation and Development, which may be an establishment owned and operated by the entity, or by a wholesaler, distributor, or other third-party under contract with the entity, a 6-month reserve, or other reasonable quantity, as determined by the Secretary, of—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idacc7f9c1e488474494ee1fd9aa13830c"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the active pharmaceutical ingredient of the eligible drug specified in the contract or cooperative agreement, which reserve shall be regularly replenished with a recently manufactured supply of such ingredient; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id441f1c0784b64d6794cb0863f6aae7dc"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the finished eligible drug product specified in the contract or cooperative agreement, which reserve shall be regularly replenished with a recently manufactured supply of such product; </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8073675fbc6d413491ef7de674c3b03d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>implement production of the eligible drug or an active pharmaceutical ingredient of the eligible drug, at the direction of the Secretary, under the terms of, and in such quantities as specified in, the contract or cooperative agreement; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6484adede2e64bf1a663e8d7fd9daf5b"><enum>(C)</enum><text>enter into an arrangement with the Secretary under which the eligible entity—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idacc0eddd33874231929906d382fcb8c2"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">agrees to transfer a portion, as determined necessary, of the reserve of active pharmaceutical ingredient maintained pursuant to subparagraph (A)(i) to another drug manufacturer in the event that the Secretary determines there to be a need for additional finished eligible drug product and such eligible entity is unable to use the reserve of active pharmaceutical ingredient to manufacture a sufficient supply of such drug product; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd7dca8cc89d94d82b683aadbe4079da4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>permits the Secretary to direct allocation of the reserve of active pharmaceutical ingredient so maintained in the event of a public health emergency, natural disaster, or chemical, biological, radiological, or nuclear threat.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida658c128035b495cbc9df5a4e11fd408"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Guidance</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary, in coordination with the Commissioner of Food and Drugs, shall issue guidance on—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1fcf2498cbef49509d71af3121f1c03d"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the factors the Secretary will use to determine which eligible drugs, or active pharmaceutical ingredient of such drugs, have vulnerable supply chains and how a contract or cooperative agreement would help minimize the vulnerability or vulnerabilities identified;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id608b39cb84d845b7bea56d004824bf91"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the factors the Secretary will consider in determining eligibility of an entity to participate in the program under this section, which shall include an entity's commitment to quality systems, including strong manufacturing infrastructure, reliable processes, and trained staff, as well as the entity's commitment to domestic manufacturing capacity and surge capacity, as appropriate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1b8c753e24f54a35bd7e4562ece23e19"><enum>(C)</enum><text>requirements for entities receiving an award under this section, including the extent of excess manufacturing capacity the manufacturers will be required to generate, the amount of redundancy required, and requirements relating to advanced quality systems.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id764378d7b3d44568b148a183a1657478"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Preference</header><text>In awarding contracts and cooperative agreements under subsection (a), the Secretary shall—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id685fe1465f5c4be1b6f6bb708e6198c4"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">give preference to eligible entities that will—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idae6ecefcda7540ebab43e669fd937b80"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">carry out the requirements of paragraph (1) through one or more domestic establishments registered under section 510(b) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/360">21 U.S.C. 360(b)</external-xref>) capable of manufacturing the eligible drug; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8d7aa223003c41d1811391e620233e11"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">source key starting materials or excipients for eligible drugs domestically or from a country that is a member of the Organisation for Economic Cooperation and Development; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1ced9088fa4946f1b28495cb4eb2b7dd"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to the greatest extent practicable, award such contracts and cooperative agreements in a manner that strengthens domestic manufacturing, resiliency, and capacity of eligible drugs and their active pharmaceutical ingredients. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id569996ec504b45aca0beb37ca24da14a"><enum>(c)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Additional contract and cooperative agreement terms</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id589fd5a1a36540749fab46bf9947db35"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each contract or cooperative agreement under subsection (a) shall be subject to such terms and conditions as the Secretary may specify, including terms and conditions with respect to procurement, maintenance, storage, testing, and delivery of drugs, in alignment with inventory management and other applicable best practices, under such contract or cooperative agreement, which may consider, as appropriate, costs of transporting and handling such drugs. </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id17ce73e643274f3ca0fe9e0ef81e39bb"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Terms concerning the acquisition, construction, alteration, or renovation of establishments</header><text>Notwithstanding section 6303 of title 41, United States Code, the Secretary may award a contract or cooperative agreement under this section to support the acquisition, construction, alteration, or renovation of non-federally owned establishments—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8d4113040d9842a4ac79754326d96da2"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">as determined necessary to carry out or improve preparedness and response capability at the State and local level; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id19d9aeb066604c3296240aa6a94f6363"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for the production of drugs, devices, and supplies where the Secretary determines that such a contract or cooperative agreement is necessary to ensure sufficient amounts of such drugs, devices, and supplies.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id9bc63492ae0946f1bb1c0566ed1cf997"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Requirements in awarding contracts</header><text>To the greatest extent practicable, the Secretary shall award contracts and cooperative agreements under this section in a manner that—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc2d726184b3243ee94492e9ea8aa0e5b"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">maximizes quality, minimizes cost, minimizes vulnerability of the United States to severe shortages or disruptions for eligible drugs and their active pharmaceutical ingredients, gives preference to domestic manufacturers, and encourages competition in the marketplace; and </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id516633f8e27a4995ade0b566aa1795c5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>increases domestic production surge capacity and reserves of domestic-based manufacturing establishments for critical drugs and active pharmaceutical ingredients of such drugs.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5edb6c287e5c4daab51ad661423ab777"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section: </text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8140e485e3584c25bc244523dacf9f0a"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Active pharmaceutical ingredient</header><text>The term <term>active pharmaceutical ingredient</term> has the meaning given such term in section 744A of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/379j-41">21 U.S.C. 379j–41</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfb1f552ade8a4b56ac4eead9bc5066dd"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Drug</header><text>The term <term>drug</term> has the meaning given such term in section 201(g) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/321">21 U.S.C. 321(g)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id10f69844d036415c8cc5f266b3e61d45"><enum>(3)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Drug shortage; shortage</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>drug shortage</term> or <term>shortage</term> has the meaning given such term in section 506C of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/356c">21 U.S.C. 356c</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id18b6247ea3d440b59f3892a08718c55c"><enum>(4)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Eligible drug</header><text>The term <term>eligible drug</term> means a drug, as determined by the Secretary, in coordination with the Assistant Secretary for Preparedness and Response, the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, and the Commissioner of Food and Drugs—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddeac8150665149929999d184051f19cb"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that is approved under section 505(j) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/355">21 U.S.C. 355(j)</external-xref>) or licensed under section 351(k) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/262">42 U.S.C. 262(k)</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6d871d63a3d34c138726f7553ad2dce1"><enum>(B)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id2ae614ef7c9b42ccb350c18cbdec29ef"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that is reasonably likely to be required to respond to a public health emergency or to a chemical, biological, radiological, or nuclear threat; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5d81b616e0cb44d8a28e0b032a008b2c" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the shortage of which would pose a significant threat to the United States health care system or at-risk populations; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9d0250cc90134981bf95bf58830fbf86"><enum>(C)</enum><text>that has a vulnerable supply chain, such as a geographic concentration of manufacturing, poor quality or safety issues, complex manufacturing or chemistry, or few manufacturers.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5e29603f7b234eaaa01fbb1c3877ecbc"><enum>(5)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means a person that—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5188ab9b6ab14ea594d861f181aff797"><enum>(A)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id9dc78b3a173543baafa6d379bd02134a"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is the holder of an approved application under subsection (j) of section 505 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/355">21 U.S.C. 355</external-xref>) or subsection (k) of section 351 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/262">42 U.S.C. 262</external-xref>) for an eligible drug; </text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id66b5043a04624b22994396345057ad22" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">maintains at least one domestic establishment registered under section 510(b) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/360">21 U.S.C. 360(b)</external-xref>) or one foreign establishment registered under section 510(i) of such Act that is located in a country that is a member of the Organisation for Economic Cooperation and Development that is capable of manufacturing the eligible drug; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="idbb79d716d6ef4d8b8be4cdd9f8958565"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has a strong record of good manufacturing practices of drugs; </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idad495e3197b9438980d2fac0db159f14"><enum>(B)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id13288186f3f040d08580f5a5d39b341e"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is a manufacturer of an active pharmaceutical ingredient for an eligible drug, in partnership with an entity that meets the requirements of subparagraph (A);</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id771FDEAB6B784831B3159F815E166E47" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">maintains at least one domestic establishment registered under section 510(b) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/360">21 U.S.C. 360(b)</external-xref>) or one foreign establishment registered under section 510(i) of such Act that is located in a country that is a member of the Organisation for Economic Cooperation and Development that is capable of manufacturing the active pharmaceutical ingredient; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="id700C607A9FE34BA0B98289014B980732"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has a strong record of good manufacturing practices of active pharmaceutical ingredients; or</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb8d2da07829640aea734b563c9efad99"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is a distributor or wholesaler of an eligible drug, in partnership with an entity that meets the requirements of subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3b9ad3ea63194005b28e2347f7009c92"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date on which the first award is made under this section, and every 2 years thereafter, the Secretary shall submit a report to Congress detailing—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3b8af86105b045bc847cc1bf21537d81"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the list of drugs determined to be eligible drugs, as described in subsection (e)(2), and the rationale behind selecting each such drug; and </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id041b210c1b1f45a4891ae029184620e6"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an update on the effectiveness of the program under this section, in a manner that does not compromise national security.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0452723069f04bf79d06248db695a172"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>To carry out this section, there is authorized to be appropriated $500,000,000 for fiscal year 2026. </text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

