<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" slc-id="S1-DAV25815-PP4-S9-X5K"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 190 IS: A resolution seeking justice for the Japanese citizens abducted by North Korea.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 190</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250430">April 30, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S383">Mr. Sullivan</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S355">Mr. Cruz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S407">Mr. Hagerty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S353">Mr. Schatz</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S288">Ms. Murkowski</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">A resolution seeking justice for the Japanese citizens abducted by North Korea.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the United States Government recognizes that North Korea was abducting Japanese citizens since the 1970s;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in September 2002, North Korea admitted that it had abducted Japanese citizens and promised to prevent further recurrences;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in October of 2002, only 5 abductees were returned to Japan after being held prisoner for 24 years, despite the explicit commitment of North Korea to investigate what had happened to all abductees;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Universal Declaration of Human Rights upholds the basic principles of liberty and freedom enshrined within the United States Constitution and Bill of Rights;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas human rights awareness is essential to the realization of fundamental freedoms and contributes to promoting equality, preventing conflict and human rights violations, and enhancing participation in democratic processes;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas these abductions of Japanese citizens by North Korea directly conflict with the basic principle of liberty and freedom; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas there have been several attempts at dialogue between North Korea and Japanese leaders in an effort to yield stable results: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="S1"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="ide41cc0937acf4c32a77977fe08b81416"><enum>(1)</enum><text>calls on North Korea to release any abducted foreign nationals, including those from Japan;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5f505aa490a04d3db5ff0c94d21fab9b"><enum>(2)</enum><text>urges North Korea to return the remains and provide information on any deceased abductees;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8c8c2c0427054b5487c27c3714d8b92d"><enum>(3)</enum><text>urges North Korea to make such reparations as are appropriate regarding abductees;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf60039b1124644e09e7cc4f7502ed231"><enum>(4)</enum><text>urges North Korea to apologize and permanently cease such activities; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6e23e44de8f9469fa6140568b6507cf9"><enum>(5)</enum><text>encourages the President to ensure that this matter is addressed in any future interaction with North Korea officials.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

