<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4B5968F4184B4914B6357396968537EE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4232 IH: No Tax Dollars for Riots</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4232</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250627">June 27, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000401">Mr. Kiley of California</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide penalties for certain misconduct by officers and members of the board of directors of nonprofit entities, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC7B3FF3F3373410383894634A2214F21" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H8415545731824C8E8D36B3A92B8F8835" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No Tax Dollars for Riots</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H3C47215E45B34791B5D91389BFA121F8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Penalties related to certain misconduct by officers of nonprofit entities</header> 
<subsection id="HA31F26C7E3C24D778CAEC91A3DFDDD16"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Limitation on Federal funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No Federal funds may be made available to an entity that is exempt from taxation under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 if an officer of such entity or member of the board of directors of such entity is convicted of an offense under section 111 or 2101 of title 18, United States Code, and the conduct giving rise to the offense occurred while such individual was serving as such an officer or board member.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H6EDD9ED25AF840FA9BF5AC9635D687AF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitation on exemption from taxation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An entity that is exempt from taxation under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 shall be ineligible for such exemption beginning on the date on which an officer of such entity or member of the board of directors of such entity is convicted of an offense under section 111 or 2101 of title 18, United States Code, and the conduct giving rise to the offense occurred while such individual was serving as such an officer or board member.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

