<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6E68E3D80BE6403692253EA4E84FA315" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5538 IH: Child Rescue Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5538</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250919">September 19, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000138">Mr. Vindman</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Attorney General to convene a national working group to study proactive strategies and needed resources for the identification and rescue of children from sexual exploitation and abuse, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H1A8B038BE21A45EBAAF6E6BE869350C9" style="OLC"><section id="HCAF376025E434851B0597E80A1E4C08D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Child Rescue Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HE1BDA5CD69D543A18A88F17A87279E9A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H7C203B4AA6524FEF887D70BB12131680"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The growing international trade in child sexual abuse material creates demand and incentive for the sexual assault of children throughout the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H403E2C3E78074E20BBD6CBCCADE7F2C4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>United States law enforcement efforts to combat child sexual exploitation have the potential to help multiple distinct groups of victims, including—</text><subparagraph id="H2188456528B04675A998138B6EDE4472"><enum>(A)</enum><text>children depicted in child sexual abuse material (CSAM) who are still being abused;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD06BA125B26C48588E9EE384AFB75B28"><enum>(B)</enum><text>children and adults whose victimization as a child continues to be viewed and shared online; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3A6E0F7813824AC4A66ECFF3EDA0615B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>children who are being sexually abused or exploited by adults who could be interdicted while accessing or sharing CSAM online.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDE209F46EB254804A242E141A65062E9"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In 2021, law enforcement investigative systems detected more than 325,000 unique Internet Protocol addresses in the United States seen distributing child sexual abuse material across peer-to-peer file sharing networks.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFDE4F14C7E8D46E395C83BEACE77B78D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A growing body of research, including academic studies, analysis by the United States Sentencing Commission, and findings by law enforcement polygraphers, indicates that a significant percentage of majority of individuals possessing and sharing CSAM are <quote>dual offenders</quote> who possess illegal imagery and also commit contact offenses. In 2021, the United States Sentencing Commission found that in fiscal year 2019, 48 percent of <quote>non-production child pornography offenders engaged in aggravating sexual conduct prior to, or concurrently with</quote>, their current offense. Studies including Seto et al, the Butner Redux, the OJJDP study, and Bourke et al Tactical Polygraph study have found that between 50 and 80 percent of offenders who possess CSAM are also committing contact sexual offenses against children.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC61F31BD99F74E0581568B38D16B4F4C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>According to a 2018 study by the National Center for Missing and Exploited Children (NCMEC), <quote>in cases involving a single victim and single offender, actively traded cases were associated with having prepubescent victims. Actively traded cases were also associated with more egregious content in terms of sexual activity, and more likely to involve familial offenders, particularly nuclear family members</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H04B526E731B84BDF833BEECE1A88EC19"><enum>(6)</enum><text>CyberTipline reports often lead to the rescue of children through the successful investigation of offenders who are not only exploiting children by circulating CSAM, but who are also committing contact offenses. In 2020, 21,700,000 CyberTipline reports were submitted to NCMEC and approximately 288,000 CyberTipline reports were made available to the 61 Internet Crimes Against Children (ICAC) units across the country.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB9073FFFC4014140A28D190819000EBF"><enum>(7)</enum><text>United States law enforcement’s ability to detect and interdict online traffic in CSAM provides an opportunity to locate sexual predators and rescue children through victim-centric investigations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB2FD712D89074389963A611647FC3A66"><enum>(8)</enum><text>With inadequate resources, United States law enforcement agencies are increasingly unable to adequately respond to this rapidly growing number of CyberTips and other investigative leads, a problem which also reduces the number of proactive undercover investigations and education activities they can conduct.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4AC04B8DCDD146829C021E997A6D6E66"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Investigations of these crimes are complicated by the increasing prevalence of encryption and anonymizing services available to offenders.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H516D7BB55FCF4B0D883DEFEF666CCFE3"><enum>3.</enum><header>United States Working Group on Children in Imminent Danger of Sexual Abuse and Exploitation</header><subsection id="HC51D854BBE334DDD8096EC956117D390"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Attorney General shall establish a national working group, to be known as the <quote>United States Working Group on Children in Imminent Danger of Sexual Abuse and Exploitation</quote> (hereinafter referred to as the <quote>Working Group</quote>), to study victim-centric policing strategies and resource needs to identify and rescue—</text><paragraph id="H1DA8BB6D2CE54FB6800083DE27690012"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">children in the United States who are visually depicted in child sexual abuse material; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB01D54EBEEF84BE391461A08C7DAD4C4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>children in the United States who are victims of sexual abuse by individuals who are engaged in an offense relating to child sexual abuse materials; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA19C269456A046CBBECFCC19728FBA85" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">children located outside the United States who are visually depicted in child sexual abuse materials where the perpetrators are in the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H907980901D364461964166FDCF96B5B0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties of the working group</header><paragraph id="H65DB312A40714F619CC9EDED4C702EDB" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Information request</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the establishment of the Working Group under subsection (a), the Working Group shall solicit from each State, Tribal, or local law enforcement agency the information necessary to develop the estimates under paragraph (2). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5C77C42A89524F7CBB7557EF069DAA0A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Development of estimates</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Working Group shall:</text><subparagraph id="H4962FAD4766A4591A53EE000FA7A4C5D" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Develop estimates of the total number of individuals suspected with respect to child sexual abuse material or other crimes involving sexual contact with children in the United States, including those who are—</text><clause id="H5DDE0CFB87FE4FDCA85DE1E4CF3DEC1C" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>known to a law enforcement agency; </text></clause><clause id="H9041E96FD0A84D44BB71152034A1A54F" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>identified by law enforcement through proactive policing; or </text></clause><clause id="H83D1B95A6AFC4483BFEE157FAD97DB76" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>reported to the CyberTipline of NCMEC (or any successor to the CyberTipline operated by NCMEC). </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H02794B212DD841B8A19153C58E943042"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Develop estimates of the total number of child victims of child sexual abuse in the United States who could be located and protected from further abuse through the apprehension of suspects described under subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9D1694776756471D815B7247EA9E6C78"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Develop recommendations of the funding, resources, and proactive and reactive strategies necessary for law enforcement agencies to successfully identify, locate, and protect child victims—</text><clause id="H634E010B42254658A1C2E0E5B9E6B423"><enum>(i)</enum><text>described in subparagraph (B); and</text></clause><clause id="H3C42DDC91A1B400C86ED312C431700D7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>who appear in child sexual abuse material known to a law enforcement agency or NCMEC.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF7B0057B34A54B90A3839F33F653F583"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Develop or obtain estimates of the number of child sexual abuse reports made annually to law enforcement agencies and to State, Tribal, and local child protective services, broken out by locality and relationship between victim and offender, including adults in a position of trust or authority. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5D2D7D8733D1457D89432E02119D1E69"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Develop recommendations for strategies, best practices, and resources that could be used by law enforcement agencies to determine whether offenders alleged to have committed a crime involving sexual contact should also be investigated for potential child sexual abuse material crimes. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3EEF73A296724402855A5200BED7DBC5"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Develop recommendations of victim-centric and proactive policing strategies, international collaboration, and resource needs to apprehend offenders in the United States who are engaged in offenses related to children as described in subsection (a)(3).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD9B8A960A33F48E2BD614C807A48982D"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Develop estimates of, or compile data solicited under paragraph (1)—</text><clause id="HE9B35B0D54174EF4ADF84302B5D73CD9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the number of adults who were arrested by law enforcement agencies during the 5-year period preceding the date of enactment of this Act, by year, for offenses or violations described in subparagraphs (A) through (D); </text></clause><clause id="H64C2C67562D84230B454CC229C2D72EC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the number of adults who were prosecuted at the State, Tribal, or Federal level during the 5-year period preceding the date of the enactment of the Act, by year, for offenses described in subparagraphs (A) through (D); and</text></clause><clause id="HBB453752812E47F88394930909977C24"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the number of children who are unidentified victims of child sexual abuse material described in subparagraph (C)(ii).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6DC45C1A406A42B39E7926CAB9FCDC86"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Analyze and summarize common reasons why investigations of reports of child sexual abuse or exploitation do not go forward.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2F5B0DB5331E496BB69EC30360406D29"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Develop guidance for Internet Crimes Against Children Task Forces to adopt a prioritization framework with respect to the investigation and prosecution of all child sexual abuse and exploitation, including prioritizing investigating individuals using encryption or anonymization.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA78C64E4CBD14F6DBDFC778AD7EDB762"><enum>(J)</enum><text>Develop guidance on the Attorney General’s response to technology companies that refuse to comply with lawful requests for information related to offenders who use virtual private networks.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4423167C1D834368BD568ECD2EBFF630"><enum>(K)</enum><text>Evaluate the current duties and responsibilities of ICAC Task Forces pursuant to section 21114 of title 34, United States Code, including on—</text><clause id="HD0A4BACC1FF04EE1AE1ADA937648BB56"><enum>(i)</enum><text>workloads; and</text></clause><clause id="HDBDE8BBD890848CC808299B97BDA7875"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>their ability to pursue investigations which are most likely to result in the identification of offenders described in subparagraph (A) and children described in subparagraph (B).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEA73BF9851D04F8F9F174432CB5F64E0" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report</header><subparagraph id="HA50EDA7ABA06497D95D8842369A2ACFA"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 365 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Working Group shall submit to the Attorney General, the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate, the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate, the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives, a report that contains—</text><clause id="H283D4C3D2B1E4973B8BA77B9EC4E8A16"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a detailed statement of the findings and conclusions of the Working Group, together with recommendations for legislation; and</text></clause><clause id="H5F54FF8476F74EA5B9B516C7DDC9D25F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a summary of the support, documents, and witnesses provided by the Attorney General to the Working Group.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5CE527C51B8D4F5DB2C3A392C2257233"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Material included</header><text>A majority vote of the members of the Working Group shall determine the findings, conclusions, and recommendations included in the report submitted under subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2EF103D100344BE1885EB6EE85829435"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Documentation of numerical edits</header><text>If for any reason the Working Group is unable to develop the estimates under paragraph (2), the Working Group shall in the report under this paragraph document the reasons such estimates could not be developed and make recommendations toward developing such estimates.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3820D0FCF822414FA41A3D3E01FE26AB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Members of the Working Group</header><paragraph id="H4C88EE9D92A2426C8BDCDE2C60E2E546"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><subparagraph id="HFDDBD5A0783F4C0F87B839D9E73079DE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Attorney General discretion</header><text>The Working Group shall be composed of representatives of Federal departments and agencies, law enforcement agencies, Tribal governmental agencies, nongovernmental organizations, and other subject matter experts as the Attorney General determines appropriate.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF548904AA4B6484CA7C52E6A51BF0190"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Specified members</header><text>The Attorney General shall appoint representatives of the following agencies and nongovernmental organizations to the Working Group:</text><clause id="H1D51E57200A34A36AE1000AC349B7B58"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Three representatives from State or unit of local government who have received a grant from the Internet Crimes Against Children Task Force program with extensive, direct experience conducting both CyberTipline investigations and proactive, online undercover investigations, including the use of specialized tools for peer-to-peer investigations.</text></clause><clause id="H901897B0B5A14565ACB8E8A1AD61E7A0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The Chief or Deputy Chief of the Child Exploitation and Obscenity Section of the Criminal Division of the Department of Justice.</text></clause><clause id="HB7C42D949C1E4101A00875B5EBD24D55"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The National Coordinator for Child Exploitation Prevention and Interdiction of the Department of Justice.</text></clause><clause id="HCB00C59FD52645568FA6A5E1D54DDA45"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>A representative of the Behavioral Analysis Unit of the United States Marshals Service with subject matter expertise in child exploitation offenders who also commit contact offenses.</text></clause><clause id="H950745A69B0844009592538F419226A5"><enum>(v)</enum><text>A special agent of Homeland Security Investigations with expertise in both CyberTipline investigations and proactive online investigations.</text></clause><clause id="H28073DDB67514C26BB67D398BEA3C5DE"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>A subject matter expert within Homeland Security Investigations with expertise in child victim identification.</text></clause><clause id="H82C170EA541746AFA858D0CA9EABF182"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>A special agent of the Federal Bureau of Investigation with expertise in both CyberTipline investigations and proactive online investigations and the use of polygraphs in child sexual abuse material investigations.</text></clause><clause id="H1B73C876599641BDAECA21BAE1822F43"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>A representative from the National Children’s Alliance with expertise in child exploitation and child victim forensic interviewing.</text></clause><clause id="H84DBBD9ECA02410E8034CB188C486063"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>A special agent of the United States Secret Service with expertise in investigations of child sexual abuse material or polygraphs of child sexual exploitation suspects.</text></clause><clause id="H2A984D9D68AB4C6797C79D100E13A4CE"><enum>(x)</enum><text>A Postal Inspector at the United States Postal Inspection Service with expertise in child sexual abuse material investigations.</text></clause><clause id="HAFB52D564B7547C9BF5669DA4AEA26C0"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>A representative from the National District Attorney’s Association.</text></clause><clause id="H6CFCC191BB1C40E9ABD56DFAB8C0F747"><enum>(xii)</enum><text>A representative from the academic community with expertise in developing technology that can proactively detect the distribution of child sexual abuse material online.</text></clause><clause id="H19B9C64E51334B85830D36F553D0EB8A"><enum>(xiii)</enum><text>A representative of the Office of Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention with expertise in available data sources and methods for developing prevalence estimates using direct and indirect methods of estimation.</text></clause><clause id="H1F6207CCDF6C4CFFA6A3A4C2419DE00F"><enum>(xiv)</enum><text>A representative of the Executive Office of the United States Attorney.</text></clause><clause id="H4187F3A87EED4DCB8009B4F739D93277"><enum>(xv)</enum><text>A recently retired Internet Crimes Against Children Task Force Commander.</text></clause><clause id="H4E416C9DC7E44E12AAFC923446AA4E24"><enum>(xvi)</enum><text>A representative from National Child Protection Task Force.</text></clause><clause id="H8B78CD65258C47579EC92B85B9EF9392"><enum>(xvii)</enum><text>Representatives from the Department of Justice Office of Tribal Justice and the Bureau of Indian Affairs Office of Justice Services.</text></clause><clause id="HE326FF0727C9491B93F45C1324007711"><enum>(xviii)</enum><text>A representative of the Rape, Abuse &amp; Incest National Network with subject matter expertise on child sexual exploitation and abuse.</text></clause><clause id="H075FB8575C14450B9238127255D5ADFE"><enum>(xix)</enum><text>A representative of the International Justice Mission with subject matter expertise on cross-border, live-streamed child sexual abuse.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H24C8056068A44BB2822458F6CC0D82A2"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text>The Working Group shall establish a Technical Assistance Board to provide guidance and technical assistance to the Working Group, composed of the following: </text><clause id="H09A62515F7C646F0BE1BA909D557792D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>A representative from the ICAC Child Online Protection System (ICACCOPS) at the National Criminal Justice Training Center with subject matter expertise on child sexual exploitation and abuse investigations.</text></clause><clause id="HC6EAC5E47A1A4699BFA8952A99D77419"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A representative from the Child Rescue Coalition with subject matter expertise on the Child Protection System and other child sexual exploitation and abuse investigations.</text></clause><clause id="H4B85E9483A414924B7070C0CC9B8652A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>A representative from the National Center for Missing and Exploited Children with subject matter expertise on child sexual exploitation and abuse and child victim identification.</text></clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">The Working Group shall consult with the members of the Technical Assistance Board throughout the execution of its duties under subsection (b). Representatives of the Technical Assistance Board under paragraph (1) from each organization shall have the right to be present at each Working Group meeting.</continuation-text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBBF6050FEF5D4A5D813F1C0DC43B9F2D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Cessation of membership</header><text>If an individual is appointed to the Working Group based on membership in an agency or organization and the individual ceases to be a member of that agency or organization, the individual shall cease to be a member of the Working Group on the date on which the member ceases to be a member of the agency or organization.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1B033728DE5A472DAD96BF58847A2EB4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Terms</header><text>A member of the Working Group shall be appointed for the life of the Working Group.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H442F88C0687E452B8CB1302A50F54313"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Vacancies</header><subparagraph id="H805AE18094534B199038E450A56EACE5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Vacancy before expiration of term</header><text>A member appointed to the Working Group to fill a vacancy occurring before the expiration of the term for which the member’s predecessor was appointed shall be appointed only for the remainder of that term.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H426B0E6333E6468C863D162F28B0F5A6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Manner of appointment</header><text>A vacancy in the Working Group shall be filled in the manner in which the original appointment was made.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H03F4570B23AB49388AF6F3A47ECB2849"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Compensation</header><text>A member of the Working Group shall serve without pay. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC674491FEACC431E97305C3BCEA5C3CE"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Quorum</header><text>A majority of the members of the Working Group shall constitute a quorum, but a lesser number may hold hearings.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1153AB9AD72B44998790672F6744F873"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Chairperson</header><text>The Chairperson of the Working Group shall be appointed by the Attorney General from the membership of the Working Group. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA20C9F8FA41D4C0FAF838CCE8800C5A7"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text>The Working Group shall hold virtual meetings monthly, and any subgroup of the Working Group shall hold additional meetings as necessary.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6A41DB4511A24A3880816354C76EAF4F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Staff of working group; experts and consultants</header><paragraph id="HCA93622C44504995BF8AD6BEEBE426E8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Staff</header><text>The Chairperson of the Working Group may appoint and fix the pay of additional personnel as the Chairperson considers appropriate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3E8E5F390E1F4782907121B97FBC04AA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Experts and consultants</header><text>The Chairperson of the Working Group may procure temporary and intermittent services under section 3109(b) of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H832374C0F9D341178BC870B5A91E646D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Detailees</header><text>Upon request of the Chairperson of the Working Group, the head of any Federal department or agency may detail, on a reimbursable basis, any of the personnel of that department or agency to the Working Group to assist in carrying out the duties of the Working Group under this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBC9C815EAA514068B7326D67F3AACB79"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Powers of the working group</header><paragraph id="H50F23619A73F454BB5F813BB391DF943" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Subpoena power</header><subparagraph id="H9F2E95D5D2DB4B2FA0D1E83A6DA08D79" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>By Working group</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Working may subpoena witnesses and records related to the purposes of this Act.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB113E8F74DD74A1E8E46950D72ECE265" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text>The district courts of the United States have jurisdiction to enforce a subpoena issued under this section. Trial is in the district in which the proceeding is conducted. The court may punish a refusal to obey a subpoena as a contempt of court. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3FE010CBFC3A439DB21B2D35B5B1642A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Hearings and Sessions</header><subparagraph id="H706A2F67774E4314821613ED67945B48"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Working Group may, for the purpose of carrying out this Act, hold hearings, sit and act at times and places, take testimony, and receive evidence as the Working Group considers appropriate.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H937EF771D57D4949ABDA2F47212CA069"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Witnesses</header><text>The Working Group may administer oaths or affirmations to witnesses appearing before the Working Group.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFD5BA12FF3E849439EF1BE6BE53DC186"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Powers of members and agents</header><text>Any member or agent of the Working Group may, if authorized by the Chairperson, take any action that the Working Group is authorized to take under this Section, including requesting information.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE25DBE5344384C0FB8B7766744608FBC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Obtaining Official Information</header><subparagraph id="H94EB7FF3DF484292B8D7A0151731EA2B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>United States Agencies and Departments</header><clause id="H5A41A4E18AF04B6F9A25C19DB7B4D7D9"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Working Group may secure directly from any department or agency of the United States information necessary to enable the Working Group to carry out this Act.</text></clause><clause id="H03BED95AE2F84C9296A068D889AAEDCF"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Furnishing information</header><text>Upon request of the Chairperson of the Working Group for information solicited pursuant to subsection (b), the head of the department or agency of the United States shall furnish that information to the Working Group.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HED21857AB3DA423CB00388F2BDF6526C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>State and Local Information</header><clause id="HB7A5B51651D045668255FE39A9C77259"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Working Group may obtain and review information and data from State and local departments and agencies for purposes of carrying out this Act.</text></clause><clause id="H27D1DE8C04CA42C59436DEE2092F7B8D"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Costs</header><text>The Working Group shall pay reasonable costs to state and local agencies for records obtained pursuant to subsection (b).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAEA4C234C0F7466EA2579827901F18F8" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Clearance for members of Working Group</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case that the Working Group interacts with controlled unclassified information, the Working Group shall follow all laws, regulations, and government-wide policies with respect to such information. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H494ADB95D8C84A9593FFF90E3CFC1228"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Termination of working group</header><paragraph id="HD840A16DA40848CDB27673D34647166D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Working Group shall terminate 120 days after submission of the report under section 9, unless the Attorney General determines that such termination is not appropriate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC425752E162F4A958B8512D1020FA030"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reconvening group</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Working Group terminates under subsection (a), the Attorney General may reconvene the Working Group in accordance with this Act. If the Attorney General reconvenes the Working Group, the Working Group shall be convened in accordance with this section. The Attorney General may re-appoint members to the Working Group who served a previous term if the Working Group is reconvened.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H972A156930BD4CB7974D605FD2E7E3C1"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H816379A8197D43FA9E1F354E496878D0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Child</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>child</quote> means any individual under the age of eighteen years. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H928CAE23618F4C89A6B85F5FBC38D3DC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Child sexual abuse material</header><text>The term <term>child sexual abuse material</term> shall have the meaning given the term <term>child pornography</term> in section 2256 of title 18, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6D8744E313EE41379361BD6D6C457D92"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Crime involving sexual contact</header><text>The term <quote>crime involving sexual contact</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="H0D2745EAEC0B4220B30F15EF6F6B07B2"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an offense involving a child under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/109A">chapter 109A</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, or any attempt or conspiracy to commit such an offense; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBE8FF39AE7E04480928E9629392856A6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an offense involving a child under a State or Tribal statute that is similar to a provision described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7ACDD45D0DEA47CEB2A34524937E0C16"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Known to law enforcement</header><text>The term <term>known to law enforcement</term> means that a Federal, State, Tribal, or local law enforcement agency has evidence of a crime that can be attributed to a person or location, including an email address, Internet Protocol address, screen name, universally unique identifier, phone number, or other information attributable to that person or location.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC1F0B0DC1F9C4EBEAA749E04A6F50B9A" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Law enforcement agency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>law enforcement agency</quote> means an agency of the Federal Government, a State, a political subdivision of a State, or a federally recognized tribe that is authorized by law to supervise the prevention, detection, investigation, or prosecution of any violation of criminal law. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBA08C83F9F7540C688B52C640207D72C"><enum>(6)</enum><header>NCMEC</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>NCMEC</quote> means the National Center for Missing &amp; Exploited Children. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD0F1F8A3EDC54AB5BCB37B1C5ECA9320" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Proactive policing</header><text>The term <term>proactive policing</term> means a covert or undercover investigation conducted by a law enforcement agency that involves a person or organization that the law enforcement agency believes is engaging or has engaged in an offense or violation relating to child sexual abuse, child sexual abuse material, child exploitation, or child sex trafficking crimes.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H48447BDD094F4047B8021CDBCFB44623"><enum>(8)</enum><header>State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>State</quote> means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, or any other territory or possession of the United States. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H282B3E8AD0F7411BBD001356F3DAD6B3"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Victim-centric</header><text>The term <term>victim-centric</term> refers to the systematic focus on the needs and concerns of a victim to ensure that services are delivered in a compassionate, sensitive, non-judgmental, and culturally considerate manner that seeks to minimize retraumatization associated with the criminal justice process by providing the support of victim advocates and service providers, empowering victims as engaged participants in the process, and providing victims an opportunity to play a role in seeing their abusers brought to justice.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9D94302DCA374A21BC159325D53DCA10"><enum>(10)</enum><header>United States</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>United States</quote> means the 50 States of the United States of America and the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, the Virgin Islands, American Samoa, Wake Island, Midway Islands, Kingman Reef, Johnston Atoll, the Northern Mariana Islands, and any other trust territory or possession of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

