<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7270B751E5C84BD0AD5ECA7CF45E93C4" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1483 IH: Protecting Investors’ Personally Identifiable Information Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1483</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250221">February 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000583">Mr. Loudermilk</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="W000812">Mrs. Wagner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001204">Mr. Meuser</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001058">Mr. Huizenga</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the Securities and Exchange Commission from requiring that personally identifiable information be collected under consolidated audit trail reporting requirements, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H4A7E7E4170B34B1D9B72C86E4D286225" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H762C6B839A474E128EB7D6DC697CA986" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting Investors’ Personally Identifiable Information Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section> <section id="H4471D4707A4E404BAD824ED183F7E5A5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Personally identifiable information excluded from consolidated audit trail reporting requirements</header> <subsection id="H3420C9422D0E4BDA9D5164CB86D1F0ED"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Securities and Exchange Commission may not require a national securities exchange, a national securities association, or a member of such an exchange or association to provide personally identifiable information with respect to a market participant to meet the requirements relating to an order or a reportable event under section 242.613(c)(7) of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations). </text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3E31945670AC47D0BA612901490C51A0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definition of personally identifiable information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>personally identifiable information</term> means information that can be used to distinguish or trace an individual’s identity, either alone or when combined with other personal or identifying information that is linked or linkable to a specific individual, including an individual’s name, address, date or year of birth, Social Security number, telephone number, email, and IP-address.</text> </subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

