<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H68173CF01E9E4816A8C376361AF22D89" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4490 IH: Providing Appropriate Recognition and Treatment Needed to Enhance Relations Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4490</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250717">July 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001091">Mr. Castro of Texas</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="K000397">Mrs. Kim</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000176">Mr. Olszewski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000301">Mr. Johnson of South Dakota</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001055">Mr. Case</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000600">Mrs. Radewagen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000454">Mr. Foster</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001127">Mrs. Cherfilus-McCormick</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the International Organizations Immunities Act to extend diplomatic privileges and immunities to certain additional international and regional organizations, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HEC3FEFABA5914FF8B6DD5806340EA263" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HD535DE297DC84E1AA01039415B63F716" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Providing Appropriate Recognition and Treatment Needed to Enhance Relations Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>PARTNER Act</short-title></quote>.</text> <toc container-level="legis-body-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"> <toc-entry idref="HD535DE297DC84E1AA01039415B63F716" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="HAE9A9B4CC0864B60B0FEBCCE477E95D4" level="section">Sec. 2. Extension of diplomatic privileges and immunities to the Association of Southeast Asian Nations.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H806EFA0ED0DA4AB3BA3ACF48D5430C6E" level="section">Sec. 3. Extension of diplomatic privileges and immunities to the European Organization For Nuclear Research (CERN).</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="HFD61E6D7EE3D4D25AEAE18D52A6C1412" level="section">Sec. 4. Extension of diplomatic privileges and immunities to the Pacific Islands Forum.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="HA1187087E2A64D4FB970E85FDCCA51FE" level="section">Sec. 5. Extension of diplomatic privileges and immunities to the Caribbean Community.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H9E27F8ED93F74C87840D57AF366F7A61" level="section">Sec. 6. Extension of certain privileges and immunities to the African Union.</toc-entry> </toc></section> <section id="HAE9A9B4CC0864B60B0FEBCCE477E95D4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Extension of diplomatic privileges and immunities to the Association of Southeast Asian Nations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The International Organizations Immunities Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/288">22 U.S.C. 288 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HD3C8AF120F574DD4A839ECEB523AFD48" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H30EEF57B34B04CFEB6AF4FCE99655F77"><enum>18.</enum><header>Extension of diplomatic privileges and immunities to the Association of Southeast Asian Nations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Under such terms and conditions as the President shall determine, the President is authorized to extend the provisions of this title to the Association of Southeast Asian Nations in the same manner, to the same extent, and subject to the same conditions, as it may be extended to a public international organization in which the United States participates pursuant to any treaty or under the authority of any Act of Congress authorizing such participation or making an appropriation for such participation.</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section id="H806EFA0ED0DA4AB3BA3ACF48D5430C6E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Extension of diplomatic privileges and immunities to the European Organization For Nuclear Research (CERN)</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The International Organizations Immunities Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/288">22 U.S.C. 288 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H331175E2FF9541A29CFC71DFE04433F1" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H0B1F11A0324942B388AACFA924FFC562"><enum>19.</enum><header>Extension of diplomatic privileges and immunities to the European Organization For Nuclear Research (CERN)</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Under such terms and conditions as the President shall determine, the President is authorized to extend the provisions of this title to the European Organization for Nuclear Research (CERN) in the same manner, to the same extent, and subject to the same conditions, as it may be extended to a public international organization in which the United States participates pursuant to any treaty or under the authority of any Act of Congress authorizing such participation or making an appropriation for such participation.</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section id="HFD61E6D7EE3D4D25AEAE18D52A6C1412"><enum>4.</enum><header>Extension of diplomatic privileges and immunities to the Pacific Islands Forum</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The International Organizations Immunities Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/288">22 U.S.C. 288 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H66AD9B3125A141A3BA9A1B10A3F5F409" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HB36E84F289A74D1EA9FA115F0653212A"><enum>20.</enum><header>Extension of diplomatic privileges and immunities to the Pacific Islands Forum</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Under such terms and conditions as the President shall determine, the President is authorized to extend the provisions of this title to the Pacific Islands Forum in the same manner, to the same extent, and subject to the same conditions, as it may be extended to a public international organization in which the United States participates pursuant to any treaty or under the authority of any Act of Congress authorizing such participation or making an appropriation for such participation.</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section id="HA1187087E2A64D4FB970E85FDCCA51FE"><enum>5.</enum><header>Extension of diplomatic privileges and immunities to the Caribbean Community</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The International Organizations Immunities Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/288">22 U.S.C. 288 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H2CE0433A957049C8AF4A47DB42E443EB" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H404B9C5061C94E5985D0273095EE8D25"><enum>21.</enum><header>Extension of diplomatic privileges and immunities to the Caribbean Community</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Under such terms and conditions as the President shall determine, the President is authorized to extend the provisions of this title to the Caribbean Community in the same manner, to the same extent, and subject to the same conditions, as it may be extended to a public international organization in which the United States participates pursuant to any treaty or under the authority of any Act of Congress authorizing such participation or making an appropriation for such participation.</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section id="H9E27F8ED93F74C87840D57AF366F7A61"><enum>6.</enum><header>Extension of certain privileges and immunities to the African Union</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 12(b) of the International Organizations Immunities Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/288f-2">22 U.S.C. 288f–2(b)</external-xref>) is amended:</text> 
<paragraph id="H6A9B75AD3A5346E59A970C0166E3262B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>to extend, or enter into an agreement to extend, to the African Union Mission</quote> and inserting <quote>to extend, or enter into an agreement to extend—</quote>;</text> <quoted-block id="H003C0123A99E48149E1E47F486AF35FF" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H86E6D4D755D24531B6324994BB52EC17"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to the African Union Mission</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H432D5A09E6374DF1BA2BA0233A55DA13"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5850644CBC544E1493ABB34204EB2B1E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H7794A7C9592F4A9C8D26B4B854C3364C" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="H0710C178962547578C7676265394FB3D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to the permanent observer mission of the African Union to the United Nations in New York, and to its members, the privileges and immunities enjoyed by the permanent missions to the United Nations of member states, and their members, subject to corresponding conditions and obligations.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

