<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="HA9B479C6E7BB4727A58083229A49793C"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5609 IH: Stop RFK’s Bad Science Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5609</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250926">September 26, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001215">Ms. Stevens</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the National Institutes of Health to reinstate funding to recipients of grants or other awards, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H61F20796C3BA4BF1A8F4F67FA2BB2168"><section id="H3279912EBBC645628D115E076B9447EA" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop RFK’s Bad Science Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Stop RFK’s BS Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HA152AF0B189346159A915048306CF289"><enum>2.</enum><header>Reinstatement of funding for national institutes of health grants and other awards</header><subsection id="HF26212E78F1946059DF0B8B76A140D4B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Effective beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, any covered grants or awards terminated or suspended during the period beginning on January 20, 2025, and ending on the date of the enactment of this Act, shall be, unless the Director makes a finding of financial mismanagement, research fraud, or malfeasance with respect to such grants or awards—</text><paragraph id="H616D198EC66344B1AF34F41FB52CE4EC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>reinstated; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H52C339C3C51A48E7B1D0D7D22A7DA361"><enum>(2)</enum><text>considered obligated.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H584A54EBA6204F9792FC35202E6F77C8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Approved requests</header><text>A payment request made by the recipient of a covered grant or award to a National Institutes of Health official with respect to such covered grant or award shall be disbursed as soon as possible, and in no case later than 30 calendar days after the date on which such a payment request is submitted to the National Institutes of Health official.</text></subsection><subsection id="H132D35E8A7A74D97937C3928CE83CA58"><enum>(c)</enum><header>1-Year extension of term</header><text>In the case of a covered grant or award that is reinstated or disbursed under subsection (a) or (b) (as the case may be), the budget period of such grant or award shall be extended for a 1-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD0F50E2043764393B7CC5CFBD5297D75"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HC310D3019E7D4B0EB820B2DEA0367F3E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Budget period</header><text>The term <quote>budget period</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 1.2 of the document entitled <quote>NIH Grants Policy Statement</quote>, published in April 2024 by the National Institutes of Health.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H77E1B3254E2B4321A5A4AC428CC30066"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered grant or award</header><text>The term <quote>covered grant or award</quote> means a grant or other award made by a National Institutes of Health official under a provision of law administered by such an official.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H01EF7C7107AF467A9D36F5155B1F5285"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The term <quote>Director</quote> means the Director of the National Institutes of Health.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8C6EC82746514AB5A6FC9C5AC8C8992F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>National institutes of health official</header><text>The term <quote>National Institutes of Health official</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="H25916F36A18F4539A462E99C0F00213F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Director; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H63F73610325F44C7ADB63E878665E78D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other official within the National Institutes of Health with responsibility for making a grant or award of Federal funds under a provision of law administered by the Director or such other official.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

