<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF683B507C11E4B85B2CE158931570128" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3438 IH: Fair Wage Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3438</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250515">May 15, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="G000600">Ms. Perez</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to provide for a Federal, cost-of-living based minimum wage, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H5B86FDE3E4E7478299E99340730E6A3C" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H2629E773FD964829B4206D83D6BE4EFC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Fair Wage Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HFA45FE920FCB4A2F9B2E3A47DBA7E8E9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Cost-of-living based minimum wage</header> <subsection id="HDBDBB503FBE94A91BD5434774225C027"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 6(a)(1) of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/206">29 U.S.C. 206(a)(1)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
<quoted-block id="H13ACE1FC29664C1AB19F8561199943DD" style="OLC">
<paragraph id="H41F28E8B34E34DAAB5E58435DB446244"><enum>(1)</enum><text>except as otherwise provided in this section, not less than the amount determined by the Secretary under subsection (h) for the metropolitan statistical area or the nonmetropolitan portion in which the employer resides;</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H8BBC1F0BCC3C48EA950380B10E6E859C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Determination of regional minimum wage</header><text>Section 6 of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/206">29 U.S.C. 206</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block id="H65227C09E8E34B7FB287EF02BAC171D8" style="OLC">
<subsection id="H5E8BFDC97BC94930AB2580614133AD25"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Determination of minimum wage</header>
<paragraph id="H31FD74BF37014CD599205164B001C0BC"><enum>(1)</enum>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HB722ADFA213B479ABD0A773C6DF55281"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On the effective date of the <short-title>Fair Wage Act of 2025</short-title>, the wage determined under this paragraph for a metropolitan statistical area or nonmetropolitan portion shall be equal to the result obtained—</text> <clause id="H9FD5A73B12AC4864818C1F45E7E9AF54" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by multiplying—</text>
<subclause id="H1A4B2568787D4105BC5E2DDC2C378B26"><enum>(I)</enum><text>40 percent of the national average hourly wage of private sector, non-supervisory workers (as reported by the Bureau of Labor Statistics of the Department of Labor for the most recent month for which data are available); by</text></subclause> <subclause id="HCC14F60ECBEC4135AFE0B51528C1DCA3"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the adjustment percentage specified in paragraph (2) for the area or portion; and</text></subclause></clause>
<clause id="H562633C75F474554BDB797363996591C" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by rounding the result obtained under clause (i) to the nearest tenth of a dollar.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCEC82D909F0D4EAC8731B0E9631C9AA1" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Not later than 1 year after such effective date, subparagraph (A)(i)(I) shall be applied by substituting <quote>45 percent</quote> for <quote>40 percent</quote>.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H554F6D72EF364559AD0DC6CD8F5AE3CC" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Not later than 2 years after such effective date, subparagraph (A)(i)(I) shall be applied by substituting <quote>50 percent</quote> for <quote>40 percent</quote>.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB3DD90BB3E2D40E1BB3E139A56A90EEC" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 5 years after such effective date, and for each 3-year period thereafter, the wage determined under this paragraph for a metropolitan statistical area or nonmetropolitan portion shall be equal to the greater of—</text>
<clause id="H294BE00A07AB4AD8A76B758EF2F63094"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the result obtained under subparagraph (C); or</text></clause> <clause id="HF23C1EF42C5C45F0A1D6F3193D8C5FBB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the wage determined under this paragraph for such area or portion for the preceding three-year period.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1ACCE11CFFE74D3A8648035CD6EA4DC3"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The adjustment percentage specified in this paragraph for a metropolitan statistical area or nonmetropolitan portion shall be—</text> <subparagraph id="HAE069819ED5C4CAA82CDC86D1D16D574"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">87.5 percent, for a metropolitan statistical area or nonmetropolitan portion with a regional price parity of less than 90;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H248177077CBF492E88614E305C805410"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">92.5 percent, for a metropolitan statistical area or nonmetropolitan portion with a regional price parity of less than 95, but not less than 90;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDE63FAD403F14BDEA51255FF9B35D543"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">100 percent, for a metropolitan statistical area or nonmetropolitan portion with a regional price parity of less than 105, but not less than 95;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H4CAC26D7CAC94C03BCD704EE1F471035"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">107.5 percent, for a metropolitan statistical area or nonmetropolitan portion with a regional price parity of less than 110, but not less than 105; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD6DFD7D795614F1FB07F42200F181440"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">115 percent, for a metropolitan statistical area or nonmetropolitan portion with a regional price parity of not less than 110.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA9939164DC2946CEB989C605F02649A4"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection:</text> <subparagraph id="H3DEC848F8CD641B887AEF357F9199D62"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>metropolitan statistical area</term> means a geographic area, defined by the Office of Management and Budget for statistical purposes, containing a large population nucleus and adjacent communities having a high degree of social and economic integration with that nucleus.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H68B0208C3A2F4A8DA197AC9B5631A1B9"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>nonmetropolitan portion</term> means any county (or portion thereof) which is not within a metropolitan statistical area. All nonmetropolitan portions of a State shall be treated, in aggregate, as a single nonmetropolitan portion for the State.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2B9E3BC6AA214E63971502A4E456C2A6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The term <term>regional price parity</term> means the regional price parity for a metropolitan statistical area or nonmetropolitan portion determined by the Bureau of Economic Analysis of the Department of Commerce for the most recent year for which data are available. In determining regional price parities for purposes of this subsection, the Bureau of Economic Analysis shall use the same methodology used to determine such parities for the most recent year for which such parities were reported by the Bureau before the date of the enactment of this subsection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section>
<section id="H9B6E0CC715574C8D9599B6B6D89CF793"><enum>3.</enum><header>Minimum cash wage for tipped employees</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Clause (i) of section 3(m)(2)(A) of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/203">29 U.S.C. 203(m)(2)(A)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>the cash wage required to be paid such an employee on the date of the enactment of this paragraph</quote> and inserting <quote>an amount equal to 30 percent of the wage determined under section 6(a)(1) for the metropolitan statistical area or the nonmetropolitan portion in which the employer resides</quote>.</text></section> <section id="H349122C6890F4C9ABCD65E8A838D224E"><enum>4.</enum><header>Minimum wage for newly hired employees who are 18 years old or younger</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 6(g) of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/206">29 U.S.C. 206(g)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="H4E3D59C9C8284E1DB8426209F010AF89"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>a wage which is not less than $4.25 an hour</quote> and inserting <quote>a wage which is not less than 2/3 of the wage determined under subsection (a)(1) for the metropolitan statistical area or the nonmetropolitan portion in which the employer resides</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H304C9D3E248E4022980F844ED2BC5491"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (5)—</text>
<subparagraph id="H03B1B7E4D2834A21B32F8EE01942F050"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>has not attained the age of 20 years</quote> and inserting <quote>is the age of 18 years or younger</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H922EDE6843B14EB0BD2BDD6D23735F6C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>25 years</quote> and inserting <quote>24 years or younger</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section>
<section id="H4B390597F85F4CDABCEEB354EC0F9049"><enum>5.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The amendments and repeals made by this Act shall take effect on the first day of the third month that begins after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></section> </legis-body></bill>

