<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-TAM25532-JDD-Y6-F4K"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1394 IS: Expanding Access to Family Planning Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1394</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250409">April 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S394">Ms. Smith</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S229">Mrs. Murray</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S366">Ms. Warren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S353">Mr. Schatz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S418">Mr. Fetterman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To provide enhanced funding for family planning services.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="idCB0477137C8147CD8F568093F7FF33A8"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Expanding Access to Family Planning Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id5DCCE326DF874489B99083A26781C4BA"><enum>2.</enum><header>Title X Clinic Fund</header><subsection id="idB820E14CEF664856A64FC277EF5323BC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is established a Title X Clinic Fund to be administered through the Office of the Secretary of the Department of Health and Human Services (referred to in this section as the <quote>Office of the Secretary</quote>), to provide for expanded and sustained national investment in clinics providing family planning services supported under title X of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300">42 U.S.C. 300 et seq.</external-xref>) (referred to in this section as <quote>title X clinics</quote>).</text></subsection><subsection id="id3d26227615e64013b3e6963b81edd8cc"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>There is appropriated to the Office of the Secretary for the Title X Clinic Fund, out of any monies in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2035—</text><paragraph id="id3A72CF775B384C1880B8B93B1A6D68E2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$512,000,000 for necessary expenses for grants and contracts under title X of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300">42 U.S.C. 300 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id38F8D1CFA29D4E09AF17DCA484D1529E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$50,000,000 for infrastructure, including the construction and renovation (including equipment) of title X clinics.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="iddde32749d58a4316bf54008d0aba5ee9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>Amounts appropriated under subsection (b) shall remain available until expended. </text></subsection><subsection id="id13f860a818aa43888b2255897ee075a6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Conditions on funding</header><paragraph id="id6162bf10601c4c46b17c8d5f7ffe037d"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>No recipient of funds made available under this section that makes a subaward for the provision of title X services may prohibit an entity from participating in such subaward program for reasons other than the entity's inability to provide such title X services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1cc6bbe1ba684ccba27df1703e82171c"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Pregnancy counseling</header><text>In the case of services provided by a title X clinic that receives funding made available under this section, all pregnancy counseling shall be nondirective, and, with respect to all patients of the title X clinic with a positive pregnancy test, the following shall apply:</text><subparagraph id="id4ad536abbaaa498893537775f7524c7e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>All such patients shall be given the opportunity to be provided information and counseling regarding each of the following options:</text><clause id="id03fda1fa2c0b4eb98fefbdb1cdcbe45e"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Prenatal care and delivery.</text></clause><clause id="idf5f0116d7ede44ca92290bbc66b94b98"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Infant care, foster care, and adoption.</text></clause><clause id="id0a8fabdd6bc14195bc5d8484f1ce06af"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Pregnancy termination.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida29e94030a204652b32f457a6a7bb76d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>If the patient requests such information and counseling, such patient shall be provided with neutral, factual information and nondirective counseling on each option described in subparagraph (A), including referral upon request, except with respect to any option about which the patient indicates no interest in receiving such information and counseling.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

