<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" slc-id="S1-NEW25392-PDG-GV-6H5"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 163 IS: Recognizing the contributions of Clela Rorex, a pioneering county clerk who, in 1975, advanced civil rights for all couples seeking to be married.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 163</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250409">April 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S330">Mr. Bennet</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S408">Mr. Hickenlooper</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing the contributions of Clela Rorex, a pioneering county clerk who, in 1975, advanced civil rights for all couples seeking to be married.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas Clela Ann Rorex (referred to in this preamble as <quote>Clela</quote>) was born in Denver on July 23, 1943;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas Ruby Rorex, the mother of Clela, was a dance and theater teacher, and Cecil Rorex, the father of Clela, served for 30 years as clerk of Routt County, Colorado, where Clela grew up in Steamboat Springs;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Clela earned her bachelor’s degree from the University of Colorado Boulder in 1973 and a master’s degree in Public Administration from the University of Colorado Denver in 1981;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in January 1975, at the age of 31, Clela became the Boulder County Clerk and Recorder;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 1975, when a same-sex couple requested a marriage license in Boulder County, Clela consulted the assistant district attorney and learned that Colorado state laws did not specifically prohibit granting a marriage license to a same-sex couple;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, as a newly elected county clerk, Clela issued a marriage license to Dave McCord and Dave Zamora, the first marriage license issued to a same-sex couple in the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Clela was quoted in 2016 as saying, <quote>After having been so deeply involved in the women’s rights movements, who was I to then deny a right to anyone else? It wasn’t my job to legislate morality.</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, after issuing the first marriage license to a same-sex couple in 1975, Clela issued 5 more marriage licenses to same-sex couples over the next month;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas national news outlets circulated the groundbreaking story of Clela issuing marriage licenses to same-sex couples, after which Clela reported receiving a deluge of death threats and condemnation in hundreds of letters and phone calls to the Boulder County Clerk’s office;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas, despite the threats, Clela continued her advocacy efforts on behalf of the LGBTQ community, including by marching, volunteering, and donating to LGBTQ efforts for decades;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2014, a series of court rulings cleared the way for same-sex marriages in Colorado, and, in 2015, the Supreme Court of the United States legalized same-sex marriage nationwide, 40 years after Clela issued the first same-sex marriage license in the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Clela was 78 years old when she died on June 19, 2022, in Longmont, Colorado;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in honor of Clela and her advocacy for human rights, Boulder County, Colorado, declared July 23, 2022, to be <quote>Clela Rorex Day</quote>; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Clela should be recognized for her leadership as a national civil rights leader, paving the way for countless individuals: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="S1"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id7045b9952e554e10aa71f19d7fa7d991"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognizes—</text><subparagraph id="id053D33E89B574672B3D404629FE5A49C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the contributions of Clela Rorex as a pioneer for civil rights and same-sex marriage;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC242D8036E4D4CFBA507BC6C22C8740A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the respect and bravery Clela Rorex demonstrated when issuing the first same-sex marriage license in the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD08F08D28E1342D8A320B999BA5EC534"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the courage Clela Rorex exhibited following the threats she received when she issued marriage licenses to same-sex couples; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id4f4ab8b2983d4b63a1fb2d8d687faf8f"><enum>(2)</enum><text>designates March 26, 2025, as <quote>Clela Rorex Day</quote>. </text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

