<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0C23A3B318C24E7DA68FE30D1FC29555" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 196 IH: Expressing support for the designation of the week beginning March 2, 2025, as “School Social Work Week”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 196</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250305">March 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S001221">Ms. Scholten</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of the week beginning March 2, 2025, as <quote>School Social Work Week</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text> Whereas the importance of school social work is recognized in the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6301">20 U.S.C. 6301 et seq.</external-xref>) and the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1400">20 U.S.C. 1400 et seq.</external-xref>) through the inclusion of school social work programs and services in such Acts;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas school social workers are especially skilled in providing services to students who face serious challenges to school success, including disability, poverty, discrimination, abuse, neglect, mental illness, homelessness, bullying, familial stressors, and other barriers to learning; </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas school social workers are more necessary now than at any time in recent memory, as more students are struggling with mental and behavioral health disorders, with nearly 1 in 6 children from 2 to 8 years old (17.4 percent) having a diagnosed mental, behavioral, or developmental disorder; </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas individuals who wish to access community mental health services often find such services unavailable, inaccessible, or inadequate; </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas school social workers, being licensed mental health professionals in schools in the United States, provide necessary assessment, interventions, counseling, family outreach, and community referrals; </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas school mental health programs are critical to early identification and intervention of mental health problems and in the provision of appropriate mental health services when needed; </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas school social workers maintain knowledge of school culture and school climate, which are necessary for responsible school safety planning; </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas fewer than 1 in 5 children in need of mental health services actually receive these services, and research indicates that school mental health programs improve educational outcomes by decreasing absences, dropout rates, and discipline referrals, while improving academic achievement; </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas school social workers serve as vital members of a school’s education team, playing a central role in creating partnerships between the home, school, and community to ensure student academic success; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the celebration of <quote>School Social Work Week</quote> during the week beginning March 2, 2025, highlights the vital role school social workers play in the lives of students in the United States: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H6958BF31DB774D9FA3E2151FCDBBBB92"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HEB5B116523A44E4E8F4EA8474149411D"><enum/><text>That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="H3CD360778D0348E19DDF501B4CAE93E1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the designation of <quote>School Social Work Week</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H398E96AFFA054B66A447B5F77E92CDBF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>honors and recognizes the contributions of school social workers to the successes of students in schools across the Nation; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H06DC268D8D4B4787ACFB53A3927EFD9F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>encourages the people of the United States to observe <quote>School Social Work Week</quote> with appropriate ceremonies and activities that promote awareness of the vital role of school social workers, in schools and in the community as a whole, in helping students prepare for their futures as productive citizens.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

