<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC63BD29C693A4C58956061ABAAEFB7FE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1007 IH: Antisemitism Awareness Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1007</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250205">February 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001222">Mr. Miller of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001217">Mr. Moskowitz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000478">Ms. Tenney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000133">Mr. Van Drew</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000598">Mr. LaLota</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000392">Mr. Kustoff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001306">Mr. Balderson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000450">Ms. Foxx</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000602">Ms. Gillen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000086">Mr. Owens</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000230">Mr. Davis of North Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000129">Mr. Valadao</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000401">Mr. Kiley of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000579">Mr. Ryan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000398">Mr. Kean</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000246">Mr. Edwards</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001313">Ms. Brown</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001228">Mr. Schmidt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000740">Mrs. Bice</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001194">Mr. Moolenaar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000459">Mr. Fleischmann</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000397">Mrs. Kim</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000317">Ms. Malliotakis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000379">Mr. Alford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001236">Mr. Moore of North Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000019">Mr. Obernolte</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001307">Mr. Baird</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000301">Mr. Johnson of South Dakota</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000609">Mr. Rutherford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001212">Mr. Stauber</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001126">Mr. Carey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000871">Mr. Mann</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000188">Mr. Norcross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001260">Mr. Buchanan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001233">Mr. Messmer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001133">Mr. Ciscomani</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000486">Mr. Torres of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000601">Mr. Goldman of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000446">Mr. Feenstra</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001091">Mrs. Hinson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000307">Mr. James</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000601">Mr. Landsman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001190">Mr. Schneider</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000795">Mr. Wilson of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001137">Mr. Crank</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000298">Mr. Estes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000600">Mr. Langworthy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000614">Mr. Pappas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001228">Ms. Maloy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001215">Mrs. Miller-Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000804">Mr. Wittman</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001215">Ms. Stevens</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for the consideration of a definition of antisemitism set forth by the International Holocaust Remembrance Alliance for the enforcement of Federal antidiscrimination laws concerning education programs or activities, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8110D73850B14AE297655679D749065D" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H6E211C2425A340E5BB50961B6EA8434C"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Antisemitism Awareness Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H095983FEA0384AC9B121985A572DD206"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text>
<paragraph id="H4B5203DD75394DE1ACBF0CD701E998A5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d">42 U.S.C. 2000d et seq.</external-xref>), prohibits discrimination on the basis of race, color, and national origin in programs and activities receiving Federal financial assistance;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H29F474B0FFE74D2D9BA3A079163DA254"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">while such title does not cover discrimination based solely on religion, individuals who face discrimination based on actual or perceived shared ancestry or ethnic characteristics do not lose protection under such title for also being members of a group that share a common religion; </text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HEDB910B95D4C43CE822C53FCB5077D15"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">discrimination against Jews may give rise to a violation of such title when the discrimination is based on race, color, or national origin, which can include discrimination based on actual or perceived shared ancestry or ethnic characteristics; </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5B0E98060D764AFD8E8D49FA0C36A646"><enum>(4)</enum><text>it is the policy of the United States to enforce such title against prohibited forms of discrimination rooted in antisemitism as vigorously as against all other forms of discrimination prohibited by such title; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5B36C7CF86B8414B815406D43F4B0B40"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">as noted in the U.S. National Strategy to Counter Antisemitism issued by the White House on May 25, 2023, it is critical to—</text> <subparagraph id="HB5C44776C77B4D02BEF40AD39048E097"><enum>(A)</enum><text>increase awareness and understanding of antisemitism, including its threat to America;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H3638D6BC4F114E64BDC320020601D6A4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>improve safety and security for Jewish communities; </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H140CB534C83B498885C34D922FB43E00"><enum>(C)</enum><text>reverse the normalization of antisemitism and counter antisemitic discrimination; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H3950EC3073254B3790A8D57E77579386"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">expand communication and collaboration between communities. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> <section id="H7BFA9F212E5A47409DC0FF02D2269829"><enum>3.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
<paragraph id="H0E54D31EFF5B4C9894346C5ABEB94BFE"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Antisemitism is on the rise in the United States and is impacting Jewish students in K–12 schools, colleges, and universities.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H99D9C57AC7E247A7A468B345F02E8053"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The International Holocaust Remembrance Alliance (referred to in this Act as the <quote>IHRA</quote>) Working Definition of Antisemitism is a vital tool which helps individuals understand and identify the various manifestations of antisemitism.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H3257928CF74740CABB0DA7FCBE85767C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>On December 11, 2019, Executive Order 13899 extended protections against discrimination under the Civil Rights Act of 1964 to individuals subjected to antisemitism on college and university campuses and tasked Federal agencies to consider the IHRA Working Definition of Antisemitism when enforcing title VI of such Act.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEBF78CF6B1B947A8968024E9144D479F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Since 2018, the Department of Education has used the IHRA Working Definition of Antisemitism when investigating violations of that title VI.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD64F9F83C8FE4FE9B6C9B97396B9FC53"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The use of alternative definitions of antisemitism impairs enforcement efforts by adding multiple standards and may fail to identify many of the modern manifestations of antisemitism.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB694B2DC59D348A4B83A80B2612ED716"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The White House released the first-ever United States National Strategy to Counter Antisemitism on May 25, 2023, making clear that the fight against this hate is a national, bipartisan priority that must be successfully conducted through a whole-of-government-and-society approach.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="HCA3B6E7E5BA648DCB0FD856600DE7847"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For purposes of this Act, the term <term>definition of antisemitism</term>—</text> <paragraph id="HD7A9FCEE15CA415CA59D8F92C8E7ED44"><enum>(1)</enum><text>means the definition of antisemitism adopted on May 26, 2016, by the IHRA, of which the United States is a member, which definition has been adopted by the Department of State; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9B10D6B62C9B4804BA4EC9D5167A9BD1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>includes the <quote>[c]ontemporary examples of antisemitism</quote> identified in the IHRA definition.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H07BA3CF3F68E42D7BD153249F598A8C7"><enum>5.</enum><header>Rule of construction for title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In reviewing, investigating, or deciding whether there has been a violation of title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d">42 U.S.C. 2000d et seq.</external-xref>) on the basis of race, color, or national origin, based on an individual’s actual or perceived shared Jewish ancestry or Jewish ethnic characteristics, the Department of Education shall take into consideration the definition of antisemitism as part of the Department’s assessment of whether the practice was motivated by antisemitic intent.</text></section>
<section id="H9D69F8CEFAEF4EF985EE74FDF6D3880A"><enum>6.</enum><header>Other rules of construction</header>
<subsection id="HA42A0940461C485E9A5326959C85095F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>General rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed—</text> <paragraph id="H5C7DB9BD645148168C1E58C2F6ECFDC9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to expand the authority of the Secretary of Education;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8BC19E53CDD045CFA93D1A1AF4B94062"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to alter the standards pursuant to which the Department of Education makes a determination that harassing conduct amounts to actionable discrimination; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFC0BB62E689745E9B538FAEAF7EEC8CE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to diminish or infringe upon the rights protected under any other provision of law that is in effect as of the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H624C1FDD32C74329BA45AC70CB7F5BF0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Constitutional protections</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to diminish or infringe upon any right protected under the First Amendment to the Constitution of the United States.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

