<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF16672D463BD49FB80C3624044791982" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3825 IH: Kelsey Smith Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3825</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250606">June 6, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001228">Mr. Schmidt</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="D000629">Ms. Davids of Kansas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000298">Mr. Estes</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M000871">Mr. Mann</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to require providers of a covered service to provide location information concerning the telecommunications device of a user of such service to an investigative or law enforcement officer or an employee or other agent of a public safety answering point in an emergency situation involving risk of death or serious physical harm or in order to respond to the user’s call for emergency services.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB6DBF47721B24C3C8A6F7CF8CFDE5BFE" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H13C70EEEC3EE41E18EE0493D114BBCDF"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Kelsey Smith Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H25CD773A056A4EF6A815BDD3F189E132"><enum>2.</enum><header>Required emergency disclosure of location information to law enforcement or public safety answering point</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 222 of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/222">47 U.S.C. 222</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H17285E758CF64E1D92AA438F7907DEB8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (d)—</text> <subparagraph id="H86A7649BFCF24C0B904D1BF0DFE4E241"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by redesignating subparagraphs (A), (B), and (C) as clauses (i), (ii), and (iii), respectively, and adjusting the margins accordingly;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H378BC16BA0D34904970AD1D89C7C1287"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (1) through (4) as subparagraphs (A) through (D), respectively, and adjusting the margins accordingly;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD177613E9E92484E884FD9723A72B3F9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), as so redesignated, by striking <quote>Nothing in this section</quote> and inserting the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB595D53A33874DB7B2F872E35179DA16"> 
<paragraph id="H2D2A7CAB052E47B994544524C7A2E4CA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Permitted disclosures</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H331F1687F93144E49C7EE421C8061661"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD9947A6585464FCFB605555CB5E5D29A"> 
<paragraph id="H3DA3CCFD71CC4F558691BADB187B0583"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Required emergency disclosure of location information to law enforcement or public safety answering point</header> 
<subparagraph id="HEB4B6372920C4E36B3F9E93EB9F5CB4B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Location information requests</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding subsections (a), (b), and (c), at the request of an investigative or law enforcement officer or an employee or other agent of a public safety answering point acting on behalf of such an officer, who is acting in the course of the official duties of the officer or agent, a provider of a covered service shall provide to the officer or agent the available location information of a telecommunications device without delay if the officer or agent asserts—</text> <clause id="H1DE0F2AA10524D7683A7C00867F427AA"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that the device was used to place a 9–1–1 call requesting emergency assistance during the preceding 48-hour period; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H342576A18861430B9BD71EE67D6BADEF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reasonable suspicion that the device is in the possession of an individual who is involved in an emergency situation that involves the risk of death or serious physical harm.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H05410CFF983D49B4A627946C4451D945"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Records of disclosed records</header><text>If an investigative or law enforcement officer, or an employee or other agent of a public safety answering point acting on behalf of such an officer, submits a request for location information to a provider of a covered service under subparagraph (A), the investigative or law enforcement agency employing the officer shall maintain a record of the request that includes each of the following:</text> 
<clause id="HBF8258FF27134D57B72CF35353438FEA"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The name of the officer or agent making the request (and, in the case of a request made by an agent, the name of the officer on whose behalf the agent is acting).</text></clause> <clause id="H5668532974F24162889452CCB7C0977F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A description of the request that explains the need for disclosure of location information.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H2AA0364DAF41484F9E17C8D6F5DE96DA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>A declaration that disclosure of location information is needed based on the conditions described in clause (i) or (ii) of subparagraph (A).</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H37C4F968F922472C8E478EA63B97724F"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Hold harmless</header><text>No cause of action shall lie in any court, nor shall any civil or administrative proceeding be commenced by any person or entity, against a provider of a covered service, or its directors, officers, employees, agents, or vendors, for providing location information or assistance in accordance with subparagraph (A) and any regulations promulgated under this paragraph.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H696DC5F2082447D9BDC321AD973DCD81"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Relationship to State law</header> 
<clause id="H76AE31E461E84A91AB0114224CA49DE8"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Nothing in this section exempts a telecommunications carrier or a provider of a covered service from complying, in a circumstance described in clause (ii), with any applicable State law that requires the carrier or provider to provide location information of a telecommunications device to an investigative or law enforcement officer or an employee or other agent of a public safety answering point acting on behalf of such an officer in response to a request by the officer or agent.</text></clause> <clause commented="no" id="HD34AC78DDC2B49988001F155DFD5EA2D"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>A circumstance described in this clause is a circumstance in which the officer or agent—</text> 
<subclause commented="no" id="H1EDAA39BC50049EF8B4A0CFE2031D5F8"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">makes the request while acting in the course of the official duties of the officer or agent; and</text></subclause> <subclause commented="no" id="H3BEBF9C4354146B7A70C4AC15B812010"><enum>(II)</enum><text>asserts that the request is made for the purpose of responding to—</text> 
<item commented="no" id="H1067FE66B295408B9AFC3FF444299155"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>a call for emergency services; or</text></item> <item commented="no" id="HD9F2771B288F4E13A46A39B54C72B89A"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an emergency situation that involves the risk of death or serious physical harm.</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H126F024A1FD6434194C9785EA7BAFDB5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (f)(1), by striking <quote>subsection (d)(4)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (d)(1)(D)</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEE60435116FF4222A41647ED238BE3E8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (h), by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB35CBA6DC7C14B8ABE113673B4F9B785"> 
<paragraph id="HD7E16293556847E3AB63148DC907CD50"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Covered service</header><text>The term <term>covered service</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HDC62A84C07C64D829823272DB5B35855"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a commercial mobile service (as defined in section 332(d)); or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBBA7AA55CA684BFEB9F7159E07353368"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an IP-enabled voice service (as defined in section 7 of the Wireless Communications and Public Safety Act of 1999 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/615b">47 U.S.C. 615b</external-xref>)).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H61BF7FFC1A96493BBEE27AED9F5B8D9E"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Investigative or law enforcement officer</header><text>The term <term>investigative or law enforcement officer</term> has the meaning given the term <term>Investigative or law enforcement officer</term> in section 2510 of title 18, United States Code.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H159B4FA062B0449D8CB3E7E06405C974"><enum>3.</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2707(a) of title 18, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <quote>Except as provided in section 2703(e)</quote> the following: <quote>of this title and section 222(d)(2)(C) of the Communications Act of 1934</quote>.</text></section> </legis-body></bill>

