<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA0CB7B0FD18E4D00898A2BF8194E4695" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5050 IH: Safety and Opportunity for Girls Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5050</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250826">August 26, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001211">Mrs. Miller of Illinois</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="M000194">Ms. Mace</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001086">Mrs. Harshbarger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001115">Mr. Cloud</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001309">Mr. Burchett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000825">Ms. Boebert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000576">Mr. Grothman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001325">Mrs. Biggs of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000596">Mrs. Luna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000578">Mr. LaMalfa</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000469">Mr. Fulcher</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To clarify protections related to sex and sex-segregated spaces and to activities under title IX of the Education Amendments of 1972.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HFD82CE687BB84084AF83C4100F53B59C" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HD24BB091E7EF42C79D475A84BD692206" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Safety and Opportunity for Girls Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H9027289F18374A908CA3D007C9F3CB38"><enum>2.</enum><header>Amendment to title IX of the Education Amendments of 1972</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 901 of title IX of the Education Amendments of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1681">20 U.S.C. 1681</external-xref>) is amended by adding at end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HC4DD073E715D411E86A0D54E44865813" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="H8912D236F22A43609F9B2DD8EB8E2C2C"><enum>(d)</enum><text>For purposes of this title:</text> <paragraph id="H03A4C4C0AF1946D3B794D95EF90CADB8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Female</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>female</quote>, when used to refer to a natural person, means an individual who naturally has, had, will have, or would have, but for a congenital anomaly, historical accident, or intentional or unintentional disruption, the reproductive system that at some point produces, transports, and utilizes eggs for fertilization.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H25CAEBEC80AC4E748F7F9568A210E487"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Male</header><text>The term <quote>male</quote>, when used to refer to a natural person, means an individual who naturally has, had, will have, or would have, but for a congenital anomaly, historical accident, or intentional or unintentional disruption, the reproductive system that at some point produces, transports, and utilizes sperm for fertilization.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8316F8B7D3DC4FA0B343C14E81A5DE54"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Sex</header><text>The term <quote>sex</quote>, when referring to an individual’s sex, means to refer to either male or female, as biologically determined.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H129A11E1734149FFAA1504163B63F2C2"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Sex-segregated</header><text>The term <quote>sex-segregated</quote> means limited to or separated by sex.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H5A77F695AC0D48168EC5098AD37D3E6F"><enum>(e)</enum><text>Nothing in this title may be construed—</text> 
<paragraph id="H19D75D1AED5A46A085BC5B8DC192D27A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to prohibit, to authorize the Secretary to prohibit, or to authorize the Secretary to make receipt of funding under this title contingent upon an educational institution forgoing the maintenance of sex-segregated spaces by educational institutions, including bathrooms and locker rooms; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5E5D6BAA9409460E878D79FD8C41F04A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to prohibit, to authorize the Secretary to prohibit, or to authorize the Secretary to make receipt of funding under this title contingent upon an educational institution forgoing the maintenance of sex-segregated athletic or academic programs by educational institutions.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

