<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD94A56510D9F4488BF2871F1E468A95A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2441 IH: Improving Disclosure for Investors Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2441</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250327">March 27, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001058">Mr. Huizenga</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001213">Mr. Steil</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="A000148">Mr. Auchincloss</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for the electronic delivery of certain regulatory document required under the securities laws.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0D2807ED32EE4DB081D79A510BE84205" style="OLC"><section id="H3EAD29A16F3B4E47A7178B3A145247E9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Improving Disclosure for Investors Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H3071E25768004B899FE0F265F735FC14"><enum>2.</enum><header>Electronic delivery</header><subsection id="H13B4D85D1E514397AC35BD7DE7FF5D58"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Promulgation of rules</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Securities and Exchange Commission shall propose and, not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this section, the Commission shall finalize, rules, regulations, amendments, or interpretations, as appropriate, to allow a covered entity to satisfy the entity’s obligation to deliver regulatory documents required under the securities laws to investors using electronic delivery.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF9BF14138C984D4BB482D53C6D67C7D3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Required provisions</header><text>Rules, regulations, amendments, or interpretations the Commission promulgates pursuant to subsection (a) shall:</text><paragraph id="HE6D4F5EE18734438BD2C8C5DC23C862C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>With respect to investors that do not receive all regulatory documents by electronic delivery, provide for—</text><subparagraph id="H97E2C89B853149D7A46F3D281288CCB6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>delivery of an initial communication in paper form regarding electronic delivery;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H60974ED8A9D04C72989407E459C9CEEA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a transition period not to exceed 180 days until such regulatory documents are delivered to such investors by electronic delivery; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE0E33986D18A45F2BF6E4094DA9EE957"><enum>(C)</enum><text>during a period not to exceed 2 years following the transition period set forth in subparagraph (B), delivery of an annual notice in paper form solely reminding such investors of the ability to opt out of electronic delivery at any time and receive paper versions of regulatory documents.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H07C37895BA6F41A6931953BFAF8B46AA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Set forth requirements for the content of the initial communication described in paragraph (1)(A).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD325076AE5344B67BC8A1115DF90DE60"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Set forth requirements for the timing of delivery of a notice of website availability of regulatory documents and the content of the appropriate notice described in subsection (f)(3)(B).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE1B8F276145040A282A51344BB0094C6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Provide a mechanism for investors to opt out of electronic delivery at any time and receive paper versions of regulatory documents.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF1A85FEC15C048A4902E8F6C405F320F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Require measures reasonably designed to identify and remediate failed electronic deliveries of regulatory documents.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H328E9DBB13754B3AB10A0B8C9A4F024E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Set forth minimum requirements regarding readability and retainability for regulatory documents that are delivered electronically.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF0CD86A15CBE401C8CC6342D21EEC450"><enum>(7)</enum><text>For covered entities other than brokers, dealers, investment advisers registered with the Commission, and investment companies, require measures reasonably designed to ensure the confidentiality of personal information in regulatory documents that are delivered to investors electronically.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5B17603286784A7EAB63C347335F949F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed as altering the substance or timing of any regulatory document obligation under the securities laws or regulations of a self-regulatory organization.</text></subsection><subsection id="H50FA9E5EBC7A484BB0CC3B2145890C97"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Treatment of revisions not completed in a timely manner</header><text>If the Commission fails to finalize the rules, regulations, amendments, or interpretations required under subsection (a) before the date specified in such subsection—</text><paragraph id="H6BCA65BB7A1C42BAAFFE4F6E946C9802"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a covered entity may deliver regulatory documents using electronic delivery in accordance with subsections (b) and (c); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9F863A5C01C640EBBA04EA653C3D9754"><enum>(2)</enum><text>such electronic delivery shall be deemed to satisfy the obligation of the covered entity to deliver regulatory documents required under the securities laws.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H15AA2238AE3E40DF9974FDF26C12CFF2"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Other required actions</header><paragraph id="H367B736B19084A0B881CBF33BC0BD898"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Review of rules</header><text>The Commission shall—</text><subparagraph id="H1896E13898274E2A8FAAF997C5A1D037"><enum>(A)</enum><text>within 180 days of the date of enactment of this Act, conduct a review of the rules and regulations of the Commission to determine whether any such rules or regulations require delivery of written documents to investors; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2B25DD5AEDC84ABAAE5813104EA2E1DB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>within 1 year of the date of enactment of this Act, promulgate amendments to such rules or regulations to provide that any requirement to deliver a regulatory document <quote>in writing</quote> may be satisfied by electronic delivery.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9488185A050349BCA08833A776927F1C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Actions by self-regulatory organizations</header><text>Each self-regulatory organization shall adopt rules and regulations, or amend the rules and regulations of the self-regulatory organization, consistent with this Act and consistent with rules, regulations, amendments, or interpretations finalized by the Commission pursuant to subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0831DACE61FA4102BEFCBC7B1C87F287"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rule of application</header><text>This subsection shall not apply to a rule or regulation issued pursuant to a Federal statute if that Federal statute specifically requires delivery of written documents to investors.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7ADCCAC2D38A4D06B5E0D67FE390FF59"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HB4C2EC978BBD41BEA60954D1402437B4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Securities and Exchange Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAC4147A01C924903A937F7764FEF9004"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered entity</header><text>The term <term>covered entity</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H306A1B4798224EFDB5FF3692E73396AB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an investment company (as defined in section 3(a)(1) of the Investment Company Act of 1940 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/80a-3">15 U.S.C. 80a–3(a)(1)</external-xref>)) that is registered under such Act;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3559AEF16D3547DBBCFFDBF9A14D84DC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a business development company (as defined in section 2(a) of the Investment Company Act of 1940 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/80a-2">15 U.S.C. 80a–2(a)</external-xref>)) that has elected to be regulated as such under such Act;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H06E22E0ED1834FBE812A4A00EA5A9DCD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a registered broker or dealer (as such terms are defined, respectively, in paragraphs (4) and (5) of section 3(a) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78c">15 U.S.C. 78c(a)</external-xref>));</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8CB06AC716CB4AF883260DD22273EFC3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a registered municipal securities dealer (as defined in section 3(a)(30) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78c">15 U.S.C. 78c(a)(30)</external-xref>));</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H41D3563A650B4168881AFEC4EEBB16D7"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a registered government securities broker or government securities dealer (as such terms are defined, respectively, in paragraphs (43) and (44) of section 3(a) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78c">15 U.S.C. 78c(a)</external-xref>));</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H33FE97F79EC34BE6955A909CF7F65B4C"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a registered investment adviser (as defined in section 202(a)(11) of the Investment Advisers Act of 1940 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/80b-1">15 U.S.C. 80b-1(a)(11)</external-xref>));</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCA600E054AC549378B1B8DD55B95F4BF"><enum>(G)</enum><text>a registered transfer agent (as defined in section 3(a)(25) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78c">15 U.S.C. 78c(a)(25)</external-xref>)); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDF60434CB69E42A1933512DDC5F45B43"><enum>(H)</enum><text>a registered funding portal (as defined in the second paragraph (80) of section 3(a) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78c">15 U.S.C. 78c(a)</external-xref>)).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD8197EC1901C4CD3B9B76B9BC1D74ECB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Electronic delivery</header><text>The term <term>electronic delivery</term>, with respect to regulatory documents, includes—</text><subparagraph id="H03B0007B23564587BDD6A9B6BE92D70F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the direct delivery of such regulatory document to an electronic address of an investor;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0047CE7CD01D48D0AC0D2C4EA7992C1F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the posting of such regulatory document to a website and direct electronic delivery of an appropriate notice of the availability of the regulatory document to the investor; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6FC3320BAC954AA09860864F8A968E38"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an electronic method reasonably designed to ensure receipt of such regulatory document by the investor.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE92121F7788D401498B3CE65396B37B8"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Regulatory documents</header><text>The term <term>regulatory documents</term> includes—</text><subparagraph id="H0FA3D4B001534B26872389575A6E1350"><enum>(A)</enum><text>prospectuses meeting the requirements of section 10(a) of the Securities Act of 1933 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/77j">15 U.S.C. 77j(a)</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4B090F04630240ED99E340048DAEDECD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>summary prospectuses meeting the requirements of—</text><clause id="H5E494D9B41064E02837F3495DF9BBC59"><enum>(i)</enum><text>section 230.498 of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations; or</text></clause><clause id="H1259FFBE86B54824A10CA52252A84730"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>section 230.498A of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2C026C480B314BECA6AD76BCDC9CB39E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>statements of additional information, as described under section 270.30e–3(h)(2) of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA48F115E3C48442C8E244C7695D5F1A9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>annual and semi-annual reports to investors meeting the requirements of section 30(e) of the Investment Company Act of 1940 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/80a-29">15 U.S.C. 80a–29(e)</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC0C2E96060594A45A8B50AAE02FB87C5"><enum>(E)</enum><text>notices meeting the requirements under section 270.19a–1 of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2E31FF54FB384ECF9F5B7919AB47E38D"><enum>(F)</enum><text>confirmations and account statements meeting the requirements under section 240.10b of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE1BD697FDABC49019022558EB09E9604"><enum>(G)</enum><text>proxy statements meeting the requirements under section 240.14a–3 of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0EB0FA0F07454B349DA720DDE6D6A302"><enum>(H)</enum><text>privacy notices meeting the requirements of Regulation S–P under subpart A of part 248 of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC74C257C8076470ABA4BC3D6B96C78BC"><enum>(I)</enum><text>affiliate marketing notices meeting the requirements of Regulation S–AM under subpart B of part 248 of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC09CAFD609184E70B5CD2EDD0FC077B9"><enum>(J)</enum><text>all other regulatory documents required to be delivered by covered entities to investors under the securities laws and the rules and regulations of the Commission and the self-regulatory organizations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF8EF47A0D6DD4A65BC308E69629FB22C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Securities laws</header><text>The term <term>securities laws</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3(a) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78c">15 U.S.C. 78c(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2EC21427C49747CDA5E57D58B9E87294"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Self-regulatory organization</header><text>The term <term>self-regulatory organization</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="HC8AB0EE087E64BF28D48B36C73EF7C1B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a self-regulatory organization, as defined in section 3(a)(26) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78c">15 U.S.C. 78c(a)(26)</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0D9C4CDDF1934E55BCB255C9AADA490E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Municipal Securities Rulemaking Board.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2E545BB878A4418590509BA272B6949C"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Website</header><text>The term <term>website</term> means an internet website or other digital, internet, or electronic-based information repository, such as a mobile application, to which an investor of a covered entity has been provided reasonable access.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

