<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA081BD90D52F4E47960A9745AB3AFBC2" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3670 IH: IHS Provider Expansion Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3670</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250602">June 2, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001218">Ms. Stansbury</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="L000273">Ms. Leger Fernandez</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Indian Health Care Improvement Act to establish within the Indian Health Service an Office of Graduate Medical Education Programs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H235924ECAE53415DBE2FBFD64AA9BE25" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H78E63D275A684E98BB73576377A3C1B4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>IHS Provider Expansion Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HF1160B8D33FD47E59B3D016EF13AD076"><enum>2.</enum><header>Indian Health Service Office of Graduate Medical Education Programs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title I of the Indian Health Care Improvement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/1611">25 U.S.C. 1611 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H46A4CE244002434E8118ABB1E1EDABA6" display-inline="no-display-inline">
<section id="HA8ED6338E48D4A01A0BEF99FE67D5AEB"><enum>125.</enum><header>Office of Graduate Medical Education Programs</header>
<subsection id="H5C338AA291B64563884CA387D16B0C27">
            <enum>(a)</enum>
            <header>Establishment</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, acting through the Service, (in this section referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall establish within the Service an Office of Graduate Medical Education Programs (in this section referred to as the <quote>Office</quote>).</text>
          </subsection>
<subsection id="HCCD0CEC82FAE46F8ACCDDE49CF8B405D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Office shall have the following duties:</text> <paragraph id="HA5F728C6945D47F9B647EB26054543EA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To create a pipeline for future health care professionals, paraprofessionals, and other health-related professionals (as identified by the Secretary) to participate in residency and fellowship programs.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H89702D9521864A09AC5603B610135D92"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To oversee current residency and fellowship programs at facilities of the Service and facilitate the establishment of additional residency programs that support recruitment and retention of health care professionals, paraprofessionals, and other health-related professionals (as identified by the Secretary) working at such facilities.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEEF336B22D6E4F33A3E893F12E44838C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>To serve as the central hub for residency programs at facilities of the Service.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6BFBC879C79C41CBBC4F5B5EA85A38AA"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To work in consultation or coordination with academic institutions.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6526782B440D458580D4A303A8CB3E5C"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To coordinate medical student and elective rotational and education track programs.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H8905CADC5D7645F9B9E446CFF82D968F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Interagency working group</header>
<paragraph id="H6344D549E9AC4759AA8FE77CE46CCC48"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, the Secretary of Labor, the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration, and the Administrator of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services, shall establish an interagency working group (in this subsection referred to as the <quote>working group</quote>) to assist the Secretary in establishing the Office under subsection (a), including by—</text> <subparagraph id="H001FF37FE8A443DFA73C2DFEA15AD9FD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>supporting the implementation of the Office; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H042F6E2AF41E40929B4C74227325A01F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>developing long-term planning for long-term sustainability of the Office.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4881AB0FAE2D4A83BD97FBA784D40B46"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Quarterly reports</header><text>Not later than the date that is 120 days after the date of enactment of this section, and every 3 months thereafter, the working group shall submit to Congress a report on the activities of the working group.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1DDBDDDFCDAC4976BB15CDE758B27E8D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Termination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The working group shall terminate on the date that is 10 years after the date of enactment of this section.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD87AAD178FB3454D88936D00FE51B83F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to the availability of appropriations, there is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section, not less than—</text>
<paragraph id="HC1EF82DC6253486888D03896BE73AAC3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$4,000,000 for fiscal year 2027; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H442E9439649143B88FFB37370C8EF74D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$4,000,000 for each subsequent fiscal year.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

