<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6CCFC60217294B99AF6838A0AB3734ED" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2761 IH: Halting All Parades for Presidents’ Yearly Birthdays, It Risks Taxpayer Harm, Damages, And Your Budget Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2761</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20250409">April 9, 2025</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To prohibit the use of Federal funds for a military parade in the District of Columbia intended for the personal celebration of President Donald J. Trump, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H76C5D252559A4C71A034754A9B0B7FD9" style="OLC">
<section id="HC447A9C1D3254C46AFFAE542BFEB5021" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Halting All Parades for Presidents’ Yearly Birthdays, It Risks Taxpayer Harm, Damages, And Your Budget Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>HAPPY BIRTHDAY Budget Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HC7308015F4BE419EB17942FCE51AFDB6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
<paragraph id="H95987DB0774A4DFCA0B89D28A4EBE25C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Military parades are traditionally reserved for national celebrations, commemorations of military service, or significant public occasions, not personal milestones such as birthdays.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFCC41DC9530146C0900A121E61C1CBDC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A military parade previously considered in President Donald J. Trump’s first term was canceled due to cost concerns, including costs to the military of $92 million and public safety costs to the District of Columbia of over $21 million.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA91114E364D946049DA17C3FA18B944A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Heavy military vehicles risk causing damage to District of Columbia roads, which are not designed to support such weight, requiring taxpayer-funded repairs.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5E075A61A5184CD796FA2ECA51033227"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">President Trump has conducted mass layoffs and firings in the Federal Government through the so-called “Department of Government Efficiency (DOGE)” under the guise of “saving taxpayer money”.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H10F95994B7A6470687014D05EF61B13C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The District of Columbia is often not fully reimbursed for expenses incurred during Federal events, placing an undue financial burden on local agencies and taxpayers.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE96DE432E66F41568AED44939213B40B"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The Washington City Paper reported that President Trump has expressed interest in holding a military parade in the District of Columbia on June 14, 2025, as a personal birthday celebration.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE983676CAFC74586906C0DC992AC1C30"><enum>(7)</enum><text>While June 14, 2025, is the United States Army’s 250th birthday and Flag Day, it is also President Donald J. Trump’s 79th birthday.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4164405A12104F4491BE3FC02CD16796"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The U.S. Army has never held a military parade to celebrate its own birthday, and the Army’s 250th anniversary celebration has been in the planning stages for several years with no plans for a parade in the District of Columbia.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE63283B7F66C42DC84F724874DFC8AA3"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is unlikely that President Trump will include an air, sea, or terrestrial extravaganza to celebrate the birthdays of the other military branches, further highlighting the personal nature of the proposed celebration.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HD37449B21C474AF0A4BEE42FF651C835"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that public funds should be used to support the well-being and security of the American people and not expended on displays of military force for personal glorification.</text></section>
<section id="HFD42631546D84C2C8FC8C669C60A51BE"><enum>4.</enum><header>Prohibition on use of funds for military parade in District of Columbia</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No Federal funds may be obligated or expended for the planning, execution, security, transportation, or infrastructure support of any military parade in the District of Columbia that is primarily intended to celebrate the birthday, personal milestone, or private interest of any individual, including President Donald J. Trump.</text></section> <section id="HBC9733A9B06B49268AA4E776A80B7669"><enum>5.</enum><header>Alternative birthday celebrations</header> <subsection id="H39834DB4581B4EB2946539AD14F094ED"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Alternative celebrations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress encourages President Trump to consider alternative birthday celebrations that do not involve armored vehicles or fighter jets, such as cake, golf, or bingo night.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H75F5DE0560DF442A9274689499390F48"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Birthday wishes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In recognition of his birthday, Congress extends a sincere <quote>Happy Birthday</quote> to Donald J. Trump, free of charge, and encourages all Americans who wish to send birthday wishes to the President to do so through the United States Postal Service, the only service expressly authorized in the Constitution of the United States for the transmission of personal correspondence, where neither snow nor rain nor heat nor gloom of night stays these couriers from the swift completion of their appointed rounds.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

