<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" slc-id="S1-NEW25496-F57-2M-HHC"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 222 ATS: Expressing support for the designation of May 2025 as “Motorcycle Safety Awareness Month”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 222</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250513">May 13, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S376">Ms. Ernst</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S380">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S363">Mr. King</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S431">Mr. Curtis</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of May 2025 as <quote>Motorcycle Safety Awareness Month</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, according to the Motorcycle Industry Council, motorcycling is a great tradition enjoyed by an estimated 30,000,000 individuals annually in the United States, representing approximately 9 percent of the population;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas motorcycles are a valuable component of the transportation mix;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas motorcycles are fuel-efficient and decrease congestion while having little impact on the transportation infrastructure of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the motorcycling community promotes rider safety education, licensing, and motorcycle awareness;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the motorcycling community is committed to decreasing motorcycle crashes through training and safety education, personal responsibility, and increased public awareness;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to the Motorcycle Industry Council, approximately 87 percent of motorcycles are operated on highways in conjunction with other vehicles;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas motorcyclist fatalities occur more frequently than passenger vehicle motorist fatalities;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas motorcycle awareness is beneficial to all road users and will help decrease motorcycle crashes; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration promotes Motorcycle Safety Awareness Month to encourage riders to be properly licensed, receive training, and wear personal protective equipment, and to remind all riders and motorists to always share the road: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H99C42FD7B67D4E1CBA06B951CFC774D3"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H9E9BD46CB64B4D28BE2C1032543A2840"><enum/><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="HE9E23CBA768D4C199A7B28E76AAFE51B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the designation of May 2025 as <quote>Motorcycle Safety Awareness Month</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H827EFE40620343FD9A2E73EDF30A5F85"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the contribution of motorcycles to the transportation mix;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA577B68E43F84AC2A1D09412CF82FDBA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>encourages motorcycle awareness by all road users;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H27EF61FF0D484E33851B0A326D1FDB2E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>recognizes that motorcyclists have a right to the road and that all motorists should safely share the roadways;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H649F83D1D2BD4313A254C177D18501D5"><enum>(5)</enum><text>encourages rider safety education, training, and proper gear for safe motorcycle operation; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD5C6341D322E4F95B7378F8C06073995"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supports the goals of Motorcycle Safety Awareness Month.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

