<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-BUR25445-9LL-V0-8ML"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1691 IS: Traveler Privacy Protection Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code>II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1691</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250508">May 8, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S389">Mr. Kennedy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S369">Mr.
                    Markey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S411">Mr. Marshall</cosponsor>,
                    <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S375">Mr. Daines</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was
                read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on
                    Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To limit the use of facial recognition technology in airports, and for other
 purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section commented="no" section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Traveler Privacy Protection Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idf1f6b316de4e4d5c83d0aa758b8be629"><enum>2.</enum><header>Limitation on use of facial recognition technology</header><subsection id="id1e57992eb9b443d5ace1a93ada963e08"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general </header><text>Section 44901 of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idda9f54f41bf04cc5905f086222bdf7fa"><subsection id="idb4e5bf84387a4448a5d8729bcdde9220"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Limitation on use of facial recognition technology</header><paragraph id="id2c9f26e477d94fe982f872f3685f7e87"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text><subparagraph id="id48e8fa2e90e146558c432508dae4f993"><enum>(A)</enum><header>1:1 matching software</header><text>The term <term>1:1 matching software</term> means a technology that compares a real-time biometric to a photograph on a passenger’s identification document.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide92ce52df61043eda84d0f9f90959d1a"><enum>(B)</enum><header>1:N identification software</header><text>The term <term>1:N identification software</term> means a technology that compares a real-time biometric collected from a passenger to a biometric of the passenger already accessible by the Department of Homeland Security.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id08b9de21c5b34e85a756301c83bba421"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Administration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Administration</term> means the Transportation Security Administration. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7390674588c5482d915ee1530537abd9"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idad19142adbab44f0ab3808f94d892025"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Affirmative express consent</header><text>The term <term>affirmative express consent</term> means an affirmative act by a passenger that—</text><clause id="ida758ef954f7f48f68eb4fead9a254d4e"><enum>(i)</enum><text>clearly communicates the authorization of the passenger for an act or practice;</text></clause><clause id="idc5d99db08a1b46b0b76b3fe9b5bc7d5e"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is provided in response to a notice that meets the requirements of section 2(a)(2); and</text></clause><clause id="id5c1173196c9a4605b4de990064b4ba81"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>is not—</text><subclause id="id1daa99979ff84ecfa5f8c10e6793a699"><enum>(I)</enum><text>acceptance of general or broad terms of service or a similar document; or</text></subclause><subclause id="idb58dc60d49db4447ad1179388e07ae6b"><enum>(II)</enum><text>accomplished by entering an airport security checkpoint or standing in a line. </text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbdc9062ebf174622918f154630609e39"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Airport</header><text>The term <term>airport</term> has the meaning given such term in section 47102.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idAF6BC6CFD1FD4A2F8C40D5ED8D1F864E" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Approved identification document</header><text>The term <term>approved identification document</term> means any document identified by the Transportation Security Administration as acceptable identification consistent with applicable laws and regulations, including—</text><clause id="idB907BEE5BE32453094A53B3C1686E40B" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a State driver’s license or other photo identification card issued by a department of motor vehicles of a State;</text></clause><clause id="idD06AD361B4CD4EFD8F0DC092B85CE90A" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an enhanced driver’s license issued by a State;</text></clause><clause id="idEE71672B2E9E4DB3B9A55F3E46F3C369" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a United States passport or passport card;</text></clause><clause id="idEC82F6AC42C1410B9DC0C59CB2D307B8" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text> biometrically secure card issued by a trusted traveler program of the Department of Homeland Security, including— </text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id339d123eeeaa4dd9873edbacb42d886b"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Global Entry; </text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2ecadbf383154640b79f2caecd9da7de"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nexus; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id01b6ffa640604558a3914abc6022fc41"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Secure Electronic Network for Travelers Rapid Inspection (SENTRI);</text></subclause></clause><clause id="idD68DA21EF602453DBFCE1DFFC5F8D7C9" commented="no"><enum>(v)</enum><text>an identification card issued by the Department of Defense, including such a card issued to a dependent;</text></clause><clause id="id26EC39E0BA8F4D8BA69AAE80289495BA" commented="no"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>a permanent resident card;</text></clause><clause id="idB706C2BCC58B4FA8A45BAF6F085790FF" commented="no"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>a border crossing card issued by the Department of State;</text></clause><clause id="idC4D58003D4DC4F4C98A8579B363E0AAA" commented="no"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>an acceptable photo identification issued by a Federally recognized Indian Tribe, including an Enhanced Tribal Card (ETC);</text></clause><clause id="idCB11E319D05A4DFE88F554AA7DA2CBBA" commented="no"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>a personal identity verification credential issued in accordance with Homeland Security Presidential Directive 12;</text></clause><clause id="id001445F36E0A4259A74356728F246B80" commented="no"><enum>(x)</enum><text>a passport issued by a foreign government;</text></clause><clause id="id03868B59D3564895BEF27935140F1D8F" commented="no"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>a driver’s license issued by a province of Canada;</text></clause><clause id="id6f30679b7d7f4f5fa69efdd085515316"><enum>(xii)</enum><text>a Secure Certificate of Indian Status issued by the Government of Canada; </text></clause><clause id="id5E279D426D464F339436C9D441DA6EF6" commented="no"><enum>(xiii)</enum><text>a transportation worker identification credential (TWIC);</text></clause><clause id="idC1D76A3D40FD472FB5BDADF4AB5E1119" commented="no"><enum>(xiv)</enum><text>a United States Citizenship and Immigration Services Employment Authorization Card (I–766);</text></clause><clause id="id2C4967C33225489DAEC4D878B580B246" commented="no"><enum>(xv)</enum><text>a Merchant Mariner Credential issued by the Coast Guard; and</text></clause><clause id="id043CD5733ACD405CBEB274DC6B0933C4" commented="no"><enum>(xvi)</enum><text>a Veteran Health Identification Card (VHIC) issued by the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc11ea8452aa74d46a1ffec2049c930b8"><enum>(H)</enum><header>Biometric information</header><text>The term <term>biometric information</term> means any data that allows or confirms the unique identification or verification of an individual and is generated from the measurement or processing of unique biological, physical, or physiological characteristics, including—</text><clause id="ide979ceef0edf48908486d816aa1a7052"><enum>(i)</enum><text>fingerprints;</text></clause><clause id="idc89b7836a00844e7865f2bc1fba9bcc0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>voice prints;</text></clause><clause id="id2a445b813c414af8a5b01717417b4ac9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>iris or retina imagery scans;</text></clause><clause id="id3b2cd94348b341ed9a82a28cb42556d5"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>facial or hand mapping, geometry, or templates; </text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7c56f4e5ad5e45d8a06244c194302cf9"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">deoxyribonucleic acids (DNA); and</text></clause><clause id="id9c94307e19ac444998bc8c7a0d6c2d33"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>gait. </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8bc077f82d92408a8d3d9ba026de19ce"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Identity verification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>identity verification</term> means the confirmation of the identity of a passenger before admittance to the sterile area of the airport.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id43f004c1033d47b4bc769bcc132c3a6e"><enum>(J)</enum><header>Passenger</header><text>The term <term>passenger</term> means an individual who is not an employee or contractor of the Administration.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id09b4aea7a6694702a520632f28a1587d"><enum>(K)</enum><header>Screening location; sterile area</header><text>The terms <quote>screening location</quote> and <quote>sterile area</quote> have the meanings given those terms in section 1540.5 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1e7740360894497bb307a1d631f26c50" commented="no"><enum>(L)</enum><header>Trusted Traveler Program</header><text>The term <term>Trusted Traveler Program</term> means any of the following:</text><clause id="id0415903d1a2e41158bb9c1141d391447" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Global Entry.</text></clause><clause id="id72651f5fa12e425eac47234b69008f70" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The PreCheck Program.</text></clause><clause id="idb057f62fa0f841f19991dccba317e7c9" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>SENTRI.</text></clause><clause id="ida635411b20cc4944a8c4aebb8f7fcb2a" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>NEXUS.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id08b98cc830ee44cc9c092eee806343d2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Privacy for passengers</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id98e7e59857884af68628fd402a551249"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraphs (B), (C), and (D) the Administrator may not, for any purpose, capture, collect, store, or otherwise process biometric information collected through or for the use of facial recognition technology or facial matching software with respect to a passenger.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9f0a76ea7fe54e299b00ee714f85dce5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Use of technology for verification of documents</header><text>The Administrator may use technology to process, capture, scan and receive data from an identification document containing a photograph of a passenger to access secure flight data, authenticate the pre-screening status of a passenger, or verify the accuracy of the identification document.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide5403b444dae4f22a73a3b8212eca159"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Technology for trusted traveler programs</header><text>The Administrator may use facial recognition or facial matching technology to perform identity verification solely at the screening location if the Administrator—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8c87545dc9d8415ebc18884c5abc175d"><enum>(i)</enum><text>ensures that each passenger enrolling in a Trusted Traveler Program is given clear and conspicuous notice at the time of enrollment and renewal of enrollment of how biometric information of the passenger will be used, processed, stored, shared, and deleted;</text></clause><clause id="idacddd9bb43dc4f0bbfc6b964e89cc97c"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provides each passenger enrolled in a Trusted Traveler Program with the option to opt-out of the use of facial recognition or facial matching technology for identity verification at the screening location;</text></clause><clause id="id459ac8eacfdd40698f54c2925554d797"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>notifies each passenger enrolled in a Trusted Traveler Program at the point of identity verification and as the passenger approaches the point of identity verification of such opt-out option via simple and clear signage, spoken announcements, and other accessible and easy-to-understand notifications;</text></clause><clause id="idef34032211da4accb97619975fe2b880"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>ensures equal ability for passengers to choose either identification option;</text></clause><clause id="idaa10e495c6dc486ba0454db5aba0788e"><enum>(v)</enum><text>does not subject passengers who choose the opt-out option to discriminatory treatment, additional screening requirements, less favorable screening conditions, or other unfavorable treatment; and</text></clause><clause id="id4caf68df9a6e4bef92ae8f571a733233"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>for each passenger who chooses the opt-out option, performs identity verification using an approved identification document and without collecting any biometric information from such passenger.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5f4fcfe32420471e98c00747eb873a8d"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Technology for general passengers</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idef953c20768b49f6bec56f6c0363c050"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall perform identity verification for passengers not enrolled in a Trusted Traveler Program using an approved identification document and without collecting any biometric information from such passengers.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id32a8451fde53498694a33c45a0e7cecb"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Authority to use facial matching</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator may use facial recognition or facial matching technology to perform identity verification for passengers not enrolled in a Trusted Traveler Program solely at the screening location if the Administrator—</text><subclause id="id4d00badab8ee42e2a9207d87d758f428"><enum>(I)</enum><text>provides each passenger with the option to opt-in to the use of facial recognition or facial matching technology for identity verification at the screening location;</text></subclause><subclause id="idad6689102ce8418c8bf1b5976b813222"><enum>(II)</enum><text>notifies each passenger at the point of identity verification and as the passenger approaches the point of identity verification of such opt-in option via simple and clear signage, spoken announcements, and other accessible and easy-to-understand notifications;</text></subclause><subclause id="id4c1ef4cad287431bb173dcc6e5285f7f"><enum>(III)</enum><text>ensures equal ability for passengers to choose either identification option;</text></subclause><subclause id="id0d2e9860b98e4e99b0110e171b739273"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>receives affirmative-express consent from the passenger to use facial recognition or facial matching technology for identity verification prior to each use of facial recognition or facial matching technology with respect to such passenger; and</text></subclause><subclause id="idec3e82c75b374f7396874ee066785854"><enum>(V)</enum><text>does not subject passengers who do not choose the opt-in option to discriminatory treatment, additional screening requirements, less favorable screening conditions, or other unfavorable treatment.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id14BE8C70C78C4D84B39953346B69CE8D"><subparagraph id="id123fc7a98cff415695f8fd82f7ec1955"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Notification guidelines</header><text>A notification provided in accordance with subparagraph (C)—</text><clause id="idb7df461dbb53439cb32c17cd87531a97"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6ccb213b2f9249df82b44f5c1995ed81"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">notify passengers of the option described in subparagraph (C)(ii) via simple and clear signage, spoken announcements, and other accessible and easy to understand notifications;</text></subclause><subclause id="id7c78d600b5b14741bf2e77bf52e15cf3"><enum>(II)</enum><text>describe the specific steps passengers may take to exercise such option;</text></subclause><subclause id="idc50efb05dc954011b16ca67529e64880"><enum>(III)</enum><text>notify passengers that an election not to use facial recognition technology or facial matching software will not subject them to discriminatory treatment, additional screening requirements, less favorable screening conditions, or other unfavorable treatment solely as a result of that election; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1087a69dfc444f4a91faa8373cab760b"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>be properly placed across relevant areas of the airport including airline check-in areas, airport security checkpoints, and airport gate areas; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="idcc01e9aa45874df98701ccc44e8b9785"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>may not encourage passengers to choose one method of identity verification over another method.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0b0a82a539d6426dabcbed6cffd4ebe2"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The option described in subparagraph (D)(ii) does not apply with respect to a passenger—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7d58096ae92b4093a301c986c4f64fea"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">who does not provide an acceptable form of identification at a security checkpoint; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide424cab0aeec43dbb248afec3149c89c"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whose identity the Administrator may need to verify through alternative measures to enter the sterile area.</text></clause></subparagraph><paragraph id="idd0a5e22ad01c44c08be372c215acb071"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Data minimization of passengers</header><text>Beginning on the date that is 30 days after the date of the enactment of this subsection, in processing biometric information collected through the use of 1:1 matching software or 1:N identification software with respect to a passenger, the Administrator—</text><subparagraph id="id0e68f1cdc9474353a595527366d75e58"><enum>(A)</enum><text>may capture facial images only as directly relevant and necessary to accomplish the identity verification of the passenger; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id94fc2571480245f2bc85aab43080ede5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may not, except as provided in paragraph (4)—</text><clause id="idbcc4bb9052424d2ba3c7a3440fce315f"><enum>(i)</enum><text>share outside of the Administration any biometric information collected through the use of facial recognition or facial matching technology;</text></clause><clause id="id424b7bd16ad7436593a6ae3d451a066a"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>store biometric information collected through 1:1 matching software for longer than is necessary to complete identity verification of a passenger or through 1:N identification software for longer than 24 hours after the scheduled flight departure time of the passenger; or</text></clause><clause id="idcba7ae43b0e543eb82bbc06cd0a5659c"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>compare the image of a passenger against anything other than the photo identification document provided by the passenger, except to the extent necessary to operate a Trusted Traveler Program.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id8784e823c14a4510ab7a7208398f8ba4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Exception for testing and evaluation</header><text>The Administrator may, for the purpose of testing and evaluation, in a separate area from the general passenger screening area, retain the captured facial image of a passenger undergoing identity verification as a part of a Trusted Traveler Program taken at a screening location so long as—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="idd19d4149af5044c5860ccc2b9f0e8473"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the screening location where the identity verification is conducted and images are processed for testing otherwise meets the requirements described in paragraphs (2) and (3);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1daaee267cb047cca596ffd479b9a310"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Administrator gives notice to the passenger in accordance with section 552a of title 5 (commonly referred to as the <quote>Privacy Act of 1974</quote>) regarding the storage, use, and sharing of biometric information by the Administration;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9117fd4beb8c484d845d7190e474e1f9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the notice described in subparagraph (B) provides clear and conspicuous notice to passengers at the point of identity verification and as passengers approach the point of identity verification of how biometric data collected will be stored, used, shared, or otherwise processed;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide5026908e97e40c0b19a5f81ff403938"><enum>(D)</enum><text>images collected, shared, stored, or otherwise processed by the Administration, including images collected prior to the date of enactment of this subsection, are deleted not later than 90 days after collection; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1844bf07142747a28b80a1e89bbbdc1e"><enum>(E)</enum><text>captured facial images are not used for any purpose other than to test and evaluate the 1:1 matching software or 1:N identification software used by the Administration.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id6762e13e42954519b1de1e0bf9b85c49"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Disposal of facial biometrics</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this subsection, the Administrator shall dispose of any biometric information, including images and videos, collected, or stored by the Administration prior to such date of enactment that, if collected or stored on or after such date of enactment, would violate this subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id29b108cfe72b4105b8f1978744fb84a1"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Prohibition on passive surveillance</header><text>Under no circumstances may the Administrator use facial recognition technology or facial matching software to track or identify passengers outside of the screening location, or to profile, target, or discriminate against any passenger solely for exercising their Constitutional rights or to enable systemic, indiscriminate, or wide-scale monitoring, surveillance, or tracking.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idcea432a535ef484bb22c6e2781ed50f9"><enum>(7)</enum><header>GAO report on use of facial recognition technology</header><subparagraph id="id12684495a4e14c61971411785b5f86f1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this subsection, and annually thereafter, the Comptroller General of the United States shall study the use of 1:1 matching software and 1:N identification software by the Administration, and submit to Congress a report that includes—</text><clause id="idbaac2fdec79f43ca991d54bae0635984"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an assessment of the effectiveness of the use by the Administration of 1:1 matching software and 1:N identification software—</text><subclause id="ida61139bb1e274dd0bd14f57e3b4f1f21"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to strengthen security;</text></subclause><subclause id="id1f4dd37df72b4603b2994e0912ed8d39"><enum>(II)</enum><text>to improve the experiences of passengers and air carrier, airport, and Administration employees at airports; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id234463b160524029b683a1a0c93cbed5"><enum>(III)</enum><text>to manage the costs of security screening;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id3768279b192440159def05d0cee89183"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an assessment of false positive and false negative facial identification matches to identification documents detected at airports using 1:1 matching software and 1:N identification software at screening locations and at airports not using such technology or software;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfbf6aab8c913490f95c5facaad998e3e"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a summary of the methodology and results of any testing performed by the Comptroller General in relation to the efficacy of the use of 1:1 matching software and 1:N identification software by the Administration, including any research on bias, disaggregated by age, race, ethnicity to the extent practicable, and sex, the different technologies used by the Administration, and efforts to minimize the bias in operations of the Administration; and</text></clause><clause id="idc0dcd911990f4f34a31ea274f960e8e4"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>recommendations to protect passenger privacy, civil rights, and civil liberty interests.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id74428cf9a52a4d4e92924cc69f438bbd"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Form</header><text>A report submitted under subparagraph (A) shall be submitted in unclassified form but may include a classified annex.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfbc4dd229219489983b6b578ebce5257"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Rule of construction; protection of personal
 information</header><text>Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed to authorize or require the unauthorized disclosure of the personal information of passengers, and the report required by this paragraph shall be released in a manner that protects personal information from unauthorized use or unauthorized disclosure.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="id7ed85c0b55a346efa139339d277f9846"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Amendments to aviation and transportation security act</header><text>The Aviation and Transportation Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/107/71">Public Law 107–71</external-xref>; 115 Stat. 597) is amended—</text><paragraph id="ida5c8d816477842cba488bb82a302cc00"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 109(a)(7) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/114">49 U.S.C. 114</external-xref> note) by inserting <quote>, subject to the restrictions of section 44901(n) of title 49, United States Code,</quote> after <quote>technologies</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idefcba4a33bf24915b61219c95f11b971"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 137(d)(3) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/44912">49 U.S.C. 44912</external-xref> note), by inserting <quote>, subject to the restrictions of section 44901(n) of title 49, United States Code,</quote> after <quote>biometrics</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ida610641dc2094289b7c1c8e162fe3328"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Additional modifications with respect to air transportation
 security</header><text>Section 44903 of title 49, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="idb973b2088b8c43beba11474d352294bf"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (c)(3), by inserting <quote>, subject to the restrictions of section 44901(n),</quote> after <quote>other technology</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd2139aacb9874640b7f230a70769786e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (g)(2)(G), by inserting <quote>, subject to the restrictions of section 44901(n),</quote> after <quote>technologies</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc2ac59bfb71d4905ac4d626be4b368ef"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (h)(4)(E), by inserting <quote>, subject to the restrictions of section 44901(n),</quote> after <quote>technology</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


