<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H40D07C2558B64AA695D245D9C7586BC7" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 800 IH: DEI to DIE Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 800</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250128">January 28, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001216">Mr. Mills</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To enact into law the executive order relating to ending diversity, equity, and inclusion programs in the Federal Government, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD782A11A28A74CFB93EFE857365EFBED" style="OLC"><section id="H29E9E5BDB60647389B491645EF7994E6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>DEI to DIE Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H08A1C82B29694E569784BD424277326B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Elimination of diversity, equity, and inclusion in Federal Government</header><subsection id="H7DC4BE0F93C14153A151C718835AA4DA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H7D6D7C520B8E4996A62F30B0BF5B344D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Biden Administration forced illegal and immoral discrimination programs, going by the name <quote>diversity, equity, and inclusion</quote> (in this Act referred to as <quote>DEI</quote>), into virtually all aspects of the Federal Government, in areas ranging from airline safety to the military.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H067137D22F9A426282C845E1570DBCA1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This was a concerted effort stemming from President Biden’s first day in office, when he issued Executive Order 13985, <quote>Advancing Racial Equity and Support for Underserved Communities Through the Federal Government</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFD99FE6BCF5D4E5F815900D68EF63E03"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Pursuant to Executive Order 13985 and follow-on orders, nearly every Federal agency and entity submitted <quote>Equity Action Plans</quote> to detail the ways that they have furthered DEIs infiltration of the Federal Government.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEA8D245D816B45BB8B25843E9D7B063B"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The public release of these plans demonstrated immense public waste and shameful discrimination.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB145AE4933644BEF893B6B15D1952B90"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That ends today. Americans deserve a Government committed to serving every person with equal dignity and respect, and to expending precious taxpayer resources only on making America great.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0C113FB10C564C27B5BFB044A9414105"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elimination</header><paragraph id="H1D79597AC3DB4C3BB1B4E2AF80F925E2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director of the Office of Management and Budget (in this Act referred to as <quote>OMB</quote>), assisted by the Attorney General and the Director of the Office of Personnel Management (in this Act referred to as <quote>OPM</quote>), shall coordinate the termination of all discriminatory programs, including illegal diversity, equity, and inclusion (in this Act referred to as <quote>DEI</quote>) and diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility (in this Act referred to as <quote>DEIA</quote>) mandates, policies, programs, preferences, and activities in the Federal Government, under whatever name they appear.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF58552256F664D17A115724B72CBB96D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application</header><text>To carry out paragraph (1), the Director of OPM, with the assistance of the Attorney General as requested, shall review and revise, as appropriate, all existing Federal employment practices, union contracts, and training policies or programs to comply with this Act. Federal employment practices, including Federal employee performance reviews, shall reward individual initiative, skills, performance, and hard work and shall not under any circumstances consider DEI or DEIA factors, goals, policies, mandates, or requirements.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2C072A1463A2412A970A60C34542875B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Required actions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each agency, department, or commission head, in consultation with the Attorney General, the Director of OMB, and the Director of OPM, as appropriate, shall take the following actions not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act:</text><paragraph id="H7CEF62F0DC554E4097C8F66D1D117087"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Terminate, to the maximum extent allowed by law, all DEI, DEIA, and <quote>environmental justice</quote> offices and positions (including <quote>Chief Diversity Officer</quote> positions); all <quote>equity action plans</quote>, <quote>equity</quote> actions, initiatives, or programs, <quote>equity-related</quote> grants or contracts; and all DEI or DEIA performance requirements for employees, contractors, or grantees.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5E8F808B25524537AF268E1C7ADD42F4"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Provide the Director of the OMB with a list of all—</text><subparagraph id="H2D2E7D9E7457485989E718A943624CD6"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">agency or department DEI, DEIA, or <quote>environmental justice</quote> positions, committees, programs, services, activities, budgets, and expenditures in existence on November 4, 2024, and an assessment of whether these positions, committees, programs, services, activities, budgets, and expenditures have been misleadingly relabeled in an attempt to preserve their pre-November 4, 2024 function; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6EA2659CCAB14012B21957B39795C479"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Federal contractors who have provided DEI training or DEI training materials to agency or department employees; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF058546D729C4CDDB40AFF845A35FDB9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Federal grantees who received Federal funding to provide or advance DEI, DEIA, or <quote>environmental justice</quote> programs, services, or activities since January 20, 2021.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0297CFD0401E4C26A50DD25B581BCE18"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Direct the deputy agency or department head to—</text><subparagraph id="H679998F437A443C39C40A8212F1AAEFA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>assess the operational impact (including the number of new DEI hires) and cost of the prior administration’s DEI, DEIA, and <quote>environmental justice</quote> programs and policies; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0C03BF8894F243D5B4A9F5D919F7E4B6"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommend actions, such as congressional notifications under section 530D of title 28, United States Code, to align agency or department programs, activities, policies, regulations, guidance, employment practices, enforcement activities, contracts (including set-asides), grants, consent orders, and litigating positions with the policy of equal dignity and respect identified in subsection (a) of this Act. The agency or department head and the Director of OMB shall jointly ensure that the deputy agency or department head has the authority and resources needed to carry out this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4147FE9693D3482494D21AB7FC13553E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To inform and advise the President, so that he may formulate appropriate and effective civil-rights policies for the Executive Branch, the Assistant to the President for Domestic Policy shall convene a monthly meeting attended by the Director of OMB, the Director of OPM, and each deputy agency or department head to—</text><paragraph id="HD4AE63EB87824F1D8639B6E36F5E5B94" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text>hear reports on the prevalence and the economic and social costs of DEI, DEIA, and <quote>environmental justice</quote> in agency or department programs, activities, policies, regulations, guidance, employment practices, enforcement activities, contracts (including set-asides), grants, consent orders, and litigating positions;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE98107C62E7C45188C43A89BCE313217"><enum>(2)</enum><text>discuss any barriers to measures to comply with this Act; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2F1CC9C88BFD4185B08DB2AB05A8D187"><enum>(3)</enum><text>monitor and track agency and department progress and identify potential areas for additional Presidential or legislative action to advance the policy of equal dignity and respect.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5CE33264A41847B2929C9D0550AE61B0"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Severability</header><text>If any provision of this Act, or the application of any provision to any person or circumstance, is held to be invalid, the remainder of this Act and the application of its provisions to any other persons or circumstances shall not be affected.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

