<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7971339BFD564E4380454160AAB85A08" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4090 IH: To codify certain provisions of certain Executive Orders relating to domestic mining and hardrock mineral resources, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4090</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250623">June 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001212">Mr. Stauber</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To codify certain provisions of certain Executive Orders relating to domestic mining and hardrock mineral resources, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H506DBF3278A94CEAA443A8070EF06BC5" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H76CD088FC7CC463F8EEB525210F50F72" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the policy of the United States to establish the position of the United States as the leading producer of hardrock minerals, including rare earth minerals, which will—</text> <paragraph id="HD61E617029234E4AAA6830545D0ABFB4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>create jobs and prosperity at home;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBFC0EF9AA99648F29B56DC983E26EA62"><enum>(2)</enum><text>strengthen supply chains for the United States and the allies of the United States;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H831EE0FE6F9145748ACD1E2420F60525"><enum>(3)</enum><text>safeguard the national Security of the United States; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC05714EE1685472FB47896508FCE4634"><enum>(4)</enum><text>reduce the global influence of malign and adversarial states.</text> </paragraph></section> <section id="HA91ECF822DF74BA6AC41566CE1315B22"><enum>2.</enum><header>Analyzing economic impacts of mineral net import reliance</header> <subsection id="H01B4213E05BC4917A08F84B049B93CD4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Cost of net import reliance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate—</text> 
<paragraph id="H28BC586AF63B4A0992C8B42B05CF12FF" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for each mineral commodity included in the document published by the United States Geological Survey titled <quote>Mineral Commodity Summaries 2025</quote> (Version 1.2; March 2025) for which the United States is reliant on imports, the dollar value associated with such reliance; and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HC9BD7162950D43E396E3EA2986BB82F4" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the overall impact on the economy of the United States of imports and exports of mineral commodities listed in the document published by the United States Geological Survey titled <quote>Mineral Commodity Summaries 2025</quote> (Version 1.2; March 2025) for which the United States is reliant on imports.</text> </paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD024FA4A2B85421A878A9EF9CCF13AF1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Subsequent inclusion</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning in 2026, the Secretary, acting through the Director of the United States Geological Survey, shall include in each Mineral Commodity Summaries published by the United States Geological Survey the information described in paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (a).</text></subsection> </section> <section id="H2E1F2E97F3AE4DD8ACDFAFED8767F7E1"><enum>3.</enum><header>Priority projects</header> <subsection id="HC8DC961AD5C54F6FB00190F5AA0CA8E5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Project identification</header> <paragraph id="HEE6CC294CC6F4220ABB02BCC99158EC2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 10 days after the date of the enactment of this Act and annually thereafter, the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Agriculture, shall submit to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate a list of each mining project on Federal land for which a plan of operations, a permit application, or other application for approval has been submitted to the Department of the Interior.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA1EB152EEE06490FA42BF64E433BE3B6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Approval of certain projects</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 10 days after the date on which the Secretary submits the list required under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall, in consultation with the Secretary of Agriculture, with respect to each mining project included on the list—</text> <subparagraph id="H4FC0079C1B8D426BAE7B2BAEE85B98FB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identify each priority mining project for which the Secretary can immediately approve or issue each plan of operations, permit application, and other application for approval submitted to the Department of the Interior; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H102AF7FF277C49A1BAB817DE9476D1FA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>take all necessary and appropriate actions to expedite and approve or issue each such plan of operations, permit application, and other application for approval.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H1D4F8273A06B4E0D8AF7C9BE89B76B29"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Identification of potential hardrock mineral and byproduct production</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 10 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Agriculture, shall submit to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate a list of each mining project on Federal land, whether active, inactive, or proposed, that has the potential to—</text> 
<paragraph id="H5640259F851B4E62A96A61BDFCEBF941"><enum>(1)</enum><text>increase production of hardrock minerals or the byproducts of hardrock minerals;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H034D409402984CB6AF4DB284E262E80E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>expand operations to include the byproducts of hardrock minerals; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1E75DB083AC44B338C7F7E783C191FBB"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">produce hardrock minerals from mine tailings.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H11D010F8F92447D79ECA90D2BAF09C05"><enum>4.</enum><header>Mining potential on Federal land</header> <subsection id="H7B28A6AFACED47E0A6A3BFB13FB501C6" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall identify all Federal land managed by the Secretary or the Secretary of Agriculture, which may be leased for the exploration, development, or production of hardrock minerals or is open to location under the Act of May 10, 1872 (commonly known as the Mining Law of 1872), where—</text> 
<paragraph id="H7DAA8C8F5B614E44ADAFFFDB74ADE572"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">hardrock mineral exploration is being conducted;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H963AB1EAA8044C039283851EA8086894"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary, in consultation with the United States Geological Survey, determines hardrock minerals may be present but where thorough exploration has not been conducted; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3472AC25B62C4CE894E5C581521BF873"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">known economically recoverable hardrock minerals are present.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H3CA6E519533A455FBB6F6B569D487461"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In identifying Federal land under subsection (a), the Secretary shall prioritize identifying Federal land on which the exploration, construction, or operation of a mining project—</text> 
<paragraph id="HDC0E8FA0564E4A95BF1D56FF8B40AAF0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>can most quickly be fully permitted and operational; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H49A5F609B3EB4ACC9784284B3CA412F1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>would have the greatest potential effect on the robustness of the domestic mineral supply chain.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF081EE4FADBA4CB8899AB233C6735F67"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Submission of list</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall annually submit to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate a list of all Federal land identified under subsection (a).</text></subsection></section> <section id="H63878CC001594FDD8554EA2521571DE0"><enum>5.</enum><header>Regulatory review</header> <subsection id="H965AD0C73BBE478A82A7BCEB2518FD4F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Identifying burdensome Federal regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Agriculture, shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="HAEA4A3E942314DED83A704AE8A3AC6E7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>review all existing regulations, orders, guidance documents, policies, settlements, consent orders, public land withdrawals, and any other agency actions within the jurisdiction of the Secretary (in this section referred to collectively as <quote>agency action</quote>) to identify each agency action that imposes an undue burden on the exploration, identification, development, or operation of domestic mining projects;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HF383F3F2D1524B86B7D01222B1416F8E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>solicit industry feedback on regulatory bottlenecks and recommended strategies to expedite approval of mining projects on Federal land; and</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBA8D27A92DCD430CB6750A3A120C4863"><enum>(3)</enum><text>begin implementing an action plan—</text> <subparagraph id="H463E77BBF2E24510BEED0A339556ADF7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to implement industry feedback received pursuant to paragraph (2); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2622165076024F9481365019FD57A584"><enum>(B)</enum><text>suspend, revise, or rescind, as applicable, each agency action identified as unduly burdensome under paragraph (1) as expeditiously as possible.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF5CB6A1BA1724A67B2A84E46AFE78846"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Agriculture, shall submit to Congress a report including—</text> 
<paragraph id="HA23A62C42B67405D8EC5E540DD3D77CD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recommendations for changes to law in effect as of the date of the enactment of this Act necessary to accomplish the policy described in section 1; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H607538E534624B9DA576744D1A50D395"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a nationwide review of State and local statutes, regulations, and ordinances the Secretary determines impede development of domestic mining and mineral exploration projects.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HA692F778C1AB4A6FBB6CD10D1BABE715"><enum>6.</enum><header>Map baby map</header> 
<subsection id="HA5D036305B3E407EAFC43B37F100BC3A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall prioritize efforts to accelerate the ongoing, detailed geologic mapping of the United States, with a focus on mapping previously unknown deposits of hardrock minerals.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H27DD27B66B5140ABB6D0C9366369E15D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate a report regarding the progress and estimated completion date of the comprehensive national modern surface and subsurface mapping and data integration effort of the Department of the Interior described in section 40201 of the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/311">43 U.S.C. 311</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H96BA561D68224C839C47B583126E4094"><enum>7.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H414667661E644961BAFA2414E209F193"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Federal land</header><text>The term <term>Federal land</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H6F8128CA25524384AC00D0BA54CB52D2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>National Forest System land;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEA11CD732F0F4BDBAC233AD417132C93"><enum>(B)</enum><text>public lands; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC991D87B792D4105A8904FCC8B9D03B6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any land that may be leased for the exploration, development, or production of hardrock minerals.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1FD3D9BB311A4C18AF88D7DA7FA52C4E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Hardrock mineral</header><text>The term <term>hardrock mineral</term>—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF2A01759F2BC42F8BFCCA51E413B68A7"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes deposits of—</text> <clause id="H8BDB4A88B64B40BEB99BEE208834A484"><enum>(i)</enum><text>minerals found in sedimentary or other rocks;</text> </clause> 
<clause id="HFE22DC13B8A648EC9EB59DF01682F5C5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>base metals;</text></clause> <clause id="H9B472AC5F212496D8C1D4593B24584B5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>precious metals;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H9A25677DB3ED4C149C2E1EEC5227C1F9"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>industrial metals; and</text></clause> <clause id="HC1545A8BB7C14B9FB0740C968F552F41"><enum>(v)</enum><text>precious and semi-precious gemstones; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF48ADC97EA9549299844C585C4F03F5D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include deposits of—</text> <clause id="HAED6FA5A3A2B4311B8238F32442A50AA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>coal;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HEAD08BC3075E4A5B81AB3D4BDCEEC134"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>oil;</text></clause> <clause id="HFB4B7A7880EA4638A64D8C684BC48BA4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>oil shale;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HC8612525F7D946AC97F9D94FEEB34C26"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>gas;</text> </clause> <clause id="H37BE133921D444B7A27AC7DD7CC46F1B"><enum>(v)</enum><text>sodium;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H6C37E33959754001AEC429CC27D0C9C3"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>potassium;</text></clause> <clause id="HEF2D42C13FE849ECBBE4613AFCD3E4CC"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>sulfur; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H6C6983F8756D4E2AB1420215CF97B62F"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>mineral materials subject to disposition under the Act of July 31, 1947, commonly known as the Materials Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/601">30 U.S.C. 601 et seq.</external-xref>).</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1C0C5C6E99C04D58AF88810D3FEF1C6F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public lands</header><text>The term <term>public lands</term> has the meaning given the term in section 103 of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1702">43 U.S.C. 1702</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H76602CFC2E404EE9B3DF429B6863D2B6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text></paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

