<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-EDW25091-C3S-YJ-H6V"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1067 IS: Concrete and Asphalt Innovation Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1067</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250313">March 13, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S384">Mr. Tillis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S373">Mr. Cassidy</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To strengthen and enhance the competitiveness of cement, concrete, asphalt binder, and asphalt mixture production in the United States through the research, development, demonstration, and commercial application of technologies to reduce emissions from cement, concrete, asphalt binder, and asphalt mixture production, and for other purposes. </official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Concrete and Asphalt Innovation Act of 2025</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="id0dd8e20a77024837ac372a7cb0d381ae"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Unless otherwise provided, in this Act:</text><paragraph id="id103d34e6dce64efbb3fd9624606e480e"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Alternative fuels</header><text>The term <term>alternative fuels</term> means any solid, liquid, or gaseous material, or any combination of those materials, used to replace or supplement any portion of fuels used in combustion or pyrolysis for the production of low-emissions cement, concrete, asphalt binder, or asphalt mixture.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idacf47d6029c94172b40ad2dcc7d4ec1c"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Baseline embodied greenhouse gas emissions</header><text>The term <term>baseline embodied greenhouse gas emissions</term> means the reported industry averages (using regional averages, if available, and otherwise using national averages) of embodied greenhouse gas emissions of cement, concrete, asphalt binder, or asphalt mixture, as determined by the Secretary under section 3(h)(1). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id90b1493288e2456b9cca5245a53e9314"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Commercially available</header><text>The term <term>commercially available</term>, with respect to cement, concrete, asphalt binder, and asphalt mixture, means that the cement, concrete, asphalt binder, or asphalt mixture is, or the component materials of cement, concrete, asphalt binder, and asphalt mixture are—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="idEA35767D2AAF4B478263E18B861B1AFD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>readily and widely available for public purchase in the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idE3BC1F130BE64710A46D0E435654B4E3"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">produced using a production method that is widely in use.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id4f0c7208caad4cdeb220df199a01bd10"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Department</header><text>The term <quote>Department</quote> means the Department of Energy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id228C885407A748E4A9075F6B4EF91D6A"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="idCEC128A570384E86AE8DBAAF2BEDBB02"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a Federal entity, including a federally funded research and development center of the Department; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="idB0B99DBAA76E4F88A5F8DCB2E839BB3D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a State, territory, or possession of the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9DF72A875D154AFDBA6AADA419F190EC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a municipality of a State or equivalent geographic area in a territory or possession of the United States; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2946a42edc3f4d23823daeabd11665c3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an Indian tribe (as defined in section 207(m)(1) of title 23, United States Code);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id23CB4F85F8A64EC98C556A7AF59D3058"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a State energy office (as defined in section 124(a) of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/15821">42 U.S.C. 15821(a)</external-xref>));</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id27A7EDFA52794938A3F5170BD93B6684"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a State energy financing institution (as defined in section 1701 of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/16511">42 U.S.C. 16511</external-xref>)); </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id641A9DBCFBB14AE0ADBB656BFED60102"><enum>(G)</enum><text>an institution of higher education;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id90E55A38223D4564A1F8314F283C79B7"><enum>(H)</enum><text>a nonprofit research institution;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="idCDBCCA84D93C49ECAD040F621AC0F148"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a private entity;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id9603689B729D401BB7FDB77C1A7791A3"><enum>(J)</enum><text>any other relevant entity the Secretary determines to be appropriate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id10F20033C647473EBB17EC60B88CC72A"><enum>(K)</enum><text>a partnership or consortium of 2 or more entities described in any of subparagraphs (A) through (J).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id4cc0dcc574d244a7b6919e130e1e6591"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Embodied greenhouse gas emissions</header><text>The term <term>embodied greenhouse gas emissions</term> means greenhouse gas (as defined in section 901 of the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/17321">42 U.S.C. 17321</external-xref>)) emissions, measured in kilograms of carbon dioxide-equivalent emissions, generated as a result of the production of a material, including extraction, production, transport, and manufacturing.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id83c94cac2dce4b8d8841d463366089ca"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Engineering performance standard</header><text>The term <term>engineering performance standard</term> means a standard in which the requirements are stated in terms of required results, with criteria for verifying compliance rather than specific composition, design, or procedure. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb86738dbb5094a92a1068ca7a2a6d5e5"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Environmental product declaration</header><text>The term <term>environmental product declaration</term> means a product-specific type III environmental product declaration that—</text><subparagraph id="id2ae0497bb374431fbacdabfb6c18ee05"><enum>(A)</enum><text>conforms to ISO Standard 14025;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb8a839568f974fc1a199af29e786b423"><enum>(B)</enum><text>assesses the embodied greenhouse gas emissions of the product;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id62becc36cdd544eaaa1a95c35ec8b501"><enum>(C)</enum><text>assesses copollutant emissions; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd621275cea3e44f098022e09f392d4c6" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(D)</enum><text>allows for environmental impact comparisons between different cements, concretes, asphalt binders, and asphalt mixtures produced using the same product category rule. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idbc05d39d20ab49a89b619946fb1cd42a"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Low-emissions cement, concrete, asphalt binder, or asphalt mixture</header><text>The term <term>low-emissions cement, concrete, asphalt binder, or asphalt mixture</term> means cement, concrete, asphalt binder, or asphalt mixture—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4F10C5EB1722410E9B2FFBCB810D69EE"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that has substantially lower embodied greenhouse gas emissions and copollutant emissions than the baseline embodied greenhouse gas emissions of the cement, concrete, asphalt binder, or asphalt mixture, as applicable; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idDDD20B233A0B41A78B4FABE6AA76FCBD"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the substantially lower embodied greenhouse gas emissions and copollutant emissions of which are achieved through any combination of—</text><clause id="id24d8c26a28b34409926891130cc59bdc"><enum>(i)</enum><text>production processes using low-carbon feedstocks;</text></clause><clause id="idd285c051bf394dc986b05366efe6eed0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>higher energy efficiency at the level of the cement, concrete, asphalt binder, or asphalt mixture plant;</text></clause><clause id="id510e7f8701c74eea8b6d29d550bab777"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>low-carbon fuel substitution at the level of the cement, concrete, asphalt binder, or asphalt mixture plant;</text></clause><clause id="idf9897f0d822542ed934d8ec2352a7136"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>local production of, and use of locally sourced material in, the concrete or asphalt mixture, resulting in reduced concrete or asphalt mixture delivery miles and reduced emissions from transportation;</text></clause><clause id="ideb30ee247bb44c4497e6be549fe8aea2"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the reduction of clinker content in the cement component of concrete or the substitution of clinker content with less carbon-intensive alternative materials, such as slag cement, coal ash, natural pozzolans, recycled ground-glass pozzolan, or other supplementary cementitious material;</text></clause><clause id="id0f696b27779c45a28632e923a9d93018"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the reduction of petroleum-based asphalt in the asphalt binder component of asphalt mixtures, or the substitution of petroleum-based asphalt with less carbon-intensive alternative materials such as biobased binder, recycled material, or other alternative;</text></clause><clause id="id1827e1c07c2b400ab1892371803c3286"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>the reduction of cement in concrete or asphalt binder in asphalt mixtures through mixture optimization, including the use of admixtures;</text></clause><clause id="id936b15ebd49941619e9f1bed0a6c6ebb"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>the capture, storage, or use of point source carbon dioxide emissions during the cement, concrete, or asphalt binder production process;</text></clause><clause id="id55d187bc22614c7c88c03b9144b88257"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>the use and storage of carbon in concrete or asphalt mixture materials;</text></clause><clause id="idabd153c62a74405a9e5e13aca618445e"><enum>(x)</enum><text>the use of noncarbonate feedstocks at the level of the cement plant; or</text></clause><clause id="ide15f30b309d04fc79ab9f5982089c30a"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>other technologies, practices, or processes determined by the Secretary.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id1495186D8BA8487CB4E264827AD131B3"><enum>(10)</enum><header>National Laboratory</header><text>The term <term>National Laboratory</term> has the meaning given the term in section 2 of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/15801">42 U.S.C. 15801</external-xref>). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="ideab9cabc51ac40e78c79de1ea8c441e1"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Portland cement</header><text>The term <term>portland cement</term> means any hydraulic cement produced by pulverizing portland-cement clinker, usually including calcium sulfate and other ingredients as identified in specifications. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2ebea57328c8445685f6a09a6f598ca7"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Relevant centers</header><text>The term <term>relevant Centers</term> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id885af694f1ee434db3d4a2979cd5f530"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Turner-Fairbank Highway Research Center;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddfe6f0be119c4a5d9470aea87fea2aa2"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the William J. Hughes Technical Center;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idea2e561ecc5b40f6bb6072b7febf64ca"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the U.S. Army Engineer Research and Development Center, including the Construction Engineering Research Laboratory;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id67697cdb12794b66baded9fd9bb2fa0c"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Technical Service Center of the Bureau of Reclamation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf8c8a15f56da45bc9ad237372543819c"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the National Institute of Standards and Technology; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb513949922df4b2e81d479cc166b5362" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(F)</enum><text>any other center or institute identified by the Secretary. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id36be20de9f87423a947a0bfd1f7766d4"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Energy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc2558a322c2845a9b5ed91bc52a935be"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Task Force</header><text>The term <term>Task Force</term> means the Interagency Task Force for Concrete and Asphalt Innovation established under section 7(a).</text></paragraph></section><section id="idb602ea54d0fd42f5a590b2c5c7454cb2"><enum>3.</enum><header>Low-emissions cement, concrete, asphalt binder, and asphalt mixture production research program</header><subsection id="idd987fa0377d74bf7b7d36ad4e37e5fa6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of this section is to advance the research and development of innovative technologies aimed at—</text><paragraph id="id455549b5b4174a0189cc96b3ecdb814c"><enum>(1)</enum><text>achieving significant greenhouse gas emissions and copollutant emissions reductions in the production processes for cement, concrete, asphalt binder, and asphalt mixture products;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4ff6e99a000e492886da09c254f952d0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>increasing the technological and economic competitiveness of industry and production in the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4c96fed575af4376941955a3f30ffe4d"><enum>(3)</enum><text>increasing the stability of supply chains through enhanced domestic production, nearshoring, and cooperation with allies; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbd5a4e0498fb4116ad1fa4cca1ad4368"><enum>(4)</enum><text>creating quality domestic jobs. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id58b191b2e8fb44fdb35493723b7f091a"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment of program</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall establish a program of research, development, demonstration, and commercial application of tools, technologies, and methods for the production and use of low-emissions cement, concrete, asphalt binder, or asphalt mixture.</text></subsection><subsection id="idf05cdd388be046018738c8cdbf1e613e"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>In carrying out the program established under subsection (b), the Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="id436a1c637b904963b7d903732779842d"><enum>(1)</enum><text>coordinate the activities carried out under that program with, as applicable—</text><subparagraph id="id223ca68f71bd482194ace30e42e76cc2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the activities of the Industrial Efficiency and Decarbonization Office of the Office of Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy of the Department, the Advanced Materials and Manufacturing Technologies Office of the Office of Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy of the Department, the Office of Fossil Energy and Carbon Management of the Department, the Office of Manufacturing and Energy Supply Chains of the Department, the Building Technologies Office of the Department, the Office of Clean Energy Demonstrations of the Department, the Department of Transportation, the Department of Defense, and the General Services Administration, including activities carried out pursuant to a collaborative research and development partnership described in section 6(a) of the American Energy Manufacturing Technical Corrections Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6351">42 U.S.C. 6351(a)</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id738047b9ae8a45259027abea063be720"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the activities carried out under sections 454, 455, and 456 of the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/17113">42 U.S.C. 17113</external-xref>, 17114, 17115); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id954e50530ea64406ae17677a47268ab3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>activities carried out pursuant to the national plan for smart manufacturing technology development and deployment developed under section 6006 of the Energy Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/17115a">42 U.S.C. 17115a</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idef1eeb355b10445690d1c2ac954b5a7f"><enum>(2)</enum><text>conduct research, development, and demonstration of technologies for the production and use of low-emissions cement, concrete, asphalt binder, and asphalt mixtures that have the potential to increase—</text><subparagraph id="idf8693a62cd8c4da6a0970e4fb3855643"><enum>(A)</enum><text>domestic production and use of low-emissions cement, concrete, asphalt binder, and asphalt mixtures; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8c6fb801d0694ec48680a6e267a73c54"><enum>(B)</enum><text>employment in fields relating to that domestic production and use.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id54a2c24a7860439cb8e7dbc81fa68854"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Focus areas</header><text>In carrying out the program established under subsection (b), the Secretary shall focus on—</text><paragraph id="id2a389a317ad546daaa4a78a39ae44006"><enum>(1)</enum><text>carbon capture and utilization technologies for cement or asphalt binder production processes, which may include—</text><subparagraph id="idaffad7a1a8814c5893a1a999138412a8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>oxycombustion and chemical looping technologies; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb9ede208acf245e195a79fa5610821c5"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">precombustion technologies;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id92a402308d5b45b08d4dd2aa8b193499"><enum>(C)</enum><text>postcombustion technologies;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id623317f88b344c3d997e283f19850bc9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>direct carbon dioxide separation technologies;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id534022269a1e40d4b2c7ceadd8208fa9"><enum>(E)</enum><text>reactive carbon capture technologies; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id86a81c325b59456b80e98a6371074661"><enum>(F)</enum><text>carbon utilization technologies; </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id65784a5bc9ca4710a67d4a422199762d"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">alternative materials, technologies, and processes that—</text><subparagraph id="id037a96040b744f68a8758238df5eee5d"><enum>(A)</enum><text>produce fewer greenhouse gas and copollutant emissions during production, use, or end use of cement, concrete, asphalt binder, or asphalt mixtures; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9b29c361306e48afbd80f81a351d481a"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to quality, durability, and resilience, provide products that are equivalent to or better than commercially available products; </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide76dd6c693ce45e590468d8028020659"><enum>(3)</enum><text>medium- and high-temperature heat-generation technologies used for production of low-emissions cement, asphalt binder, and asphalt mixtures, which may include—</text><subparagraph id="id7bd22a718cb64b35ac10af533c3b41bd"><enum>(A)</enum><text>alternative fuels;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4cd313870fad44438f9ff5ae9be471df"><enum>(B)</enum><text>renewable heat-generation and storage technology;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd24b9637a3364d77818517c2536db7aa"><enum>(C)</enum><text>electrification of heating processes;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id27c9f5b141c74e8a8df2e5519b5a7add"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">other heat-generation and storage sources;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id669e41fe840a47d390245211567107e9"><enum>(E)</enum><text>products that enable higher efficiency of cement, concrete, or asphalt utilization; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idec5052ab65d34ec3806d9451ad457fad"><enum>(F)</enum><text>products that have increased durability and require less frequent replacement; </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide265fe02cbbf4087bef58450eeada147"><enum>(4)</enum><text>technologies and practices that minimize energy and natural resource consumption, which may include—</text><subparagraph id="idd3f416b7bfa84ccf9b4a712a67488913"><enum>(A)</enum><text>designing products that enable reuse, refurbishment, remanufacturing, or recycling;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id51833abbc7f44d608bd7e2d8fbbde7cb"><enum>(B)</enum><text>minimizing waste, including waste heat, from cement, concrete, asphalt binder, and asphalt mixture production processes, including through the reuse of waste as a resource in other industrial processes for mutual benefit;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd5a15870c35245a799653845f81c8185"><enum>(C)</enum><text>increasing resource efficiency; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8ede3d6cce0f4e719a32e32f1817bee2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>increasing the energy efficiency of cement, concrete, asphalt binder, or asphalt mixture production processes;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id58ab35b46d0e450c98666cef4bb76b28"><enum>(5)</enum><text>technologies and approaches to reduce copollutants from the production of cement, concrete, asphalt binder, or asphalt mixtures, including—</text><subparagraph id="id384ea0dd8cd748f29571e67cfe686061"><enum>(A)</enum><text>sulfur dioxide; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0840c2a1e5334683bea8cae44071c954"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">nitrogen oxide;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide6bd997bc7ad4a3f8e8dd44fb44e9796"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">particulate matter;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4741debdbef14375a2441253d180e9d6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>carbon monoxide emissions; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd1c0fdebe7f242ada8cc5159673ef199"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a hazardous air pollutant (as defined in section 112(a) of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7412">42 U.S.C. 7412(a)</external-xref>));</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3f5adc49ebb94c6e8783e2b73e18ecfb"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">high-performance computing to develop advanced materials and production processes that may contribute to the focus areas described in paragraphs (1) through (5), including—</text><subparagraph id="id0b8c20edf7af4d25a6e872c4e82ea5ba"><enum>(A)</enum><text>modeling, simulation, and optimization of the design of energy-efficient and sustainable products; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id02d591742c48469585fe867694d1392c"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the use of digital prototyping and additive production to enhance product design; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id75579d6a7ca441528736430b9cab0824"><enum>(7)</enum><text>technologies that can be retrofitted at cement, concrete, asphalt binder, or asphalt mixture plants that represent the most common facility types in the United States and in other countries.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id96199d888bf846f393449835a1d354d3"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Strategic plan</header><paragraph id="id038d55b010e94b12a228fa069f0f061a"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall develop and submit to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate and the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives a 5-year strategic plan identifying research, development, demonstration, and commercial application goals for the program established under subsection (b).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf9d6aec612f549d1b4c01caff8d99794"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The strategic plan developed under paragraph (1) shall—</text><subparagraph id="idd19b436bea724a54b250ed9946547e91"><enum>(A)</enum><text>establish technological and programmatic goals to achieve the requirements described in subsection (c);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide41180833cac4048a93f18854e647e16"><enum>(B)</enum><text>document existing activities of the Department and other Federal agencies relating to low-emissions cement, concrete, asphalt binder, or asphalt mixtures;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id991667e18cbc4b1cbc0fa89078194186"><enum>(C)</enum><text>identify existing programs of the Department that—</text><clause id="id58bb09d36f1c4d0fbcdb69c4641c46c9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>relate to the production of low-emissions cement, concrete, asphalt binder, or asphalt mixtures; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb7833349853b4df0b3bdd4f473669c78"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">support, or could support, the research, development, demonstration, and commercial application activities described in this section, including any demonstration projects carried out under subsection (f);</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9bcc417b4300479292b1cc1e7ed236c1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to avoid duplication of efforts, incorporate findings from—</text><clause id="idbf6ac2c69ddb477b952cfd5c2d483d3d"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the document of the Department entitled <quote>Industrial Decarbonization Roadmap</quote>, numbered DOE/EE–2635, and dated September 2022;</text></clause><clause id="idccaf0694cf0c40e6bd47bd64c9122b27"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the document of the Department entitled <quote>Pathway to Commercial Liftoff: Low-Carbon Cement</quote>, and dated September 2023; </text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1564026125a94749b12215a0ae7b242e"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Label Program for Low Embodied Carbon Construction Materials of the Environmental Protection Agency and any other relevant program of the Environmental Protection Agency; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="ida4c56596a55d4ce1b93bba751bee1e2d"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the Energy Star program established by section 324A of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6294a">42 U.S.C. 6294a</external-xref>);</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id12c22797dec94528aed1622fe3b5998b"><enum>(E)</enum><text>identify any new programs needed to fully carry out this section;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id902dd5abc6334f2d9228479fd397942c"><enum>(F)</enum><text>identify resource needs of the Department relating to the research, development, and demonstration of technologies for the production and use of low-emissions cement, concrete, asphalt binder, and asphalt mixtures;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9dcc019a8ae249a696dd1417e3e9ba36"><enum>(G)</enum><text>identify research areas that the private sector is unable or unwilling to undertake due to the cost of, or risks associated with, the research; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id67fbd4d89be24059bcee1e0616bf56c1"><enum>(H)</enum><text>identify and engage in opportunities for the Department, National Laboratories, and relevant Centers to participate in international standards setting to enhance United States manufacturing competitiveness.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idcd71034efbdf4531808108d59fb2be52"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Updates to plan</header><text>Not less frequently than once every 2 years, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate and the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives an updated version of the strategic plan developed under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id7fcba466a1ef4931a557de8cefc664a3"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Demonstration initiative</header><paragraph id="idfb905d5c1db34a189549a39979429eaa"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary, in consultation with industry partners, institutions of higher education, environmental nongovernmental organizations, the Secretary of Transportation, the Administrator of General Services, National Laboratories, and relevant Centers, shall establish, as part of the program established under subsection (b), an initiative (referred to in this subsection as the <quote>initiative</quote>) for the demonstration of 1 or more methods for the production of low-emissions cement, concrete, asphalt binder, and asphalt mixtures that use either—</text><subparagraph id="id62cbc49b9e7849e9af28a8cbc5b28ac7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a single technology; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idcb4d4f4a741446afa5448a7f957c9e4e"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a combination of multiple technologies.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idb70538040a0442219b15205c981221f5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Selection of eligible entities</header><subparagraph id="id328011cd8ed74627a986727788de3ed7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall select eligible entities to carry out demonstration projects under the initiative.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4fa3656b82d248e684beed34c4f1b346"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>In selecting eligible entities to carry out demonstration projects under subparagraph (A), the Secretary, to the maximum extent practicable, shall—</text><clause id="id4a65e92638e84b5caf86559da59e90b5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>ensure—</text><subclause id="idfbf1c66f98364da19b6a84a09c3b616e"><enum>(I)</enum><text>regional diversity among the eligible entities selected, including by selecting eligible entities located in rural areas (as defined in section 343(a) of the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1991">7 U.S.C. 1991(a)</external-xref>));</text></subclause><subclause id="id8314951a20b847519a7f443d86d200bb"><enum>(II)</enum><text>technological diversity among the eligible entities selected; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc19fd8320db64e7a91e7017b6d2ba515"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that the projects carried out by those eligible entities under the initiative expand on the existing technology demonstration programs of the Department; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id0f5f78f2e36244e3944b289a4ce718a0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>prioritize the selection of eligible entities—</text><subclause id="id8723dae6a5984622ab5b4c891acf7fa8"><enum>(I)</enum><text>based on the extent to which the projects carried out by the eligible entities contribute to emissions reductions; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id75cd698fc43a4ac99d3e6b0a1b3d6471"><enum>(II)</enum><text>that will carry out projects that leverage matching funds from non-Federal sources.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4d981aa8e04a41f2b87e7ceefb352bfe"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Reports</header><subparagraph id="ide30d261cb5044d92ac1b10821b293827"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not less frequently than once every 2 years for the duration of the initiative, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate and the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives a report that, for the period covered by the report—</text><clause id="id13ac82255b8c4c88ba1256130220756c"><enum>(i)</enum><text>describes the activities carried out by the Secretary in support of the initiative;</text></clause><clause id="idbb3f7a779c5840778fa9665b31fd20c9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provides a review of the cost-competitiveness and other value streams, the technology readiness level, and the adoption readiness level of each technology demonstrated under the initiative;</text></clause><clause id="id7668a1be2a08400794f0240e9497c7b1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>describes the status and outcomes of any projects carried out under the initiative; and</text></clause><clause id="idaa8a9a2ed7304421a85827215540b25f"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>recommends appropriate application of cement, concrete, asphalt binder, and asphalt mixture materials, in consultation with engineering and design experts with demonstrated records of utilization of novel materials in construction.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id46ab794a22094564838767b35b7c3358"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Final report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the initiative is terminated, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate and the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives a report assessing the success of, and any education provided by, the demonstration projects carried out by any recipients of financial assistance under the initiative.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id59b028cd64894ff3968fad32bc20d23c"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out the initiative $200,000,000 for the period of fiscal years 2025 through 2029.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2a940cc59d714824ace962b6515519cb"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The Secretary may terminate the initiative if the Secretary determines that sufficient low-emissions cement, concrete, asphalt binder, and asphalt mixtures are commercially available domestically at a price comparable to the price of cement, concrete, asphalt binder, and asphalt mixtures produced through traditional methods of production.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id924b83fcc0634d5d981ca5d58f47a902"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Technical assistance program</header><paragraph id="idf08ff53b8d52468eba02ba9743d3d811"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Transportation, the Secretary of Commerce (acting through the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology), and the Administrator of General Services, shall provide technical assistance to eligible entities to carry out an activity described in paragraph (2) to promote the commercial application of technologies for the production and use of low-emissions cement, concrete, asphalt binder, or asphalt mixtures.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide4f7666e60a64b85836ad564849c5b30"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Activities described</header><text>An activity referred to in paragraph (1) is—</text><subparagraph id="ide870b21477fa448e8c0eef33336372e5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the updating of local codes, specifications, and standards to engineering performance standards;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4b0b1e43e6204818a0c437f152c19d98"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a lifecycle assessment of the final product;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9c58948df0e44fba958b4a6308e93d8c"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an environmental product declaration;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id58b5fb5e5ba745b2a00be930a655d249"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a techno-economic assessment;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfd1ce6a3575f4e6abd3015f836af5dd2"><enum>(E)</enum><text>an environmental permitting or other regulatory process;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3871ef8c586840b69bae1daba3d99d99"><enum>(F)</enum><text>an evaluation or testing activity; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5d2775cba05448089b6a5b66cc871142"><enum>(G)</enum><text>any other activity that promotes the commercial application of technologies developed through the program established under subsection (b).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id55304efadf2a4c15b9cb18b98cbadf50"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Applications</header><text>The Secretary shall seek applications for technical assistance under this subsection—</text><subparagraph id="id8fca279f667248d8a9465542b10f59b3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>on a competitive basis; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id033f971e8800409da4e67af84e39a6d4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>on a periodic basis, but not less frequently than once every 12 months.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5295fa1a114f4236bf3a0ecb68521fcd"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Regional centers</header><text>The Secretary may designate or establish 1 or more regional centers to provide technical assistance to eligible entities to carry out the activities described in paragraph (2).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idBF326F2E620A48BFB3E4E9B66E1D732A"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Determination of emission levels</header><paragraph id="idFFC14F22AADA48299503F68361FBD8F9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Baseline embodied greenhouse gas emissions</header><text>The Secretary shall determine current baseline embodied greenhouse gas emissions of cement, concrete, asphalt binder, and asphalt mixtures, including a detailed methodology for determining each of those emissions.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb7c04453bf1b44a488161a2fc9ce62d1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Timeline for regional-level emissions reductions</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall determine a timeline for regional-level emissions reductions, to the maximum extent practicable, taking into consideration—</text><subparagraph id="id48e33f8026fe4bb0a1de531172949492"><enum>(A)</enum><text>potential for greenhouse gas emissions reductions;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id151dc694b0504c76aa779bc02a445a84"><enum>(B)</enum><text>feedstock availability;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida9bcc948f9344a4288808522238ef60b"><enum>(C)</enum><text>equipment and skilled workforce availability;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1fd06ebaa8f74bab8d2aba885c3d8893"><enum>(D)</enum><text>technology and market readiness levels of low-emissions cement, concrete, asphalt binder, and asphalt mixture technologies;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id36c625dfca254edea0cbbc61c44ccb98"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the regulatory and specification landscape; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida3a1907e094d4750b48fe96905608a88"><enum>(F)</enum><text>any other factor, as determined by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9a0a3e9c108d400e97e1426e7fad40f2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Consultation</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf4650b72b88440d583dba55f044d56f7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>EPA</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out this subsection, the Secretary may consult with the Label Program for Low Embodied Carbon Construction Materials of the Environmental Protection Agency and any other relevant program of the Environmental Protection Agency.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idab526e70416542d7bcbd8ec2792270a9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Stakeholders</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out this subsection, the Secretary shall consult with the following stakeholders, who shall reflect regional diversity to the maximum extent practicable: </text><clause id="id738d20da5c9e4234ab99e574047eb0fe"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Entities in the cement, concrete, asphalt binder, and asphalt mixture sectors, including—</text><subclause id="id9d16f4b8ddba47bf897b6dd8eb11efde"><enum>(I)</enum><text>ready-mix or site-mixed concrete producers;</text></subclause><subclause id="id8fb41ae9252e4f02bf6abc706a1cdb6e"><enum>(II)</enum><text>precast concrete producers;</text></subclause><subclause id="idbc26ed43b1d3448795a0be23df67bfa4"><enum>(III)</enum><text>portland cement and other cement producers;</text></subclause><subclause id="id66bde14fac4340fab657cc51689c39bc"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>aggregate producers;</text></subclause><subclause id="id5d552a9f27d74b189e57ce409f0c4a09"><enum>(V)</enum><text>asphalt binder producers;</text></subclause><subclause id="id3464492500f54758813185f501bc114c"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>asphalt mixture producers;</text></subclause><subclause id="id6d3a687019994055a776bddc6e30f6af"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>producers of emerging cement, concrete, asphalt binder, or asphalt mixture solutions; and</text></subclause><subclause id="ide2516881385746c7b91887820cf8e3fe"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text>distributors and users of cement, concrete, asphalt binder, or asphalt mixture production.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id66343741b4dc46998b9a8341edd51e25"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Contracting companies with at least 1 Federal Government contract awarded in the preceding 5 years.</text></clause><clause id="id4726723d5e214d3ca4c9d3c64f0fd5bf"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Contracting companies with at least 1 private sector contract awarded in the preceding 5 years.</text></clause><clause id="idd6cbd06c0579458b893afb5b6aa65271"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Experts, including from nongovernmental organizations, on the environmental impact of cement, concrete, asphalt binder, and asphalt mixture production in architectural and nonarchitectural applications, with expertise in—</text><subclause id="idad5e99fcb8ad44d98e3602f476eea7f1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>developing codes, specifications, and standards for cement, concrete, asphalt binder, and asphalt mixtures;</text></subclause><subclause id="idd6a5330861e646b6a1dd674c08001849"><enum>(II)</enum><text>conducting performance tests on cement, concrete, asphalt binder, and asphalt mixtures;</text></subclause><subclause id="ideee1d0ae9e5e4f50aaefe2b3055cb542"><enum>(III)</enum><text>working with the National Institute of Building Sciences;</text></subclause><subclause id="idfd378bc70e4745bda8d6f884023c9ea9"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>working for State departments of transportation from different regions of the United States; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id2c68df6abeff49e88c408d1e8eeb0c66"><enum>(V)</enum><text>developing benchmarks for embodied greenhouse gas emissions.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id5c3ec72819194b55af3b4efd4839c9c2"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Public agencies at the State, county, and local government. </text></clause><clause id="idc7a07bb58613465d9264f8e260856007"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Stakeholders in any other relevant industries, as determined by the Secretary.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id6c6be2c9758f4f35a755ab7e3adc90ac"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Manufacturing USA institutes</header><text>In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="ida430796528374d8b8341e838ba4f3f9c"><enum>(1)</enum><text>support, including through financial assistance provided under subsection (e) of section 34 of the National Institute of Standards and Technology Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/278s">15 U.S.C. 278s</external-xref>), Manufacturing USA institutes established or supported under section 4(d);</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="ida0f672904dd641259a53e4c9c837ba82"><enum>(2)</enum><text>leverage the resources of those Manufacturing USA institutes; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id6ab92ae829d84a2c9a3070d350bef0d1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>integrate the activities carried out under the program established under subsection (b) with the activities of those Manufacturing USA institutes.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idc8f4aa8bce6043228f11b7dcedab90d9"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Other Federal agencies</header><text>In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall coordinate with relevant officials at other Federal agencies that are carrying out research and development initiatives to increase industrial competitiveness and achieve significant greenhouse gas emissions reductions in the production of low-emissions cement, concrete, asphalt binder, or asphalt mixtures, including relevant officials at the Department of Defense, the Department of Transportation, the General Services Administration, and the National Institute of Standards and Technology.</text></subsection></section><section id="id534fa2e1d19244f7bb3a59d1d98d746a"><enum>4.</enum><header>Low-emissions concrete and low-emissions asphalt Manufacturing USA institutes</header><subsection id="id777acb14c10a413d80e5d933eaa7dc4b"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="id92d0c52ba23b4bae98a37a34b29abb96"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Manufacturing USA institute</header><text>The term <term>Manufacturing USA institute</term> has the meaning given the term in section 34(d) of the National Institute of Standards and Technology Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/278s">15 U.S.C. 278s(d)</external-xref>). </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2f9ca3e087a34703b4706306dc9b238c"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Commerce, acting through the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id3cc87b1ef7de4d61b1abb9e186b327ad"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of this section is to support—</text><paragraph id="id28b280980b8643f2974bd5015aae9bfb"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the development of standardized testing and technical validation of low-emissions cement, concrete, asphalt binder, and asphalt mixtures; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id526a551538b64ff7951163b0827f1921"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the expansion, reskilling, and upskilling of the manufacturing workforce to increase employment in fields relating to the domestic production and use of low-emissions cement, concrete, asphalt binder, and asphalt mixtures; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9c8e63afbfbc47708576e31ad92b283c"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the quantification of embodied greenhouse gas emissions to identify low-emissions cement, concrete, and asphalt materials.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4c70313c8a6b4af8ab63cf31d20a1256"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall consider strategies for—</text><paragraph id="idb01aee5e481b4937b19264f524610702"><enum>(1)</enum><text>improving the durability and performance of cement, concrete, asphalt binder, and asphalt mixtures, including low-emissions cement, concrete, asphalt binder, and asphalt mixtures;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id03ab1f35d1d04267ad58d1254fda89a0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>reducing the cost of low-emissions cement, concrete, asphalt binder, and asphalt mixtures;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4fb37429300c4f7fb5e88a9596350719"><enum>(3)</enum><text>supporting continuous innovation and emissions reductions in the production of low-emissions cement, concrete, asphalt binder, and asphalt mixtures;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idda92a86f892941a68dee16897ebf8af3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>increasing employment in fields relating to the domestic production and use of low-emissions cement, concrete, asphalt binder, and asphalt mixtures; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbf7f6c983d5e4d8f8ec84fac962d0050"><enum>(5)</enum><text>providing information to satisfy the responsibilities of the Task Force.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id9690125559de434aa110f8df43dc1424"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authority To establish or support the establishment of Manufacturing USA institutes focused on low-Emissions cement and concrete and low-Emissions asphalt binder and mixtures</header><paragraph id="id013f8f4bdcb6411fbe3a5fa7ac57eda9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subsection (g), the Secretary may, in consultation with the Secretary of Energy, the Secretary of Transportation, the Secretary of Defense, and the Administrator of the General Services Administration, establish, or award financial assistance under section 34(e)(1) of the National Institute of Standards and Technology Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/278s">15 U.S.C. 278s(e)(1)</external-xref>) to plan, establish, or support, 2 Manufacturing USA institutes, 1 for low-emissions cement and concrete and 1 for low-emissions asphalt binder and mixtures that— </text><subparagraph id="id49398abf7f2c4ae8a0b8b99799b3572c"><enum>(A)</enum><text>establish advanced testing capabilities for properties of low-emissions cement or concrete and low-emissions binder or mixtures, respectively, produced by an eligible entity;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfce26ff0801c4d7a993cc44c9a062231"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide centralized, publicly available data on the properties of low-emissions cement or concrete and low-emissions asphalt binder or mixtures, respectively;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf906ccfe2cdc434fae38604902f22c88"><enum>(C)</enum><text>support the development and implementation of education, training, and workforce recruitment courses, materials, and programs addressing workforce needs in fields related to the domestic production and use of low-emissions cement or concrete, and low-emissions asphalt binder or mixtures, respectively, through training and education programs at all appropriate education levels; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id837c6325962f43f2b78789a1489f337d"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">quantify embodied greenhouse gas emissions for low-emissions cement, concrete, asphalt binder, and mixtures; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3d408c7654c54b18865d1c79e96ce590"><enum>(E)</enum><text>provide collected information to the Task Force.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id95d6570a0d1946ca9f482fe49ad4d88d"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>In addition to subparagraphs (A) through (E) of paragraph (1), the Secretary shall require the Manufacturing USA institutes established, planned, or supported under such paragraph to coordinate with the research program established under section 3(b) to carry out activities focused on researching, developing, demonstrating, and deploying low-emissions cement, concrete, asphalt binder, and asphalt mixtures.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb3f3ab112f8c4577a11defc4ee4390d4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Support and assistance for States</header><subparagraph id="id57b629b64bd542a2b13a149273fb7324"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Manufacturing USA institutes established, planned, or supported under paragraph (1) shall, pursuant to a request from a State agency for testing support, guidance, or resources, provide the State agency with such testing support, guidance, or resources in the form of technical assistance or a grant.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id69c06788eac94b4ca3ca544714afe4dd"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Condition</header><text>The Secretary shall require, as a condition on the receipt of a grant under subparagraph (A), that the recipient of the grant make publicly available all data collected by the recipient using amounts from the grant.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id373a060a6b7741e38f62d950c5ac1618"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Selection of cement, concrete, asphalt binder, or asphalt mixtures for testing</header><text>In selecting cement, concrete, asphalt binder, or asphalt mixtures from eligible entities for testing by the Manufacturing USA institutes established, planned, or supported under subsection (d)(1), the Manufacturing USA institutes shall—</text><paragraph id="idaa5733d48ee0436f91c693bc32fb208a"><enum>(1)</enum><text>seek to achieve regional diversity in the cement, concrete, asphalt binder, or asphalt mixtures from eligible entities selected for testing;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id359530fa77334a168b355476df41e543"><enum>(2)</enum><text>seek to achieve technological diversity in the cement, concrete, asphalt binder, or asphalt mixtures from eligible entities selected for testing;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id532f913c30d2429f87450ce1bfebbe58"><enum>(3)</enum><text>prioritize cement, concrete, asphalt binder, or asphalt mixtures from eligible entities that leverage matching funds from non-Federal sources; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id958e4aa499284acca96880a4cde29edf"><enum>(4)</enum><text>prioritize projects that would have the greatest reduction in emissions on a lifecycle basis.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id37e9af34d81245d08f626ff3a6060b02"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Alternatives</header><text>The Secretary may carry out this section by—</text><paragraph id="id00250c79cd8444118a8030aa11caeeea"><enum>(1)</enum><text>leveraging resources of relevant existing Manufacturing USA institutes;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id549f3e7c122c4cc1abaa6e09c4c4d441"><enum>(2)</enum><text>leveraging resources of relevant agencies, such as the Cement and Concrete Center of Excellence of the Department of Energy; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc97ebbff34d14416a3546892aa4e72a5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>integrating program activities into a relevant existing Manufacturing USA institute; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide2ebe7829dab41cbbaaaa3b547360e18"><enum>(4)</enum><text>establishing new Manufacturing USA institutes in accordance with subsection (d).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id87e817920c04468d97a3ca17b67df68e"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>The Secretary shall carry out this section using amounts otherwise available to the Secretary.</text></subsection></section><section id="id8fec572cc4dd455fb8052552fd877077"><enum>5.</enum><header>Federal Highway Administration</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id56f6d7cedecf4b5b9efe4bdebc4662d6"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Performance-Based low-Emissions transportation materials grants</header><paragraph id="idb3281678e95e4629903d055220bbd90e"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of this subsection is to encourage States to improve State-level cement, concrete, asphalt binder, and asphalt mixture specifications and standards to facilitate the purchase of low-emissions cement, concrete, asphalt binder, or asphalt mixtures.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6ada441ffa5746d59e8ee1e8c8181655"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Administrator of the Federal Highway Administration (referred to in this section as the <term>Administrator</term>) shall provide to States—</text><subparagraph id="id34b738445050439e97e34782b8425f80"><enum>(A)</enum><text>reimbursement for the additional cost of using low-emissions cement, concrete, asphalt binder, and asphalt mixtures used in highway projects of the State;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf075a5cd243345c8ba04467d8e785264"><enum>(B)</enum><text>incentives for the acquisition of low-emissions cement, concrete, asphalt binder, and asphalt mixtures for use in highway projects of the State; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5e4f595a3f564cb99cad78f142d98f3f"><enum>(C)</enum><text>technical assistance to update the specifications and standards of the State to be performance-based specifications and standards; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id53b88915e80b44719dba7238a563cb6c"><enum>(D)</enum><text>technical assistance to benchmark and quantify embodied greenhouse gas emissions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idfef8b48ad8754e5193a8da77460d4443"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Reimbursement and incentive amounts</header><subparagraph id="id11685e90974e4d73b284925c6d23beaf"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Incremental amount</header><text>The amount of reimbursement under paragraph (2)(A) shall be equal to the incrementally higher cost of using such materials relative to the cost of using traditional materials, as determined by the State and verified by the Administrator.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2b05513120b6470dae092ea247223e21"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Incentive amount</header><text>The amount of an incentive under paragraph (2)(B) shall be equal to 2 percent of the cost of using low-emissions cement, concrete, asphalt binder, and asphalt mixtures on a highway project of the State.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd4a537093a8f47f1af1589da2f9c5baa"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Amounts provided for reimbursement and incentives under this subsection may not exceed the amount authorized to be appropriated under paragraph (6). </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id930b20fc08144b898773699edcaf5579"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>To be eligible to receive reimbursement or incentives under this subsection, a State shall have in effect, as appropriate, special provisions, specifications, or standards, such as engineering performance standards, or a collection of embodied greenhouse gas emissions reporting tools, such as environmental product declarations, that facilitate the purchase of low-emissions cement, concrete, asphalt binder, and asphalt mixtures.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf4a379782f884e27976c1131027fbcbe"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>In carrying out this subsection, the Administrator shall leverage the Every Day Counts Initiative of the Department of Transportation to promote the commercialization of low-emissions cement, concrete, asphalt binder, and asphalt mixtures.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc74b68301a024e4c8c9cd935beb38933"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this subsection $15,000,000 for the period of fiscal years 2025 through 2027.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc00cd21b47a944a09ff72738103f209e"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Directory of low-Emissions cement, concrete, asphalt binder, or asphalt mixtures</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id980d1c69db4044e3bcf84f8a8852c80d"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator shall establish and maintain a publicly available directory of low-emissions cement, concrete, asphalt binder, or asphalt mixtures submitted by States that the Administrator determines to be eligible for reimbursement or incentives under subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc9cf326225aa47888bbc4e7100d48b84"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Submission and approval</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4f2b76e2ad5841a68e863c01c7f73558"><enum>(A)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall establish a procedure under which States may submit new low-emissions cement, concrete, asphalt binder, or asphalt mixtures to be included in the directory under paragraph (1). </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4c03223535ca461888e83184939ec039"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Submission</header><text>To be considered for inclusion in the directory under paragraph (1), a State shall submit an application relating to the low-emissions cement, concrete, asphalt binder, or asphalt mixture to the Administrator at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Administrator determines to be necessary.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idebc2d4d0060b478eb658b7b272be8dd5"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Decision deadline</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date on which the Administrator receives an application under subparagraph (B), the Administrator shall—</text><clause id="idaa1196ae224b45bbaf98519eb1c8bb8a"><enum>(i)</enum><text>approve the application and include the low-emissions cement, concrete, asphalt binder, or asphalt mixture in the directory under paragraph (1); or</text></clause><clause id="id5cda306c454845ca9425944a8f1b5168"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>deny the application.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9bcf0d1fcba249218af2d11deb855335"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Written reasons for denial</header><text>If the Administrator denies an application under subparagraph (C)(ii), the Administrator shall provide the State a written explanation for the denial. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8cdf64077c0a419f9c613176cc63b279"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Project selection</header><text>Low-emissions cement, concrete, asphalt binder, or asphalt mixtures approved under paragraph (2)(C)(i) and included in the directory under paragraph (1) may be used in any highway project. </text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id4565aa8af5894dc7a5c7a9442fb948c1"><enum>6.</enum><header>Advance purchase commitment program</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id893393446118468c8c8f257cc9527206"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purposes of this section are—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0dddd6992e1c4fe29f19f54269607f55"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to allow States to purchase or contractually guarantee the direct purchase of conforming low-emissions cement, concrete, asphalt binder, or asphalt mixtures; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcff0bf6028024c6c881df44f596bf03c"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to encourage continuous innovation and long-term emissions reductions in the production of concrete, cement, asphalt binder, and asphalt mixtures. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6e55ac9a4fff42cb9d35cc8fcc96656e"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible projects</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 133 of title 23, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6a5408ef2cf343f8848a97f0d801733b"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b), by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id76DECF6EA8EC48AB9FBA425E9970B51F"><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbf3c807d311a4971b139268dd85356fc"><enum>(25)</enum><text>A project that includes the use of innovative, domestically produced cement, concrete, asphalt mixture, or asphalt binder manufactured using a process described in subsection (l)(1).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id84876120ae984a2d811048d76ea0baa8"><enum>(26)</enum><text>Subject to subsection (l)(2), a project that is carried out through an advance multiyear contract with a producer for a specified quantity and specified price of innovative, domestically produced cement, concrete, asphalt mixture, or asphalt binder manufactured using a process described in subsection (l)(1).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaf4c43fc1f3745318f18d15243544545"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idA61FC80BDA3F476CB8862EB6DFCF0344"><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id33a848b3208a4e1fb0712ec831c78450"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Requirements for certain projects</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6ae48113f13345a4b7e54e132db38417"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Manufacturing process described</header><text>The process referred to in paragraphs (25) and (26) of subsection (b) is a manufacturing process that—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5a18ef0999fb49cf9c7ecd42462aafcd"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">produces materials with—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id32ab2b504321487fbe0b3a3b3c8b44b3"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">superior durability to conventional materials; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id917688c80f5a4f2593732070c17c30e1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">superior performance with respect to—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc8211ef4c1884bb682663f02b259b87e"><enum>(I)</enum><text>compressive strength;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ided5681631114488f8934678d775673d9"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">tensile strength; or </text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3953def3223a47b6ad1a7334941c2013"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">workability; or</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0318cbc9e58c450e9e1dcba47fc28f1a"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">produces materials that meet the engineering specifications of the State and achieves superior performance with respect to—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id954d3167817d4355847ce04e7dab5dd7"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">environmental performance; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4d3fe9bc051f4f8791f5d48beba89d13"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>energy efficiency.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1a11663b6fbb47d78ab94563b5e22be0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Advance multiyear contracts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an advance multiyear contract described in subsection (b)(26), the contract—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id87fd11da54614e2bbec6a9005bcecef6"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall not include in the cancellation provisions consideration of recurring manufacturing costs of the producer associated with the production of unfunded units to be delivered under the contract;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3711473ff492489cbfb6b396409a7c8d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall provide that payments to the producer under the contract are not made in advance of incurred costs on funded units; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id184e38b8afdb4df79ce16742b273accd"><enum>(C)</enum><text>shall not include a price adjustment based on a failure to award a follow-on contract; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id631690f519b54d12b62a238d32c4e575"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall require that the producer submit to the applicable State a statement that describes the quantity and cost of the cement, concrete, asphalt mixture, and asphalt binder;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id70648cf6b189451bb876344101674efe"><enum>(E)</enum><text>shall require that the producer shall demonstrate to the applicable State material progress toward commercial production and operational capacity of cement, concrete, asphalt mixture, or asphalt binder production with respect to logistics, planned material storage, handling capacities, and delivery mechanisms, and includes termination options in the event of failure to demonstrate such progress; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2f197493ecef485bab72bb32766b6ccf"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall fulfill the preference criteria set by the applicable State, to the maximum extent practicable.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4b2c7383bb7c4a6cacb6e7f5dcfa8312"><enum>(c)</enum><header>STP set-Aside</header><text>Section 133(h)(6) of title 23, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9EBA384B6C3A4707ADD8238945418534"><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id69d8cbd1108b4df3bbba5438b2768b9e"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Procurement for innovative building materials</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id81ca653121284fc794a5574d36f85efd"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out a project under this subsection, a State may use amounts set aside under this subsection to enter into an advance multiyear contract described in subsection (l)(2) for a specified quantity and specified price of innovative, domestically produced cement, concrete, asphalt mixture, or asphalt binder.</text></clause><clause id="ida8b2d7c9230747209531adf8cc6fd661"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>A State may not provide payments to a producer under a contract described in clause (i) unless materials have been delivered according to contract terms and conditions.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="idb194d60e734f44458cadbb7b40024859"><enum>7.</enum><header>Interagency Task Force for Concrete and Asphalt Innovation</header><subsection id="id5b1e230b8b6e4323afb6751c963cb7a6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, in coordination with the Secretary of Transportation, the Administrator of General Services, the Secretary of Defense, and the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology, shall establish a task force, to be known as the <quote>Interagency Task Force for Concrete and Asphalt Innovation</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="ide6363efc1fd44e39afe675fda9531313"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Objectives</header><text>In carrying out the duties of the Task Force, the Task Force shall consider strategies for—</text><paragraph id="id3eeb1aaf77e34d69b80d11f17720d57a"><enum>(1)</enum><text>improving the durability and performance of low-emissions cement, concrete, asphalt binder, or asphalt mixtures;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0870363ae8234e2ba0287b659d2a990d"><enum>(2)</enum><text>reducing the cost of low-emissions cement, concrete, asphalt binder, or asphalt mixtures;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfb3ed045b0ec4eb88e6046a724736bb4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>supporting continuous innovation and emissions reductions in the production of low-emissions cement, concrete, asphalt binder, or asphalt mixtures;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8c1803ceee634a29b462b88a8e61cd18"><enum>(4)</enum><text>increasing employment in fields related to the domestic production of low-emissions cement, concrete, asphalt binder, or asphalt mixtures; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc0778b1c462a4fb1b28b948c9b86339a"><enum>(5)</enum><text>ensuring a trained workforce in fields related to the domestic production and use of low-emissions cement, concrete, asphalt binder, or asphalt mixtures.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id10988c7581d04698a5b0f6e4dee8fcb6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Composition</header><text>The Task Force shall be composed of 2 members from each of—</text><paragraph id="id45c2a7f9f05f40568e1258fba2ddb52b"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Department of Energy;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1fc395532e434d70aafc400d0a71d156"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Department of Transportation;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1c0007fd44694f0a8b5465e5b16e053f"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the General Services Administration;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idace1358cb8b34a2e93e5bf7bc27bb9c1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the Department of Defense; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4a69b2820e754d7bb7ac978eba8d6152"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the National Institute of Standards and Technology.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ide562135ad0414b8cb7c45841c1bc6bd1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In carrying out the duties of the Task Force, the Secretary shall consult with the following stakeholders, who shall reflect regional diversity to the maximum extent practicable:</text><paragraph id="id14afb8b82a574e719d69d28bd4c712db"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Entities in the cement, concrete, asphalt binder, and asphalt mixture sectors, including—</text><subparagraph id="id68c4c81dde9f4722bd27c34a0a8d8101"><enum>(A)</enum><text>ready-mix or site-mixed concrete producers;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id50632fc7527a426a841191e03584b1c7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>precast concrete producers;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida71bc0f60615434bbe73fa9659099cbe"><enum>(C)</enum><text>portland cement and other cement producers;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1327b76f99a64bee8ee7a3efc9a6390d"><enum>(D)</enum><text>aggregate producers;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc6876bde762b47bb9a388c626e350816"><enum>(E)</enum><text>asphalt binder producers;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddd90ee8f768842e9880a40541813579d"><enum>(F)</enum><text>asphalt mixture producers;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2af75625ac864748add2b5f5d2dcab7c"><enum>(G)</enum><text>producers of emerging cement, concrete, asphalt binder, or asphalt mixture solutions; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida3cdc1bb43404c0a88389ba6b9a0927e"><enum>(H)</enum><text>distributors and users of cement, concrete, asphalt binder, or asphalt mixture production.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id84bdacf22b3c49e2a5a0bb1b0c19a8a3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Contracting companies with at least 1 Federal Government contract awarded in the preceding 5 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3a6cd6a84c134f55b914e4647388b42a"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Contracting companies with at least 1 private sector contract awarded in the preceding 5 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id41c634262dfe4872bce51f25c3b3ae35"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Experts, including from nongovernmental organizations, on the environmental impact of cement, concrete, asphalt binder, and asphalt mixture production in architectural and nonarchitectural applications, with expertise in—</text><subparagraph id="idb7886ce7baba4f99aca4d9be8a821658"><enum>(A)</enum><text>developing codes, specifications, and standards for cement, concrete, asphalt binder, and asphalt mixtures;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0e30dd938ece4937b707290b1395a2dc"><enum>(B)</enum><text>conducting performance tests on cement, concrete, asphalt binder, and asphalt mixtures;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id35bc12235b174c218b1bc5fe2f06c341"><enum>(C)</enum><text>working with the National Institute of Building Sciences;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9c2a11ac98354e36b23086e16f035a35"><enum>(D)</enum><text>working for State or local departments of transportation from different regions of the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5575d820ec114e4c9db973fd5a0b56a9"><enum>(E)</enum><text>developing benchmarks for embodied greenhouse gas emissions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idcfb542ca73d14b11830ae2e5e42b27f4"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Stakeholders in any other relevant industries, as determined by the Secretary. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ida2696807046345dcbaf70143b6d0f8ba"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text>The Task Force shall—</text><paragraph id="id1f775d340d4b46d6ad860fc7766f5f13"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide recommendations to the Secretary on—</text><subparagraph id="ida4532b1df9244bbf97f1b63e529d163b"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the use of engineering performance standards for low-emissions cement, concrete, asphalt binder, and asphalt mixtures, including taking into account lessons learned from the reimbursement and incentives provided under section 5(a)(2); </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb28fe2f3f4fa4817833f1bcaab0e92d4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>creating guidelines and best practices for the testing and evaluation of low-emissions cement, concrete, asphalt binder, and asphalt mixtures, including taking into account lessons learned from the Manufacturing USA institutes planned, established, or supported under section 4(d);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idaf2f9946be59403a8f9959ef2680c45a"><enum>(C)</enum><text>improving the product category rules governing the creation of relevant environmental product declarations for low-emissions cement, concrete, asphalt binder, and asphalt mixture, including—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb93a5a31b0fb4cd6807124ce1d8cbfa8"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">taking into account lessons learned from the technical assistance program established under section 3(g); and</text></clause><clause id="id39a90e49f63049a7b0915a9825e4ee12"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>coordinating with the Label Program for Low Embodied Carbon Construction Materials of the Environmental Protection Agency and any other relevant program of the Environmental Protection Agency; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd6efe8efc4c1418d9e00d7ddedc53b02"><enum>(D)</enum><text>incentives that would encourage the use of low-emissions cement, concrete, asphalt binder, and asphalt mixtures;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id8785b9aa91dd4513a391dbf9944d901f"><enum>(2)</enum><text>coordinate meetings and facilitate discussions through forums such as roundtables, workshops, or conferences to inform the recommendations provided under paragraph (1); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2bcfdff29f4147f5bbc2325dfeed7923"><enum>(3)</enum><text>host briefings and provide updates to—</text><subparagraph id="id7899c66d43ac4b68a6bff1e451554e15"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id16823ebd38e242369995838ab78d8ab2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idd9bb7c378aa741a0b9fdf9f22b862195"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Once every 2 years, the Secretary, in consultation with the Task Force, shall submit to Congress a report that describes—</text><paragraph id="id3ef99fb5c3c74879a577e2fb05299f09"><enum>(1)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id58e5362fe4a24055bc92253dd69ab388"><enum>(A)</enum><text>each of the recommendations made under subsection (e)(1); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5d7d24e7bdee49d4b8310356df04a7cb" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the response of the Secretary to each of those recommendations, including how best to implement each recommendation; </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="ideda0a35416854070b57ae52754e47729"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the determinations made by the Secretary under section 3(h)(1);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida12dcba5f4c44bc5ac49471f73ac0b41"><enum>(3)</enum><text>changes to State and local codes and specifications facilitated by the Task Force during the period covered by the report; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd254ae9999644fa5b044cd220e218319"><enum>(4)</enum><text>meetings with cement, concrete, asphalt binder, and asphalt mixture producers, contractors, engineers, academics, State and local government officials, or any other relevant stakeholders coordinated by the Task Force during the period covered by the report.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id686331a9633a491fbdadab1aa7a50567"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The Secretary may terminate the Task Force if the Secretary determines that sufficient low-emissions cement, concrete, asphalt binder, and asphalt mixtures are commercially available domestically at a price comparable to the price of cement, concrete, asphalt binder, and asphalt mixtures produced through traditional methods of production.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

