<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-NEW25110-3KX-C9-XXT"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 87 ATS: Designating February 2025 as “American Heart Month”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 87</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250221" legis-day="20250220">February 21 (legislative day, February 20), 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S266">Mr. Crapo</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Designating February 2025 as <quote>American Heart Month</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas cardiovascular disease (referred to in this preamble as <quote>CVD</quote>) affects men, women, and children of every age and race in the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas CVD continues to be the leading cause of death in the United States, claiming the lives of over 940,000 individuals in the United States in 2022;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas heart disease and stroke claimed more lives in 2021 in the United States than all forms of cancer and chronic lower respiratory disease combined;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, from 2019 to 2020, deaths from heart disease increased by 4.8 percent, the largest increase in heart disease deaths since 2012;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas individuals in the United States have made significant progress in reducing the death rate for CVD, but this progress has been more modest with respect to the death rate for CVD among certain racial and ethnic minority populations;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas CVD results in tremendous health care costs and lost productivity, and, if not addressed, the United States alone will spend over $1,000,000,000,000 by 2035 on costs relating to CVD;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, between 2019 and 2020, heart disease accounted for $252,000,000,000 in health care expenditures and lost productivity in the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2021, sudden cardiac arrest accounted for over 20,000 deaths in the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas approximately every 40 seconds an individual in the United States will have a heart attack;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2021, stroke accounted for approximately 1 in every 21 deaths in the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas CVDs are the leading causes of maternal death among women in the United States, accounting for more than ¼ of pregnancy-related deaths between 2017 and 2019;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas congenital heart defects are—</text><paragraph id="id9ae6c0171fcd4f01aed41bf190ed3425"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the most common types of birth defects in the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id86f11913131d47dfa07cf3dc6c52cadd"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the leading cause of death for infants with birth defects;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas extensive clinical and statistical studies have identified major and contributing factors that increase the risk of CVD, including—</text><paragraph id="ideaa75bf8cce846a2989e8badc702ba39"><enum>(1)</enum><text>high blood pressure;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb4dd52c3bdfd4218bc016d6a13c71af5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>high blood cholesterol;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd4641450aa654d48867530758a1490c1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>poor diet;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida929c3c545164c9281e3de14a203c193"><enum>(4)</enum><text>tobacco use and exposure to nicotine;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida7c9992f2c934bd0b739a91874022730"><enum>(5)</enum><text>physical inactivity;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd48d2afd575744b1b2e3bef4978eee84"><enum>(6)</enum><text>insufficient or poor-quality sleep;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id791f488acbeb4921ab455cfcfdfa7dd4"><enum>(7)</enum><text>obesity; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida08043af321a428692a9985588d6c000"><enum>(8)</enum><text>diabetes mellitus;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas an individual can greatly reduce the risk of CVD through lifestyle modification coupled with medical treatment when necessary;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas greater awareness and early detection of risk factors for CVD can improve and save the lives of thousands of individuals in the United States each year;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas under section 101(1) of title 36, United States Code, the President is requested to issue an annual proclamation designating February as American Heart Month;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the American Heart Association and many other organizations celebrate National Wear Red Day during February by <quote>going red</quote> to increase awareness about CVD as the leading cause of death for women; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, every year since 1964, the President has issued a proclamation designating the month of February as <quote>American Heart Month</quote>: Now, therefore, be it </text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="ide7e8523cf950446486cf02f0a9f85892" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>designates February 2025 as <quote>American Heart Month</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idda69adbd7e2d4f4094b6713abe319564"><enum>(2)</enum><text>supports the goals and ideals of American Heart Month;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id72e8deb309c04f4b8185b3d8531a76a5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recognizes and reaffirms the commitment of the United States to fighting cardiovascular disease (referred to in this resolution as <quote>CVD</quote>) by—</text><subparagraph id="idb26e866d69804084adade4a9a62c64f2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>promoting awareness about the causes, risks, and prevention of CVD;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc6feb3f54a9b473b9af30db4900802c3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>supporting research on CVD; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3e71dd8b3efd4ca58bce7c5b1c34bd46"><enum>(C)</enum><text>taking other steps to improve health outcomes associated with CVD and reduce associated long-term disability and mortality;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id7a22a5751d374d96b3b4bf076e36b7b1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>commends the efforts of States, territories, and possessions of the United States, localities, nonprofit organizations, businesses, other entities, and the people of the United States who support American Heart Month; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id627b3951180a4ecaada0091aa41ebed0"><enum>(5)</enum><text>encourages every individual in the United States to learn about their risk for CVD. </text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

