<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA6B911F6F3EB47A6946008C7303E1C8B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2366 IH: American Families United Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2366</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250326">March 26, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000299">Ms. Escobar</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S000168">Ms. Salazar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001112">Mr. Carbajal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001131">Mr. Casar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001110">Mr. Correa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000631">Ms. Dean of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000586">Mr. Garc&#237;a of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001226">Mr. Menendez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000305">Ms. Ross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001226">Ms. Salinas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001156">Ms. S&#225;nchez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001205">Ms. Scanlon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001200">Mr. Soto</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001201">Mr. Suozzi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000593">Mr. Levin</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to promote family unity, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6413EB9C361B4CADBCF05F9D02EE7B6B" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HDA90ADD45E7E45E1842C18884BE4E016" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>American Families United Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H65F9454E0B0A4B19A50575F7CC25CCE1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed—</text>
<paragraph id="H8FCF57BAECB84BA381AC926BF71E53B2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to provide the Secretary of Homeland Security or the Attorney General with the ability to exercise the discretionary authority provided in this Act, or by an amendment made by this Act, except on a case-by-case basis; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA9FD483E23AF40E697015F0CF21C3F2D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to otherwise modify or limit the discretionary authority of the Secretary of Homeland Security or the Attorney General under the immigration laws (as defined in section 101(a)(17) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(17)</external-xref>)).</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="H179971E84F39459888DDCF25064E2EBF"><enum>3.</enum><header>Discretionary authority with respect to family members of united states citizens</header>
<subsection id="H294CFB12E6414F268F8D2BEE3CED757F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Applications for relief from removal</header><text>Section 240(c)(4) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1229a">8 U.S.C. 1229a(c)(4)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HEF580F558CE443C3AEB3F18C4B37FD6C" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subparagraph id="H13BD00BD5E594EC2A7153F9C8FA422CD"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Judicial discretion</header> <clause id="H1601EC40127149C4BD8133570674702E"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of an alien who is the spouse or child of a citizen of the United States, the Attorney General may subject to clause (ii)—</text>
<subclause id="H9A67766489F341FEA5DADD38EF4FCA8A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>terminate any removal proceedings against the alien;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H8BFB91D7E1B04DFAA84D8D5A7A012B82"><enum>(II)</enum><text>decline to order the alien removed from the United States;</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H7BC4066D23A744D7ABBE52C39B195520"><enum>(III)</enum><text>grant the alien permission to reapply for admission to the United States; or</text></subclause> <subclause id="H63E4B17285794B72B0EBE23F630FA36E"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>subject to clause (iii), waive the application of one or more grounds of inadmissibility or deportability in connection with any request for relief from removal.</text></subclause></clause>
<clause id="H27E6A7CABC544FE388DED246F510670F"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Limitation on discretion</header>
<subclause id="H2FF51807B62349C8874173B67FF1F5B6"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Attorney General may exercise the discretion described in clause (i) if the Attorney General determines that removal of the alien or the denial of a request for relief from removal would result in hardship to the alien’s United States citizen spouse, parent, or child. There shall be a presumption that family separation constitutes hardship.</text></subclause> <subclause id="HBB3A784A21EA43E9B0BBB35283143754"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Widow and surviving child of deceased united states citizen</header><text>In the case of the death of a citizen of the United States, the Attorney General may exercise discretion described in clause (i) with respect to an alien who was a child of such citizen, or was the spouse of such citizen and was not legally separated from such citizen on the date of the citizen’s death, if—</text>
<item id="H86AF6578A00B43BEAA2DBA12DDCC9E63"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the Attorney General determines that removal of the child or spouse or the denial of a requested benefit would result in hardship to the child or spouse; and</text></item> <item id="HD73A7D9B35304575B45F1E277676B293"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the child or spouse seeks relief requiring such discretion not later than two years after the date of the citizen’s death or demonstrates to the satisfaction of the Attorney General the existence of extraordinary circumstances that prevented the spouse or child from seeking relief within such period.</text></item></subclause></clause>
<clause id="H54FA3CDA19714CF9A0E13E9EFE3AF2F8"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Exclusions</header><text>This subparagraph shall not apply to an alien whom the Attorney General determines—</text> <subclause id="H2BD8A6C961324817ABE33BC1B2B56310"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is inadmissible under—</text>
<item id="H414FF987BD4F474D9648ABEE6CCE112A"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>paragraph (2) or (3) of section 212(a); or</text></item> <item id="H60ECA8D1817740D4BB68B2A3249DAF79"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>subparagraph (A), (C), or (D) of section 212(a)(10); or</text></item></subclause>
<subclause id="HB88F297A12D343B0BEBF411A7AACC6EC"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is deportable under paragraph (2), (4), or (6) of section 237(a).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H7EB96358BEDA42448B490473E5C795F2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Secretary’s discretion</header><text>Section 212 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="H42D7091E211448879D63A62786A6D65E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating the second subsection (t) as subsection (u); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6561D31F24344FF5828127CF879A07A3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block id="H8FD42616FF6A4701816B63FBC294920D" style="OLC">
<subsection id="H34B6770D84A44408AF0424A422405E1E"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Secretary’s discretion</header>
<paragraph id="H2EBBC65709734EEF88D27FDE721E8A99"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of an alien who is the spouse or child of a citizen of the United States, the Secretary of Homeland Security may, subject to paragraph (2)—</text> <subparagraph id="HED78614889E344D79A08CD570CD073CA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>waive the application of one or more grounds of inadmissibility or deportability in connection with an application for an immigration benefit or request for relief from removal;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H4DF7835BB2A240F5A4E71C13930140F9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>decline to issue a notice to appear or other charging document requiring such an alien to appear for removal proceedings;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB63F5886BC784D3DB51D8EB4272EB5AA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>decline to reinstate an order of removal under section 241(a)(5); or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H1E65D440B01F4E8AB9E8582A978AA1C6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>grant such alien permission to reapply for admission to the United States or any other application for an immigration benefit.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H07AD474B12AB417881AEFC49CD819DBD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation on discretion</header> <subparagraph id="H9971C402C7EB4E2B95BF781E7A9F1614"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security may exercise discretion described in paragraph (1) if the Secretary determines that removal of the alien or the denial of a requested benefit would result in hardship to the alien’s United States citizen spouse, parent, or child. There shall be a presumption that family separation constitutes hardship.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA7E343DD70A54C49BE524673D29789FA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Widow and orphan of deceased united states citizen</header><text>In the case of the death of a citizen of the United States, the Secretary of Homeland Security may exercise discretion described in paragraph (1) with respect to an alien who was a child of such citizen, or was the spouse of such citizen and was not legally separated from such citizen on the date of the citizen’s death, if—</text> <clause id="HBC82F97C11ED464596179C99498B24DB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Secretary determines that the denial of a requested benefit would result in hardship to the child or spouse; and </text></clause>
<clause id="H37A23FE185BA4232AF6D072B6BCD2A76"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the child or spouse seeks relief requiring such discretion not later than two years after the date of the citizen’s death or demonstrates to the satisfaction of the Secretary the existence of extraordinary circumstances that prevented the spouse or child from seeking relief within such period.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H53C2266954A043B8BE16846A6DF3AD0B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exclusions</header><text>This subsection shall not apply to an alien whom the Secretary determines—</text>
<subparagraph id="HBD16A01859064D099EFA9658B5210FF1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is inadmissible under—</text> <clause id="H70C85A6DA08B46CC890ADB64F2BCB282"><enum>(i)</enum><text>paragraph (2) or (3) of subsections (a); or</text></clause>
<clause id="H1985C55A5E9B47358BAE1432F08D21A4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>subparagraphs (A), (C), or (D) of subsection (a)(10); or</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7C1838E7DAF749EDB8633ED8C2E8519E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is deportable under paragraphs (2), (4), or (6) of section 237(a).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="H095CD1C7C51D4F8CB2D74FEFE155F7BE"><enum>4.</enum><header>Motions to reopen or reconsider</header>
<subsection id="H283A3B6F32994334A46645C6139E20D2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A motion to reopen or reconsider the denial of a petition or application or an order of removal for an alien may be granted if such petition, application, or order would have been adjudicated in favor of the alien had this Act, or an amendment made by this Act, been in effect at the time of such denial or order.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HA274736D1AD149A1B3601C66020C2CC2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Filing requirement</header><text>A motion under subsection (a) shall be filed no later than the date that is 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, unless the alien demonstrates to the satisfaction of the Secretary of Homeland Security or Attorney General, as appropriate, the existence of extraordinary circumstances that prevented the alien from filing within such period.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

