<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="H6509BBE5C5C34762B843FBAFD6EA27E0" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 186 RH: Of inquiry requesting the President to transmit certain documents to the House of Representatives relating to the conflicts of interest of Elon Musk and related information.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">House Calendar No. 22</calendar><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 186</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 119–57]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250304">March 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000687">Mr. Mfume</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001313">Ms. Brown</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001218">Ms. Stansbury</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000598">Mr. Garcia of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000476">Mr. Frost</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000602">Ms. Lee of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001131">Mr. Casar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001130">Ms. Crockett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000621">Ms. Randall</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001230">Mr. Subramanyam</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001324">Mr. Bell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001231">Ms. Simon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001241">Mr. Min</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000617">Ms. Pressley</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250409">April 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Reported adversely, referred to the House Calendar, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Of inquiry requesting the President to transmit certain documents to the House of Representatives relating to the conflicts of interest of Elon Musk and related information.</official-title></form><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HBD3BBD0C775E4A299215476C749C36B2" committee-id="HGO00"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HA7E64183CCB645F38C891049E299F3F6"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the President is requested to transmit, to the extent that such documents are in the possession of the President, to the House of Representatives, not later than 14 days after the adoption of this resolution, in a complete and unredacted form, a copy of any document, record, report, memorandum, correspondence, or other communication that refers or relates to—</text><paragraph id="H36D8A69F6B764AC793489BDDA350CB35"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Elon Musk and his role, official or nonofficial, with the Federal Government;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6FED737F21B44ADF9FD6595F02D37171"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any realized or perceived conflict of interest Elon Musk may have related to his role with the United States DOGE Service (commonly referred to as the <quote>Department of Government Efficiency</quote> or <quote>DOGE</quote>), any DOGE agency team, or any other government or pseudo-government entity;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB00BFE8A82FF43FDAB09DA6ABA59BD44"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any Elon Musk-owned, -managed, -licensed, or -controlled corporations, partnerships, limited liability companies, limited partnerships, or ventures, or entity on which Elon Musk serves on the board of directors; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H61E3F3485A06443595ADA38031EEE85F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>any Federal Government contract involving any Elon Musk-owned, -managed, -licensed, or -controlled corporations, partnerships, limited liability companies, limited partnerships, or ventures, or entity on which Elon Musk serves on the board of directors.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date date="20250409">April 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Reported adversely, referred to the House Calendar, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></resolution> 

