<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MUR25119-KSN-FV-2CX"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 S1249 IS: Drone Integration and Zoning Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1249</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250402">April 2, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S346">Mr. Lee</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To prescribe zoning authority with respect to commercial unmanned aircraft systems and to preserve State, local, and Tribal authorities and private property with respect to unmanned aircraft systems, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header><subsection id="idCB76D39E68534AC0A58057E028248496"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Drone Integration and Zoning Act</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="idC34729A3709D418E9BD9424B19E2DAE4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents of this Act is as follows:</text><toc><toc-entry idref="S1" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="id7CB369D5751D41A9B2FBD453BC888C17" level="section">Sec. 2. Definitions.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="id25886fe0bd0e4b1ca9e49ad8d42afcce" level="section">Sec. 3. Federal Aviation Administration updates to navigable airspace.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="id3bec8b60017341b099c24d31985557d5" level="section">Sec. 4. Preservation of State, local, and Tribal authorities with respect to civil unmanned aircraft systems.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="idfd0c7e760acb4b20a0f299574143d901" level="section">Sec. 5. Preservation of local zoning authority for unmanned aircraft take-off and landing zones.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="id4db0a07238db48d3a650277f41b590a6" level="section">Sec. 6. Rights to operate.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="id5E11D19C643B4C46A8B551B02945B90B" level="section">Sec. 7. Updates to rules regarding the commercial carriage of property.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="idFFD721E31DF4472483CE8C516E95F1B6" level="section">Sec. 8. Designation of certain complex airspace.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="idFBF0D26E4A05496388D7A5ECB6003292" level="section">Sec. 9. Improvements to plan for full operational capability of unmanned aircraft systems traffic management.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="idDF2B714D473E4104B3E43539CC826521" level="section">Sec. 10. Updates to rules regarding small unmanned aircraft safety standards.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="idd0e8f9c1cbb14179911da5644d052d6e" level="section">Sec. 11. Rules of construction.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section><section id="id7CB369D5751D41A9B2FBD453BC888C17"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="ida2822cde1e7e4d4c852f63c665bc48a0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id05831d80bb14442583d216922110a7e5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Civil</header><text>The term <term>civil</term>, with respect to an unmanned aircraft system, means that the unmanned aircraft is not a public aircraft (as defined in section 40102 of title 49, United States Code).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id14c40534a7554f88b50dc3b55213ac3c"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Commercial operator</header><text>The term <term>commercial operator</term> means a person who operates a civil unmanned aircraft system for commercial purposes.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1402f36d4e7c445fa42b8e7f5682f464"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Immediate reaches of airspace</header><text>The term <term>immediate reaches of airspace</term> means, with respect to the operation of a civil unmanned aircraft system, any area within 200 feet above ground level.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4cfc35f272434431920995da052c25f2"><enum>(5)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Indian Tribe</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Indian Tribe</term> has the meaning given that term in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id08aa662aa7b746168c0b87aa7f366459"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Local government</header><text>The term <term>local government</term> means the government of a subdivision of a State.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8e13d304fb674c4dbd229f4817230380"><enum>(7)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means each of the 50 States, the District of Columbia, and the territories and possessions of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9473c9bb0f444466b8ebf1a19d5a7d3e"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Tribal government</header><text>The term <term>Tribal government</term> means the governing body of an Indian Tribe.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf6c8f2767dfc48d28d285020e7f54a89"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Unmanned aircraft; unmanned aircraft system</header><text>The terms <term>unmanned aircraft</term> and <term>unmanned aircraft system</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 44801 of title 49, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd366761ac6264704b8d7e302dec7b729"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Unmanned aircraft take-off and landing zone</header><text>The term <term>unmanned aircraft take-off and landing zone</term> means a structure, area of land or water, or other designation for use or intended to be used for the take-off or landing of civil unmanned aircraft systems operated by a commercial operator.</text></paragraph></section><section id="id25886fe0bd0e4b1ca9e49ad8d42afcce"><enum>3.</enum><header>Federal Aviation Administration updates to navigable airspace</header><subsection id="idD80D09E560654E479D37B32150DD8823"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1128a764011442f68a34946ebe04148a"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Immediate reaches of airspace definition</header><text>Section 44801 of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idC6C85C1CED824ED88BA094D516C6F794"><paragraph id="idBB038DCF72864EE88FBE2F0E3C3E0E11"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Immediate reaches of airspace</header><text>The term <term>immediate reaches of airspace</term> means, with respect to the operation of a civil unmanned aircraft system, any area within 200 feet above ground level.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id22f7fff56c80436c921b41a9da0fac8b"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Navigable airspace definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (32) of section 40102 of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new sentence: <quote>In applying such term to the regulation of civil unmanned aircraft systems, such term shall not include the area within the immediate reaches of airspace (as defined in section 44801).</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id5D6B82CC475141578BF40F24FBDCB33A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><paragraph id="idD82A930A6B034B2188B890E344DDD0FA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall conduct a rulemaking proceeding to update the definition of <quote>navigable airspace</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idA8757357378C4CA1B58DDF68F5F05ED4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In conducting the rulemaking proceeding under paragraph (1), the Administrator shall consult with appropriate State, local, or Tribal government officials.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id53384EACB1EA4AF28B2A93FC4D6B76C1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Designation requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In conducting the rulemaking proceeding under subsection (b), the Administrator shall designate the area between 200 feet and 400 feet above ground level—</text><paragraph id="id06CA69D4D0374C41B5414413C909E86C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for use of civil unmanned aircraft systems under the exclusive authority of the Administrator; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idA2661F5716344FA0B27C56C4D3EC341D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for use by both commercial operators or hobbyists and recreational unmanned aircraft systems, under rules established by the Administrator.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0C4950759C404E449E22EB024EF34B1B"><enum>(d)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Final rule</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall issue a final rule pursuant to the rulemaking conducted under subsection (b).</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8DB3C820F7E24BA69255660DAA1EA664"><enum>(e)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Rules of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section may be construed to—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id066BF4B19899458C8648F5036189C0DB"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prohibit the Administrator from promulgating regulations related to the operation of unmanned aircraft systems at more than 400 feet above ground level; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd7540a6bab6644068e759eca578ef834"><enum>(2)</enum><text>diminish or expand the preemptive effect of the authority of the Federal Aviation Administration with respect to manned aviation.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id3bec8b60017341b099c24d31985557d5"><enum>4.</enum><header>Preservation of State, local, and Tribal authorities with respect to civil unmanned aircraft systems</header><subsection id="id576F405C57054AFEBBE73B025E1F42C4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings; sense of Congress</header><paragraph id="id954B0FBDC0C649B699D284389F4D4CE6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds the following:</text><subparagraph id="idb17b252d189d4be28aabe031329df0d8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Using its constitutional authority to regulate commerce among the States, Congress granted the Federal Government authority over all of the navigable airspace in the United States in order to foster air commerce.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2B50D8509D7B41768FEC64B5962AF876"><enum>(B)</enum><text>While the regulation of the navigable airspace is within the Federal Government's domain, the Supreme Court recognized in United States v. Causby, 328 U.S. 256 (1946), that the Federal Government’s regulatory authority is limited by the property rights possessed by landowners over the exclusive control of the immediate reaches of their airspace.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id607b66f3c01644d3b6c5b6b5d6152574"><enum>(C)</enum><text>As a sovereign government, a State possesses police powers, which include the power to protect the property rights of its citizens.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idcc3b740b767348a8ab56f488697f3f3f"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The proliferation of low-altitude operations of unmanned aircraft systems has created a conflict between the responsibility of the Federal Government to regulate the navigable airspace and the inherent sovereign police power possessed by the States to protect the property rights of their citizens.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idE48F539DCBD940A5941F5B35B20A1A22"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that—</text><subparagraph id="ide55ddaec5c7340bdb1b4e5e829aad1f7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in order for landowners to have full enjoyment and use of their land, they must have exclusive control of the immediate reaches of airspace over their property;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id541dd78dfea348debfde89d207432086"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the States possess sovereign police powers, which include the power to regulate land use, protect property rights, and exercise zoning authority; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id841574dfe7804542870d03afcb2feb85"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Federal Government lacks the authority to intrude upon a State’s sovereign right to issue reasonable time, manner, and place restrictions on the operation of unmanned aircraft systems operating within the immediate reaches of airspace.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id845b7537836f44dab232e493029f92a7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements related to regulations and standards</header><paragraph id="idB8946D8E4BF14B578AA2B1EF6937D576"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In prescribing regulations or standards related to civil unmanned aircraft systems, the following shall apply:</text><subparagraph id="idB1CE25CE77F74D95BFD64D0363EA11D0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Administrator shall not authorize the operation of a civil unmanned aircraft in the immediate reaches of airspace above property without permission of the property owner.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="idDBB29DE0418547E3A7348B26B23E976E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Subject to paragraph (2), in the case of a structure that exceeds 200 feet above ground level, the Administrator shall not authorize the operation of a civil unmanned aircraft—</text><clause commented="no" id="id8fd77c75bdf34f36bbade8ac9febb222"><enum>(i)</enum><text>within 50 feet of the top of such structure; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="id92e2971bd93142abb85bcae8d0d6e8de"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>within 200 feet laterally of such structure or inside the property line of such structure’s owner, whichever is closer to such structure.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9814f5a2818e4ff2b15c69455cd68d2e"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Administrator shall not authorize the physical contact of a civil unmanned aircraft, including such aircraft’s take-off or landing, with a structure that exceeds 200 feet above ground level without permission of the structure’s owner.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id577BE5AC6167448B833B2D457EF10C54"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The Administrator shall ensure that the authority of a State, local, or Tribal government to issue reasonable restrictions on the time, manner, and place of operation of a civil unmanned aircraft system that is operated below 200 feet above ground level is not preempted.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id7EDD2EE9709C4A19B7635D721A0CB5E8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The limitation on the operation of a civil unmanned aircraft under paragraph (1)(B) shall not apply if—</text><subparagraph id="id8c4e662daded414ea202aba4e1974e39"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the operator of such aircraft has the permission of the structure’s owner;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3494ba94159843b182c0cc731b8e5190"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such aircraft is being operated directly within or above an authorized public right of way; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfb9f74a7e12a47eabab17eacdb933456"><enum>(C)</enum><text>such aircraft is being operated on an authorized commercial route designated under subsection (c).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id00502ab80e544549b6fe1b327d08e462"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Reasonable restrictions</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (1)(D), reasonable restrictions on the time, manner, and place of operation of a civil unmanned aircraft system include the following:</text><subparagraph id="ideac53ae7d0cc42d5aac5e9dd090a0b2e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Specifying limitations on speed of flight over specified areas.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf0c1686c2662403ca261baea2302e515"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Prohibitions or limitations on operations in the vicinity of schools, parks, roadways, bridges, moving locations, or other public or private property.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2d7296d130be41d694e9bfa9667bd9f7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Restrictions on operations at certain times of the day or week or on specific occasions such as parades or sporting events, including sporting events that do not remain in one location.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id574fd1b0525043088dc4b5e505d7390d"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Prohibitions on careless or reckless operations, including operations while the operator is under the influence of alcohol or drugs.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id52a6c15a95424c8086576b464f580bad"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Other prohibitions that protect public safety, personal privacy, or property rights, or that manage land use or restrict noise pollution.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0FECB4D0D1774B279BDD1898F15D0764"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Designation of authorized commercial routes</header><paragraph id="idC977E7195F104B99BA72F859EB832951"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of subsection (b)(2)(C), not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall establish a process for the designation of routes as authorized commercial routes. No area within 200 feet above ground level may be included in a designated authorized commercial route.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idC8E8C8CAAAF340F4ADA4E1DF8936027A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application</header><text>Under the process established under paragraph (1), applicants shall submit an application for such a designation in a form and manner determined appropriate by the Administrator.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7FFA123C02074CB5A9577BF529942023"><enum>(3)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Timeframe for decision</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Under the process established under paragraph (1), the Administrator shall approve or disapprove a complete application for designation within 90 days of receiving the application.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7EB3092B98CA477B8C01EA876A06990A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In reviewing an application for the designation of an area under this subsection, the Administrator shall consult with and heavily weigh the views of—</text><subparagraph id="idf75af093cfc04bf3b01ebad8ce25b3bc"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the applicable State, local, or Tribal government that has jurisdiction over the operation of unmanned aircraft in the area below the area to be designated;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfb73ae72d1a54d86ae72dc3a9027bfd3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>owners of structures who would be affected by the designation of a route as an authorized commercial route; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2f96c36f359b453baa282d0a592c986e"><enum>(C)</enum><text>commercial unmanned aircraft operators.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id7516EC2A95254E778F9154E52E01008D"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Denial of application</header><text>If the Administrator denies an application for a designation under this subsection, the Administrator shall provide the applicant with—</text><subparagraph id="id40AAFE5891BB47DBB4FC3D4B1209E9B3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a detailed description of the reasons for the denial; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id32D9E1A0BA9447AE8D924255017BEE90"><enum>(B)</enum><text>recommendations for changes that the applicant can make to correct the deficiencies in their application.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idEF08E73922B54745ADFA89F223A64FBE"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Approval of application</header><text>If the Administrator approves an application for a designation under this subsection, the Administrator shall clearly describe the boundaries of the designated authorized commercial route and any applicable limitations for operations on the route.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB3AA762AFE6F406C9EE44FDF3D70EEDE"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Delegation</header><text>The Administrator may delegate the authority to designate authorized commercial routes under this subsection to a State, local, or Tribal government that has entered into an agreement with the Administrator under section 8 with respect to an area designated as complex airspace.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id19e2dc09657f49fd9d5254f6315a4dc2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rules of construction</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8c978b46e32f40dca091508169b26798"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Safety hazard</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to permit a State, local, or Tribal government to issue restrictions, or a combination of restrictions, that would create a significant safety hazard in the navigable airspace, airport operations, air navigation facilities, air traffic control systems, or other components of the national airspace system that facilitate the safe and efficient operation of civil, commercial, or military aircraft within the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id755912eae26d42dd94ac1a9645e380ad"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Cause of action</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section may be construed to prohibit a property owner or the owner of a structure with a height that exceeds 200 feet above ground level from pursuing any available cause of action under State law related to unmanned aircraft operations above 200 feet above ground level.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idfd0c7e760acb4b20a0f299574143d901"><enum>5.</enum><header>Preservation of local zoning authority for unmanned aircraft take-off and landing zones</header><subsection id="id336ec4f4f8a8492ea967e2db251bdfe7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>General authority</header><text>Subject to the succeeding provisions of this section, nothing in this Act shall limit or affect the authority of a State, local, or Tribal government over decisions regarding the designation, placement, construction, or modification of an unmanned aircraft take-off and landing zone.</text></subsection><subsection id="ida9779a8abf4b4f37bfde6defa788d1b0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Nondiscrimination</header><text>The regulation of the designation, placement, construction, or modification of an unmanned aircraft take-off and landing zone by any State, local, or Tribal government may not—</text><paragraph id="idc50b4b7631f64f89afada5e3859946d4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>unreasonably discriminate among commercial operators of unmanned aircraft systems; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf5b5549a09d74e48b4625e2d0f233420"><enum>(2)</enum><text>prohibit, or have the effect of prohibiting, a commercial operator from operating an unmanned aircraft system.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id603fe62d0b1c4e50aa1c880b752bf071"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applications</header><paragraph id="idCC5C943E80574FCEA262CC59AD43681A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Requirement to act</header><subparagraph id="id4104DC57BAD74944B787EC3EF4BE9446"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A State, local, or Tribal government shall act on any complete application for authorization to designate, place, construct, or modify an unmanned aircraft take-off and landing zone within 60 days of receiving such application.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id03ca81916b2942f2b6aa8c688d19b5d0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Denial</header><text>If a State, local, or Tribal government denies an application for the designation, placement, construction, or modification of an unmanned aircraft take-off and landing zone, the State, local, or Tribal government shall, not later than 30 days after denying the application, submit to the commercial operator a written record that details—</text><clause id="id80d9f8cbc3024cb3bf441a15e3720fe2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the findings and substantial evidence that serves as the basis for denying the application; and</text></clause><clause id="id622c7ecb88ca413cbc574811fe0f4a0e"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>recommendations for how the commercial operator can address the reasons for the application’s denial.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id39b8304578924f59860fc592583e9ad5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Fees</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a State, local, or Tribal government may charge a fee to consider an application for the designation, placement, construction, or modification of an unmanned aircraft take-off and landing zone, or to use a right-of-way or a facility in a right-of-way owned or managed by the State, local, or Tribal government for the designation, placement, construction, or modification of an unmanned aircraft take-off and landing zone, if the fee is—</text><subparagraph id="id9fed40d6d7db47e58c4971909fabb9dc"><enum>(A)</enum><text>competitively neutral, technologically neutral, and nondiscriminatory; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0350ccf0bc6a41d989dec2a782b4766f"><enum>(B)</enum><text>publicly disclosed.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide46b4ebecff847d1b8bb2df5cd0f44e5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this subsection may be construed to prevent any State, local, or Tribal government from imposing any additional limitation or requirement relating to consideration by the State, local, or Tribal government of an application for the designation, placement, construction, or modification of an unmanned aircraft take-off and landing zone.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id27603e0416324320b9e73ffb8fdd2ab8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Judicial review</header><text>Any person adversely affected by any final action or failure to act by a State, local, or Tribal government that is inconsistent with this section may, within 30 days after the action or failure to act, commence an action in any court of competent jurisdiction, which shall hear and decide the action on an expedited basis.</text></subsection><subsection id="idC9B193AD3E08422C81D518C20F682E7E"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The provisions of this section shall take effect on the day that is 180 days after the final rule under section 3(d) is issued.</text></subsection></section><section id="id4db0a07238db48d3a650277f41b590a6"><enum>6.</enum><header>Rights to operate</header><subsection id="id4D4E524057D1441182508EEC32A577C3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><paragraph id="idA13F536B2917491AB4AE00A4AB7BE619"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subsection (b), a State, local, or Tribal government may not adopt, maintain, or enforce any law, rule, or standard that unreasonably or substantially impedes—</text><subparagraph id="idCC753DD12A574F58BAE424669C70D5B8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the ascent or descent of an unmanned aircraft system, operated by a commercial operator, to or from the navigable airspace in the furtherance of a commercial activity; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id99BF211B483844B4AC73366C6167AF7E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a civil unmanned aircraft from reaching navigable airspace where operations are permitted.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id606624B040634A409F2D0283155F95F7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Unreasonable or substantial impediment</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (1), an unreasonable or substantial impediment with respect to civil unmanned aircraft includes—</text><subparagraph id="idb566ce8e7ba7433daa0af00a6b63a01c"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a complete and total ban on overflights of civil unmanned aircraft over the entirety of airspace within a State, local, or Tribal government’s jurisdiction; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id201f8bab1e70497789bfd164470e6ccc"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a combination of prohibitions or restrictions on overflights within airspace under a State, local, or Tribal government’s jurisdiction such that it is nearly impossible for civil unmanned aircraft to reach the navigable airspace.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id55A2C92C2C384E6193CEF38772DF491E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rules of construction</header><text>Nothing in subsection (a) may be construed to prohibit a State, local, or Tribal government from—</text><paragraph id="id6A8B78B3A2464DF296EA14F1F8988A3C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>adopting, maintaining, or enforcing laws, rules, or standards that regulate unmanned aircraft systems below 200 feet above ground level; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idC25272D552224D7A835AB456F97AB67A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>prescribing emergency procedures for a civil unmanned aircraft system descending into an area 200 feet above ground level.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id5E11D19C643B4C46A8B551B02945B90B"><enum>7.</enum><header>Updates to rules regarding the commercial carriage of property</header><subsection id="id6C451CA7E5FA43F192539EF42E37D26F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Improving regulations</header><text>Section 44808 of title 49, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="idF505CCBB8B3A47EA9594F6EF9B703EB9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (b)(5) as subsection (c), and indenting appropriately;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idD44C794063A64E5B9796BAFB8FDA821C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (A), (B), and (C) of subsection (c), as redesignated by paragraph (1), as paragraphs (1), (2), and (3), respectively, and indenting appropriately;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id181642FC8F754EE48B0D8A97B5B7397D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (b)(6) as subsection (d), and indenting appropriately; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id389D0BF9F300469B95CEF910FCD83CF8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (b), as previously amended, by adding at the end the following new paragraphs:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idC007809712E3423E85E849B5AA61186A"><paragraph id="id49939ac1a9d84d6bbebd9e74470f52c0"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Ensure that the provision of section 41713 shall not apply to the carriage of property by operators of small unmanned aircraft systems.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4d361321b5954b3984843d6b9af02cb9"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Ensure that an operator of a small unmanned aircraft system is not required to comply with any rules approved under this section if the operator is operating solely under a State authorization for the intrastate carriage of property for compensation or hire.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8364532b002941299869a797dc7d728e"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Ensure that the costs necessary to receive such an authorization are minimal so as to protect competition between market participants.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2b9378b00e4447219eb8da01dc48bc8c"><enum>(8)</enum><text>A streamlined application process that only contains requirements minimally necessary for safe operation and substantially outweigh the compliance costs for an applicant.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idA0D33CBAAC3F465296D06716DFCE4BEA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clarification regarding preemption</header><text>Section 41713(b) of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id164760133CCF417AB5D47CA0B42104B8"><paragraph id="id821A3FEFFA61452DB3D2E469BB60C38E" indent="up1"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Not applicable to the operation of a civil unmanned aircraft system</header><text>Paragraphs (1) and (4) shall not apply to the operation of a civil unmanned aircraft system.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="id23B741E6419F464B93403F5C8042C44A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exclusion from definition of air carrier</header><text>Section 40102(2) of title 49, United States Code, is amended by inserting <quote>(but does not include an operator of civil unmanned aircraft systems)</quote> before the period at the end.</text></subsection><subsection id="idA3A913C6A13C41A58258E9039744465A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>State authorization for the intrastate carriage of property</header><text>A State may not be prohibited from issuing an authorization (and the Federal Government may not require a Federal authorization) for the carriage of property by a commercial operator of a civil unmanned aircraft that is operating in intrastate commerce if the civil unmanned aircraft is only authorized by the State to operate—</text><paragraph id="id270CDCFEDE554DD6B4C55F7B2192B22B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>within the immediate reaches of airspace; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2F3649704D9E40A4837E111F498D8FAA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>within the lateral boundaries of the State.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idFFD721E31DF4472483CE8C516E95F1B6"><enum>8.</enum><header>Designation of certain complex airspace</header><subsection id="id3bb6f86a3cd94ce0a44949323f27f6aa"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Process for designation</header><paragraph id="id53E94ED4BE6046219CD8176164981303"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Transportation shall establish a process under which a State, local, or Tribal government may submit an application to the Administrator (in a form and manner determined appropriate by the Administrator) for the designation of an area as an area of <quote>complex airspace</quote>. Such process shall allow for individual or collective designations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0D4F7BF36BC64ECB89E7078A0806B827"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Timeframe for decision</header><text>Under the process established under paragraph (1), the Administrator shall approve or disapprove a complete application for designation within 90 days of receiving the application.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8037ddd13ad14a71913b8b6025062e23"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Review of application</header><text>In reviewing an application for a designation under this section, the Administrator may deny the request if the State, local, or Tribal government does not have—</text><subparagraph id="id35B5550017BA49ADAA473ABA23DDFCA8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the financial resources to carry out the authority to be granted under the designation; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idF07FCC6BBCA444809A1CFD65D38FCCD2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the technological capabilities necessary to carry out the authority granted to the State under the designation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idec85e986d51c44688f8e39678247f8b7"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Denial of application</header><text>If the Administrator denies an application for a designation under this section, the Administrator shall provide the State, local, or Tribal government with—</text><subparagraph id="idEEA89F6708DF4981AD0255C6B8FCB586"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a detailed description of the reasons for the denial; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id497A2580644E4792AA3366BF646E9DFE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>recommendations for changes that the State can make to correct the deficiencies in their application.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1d58620d3b824fd7a4b98bc7e4a2f6f8"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Approval of application</header><text>If the Administrator approves an application for a designation under this section, the Administrator shall, upon the request of the State, local, or Tribal government, enter into a written agreement with the State, local, or Tribal government (which may be in the form of a memorandum of understanding) under which the Administrator may assign, and the State, local, or Tribal government may assume, one or more of the responsibilities of the Administrator with respect to the management of civil unmanned aircraft operations within the area that has been so designated.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idAAFE2B4E3272433AB37B5EAA5C0D208E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Agreements</header><paragraph id="id503d1297c5bc437ab79f8ef850215a58"><enum>(1)</enum><header>State, local, or tribal government responsibilities under agreement</header><text>If a State, local, or Tribal government enters into an agreement with the Administrator under subsection (a)(5), the State, local, or Tribal government shall be solely responsible, and solely liable, for carrying out the responsibilities assumed in the agreement until the agreement is terminated.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idC9642D082C56428A9CE2DFE4B30BA30D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Termination by State, local, or Tribal government</header><text>A State, local, or Tribal government may terminate an agreement with the Administrator under subsection (a)(5) if the State, local, or Tribal government provides the Administrator 90 days of notice.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7c38d7c8900243bfa205067e6aa89992"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Termination by Administrator</header><text>The Administrator may terminate an agreement with a State, local, or Tribal government under subsection (a)(5) if—</text><subparagraph id="idab0a7a9a316f43d3a1a24200678ceebb"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Administrator determines that the State, local, or Tribal government is not adequately carrying out the responsibilities assigned under the agreement; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida0529796ad3b447abbcb2178a2228cde"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Administrator provides the State, local, or Tribal government with—</text><clause id="id723cb4885b3144489e0b84e5ce990ed0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>written notification of a determination of noncompliance with the responsibilities assigned under the agreement; and</text></clause><clause id="id06b77ac4bf9e428692318fe2fdf345cc"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a period of not less than 180 days for the State, local, or Tribal government to take such corrective actions as the Administrator determines necessary to comply with the responsibilities assigned under the agreement.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id5EB3C69F211D4C55ABA64A23DFA3D6E6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Complex airspace defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>complex airspace</term> means an area of airspace that—</text><paragraph id="id1004D348EA854034A897263938B90FCB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is at least 200 feet above ground level; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id39607788694F4F0EB93F89278648FAC0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>includes 1 or more structures that have a height that exceeds 200 feet above ground level.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idFBF0D26E4A05496388D7A5ECB6003292"><enum>9.</enum><header>Improvements to plan for full operational capability of unmanned aircraft systems traffic management</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 376 of the FAA Reauthorization Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/254">Public Law 115–254</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="idB84AB0CF614E45A79093C14DF628F1DB"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (b), by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id440599F2AE964227ABB2FAE091C170C5"><paragraph id="id45a0ef793fe84963a181d93f92d3fa86"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Permit the testing of a State, local, or Tribal government’s time, place, and manner restrictions within the immediate reaches of airspace (as defined in section 44801).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="idCD3D86945EAD44779BAAC96202F8DD5F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text><subparagraph id="id78B049D2DE7549579860D2FD583DBDC9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>industry and government</quote> and inserting <quote>industry, the Federal Government, and State, local, or Tribal governments</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idDBF59D64DC9C40C8BFC6BF27D8DE871E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)(G), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id312EDAA61019403D9B0BB3B10525FCF4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)(C), by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE47308DDE16647B9B15F5117A6FDECC7"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraphs:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id81A14CC8052A4671B474C30C7E4D0D98"><paragraph id="idc173a59ccfef443dbac4229e00356ef9"><enum>(5)</enum><text>establish a plan for collaboration and coordination with a State, local, or Tribal government’s management of unmanned aircraft systems within the immediate reaches of airspace (as defined in section 44801); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idabf6e675df134b94a926eccdda430c85"><enum>(6)</enum><text>establish a process for the interoperability and sharing of data between Federal Government, State, local, or Tribal government, and private sector UTM services.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idEE1BF5B1302745758B9B93C9D271861D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (d)—</text><subparagraph id="id00E18E402B0942FBA4A92D27D0C21CB8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)(J), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7E729D084CFE470BBE5C1C47E052B3E5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1E3777ABF10A4891B2979C29167EFA6F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idF7993DDC494B4056BD6C9D1EE53908EE"><paragraph id="idE3D135A05F964468B2F72529092F963F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>shall consult with State, local, and Tribal governments.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idA04D13187F304B9EA7CD97B607BD609D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (g), by inserting <quote>and State, local, and Tribal governments</quote> after <quote>Federal agencies</quote>.</text></paragraph></section><section id="idDF2B714D473E4104B3E43539CC826521"><enum>10.</enum><header>Updates to rules regarding small unmanned aircraft safety standards</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 44805 of title 49, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="id9750C0B1BC5949FBB5A881D332BFE527"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text><subparagraph id="id166C59CFD1FE4898AF13AB35814B3C6D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idFDD692469F834F6F9C605E1DA0DE48FD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6C7F3B6339304163B340CD9E4CAF2A34"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id25430E89E9234CBC8265004E09C509C3"><paragraph id="id7C76E15A60FC49B3A7CBF9A2BB82C66C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>ensuring that no State is prohibited from requiring additional equipage for a small unmanned aircraft system so long as such small unmanned aircraft system is solely authorized to operate in the immediate reaches of airspace (as defined in section 44801) and the lateral boundaries of a State.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9CE79F68A12246B8832EB55DAFE18A89"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (e), in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by striking <quote>may</quote> and inserting <quote>shall</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7782B8F61F994A89A8CE5442EE0FCFD3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idDFCDDBC6D92241C084A4B2A36265CCC9"><subsection id="id42C4FA2EE47846C29BDF28C42C300533"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Requirements for accepting risk-Based consensus safety standards</header><paragraph id="id53935F158C4B43D686C310DC70518538"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Cost-benefit analysis</header><text>The Administrator shall not accept a risk-based consensus safety standard under subsection (a)(1) unless the Administrator has first conducted a cost-benefit analysis and certified that the benefit of the safety standard substantially outweighs the costs to the manufacturer and consumer.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2BD7A4FD03BC42B48E3F9AE5D0BDBE65"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Must be essential</header><text>The Administrator shall not accept a risk-based consensus safety standard under subsection (a)(1) unless the Administrator determines that the safety standard is essential for small unmanned aircraft systems to operate safely in the UTM.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="idd0e8f9c1cbb14179911da5644d052d6e"><enum>11.</enum><header>Rules of construction</header><subsection id="id9eb4c56038e744f8bda12189ed3418fc"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subsection (b), nothing in this Act may be construed to—</text><paragraph id="ida5a1f5b0bde941dca7492eb14ddfbfc1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>diminish or expand the preemptive effect of the authority of the Federal Aviation Administration with respect to manned aviation; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id663179cca5524628856b8a9fcc446a0d"><enum>(2)</enum><text>affect the civil or criminal jurisdiction of—</text><subparagraph id="id1e3c3131eab845d6b917fbc6a9a393b9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any Indian Tribe relative to any State or local government; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5a450215f29742eeb18612abe1243a6d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any State or local government relative to any Indian Tribe.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id49bb1ff312b948baaf0b155c6bc901a5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Enforcement actions</header><text>Nothing in subsection (a) may be construed to limit the authority of the Administrator to pursue enforcement actions against persons operating civil unmanned aircraft systems who endanger the safety of the navigable airspace, airport operations, air navigation facilities, air traffic control systems, or other components of the national airspace system that facilitate the safe and efficient operation of civil, commercial, or military aircraft within the United States.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

