<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4FBC9A16B8C848668DA66F2824299514" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 748 IH: Condemning attempts to use Federal regulatory power or litigation to suppress lawful speech, particularly speech critical of a political party or the President of the United States, and warning against the rise of authoritarianism.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 748</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250919">September 19, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="A000370">Ms. Adams</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000380">Mr. Amo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001318">Ms. Balint</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001324">Mr. Bell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000490">Mr. Bishop</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001296">Mr. Boyle of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001313">Ms. Brown</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001131">Mr. Casar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001123">Mr. Cisneros</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001069">Mr. Courtney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001119">Ms. Craig</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001121">Mr. Crow</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000197">Ms. DeGette</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000216">Ms. DeLauro</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000635">Ms. Dexter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000399">Mr. Doggett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000301">Ms. Elfreth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000299">Ms. Escobar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000481">Mr. Figures</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000468">Mrs. Fletcher</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000477">Mrs. Foushee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000483">Ms. Friedman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000476">Mr. Frost</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000598">Mr. Garcia of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001081">Mrs. Hayes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001103">Mr. Hernández</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001047">Mr. Himes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001094">Ms. Hoyle of Oregon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="I000058">Mr. Ivey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000309">Mr. Jackson of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000305">Ms. Jacobs</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000310">Ms. Johnson of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000400">Ms. Kamlager-Dove</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000601">Mr. Landsman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000557">Mr. Larson of Connecticut</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000606">Mr. Latimer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000602">Ms. Lee of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000273">Ms. Leger Fernandez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000607">Mr. Liccardo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001223">Mr. Magaziner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001208">Mrs. McBath</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001238">Ms. McBride</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001232">Mrs. McClain Delaney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001229">Mrs. McIver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001226">Mr. Menendez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000687">Mr. Mfume</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001241">Mr. Min</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001206">Mr. Morelle</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001234">Ms. Morrison</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000172">Ms. Ocasio-Cortez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000176">Mr. Olszewski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000620">Ms. Pettersen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000621">Ms. Randall</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000620">Ms. Rivas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000305">Ms. Ross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000599">Mr. Ruiz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000579">Mr. Ryan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001205">Ms. Scanlon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000185">Mr. Scott of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001231">Ms. Simon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001200">Mr. Soto</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001218">Ms. Stansbury</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001211">Mr. Stanton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000474">Mrs. Torres of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000482">Mrs. Trahan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000491">Mr. Tran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000187">Ms. Waters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000830">Mr. Whitesides</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000788">Ms. Williams of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001130">Ms. Crockett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000585">Mr. Gomez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001225">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000173">Ms. Omar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001223">Mrs. Sykes</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001220">Mr. McGarvey</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Condemning attempts to use Federal regulatory power or litigation to suppress lawful speech, particularly speech critical of a political party or the President of the United States, and warning against the rise of authoritarianism.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas freedom of speech and freedom of the press are foundational principles of the United States, enshrined in the First Amendment to the Constitution and by the Founders of this country;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas independent journalists, commentators, comedians, and media outlets have historically played a vital role in holding those in power accountable, regardless of political party;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the use of indirect or direct government power to silence criticism of a political party or the President of the United States undermines democratic norms and chills public discourse;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas authoritarians and authoritarian regimes throughout history have sought to control or co-opt media, silence dissent, and weaponize regulatory agencies to punish critics, eroding civil liberties and undermining democracy from within;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas efforts to pressure the Federal Communications Commission (FCC), or to bring politically motivated lawsuits, as tools to threaten or punish media figures for their criticism of elected officials or satire mirror tactics used by authoritarian governments to intimidate and silence critics;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Trump Administration and President Donald John Trump have issued public calls to use the awesome power of the Federal Government to investigate, fine, or otherwise penalize media figures and networks critical of the President, silencing free speech and echoing authoritarian tactics;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas late-night television host Jimmy Kimmel, who has been an outspoken critic of the Trump Administration, was taken off the air indefinitely following FCC Chair Brendan Carr threatening coercive government action against the Walt Disney Company and American Broadcasting Companies, Inc. (ABC) for Kimmel’s remarks;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas major law firms have reportedly been enlisted to file or threaten lawsuits against networks or personalities whose programming is critical of former President Trump, further chilling free expression;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the firing or forced removal of media personalities under political pressure can have a chilling effect on dissent and signal a dangerous slide toward authoritarian practices rather than democratic accountability; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas maintaining a free and open press is essential to a healthy democracy and to public accountability, and the erosion of this freedom has historically been a precursor to the rise of authoritarianism and the decline of democratic institutions: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H4D6D392315054BF78BA6E98A7939CAB9"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H3AF924EED4D34FA3AE975255FE9DD747"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="H731D40C4E53347DAA42D834F5507932B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">condemns the use of regulatory agencies, including the Federal Communications Commission, and the threat or filing of lawsuits as tools to suppress, intimidate, or punish lawful speech critical of any political party or the President of the United States;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HABE1F56B735141F082C4722C7F1F628F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">warns that such practices echo the tactics of authoritarian regimes and pose a serious threat to the democratic traditions and constitutional freedoms of the United States;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H158642E7D69A4EBB9AD50E8F05FD778C"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reaffirms its commitment to upholding the First Amendment and protecting the freedom of the press and freedom of expression for all individuals, regardless of political viewpoint;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE3605E6F15AC487188CF3B4E5207306C"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">calls upon all public officials, regardless of party affiliation, to refrain from using their positions of power to pressure media organizations or individuals into censoring or silencing speech protected by the Constitution;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0EE7B4180FE34C7CA7E6E5529F178424"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">urges the Department of Justice, the Federal Communications Commission, and other relevant agencies to ensure that their policies and practices safeguard free expression and do not become tools of political retribution; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9F738F0548274C2EAB9C2C51579DDE03"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">affirms that a vibrant, independent media and the ability of Americans to criticize their government are indispensable to the preservation of democratic governance and to preventing the rise of authoritarianism.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

