<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCC4B1923145241AEB6D98131B4706E64" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1823 IH: To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs and the Comptroller General of the United States to report on certain funding shortfalls in the Department of Veterans Affairs.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1823</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250304">March 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001301">Mr. Bergman</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B001295">Mr. Bost</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs and the Comptroller General of the United States to report on certain funding shortfalls in the Department of Veterans Affairs.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HDEEF4F9D7C684DC7805072D64A8D393F" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HA05E87D31F244231942CD55138FFC128" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Funding shortfalls in certain administrations of the Department of Veterans Affairs: review; report</header>
<subsection id="H0AB7DFA20D69462BA84F92AB9E9583C3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>GAO review</header>
<paragraph id="H0D18372683AF42E4B2F8BB573502DFF2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Review required</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall begin a review regarding the circumstances surrounding, and the causes of—</text> <subparagraph id="HD9A93FCD4D5A48FC9AEAE18AA2E185BA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the shortfall in the funding of the Veterans Benefits Administration for fiscal year 2024; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE3309D3601E148D68C17B710895CB1D5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the expected shortfall in the funding of the Veterans Health Administration in fiscal year 2025.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA610696B707C405EA12C39DAAE50ACCE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The review under this subsection shall include the following elements:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H0FDA710E78814713BBEEA18DDBDC3678"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A comparison of monthly obligations and expenditures in relevant accounts against the spending plan of the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF7173041A3154DD197075C1F27BF3CB5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Any transfers between accounts described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB6C8A6CB6A444482B01927F0AA4AE67C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The reasons for any significant diversions of obligations or expenditures from such spending plan.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5F02013C09C147E4BD2274ECAE6176EE"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An analysis of the accuracy of any projections or estimates relevant to diversions described in subparagraph (C).</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HAD79A6F90F15454DB3EF5BC79E869A81"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Remedial actions the Secretary of Veterans Affairs may take—</text> <clause id="HE0C9DD72762D434A915B20CDCD806172"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to improve the accuracy of supporting information submitted under section 1105(a) of title 31, United States Code, with respect to the Department; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HEEF3E813851843D78BDBA44AE129936C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to prevent funding shortfalls for the Department.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA402BC3EBFE74304B31C8613226C604A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after completing such review, the Comptroller General shall submit to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs a written report containing the results and findings of such review.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HF8859E1F4863453189E24F550A513F45" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report of the Secretary of Veterans Affairs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the Secretary of Veterans Affairs receives the report of the Comptroller General under subsection (a), the Secretary shall submit such report to the appropriate congressional committees.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H7CD9D24F782E4111A4DA00A5AC204635"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means—</text> 
<paragraph id="H2EE0A5F49EF0409BA42B980BDC0D9904"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Senate; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF04317190BC64231953CE1ED84A7278F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

