<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3E74F44FF4D14FF5865810BAD77F6036" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 804 IH: Recognizing the importance of Spanish-language media in the United States.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 804</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251014">October 14, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barrag&#225;n</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="M001226">Mr. Menendez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000168">Ms. Salazar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001225">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000400">Ms. Kamlager-Dove</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001091">Mr. Castro of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000172">Ms. Ocasio-Cortez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000621">Ms. Pou</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001218">Ms. Stansbury</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001226">Ms. Salinas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000402">Mr. Kennedy of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000482">Mrs. Trahan</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing the importance of Spanish-language media in the United States.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas more than 41,000,000 people in the United States speak Spanish at home, making it the most widely spoken language in the Nation after English;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Spanish-language news outlets provide essential information on elections, public health, emergency preparedness, and civic participation to communities that might otherwise face language barriers;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas access to trustworthy, culturally relevant news in Spanish strengthens American democracy, combats the spread of misinformation, and ensures that all communities can fully engage in civic life;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas local Spanish-language news outlets play a crucial role in connecting communities, delivering neighborhood-level coverage, and fostering civic engagement;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Spanish-language entertainment media celebrates Latino culture, strengthens community identity, and enriches the broader cultural fabric of the United States;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Spanish-language media supports education by providing bilingual content, resources for English learners, and coverage of programs that promote literacy and lifelong learning;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Spanish-language media highlights Latino contributions to the arts, culture, and society, showcasing achievements in film, music, literature, and other creative fields;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Spanish-language media fosters cross-cultural understanding, dialogue, and appreciation of Latino culture throughout the United States;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Spanish-language media outlets create jobs and support economic activity in the news and entertainment media sectors;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Spanish-language media now serves tens of millions of viewers, listeners, and readers across the United States, reflecting the diversity and growth of Latino communities in both urban and rural areas; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the continued vitality of Spanish-language media is essential to ensuring that the Nation’s bilingual and Latino American communities remain informed, connected, and represented: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H79D5FA33D6BC43618E0ADF23AE146482"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H755A29EE077B4D1EAC6111B25E3D0986"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text> 
<paragraph id="H000EC99F4FE0406D8CEAEDEA2740C619"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognizes the indispensable role of Spanish-language news and entertainment media in informing, educating, and culturally enriching communities across the United States;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4F87DE43BE654104AF752F0FA15CC121"><enum>(2)</enum><text>affirms that access to news and cultural content in Spanish is a matter of opportunity, inclusion, and democratic participation;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H822EE61EF0B5414DAE693030DD10FCCA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>commends Spanish-language journalists, broadcasters, and entertainers for their contributions to American democracy, culture, and society; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDFF148BF1D394C399D90B4A867AAF1FB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>encourages continued support for policies and initiatives that promote language access and ensure the sustainability and growth of Spanish-language media outlets nationwide.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

