<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA15133DBC69B4D4B831B3F5478FA4160" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5734 IH: Hiring Preference for Veterans and Americans With Disabilities Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5734</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251010">October 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000300">Mr. Evans of Colorado</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="D000230">Mr. Davis of North Carolina</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To clarify that a State or local jurisdiction may give preference to individuals who are veterans or individuals with a disability with respect to hiring election workers to administer an election in the State or local jurisdiction, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD16A90A7016A4C308A18D793FE454030" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HB299CEEC02E4427784D513C1093C4317" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Hiring Preference for Veterans and Americans With Disabilities Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H11B677A3E4DD41B99965CA7177029652"><enum>2.</enum><header>Clarification of rules with respect to hiring of election workers</header> <subsection id="H542970F709E34363B50C55FA56748727"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Preferences for veterans and individuals with disabilities</header> <paragraph id="H0FAFE12F393C4908882164A7541FA94F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Preferences</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In hiring election workers to administer an election in a State or local jurisdiction, the State or local jurisdiction may give preference to individuals who are veterans or individuals with a disability.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDFBC31E5F3E44D9F895DE5D7ECCA4A3F" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Individual with a disability defined</header><text>In this subsection, an <quote>individual with a disability</quote> means an individual with an impairment that substantially limits any major life activities.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HBD77DC1E52B24490A6AF8DC9F12FF065"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Preference and waiver of residency requirement for spouses and dependents of absent military voters</header> <paragraph id="HEE68959106B34851ACF52F1CF5A6A61A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Preference and waivers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In hiring election workers to administer an election in a State or local jurisdiction, the State or local jurisdiction—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H802F19B6647F42398CCABF56507C630F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>may give preference to an individual who is a nonresident military spouse or dependent; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA3C571C478EA4634A26A8316778A7C7C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may not refuse to hire such an individual as an election worker solely on the grounds that the individual does not maintain a place of residence in the State or local jurisdiction.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2495AC88C8F1412284D9AB786D3570C0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Nonresident military spouse or dependent defined</header><text>In this subsection, a <quote>nonresident military spouse or dependent</quote> means an individual who is an absent uniformed services voter under section 107(1)(C) of the Uniformed and Overseas Citizen Absentee Voting Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/20310">52 U.S.C. 20310(1)(C)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

