<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF2E9D886222E46ED9C636F99D26219D7" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4530 IH: Suppressing Tactics of Prohibited Shells Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4530</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250717">July 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001224">Mr. Self</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="C001055">Mr. Case</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To apply licensing requirements under the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 to subsidiaries of entities listed on the Entity List or Military End User List, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H88202F9D73A1415B9FCBFC44904EA0D1" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H84F98D657C074765847D2D1ACF6A83C9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Suppressing Tactics of Prohibited Shells Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>STOP Shells Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H97237221729748ED8CDD90E1D81A10DB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Application of licensing requirements under the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 to subsidiaries of entities listed on the Entity List or Military End User List</header> <subsection id="HA420145866FF4E759C8A0225DBFB6DC6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Commerce is authorized to and shall apply the licensing requirement under the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 to affiliates owned 50 percent or more in aggregate, directly or indirectly, by an entity listed on the Entity List or the Military End User List.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA293CDFDAF294A15AA45C547D3516C71"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Foreign Direct Product Rule Assessment</header> 
<paragraph id="H1A7E34DF74834150A712C463333B1E33"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Prior to adding an entity to the Entity List or Military End User List, the Secretary of Commerce shall conduct an assessment to determine whether application of the Foreign Direct Product Rule to the licensing requirement for the entity would advance United States national security or foreign policy interests.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBCBF4A182D3C415B808FA6E506258BD6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Congressional notification</header><text>Not later than 2 days after adding an entity to the Entity List, the Secretary shall provide the appropriate congressional committees with the respective Foreign Direct Product Rule Assessment for the entity.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1E809ACF1CEA46B6B03EF276C74D7A63"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Waiver</header> 
<paragraph id="HAF2C67595D324D869F819D2C3CB95F80"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to subsection (d), the Secretary of Commerce is authorized to exempt, on a case-by-case basis, from the requirement set forth in subsection (a) any entity determined by the Secretary of Commerce, in consultation with the Secretaries of State, Defense, and Energy, whose exemption is in the national security interest of the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H212217857D264F0EAD9A1ABA80EF0605"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Congressional notification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 days after issuing a waiver under this subsection, the Secretary shall notify the appropriate congressional committees and include a detailed explanation of the national security or foreign policy interest that justified the waiver.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD2DB6F3811E64CE0A16DE0ECA4410C27"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text> <paragraph id="HFBA570C7772F4BFD99D494043DFB2D29"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>Entity List</term> means the list maintained by the Bureau of Industry and Security of the Department of Commerce and set forth in Supplement No. 4 to part 744 of title 15, Code of Federal Regulations, or successor regulations;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4955732045D848ACB5B87F858B5CE16C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>Military End User List</term> means the list maintained by the Bureau of Industry and Security of the Department of Commerce and set forth in Supplement No. 7 to part 744 of title 15, Code of Federal Regulations, or successor regulations; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H02B0EF81BBF3454BA711C0EC7F05ADA7"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>Foreign Direct Product Rule</term> has the meaning as described in part 734.9 of title 15, Code of Federal Regulations, or successor regulations.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

