<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1F8C6EEC63F7409C88E3831749836A59" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1023 IH: Reporting on Investments in Foreign Adversaries Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1023</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250205">February 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="O000086">Mr. Owens</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="H001102">Mr. Harris of North Carolina</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require disclosure of certain foreign investments within endowments, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HCF5AEFC7737A43E7B79BBB61502FEAD2" style="OLC"><section id="H7E5ABD2E824945BC892BB9BEE89EC41C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Reporting on Investments in Foreign Adversaries Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>RIFA Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H94B6612DED9A4C81B650F9CD805688C2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Investment disclosure report</header><subsection id="H4D3D5A52C9484C67B1B84972AAE8D43C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Part B of title I of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1011">20 U.S.C. 1011 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 117 the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2B139FAEA16B45E5B79EB27C255480F7"><section id="H8B06E63D95714EBD8A05B90F9F47D441"><enum>117A.</enum><header>Investment disclosure report</header><subsection id="H2E6BC7048F504336B7BB0D73DFDAEFA9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Investment disclosure report</header><text>A specified institution shall file a disclosure report in accordance with subsection (b) with the Secretary on each July 31 immediately following any calendar year in which the specified institution purchases, sells, or holds (directly or indirectly through any chain of ownership) one or more investments of concern.</text></subsection><subsection id="HFEF0A44B6EC64DBDAC78C7F6F6CCCFA8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents of report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each report to the Secretary required by subsection (a) shall contain, with respect to the calendar year preceding the calendar year in which such report is filed, the following information: </text><paragraph id="HC173CAA580E94A7D9A1E70E7C6D9CFEC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A list of the investments of concern purchased, sold, or held during such calendar year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6CC856B664D14C0587E0F053E1AC93D9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The aggregate fair market value of all investments of concern held as of the close of such calendar year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H19B04FA975FE4E16B781A17A6C423AAB" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The combined value of all investments of concern sold over the course of such calendar year, as measured by the fair market value of such investments at the time of the sale.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE7131F40819749868D9374EC65E21164" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The combined value of all capital gains from such sales of investments of concern. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB8A914F5F5DA4417AD5D164A0517926E" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Treatment of certain pooled investments</header><paragraph id="HFD3F670C7C224A5FB1CE305610B68DB4" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Pooled investment classification</header><subparagraph id="H61EA9E18B89646CA92452E1B44D5FCDD" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of this section, except as provided in subparagraph (B), a specified interest acquired by a specified institution in a regulated investment company, exchange traded fund, or any other pooled investment that holds an investment of concern shall be treated as an investment of concern and shall be reported pursuant to paragraph (2)(A).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF4350661280A4D97A2B78EC1C26F70A4" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Certification of pooled investment</header><text>Notwithstanding subparagraph (A), such specified interest shall not be subject to subparagraph (A) if the Secretary certifies, pursuant to paragraph (2)(B), that such pooled investment is not holding an investment of concern.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0A529568371B4C2CBCB81EF666C3CE7D" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Procedures</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, after consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury and the Securities and Exchange Commission, shall establish procedures under which a pooled investment described in paragraph (1)—</text><subparagraph id="HDFC197E1F4E745ADBF2ADBC308CC8049" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall be reported in accordance with the requirements of subsection (b); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA9807016E9714EA7971A66A6C305C244" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may be certified under paragraph (1)(B) as not holding an investment of concern.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA60446CA330843B2B5EC372EA3C9D3FD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Treatment of related organizations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, assets held by any related organization (as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/4968">section 4968(d)(2)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986) with respect to a specified institution shall be treated as held by such specified institution, except that—</text><paragraph id="H0692B466B53640009005E604CC4DCD4F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>such assets shall not be taken into account with respect to more than 1 specified institution; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB059A26D0AFE40FC86F9B721ADD6746A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>unless such organization is controlled by such institution or is described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/509">section 509(a)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 with respect to such institution, assets which are not intended or available for the use or benefit of such specified institution shall not be taken into account.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HED7880FCF9164F4EB659E1343B512012"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Valuation of debt</header><text>For purposes of this section, the fair market value of any debt shall be the principal amount of such debt.</text></subsection><subsection id="H538D900262AB48B888B07F9DF62FAB9F"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, after consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury and the Securities and Exchange Commission, may issue such regulations or other guidance as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section, including regulations or other guidance providing for the proper application of this section with respect to certain regulated investment companies, exchange traded funds, and pooled investments.</text></subsection><subsection id="H0E592B1AE0F644C4A1821E4FEEB75EE9"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Compliance officer</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any specified institution that is required to submit a report under subsection (a) shall designate, before the submission of such report, and maintain a compliance officer, who shall—</text><paragraph id="HF3711234922B4E658C368BDED0059612"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be a current employee or legally authorized agent of such institution; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3865CC169EB946428B4467BA468182E7"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be responsible, on behalf of the institution, for personally certifying accurate compliance with the reporting requirements under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFC83F576A53548F29776C162E7C7B913" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Database requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning not later than the May 31 of the calendar year following the date of enactment of the RIFA Act, the Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="HC498711E338644B1983D936A20D669C3" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish and maintain a searchable database on a website of the Department, under which all reports submitted under this section—</text><subparagraph id="HDF59731F6A2A41CD9248223D827A89C4" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are made publicly available (in electronic and downloadable format), including any information provided in such reports;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H383C8399C51E41A3BC679A3C7E6FAD3B" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>can be individually identified and compared; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2BAC5CC101234095B3483A64C7880C44" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>are searchable and sortable; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDDDA8AA3AD864DE393DA8A767809F201" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not later than 30 days after receipt of a disclosure report under this section, include such report in such database.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC162E0063E6D433BB1761F21D3DE76F3" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><paragraph id="HEB9EC1167AAB4A09986190B10F0273B2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Investigation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary (acting through the General Counsel of the Department) shall conduct investigations of possible violations of this section by institutions and, whenever it appears that an institution has knowingly or willfully failed to comply with a requirement of this section (including any rule or regulation promulgated under such section), shall request that the Attorney General bring a civil action in accordance with paragraph (2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H25CB0EBC30A5413FACBE95392DB424F0" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Civil action</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whenever it appears that an institution has knowingly or willfully failed to comply with a requirement of this section (including any rule or regulation promulgated under any such section) based on an investigation under paragraph (1), a civil action shall be brought by the Attorney General, at the request of the Secretary, in an appropriate district court of the United States, or the appropriate United States court of any territory or other place subject to the jurisdiction of the United States, to request such court to compel compliance with the requirement of this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDAD68FE575544516B95A227C163BD56F" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Costs and other fines</header><text>An institution that is compelled to comply with a requirement of this section pursuant to paragraph (2) shall—</text><subparagraph id="H91C15866CB894AE6A25EA6B92848E124" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>pay to the Treasury of the United States the full costs to the United States of obtaining compliance with the requirement of this section, including all associated costs of investigation and enforcement; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0085DEF75E954577808BFB8ABA702A8C" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>be subject to the applicable fines described in paragraph (4).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD10464ED053A4C7B9A4B145B4090BCD1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Fines for violations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall impose a fine on an institution that is compelled to comply with a requirement of this section pursuant to paragraph (2) as follows:</text><subparagraph id="HE0C82B3A7B404B60A5F929C895FD7A68"><enum>(A)</enum><header>First-time violations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a specified institution that knowingly or willfully fails to comply with a requirement of this section with respect to a calendar year, and that has not previously knowingly or willfully failed to comply with such a requirement, the Secretary shall impose a fine on the institution in an amount that is not less than 50 percent and not more than 100 percent of the sum of— </text><clause id="H040CCB402954459C929E2577BDAE4D9B"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the aggregate fair market value of all investments of concern held by such institution as of the close of such calendar year; and</text></clause><clause id="HA6AF4196ED3D4EBE82485A25067E76B1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the combined value of all investments of concern sold over the course of such calendar year, as measured by the fair market value of such investments at the time of the sale.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD7AECF0F49504B5AA2BBBCB848589C84"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Subsequent violations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a specified institution that has been fined pursuant to subparagraph (A) with respect to a calendar year, and that knowingly or willfully fails to comply with a requirement of this section with respect to any additional calendar year, the Secretary shall impose a fine on the institution with respect to any such additional calendar year in an amount that is not less than 100 percent and not more than 200 percent of the sum of—</text><clause id="H4DC5C1DF3F784C04AA3CF479C07026BC"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the aggregate fair market value of all investments of concern held by such institution as of the close of such additional calendar year; and</text></clause><clause id="HE79ED0BEDAC643FB9F61763AAE8F2CF6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the combined value of all investments of concern sold over the course of such additional calendar year, as measured by the fair market value of such investments at the time of the sale.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDCC4BA8FD1184A309711A19082401B6E"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H0A45FBDAF2504783A091EC4FCF386841"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Foreign country of concern</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>foreign country of concern</term> means the following:</text><subparagraph id="H195BFE359A9C4FF08DAB29192421B5BB" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Any covered nation defined in section 4872 of title 10, United States Code.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEC1F09DD16A54D5E9531958B9A78837A" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any country the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of State, and the Director of National Intelligence, determines, for purposes of this section, to be engaged in conduct that is detrimental to the national security or foreign policy of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5A60C0FECDCB45419E360645C0DC2A1D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Foreign entity of concern</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>foreign entity of concern</term> has the meaning given such term in section 10612(a) of the Research and Development, Competition, and Innovation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/19221">42 U.S.C. 19221(a)</external-xref>) and includes a foreign entity that is identified on the list published under section 1286(c)(8)(A) of the John S. McCain National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2019 (10 U.S.C. 22 4001 note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/232">Public Law 115–232</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1D870B30D907479F83C4526B5BD96819"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Institution</header><text>The term <term>institution</term> means an institution of higher education (as such term is defined in section 102, other than an institution described in subsection (a)(1)(c) of such section).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2283A8362A9846B2B0EB73239135A9D0"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Investment of concern</header><subparagraph id="H06F044F9D00548059F616780F5D992A5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>investment of concern</term> means any specified interest with respect to any of the following:</text><clause id="H23A7288DBD5F40DDBC297BAA73317DA5"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A foreign country of concern.</text></clause><clause id="H4A87A9F4A8974A5994471C857F58CC64"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A foreign entity of concern.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H179E4343903B4F7BB6483F218E20F47D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Specified interest</header><text>The term <term>specified interest</term> means, with respect to any entity—</text><clause id="H2C9963EC714D47C885FAC7982FCD229D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>stock or any other equity or profits interest of such entity;</text></clause><clause id="H6A71B0D0C04B4F019F09BE82426731A3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>debt issued by such entity; and</text></clause><clause id="H88F8461F7F2C4C97B7C84D798B2BDBB4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any contract or derivative with respect to any property described in clause (i) or (ii).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC9EA7C143C354345A9327E2C3943ADCA"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Specified institution</header><subparagraph id="HE6FAFB49EBF744BB8CE48DF421E4C869"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>specified institution</term>, as determined with respect to any calendar year, means an institution if—</text><clause id="H314500D762984D9DA0B78DB0EF05D75F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>such institution is not a public institution; and</text></clause><clause id="H6B47C67C43CF49FD98B8D95D660EB229" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the aggregate fair market value of—</text><subclause id="HD1927725F9F5438D9EE59C03A8BF1DA6"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the assets held by such institution at the end of such calendar year (other than those assets which are used directly in carrying out the institution’s exempt purpose) is in excess of $6,000,000,000; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H2EFADF80700D407CB5224CF8FD39E055" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the investments of concern held by such institution at the end of such calendar year is in excess of $250,000,000. </text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCB96792F3C2A4586B41BE3288F54824C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>References to certain terms</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purpose of applying the definition under subparagraph (A), the terms <term>aggregate fair market value</term> and <term>assets which are used directly in carrying out the institution’s exempt purpose</term> shall be applied in the same manner as such terms are applied for the purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/4968">section 4968(b)(1)(D)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HCEBBE9F3DC34487B9C3707D37DCBA000"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Program participation agreement</header><text>Section 487(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1094">20 U.S.C. 1094</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H9277DC877EF140DF989323E0E67FC774" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H5557B4B95D79408896172F5364439B97"><enum>(30)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HD247F497D7474BB792A542DDD09CF2F6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An institution will comply with the requirements of section 117A.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB8F8E75A9A8C4E7495522BCD35C94B43" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An institution that, for 3 consecutive institutional fiscal years, violates any requirement of section 117A shall—</text><clause id="H1E00F9039CA84D69A8F7D9DCE3E2B76B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>be ineligible to participate in the programs authorized by this title for a period of not less than 2 institutional fiscal years; and</text></clause><clause id="HEF6C93315FDA42CB8845413C69F8B785"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in order to regain eligibility to participate in such programs, demonstrate compliance with all requirements of such section for not less than 2 institutional fiscal years after the institutional fiscal year in which such institution became ineligible. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

