<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HBC6C4C65B44941719402312B1AD17C91" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 1229 IH: United States-Israel Defense Partnership Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1229</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250212">February 12, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000795">Mr. Wilson of South Carolina</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="N000188">Mr. Norcross</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To enhance bilateral defense cooperation between the United States and Israel, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF7277DD56D7F4F0DAC7F53923977F30D" style="OLC"><section id="H204AA48838194EACB1A941ED9E14A169" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>United States-Israel Defense Partnership Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8F54ED9F627D4DF6A45E193896DECD48"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA6CC28E7A0A94360A195F31416ABA410"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the United States and Israel—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H884C25ACED234C938FF1184CF716C057"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are bound closely by historic and cultural ties and mutual interests; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCD3BA0674ED54202BE07A4E07C406D10"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">face common threats, which are constantly evolving in scope, scale, and lethality;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H131186209D38427CAFAFD535E0F4177C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to most effectively counter such shared threats, the United States and Israel must expand their defense partnership to develop new technologies and leverage the unique capabilities offered by defense industrial base of each country; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC9F8B6ADBE044ED487F98DCD16625772"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">this Act furthers such goal through the establishment of several joint initiatives.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HAC6A3BC002C044079EA9325ACC972169"><enum>3.</enum><header>United States-Israel program on countering unmanned systems</header><subsection id="H338EAE1589F747DF9E7B61FE725BBE9C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress makes the following findings:</text><paragraph id="HEA9BEDA7199B4542B8CA56A8CB2C80FA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The increasing use of unmanned systems by state and nonstate actors poses a significant threat to the national security of the United States and its allies, including Israel.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF126C56BBA63420B8340E37BFF26AA3D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Cooperation in developing and deploying counter-unmanned systems technology will enhance mutual security and strengthen bilateral defense capabilities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8402986FFDE84D33952F8E04223DFEF6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Israel is a global leader in the development of advanced counter-unmanned systems technologies, and a cooperative program will leverage shared expertise and resources to address evolving threats.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6899A46331364E0DAD8B9DEFBE31DA12"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H57650C9E7B5946C0A072274D8CB8CAEE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense, with the concurrence of the Minister of Defense of Israel, shall establish a cooperative program between the United States and Israel, to be known as the <quote>United States-Israel Counter-Unmanned Systems Program</quote>, for the purpose of enhancing cooperation between the United States and Israel for purposes of—</text><subparagraph id="H01B2A442C11D48149EF9F14837831E70"><enum>(A)</enum><text>developing, testing, evaluating, and deploying advanced technologies for countering unmanned systems that threaten the United States and Israel;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H843B60267E1B4895905F91E90197E13D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>sharing technical expertise and data on emerging unmanned systems and related threats;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA27F05C529BD470E918F93779E6ECBD3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>conducting joint research and development initiatives; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD19C0A4ADAF74A038D25BADFB77747D6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>deploying and integrating counter-unmanned systems for mutual defense.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD0307A66B9CC4077B83FE2A42F6C230F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Activities</header><text>The program established under this subsection shall include the following:</text><subparagraph id="HAC29AABB49BA4600B052E022ADBCC06E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Collaborative research initiatives involving government, private sector, and academic institutions in the United States and Israel, conducted in a manner that protects sensitive technology and information and the national security interests of the United States and Israel.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H161A052EDC8D474B9005ED2FA38F8E43"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Joint training exercises and information-sharing mechanisms to enhance operational readiness of personnel of the United States and of Israel.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC8C34C8D645E4D049F997730CAF76D19"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The establishment, within the Department of Defense, of a United States-Israel Counter-Unmanned Systems Program Office to oversee program execution and coordination.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H00694364354D4C5EA51D97B930F604DF"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The procurement and deployment of counter-unmanned systems.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE73F2AF1527B4359BAE461CBD369A55D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Annual report</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC73B483128AE4099B403BA114BCEA614"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives a report on the implementation of the program established under this section. </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA81D5BAA0D2947E9BA7D757D975388B2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each report required by paragraph (1) shall include, for the preceding year—</text><subparagraph id="H15942B79EC204729B17D0D45A88DD140"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of activities conducted under the program;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H769DED6F65B64B0DA484CC0AEDC9A7F4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an assessment of progress made in addressing unmanned systems threats and requirements; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H73132E33F966441DAFE90BAECA66FA1D"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an assessment of the program’s collaboration with other relevant United States Government programs, including the United States-Israel Operations-Technology Working Group and Counter Unmanned Aerial Systems program run by the Irregular Warfare Technical Support Directorate; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC7B935E4C40C46D2A6FF09153D479126"><enum>(D)</enum><text>recommendations for future program activities and funding.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7B8D0D25EEFE490DA602112F247F4BA6" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Form</header><text>Each report submitted under paragraph (1) shall be submitted in unclassified form but may include a classified annex as necessary to protect sensitive information. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFC35CEC639A34EBCA7576D2F2F274F87"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated $150,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030 to carry out the program under this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2DBA537A785043FC8460C3B2855529CB"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall be construed to alter or supersede agreements or obligations between the United States and Israel in existence on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H44E5E196DD0C423CBFF998D26017911E"><enum>4.</enum><header>Extension and modification of United States-Israel anti-tunnel cooperation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1279 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2016 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/92">Public Law 114–92</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/8606">22 U.S.C. 8606</external-xref> note) is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H38467AD12CC349F2B0222A91E50B1916"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(4), by striking <quote>$50,000,000</quote> and inserting <quote>$80,000,000</quote>; and </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFEE0AFBDA2414D188717B89961488437"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (f), by striking <quote>December 31, 2026</quote> and inserting <quote>December 31, 2028</quote>.</text></paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H28CC85DF1A7949C4BCBC2E7E80CC45BD"><enum>5.</enum><header>Extension and modification of United States-Israel cooperation to counter unmanned aerial systems</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1278 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/8606">22 U.S.C. 8606</external-xref> note) is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFBA509CFA2614E44B15E8B2820776702"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(4), by striking <quote>$55,000,000</quote> and inserting <quote>$75,000,000</quote>; and </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9C879FB7C4CB42CA93FD68E4283700BE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (f), by striking <quote>December 31, 2026</quote> and inserting <quote>December 31, 2028</quote>.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H34D34B2F80584816905A7DE4D427A78D"><enum>6.</enum><header>United States-Israel emerging technology capabilities cooperation</header><subsection id="HBDC3E0D8E6544A258CBB33BD694AEE77"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text>It is the policy of the United States to support and encourage further defense collaboration with Israel in areas of emerging technologies capable of enabling the warfare capabilities of both the United States and Israel to meet emerging defense challenges, including in the areas of artificial intelligence, cybersecurity, robotics, quantum, and automation.</text></subsection><subsection id="HECC6406F05464CAEAA77EE0BD27A1B99"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authority To establish emerging defense technology capabilities program with Israel</header><paragraph id="HFF47B2B471E941A5A960A9F45A95C0A7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Defense, upon request by the Ministry of Defense of Israel and in consultation with the Secretary of State and the Director of National Intelligence, is authorized to carry out, jointly with Israel, research, development, test, and evaluation in areas of emerging technologies capable of enabling the warfare capabilities of the United States and Israel to meet emerging defense challenges, including in the areas of artificial intelligence, cybersecurity, robotics, quantum, and automation. </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB4A6C7EB111E4E85B94252ABE3693E59"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Protection of sensitive information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any activity carried out pursuant to the authority provided by paragraph (1) shall be conducted in a manner that appropriately protects sensitive information and the national security interests of the United States and Israel.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD37D2DC3B2064FCA899F895CB73A121B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report</header><text>None of the activities described in paragraph (1) may be carried out until the date on which the Secretary of Defense submits to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives a report that sets forth the following:</text><subparagraph id="H5FF07E3F05E24FB98D12F705F845CCD1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A memorandum of agreement between the United States and Israel regarding sharing of research and development costs for the capabilities described in paragraph (1), and any supporting documents.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA37754EECD2342748FB07FB1E4B1038E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A certification that such memorandum of agreement—</text><clause id="H5C2C9CF92E5B446996298F547ED78834"><enum>(i)</enum><text>requires sharing of costs of projects, including in-kind support, between the United States and Israel;</text></clause><clause id="HDB4E591B2BC34A5B9CA7BC9BEF428EFA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>establishes a framework to negotiate the rights to any intellectual property developed under the memorandum of agreement; and</text></clause><clause id="H68B1A32F9D3D47E99C15B69C27E4D5CC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>requires the United States Government to receive semiannual reports on expenditure of funds, if any, by the Government of Israel, including a description of what the funds have been used for, when funds were expended, and an identification of entities that expended the funds.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H231940CA86C94D0E9D79C3EE14740743"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Lead agency</header><text>Not earlier than the date on which the Secretary of Defense submits the report required by subsection (b)(3), the Secretary of Defense shall designate the Irregular Warfare Technology Support Directorate as the lead agency of the Department of Defense in carrying out this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE0FFE4F996FC43F58D4F957F07499336"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Semiannual reports</header><text>The Secretary of Defense shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress on a semiannual basis a report that contains a copy of the most recent semiannual report provided by the Government of Israel to the Department of Defense pursuant to subsection (b)(3)(B)(iii).</text></subsection><subsection id="H0E24E767F32848BCB61D9E7CAE17CE0C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated $50,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030 to carry out the program under this section.</text></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="H72963CB7548242BEB558B7E3F1A2157A"><enum>7.</enum><header>Extension of War Reserves Stockpile authority</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 12001(d) of the Department of Defense Appropriations Act, 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/108/287">Public Law 108–287</external-xref>; 118 Stat. 1011) is amended by striking <quote>after January 1, 2027</quote> and inserting <quote>after January 1 2029</quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="H04717073338C4C2BA364BA4CF5AB7D0E"><enum>8.</enum><header>Establishment of Defense Innovation Unit office in Israel</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall establish in Israel a Defense Innovation Unit office—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9DCEA09B00AF4596B4879E08AED3B0F1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to engage the Minister of Defense of Israel and representatives of the private sector in collaborative efforts to counter development by Iran of dual-use defense technologies; and </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC4D7884DE7C04ECA9F37E0B5968D45AB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to leverage resources and innovation activities of the United States and Israel for the benefit of the national security of the United States and Israel.</text></paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="HF7E8DA53CA5F40A893A20D1066F7CA3C"><enum>9.</enum><header>National Technology Industrial Base</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB558E8FC29B541C4B790D5620A7B23C0"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall seek to engage the Minister of Defense of Israel in a discussion of the process of the ascension of Israel into the national technology and industrial base (as defined in section 4801 of title 10, United States Code). </text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3FC69EFB75E74413A377AB89E57F4599"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Protection of sensitive information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any activity carried out pursuant to the authority provided by subsection (a) shall be conducted in a manner that appropriately protects sensitive information and the national security interests of the United States and Israel. </text></subsection></section><section id="HA12FFB741AAF4A45874D441864C5FA44"><enum>10.</enum><header>Assessment of integrated air and missile defense in region covered by United States Central Command</header><subsection id="H2B3F70A77894453C8A8C34CB09A37641"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Assessment required</header><text>The Secretary of Defense shall conduct an assessment of the integrated air and missile defense in the region cover by United States Central Command.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDB820338FDEC49B096DC501E916AB97B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The assessment conducted pursuant to subsection (a) shall cover the following:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4F91B087D8EA4E2786DE9CD22F72F211"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The current strength of the integrated air and missile defense in the region described in subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H990EBB97A1A34A45BBDCAA8BB5B51E20"><enum>(2)</enum><text>How best to strengthen the integrated air and missile defense described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC7F60E23742D4FCFA7BC090DB848CDF8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>What would be required to expand or deepen cooperation among the United States, Israel, and other regional partners of the United States to achieve full operational capability of the integrated air and missile defense described in paragraph (1), including identification of the amount of funding and new legal authorities that may be required for such expansion or deepening.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4C67A72FC0BA466494A58BC3D569F441"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In carrying out the assessment required by subsection (a), the Secretary shall consider the following:</text><paragraph id="HDE5AE33642624A9DADB09AE2ABD4D467"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The strategy required by section 1658(b) of James M. Inhofe National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2023 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/263">Public Law 117–263</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC39596303F334E909C888D0D90D7CE46"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Current cooperation among partners of the United States in the region described by subsection (a) on integrated air and missile defense.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H27E6BB5A489449B4B125A33373F5E9CD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Lessons learned in countering the April 13, 2024, and October 1, 2024, airstrikes by Iran against Israel.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H74990762CB194F8E844124AB53BAD25A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFA0F8D18E5BC40ACB86B72F2184B6F47"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives a report on the assessment conducted under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD9562958464E482C99287946CC4D2D9B"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Form</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report required by paragraph (1) shall be submitted in unclassified form but may contain a classified annex.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

