<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD38949E393C04954B03644A6E8B14FF8" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 893 IH: Working Families Housing Tax Credit Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 893</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250131">January 31, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000579">Mr. Ryan</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide a credit for working families housing development, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H1867CB17D6344FD2A92B40C9DFAA1E34" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HFD6EB02F50A7444BBCAFB78D4B324345" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Working Families Housing Tax Credit Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H6AB215406A964CA48BE02955B1FF2761"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress relating to the working families housing tax credit</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text> 
<paragraph id="HD729E9C0A0F144CFBA2BF83D4EB3435F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the working family housing tax credit under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/42A">section 42A</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is a critically important Federal Government policy tool to encourage the production of quality housing for our teachers, firefighters, police officers, veterans, and all hard-working Americans; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB738B17EB1CC46ECA048BB1D54CE4F0A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress should further improve and enhance the working families housing tax credit by passing pro-housing legislation.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H76C83BE477284238BEF8D5EE5E99F5D3"><enum>3.</enum><header>Working families housing tax credit</header> 
<subsection id="HC9D8DED16CC3468C87DEA9FDB26F7A56"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subpart D of part IV of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting after section 42 the following new section:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8DE8CD71783449BAB5362976C32E0161"> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="H4B7DEA78D79B4C48A4AEB8A44EF9CAA4"><enum>42A.</enum><header>Working families housing credit</header> <subsection id="H770CEC8DA4B04B38BCA1E6FC37E6315C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of section 38, the amount of the working families housing credit determined under this section for any taxable year in the credit period shall be an amount equal to—</text> 
<paragraph id="H90F924C7981B40EE8D285DBBEB590A1C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the applicable percentage, of</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H134ABFBE231A4E9DB90B7AA41C6E3775"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the qualified basis of each qualified working families building.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8D21035F86D643368579FFFB4E26D6A3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicable percentage</header> 
<paragraph id="H1782D9A0817C4D3BBE8FE329A5AB79EE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Determination of applicable percentage</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text> <subparagraph id="H6E20D3BC4804414A92D91B8CD896F3D5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>applicable percentage</term> means, with respect to any building, the appropriate percentage prescribed by the Secretary for the earlier of—</text> 
<clause id="H771A08E7532B4E4A920DCC1BBC4F8F4D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the month in which such building is placed in service, or</text></clause> <clause id="H9A859C2092594A30A071051893495629"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>at the election of the taxpayer, the month in which the taxpayer and the housing credit agency enter into an agreement with respect to such building (which is binding on such agency, the taxpayer, and all successors in interest) as to the housing credit dollar amount to be allocated to such building.</text></clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">A month may be elected under clause (ii) only if the election is made not later than the 5th day after the close of such month. Such an election, once made, shall be irrevocable.</continuation-text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6684FC0A8D7A44D8AA7E736BFD4249DA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Method of prescribing percentages</header><text>The percentages prescribed by the Secretary for any month shall be percentages which will yield over a 15-year period amounts of credit under subsection (a) which have a present value equal to—</text> <clause id="HA6EC44F702BE44289061D3D4CA9C2793"><enum>(i)</enum><text>50 percent of the qualified basis of a new building, and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HBAD2CA7456994D35B7D74F2DBF7C055F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>60 percent of the qualified basis of a building not described in clause (i). </text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDAB1FC93807C4BE8BCB42993C67BE7D4"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Method of discounting</header><text>The present value under subparagraph (B) shall be determined—</text> 
<clause id="H36AD98848A0345CA879D7775DD277CC5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>as of the last day of the 1st year of the 15-year period referred to in subparagraph (B),</text></clause> <clause id="HDAE097C2293941068A3D1E089B391AFE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by using a discount rate equal to 72 percent of the average of the annual Federal mid-term rate and the annual Federal long-term rate applicable under section 1274(d)(1) to the month applicable under clause (i) or (ii) of subparagraph (A) and compounded annually, and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H8B19FA700A0B4D6FB7008194527F4868"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by assuming that the credit allowable under this section for any year is received on the last day of such year.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF0612C5294AE49AC92E15345CE566C4A" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Minimum credit rate</header> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HE3BDA31671CA4226AE284E9A8514B5EE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The applicable percentage for any building which is not Federally subsidized for the taxable year shall not be less than 5 percent.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6DCB2D925FAC4829863DC1DD64C5163F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Minimum credit rate for Federally subsidized buildings</header><text>In the case of any building to which subparagraph (A) does not apply, except as provided in paragraph (3), the applicable percentage shall not be less than 2 percent.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0FB3582D0D6B4FE0A6AA5944E0C1E7C6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exception for certain Federally subsidized buildings</header><text>In the case of any building to which paragraph (2)(A) does not apply, the applicable percentage is zero unless—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HADA5DD297B9B4A97A7E0566020F81DEE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a credit is allowed under section 42 with respect to such building for the taxable year, and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H120C5252DBD646ABA5B8C71162696272"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such building is financed by tax-exempt bonds as described in section 42(h)(4).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H91038B857F9B4B21AB3FAFE3D04ABD11"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Cross references</header> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H3414FFEA02CA402794325ABF572A8B27"><enum>(A)</enum><text>For treatment of certain rehabilitation expenditures as separate new buildings, see subsection (e).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H2AE3B011B9994DB891820333BE770C3C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>For determination of applicable percentage for increases in qualified basis after the 1st year of the credit period, see subsection (f)(3).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HC332BBEE6E954297908009F90A380C68"><enum>(C)</enum><text>For authority of housing credit agency to limit applicable percentage and qualified basis which may be taken into account under this section with respect to any building, see subsection (h)(6).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HCE8B62048C9B41E991C97F955F4071AB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Qualified basis; qualified working families building</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text> 
<paragraph id="HB8AE9F6F01DB4389924F87A2AD1AB112"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Qualified basis</header> 
<subparagraph id="H81E592958C9E49D4B18BC041C1A8AFA3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Determination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The qualified basis of any qualified working families building for any taxable year is an amount equal to—</text> <clause id="H708674FA76F14BBA896B9E5DAEA4F895"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the applicable fraction (determined as of the close of such taxable year) of</text></clause> 
<clause id="HD4A5710C3BF247E290B432F838EB56EB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the eligible basis of such building (determined under subsection (d)).</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8084955D235C4D0F9CD758A8955A1473"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Applicable fraction</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A), the term <term>applicable fraction</term> means the smaller of the unit fraction or the floor space fraction.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H916E004AD94D4C85A2931D9272449FD7"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Unit fraction</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (B), the term <term>unit fraction</term> means the fraction—</text> <clause id="HA6FD7D80F85F4B349ACA11AE56F1956B"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the numerator of which is the number of working families units in the building, and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H1C2DB7C278C64BCDBB313D69B26E4795"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the denominator of which is the number of residential rental units (whether or not occupied) in such building.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA2F2FC5C20764F74883EF07D37758030"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Floor space fraction</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (B), the term <term>floor space fraction</term> means the fraction—</text> 
<clause id="H71B8941F1A044A3887DA5D24E5A62D56"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the numerator of which is the total floor space of the working families units in such building, and</text></clause> <clause id="H09E294A736D142EC984A7CEF7F4E3973"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the denominator of which is the total floor space of the residential rental units (whether or not occupied) in such building.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE472FA1CE0354910B12C6D7055A8CFBC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualified working families building</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>qualified working families building</term> means any building which is part of a qualified working families housing project at all times during the period—</text> <subparagraph id="H9E6A9CB2358D47948E1457CF2A83AF8C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>beginning on the 1st day in the credit period on which such building is part of such a project, and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBF6BF9D3BF7748C6B578458DC3EB36B3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ending on the last day of the credit period with respect to such building.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HDD16AC18B68F4D7DB1FBB949F447D6D0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Eligible basis</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text> 
<paragraph id="HA02B50707BE04F31BC7E6F107D679585"><enum>(1)</enum><header>New buildings</header><text>The eligible basis of a new building is its adjusted basis as of the close of the 1st taxable year of the credit period.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H626DA097CE3E44AE857D8B5AE8124F29"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Existing buildings</header> <subparagraph id="HF80932FACE6E44DC9E673ACDEF194E61"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The eligible basis of an existing building is—</text> 
<clause id="HD2572D5C560F4ADA94BC100B699CF8A5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the case of a building which meets the requirements of subparagraph (B), its adjusted basis as of the close of the 1st taxable year of the credit period, and</text></clause> <clause id="H2D8DE6261F144DE0A21E064C7AF4B14D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>zero in any other case.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9355223325E0441CA054C07C7CC971B0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>A building meets the requirements of this subparagraph if—</text> <clause id="H9550FC1C374B46A7A2BA024098E0EE09"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the building is acquired by purchase (as defined in section 179(d)(2)),</text></clause> 
<clause id="HBC596675E05349159A080DCBF501E586"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>there is a period of at least 10 years between the date of its acquisition by the taxpayer and the date the building was last placed in service,</text></clause> <clause id="H9B3CC897780B49AEAAA83505C5DDD048"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the building was not previously placed in service by the taxpayer or by any person who was a related person with respect to the taxpayer as of the time previously placed in service, and</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" id="HE1EDA4D8D26D407283537B0FA01CC3EE"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>except as provided in subsection (f)(5), a credit is allowable under subsection (a) by reason of subsection (e) with respect to the building.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB974AB4DB5E440639E5E4EF584EB3F04"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Adjusted basis</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A), the adjusted basis of any building shall not include so much of the basis of such building as is determined by reference to the basis of other property held at any time by the person acquiring the building.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H882239457FA84D6DB18040FBAB722C75"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Special rules</header> 
<clause id="HCB16AE57675C4FD6BFFAF215633A1653"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Special rules for certain transfers</header><text>For purposes of determining under subparagraph (B)(ii) when a building was last placed in service, there shall not be taken into account any placement in service—</text> <subclause id="H35E54C0EDF404F69847924B41E36D40D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in connection with the acquisition of the building in a transaction in which the basis of the building in the hands of the person acquiring it is determined in whole or in part by reference to the adjusted basis of such building in the hands of the person from whom acquired,</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H440E5D3736BE4AF38369C3D1A11778E4"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by a person whose basis in such building is determined under section 1014(a) (relating to property acquired from a decedent),</text></subclause> <subclause id="H821893AB7ED54139A05B611BF40B020E"><enum>(III)</enum><text>by any governmental unit or qualified nonprofit organization if the requirements of subparagraph (B)(ii) are met with respect to the placement in service by such unit or organization and all the income from such property is exempt from Federal income taxation,</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H3656CF0ADE354E959239A10C8F2EADBF"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>by any person who acquired such building by foreclosure (or by instrument in lieu of foreclosure) of any purchase-money security interest held by such person if the requirements of subparagraph (B)(ii) are met with respect to the placement in service by such person and such building is resold within 12 months after the date such building is placed in service by such person after such foreclosure, or</text></subclause> <subclause id="H31F92CB101FB42AF85E879722CD442FE"><enum>(V)</enum><text>of a single-family residence by any individual who owned and used such residence for no other purpose than as his principal residence.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H02AD77C726D048C780F8C0B00C8A1B89"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Related person</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (B)(iii), a person (hereinafter in this subclause referred to as the <term>related person</term>) is related to any person if the related person bears a relationship to such person specified in section 267(b) or 707(b)(1), or the related person and such person are engaged in trades or businesses under common control (within the meaning of subsections (a) and (b) of section 52).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3C267AFF684549419BCC5ED9AEB0B5AC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Special rules relating to determination of adjusted basis</header><text>For purposes of this subsection—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H6EC9FE8225F14A12B272AE3C450EE6B5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the adjusted basis of any building shall be determined without regard to the adjusted basis of any property which is not residential rental property.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD63607E9AF064FBB85DCE6B799D717A1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Basis of property in common areas, etc., included</header> <clause id="H27DB7B2A224C4384B890F7089D57BA7A"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in clause (ii), the adjusted basis of any building shall be determined by taking into account the adjusted basis of property (of a character subject to the allowance for depreciation) used in common areas or provided as comparable amenities to all residential rental units in such building.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H31098930DFD147EE80BD29706F903FFF"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Special rule</header><text>In the case of any building for which the low-income housing tax credit is allowable under section 42, the adjusted basis of the building under this section shall be determined without regard to property used in common areas or provided as comparable amenities to all residential rental units in such building.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H5C2072FAAF494EF8A4D12137D09EF07C"><enum>(C)</enum><header>No reduction for depreciation</header><text>The adjusted basis of any building shall be determined without regard to paragraphs (2) and (3) of section 1016(a).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFAF9E2AD81BD404B9987456275792DD2"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Special rules for determining eligible basis</header> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC60768796B124B84996DAFAF1762AF8E"><enum>(A)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Federal grants not taken into account in determining eligible basis</header><text>The eligible basis of a building shall not include any costs financed with the proceeds of a Federally funded grant. </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAAA13EB619C148538F2F83447782AA0D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Increase in credit for buildings in high cost areas</header> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1A27BB25E84B4E6686B8105811C622C7"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of any building located in a difficult development area which is designated for purposes of this subparagraph—</text> 
<subclause id="HE163DCB901BA4A7EA8F8E935A95717E9"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in the case of a new building, the eligible basis of such building shall be 130 percent of such basis determined without regard to this subparagraph, and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H570A5444057648B795B2C22035EDF65C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in the case of an existing building, the rehabilitation expenditures taken into account under subsection (e) shall be 130 percent of such expenditures determined without regard to this subparagraph.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4778753460394C8795FFF110E2D4A1A2"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Clause (i) shall not apply to any building if paragraph (1) of subsection (h) does not apply to any portion of the eligible basis of such building by reason of paragraph (9) of such subsection.</text></clause> <clause id="H840A4B5002B5418692A1A2BD19F86CE4" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Difficult development areas</header> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCD33484A45714D22AFE2BDE28D6DAA50"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>difficult development areas</term> means any area designated by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development as an area which has high construction, land, or utility costs relative to area median gross income, any rural area, and any Indian area.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H298857D096244915B5C7135F7653C8D4"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Rural area</header><text>For purposes of subclause (I), the term <term>rural area</term> means any non-metropolitan area, or any rural area as defined by section 520 of the Housing Act of 1949, which is identified by the qualified allocation plan under subsection (m)(1)(B). </text></subclause> <subclause id="H8775B24CDFAB4B9CA7E270AFB5EC7F65"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Indian area</header><text>For purposes of subclause (I), the term <term>Indian area</term> means any Indian area (as defined in section 4(11) of the Native American Housing Assistance and Self Determination Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/4103">25 U.S.C. 4103(11)</external-xref>)).</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H0A4AE9F23CBC4FC68DBF11003DD0DAB8"><enum>(IV)</enum><header>Special rule for buildings in Indian areas</header><text>In the case of an area which is a difficult development area solely because it is an Indian area, a building shall not be treated as located in such area unless such building is assisted or financed under the Native American Housing Assistance and Self Determination Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/4101">25 U.S.C. 4101 et seq.</external-xref>) or the project sponsor is an Indian tribe (as defined in section 45A(c)(6)), a tribally designated housing entity (as defined in section 4(22) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/4103">25 U.S.C. 4103(22)</external-xref>)), or wholly owned or controlled by such an Indian tribe or tribally designated housing entity.</text></subclause> <subclause id="HF19CB425010148269B8534CD75F7F38A" commented="no"><enum>(V)</enum><header>Limit on areas designated</header><text>The portions of metropolitan statistical areas which may be designated for purposes of this subparagraph shall not exceed an aggregate area having 20 percent of the population of such metropolitan statistical areas. A comparable rule shall apply to nonmetropolitan areas.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H1BDE8424488A4ED093E8D6C8EB11A862" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Special rules and definitions</header><text>For purposes of this subparagraph—</text> <subclause id="HC2E9333188F340FA9D4FE74A3CEFD0FF" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>population shall be determined on the basis of the most recent decennial census for which data are available,</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HA9F36B16473345A78B0F840CC874DA99" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>area median gross income shall be determined in accordance with subsection (g)(4),</text></subclause> <subclause id="HC9C7297080C24BA697C65E5F31A34486" commented="no"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the term <term>metropolitan statistical area</term> has the same meaning as when used in section 143(k)(2)(B), and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H70CECA892C01455FB268850244C8DA41" commented="no"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the term <term>nonmetropolitan area</term> means any county (or portion thereof) which is not within a metropolitan statistical area.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HD480DC150E8041128F9C04F470B9CBA3" commented="no"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Buildings designated by State Housing Credit Agency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any building which is designated by the State housing credit agency as requiring the increase in credit under this subparagraph in order for such building to be financially feasible as part of a qualified working families housing project shall be treated for purposes of this subparagraph as located in a difficult development area which is designated for purposes of this subparagraph. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="HBD339AB3E705446EAF8EAAC901419DD6"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Credit allowable for certain buildings acquired during 10-year period</header><text>On application by the taxpayer, the Secretary may waive paragraph (2)(B)(ii) with respect to any building acquired from an insured depository institution in default (as defined in section 3 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act) or from a receiver or conservator of such an institution.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H9C2F4BF2E6ED41818F450C0F0FD10D75"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Acquisition of building before end of prior credit period</header> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H2B63B23BC4B14A1F87DFA4BD77D4E269"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, in the case of a building described in subparagraph (B) (or interest therein) which is acquired by the taxpayer—</text> 
<clause commented="no" id="H3A7D09AC59EB4D1A8F26E19C70074F88"><enum>(i)</enum><text>paragraph (2)(B) shall not apply, but</text></clause> <clause commented="no" id="HCBAEC89DC25E4520A3C50DA8FD2EF3DC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the credit allowable by reason of subsection (a) to the taxpayer for any period after such acquisition shall be equal to the amount of credit which would have been allowable under subsection (a) for such period to the prior owner referred to in subparagraph (B) had such owner not disposed of the building.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HFC99EDEA86F748E28A3A3742BC96E5B0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Description of building</header><text>A building is described in this subparagraph if—</text> <clause commented="no" id="H66D4CE7E347245DAA71AC6795BB74CD6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a credit was allowed by reason of subsection (a) to any prior owner of such building, and</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" id="H38273E8D107846B9ACA92E323209B9C3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the taxpayer acquired such building before the end of the credit period for such building with respect to such prior owner (determined without regard to any disposition by such prior owner).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H6B1223D48B2D49BBA0E6CFC100E5A0FA"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Rehabilitation expenditures treated as separate new building</header> <paragraph id="HC5AD85D8B75D48B1BD7DA3DB218D959E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Rehabilitation expenditures paid or incurred by the taxpayer with respect to any building shall be treated for purposes of this section as a separate building which is not a new building.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1F30678D18B54F1DB0C1B53C0C9E403F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rehabilitation expenditures</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (1)—</text> <subparagraph id="H335E13B1066A49A7AF9018B1311D0BC8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>rehabilitation expenditures</term> means amounts chargeable to capital account and incurred for property (or additions or improvements to property) of a character subject to the allowance for depreciation in connection with the rehabilitation of a building.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBD1B221006C841C084DD7C3A3FBC3A5F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Cost of acquisition, etc., not included</header><text>Such term does not include the cost of acquiring any building (or interest therein) or any amount not permitted to be taken into account under paragraph (3) of subsection (d).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H30DDA3F62F744A82B90658DB6BDB90C5"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Certain relocation costs</header><text>In the case of a rehabilitation of a building to which section 280B does not apply, costs relating to the relocation of occupants, including—</text> 
<clause id="H13563836C72745ED9D80C37EAAB16BAE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>amounts paid to occupants,</text></clause> <clause id="HCCFCD507F0C14675841E417F36208680"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>amounts paid to third parties for services relating to such relocation, and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HFBEF011DA8E44F0C912B3E9CB83259E6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>amounts paid for temporary housing for occupants,</text></clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">shall be treated as chargeable to capital account and taken into account as rehabilitation expenditures.</continuation-text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1E1E558C789348FCA8B55B1AA8E042EA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Minimum expenditures to qualify</header> <subparagraph id="H8AA79CC9C8744172B593DEDB21F5E18D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Paragraph (1) shall apply to rehabilitation expenditures with respect to any building only if—</text> 
<clause id="H5B33D5DE95BD4E69B51953CFC2D8CF4A"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the expenditures are allocable to 1 or more working families units or substantially benefit such units, and</text></clause> <clause id="HA5E9C49ED2EA469394E486FFA0C3BF34"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the amount of such expenditures during any 24-month period meets the requirements of whichever of the following subclauses requires the greater amount of such expenditures:</text> 
<subclause id="HA92E1344DEE54EFEA9B8AD7EF3E8C978"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The requirement of this subclause is met if such amount is not less than 20 percent of the adjusted basis of the building (determined as of the 1st day of such period and without regard to paragraphs (2) and (3) of section 1016(a)).</text></subclause> <subclause id="H7B8636A936D94FABBC47110717A31550"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The requirement of this subclause is met if the qualified basis attributable to such amount, when divided by the number of working families units in the building, is equal to or greater than the dollar amount in effect under section 42(e)(3)(A)(ii)(II) for the calendar year in which such expenditures are treated as placed in service under paragraph (4).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEE580A564A224C7D8729C372BAE2132D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Date of determination</header><text>The determination under subparagraph (A) shall be made as of the close of the 1st taxable year in the credit period with respect to such expenditures.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9F8BA8A9B82040CFBC5770A1AA0511FA"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Special rules</header><text>For purposes of applying this section with respect to expenditures which are treated as a separate building by reason of this subsection—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H1F674102FD49429FA6185DA61B48E1A9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such expenditures shall be treated as placed in service at the close of the 24-month period referred to in paragraph (3)(A), and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H60E5CD5C19074B4DBADDF254E168112B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the applicable fraction under subsection (c)(1) shall be the applicable fraction for the building (without regard to paragraph (1)) with respect to which the expenditures were incurred.</text></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">Nothing in subsection (d)(2) shall prevent a credit from being allowed by reason of this subsection.</continuation-text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB3A548F620544D97B46A92FD41A6C80F"><enum>(5)</enum><header>No double counting</header><text>Rehabilitation expenditures may, at the election of the taxpayer, be taken into account under this subsection or subsection (d)(2)(A)(i) but not under both such subsections.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H427A8774E83C4DEA94952AE70AC6B21E"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Regulations to apply subsection with respect to group of units in building</header><text>The Secretary may prescribe regulations, consistent with the purposes of this subsection, treating a group of units with respect to which rehabilitation expenditures are incurred as a separate new building.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4118725E25594C87AE96BF54454AFA62"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definition and special rules relating to credit period</header> 
<paragraph id="H23EA5EB0D46F4D8CA9D322AF58103F3C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Credit period defined</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>credit period</term> means, with respect to any building, the period of 15 taxable years beginning with—</text> <subparagraph id="H30A9B18880F9451CB970BAE7A02B4156"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the taxable year in which the building is placed in service, or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H987DD8A3637A4AD6B6953D87EA751E1C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>at the election of the taxpayer, the succeeding taxable year,</text></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">but only if the building is a qualified working families building as of the close of the 1st year of such period. The election under subparagraph (B), once made, shall be irrevocable.</continuation-text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA2F32E368F6149808502DAD8943AF046"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Special rule for 1st year of credit period</header> <subparagraph id="H753459C81BA4478692D74C4CA34AF8D0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The credit allowable under subsection (a) with respect to any building for the 1st taxable year of the credit period shall be determined by substituting for the applicable fraction under subsection (c)(1) the fraction—</text> 
<clause id="H0FA0FEB7372246069FEFC8BD2F464F7B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the numerator of which is the sum of the applicable fractions determined under subsection (c)(1) as of the close of each full month of such year during which such building was in service, and</text></clause> <clause id="H9996186EF0994975BBDBED773A968028"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the denominator of which is 12.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5BC4D994B4A64C8FA98419F1D9A52578"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Disallowed 1st-year credit allowed in 16th year</header><text>Any reduction by reason of subparagraph (A) in the credit allowable (without regard to subparagraph (A)) for the 1st taxable year of the credit period shall be allowable under subsection (a) for the 1st taxable year following the credit period.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="HE0092A0ACF3A4DDE9ECDBD00422D22C5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Determination of applicable percentage with respect to increases in qualified basis after 1st year of credit period</header> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H6F864850B0A24B1483189339F8F3F6FD"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any building which was a qualified working families building as of the close of the 1st year of the credit period, if—</text> 
<clause commented="no" id="H5908AFACC33E4980A8857525A7E961E7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>as of the close of any taxable year in the credit period (after the 1st year of such period) the qualified basis of such building, exceeds</text></clause> <clause commented="no" id="H8254D7E838D247E289388DE5261EA9C2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the qualified basis of such building as of the close of the 1st year of the credit period,</text></clause><continuation-text commented="no" continuation-text-level="subparagraph">the applicable percentage which shall apply under subsection (a) for the taxable year to such excess shall be the percentage equal to <fraction>2/3</fraction> of the applicable percentage which (after the application of subsection (h)) would but for this paragraph apply to such basis.</continuation-text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H06207B520465433CB820C0D59EB234A9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>1st year computation applies</header><text>A rule similar to the rule of paragraph (2)(A) shall apply to any increase in qualified basis to which subparagraph (A) applies for the 1st year of such increase.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD53D67E547554D828C3478892518A881"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Dispositions of property</header><text>If a building (or an interest therein) is disposed of during any year for which credit is allowable under subsection (a), such credit shall be allocated between the parties on the basis of the number of days during such year the building (or interest) was held by each.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4B20A8EDCAE14CE2BE45B92F70C82252"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Credit period for existing buildings not to begin before rehabilitation credit allowed</header> 
<subparagraph id="HC863F8A166E94893A0EC63C173109143"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The credit period for an existing building shall not begin before the 1st taxable year of the credit period for rehabilitation expenditures with respect to the building.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7F500B71F348437EAAD6C3C1EC424A8E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Acquisition credit allowed for certain buildings not allowed a rehabilitation credit</header> <clause id="HCA0099FE855C4CB69230950507C48728"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of a building described in clause (ii)—</text> 
<subclause id="HAC04B1815148419A93AEAE88DC5148A4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>subsection (d)(2)(B)(iv) shall not apply, and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H9555E35673C046FFA208594346D053EC"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the credit period for such building shall not begin before the taxable year which would be the 1st taxable year of the credit period for rehabilitation expenditures with respect to the building under the modifications described in clause (ii)(II).</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H4A3DCE836E2C4CA1BFC5E2C222418754"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Building described</header><text>A building is described in this clause if—</text> <subclause id="HEC55F3D586944E7C8E927EC615CA4B4F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a waiver is granted under subsection (d)(4) with respect to the acquisition of the building, and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H44260C64A88B4EE192C1DC0BCAB21E10"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a credit would be allowed for rehabilitation expenditures with respect to such building if subsection (e)(3)(A)(ii)(I) did not apply and if the dollar amount in effect under subsection (e)(3)(A)(ii)(II) were two-thirds of such amount.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HA64C8D6889724B0384B6E4E292CC8FEB"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Qualified working families housing project</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text> 
<paragraph id="H3D15094FC90845E685B8F31B762FC9F5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Qualified working families housing project</header> 
<subparagraph id="HF4F426BC391042E7B5449F01D9E82300"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>qualified working families housing project</term> means any project for residential rental property if such project meets the low-income requirements of subparagraph (B) and the working families requirements of subparagraph (C).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCF5937A72BA14BB5A29083DA51D50FA4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Low-income requirements</header><text>The project meets the low-income requirements of this subparagraph if 20 percent or more of the residential units in such project are both rent-restricted and occupied by individuals whose income is 60 percent or less of area median gross income.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4B13BFED98BE4E7CBE313610C385F690"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Working families requirements</header> 
<clause id="H7AE1ABE532A74C89B676F96BEE632A37"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The project meets the working families requirements of this subparagraph if 40 percent or more of the residential units in such project are both rent-restricted and occupied by individuals whose income does not exceed the imputed income limitation designated by the taxpayer with respect to the respective unit.</text></clause> <clause id="H9A56063C51024694A5A3D6C6BCC42DF4"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Special Rules Relating to Income Limitation</header><text>For purposes of clause (i)—</text> 
<subclause id="HB63A2295AFE04D7CAF890224AA10E026"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Designation</header><text>The taxpayer shall designate the imputed income limitation of each unit taken into account under such clause. </text></subclause> <subclause id="HC1377FC02D054DF3A2DFEE5AA52B9E14"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Average test</header><text>The average of the imputed income limitations designated under subclause (I) shall not exceed 100 percent of area median gross income. </text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H57DEA9313D804036A62AD6C197744E90"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Permitted increments</header><text>The designated imputed income limitation of any unit under subclause (I) shall be 70, 80, 90, 100, 110, 120, 130, 140, 150, 160, 170, or 180 percent of area median gross income.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">Any designation under this paragraph, once made, shall be irrevocable. For purposes of this paragraph, any property shall not be treated as failing to be residential rental property merely because part of the building in which such property is located is used for purposes other than residential rental purposes.</continuation-text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF398A8E9E89E450295BA78A9862BD2E6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rent-restricted units</header> <subparagraph id="HAFB2E655328A463A91226730AC1EA433"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of paragraph (1), a residential unit is rent-restricted if the gross rent with respect to such unit does not exceed 30 percent of the imputed income limitation applicable to such unit. For purposes of the preceding sentence, the amount of the income limitation under paragraph (1) applicable for any period shall not be less than such limitation applicable for the earliest period the building (which contains the unit) was included in the determination of whether the project is a qualified working families housing project.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF04034E53E874054AA130B0ADC18DC2E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Gross rent</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A), gross rent—</text> <clause commented="no" id="HFE9BC415C4A243F998E993ED182CBE25"><enum>(i)</enum><text>includes any utility allowance determined by the Secretary after taking into account such determinations under section 8 of the United States Housing Act of 1937,</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" id="HEB30B40578A24B30A755AB3975889152"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not include any fee for a supportive service which is paid to the owner of the unit (on the basis of the working families status of the tenant of the unit) by any governmental program of assistance (or by an organization described in section 501(c)(3) and exempt from tax under section 501(a)) if such program (or organization) provides assistance for rent and the amount of assistance provided for rent is not separable from the amount of assistance provided for supportive services, and</text></clause> <clause id="HFE292D295DC44F5CB2679C136366C7D1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>does not include any rental payment to the owner of the unit to the extent such owner pays an equivalent amount to the Farmers' Home Administration under section 515 of the Housing Act of 1949.</text></clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">For purposes of clause (ii), the term <term>supportive service</term> means any service provided under a planned program of services designed to enable residents of a residential rental property to remain independent and avoid placement in a hospital, nursing home, or intermediate care facility for the mentally or physically handicapped.</continuation-text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H777EC5F424934BEF8328BDC422921632"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Imputed income limitation applicable to unit</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the imputed income limitation applicable to a unit is the income limitation which would apply under paragraph (1) to individuals occupying the unit if the number of individuals occupying the unit were as follows:</text> <clause id="HFAB739118D244731B06F42818EF35819"><enum>(i)</enum><text>In the case of a unit which does not have a separate bedroom, 1 individual.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA1369C45C6AF48758272F1DC022F54E3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>In the case of a unit which has 1 or more separate bedrooms, 1.5 individuals for each separate bedroom.</text></clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">In the case of a project with respect to which a credit is allowable by reason of this section and for which financing is provided by a bond described in section 142(a)(7), the imputed income limitation shall apply in lieu of the otherwise applicable income limitation for purposes of applying section 142(d)(4)(B)(ii). </continuation-text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H842419605F4248F5B400FD4D8A76D7D4"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Treatment of units occupied by individuals whose incomes rise above limit</header> <clause id="H77C2AFFBB51D4BD0B3C40D1155A3D49A"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in clause (ii), notwithstanding an increase in the income of the occupants of a working families unit above the income limitation applicable under paragraph (1), such unit shall continue to be treated as a working families unit if the income of such occupants initially met such income limitation and such unit continues to be rent-restricted.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H0D95C6110F5547B0AFCA0EF911F87E5F"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Next available unit must be rented to working families tenant if income rises above 140 percent of income limit</header><text>If the income of the occupants of the unit increases above 140 percent of the income limitation applicable under paragraph (1), clause (i) shall cease to apply to such unit if any residential rental unit in the building (of a size comparable to, or smaller than, such unit) is occupied by a new resident whose income exceeds such income limitation.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H602A42DCEE7D4FE69A825E7087EB3CA0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Date for meeting requirements</header> <subparagraph id="H620776838D0646C1AB910DF89BBFFEB4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as otherwise provided in this paragraph, a building shall be treated as a qualified working families building only if the project (of which such building is a part) meets the requirements of paragraph (1) not later than the close of the 1st year of the credit period for such building.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H86EC07DD59874E8BA11E3441DC7E7010"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Buildings which rely on later buildings for qualification</header> 
<clause id="H121A0019CD1D46B2A47B7793D5AA6180"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In determining whether a building (hereinafter in this subparagraph referred to as the <quote>prior building</quote>) is a qualified working families building, the taxpayer may take into account 1 or more additional buildings placed in service during the 12-month period described in subparagraph (A) with respect to the prior building only if the taxpayer elects to apply clause (ii) with respect to each additional building taken into account.</text></clause> <clause id="H3122B231F9E94B37B274A3C7467CB805"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Treatment of elected buildings</header><text>In the case of a building which the taxpayer elects to take into account under clause (i), the period under subparagraph (A) for such building shall end at the close of the 12-month period applicable to the prior building.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H3752D03D968B4202BA7BFB7E6370F4FE"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Date prior building is treated as placed in service</header><text>For purposes of determining the credit period for the prior building, the prior building shall be treated for purposes of this section as placed in service on the most recent date any additional building elected by the taxpayer (with respect to such prior building) was placed in service.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE0582F0690174619A6BFB79E68CEAB20"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Special rule</header><text>A building—</text> 
<clause id="H087845DDDA3B4726A06F9B6F3BC434A7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>other than the 1st building placed in service as part of a project, and</text></clause> <clause id="HFB8628285326405A8D2B625CF6AB5173"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">other than a building which is placed in service during the 12-month period described in subparagraph (A) with respect to a prior building which becomes a qualified working families building,</text></clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">shall in no event be treated as a qualified working families building unless the project is a qualified working families housing project (without regard to such building) on the date such building is placed in service.</continuation-text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBEA880CA74BA41108EC47D16B1F58A55"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Projects with more than 1 building must be identified</header><text>For purposes of this section, a project shall be treated as consisting of only 1 building unless, before the close of the 1st calendar year in the project period (as defined in subsection (h)(1)(F)(ii)), each building which is (or will be) part of such project is identified in such form and manner as the Secretary may provide.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H250A8597FFCF4716A55DAD9A34DC90F7"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Certain rules made applicable</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraphs (2) (other than subparagraph (A) thereof), (3), and (7) of section 142(d), and section 6652(j), shall apply for purposes of determining whether any project is a qualified working families housing project and whether any unit is a working families unit; except that, in applying such provisions for such purposes—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HFDE45BE736144519AFB1758960BB339D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the term <term>gross rent</term> shall have the meaning given such term by paragraph (2)(B) of this subsection, and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H4AB4AB51CC114CB0A277FB0B37D8D6C3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the term <term>applicable income limit</term> means the limitation under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H22E5DCB1165D4FE6887DF8A7AF71A70D"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Election to treat building after credit period as not part of a project</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the taxpayer may elect to treat any building as not part of a qualified working families housing project for any period beginning after the credit period for such building.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF2B6443456BC40A897AAE2A6C6AA97A3"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Special rule where de minimis equity contribution</header><text>Property shall not be treated as failing to be residential rental property for purposes of this section merely because the occupant of a residential unit in the project pays (on a voluntary basis) to the lessor a de minimis amount to be held toward the purchase by such occupant of a residential unit in such project if—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HDBE1E743C20246258FA305AA35AF8ECC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>all amounts so paid are refunded to the occupant on the cessation of his occupancy of a unit in the project, and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H98E4AC8DBC604E9689A40BCA001D3FF3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the purchase of the unit is not permitted until after the close of the credit period with respect to the building in which the unit is located.</text></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">Any amount paid to the lessor as described in the preceding sentence shall be included in gross rent under paragraph (2) for purposes of determining whether the unit is rent-restricted.</continuation-text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H231B7AECB18C41E0A00B1E92BB3D44F1"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Scattered site projects</header><text>Buildings which would (but for their lack of proximity) be treated as a project for purposes of this section shall be so treated if all of the dwelling units in each of the buildings are rent-restricted (within the meaning of paragraph (2)) residential rental units.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H180E9598A40F4812BAD46450AEF0012E"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Waiver of certain recertifications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On application by the taxpayer, the Secretary may waive any annual recertification of tenant income for purposes of this subsection, if the entire building is occupied by working families tenants.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H931C939B4BCF44F2950BBB90213FA333"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Clarification of general public use requirement</header><text>A project does not fail to meet the general public use requirement solely because of occupancy restrictions or preferences that favor tenants—</text> <subparagraph id="H7D0FFEDA90FF4D0FB98F57C683B66E8B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>with special needs, or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H27991DFC959F494089C2D57176C0E448"><enum>(B)</enum><text>who are members of a specified group under a Federal program or State program or policy that supports housing for such a specified group.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6141A1FBD3F0467C92529780902288D5"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Prevailing wage requirements</header><text>No credit shall be determined under this section with respect to any building (including any rehabilitation expenditures treated as a separate building under subsection (e)) unless such building meets requirements similar the requirements described in section 45(b)(7).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H042C0832526946B7BD19D5B8FA8373AC"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Limitation on aggregate credit allowable with respect to projects located in a State</header> 
<paragraph id="HD8DE5B6FEEF54B028B74E80E71A30A5C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Credit may not exceed credit amount allocated to building</header> 
<subparagraph id="H161E94F875A74145B18AE2C77353A76E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The amount of the credit determined under this section for any taxable year with respect to any building shall not exceed the housing credit dollar amount allocated to such building under this subsection.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3D33365BA8534EF998D97016EFA5A8DE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Time for making allocation</header><text>Except in the case of an allocation which meets the requirements of subparagraph (C), (D), (E), or (F), an allocation shall be taken into account under subparagraph (A) only if it is made not later than the close of the calendar year in which the building is placed in service.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE99F641342F04C7A814F85EF4935C596"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Exception where binding commitment</header><text>An allocation meets the requirements of this subparagraph if there is a binding commitment (not later than the close of the calendar year in which the building is placed in service) by the housing credit agency to allocate a specified housing credit dollar amount to such building beginning in a specified later taxable year.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H17182FDEBCA24184856EDD6D97DCB2A8"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Exception where increase in qualified basis</header> <clause id="HD5DACA3787A941B6A32D64E2B3F8131E"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An allocation meets the requirements of this subparagraph if such allocation is made not later than the close of the calendar year in which ends the taxable year to which it will 1st apply but only to the extent the amount of such allocation does not exceed the limitation under clause (ii).</text></clause> 
<clause id="H7E7C3C2DA9124BACA489BF14A9E20FDD"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The limitation under this clause is the amount of credit allowable under this section (without regard to this subsection) for a taxable year with respect to an increase in the qualified basis of the building equal to the excess of—</text> <subclause id="H7C02C339291F4FD1BE7C3C1CA3CE000F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the qualified basis of such building as of the close of the 1st taxable year to which such allocation will apply, over</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H81753FC081D141C895DD99FB6D4F7722"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the qualified basis of such building as of the close of the 1st taxable year to which the most recent prior housing credit allocation with respect to such building applied.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HECD0DF8E1D784FDE9B34E323306F5093"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Housing credit dollar amount reduced by full allocation</header><text>Notwithstanding clause (i), the full amount of the allocation shall be taken into account under paragraph (2).</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H02659C0217F646AA8BA2AB5A9598299C"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Exception where 10 percent of cost incurred</header> 
<clause id="H116A5C06F7444C8DAAA4457325304ABD"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An allocation meets the requirements of this subparagraph if such allocation is made with respect to a qualified building which is placed in service not later than the close of the second calendar year following the calendar year in which the allocation is made.</text></clause> <clause id="H25D6188B68954612A7CE116303B9EBD7"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Qualified building</header><text>For purposes of clause (i), the term <term>qualified building</term> means any building which is part of a project if the taxpayer's basis in such project (as of the date which is 1 year after the date that the allocation was made) is more than 10 percent of the taxpayer's reasonably expected basis in such project (as of the close of the second calendar year referred to in clause (i)). Such term does not include any existing building unless a credit is allowable under subsection (e) for rehabilitation expenditures paid or incurred by the taxpayer with respect to such building for a taxable year ending during the second calendar year referred to in clause (i) or the prior taxable year.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4AF75E153A5147D3B0EE6C768B892B4F"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Allocation of credit on a project basis</header> 
<clause id="H76B3DCE543F24522944B8BA68EF1B338"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of a project which includes (or will include) more than 1 building, an allocation meets the requirements of this subparagraph if—</text> <subclause id="HD785F6F6866F466B915F83B577C84422"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the allocation is made to the project for a calendar year during the project period,</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H420C2768C0674195A6E0A875ECF667CC"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the allocation only applies to buildings placed in service during or after the calendar year for which the allocation is made, and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H380E1B9530624039A9559E22E4F9F604"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the portion of such allocation which is allocated to any building in such project is specified not later than the close of the calendar year in which the building is placed in service.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H4293899E6A0C44F7B10DB7F026296B00"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Project period</header><text>For purposes of clause (i), the term <term>project period</term> means the period—</text> <subclause id="HF747A187347F4F1F8306250838102317"><enum>(I)</enum><text>beginning with the 1st calendar year for which an allocation may be made for the 1st building placed in service as part of such project, and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HDED827A57E4147D6B22889391797BAFC"><enum>(II)</enum><text>ending with the calendar year the last building is placed in service as part of such project.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H071015ED6B414683A6073664F6E8F45B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Allocated credit amount to apply to all taxable years ending during or after credit allocation year</header><text>Any housing credit dollar amount allocated to any building for any calendar year—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H07A51AA631C3420FAE850B5690BFB61E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall apply to such building for all taxable years in the credit period ending during or after such calendar year, and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEB150984E50040F085CAFF804219196F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall reduce the aggregate housing credit dollar amount of the allocating agency only for such calendar year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6B86C1BD94614D40B001AEF92985D028"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Housing credit dollar amount for agencies</header> 
<subparagraph id="H96C920FA24844F42944F1F0192B0F35B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The aggregate housing credit dollar amount which a housing credit agency may allocate for any calendar year is the portion of the State housing credit ceiling allocated under this paragraph for such calendar year to such agency.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE44CF33C2CDD44E393492CB8ED1C86CB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>State ceiling initially allocated to State housing credit agencies</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (D), the State housing credit ceiling for each calendar year shall be allocated to the housing credit agency of such State. If there is more than 1 housing credit agency of a State, all such agencies shall be treated as a single agency.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H27CD422CD3F740D8B9E1F78AB8AB42FE"><enum>(C)</enum><header>State housing credit ceiling</header><text>The State housing credit ceiling applicable to any State for any calendar year shall be an amount equal to the sum of—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H13F827A4A3DF48179042B5EE8C5C5FE1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the unused State housing credit ceiling (if any) of such State for the preceding calendar year,</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA277F277D200476FA21DD0118BC824B1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the greater of—</text> <subclause id="H3E1DF743DA1B4D30A7E856B3F5656969"><enum>(I)</enum><text>$1.00 multiplied by the State population, or</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H5E4056BBCD62451CAB260F99652BA686"><enum>(II)</enum><text>$1,500,000, plus</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H4E9B49B288014AB89E32A703C4F3D9D4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the amount of State housing credit ceiling returned in the calendar year.</text></clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">For purposes of clause (i), the unused State housing credit ceiling for any calendar year is the excess (if any) of the sum of the amounts described in clauses (ii) (reduced by the aggregate amounts described in paragraph (10)(A)(i) with respect to all elections made for such calendar year) and (iii) over the aggregate housing credit dollar amount allocated for such year. For purposes of clause (iii), the amount of State housing credit ceiling returned in the calendar year equals the housing credit dollar amount previously allocated within the State to any project which fails to meet the 10 percent test under paragraph (1)(E)(ii) on a date after the close of the calendar year in which the allocation was made or which does not become a qualified working families housing project within the period required by this section or the terms of the allocation or to any project with respect to which an allocation is cancelled by mutual consent of the housing credit agency and the allocation recipient.</continuation-text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1A23ABE254C941D1942B0879E1318603"><enum>(D)</enum><header>State may provide for different allocation</header><text>Rules similar to the rules of section 146(e) (other than paragraph (2)(B) thereof) shall apply for purposes of this paragraph.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H18ED8F6F043C461C92AF8C0BC2D6F8C9"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Population</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, population shall be determined in accordance with section 146(j).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H51926AD334194B31AA816F17773E8E24"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Cost-of-living adjustment</header> 
<clause id="HED3E3062FAF1493EA9161589A1E2FA42" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of a calendar year after 2026, the $1,500,000 and $1.00 amounts in subparagraph (C) shall each be increased by an amount equal to—</text> <subclause id="H2B06363C71C2490EBBCA145B907F066D" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>such dollar amount, multiplied by</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HE2377B14FB814C32938C76307276AEB9" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the cost-of-living adjustment determined under section 1(f)(3) for such calendar year by substituting <quote>calendar year 2025</quote> for <quote>calendar year 2016</quote> in subparagraph (A)(ii) thereof.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H0AAAEC07C61248298624942E4B456464"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Rounding</header> <subclause id="HE7FA6A5F5B9448CB87267C3596E54528"><enum>(I)</enum><text>In the case of the $1,140,000 amount, any increase under clause (i) which is not a multiple of $5,000 shall be rounded to the next lowest multiple of $5,000.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H0108EADF53624A82930E15307D1C0F1E"><enum>(II)</enum><text>In the case of the $1.00 amount, any increase under clause (i) which is not a multiple of 5 cents shall be rounded to the next lowest multiple of 5 cents.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H755DD33F8C884385AB3511B375AD3918"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Portion of State ceiling set-aside for certain projects involving qualified nonprofit organizations</header> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H638215C72113406393B6C435F3120F5D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not more than 90 percent of the State housing credit ceiling (determined without regard to paragraph (7)) for any State for any calendar year shall be allocated to projects other than qualified working families housing projects described in subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H4412CE794EEB417B894F304452D0CBFE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Projects involving qualified nonprofit organizations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of subparagraph (A), a qualified working families housing project is described in this subparagraph if a qualified nonprofit organization is to own an interest in the project (directly or through a partnership) and materially participate (within the meaning of section 469(h)) in the development and operation of the project throughout the credit period.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HBDD4B07B1D5A43F59395B39728EC961D"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Qualified nonprofit organization</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>qualified nonprofit organization</term> means any organization if—</text> 
<clause commented="no" id="H30340CEC074E413E980DE43443697213"><enum>(i)</enum><text>such organization is described in paragraph (3) or (4) of section 501(c) and is exempt from tax under section 501(a),</text></clause> <clause commented="no" id="H2F530F360DBD4533B97570684C292CB6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>such organization is determined by the State housing credit agency not to be affiliated with or controlled by a for-profit organization, and</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" id="HD72735676E354C79A7C3487683E7000C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">one of the exempt purposes of such organization includes the fostering of working families housing.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H78F68D5160854E82A9B33C7AA9CAB093"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Treatment of certain subsidiaries</header> <clause commented="no" id="HD8B6187C97CF4A69BB2D349A63545524"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, a qualified nonprofit organization shall be treated as satisfying the ownership and material participation test of subparagraph (B) if any qualified corporation in which such organization holds stock satisfies such test.</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" id="HFD38601251414640AC0F173EBEF51B3D"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Qualified corporation</header><text>For purposes of clause (i), the term <term>qualified corporation</term> means any corporation if 100 percent of the stock of such corporation is held by 1 or more qualified nonprofit organizations at all times during the period such corporation is in existence.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H5CF32BD5221A4D0F94CB4657E35A77CC"><enum>(E)</enum><header>State may not override set-aside</header><text>Nothing in subparagraph (E) of paragraph (3) shall be construed to permit a State not to comply with subparagraph (A) of this paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H7D1CEE8C7B764EBAA871707BBA265618"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Buildings eligible for credit only if minimum long-term commitment to working families housing</header> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H8EB2A2F2A6A941E88785665D2F443CBA"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No credit shall be allowed by reason of this section with respect to any building for the taxable year unless an extended working families housing commitment is in effect as of the end of such taxable year.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H4D4D9CF6F1494219A5E75BA885DDC481"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Extended working families housing commitment</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>extended working families housing commitment</term> means any agreement between the taxpayer and the housing credit agency—</text> 
<clause commented="no" id="H95748E50C23B47128BF773BA477C8F6D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>which requires that the applicable fraction (as defined in subsection (c)(1)) for the building for each taxable year in the extended use period will not be less than the applicable fraction specified in such agreement and which prohibits the actions described in subclauses (I) and (II) of subparagraph (E)(ii),</text></clause> <clause commented="no" id="HB9EF14AAF72F468A8F2B9FFE57964406"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>which allows individuals who meet the income limitation applicable to the building under subsection (g) (whether prospective, present, or former occupants of the building) the right to enforce in any State court the requirement and prohibitions of clause (i),</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" id="HC7572739DDD748858695B9826A3B5F85"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>which prohibits the disposition to any person of any portion of the building to which such agreement applies unless all of the building to which such agreement applies is disposed of to such person,</text></clause> <clause commented="no" id="HB4D9FD83903841F1A2A9AB75B53D4538"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>which prohibits the refusal to lease to a holder of a voucher or certificate of eligibility under section 8 of the United States Housing Act of 1937 because of the status of the prospective tenant as such a holder,</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" id="HEA62BCD3C9B64FCBBA11ECDE4A002FE5"><enum>(v)</enum><text>which is binding on all successors of the taxpayer, and</text></clause> <clause commented="no" id="HA3E81B09704544E99CD214F1F9397BDB"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>which, with respect to the property, is recorded pursuant to State law as a restrictive covenant.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HA985BF4CC52546C9A30D901ECE53D012"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Allocation of credit may not exceed amount necessary to support commitment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The housing credit dollar amount allocated to any building may not exceed the amount necessary to support the applicable fraction specified in the extended working families housing commitment for such building, including any increase in such fraction pursuant to the application of subsection (f)(3) if such increase is reflected in an amended working families housing commitment.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H72D232C150E9414DB4C7B53FFCC5DB58"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Extended use period</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>extended use period</term> means the period—</text> 
<clause id="HAAFB559A38A240D4AD39EA22F738BB4E"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">beginning on the 1st day in the credit period on which such building is part of a qualified working families housing project, and</text></clause> <clause id="H45080AE0B49F4CB8923B23498E94DA36"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>ending on the later of—</text> 
<subclause id="H720DF2B034504DC2A57CE389ABF6A2EB"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the date specified by such agency in such agreement, or</text></subclause> <subclause id="HCBF59FBE242E49F9AF8FFA876F23DD27"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the date which is 15 years after the close of the credit period.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H337D4B1F88334C259B6F92A07E527520"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Exceptions if foreclosure or if no buyer willing to maintain working families status</header> 
<clause id="HE098870E068046F4A45E272BF45C71D8" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The extended use period for any building shall terminate on the 61st day after the taxpayer (or a successor in interest) provides notice to the Secretary and the housing credit agency that the building has been acquired by foreclosure (or instrument in lieu of foreclosure) and that the taxpayer intends the termination of such period, unless, before such date, the Secretary or the housing credit agency determines that such acquisition is part of an arrangement with the taxpayer a purpose of which is to terminate such period.</text></clause> <clause id="H20B77AF093DE446C97244C361569BC6D"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Eviction, etc., of existing working families tenants not permitted</header><text>The termination of an extended use period under clause (i) shall not be construed to permit before the close of the 3-year period following such termination—</text> 
<subclause id="H958EC8D16B33477D87285B45DB0756DF"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the eviction or the termination of tenancy (other than for good cause) of an existing tenant of any working families unit, or</text></subclause> <subclause id="H323F73630CBD4C97BCF38F22DA612C56"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any increase in the gross rent with respect to such unit not otherwise permitted under this section.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB1456942B5DD4EB0914757BE6F57C908"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Effect of noncompliance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If, during a taxable year, there is a determination that an extended working families housing agreement was not in effect as of the beginning of such year, such determination shall not apply to any period before such year and subparagraph (A) shall be applied without regard to such determination if the failure is corrected within 1 year from the date of the determination.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7768B4C4567143BE8A00FA80636E632A"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Projects which consist of more than 1 building</header><text>The application of this paragraph to projects which consist of more than 1 building shall be made under regulations prescribed by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE944217134A54778BF52905A5BA03631"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Special rules</header> 
<subparagraph id="H02CC6A99B49640558A6FB1AAACFE9879"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Building must be located within jurisdiction of credit agency</header><text>A housing credit agency may allocate its aggregate housing credit dollar amount only to buildings located in the jurisdiction of the governmental unit of which such agency is a part.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA3FC0CC48BD245FA82B06920AAB9F71E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Agency allocations in excess of limit</header><text>If the aggregate housing credit dollar amounts allocated by a housing credit agency for any calendar year exceed the portion of the State housing credit ceiling allocated to such agency for such calendar year, the housing credit dollar amounts so allocated shall be reduced (to the extent of such excess) for buildings in the reverse of the order in which the allocations of such amounts were made.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H391E7FC1EB1E4A24BBCCD1D52DE506B8"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Credit reduced if allocated credit dollar amount is less than credit which would be allowable without regard to placed in service convention, etc</header> 
<clause id="HFEC13B50D222472CAA0ABCB1ACD73493"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The amount of the credit determined under this section with respect to any building shall not exceed the clause (ii) percentage of the amount of the credit which would (but for this subparagraph) be determined under this section with respect to such building.</text></clause> <clause id="H4FD43E153009475F802DA44CD2A35923"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Determination of percentage</header><text>For purposes of clause (i), the clause (ii) percentage with respect to any building is the percentage which—</text> 
<subclause id="H52D61350C5484D00BCF8A8D0304D2E0F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the housing credit dollar amount allocated to such building, bears to</text></subclause> <subclause id="H94DB792853D44F72B6A096A913EA94BB"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the credit amount determined in accordance with clause (iii).</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="HCAACA2BD29BB40D9BE20EC3EB66E8A0C"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Determination of credit amount</header><text>The credit amount determined in accordance with this clause is the amount of the credit which would (but for this subparagraph) be determined under this section with respect to the building if—</text> <subclause id="HFBFA9A6B2A974751895ABEE5D55D5B48"><enum>(I)</enum><text>this section were applied without regard to paragraphs (2)(A) and (3)(B) of subsection (f), and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H104434A794924053A853ACC3BD28D82D"><enum>(II)</enum><text>subsection (f)(3)(A) were applied without regard to <quote>the percentage equal to <fraction>2/3</fraction> of</quote>.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD7D4B579D3B541B4A45E651399B9E100"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Housing credit agency to specify applicable percentage and maximum qualified basis</header><text>In allocating a housing credit dollar amount to any building, the housing credit agency shall specify the applicable percentage and the maximum qualified basis which may be taken into account under this section with respect to such building. The applicable percentage and maximum qualified basis so specified shall not exceed the applicable percentage and qualified basis determined under this section without regard to this subsection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA8DFCEC427134459928AB827B965F61C"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Increase in State ceiling dedicated to certain rural development projects</header> 
<subparagraph id="H90A3CFE81DE2446F931FFEF08AAE0D2C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The State housing credit ceiling for any calendar year shall be increased by an amount equal to 20 percent of the amount determined under paragraph (3)(C)(ii). </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA1040F5B8E4142EBB77CDEEA548CF429" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Use of increased amount</header> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H264E9E04242E4E7DB66DD285025BF90F"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount of the increase under subparagraph (A) for any calendar year may only be allocated to buildings located in a rural area or exurban area.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H5635162D62D444C4B64449CCA42CBDA8" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(ii)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Rural area</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of clause (i), the term <term>rural area</term> means any non-metropolitan area, or any rural area as defined by section 520 of the Housing Act of 1949, which is identified by the qualified allocation plan under subsection (l)(1)(B).</text></clause> <clause id="HEDE00417902B4256B6C626D04D3D1DE0"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Exurban area</header><text>For purposes of clause (i), the term <term>exurban area</term> has the meaning given such term by the Secretary after consultation with the Bureau of the Census.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H26CE8D8D97514AF28D1B6D8BDA808900"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Other definitions</header><text>For purposes of this subsection—</text> <subparagraph id="H1B9843B77C334BF5BCE73027A9AA24A8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Housing credit agency</header><text>The term <term>housing credit agency</term> means any agency authorized to carry out this subsection.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H62CF940F94734C368B7639ADA984773A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Possessions treated as States</header><text>The term <term>State</term> includes a possession of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4DE94A9322D14FFB8CC7BFFDF6ABDCBD"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Credit for buildings financed by tax-exempt bonds subject to volume cap not taken into account</header><text>Rules similar to the rules of subsections (h)(4), (m)(1)(D), and (m)(2)(D) of section 42 shall apply for purposes of this subsection.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HADC6D308F8D4430894F39C1FCC290A44"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Election to transfer State housing credit ceiling for allocations to low-income buildings</header> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7A004BE5192B45A58A9426CB1ED2169B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a State housing credit agency makes an election under this paragraph with respect to a calendar year—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC3D5710B7778402884752872E5FFD2E6"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the State housing credit ceiling for such calendar year under paragraph (3) (determined before application of paragraph (7)) shall be reduced by the amount specified in such election, </text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF9BD4C4CD68C4802A2D3905A28EF2D5C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the amount determined under paragraph (7) for such calendar year shall be reduced by the amount specified in such election, and</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8BCB57A0EAB24848AF8B34C79AF18C03"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the amount determined under section 42(h)(3)(C)(ii) for such calendar year shall be increased by the sum of the amounts specified in clauses (i) and (ii), except that any amount specified under clause (ii)—</text> 
<subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC66BFE53CE9F449280F5D0366DF22363"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"> may only be allocated under such section to qualified low-income buildings (as defined in section 42) located in a rural area or exurban area (as defined in paragraph (7)), and</text></subclause> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC76CAD20685844BAAEC8BB3E62FFA462"><enum>(II)</enum><text>shall not be taken into account for purposes of determining the unused housing credit ceiling under the second sentence of section 42(h)(3)(C).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBD25082FD0894EF78607D4D9E077F49F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Time and manner for making election</header> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE9F7A5E2369A4598BCF847866A389292"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An election under this paragraph—</text> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3D1C20ED9CD44B4C89EF43BDB72216D9"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall be made before the end of the calendar year with respect to which such election applies,</text></subclause> 
<subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2CFBD93A2AAF4D66B37F5E7BEB810C5B"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall be made in such manner as specified by the Secretary, and</text></subclause> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA9D6B99D5A0C49F4B2FB92FBB1F27875"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall separately specify the amount of reductions to be made under paragraph (3) and paragraph (7).</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAF8E492E81B542DFAD89568B4FF14FBA"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Frequency</header><text>A State housing credit agency may make more than one election under this section with respect to any calendar year, and any such election, once made, shall be revocable only if such revocation is made before the end of the calendar year with respect to which such election is made. </text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H33CA8AE315CC4C60AD6C23F219CDD3D6"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The aggregate amount specified in elections under this paragraph with respect to any State housing credit agency for calendar year shall not exceed the sum of—</text> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1B9CC0FF0F69493C919BF8D804A53EA6"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the amount determined under paragraph (3)(C)(ii) for such calendar year, plus</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H99CBF81632014D33814403D45BE8259C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the amount determined under paragraph (7) for such calendar year.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H530AC28607A143588B6E7009DF568198"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Definitions and special rules</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text> <paragraph id="H13DDF1C39DC94A5996D36682BA775D4A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Working families unit</header> <subparagraph id="H952BC02E8D0D4B179387A88927982988"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>working families unit</term> means any unit in a building if—</text> 
<clause id="H0301718F39F54122A07414E900C35903"><enum>(i)</enum><text>such unit is rent-restricted (as defined in subsection (g)(2)), and</text></clause> <clause id="H70A3A1113CF344CEBB3FBBEBFF78F5B2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the individuals occupying such unit meet the income limitation applicable under subsection (g)(1) to the project of which such building is a part.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H52C46DBCD95646948A8CE0899D48E467"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exceptions</header> 
<clause id="HD7B8851195A3401D8398AD5DA71DE73C"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Exclusion of low-income units</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A unit shall not be treated as a working families unit if such unit is a low-income unit (as defined under section 42(i)(3)).</text></clause> <clause id="H0CEBA84C071241559CD929D222C8AD81"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Unit must be suitable for permanent occupancy</header> <subclause id="HD33DB0B20A614AEBAC44FD4DCCB2B580"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A unit shall not be treated as a working families unit unless the unit is suitable for occupancy and used other than on a transient basis.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H0BB26AAD3B924C7D8821A74330BE0AEA"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Suitability for occupancy</header><text>For purposes of subclause (I), the suitability of a unit for occupancy shall be determined under regulations prescribed by the Secretary taking into account local health, safety, and building codes.</text></subclause> <subclause id="H51182D38676C4750B79A6AA9884BAD84"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Single-room occupancy units</header><text>For purposes of subclause (I), a single-room occupancy unit shall not be treated as used on a transient basis merely because it is rented on a month-by-month basis.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H38C4653DEB224F69B16E86D00286C0BD"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Special rule for buildings having 4 or fewer units</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any building which has 4 or fewer residential rental units, no unit in such building shall be treated as a working families unit if the units in such building are owned by—</text> <clause id="HC6B55E46148E446AA646E023F5B9CAD3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any individual who occupies a residential unit in such building, or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H05EF6EFA64B44C5BAEED8E6B0720AC98"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any person who is related (as defined in subsection (d)(2)(D)(ii)) to such individual.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H52D572BBD5E04A2CB052F7567FACAD77"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Rules relating to students</header> <clause id="H79A8D19E51DD47F9A482881398076592"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A unit occupied solely by individuals who—</text> 
<subclause id="HC9D1145619BC48BEBEC1B235F60FF026"><enum>(I)</enum><text>have not attained age 24, and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H53D12A3385C94059939776B7BBD66570"><enum>(II)</enum><text>are enrolled in a full-time course of study at an institution of higher education (as defined in section 3304(f)),</text></subclause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="clause">shall not be treated as a working families unit.</continuation-text></clause> 
<clause id="HCC3C43A3CADF4B0EABB4B4257FC623CD"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Exception for certain federal programs</header><text>In the case of a Federally-assisted building (as defined in subsection (d)(6)(C)(i) of section 42), clause (i) shall not apply to a unit all of the occupants of which meet all applicable requirements under the housing program described in such subsection through which the building is assisted, financed, or operated. </text></clause> <clause id="H25CE117DF43548B187E27977F83C5D29"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Other exceptions</header><text>Clause (i) shall not apply to a unit occupied by an individual who—</text> 
<subclause id="H1D3AFB8FF1244CA5955340162C980688"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is married, if such individual's spouse also occupies the unit,</text></subclause> <subclause id="H185335E1FB2E4E0F93C1F2607802D1D2"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is a person with disabilities (as defined in section 3(b)(3)(E) of the United States Housing Act of 1937),</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H3F951A5DFDC34EDAAF163FAF5E1065F6"><enum>(III)</enum><text>is a veteran (as defined in section 101(2) of title 38, United States Code),</text></subclause> <subclause id="H8D32A55329554078B3D1191BAE93C0AA"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>has one or more qualifying children (as defined in section 152(c)), if such children also occupy the unit, the individual is not a dependent (as defined in section 152, determined without regard to subsections (b)(1), (b)(2), and (d)(1)(B) thereof) of another individual, and such children are not claimed as dependents (as so defined) of another individual, or</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H75C0320ADD8C4DF4AC042F240C045FF8"><enum>(V)</enum><text>is, or was immediately prior to attaining the age of majority—</text> <item id="H2310574015F941179776812F4FE29BFD"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>an emancipated minor or in legal guardianship as determined by a court of competent jurisdiction in the individual's State of legal residence,</text></item> 
<item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD961B74941194804B91AB7157F357BFE"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">under the care and placement responsibility of the State agency responsible for administering a plan under part B or part E of title IV of the Social Security Act, or</text></item> <item id="H67B859E9EB51457A8457854F6A7B0239"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>was an unaccompanied youth (within the meaning of section 725(6) of the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/11434a">42 U.S.C. 11434a(6)</external-xref>)) or a homeless child or youth (within the meaning of section 725(2) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/11434a">42 U.S.C. 11434a(2)</external-xref>)).</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H828750B7790A45DE8D216655D52E1A05"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Owner-occupied buildings having 4 or fewer units eligible for credit where development plan</header> 
<clause id="H9A44F854BDD345AA9D7A9D453B8A2397"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subparagraph (C) shall not apply to the acquisition or rehabilitation of a building pursuant to a development plan of action sponsored by a State or local government or a qualified nonprofit organization.</text></clause> <clause id="H8D4D2D71F6CE4D5AB998914FEBEE4000"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Limitation on credit</header><text>In the case of a building to which clause (i) applies, the applicable fraction shall not exceed 80 percent of the unit fraction.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H23430B75CBEF4D729FE55621900CB54F"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Certain unrented units treated as owner-occupied</header><text>In the case of a building to which clause (i) applies, any unit which is not rented for 90 days or more shall be treated as occupied by the owner of the building as of the 1st day it is not rented.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H28F0495D6B314DDBB3A0A8A7D6F0B8B9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>New building</header><text>The term <term>new building</term> means a building the original use of which begins with the taxpayer.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H75AE7EB21EAF4C759BB730D8D4342A46"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Existing building</header><text>The term <term>existing building</term> means any building which is not a new building.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAE65CDB94F0547C3946B4C5D7934D393"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Application to estates and trusts</header><text>In the case of an estate or trust, the amount of the credit determined under subsection (a) shall be apportioned between the estate or trust and the beneficiaries on the basis of the income of the estate or trust allocable to each.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEE5AF6E047FD4D94BB1F7F614F171F94"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Impact of tenant's option to acquire property</header> 
<subparagraph id="H88DE61FD07D44BE5B187316FE21248E7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No Federal income tax benefit shall fail to be allowable to the taxpayer with respect to any qualified working families building merely by reason of an option held by the tenants (in cooperative form or otherwise) or resident management corporation of such building or by a qualified nonprofit organization or government agency to purchase the property or all of the partnership interests (other than interests of the person exercising such option or a related party thereto (within the meaning of section 267(b) or 707(b)(1))) relating to the property after the close of the credit period for a price which is not less than the minimum purchase price determined under subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6029BB2FDDA34C2DA25D6F922AA1A658"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Minimum purchase price</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A), the minimum purchase price under this subparagraph is an amount equal to the principal amount of outstanding indebtedness secured by the building (other than indebtedness incurred within the 5-year period ending on the date of the sale to the tenants). In the case of a purchase of a partnership interest, the minimum purchase price is an amount equal to such interest's ratable share of the amount determined under the preceding sentence.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE4E430F7FC0E4C64914D7760AEA9FCC9"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Treatment of rural projects</header><text>For purposes of this section, in the case of any project for residential rental property located in a rural area (as defined in section 520 of the Housing Act of 1949), any income limitation measured by reference to area median gross income shall be measured by reference to the greater of area median gross income or national non-metropolitan median income.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF48E38451BA3418CB017EE12B776B7D6"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Determination of whether building is Federally subsidized</header> <subparagraph id="HCEF37F321F26468ABB427392383E82BF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as otherwise provided in this paragraph, for purposes of this section, a project shall be treated as Federally subsidized for any taxable year if, at any time during such taxable year or any prior taxable year, there is or was outstanding any obligation the interest on which is exempt from tax under section 103 the proceeds of which are or were used (directly or indirectly) with respect to such project or the operation thereof.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H356F5BF66256466ABFE60B873DA28370"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Special rule for subsidized construction financing</header><text>Subparagraph (A) shall not apply to any tax-exempt obligation used to provide construction financing for any building if—</text> <clause commented="no" id="H80BBF717D0424D629AD2E6A9269E35FF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>such obligation (when issued) identified the building for which the proceeds of such obligation would be used, and</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" id="H7765C9FEFA6B4766BBBD85D2A46F8870"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>such obligation is redeemed before such building is placed in service.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H29B038DA89B445D696F513A9ADC6A043"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Reduction in basis</header><text>In the case of any building for which a credit is allowable under this section and section 42, the basis of the building shall be reduced by the amount of such credit allowed under subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB4EA1B5E832648C2A4469FE0075E8AD2"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Application of at-Risk rules</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text> <paragraph id="H041656753DD444FE910BA2FE22804E1D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, rules similar to the rules of section 49(a)(1) (other than subparagraphs (D)(ii)(II) and (D)(iv)(I) thereof), section 49(a)(2), and section 49(b)(1) shall apply in determining the qualified basis of any building in the same manner as such sections apply in determining the credit base of property.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H93B192D0337A48909B6712A97B05E21D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Special rules for determining qualified person</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (1)—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H348F59EDCDFE4ED3A756CD06CCFC6108"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the requirements of subparagraphs (B), (C), and (D) are met with respect to any financing borrowed from a qualified nonprofit organization, the determination of whether such financing is qualified commercial financing with respect to any qualified working families building shall be made without regard to whether such organization—</text> 
<clause commented="no" id="HB6CAA2FC1C724E4FB1FE2D2929635BA1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is actively and regularly engaged in the business of lending money, or</text></clause> <clause commented="no" id="HCC42C8C3FB0C412FA12B39D74FD276F0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is a person described in section 49(a)(1)(D)(iv)(II).</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HC78689CB9B3A40FEB512E5082D830D68"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Financing secured by property</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The requirements of this subparagraph are met with respect to any financing if such financing is secured by the qualified working families building, except that this subparagraph shall not apply in the case of a federally assisted building described in section 42(d)(6)(C) if—</text> <clause commented="no" id="H96482BD9A5FA490F890D8266FEA347BC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a security interest in such building is not permitted by a Federal agency holding or insuring the mortgage secured by such building, and</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" id="H193BDADC404F4AD9B8E27E07169BBB72"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the proceeds from the financing (if any) are applied to acquire or improve such building.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H14836530799542D1A07D403A99ED99A5"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Portion of building attributable to financing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The requirements of this subparagraph are met with respect to any financing for any taxable year in the credit period if, as of the close of such taxable year, not more than 60 percent of the eligible basis of the qualified working families building is attributable to such financing (reduced by the principal and interest of any governmental financing which is part of a wrap-around mortgage involving such financing).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HEB4A3611EBBA4FABA13BA8A873FF1FA2"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Repayment of principal and interest</header><text>The requirements of this subparagraph are met with respect to any financing if such financing is fully repaid on or before the earliest of—</text> <clause commented="no" id="H707FA69F90C34D5B9A1F94B508FAF4F9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the date on which such financing matures,</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" id="H486C22D0BF5743E597F2428D526018F7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the 90th day after the close of the credit period with respect to the qualified working families building, or</text></clause> <clause commented="no" id="H202B2987227F4F3292149872FC9AC4D0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the date of its refinancing or the sale of the building to which such financing relates.</text></clause><continuation-text commented="no" continuation-text-level="subparagraph">In the case of a qualified nonprofit organization which is not described in section 49(a)(1)(D)(iv)(II) with respect to a building, clause (ii) of this subparagraph shall be applied as if the date described therein were the 90th day after the earlier of the date the building ceases to be a qualified working families building or the date which is 15 years after the close of a credit period with respect thereto.</continuation-text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H0001A20FC68F462AA25A9ADC8F005934"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Present value of financing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the rate of interest on any financing described in paragraph (2)(A) is less than the rate which is 1 percentage point below the applicable Federal rate as of the time such financing is incurred, then the qualified basis (to which such financing relates) of the qualified working families building shall be the present value of the amount of such financing, using as the discount rate such applicable Federal rate. For purposes of the preceding sentence, the rate of interest on any financing shall be determined by treating interest to the extent of government subsidies as not payable.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="HCA65059F2FA842069EE6693A44EB8B88"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Failure to fully repay</header> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H216B86622A3544B580DA5B7297FD2DC3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To the extent that the requirements of paragraph (2)(D) are not met, then the taxpayer's tax under this chapter for the taxable year in which such failure occurs shall be increased by an amount equal to the applicable portion of the credit under this section with respect to such building, increased by an amount of interest for the period—</text> 
<clause commented="no" id="H3A0305D8D70B4592BF3174A8966F11B9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>beginning with the due date for the filing of the return of tax imposed by chapter 1 for the 1st taxable year for which such credit was allowable, and</text></clause> <clause commented="no" id="HC1DD9C9D649B4426BF54596504106256"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>ending with the due date for the taxable year in which such failure occurs,</text></clause><continuation-text commented="no" continuation-text-level="subparagraph">determined by using the underpayment rate and method under section 6621.</continuation-text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HBEB396B0AE984F5ABC197C5C4614A027"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Applicable portion</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A), the term <term>applicable portion</term> means the aggregate decrease in the credits allowed to a taxpayer under section 38 for all prior taxable years which would have resulted if the eligible basis of the building were reduced by the amount of financing which does not meet requirements of paragraph (2)(D).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H95BB914E5B9C46F28C40F4328FF8E359"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Certain rules to apply</header><text>Rules similar to the rules of subparagraphs (A) and (D) of section 42(j)(4) shall apply for purposes of this subsection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD3637371D0E74532973A5E87CFAEBB35"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Certifications and other reports to Secretary</header> 
<paragraph id="H89D9BFF7FD684131A60ABE10551FBF48"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Certification with respect to 1st year of credit period</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Following the close of the 1st taxable year in the credit period with respect to any qualified working families building, the taxpayer shall certify to the Secretary (at such time and in such form and in such manner as the Secretary prescribes)—</text> <subparagraph id="HE8F458ED3FE44AB0ACAC745F864C971E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the taxable year, and calendar year, in which such building was placed in service,</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAF3DE4F53BD04110B8697443924AE8F4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the adjusted basis and eligible basis of such building as of the close of the 1st year of the credit period,</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4E7FC9473F9A47CA969811FAAC93EF9D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the maximum applicable percentage and qualified basis permitted to be taken into account by the appropriate housing credit agency under subsection (h), and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H019A774F6F33468597482E10780ED641"><enum>(D)</enum><text>such other information as the Secretary may require.</text></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">In the case of a failure to make the certification required by the preceding sentence on the date prescribed therefor, unless it is shown that such failure is due to reasonable cause and not to willful neglect, no credit shall be allowable by reason of subsection (a) with respect to such building for any taxable year ending before such certification is made.</continuation-text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H60AF55874F824E959D1BC55464ACA6E0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Annual reports to the Secretary</header><text>The Secretary may require taxpayers to submit an information return (at such time and in such form and manner as the Secretary prescribes) for each taxable year setting forth—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H766ED28C9FBD4B91B515A0FD9CA05E95"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the qualified basis for the taxable year of each qualified working families building of the taxpayer,</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H213CBA3ACAE242F98C6BCD0DC50F2483"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the information described in paragraph (1)(C) for the taxable year, and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8806DEE37F2241908140F052B95525E3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>such other information as the Secretary may require.</text></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">The penalty under section 6652(j) shall apply to any failure to submit the return required by the Secretary under the preceding sentence on the date prescribed therefor.</continuation-text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H58B732ECA4D54D3B951E1D64B71D7D62"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Annual reports from housing credit agencies</header><text>Each agency which allocates any housing credit amount to any building for any calendar year shall submit to the Secretary (at such time and in such manner as the Secretary shall prescribe) an annual report specifying—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB88017784E344CF098DA9BDCBC0DDB22"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the amount of housing credit amount allocated to each building for such year,</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDA0DD090A75548B6AC0E8C3C48EDC10A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>sufficient information to identify each such building and the taxpayer with respect thereto, and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H111508ACABAC4527AF8281BC904C3200"><enum>(C)</enum><text>such other information as the Secretary may require.</text></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">The penalty under section 6652(j) shall apply to any failure to submit the report required by the preceding sentence on the date prescribed therefor.</continuation-text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H5B9E8F30D2674AE0AB8C18CE8A28CA3F"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Responsibilities of housing credit agencies</header> <paragraph id="HEA81BB579D294EF7B0F276C22FC49699"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Plans for allocation of credit among projects</header> <subparagraph id="HA6444495F30941079690F67229E35B6C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, the housing credit dollar amount with respect to any building shall be zero unless—</text> 
<clause id="H5D2B8766358847ED9D1E5AF79A07F953"><enum>(i)</enum><text>such amount was allocated pursuant to a qualified allocation plan of the housing credit agency which is approved by the governmental unit (in accordance with rules similar to the rules of section 42(m)(1)) of which such agency is a part,</text></clause> <clause id="H0C39A35BB0B04D848977F5A9E3E4BF23"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a comprehensive market study of the housing needs of working family individuals in the area to be served by the project is conducted before the credit allocation is made and at the developer's expense by a disinterested party who is approved by such agency, and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HD3384DF7DBDB441AB5DCC89ED0C775C3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a written explanation is available to the general public for any allocation of a housing credit dollar amount which is not made in accordance with established priorities and selection criteria of the housing credit agency.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3EE473805E2E49C1AAB27312391E2549"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Qualified allocation plan</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>qualified allocation plan</term> means any plan—</text> 
<clause id="H1DCFBC4B4D58481B9927F33788767A22"><enum>(i)</enum><text>which sets forth selection criteria to be used to determine housing priorities of the housing credit agency which are appropriate to local conditions,</text></clause> <clause id="H3B1E378185CC447FB64F775450F2A41F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>which also gives preference in allocating housing credit dollar amounts among selected projects to—</text> 
<subclause id="H02C7E1C6B20646B481BEF157C04221B1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>projects obligated to serve qualified tenants for the longest periods,</text></subclause> <subclause id="HC534FAC327EC46A5AC3C3571EB11BEE5" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>projects in areas with insufficient supply of housing affordable to median income households, </text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HD07438E55B9F4ECEB987FAE15D2D48FE"><enum>(III)</enum><text>projects which target housing to tenants at a range of incomes between 60 and 100 percent of area median gross income, and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H32C340C839FE4130991E03A767502D9A"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>projects located near transit hubs, and</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="HDFB53DA406B64CD4BE89DC07951E31F6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>which provides a procedure that the agency (or an agent or other private contractor of such agency) will follow in monitoring for noncompliance with the provisions of this section and in notifying the Internal Revenue Service of such noncompliance which such agency becomes aware of and in monitoring for noncompliance with habitability standards through regular site visits.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6994F4EB7FCE4ADBA256D27A044E79C3"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Certain selection criteria must be used</header><text>The selection criteria set forth in a qualified allocation plan must include—</text> 
<clause id="HDB4B07EB3475490BA96B3608B291A2CA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>project location,</text></clause> <clause id="HB56F6041D25D46AFB4EC2CA24B6A719F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>housing needs characteristics,</text></clause> 
<clause id="H7B910B21620C4CA7879F2A5A463E9FE3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>project characteristics, including whether the project includes the use of existing housing as part of a community revitalization plan,</text></clause> <clause id="H0983534FE354438D890972D86B3ADBA4"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>sponsor characteristics,</text></clause> 
<clause id="H2981FEC2E05E40698660858E1C778359"><enum>(v)</enum><text>tenant populations with special housing needs,</text></clause> <clause id="H3D9BBDFF8B944F0CA1A643C4C66A3821"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>tenant populations of individuals with children,</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA63E88DBB04B45199A04178C4DF98BC7"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>projects intended for eventual tenant ownership,</text></clause> <clause id="H8739ED85A5474891A11B1153A3FD8F12"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>the energy efficiency of the project, and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HB6F2C8ACEAA34E848361CABA8D2EE468"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>the historic nature of the project.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H69EDA83B8C3E4CC88523D2404782A5C1"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Certain selection criteria prohibited</header><text>The selection criteria set forth in a qualified allocation plan shall not include a requirement of local approval or local contributions, either as a threshold qualification requirement or as part of a point system to be considered for allocations of housing credit dollar amount.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H944F3C26F1EF40138D07927F774DD126"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Credit allocated to building not to exceed amount necessary to assure project feasibility</header> 
<subparagraph id="H9A1F182637864B0590D415BB0C56BF33"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The housing credit dollar amount allocated to a project shall not exceed the amount the housing credit agency determines is necessary for the financial feasibility of the project and its viability as a qualified working families housing project throughout the credit period.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEB3C020C5EA24066B45A1D7D9A55A8B5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Agency evaluation</header><text>In making the determination under subparagraph (A), the housing credit agency shall consider—</text> 
<clause id="H2DF5B5AC516E492AAAAA6A7B8F516D40"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the sources and uses of funds and the total financing planned for the project,</text></clause> <clause id="HAA029A4F74ED4D05BD9116EC099EAA92"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any proceeds or receipts expected to be generated by reason of tax benefits,</text></clause> 
<clause id="H1A2C86F9B10F4EBB923D73386CBF2C2F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the percentage of the housing credit dollar amount used for project costs other than the cost of intermediaries, and</text></clause> <clause id="H5EC8F27F10F64E91AC88367395DBDC97"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the reasonableness of the developmental and operational costs of the project.</text></clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">Clause (iii) shall not be applied so as to impede the development of projects in hard-to-develop areas. Such a determination shall not be construed to be a representation or warranty as to the feasibility or viability of the project.</continuation-text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H300F3DBC7A674A9D8A94D39DCFB02ACD"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Determination made when credit amount applied for and when building placed in service</header> 
<clause id="HD0794A9771FD46A89F63DC1D43235ADA"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A determination under subparagraph (A) shall be made as of each of the following times:</text> <subclause id="H372F867B40BC40B28ACB505784921032"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The application for the housing credit dollar amount.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H61FE1347F71745449B2CC1F7438409FA"><enum>(II)</enum><text>The allocation of the housing credit dollar amount.</text></subclause> <subclause id="H28D12E335CAE4378AC6FE08687302CC7"><enum>(III)</enum><text>The date the building is placed in service.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H5D4EAB08EF7B481B80ED1DED5E67FF89"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Certification as to amount of other subsidies</header><text>Prior to each determination under clause (i), the taxpayer shall certify to the housing credit agency the full extent of all Federal, State, and local subsidies which apply (or which the taxpayer expects to apply) with respect to the building.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HEEC75114B92C444A88417CCFED908891"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section, including—</text> 
<paragraph id="HCB931031A99847329D4227D2168C8709"><enum>(1)</enum><text>regulations dealing with—</text> <subparagraph id="HCA834E141F764275B2991D433E4A38AD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>projects which include more than 1 building or only a portion of a building, or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H51EB546BEAAA40B8BFF8A7E95C226BCF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>buildings which are placed in service in portions,</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H18CF4395066D487E9B527457A427B612"><enum>(2)</enum><text>regulations providing for the application of this section to short taxable years,</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDB4945C1B51F4DD4A5E126BE48187FF7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>regulations preventing the avoidance of the rules of this section, </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H25749DBFFB23460FBEF8E5B573ACB292"><enum>(4)</enum><text>regulations providing the opportunity for housing credit agencies to correct administrative errors and omissions with respect to allocations and record keeping within a reasonable period after their discovery, taking into account the availability of regulations and other administrative guidance from the Secretary, and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6F8149C4BFCA4B8E917F4E2F22FED2C9"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in consultation with the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, regulations or guidance to promote uniform definitions and to streamline requirements for with respect to qualified working families buildings which receive funding from programs administrated by the Department of Housing and Urban Development, including programs authorized by Native American Housing Assistance and Self-Determination Act of 1996. </text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H19CFBB83E6504BDEA1CBBADC5D78B379"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Treatment as part of general business credit</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/38">Section 38(b)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking <quote>plus</quote> at the end of paragraph (40), by striking the period at the end of paragraph (41) and inserting <quote>, plus</quote>, and by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4588074678344AB28F85474B24671B93"> 
<paragraph id="HAEB9DEE3F50745338DE800B17163AA92"><enum>(42)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the working families housing credit determined under section 42A(a).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HFD066060CBBE43D0A5C37E8AE295EFAB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reduction in basis</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/1016">Section 1016(a)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HDFCE450698984354A5819CC5D94A7CE0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of paragraph (37);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE39C00B0DFCC44E4A41E91FFADFB08B5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (38) as paragraph (39); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAFC5089F3BFA4503AE7524A517603EE0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (37) the following new paragraph: </text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA9854A6B744246BF93F9ECE92C3D05C2"> <paragraph id="HC47822F76DC34F92B639052D75F7303D"><enum>(38)</enum><text>to the extent provided in section 42A(i)(8), and</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1E224B852A73450CAC56734FD855DAAA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Treatment under base erosion minimum tax</header><text>Section 59A(b)(4) of he Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by redesignating subparagraphs (B) and (C) as subparagraphs (C) and (D), respectively, and by inserting after subparagraphs (A) the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE181CC459F194847A25AF06D02B4C62C"> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA9E6456E643B43DB93D2DD055AD8F045"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the working families housing credit determined under section 42A(a),</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H795021336CCC454F8A87A23F5C69FCFF"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Conforming amendments relating to low-Income housing tax credit</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/42">Section 42(n)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA0501174522E407B8B108D28055F9300"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>regulations</quote> in the matter preceding paragraph (1), </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H62682D9CAD7947C693333BF335F33E47"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting <quote>regulations</quote> before <quote>dealing with</quote> in paragraph (1),</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB39DC55C775E4D639218341B9990A9DF"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting <quote>regulations</quote> before <quote>providing</quote> in paragraphs (2) and (4), </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H63072C5DE09E4DE497AEB53763BFDB75"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting <quote>regulations</quote> before <quote>preventing</quote> in paragraph (3), </text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H364B81704F3E40DA9386BFA1314790B2"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of paragraph (3), </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB75B829941E64B69B9AB86460D05AED5"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking the period at the end of paragraph (4) and inserting <quote>, and</quote>, and </text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H46F365521E194B57AF2F9745CDEAA061"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6EC46D0A661645BE914A4D227B9760C3"> 
<paragraph id="H9922F68B122747D68F839EBE03F953E2" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in consultation with the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, regulations or guidance to promote uniform definitions and to streamline requirements with respect to qualified low-income buildings which receive funding from programs administrated by the Department of Housing and Urban Development, including programs authorized by Native American Housing Assistance and Self-Determination Act of 1996.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0836E1A40F8343AB812AB15FBB93BF9F"><enum>(f)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Conforming amendments</header> <paragraph commented="no" id="HB81C40339F0846D4A5B8267B909D9F21"><enum>(1)</enum><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/45L">Section 45L(e)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting <quote>or 42A</quote> after <quote>42</quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5A9DD02A7C104DF39BAE0C20A87EA408"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Section 50(c)(3)(C) of such Code is amended by inserting <quote>or 42A</quote> after <quote>42</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4F845073308B40818C6631F61EF7E624"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 55(c)(1) of such Code is amended by inserting <quote>42A(j),</quote> before <quote>45(e)(11)(C)</quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA51CDC46A2D54B0E9BF7F21A37D0EEFC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Subsections (i)(3)(C), (i)(6)(B)(i), and (k)(1) of section 469 of such Code are each amended by inserting <quote>or 42A</quote> after <quote>42</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9F517980C70D4A9E9A76E34EC90C2F1D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The table of sections for subpart D of part IV of subchapter A of chapter 1 of such Code is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 42 the following new item:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HC9A39A884AF84FBF8074487A54E47BD2"> 
<toc> 
<toc-entry idref="H4B7DEA78D79B4C48A4AEB8A44EF9CAA4" level="section">Sec. 42A. Working families housing credit.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF2279CD2154E4061A0A2394076172041"><enum>(g)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to buildings placed in service after December 31, 2025, in taxable years ending after such date. </text></subsection></section> <section id="H05D9B4F29BB9463A98D6E9990BAF727B"><enum>4.</enum><header>Loans and grants for infrastructure projects in connection with qualified working families housing projects</header> <subsection id="H3BB27ADB84FD45BC80B440C45093197A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall make grants and below-market-rate loans (as the Secretary determines appropriate) to local governments in rural and exurban areas for covered infrastructure projects carried out in connection with the development of qualified working families housing projects.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H211297BDC7304EC99E754FA425DE80F9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Covered infrastructure projects</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text> <paragraph id="HAC957F8ED1F44E2B84C441E1FAD3BD91"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>covered infrastructure project</term> means projects for electricity, waters, sewers, local access roads, and such other projects as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA2CBEEA08DD74156B7A84F8E6DEA5B5B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clean energy prioritization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to any infrastructure project for electricity, the Secretary shall give priority to clean energy projects.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD72C56FFCD6F43D8AB9F4D02EA170B22"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Other definitions and special rules</header><text>Terms used in this section which are also used in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/42A">section 42A</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 shall have the same meaning when used in this section as when used in such section of such Code. Requirements similar to the requirements of section 45(b)(7) of such Code shall apply with respect to infrastructure projects with respect to which grants or loans are made under this section.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H128A129741FD4BADB617DA9AAC9C9184"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated $100,000,000 to carry out the purposes of this section.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

