<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-CAN25981-VCC-WG-0GJ"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 382 IS: Expressing the sense of the Senate that Ashli Babbitt is disqualified from eligibility for military funeral honors under section 985 of title 10, United States Code.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 382</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250910">September 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S432">Mr. Gallego</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSVA00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing the sense of the Senate that Ashli Babbitt is disqualified from eligibility for military funeral honors under section 985 of title 10, United States Code.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas Ashli Babbitt, an Air Force veteran, died on January 6, 2021, while illegally attempting to breach the United States Capitol during the violent insurrection intended to overturn the certification of the 2020 Presidential election;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas law enforcement officers responded courageously to defend the Capitol, risking and, in some cases, sacrificing their lives to uphold democratic institutions;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas United States Capitol Police repeatedly ordered Ashli Babbitt, who was carrying a weapon, and other insurrectionists to step back from the locked and barricaded door leading to the House Speaker’s Lobby, but the mob continued pressing forward, pounding on the door until its glass shattered;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Ashli Babbitt then attempted to force her way inside by climbing through the door’s broken window, where a Capitol Police Officer intervened to protect dozens of House members and staff cornered nearby;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas military funeral honors are a solemn recognition reserved for those who both served in uniform and upheld their oath to support and defend the Constitution of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas under section 985 of title 10, United States Code, persons whose conduct would bring discredit upon the Armed Forces may be denied eligibility for military funeral honors;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas extending such honors to persons who actively participated in the January 6 attack undermines the integrity of those honors and the sacrifices of millions of veterans who have defended the United States; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Air Force’s August 15, 2025, decision to grant Ashli Babbitt military honors was indefensible, shameful, and a disservice to the men and women who have honorably worn the uniform: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That it is the sense of the Senate that—</text><paragraph id="id5b9315f3a5b948ac9bcf864e1c775708"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Ashli Babbitt’s actions on January 6, 2021, constitute disqualifying conduct under section 985 of title 10, United States Code, the rendering of military funeral honors to her would bring discredit upon the Air Force, and she is not eligible for such honors; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id07152240ea284bb39dc8f1f74c136711"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Senate reaffirms its gratitude to the law enforcement officers and other personnel who defended the Capitol on January 6, 2021, and rejects efforts to glorify or legitimize the actions of those who sought to overturn the Constitution of the United States.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

