<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5C25E0B7DBD44BBB8A842A847090D076" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 711 IH: Honoring the victims of Hurricane Helene and expressing condolences and support for the affected communities in western North Carolina, specifically North Carolina’s 11th Congressional District, 1 year after the hurricane made landfall in the State on September 27, 2024.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 711</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250915">September 15, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000246">Mr. Edwards</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="F000450">Ms. Foxx</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000305">Ms. Ross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001210">Mr. Murphy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000370">Ms. Adams</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001101">Mr. Harrigan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001240">Mr. McDowell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001236">Mr. Moore of North Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000405">Mr. Knott</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000603">Mr. Rouzer</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001067">Mr. Hudson</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Honoring the victims of Hurricane Helene and expressing condolences and support for the affected communities in western North Carolina, specifically North Carolina’s 11th Congressional District, 1 year after the hurricane made landfall in the State on September 27, 2024.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas Hurricane Helene caused catastrophic destruction, loss of life, and widespread suffering across western North Carolina;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas families have been displaced from their homes, communities have been devastated, and essential infrastructure, including roads and bridges, schools, and hospitals, has been severely damaged;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas first responders, emergency management personnel, community organizations, faith-based groups, and neighbors have demonstrated extraordinary courage and compassion in the face of these unprecedented challenges;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the resilience of affected residents continues to inspire the country, even as they endure hardship, grieve lost loved ones, and work toward recovery; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas it is the duty of the House of Representatives to support and stand in solidarity with citizens suffering from natural disasters and to recognize their losses and their resilience: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H233A13015FCD4094A55F5B10FACF41D7"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H386CB881730D4A4C8F86E45DEF48BAF1"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="H3B4619F1C6DD40F5952772E3FA40E2E5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>honors the memory of those who lost their lives as a result of Hurricane Helene;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAD6CABFB0B064287B238549819CCC318"><enum>(2)</enum><text>extends its deepest condolences to the families of the victims and to all individuals and communities who continue to suffer in the storm’s aftermath;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD7A2D13CEBDA4172A7773461286094DB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recognizes and expresses gratitude for the heroic efforts of first responders, volunteers, and local leaders who have risked their lives to save others and begin the process of recovery;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA9F9567379C04466AAE94BC07A2D7686"><enum>(4)</enum><text>affirms its commitment to supporting the people and communities impacted by Hurricane Helene through disaster relief, recovery, and rebuilding efforts; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3D84EBD577EE44439D83A942E52908A3"><enum>(5)</enum><text>encourages the appropriate executive branch agencies to continue to partner with Congress to accelerate recovery of the communities affected by Hurricane Helene.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

