<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H45E877BE4C194A3C8EE1165EAE20CE61" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1628 IH: 761st Tank Battalion Congressional Gold Medal Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1628</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250226">February 26, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000609">Mr. Palmer</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000298">Mr. Estes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000740">Mrs. Bice</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000628">Mr. Dunn of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001212">Mr. Stauber</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001215">Mrs. Miller-Meeks</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001212">Mr. Moore of Alabama</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">House Administration</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To award a Congressional Gold Medal to the 761st Tank Battalion, collectively, in recognition of their crucial role in the success of Allied forces in Europe and for the example they set as the first Black soldiers to go to war as part of an American armored unit.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF187C3338D3E4FDAB05D0AD7142F5E5F" style="OLC"><section id="HEF1E9D0F0B8142E9B8B463F11E49C995" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>761st Tank Battalion Congressional Gold Medal Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H5044FDD6CAFA405DB64D2C2A255CF2B1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H90CB83C42EFC4B9284AE3421BE4E32A7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The 761st Tank Battalion, known as the <quote>Black Panthers</quote>, was activated on April 1, 1942, and served as the first predominantly Black American armored battalion in the European Theater of World War II until its deactivation on June 1, 1946, in Germany.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H458A8AF95E1A4AD8BE780E9EFA5A9E08"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Lieutenant Jackie Robinson, the first Black Major League baseball player, was among the few Black officers in the 761st, but he was court martialed before seeing combat for an act of civil disobedience in refusing to move to the back of a bus.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H868A3403DF3E4757B20F65CD66153F07"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Despite resistance from many top-level American politicians and military officers, the 761st served valiantly under Lieutenant General George S. Patton.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1021542D3A5C4CFBA829AE21EC9601FB"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In his welcoming speech, Patton said, <quote>I would never have asked for you if you weren't good. I have nothing but the best in my Army. I don't care what color you are as long as you go up there and kill those…</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCE6128670F6D4A6B97A435AA22D99C59"><enum>(5)</enum><text>After entering combat in late fall 1944, the 761st lived up to their motto, <quote>Come Out Fighting</quote>, enduring 183 days of combat without being pulled from the line.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1F801D7A02E642D9AAA1C46EA4B36450"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The 761st played a crucial role in numerous battles including the Battle of the Bulge and helped break out the encircled American paratroopers in the town of Bastogne.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H644E9DCE69AC4102A95AD34EE86E74CC"><enum>(7)</enum><text>During their time in combat, the 761st inflicted 130,000 casualties on the Germans while enduring a casualty rate of almost 50 percent with the loss of 71 tanks.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H35F5E3B6C3AB4AD09711A5AEA474BAEB"><enum>(8)</enum><text>As the spearhead for several of Patton’s moves toward Germany, they were the first American unit to break through the Siegfried Line and they were one of the first American units to link up with the Russian Army at the Enns River at Steyr, Austria.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEC9F0613DB67479DA76199520C8D1F9C"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Sadly, like other Black soldiers in World War II, members of the 761st did not receive the recognition that was due them upon returning home, and instead faced prejudice at home after the war.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1C5EC460DC7747B18F904EA20B539F79"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The accomplishments of the 761st were largely unrecognized until 1978 when, over three decades after the war, the battalion finally received a Presidential Unit Citation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA2D8032CCFFC409789DB13F3538A4832"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The citation acknowledges <quote>the extraordinary gallantry, courage, professionalism, and high esprit de corps displayed in the accomplishment of unusually difficult and hazardous operations in the European Theater of Operations</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA4BA34BD0773488BB29833EBA75A8E93"><enum>(12)</enum><text>In addition to that citation, individual members of the 761st had earned the following: 1 Medal of Honor, 11 Silver Stars, and approximately 300 Purple Hearts.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H86AA0525CC3F4862A737B4426513FEDE"><enum>(13)</enum><text>The United States is eternally grateful to the soldiers of the 761st Tank Battalion for their crucial role in the success of Allied forces in Europe and for helping ensure freedom around the globe.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H44FDDCE828E5405088E6AD2EC8CFA434"><enum>3.</enum><header>Congressional Gold Medal</header><subsection id="H5992602CF6ED47E6B3C8ADFEC089A35D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Presentation authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President pro tempore of the Senate shall make appropriate arrangements for the presentation, on behalf of Congress, of a gold medal of appropriate design to the 761st Tank Battalion, collectively, in recognition of their crucial role in the success of Allied forces in Europe and for the example they set as the first Black soldiers to go to war as part of an American armored unit.</text></subsection><subsection id="HEAB33C8484654474997D347D7B64BE29"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Design and striking</header><text>For the purposes of the presentation referred to in subsection (a), the Secretary of the Treasury (hereafter in this Act referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall strike a gold medal with suitable emblems, devices, and inscriptions, to be determined by the Secretary.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE43561F219C046A5ACB18184CFA5801C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>National Museum of African American History and Culture</header><paragraph id="HF671EAB026474BE4AAAF738514AA7C90"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Following the award of the gold medal under subsection (a), the gold medal shall be given to the National Museum of African American History and Culture, where the medal shall be available for display as appropriate and available for research.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H16D3425759BE4947AC71F1F4F74F7C60"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sense of the Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that the National Museum of African American History and Culture should make the gold medal received under paragraph (1) available for display elsewhere, particularly at appropriate locations associated with the 761st Tank Battalion.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H3B543A72234C4DB9A290D42535FE0EBB"><enum>4.</enum><header>Duplicate medals</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary may strike and sell duplicates in bronze of the gold medal struck pursuant to section 3, at a price sufficient to cover the cost thereof, including labor, materials, dies, use of machinery, and overhead expenses.</text></section><section id="H93D98EE2C9FE4B3F8ECAF8A2AF8C2646"><enum>5.</enum><header>Status of medals</header><subsection id="H53813EC53F874017896FD4479EA04A71"><enum>(a)</enum><header>National medals</header><text>The medals struck pursuant to this Act are national medals for purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/51">chapter 51</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code.</text></subsection><subsection id="HEA3EC1A098114A29B0310FF87CA57599"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Numismatic items</header><text>For purposes of section 5134 of title 31, United States Code, all medals struck under this Act shall be considered to be numismatic items.</text></subsection></section><section id="HF9C427544C6D48E9BA66BAC9A90BD436" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>6.</enum><header>Authority to use fund amounts; proceeds of sale</header><subsection id="H4853B891EE604DA2A85CF7230F33BE96"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority To use fund amounts</header><text>There is authorized to be charged against the United States Mint Public Enterprise Fund such amounts as may be necessary to pay for the costs of the medals struck under this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H20E1D04636B04DFB81A1B3485EADCC94"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Proceeds of sale</header><text>Amounts received from the sale of duplicate bronze medals authorized under section 4 shall be deposited into the United States Mint Public Enterprise Fund. </text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

