<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H03F1C5A4DFCB44A5992BB28CA9A96AD7" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5707 IH: Voter Purge Protection Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5707</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251008">October 8, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="B001313">Ms. Brown</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000110">Mr. Fields</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000309">Mr. Jackson of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000462">Ms. Lois Frankel of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001225">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000490">Mr. Bishop</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000557">Mr. Larson of Connecticut</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001229">Mrs. McIver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000402">Mr. Kennedy of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000197">Ms. DeGette</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 to prohibit a State from removing the name of any registrant from the official list of voters eligible to vote in elections for Federal office in the State unless the State verifies, on the basis of objective and reliable evidence, that the registrant is ineligible to vote in such elections.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6BF23A6DDCE24A0291A704385D8D8D07" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HCF74F450218C45F0A23BBEE45E63C429" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Voter Purge Protection Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H9FC2769884B64E97B59C590D6494306B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Conditions for removal of voters from list of registered voters</header> <subsection id="HEFDC94B9FEFC496B9A529616046ADCA0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Conditions described</header><text>The National Voter Registration Act of 1993 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/20501">52 U.S.C. 20501 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 8 the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H927D43F126C94EBCA7266AFA06D64E20" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H1121931E2F084527B5A605E0C495CCFF"><enum>8A.</enum><header>Conditions for removal of voters from official list of registered voters</header> 
<subsection id="H519E6D14B7F64474BBD0C38BBFD91677"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Verification on basis of objective and reliable evidence of ineligibility</header> 
<paragraph id="H5E7F789647834E5E8A84870440A7515B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Requiring verification</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this Act, a State may not remove the name of any registrant from the official list of voters eligible to vote in elections for Federal office in the State unless the State verifies, on the basis of objective and reliable evidence, that the registrant is ineligible to vote in such elections.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCED3DA274A35432F80D88AE0FC50DB1C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Factors not considered as objective and reliable evidence of ineligibility</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (1), the following factors, or any combination thereof, shall not be treated as objective and reliable evidence of a registrant’s ineligibility to vote:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H8B357C15E03E4FA99DD36ADC603F8C7E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The failure of the registrant to vote in any election.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H88A9C8AF45BE4CB3B0C7EBF957A8EF8A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The failure of the registrant to respond to any notice sent under section 8(d), unless the notice has been returned as undeliverable.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE978109D19794FEE853AEA526A500704"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The failure of the registrant to take any other action with respect to voting in any election or with respect to the registrant’s status as a registrant.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD29F63199F8B45D4B9CA9AB837100923"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Notice after removal</header> <paragraph id="H23293AB59A0B410E933FF64D37F78F0C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Notice to individual removed</header> <subparagraph id="H8836C77548DE44DEADF55F194DA8D9B3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 48 hours after a State removes the name of a registrant from the official list of eligible voters for any reason, the State shall send notice of the removal to the former registrant, and shall include in the notice the grounds for the removal and information on how the former registrant may contest the removal or be reinstated, including a telephone number for the appropriate election official.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDF102FD111034A4E8DC7446561083499"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>Subparagraph (A) does not apply in the case of a registrant—</text> <clause id="H87FC263075044B22B532CBE6A6B36E4B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>who sends written confirmation to the State that the registrant is no longer eligible to vote in the registrar’s jurisdiction in which the registrant was registered; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H260762DB11344C9EBA490806944C20F6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>who is removed from the official list of eligible voters by reason of the death of the registrant.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA2499DD68E6E4D95A868495EB89C8338"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Public notice</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 48 hours after conducting any general program to remove the names of ineligible voters from the official list of eligible voters (as described in section 8(a)(4)), the State shall disseminate a public notice through such methods as may be reasonable to reach the general public (including by publishing the notice in a newspaper of wide circulation or posting the notice on the websites of the appropriate election officials) that list maintenance is taking place and that registrants should check their registration status to ensure no errors or mistakes have been made. The State shall ensure that the public notice disseminated under this paragraph is in a format that is reasonably convenient and accessible to voters with disabilities, including voters who have low vision or are blind.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H14B092CDA7954A60A330751FF364E5E3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conditions for transmission of notices of removal</header><text>Section 8(d) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/20507">52 U.S.C. 20507(d)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H393DEFAADFDF492E975C2A39AEF0DC43" style="traditional"> <paragraph id="H247FACAF0F504F729CB918FA032493E7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A State may not transmit a notice to a registrant under this subsection unless the State obtains objective and reliable evidence (in accordance with the standards for such evidence which are described in section 8A(a)(2)) that the registrant has changed residence to a place outside the registrar’s jurisdiction in which the registrant is registered.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H27FECDEBCA5648278D17CC2B225652B2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header> 
<paragraph id="H92DCB61ADBDB41A7B1A7274EF568BC78"><enum>(1)</enum><header>National Voter Registration Act of 1993</header><text>Section 8(a) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/20507">52 U.S.C. 20507(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H92BA0C4BADD145C1BE868BF008869C19"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>provide</quote> and inserting <quote>subject to section 8A, provide</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H99B921B9095E4A20A8E52C6121359865"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by striking <quote>conduct</quote> and inserting <quote>subject to section 8A, conduct</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H42B30792992B4312B49D7CBF68F4B308"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Help America Vote Act of 2002</header><text>Section 303(a)(4)(A) of the Help America Vote Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/21083">52 U.S.C. 21083(a)(4)(A)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>, registrants</quote> and inserting <quote>, and subject to section 8A of such Act, registrants</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4EB663B91AA742698A48DE52E53EB75B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

