<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4EE3DFDB93E54DB290A8647356ED4BD1" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2494 IH: To direct the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to annually submit to the Congress a report that analyzes State and local strategies, activities, and plans that promote affordable housing, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2494</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250331">March 31, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001127">Mrs. Cherfilus-McCormick</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to annually submit to the Congress a report that analyzes State and local strategies, activities, and plans that promote affordable housing, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD487C7B511AC4FD5BF7299B02A37A268" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H2E452E58BB674CC0BCAB1270486AB550" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> <paragraph id="H14FC593DEEBF490D8DE8A198785DCE27"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States is experiencing a housing crisis. The nation is short millions of housing units. Renters are spending more than one-third of their salary on housing costs and buyers are unable to find affordable housing. Our housing stock is short by millions. No State has been left untouched.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H92BB2E7DE449436BBB5427206FB01F28"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The role of regulating the various factors that contribute to the affordable housing crisis largely rests with States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6B78DFEE037A477A92B3F7F3124C0FF9"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">States have engaged in a variety of efforts to address this crisis including reforming zoning rules.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9A2A45C4BE4D4001815A7F0DB0971D87"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To best determine how the Federal Government can support effective solutions to the crisis, Congress must identify which State efforts are successfully addressing the crisis.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8E9FC0BBCA5C4DE2B65FBDAE8E0B3115"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The regulatory barriers clearinghouse serves as a national repository for information regarding State and local laws, regulations and policies related to affordable housing and the effects of those laws, regulations, and policies on affordable housing. The clearinghouse also collects State and local efforts that promote affordable housing.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9641719CFB8F4EE9A27638F26733E899"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The clearinghouse currently is geared toward providing such information to and for use by State and local governments.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFAD878C3B2D34695A0867792DDD8E747"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress could utilize the information provided in the clearinghouse to support a Federal response to the affordable housing crisis.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="H43567D8A0A554025AFA429D110E762FC"><enum>2.</enum><header>Regulatory barriers clearinghouse report to Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1205 of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1992 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12705d">42 U.S.C. 12705d</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H2B81BFE2A0034C0082CA061ECB772635" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="H86480BFA520740B384F6AE65B27F60CE"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development shall annually submit to the Congress a report that includes the following elements:</text>
<paragraph id="H3EE603586F6947E288989879FC3FDE39"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An analysis of information described in subsection (a).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H33A8A92C33CB48A084CEB90780F02EE1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Policy recommendations, based on the analysis described in paragraph (1), that the Congress may use to support the implementation of successful State and local strategies, activities, and plans that promote affordable housing.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

