<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H812218F9797647CBB2C17AFDCC7FCD46" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5395 IH: Disaster Relief Disbursement Accountability Act </dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5395</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250916">September 16, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001103">Mr. Hernández</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="K000402">Mr. Kennedy of New York</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001211">Mr. Stanton</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to direct the expedient disbursement of funds, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H2207DDC3C63B414D900A66024807DA3C" style="OLC">
<section id="H6040887C0CE345CB8959CE5DF6850079" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Disaster Relief Disbursement Accountability Act </short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HBD491EA09B624C55B538A990C588F3A8" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Expedient disbursement of funds</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title VI of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5195">42 U.S.C. 5195 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HED86FE46EB4A4FCE83DF7B21B1362887" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="HADF7F1FA34724376865FB10FC5267DD3"><enum>630.</enum><header>Expedient disbursement of funds</header> 
<subsection id="H6B8AB2B1B0C64A9DB7EFA0A06F63F0FC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall take any actions that are necessary to ensure that funds are disbursed to eligible entities as expediently as possible after a project is approved under this Act, including the hazard mitigation grant program under section 404 and the public assistance program under sections 403, 406, 407, 428, and 502.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H4F7204D3B51C4A3DBE1A3258BB183385"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report to Administrator</header> <paragraph id="HC73B62F28B0045898F666416386BF385"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Retroactive report</header><text>For each major disaster or emergency for which a declaration was made under section 401 or 501 and for which assistance is being disbursed as of the date of enactment of this section, each recipient of assistance for such major disaster or emergency under the hazard mitigation grant program under section 404 or the public assistance program under sections 403, 406, 407, 428, or 502 shall, not later than 1 year after such date of enactment, submit to the Administrator a report that describes the average amount of time the recipient takes to disburse such assistance to a subrecipient.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEFA6E0492E6F40A4991B2BA39123C86F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For each major disaster or emergency for which a declaration is made under section 401 or 501 after the date of enactment of this section, each recipient of assistance for such major disaster or emergency under the hazard mitigation grant program under section 404 or the public assistance program under sections 403, 406, 407, 428, or 502 shall submit to the Administrator, on an annual basis, a report that describes the average amount of time the recipient takes to disburse such assistance to a subrecipient.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HB35CED1AAD6E4AACBE3BF73105E9E5DA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this section, and annually thereafter, the Administrator shall submit to the Committees on Homeland Security and Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a report containing a summary of the information provided under subsection (b).</text></subsection> </section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

