<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H72AA21E7E247477E94CC32E4554A9FF0" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 408 IH: Censuring Representative LaMonica McIver of New Jersey.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 408</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250513">May 13, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000480">Mr. Timmons</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSO00">Committee on Ethics</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Censuring Representative LaMonica McIver of New Jersey.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, on May 9, 2025, Representative LaMonica McIver was involved in an incident at the Delaney Hall Detention Center in Newark, New Jersey, a Federal immigration detention facility operated by the United States Immigration and Customs Enforcement;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Department of Homeland Security and other sources have alleged that a group, including Representative McIver, engaged in unauthorized entry into a secure Federal facility during the arrival of a bus carrying detainees, thereby disrupting operations and endangering the safety of law enforcement agents and detainees;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas body camera footage and other evidence show Representative McIver assaulting and intimidating Federal law enforcement officers;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas assaulting, resisting, opposing, intimidating, or interfering with a police officer performing their official duties is illegal under section 111 of title 18, United States Code; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Members of the House of Representatives are entrusted with upholding the law and maintaining public confidence in the integrity and dignity of the legislative branch: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HB24CD5E567444244BC2A90902F9CB01D"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H6CDB0545A4F74BA58A05005FB936BCC5"><enum/><text>That— </text><paragraph id="H524C0A9CFAEB4D22B90D7FB86EA2699E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the House of Representatives censures Representative LaMonica McIver;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA7BFBCF339C14A0BBF968693F704F062"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Representative McIver forthwith present herself in the well of the House of Representatives for the pronouncement of censure;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H945B58CDCFD1485FA6BEA5D79F44BA32"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Representative McIver will be censured with the public reading of this resolution by the Speaker; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC5302B93556C4B8486971ED37169E0C7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the Committee on Ethics shall conduct an investigation into Representative McIver and to consider further disciplinary action, as appropriate under House rules and precedent.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

