<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1A05BDB4C7344636998043825EE44079" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1305 IH: Improving Measurements for Loneliness and Isolation Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1305</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20250213">February 13, 2025</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000474">Mr. Flood</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B001287">Mr. Bera</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a working group to formulate recommendations for standardizing the measurements of loneliness and isolation, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H3533E4C99F214482A246F18A194591D0" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HAFEFEB65A57D4AF4BE496BC8D6EE26F7" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"> This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Improving Measurements for Loneliness and Isolation Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HA4F2B3CD5F4442788DB1E549EF7E9047"><enum>2.</enum><header>Working Group on Unifying Loneliness Research</header> <subsection id="H599EA6748D0042E3BA8360748B15EE9C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="HF04350BBB90146198FF2F14B9185BE16"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>isolation</term> means the objective lack of social relationships or limited social contact with others.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9EA0CD5E9BCB43ABB222077F6A89721D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>loneliness</term> means a subjective feeling of being isolated.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1CBE5F156B3C4B8B913397366BF23359"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services (in this section referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall establish a national working group, to be known as the Working Group on Unifying Loneliness Research (in this section referred to as the <quote>Working Group</quote>), to formulate recommendations for standardizing the measurements of loneliness and isolation.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H085A5F2C8DC441A4B94D69CA1FD72610"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Goals</header><text>The goals of the recommendations under subsection (b) shall be the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H4431E468C5A24239A76C9018F331586E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Collaboration, cooperation, and consultation among Federal departments and agencies with respect to developing standardized measurements of loneliness and isolation for the purposes of—</text> <subparagraph id="H70DE87DC15F447D884F2BADDCF070683"><enum>(A)</enum><text>having standardized measurements for use in public and private research, including surveys across varying populations, with the ability to capture the level of granularity needed to guide strategic decisionmaking, planning, and evaluation of strategies to combat loneliness and isolation; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H85DFF6D779914A1297AAAECB068E85EC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>providing reliable, consistent measurement tools for use across fields and industries in health care.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2E2C1B2BEA8F4ED9AF46E2E513B0D622"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Collaboration, cooperation, and consultation among Federal departments and agencies with respect to developing standardized definitions of loneliness, isolation, and relevant terms associated with loneliness and isolation for the purposes of education, awareness, and understanding of the terms for the general public.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7F9FF6A650CB4877B04BDE9AFBADCF02"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Assessment of the alignment of previous methods of measuring loneliness and isolation in the public and private sectors.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HEB77EBA19A904C45BE9A6EDB11247AE4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Composition</header><text>The Working Group shall be composed of—</text> 
<paragraph id="HAB1ABDCED8EF4A029884F9630A52E54B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">senior-level representatives of—</text> <subparagraph id="HD03ED327ABBC43829F35D74D19C1BBF3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Department of Health and Human Services;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA87D3A7D9A2D4940973E63A58AB2CBE7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0E6D59ED70F745C1B037DE4E72CEDE1C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H44527AE45E3D41F0AFE0AB96B9A043DB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Administration for Community Living;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3F08B3246F5F4685A29779FA6D42901A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the National Institutes of Health;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5107B12053454CC5B582CBA8FCF71E95"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC94870864DD141A5A2E6AF027335D9C3"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the Health Resources and Services Administration;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H78A67FCCC8144E018CF3DB36642B16FA"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5AB4E17FBE57429C8E55C47FD4131BA5"><enum>(I)</enum><text>other agencies, groups, subject matter experts, or researchers the Secretary deems beneficial to be represented in the Working Group consistent with the goals specified in subsection (c);</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE91F9E068B9641269144FE6F13EB48F4"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">1 representative of each of the three States with the highest numbers of practitioners needed to remove the designations of all mental health care health professional shortage areas in the respective State (as reflected in the report of the Health Resources and Services Administration titled <quote>Designated Health Professional Shortage Areas Statistics</quote> (June 30, 2023), with each such representative designated by the Governor of the respective State; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD07793EE403E4DC1A81414FC05A67CB0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>1 representative of the each of the three States with the lowest numbers of practitioners needed to remove such designations, with each such representative designated by the Governor of the respective State.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H80C6285126B84252AE8FE65D601C0636"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header> 
<paragraph id="H11FD974AF7214CBC9F6A2BEB8A808027"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Working Group shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HC8DD6BB1CDD14983B3B802170D98FF3A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submit to the committees listed in paragraph (3) a report describing the work and recommendations of the Working Group; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7683DBAA41C74991826C08F25013C7D1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>make such report publicly available on the internet.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCC2970B258C94019A258E315926117BB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text>The Working Group shall meet not less than 3 times in the course of developing its report.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB6FBD6955FB8495FBEC1C88801519353"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Committees</header><text>The committees referred to in paragraph (1)(A) are the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H2BC614C249AA4456BF1A106333C570D0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Committee on Education and Workforce of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7D11A0F35D0B46AC9EADD801CECA5A5F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H25EE038D0E6A41DE9D133F496D550219"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA0B65E5590E24DDCB50A5E67C800E075"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The Committee on Finance of the Senate.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5557A83C9F0E4416911DD307D0D64611"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H896AB41002044911A698C6A3EE038E67"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <term>State</term> means the 50 States.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H03D16D0CA99F47E5BF451AC776381ACD"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>This section shall cease to be effective at the end of calendar year 2027.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body>
</bill> 


