<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ROS25104-DP5-48-74D"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S176 IS: Not One More Inch or Acre Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 176</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250122">January 22, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S374">Mr. Cotton</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S398">Mr. Cramer</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S416">Mrs. Britt</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To direct the President to take such actions as may be necessary to prohibit the purchase of public or private real estate located in the United States by citizens and entities of the People's Republic of China, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H91802103BD9546F28069B5998168AA51"><section section-type="section-one" id="HA384110BA1584EA4B610AF16C3C48D16"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Not One More Inch or Acre Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H4DFCD9ED400B4951B35351CE747205BA"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on purchase of public or private real estate located in the United States by citizens and entities of the People's Republic of China</header><subsection id="H0A130CCB802040DC9DAC3981761A1A93"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the President shall take such actions as may be necessary—</text><paragraph id="id23302C28D2844A69A09255E3EE99D0C2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to prohibit the purchase, on or after the date of the enactment of this Act, of public or private real estate located in the United States by—</text><subparagraph id="idF89172F9F21E4ED9A6AF1A2E295E8575"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any citizen of the People's Republic of China; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3AB0C6E82D7644AAA0EA8F3DB4A01B4D"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any covered foreign entity; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC4A499AAC71341C88E09BB331018C3B3"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any foreign person acting for or on behalf of the Chinese Communist Party, a covered foreign entity, or a citizen of the People's Republic of China; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5A5E76BC2AF744F68CFFAAD0D648DDD4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>if the President determines that the ownership, as of such date of enactment, by a person described in subparagraph (A), (B), or (C) of paragraph (1) of real estate located in the United States poses a national security risk to the United States, to require the sale of such real estate by not later than the date that is one year after such date of enactment.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id113DC52D609143A580547B6D67BBCD5D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><paragraph id="idCE029AB6C9074F20ACFB4E3B843F0FD5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Exception for refugees</header><text>Subsection (a) does not apply with respect to a citizen of the People's Republic of China who—</text><subparagraph id="idF213ED8DC10C40B59DBC42E4BE490A4E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>entered the United States as a refugee (as defined in section 101(a)(42) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(42)</external-xref>)); or </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7FCF0C12622E4408B1FB8F028EB4BFEC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>was granted asylum or withholding of removal under section 208 or 241(b)(3) that Act (8 U.S.C. 1158 and 1231(b)(3)).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idB43D2E4D49CF47AC87E608C06F48FBBD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception for property of United States nationals</header><text>Subsection (a)(2) does not apply with respect to the sale of real estate owned or otherwise held for personal use by a United States citizen or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence to the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id285A31FD6D244561A7CD5915AB678DEA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="idf3c6be6d055e49b0963bbc49cd8e4f48"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered foreign entity</header><text>The term <term>covered foreign entity</term> means an entity—</text><subparagraph id="idF5343CBAFC584407AA4175DF5093A11E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>acting on behalf of or otherwise directed by the Government of the People’s Republic of China or the Chinese Communist Party;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id689C4816D4AA415EAF59B4A06EAC684B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that—</text><clause id="id64E5420367FF4DC6AC1DA5333EAFB750"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is organized under the laws of the People's Republic of China; </text></clause><clause id="id8EBAF7963B39435F94A9B4F9B8969AD6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has a principal place of business in the People’s Republic of China; or</text></clause><clause id="id862354D4438B4A5BB6DE2AE597A136CE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>is owned or controlled by, or otherwise subject to the jurisdiction of, the Government of the People's Republic of China or the Chinese Communist Party; or</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id013AA4608C2842AA819713D380C583B9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>that is a subsidiary of an entity described in subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idc8f62a90a91d4c988db8e3c08300abb1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Foreign person</header><text>The term <term>foreign person</term> means an individual or entity that is not a United States person. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7EEBF3762BE948978B16C759623ADD87"><enum>(3)</enum><header>United States</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>United States</term> means the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, American Samoa, Guam, the United States Virgin Islands, and any other territory or possession of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4be8799e6fe44ab5a135b43ee25bda74"><enum>(4)</enum><header>United states person</header><text>The term <term>United States person</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="idde577127c64a46c78fa317668be8e5ee"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a United States citizen or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence to the United States; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id84942630336742ad872cbb66964a330a"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an entity organized under the laws of the United States or any jurisdiction within the United States, including a foreign branch of such an entity. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idBBDA771A837C4787A19127F4EB33D5EA"><enum>3.</enum><header>Penalty amount under Agricultural Foreign Investment Disclosure Act of 1978</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 3(b) of the Agricultural Foreign Investment Disclosure Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/3502">7 U.S.C. 3502(b)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>exceed 25 percent of</quote> and inserting <quote>be less than 10 percent, or exceed 25 percent, of</quote>. </text></section></legis-body></bill> 

