<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE2F13F7F80CF4DFE85124417F891EA35" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2836 IH: FEMA Loan Interest Payment Relief Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2836</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250410">April 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000628">Mr. Dunn of Florida</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001200">Mr. Soto</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000597">Ms. Lee of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001077">Mr. Higgins of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001212">Mr. Moore of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000806">Mr. Webster of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000593">Mr. Gimenez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001257">Mr. Bilirakis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001217">Mr. Moskowitz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000032">Mr. Donalds</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001216">Mr. Mills</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to provide for the authority to reimburse local governments or electric cooperatives for interest expenses, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H49A1771ED23B4EB0A36D5EF4B566E544" style="OLC"><section id="H795E043A0A784043837F5C8951A1C874" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>FEMA Loan Interest Payment Relief Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H5F99F08A59F64801BFC633D7C38A0E9C" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Reimbursement of interest payments related to public assistance</header><subsection id="HA05D543B09E94B929E88657B7DCE1C69"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title IV of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5170">42 U.S.C. 5170 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H012F6D0857E04AB7BEBA75C00657D0DD" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="H4377E66D46964A9488FC49869CFFDE2C"><enum>431.</enum><header>Reimbursement of interest payments related to public assistance</header><subsection id="H00288D69B43C42BB88AB5491CC49BC7D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President, acting through the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, shall provide financial assistance to a local government or electric cooperative as reimbursement for qualifying interest.</text></subsection><subsection id="H523ADB7F53D94666AF791C5D428A4B40"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><paragraph id="HB9A491CECD7540CC9A3FFA5A10EF6719"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In this section, the following definitions apply:</text><subparagraph id="HA821650D182A461B90802BAD88C9E936"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Qualifying interest</header><text>The term <quote>qualifying interest</quote> means, with respect to a qualifying loan, the lesser of—</text><clause id="HFB198A7B06F14F4BB17948D05A37F827"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the actual interest paid to a lender for such qualifying loan; and</text></clause><clause id="H6B4E531768684BF2B2D2682E3B09EC1B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the interest that would have been paid to a lender if such qualifying loan had an interest rate equal to the prime rate most recently published on the Federal Reserve Statistical Release on selected interest rates.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF1C3BAA36AED4FC38340E65CDF4EED3E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Qualifying loan</header><text>The term <quote>qualifying loan</quote> means a loan—</text><clause id="H59C65F40B9764B8BAC866224692F96EC"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">obtained by a local government or electric cooperative; and</text></clause><clause id="HF0D2D40590D1436FBA4D68592E48B6CA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>of which not less than 90 percent of the proceeds are used to fund activities for which such local government or electric cooperative receives assistance under this Act after the date on which such loan is disbursed.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF8017980C8814092A9D724CD91F4B2BC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Local government</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <quote>local government</quote> includes the District of Columbia.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HDD1AC78B52F24E128795A7DC5D5F0BAC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rules of applicability</header><paragraph id="H7B70003B3FCF448099A407AA2EE1F8CB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any qualifying interest (as such term is defined in section 431 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act, as added by this Act) incurred by a local government or electric cooperative in the 9 years preceding the date of enactment of this Act shall be treated as eligible for financial assistance for purposes of such section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0958B19A6EFE43C99FF878FED8092EE6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appropriations</header><text>Only amounts appropriated on or after the date of enactment of this Act may be made available to carry out the amendment made by this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H407A2FCE508547DAABB774877925BA49"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Alternative procedures for outstanding qualifying interest reimbursement</header><paragraph id="H3D8803D8192A40658EC6BC5661B9BC13"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the President, acting through the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, shall establish and publish in the Federal Register alternative procedures for States to obtain reimbursement for qualifying loan interest (as such term is defined in section 431(b) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act, as added by this Act) eligible under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (42 U.S.C. 5121 et. seq) for all projects pending obligation as of the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4FDCBF31F3924E07A55D21E2AAEDB8F0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application</header><text>A State requesting reimbursement pursuant to paragraph (1) shall submit an application to the President, acting through the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, for outstanding qualifying interest reimbursement not later than 60 days after the date of publication of the procedures in such subsection. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFB581BE6C36944889627DABA81AA1C15"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Reimbursement timing</header><text>In carrying out paragraph (1), the President, acting through the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, shall reimburse States requesting assistance pursuant to paragraph (1) not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act. </text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

