<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="HBA96808A1FB94DBBB2BD69BD6A93D234" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3854 RH: Modernizing All Veterans and Survivors Claims Processing Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 216</calendar><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3854</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 119–260]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250609">June 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000129">Mr. Valadao</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250909">September 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on June 9, 2025</action-instruction></action><action><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to submit a plan to expand the use of certain automation tools in the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HVR00" reported-display-style="italic" id="H67840A6DE5244A56B2341C682D1DB9A8"><section id="H181CCDA7FB5548FD82C1F8BC3B96E969" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Modernizing All Veterans and Survivors Claims Processing Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H0F74133476EE4B14ADC1250A8D25F527"><enum>2.</enum><header>Department of Veterans Affairs annual report on causes of death among veterans</header><subsection id="H04692613B417470EB96B11C3CBCF10DB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchaper II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/5">chapter 5</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H0FAB59CEB72243B68D6260D366986E4A" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HVR00"><section id="H68117EEF52814183A12C1C718D5BC28C"><enum>534.</enum><header>Annual report on causes of death among veterans</header><subsection id="HC0F8BA479A6549419AE0503C243E3951"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Senate an annual report that contains data and information on causes of death among veterans.</text></subsection><subsection id="H8AC6987DE19F4DB9AA188375DF13CA6C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>Such report shall include—</text><paragraph id="H841AD093BCC64A0292D4A442D3621FC1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>for each veteran that died during the period covered by the report an identification of—</text><subparagraph id="H48A96C46D6E24174B682CFCF6BB9CC24"><enum>(A)</enum><text>whether such veteran had a service-connected disability rated as total;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7C89612DB824428DB26CE29AC1AE390C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the primary cause of death;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD70E407C405D4B0CA867A966AE4F3028"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the secondary cause of death, if applicable; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA5DF8639C8394ED58178B53270A0BF5D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the manner of death;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H930FB435C5864C3C8654E0C83CDB27F3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for each primary cause of death identified pursuant to paragraph (1), a statement of the total number of veterans that died from such primary cause of death during the period covered by the report; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5242E48E45E54E48A2328D92CC5CC00A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>for each manner of death identified pursuant to paragraph (1), a statement of the total number of veterans that died in such manner during the period covered by the report.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBE1CDCF9E2A34B408FAAB39C4A3D9941"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>This section shall terminate on the date that is five years after the date of the enactment of the Justice for America’s Veterans and Survivors Act of 2025.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HE5573B642B374579AB8871AFB65B7540"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of chapter 5 of such title is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 533 the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H9AE9096962AD45C1884D298D5DDF0844" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HVR00"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HVR00"><toc-entry level="item">534. Annual report on causes of death among veterans</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="HF998A61606E444A6B8D972ACBA405F38"><enum>3.</enum><header>Plan for use of automation tools to process claims under laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs</header><subsection id="H0C6796523EEB44E99C64C6B8CE9D938A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and House of Representatives the plan of the Secretary to make available, to the maximum extent practicable, an automation tool described in subsection (b) to elements of the Department of Veterans Affairs for the purpose of processing claims under laws administered by the Secretary. </text></subsection><subsection id="H827EB9212D9F4617968167AFE567772D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Automation tool described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An automation tool described in this subsection is a technology developed for the Compensation Service of the Veterans Benefits Administration that—</text><paragraph id="H8C2993C047334AA69CA93CB84A740D27"><enum>(1)</enum><text>automates the retrieval of the service record or health records of a veteran;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H58E37D72C10041CA8FF5C749DA37AD8C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>compiles evidence relevant to the determination of a claim for benefits under laws administered by the Secretary;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5AF7A4DD823D4BA7991DDDC3FC1E6DA6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provides automated decision support relevant to such a determination;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H42C40FF7FFDA4F8F9C8C3F3F44A012C5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>automates information sharing between Federal agencies; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HADB38EBC797343F9958B501439792262"><enum>(5)</enum><text>assists in generating correspondence regarding such a claim.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD933284A2F464ED1BD918C0696433CA0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Analysis</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In developing the plan required under subsection (a), the Secretary shall conduct an analysis of each of the following:</text><paragraph id="H5468F2820C3D4E0F91CB62992E2C16C9"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The feasibility and benefits of the use of an automation tool described in subsection (b) by elements of the Department for the purpose of processing claims under laws administered by the Secretary.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAFC47C06FD0B446BB8D33F9ADC3A6EED"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any modification to an existing automation tool that could render such tool usable for such purpose by such an element.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0E32C338EA06485697ACB81430F34A50"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Any requirement of any such element pertaining to such purpose that cannot be addressed by using an automation tool.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4B33EEDA66774ADBABCFEF9DDAEC8379"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The extent to which the technology offices of such elements may need to collaborate with the technology office responsible for developing an automation tool in the course of the development and use of the tool by the element for such purpose.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H480B6895B5054969B0EBABB057262FD1"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A timeline for modifying and implementing any automation tool for use by such elements for such purpose.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB967EF48B71545D5A64C4CCCF7F90C23"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Priority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In providing an automation tool described in subsection (b) to elements of the Department pursuant to the plan required under subsection (a), the Secretary shall give priority to the following elements:</text><paragraph id="H71276C667A434CF4B48567137D550049"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Pension and Fiduciary Service of the Veterans Benefits Administration.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H956E544F65624611BE61FA0335555112"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Education Service of the Veterans Benefits Administration.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H11D315AFFB714E2BB4BDAAF038398209"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Program offices of the Veterans Benefits Administration, as determined by the Secretary.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCBEFC21FC3C24597B511817F24492495"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Debt Management Center.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H982582907DB4401B8811DFF43B4F28A2"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Board of Veterans’ Appeals.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H862F4F0052A647808947312DA86AC5A8"><enum>4.</enum><header>Other requirements relating to technology at Department of Veterans Affairs</header><subsection id="H1C8BE4C328624902841A5D6F22A2AE9C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Automatic notices regarding benefits for certain children of veterans</header><paragraph id="H3D1344F7932842A9A277E2099DD16D11"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall implement policies, processes, and technological capabilities, including in the National Work Queue (or successor system), to ensure that, in the case of any covered situation, a claims processors is made aware of, and assigned to address, such covered situation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBA3B60954D7348E08630EEF07351F04B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text><subparagraph id="H2B2E13D175444164AFB79E9899BE540A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The term <quote>covered situation</quote> means—</text><clause id="H4E9E75F78639479680327E2878BF6134"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any increase in the amount of dependency compensation paid to a beneficiary for a child under the laws administered by the Secretary; and</text></clause><clause id="H1A0CF6FFB4134D25B557DB0C5069AF2E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any educational assistance paid to the child of a veteran under the laws administered by the Secretary.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE1F334E511D647C48092209D08155786"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The term <quote>child</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 101(4)(A)(iii) of title 38, United States Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC88646966CDC4FC085747F8D9284A25F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Correct labeling of documents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and House of Representatives a plan to ensure that documents in the Veterans Benefits Management System (or any successor system) are correctly labeled when such documents are uploaded, including when such documents are labeled using automation tools.</text></subsection></section><section id="HA5D2201168B04B5B81C7AAE54B213A70" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>5.</enum><header>Extension of certain limits on payments of pension</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 5503(d)(7) of title 38, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>November 30, 2031</quote> and inserting <quote>January 31, 2032</quote>.</text></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date date="20250909">September 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

