<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="HC064EF98D120499881E4906EFA601B24" key="H">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3917 IH: To prohibit the participation of males in athletic programs or activities at the military service academies that are designated for women or girls.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3917</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20250611">June 11, 2025</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000301">Mr. Johnson of South Dakota</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To prohibit the participation of males in athletic programs or activities at the military service academies that are designated for women or girls.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H2837F48FF6B447D0B00F4A0A0D990C4F">
<section id="HB2B324E92C914FA69F8C8DF8012DB662" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Prohibition on participation of males in athletic programs or activities at the military service academies that are designated for women or girls</header>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H046838D4BAC54EB898B52F09FDC7F6FE"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that the United States Military Academy, the United States Naval Academy, and the United States Air Force Academy do not permit a person whose sex is male to participate in an athletic program or activity that is designated for women or girls.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF941E0CF72174F26BC89BC28FC4071E6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall be construed to prohibit a recipient from permitting males to train or practice with an athletic program or activity that is designated for women or girls so long as no female is deprived of a roster spot on a team or sport, opportunity to participate in a practice or competition, scholarship, admission to an educational institution, or any other benefit that accompanies participating in the athletic program or activity.</text></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3294D6F30FA8449595EEF6354E3637A6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text> <paragraph id="H9EFB279625B6441AAAAD53BF0D8D7D6A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>athletic programs and activities</term> includes all programs or activities that are provided conditional upon participation with any athletic team; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC8BC5A986D7941BA9152126971253806"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>sex</term> means a person’s reproductive biology and genetics at birth.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill>

