<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC7CEC7A4357F48BA890CC5ABB0D989C7" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5377 IH: Rural Health Training Opportunities Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5377</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250916">September 16, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require geographical diversity in the provision of health profession opportunity grants under section 2008 of the Social Security Act, and to require the support services provided through the use of the grants to include a transportation assistance plan.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H24DE1F30A9214550AD1A7876698A2854" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H2EA0A412F8BD4326AE5978EFB4930CAD" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Rural Health Training Opportunities Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H59F3943B994C478EAC68467E917BE9BB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Geographical diversity in provision of grants; inclusion of transportation assistance plan among support services</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2008 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1397g">42 U.S.C. 1397g</external-xref>) is amended by redesignating subsections (c) and (d) as subsections (d) and (e), respectively, and by inserting after subsection (b) the following:</text>
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4641E36749024E3B9FAC5FF8D151F7BF" style="OLC">
<subsection id="HBA94569EAF5F4E3B8A186D09BFFFB9BD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Geographical diversity; transportation assistance plan</header>
<paragraph id="H53FFBEB27E1742A9B27BC56DB7DB16CC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Preference for applications for projects to serve a rural area</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In considering applications for a grant under this section, the Secretary shall give preference to applications which describe a demonstration project that will serve a rural area in which—</text> <subparagraph id="H85DF8786557A4D228FF9BC40E9146421"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the community in which the individuals to be enrolled in the project reside is located;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H6E8015F262C14A48970A67CCFA1C4F56"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the project will be conducted; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB5917B3C669343E693593B56A47A6560"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an employer partnership that has committed to hiring individuals who successfully complete all activities under the project is located.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9983CD690C144E9196663E38AAB0EAC8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Support required to include transportation assistance plan</header><text>A project for which a grant is made under this section shall include a plan to provide project participants with transportation through means such as the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HCBF9D9EEF73C409F8666DB12B1BBFF9D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Referral to, and assistance with enrollment in, a subsidized transportation program.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HB847CDBDF65141E18519C306DE279BD8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>If a subsidized transportation program is not reasonably available, direct payments to subsidize transportation costs.</text></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>transportation</term> includes public transit, or gasoline for a personal vehicle if public transit is not reasonably accessible or available.</continuation-text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3B4FDD77035D4B178B73D9AB99367CAC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Reports to the congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During each Congress, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate a report—</text>
<subparagraph id="H07FA43203C9344B6966A31E69CB9630A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">on, with respect to the period since the period covered in the most recent prior report submitted under this paragraph—</text> <clause id="HE075E01DD8374B4F9D0A4DABC2ECEFBC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the number of applications submitted under each subsection of this section, with a separate statement of the number of applications referred to in paragraph (1); and</text></clause>
<clause id="HFF4DB9C6E5AB46C1B2D77A8820412AAA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of the applications that were approved, with a separate statement of the number of such applications referred to in paragraph (1); and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA289D451EC594BC99E18BE3B43ABC78C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that includes an assessment of the effectiveness of the demonstration projects conducted under this section with respect to addressing health professions workforce shortages or in-demand jobs in rural areas.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section>
<section id="H72A36D6297A44697B7804060A1DB5B5D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The amendments made by this Act shall take effect on October 1, 2025.</text></section> </legis-body></bill>

