<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H8CBA493A07334781A7AA7FE467C9C7BD" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4123 IH: Federal Improvement in Technology Procurement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4123</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250625">June 25, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001316">Mr. Burlison</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001230">Mr. Subramanyam</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000596">Mrs. Luna</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HSM00">Small Business</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To improve Federal technology procurement, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H5D655A46EF0A4035A00F83B976FF1B2B" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H0EA129DE883F404882A51376F3C90F59" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Federal Improvement in Technology Procurement Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>FIT Procurement Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H4108D8375E7A41B697DC8BDFD9CAB9BC"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="HDD45585E94A14A2C9EEF68CC41F0D2B7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Acquisition workforce</header><text>The term <term>acquisition workforce</term> means employees of an executive agency who are responsible for procurement, contracting, program or project management that involves the performance of acquisition-related functions, or others as designated by the Chief Acquisition Officer, senior procurement executive, or head of the contracting activity.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H96A9D5FB8C844C18802AFC601CCB29DE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator for Federal Procurement Policy.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC7B99C277C4E485984346AA6DB7B86C4" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Chief Acquisition Officer</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Chief Acquisition Officer</term> means a Chief Acquisition Officer appointed pursuant to section 1702 of title 41, United States Code.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCCC48F4DC77A4779B50FF0BB14E1D5EA"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Cross-functional</header><text>The term <term>cross-functional</term> means a structure in which individuals with different functional expertise or from different areas of an organization work together as a team.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H25B636D4C79D44DF9D87C066D4A93242"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Executive agency</header><text>The term <term>executive agency</term> has the meaning given the term in section 133 of title 41, United States Code.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3AE73E81416A4EEF8F2CC4DF2EDCBEB9"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Experiential learning</header><text>The term <term>experiential learning</term> means on-the-job experiences or simulations that serve to enhance workforce professional skills.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF272F6227D2740C6B83EC3D6B8F43073"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Information and communications technology</header><text>The term <term>information and communications technology</term>—</text> <subparagraph id="HBC09276E724C4AA39C733761403DD32C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has the meaning given the term in section 4713(k) of title 41, United States Code; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3100768CCB2A4E178177BDB184D6BC40"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes information and communications technologies covered by any definition contained in the Federal Acquisition Regulation, including a definition added after the date of the enactment of this Act by the Federal Acquisition Regulatory Council pursuant to notice and comment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBD31F143910A4C8C9CC7EBE3A719D27B"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Relevant committees of congress</header><text>The term <term>relevant committees of Congress</term> means the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9746E70A134842159C549BEAFCC62774" commented="no"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Senior procurement executive</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>senior procurement executive</term> means a senior procurement executive designated pursuant to section 1702(c) of title 41, United States Code.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9780A63527C3417BAE4993B465BC1E87"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Small business</header><text>The term <term>small business</term> has the meaning given the term <term>small business concern</term> in section 3 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/632">15 U.S.C. 632</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H698AC3A0FBAA42A3B7A58060AF6F5ADB"><enum>3.</enum><header>Acquisition workforce</header> 
<subsection id="H155F26D5F77E475389EC685A1C131FA0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Experiential learning</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Federal Acquisition Institute shall establish a pilot program to consider the incorporation of experiential learning into the Federal Credentials Program, the Federal Acquisition Certification-Contracting Officer’s Representative Program, and the Federal Acquisition Certification for Program and Project Managers Program, or any successor program.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H7F776771735B4962B09913C4A4D789CD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Training on information and communications technology acquisition</header> <paragraph id="H517E9B99C513494DBF9149D06F75E322"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of the Federal Acquisition Institute, in coordination with the Administrator, the Administrator of General Services, and the Administrator of the Office of Electronic Government, and in consultation with the heads of other executive agencies as determined to be appropriate by the Director of the Federal Acquisition Institute, shall develop and implement or otherwise provide a cross-functional information and communications technology acquisition training program for acquisition workforce members involved in acquiring information and communications technology. The training shall do the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H4988B1E1D09049358A6A942CCE1FE6D1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Include learning objectives related to market research, communicating with industry and industry perspectives on the procurement process, including how investment decisions are impacted by Government communication and engagement, developing requirements, acquisition planning, best practices for developing and executing outcome-based contracts, and source selection strategy, evaluating proposals, and awarding and administering contracts for information and communications technology.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6AD60F5A99B24AF3B4BA2A640255FB1F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Include learning objectives that provide a basic understanding of key technologies executive agencies need, such as cloud computing, artificial intelligence and artificial intelligence-enabled applications, and cybersecurity solutions.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H06DCA56B702449E19623193F9A36B00B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Include learning objectives that encourage the use of commercial or commercially available off-the-shelf technologies to the greatest extent practicable.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H260627BF7729417494699DA7D93C9E78"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Include case studies of lessons learned from Federal information and communications technology procurements and contracts, and related matters as determined to be relevant by the Director of the Federal Acquisition Institute.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H283A876313A9449581FCEE48A07F790A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Include experiential learning opportunities, and opportunities to practice acquisition teaming involving collaboration of team members with varied relevant domain expertise to complete acquisition-related tasks, including tasks with accelerated timelines.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0DD523D06A7C4065B609974DF508355A"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Include continuous learning recommendations and resources to keep the skills of acquisition workforce members current, including tools that help adopt or adapt the use of innovative acquisition practices or other flexible business practices commonly used in commercial buys.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H41CA324DC2694E9291053C9D547EF6BA"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Be made available to acquisition workforce members designated by a Chief Acquisition Officer, senior procurement executive, or head of the contracting activity to participate in the training program.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H60CC4410BD74454B90A8D44CECF5C5AE"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Inform executive agencies about streamlined and alternative procurement methods for procurement of information and communications technology, including—</text> 
<clause id="H1F0762F78ED646CB973D2EF1B922DB03"><enum>(i)</enum><text>simplified procedures for certain commercial products and commercial services in accordance with subpart 13.5 of the Federal Acquisition Regulation, prize competitions under the America COMPETES Reauthorization Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/358">Public Law 111–358</external-xref>), competitive programs that encourage businesses to engage in Federal research or research and development with the potential for commercialization, and joint venture partnerships;</text></clause> <clause id="H5EB3BE8690F346E4AAB2C072775E6CDD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>innovative procurement techniques designed to streamline the procurement process and lower barriers to entry, such as use of oral presentations and product demonstrations instead of lengthy written proposals, appropriately leveraging performance and outcomes-based contracting, and other techniques discussed on the Periodic Table of Acquisition Innovations or other similar successor knowledge management portals; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H4FC28FB3F6324B4E93C4BFDE5A9F9283"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>information on appropriate use, examples and templates, and any other information determined relevant by the Administrator to assist contracting officers and other members of the acquisition workforce in using the procedures described in clauses (i) and (ii).</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD2EFB3F72197402283894E81EF66AFAB"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Incorporate learning objectives to identify and mitigate waste, fraud, and abuse and ensure the protection of established privacy, civil rights, and civil liberties in the procurement process.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8C60C46C572A4472B0690B080EEE7991"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of the Federal Acquisition Institute shall provide to the relevant committees of Congress, the Chief Acquisition Officers Council, and the Chief Information Officers Council—</text> <subparagraph id="HDEFE5C3BD870483B99E3AB97F40B2E99"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a report on the progress of the Director in developing and implementing or otherwise providing the information and communications technology acquisition training described in paragraph (1); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA95EED819FF94B78A9CDA0A9716DEF9B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a list of any acquisition training that the Director determines to be outdated or no longer necessary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H962323B0EAF54C778159CE4628666282"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>The training program shall be updated as appropriate, but at least every 2 years after implementation, and offered for a minimum of 6 years following the date of implementation of the training program.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HAF2CBA254BFC420EA3A3472427467FC8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Acquisition workforce training fund</header><text>Section 1703(i)(3) of title 41, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>Five percent</quote> and inserting <quote>Seven and a half percent</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HFC859395B6134E8997C1504B7B0E8FBF"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Harmonization of acquisition workforce training requirements</header><text>Section 2 of the Artificial Intelligence Training for the Acquisition Workforce Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/207">Public Law 117–207</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/41/1703">41 U.S.C. 1703</external-xref> note) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HF06ACD8E7AF74643869F461E0D486E29"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(4), by striking <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">Director.</header-in-text>—The term <term>Director</term> means the Director of the Office of Management and Budget.</quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">Administrator.</header-in-text>—The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of General Services.</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE0711FB420C14452919EC9000D7D6D12"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H9A57DB6A626E4EE2A8FB261413425B8C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>Director, in coordination with the Administrator of General Services and any other person determined relevant by the Director</quote> and inserting <quote>Administrator, in coordination with the Director of the Office of Management and Budget</quote>;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE80135CB4FED411C8C59F2E56EC4B3D0"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (4), by striking <quote>Director</quote> and inserting <quote>Administrator</quote>;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDA9FB13312B1467D8A34014D60601B68"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (5), by striking <quote>Director</quote> and inserting <quote>Administrator</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBA94F62AD6C847A7B9E41AE9737AB9DD"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (6), by striking <quote>Director</quote> and inserting <quote>Administrator</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HE4E31AF038CA457F9867759B3D207944"><enum>4.</enum><header>Innovative procurement methods</header> 
<subsection id="H7161506688B94BAB9FC761430BE0F422"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Increase in simplified acquisition threshold</header><text>Section 134 of title 41, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>$250,000</quote> and inserting <quote>$500,000</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H8FA9CC594A4042619A3D3816C0A6FAC8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Increase in micro purchase threshold</header><text>Section 1902(a)(1) of title 41, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>$10,000</quote> and inserting <quote>$25,000.</quote>.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H28E7A97BF77B40D3B163638FCB883E92"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Advances for commercial technology subscriptions and tenancy</header><text>Section 3324(d) of title 31, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H3B880BEB284C49399102DC426CCFB04D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)(C), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H876EAF7C54974112982286564EC20EDB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text> <subparagraph id="H32110C8E92DC449196D67B1331F4EADD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>or commercially available content</quote> after <quote>publication</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H12E9DD01BD1345C8BD21A55E633E4956"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF1824F6A981E4A6EAFD6C5E5796FD5CC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HE672EA69D03E450E9103F7EEF1EA3F1E" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="H2A9247CA772240E9B919CB5000BE2269"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">charges for information and communications technology subscriptions, reservations, or tenancy, which means the sharing of computing resources in a private or public environment, including cloud environments, for which the ordering agency defines appropriate access and security standards.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H21FE0692F25841F0848CFDA054DA98D4"><enum>5.</enum><header>Increasing competition in Federal contracting</header> <subsection id="HA170D67E91AA475BBA0D87E7FC016417"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Use of past performance</header> <paragraph id="HF95CF2B834434B3A98BD11AA5FEB4B7B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall issue guidance, including examples and templates where appropriate, on—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H19EFA0630EDD4086A4961ADB37C1153D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>when a wider range of projects, such as commercial or non-government, as well as Government projects, should be accepted as relevant past performance, in order to have increased competition among eligible firms with capability to perform a requirement, such as a requirement without much precedent;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB42B8A66E13C4FA9BF48D9AA40E50E03"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a means by which an agency may validate non-government past performance references, such as by requiring an official of an entity providing past performance references to attest to their authenticity and by providing verifiable contact information for the references; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H36DDEA86140041AD9B7DEE12553FB2BC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>use of alternative evaluation methods other than past performance that may be appropriate for a requirement without much precedent, such as demonstrations and testing of technologies as part of the proposal process.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDD1D4E906B834968B357EA496F41A3E2" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Supplement not supplant</header><text>The guidance issued under paragraph (1) shall supplement existing Federal and agency policy and procedures for consideration of past performance and other evaluation factors and methods.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8131459144314E4888BE8BC5909EF2CE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Enhancing competition in Federal procurement</header> 
<paragraph id="H6D1B9ED378744B75BFE63A48DF9CB6E8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Council recommendations</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall convene the Chief Acquisition Officers Council (in this section referred to as the <quote>Council</quote>), to make recommendations to identify and eliminate specific, unnecessary procedural barriers that disproportionately affect the ability of small businesses to compete for Federal contracts, with a focus on streamlining documentation and qualification requirements unrelated to the protection of privacy and civil liberties.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H73D9D155DF9246A6B51AB6E3525EB448"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>The Council shall obtain input from the public, including from the APEX Accelerators program (formerly known as Procurement Technical Assistance Center network) and other contractor representatives, to identify Federal procurement policies and regulations that are obsolete, overly burdensome or restrictive, not adequately harmonized, or otherwise serve to create barriers to small business participation in Federal contracting or unnecessarily increase bid and proposal costs.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFAAF404C4F3044DC9A3FEBC911E49EB8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Examination of actions</header><text>The Council shall consider the input obtained under paragraph (2) and any other information determined to be relevant by the Council to identify legislative, regulatory, and other actions to increase competition and remove barriers to small business participation in the procurement process.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA2D7BEC5374346649FF05F4EAE47C567"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator, in consultation with the Federal Acquisition Regulatory Council, the Chief Acquisition Officers Council, and other executive agencies as appropriate, shall implement the regulatory and other non-legislative actions identified under paragraph (3), as determined necessary by the Administrator, to remove barriers to entry for small businesses seeking to participate in Federal Government procurement.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H662CEF618EEB4ED8AF315484750D31E6"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Briefing</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall brief the relevant committees of Congress on the legislative actions identified under paragraph (3), and the actions implemented under paragraph (4).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HCA3465E502CA470DA4A490385F292B3C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consideration of cost-Efficiency and quality</header><text>The Administrator shall advocate for and prioritize contracting policies that ensure that cost-efficiency and quality of goods and services are key determining factors in awarding Federal contracts.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H1910AB319BE64B9CA10DBF650EF82088"><enum>6.</enum><header>Comptroller general assessment of small business participation in Federal procurement</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress and make publicly available a report that—</text> <paragraph id="HBCFF74A2A4364878B0E4994DDE29F4C4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>assesses the current level of small business participation in Federal procurement, identifying barriers, opportunities, and the impact of existing policies on the ability of small businesses to compete in Federal procurement;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD7765B49D26448DD92B3429BF4A5AE52"><enum>(2)</enum><text>catalogs and evaluates the effectiveness of programs intended to support small business participation in Federal procurement; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5F4F44D6E1CA4335A327221882713130"><enum>(3)</enum><text>analyzes trends in small business involvement in Federal technology projects, including data on contract awards, the diversity of sectors represented, and the geographic distribution of small business contractors.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H8BC25B333C294D2DAEE29658A67F0E19"><enum>7.</enum><header>Conflict of interest procedures</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Federal Acquisition Regulatory Council and the Administrator shall update the Federal Acquisition Regulation as necessary to provide additional guidance to executive agencies to address personal and organizational conflicts of interest involving members of the acquisition workforce.</text></section> <section id="HA6A9B1012FEE44E5B8AA32B3C320A601"><enum>8.</enum><header>No additional funding</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No additional funds are authorized to be appropriated for the purpose of carrying out this Act.</text></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

