<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-BAG25I15-HPH-D4-F9J"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2988 IS: Veterans' Infrastructure and Transformation Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2988</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251008">October 8, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S347">Mr. Moran</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSVA00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To bolster upgrades and infrastructure for lasting development at the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id357fc39f22124a5383a8dd2b42d3f946"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Veterans' Infrastructure and Transformation Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>VITAL Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8e695c93dfc340dc87d8696c41b90e5c"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text><toc><toc-entry level="section" idref="S1">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id82a04198cd474449a5c99b965f29eb61">Sec. 2. Modification of authority for sharing of health-care resources of Department of Veterans Affairs to include flexible space utilization and streamlined service agreements.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id387a54e25a264b8e8a6a6506221292c9">Sec. 3. Use of commercial construction and facilities code and standards.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="ide1f876febd9a469ab93a5c6bac20f3db">Sec. 4. Exchanges of real property via enhanced-use lease.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="iddb655c8d3a5144f880044660cdb7a296">Sec. 5. Pilot program on authority of Secretary of Veterans Affairs to enter into enhanced-use leases for noncash consideration.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id04b5a56716c7406cbc9fba069ef5ebeb">Sec. 6. Feasibility studies for outleasing facilities of Department of Veterans Affairs.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id10cab2f68b564950a50d39abd027b2f4">Sec. 7. Report on strategic plan for infrastructure and capital assets of Department of Veterans Affairs.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id7375b3a8d736475781397557d8762020">Sec. 8. Contracting for construction project management services.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HDC3B807CCBDD49BE8BF1D0A24D31EEDE">Sec. 9. Expansion and extension of pilot program on acceptance by the Department of Veterans Affairs of donated facilities and related improvements.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id167ed388d7b849f393bcc32a6c6838f6">Sec. 10. Reforming requirements and authorities of Director of Construction and Facilities Management of Department of Veterans Affairs.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="ide8631b110e7b4065adf463dc32595160">Sec. 11. Consolidation of construction and leasing activities of Department of Veterans Affairs.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idc318c701250349b8966f84fbb9056868">Sec. 12. Consolidation of Department of Veterans Affairs acquisition, procurement, and logistics.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idfd8eea1eb7c640cc9c7f6bf4d2795803">Sec. 13. Reports to Congress.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id72b412d537f34c978d39f84da9ab6bdc">Sec. 14. General limitation on obligations.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section><section id="id82a04198cd474449a5c99b965f29eb61"><enum>2.</enum><header>Modification of authority for sharing of health-care resources of Department of Veterans Affairs to include flexible space utilization and streamlined service agreements</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 8153 of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id261a0c4ea55542feb99543ef06bd1900"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (a)(3)—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1f90a45fabca48d8a543c30279458c83"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (A), by inserting <quote>physical</quote> before <quote>space</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6f87e7a0fe3c42c6941d89e23ebed360"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)(i), by inserting <quote>physical</quote> before <quote>space</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb7e8644efcc545e7b24ebc9d4e3472ac"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (E);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id36f7db94febc42bfba3d390a7e496296"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating subparagraphs (C) and (D) as subparagraphs (D) and (E), respectively;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb3cb15315bd84641a54f7a5665110c30"><enum>(E)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (B) the following new subparagraph (C):</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb1f4c841757e4e8886196178301ea94d"><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8d32daf27f904d658917bc9d12a7a959" indent="up2"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the health-care resource required is physical space or common services and is to be acquired from an institution affiliated with the Department in accordance with section 7302 of this title or another entity, the Secretary may make arrangements, by contract, resource-sharing agreement, space-sharing agreement, or other form of agreement, for the acquisition of the space or service—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8d7f62cba2e84507a702b8d5642fe45e"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">without regard to any law or regulation (including any Executive order, circular, or other administrative policy) that would otherwise require the use of competitive procedures for acquiring the resource; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd10c385509ca47488356fe2166c999c9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if all obligations are funded through available appropriations or borne by the institution or entity, without regard to any limitations applicable to leases of the Department.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id14f62a5018c04c93a52caeccc7dbb0a9"><enum>(F)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D), as redesignated by subparagraph (D) of this paragraph, by striking <quote>subparagraph (A) or (B)</quote> and inserting <quote>subparagraph (A), (B), or (C)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3fc03369c6e94d5e9266bff355623b84"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcc44328265344e60a948a442973d2fc7"><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9771cecbea72464b80087ed9649b18fa"><enum>(h)</enum><text>In this section:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idec77aa0a95d54dbfb774fd1d2ddc6505"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>commercial service</term> means a service that is offered and sold competitively in the commercial marketplace, is performed under standard commercial terms and conditions, and is procured using firm-fixed price contracts.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idee51bbd9536d41bcbc66f0437ce15ab8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>common service</term> means a commercial service necessary to maintain or operate physical space, including maintenance, heating, ventilation, air conditioning, electricity, energy, water, wastewater, landscaping, security, laundry, or any other service as determined by the Secretary.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5ea4d4e44655444983a182bcaaa35b3e"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <term>physical space</term> means one or more buildings, a portion of a building, or parking facilities.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id387a54e25a264b8e8a6a6506221292c9"><enum>3.</enum><header>Use of commercial construction and facilities code and standards</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id868bdd8891e54d5097b02c6e5ec42c85"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs may use commercial codes and standards instead of or in addition to Federal codes and standards in the construction or alteration of facilities of the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text></subsection><subsection id="id88003a4d258d4fc5836ec0de53d02923"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Pilot projects</header><text>The Secretary shall undertake not fewer than 3 pilot projects during each of fiscal years 2027, 2028, 2029, 2030, and 2031 utilizing commercial codes and standards instead of Federal codes and standards to lease or construct facilities of the Department.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfb6ee2770bab438aa6165c28f6fc1b94"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reports</header><text>The Secretary shall submit a report to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the House of Representatives not later than 90 days after the end of each of fiscal years 2027, 2028, 2029, 2030, and 2031 detailing the use by the Secretary of the authority provided by subsection (a) and conduct of each pilot project required by subsection (b) that was initiated, ongoing, or completed during the fiscal year.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id059335a9fabe4305b04622db7cda4edb"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5d554d38355a4f4c895117f9e0467121"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>commercial codes and standards</term> means building codes or standards of the following:</text><subparagraph id="idde3571c794934c66904418445b57ad63"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The National Fire Protection Association.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide7087c75fe1e4ec5bb76551bffe410f0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The International Code Council.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id861895949be54beebee2b9e0bffc62e1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The American Society for Testing and Materials.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idaa4265e5526342eba2759c1119b9760b"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The American Society of Civil Engineers.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf9bd05d04f7e47dd911e5473b1063896"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The State or local jurisdiction in which the facility of the Department for which the Secretary is applying the authority in subsection (a) is located.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8dc9e71829024d57a8277b3355dbc087"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>Federal codes and standards</term> means the following:</text><subparagraph id="id7a9dbc4390e94adda864fd3f897081f9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Technical Information Library of the Department.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id44bd696f40fb403497b6609e422001e3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Unified Facilities Criteria of the Department of Defense.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id12edcd6717c944c197a6d76d827504a7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Building codes or standards of Federal agencies other than the Department.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide1f876febd9a469ab93a5c6bac20f3db"><enum>4.</enum><header>Exchanges of real property via enhanced-use lease</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 8162(b) of title 38, United States Code, is amended by striking paragraphs (2) through (6) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide3467cf9148c4fa68c9845cd7d3315f2"><paragraph id="id17bb3704438e4b81bdade673664d8c49" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id1c4160ad07e644ed86d38ebf6a85a19e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>For any enhanced-use lease entered into by the Secretary, the lease consideration provided to the Secretary shall consist solely of cash at fair value as determined by the Secretary, except in the case of an exchange of leased properties assessed to be of similar value.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idefb27230273747b0a7e62d1cee27fed6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Secretary may enter into an enhanced-use lease without receiving consideration.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0ecf1a51a91540d9b4a6ea2825209be7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Secretary may not waive or postpone the obligation of a lessee to pay any consideration under an enhanced-use lease, including monthly rent.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id3c05e9da92a341d5b17fcd5e2b986239" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The terms of an enhanced-use lease may provide for the Secretary to use minor construction funds for capital contribution payments.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idcb535d750a2f41e79b8540dcfeb9db4a" indent="up1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Office of Management and Budget shall review each enhanced-use lease before the lease goes into effect.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="iddb655c8d3a5144f880044660cdb7a296"><enum>5.</enum><header>Pilot program on authority of Secretary of Veterans Affairs to enter into enhanced-use leases for noncash consideration</header><subsection id="id911f2413a81a4417b7282b8177fe82a1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Pilot program required</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall carry out a pilot program to assess the feasibility and advisability of entering into enhanced-use leases for noncash consideration.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc2169d617d504a6e909aa7eadfeb4793"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Enhanced-Use leases</header><text>Under the pilot program required by subsection (a), the Secretary shall enter into at least one enhanced-use lease, but not more than three enhanced-use leases, under section 8162 of title 38, United States Code.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3bb372f4e3274fc2b5612a5a8fcb52b5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Locations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The enhanced-use leases entered into under the pilot program required by subsection (a) shall be in such locations as the Secretary considers appropriate for purposes of the pilot program.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6b48fec2238444db91eae2d9947821da"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Consideration</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfb03a3c4631a4352bd99b5c0e2faceba"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding paragraphs (3)(A), (3)(B), and (5) of section 8162(b) of such title and subject to the availability of appropriations and the provisions of this subsection, for an enhanced-use lease entered into by the Secretary under the pilot program required by subsection (a), the lease consideration provided to the Secretary may consist of noncash consideration at fair value as determined by the Secretary.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaead5ab66e1c47978c90ba1d09acbb58"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Noncash consideration received for an enhanced-use lease under the pilot program required by subsection (a) may consist of only the following:</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddba4e100739d46d592cb4b49203fafc5"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title transfer of real property.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id986e2c038acb470091831ac027291f18"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Infrastructure improvements.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf558684021e44f73a74e02a081ae02f3"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Design services.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd2fa10ec898943b0ba2ab7e808d7e0cf"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Construction services.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id231197346039478f8ae318ada1c72402"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The authority to accept consideration described in paragraph (1) shall be subject to the following:</text><subparagraph id="id5fb055d472e541bd8c2846b08bcf80cd"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Any facility accepted as noncash consideration for an enhanced-use lease is substantially complete within 10 years of entering into the enhanced-use lease, excluding commissioning and warranty services.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf55ee6d330494ef79414cc9ee000bb5b"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The partner entity assumes full responsibility for all maintenance, operations, and service costs associated with noncash consideration for the duration of the enhanced-use lease and any subsequent use by the Department, unless explicitly funded through appropriations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idf37f779f5bf946afa0c3226480d6bbd7"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Capital Asset Fund</header><text>Notwithstanding section 8118(b)(3) of title 38, United States Code, amounts in the Department of Veterans Affairs Capital Asset Fund may be used for enhanced-use leases under the pilot program required by subsection (a) for the purposes of subparagraph (C) of such section, without reference to the amount limitation in section 8104(a)(3)(A) of such title, if such use is subject to the availability of appropriations.</text></subsection><subsection id="id4452eae443c64dc8b23cfa677cfc7c07"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Fiscal oversight and reporting</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2f2668ea81e542da8a1301b51189e672"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For each fiscal year, not later than 90 days after the last day of the fiscal year, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the enhanced-use leases entered into under the pilot program required by subsection (a) that were in effect in that fiscal year.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcca7f26595444744bac7dcb275f0e023"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Each report submitted pursuant to paragraph (1) shall include, for the fiscal year covered by the report, the following:</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4f7159d9c67a4baf874dacf4dd6cac6c"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Details of the fiscal impact of each enhanced-use lease entered into under the pilot program required by subsection (a) that was in effect, including the following:</text><clause id="id39b0fccc305e4e44a7eac2921bf7c924"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Comprehensive budget justification for all obligations incurred.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5a8181d43eb8429c888c0fc9155cf100"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The funding sources for such obligations.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb09e4829f70e49459ffe7cc8dc0dc857"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Confirmation that all associated costs are within appropriated budgets.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id30b8b5426fa048dc9a3104dbb125ce43"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of any potential future costs and mitigation strategies to ensure compliance with discretionary funding.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ide8f9c34204344bf79049649b6edd65aa"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Limitation on obligations</header><text>No enhanced-use lease under the pilot program required by subsection (a) shall impose a financial or operational obligation on the Department beyond the availability of appropriations, and any agreement regarding an enhanced-use lease shall include a provision ensuring that maintenance, operations, or service costs associated with noncash consideration is borne by the partner entity or explicitly funded through appropriations for the entire lifecycle of the enhanced-use lease or facility use.</text></subsection><subsection id="id9314c078a20a4de68bb19f822cff0c43"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>The authorities provided under this section shall terminate on the date that is seven years after the date of the enactment of this Act. Such termination shall not affect the validity or terms of an enhanced-use lease entered into under this section, consideration accepted under this section, or the availability of amounts for an enhanced-use lease, provided that all obligations remain subject to the availability of appropriations.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5333e7e7c3c74ad08d5a8f65f9facc42"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Definition of enhanced-Use lease</header><text>In this section, the term <term>enhanced-use lease</term> has the meaning given such term in section 8162(a)(1) of title 38, United States Code.</text></subsection></section><section id="id04b5a56716c7406cbc9fba069ef5ebeb"><enum>6.</enum><header>Feasibility studies for outleasing facilities of Department of Veterans Affairs</header><subsection id="id8da5c21b5bf8458cb2940f375ca85503"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs, subject to the availability of funds for such purposes, may conduct feasibility studies to evaluate the potential outleasing of existing medical facilities of the Department of Veterans Affairs to generate resources, including in-kind consideration such as the construction of new facilities at alternative locations, to meet current and future health care needs of veterans.</text></subsection><subsection id="idc1857919e7b74bf68968913b2dbd9683"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>Each feasibility study conducted under subsection (a) shall—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb50e2200c62342b28b9190b98181abf1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assess the financial, operational, and strategic impacts of outleasing medical facilities of the Department, including the potential for reinvesting proceeds or in-kind contributions into new or modernized facilities of the Department; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0dd9dd0b42364a1bbbe7cece10bc4bb8"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consider that any resulting obligations in connection with such outleasing shall be funded through appropriations or borne by the partner entity for the entire lifecycle of the outleasing arrangement.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id86dbbadda3de446cbf95618f98c3885b"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than one year after conducting any feasibility study under subsection (a), the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report detailing—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1b442c3f9b8646a48801a12547d0c916"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the findings of the Secretary with respect to such study;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2d70cd1240cd4872941ff5b3a52290d2"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the recommendations of the Secretary for potential outleasing arrangements pursuant to such study; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id71f1a8d776e24876a2b434ccd8b7429c"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a budget justification confirming that all costs for such arrangements are within appropriated funds or covered by the partner entity.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id10cab2f68b564950a50d39abd027b2f4"><enum>7.</enum><header>Report on strategic plan for infrastructure and capital assets of Department of Veterans Affairs</header><subsection id="idee393cf5d5ee43d8897eb1662c42e58d"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on the strategic plan for infrastructure and capital assets of the Department of Veterans Affairs, which summarizes a facility lifecycle strategy targeting modernization of owned and leased facilities and infrastructure required to mitigate increasing systemic failures, veteran and staff safety, benefits delivery interruptions, and funding associated to address emergency repairs.</text></subsection><subsection id="id8abd65b8dd2e470ab1ca77bf4638bbfb"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall cover known and projected requirements over a period of not less than 10 years for the following:</text><paragraph id="id689dda40852840cb90e619cbc6772bf4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Land acquisition.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id189fe8f4ae874b20aac8e7c0907c71e5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Operations and maintenance of facilities of the existing capital asset portfolio of the Department.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7ca39affbc954dafb0364d47ec1d0a29"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Operations and maintenance of the planned future capital asset portfolio of the Department.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddf069962f5aa4cffa6135cf5b540833f"><enum>(4)</enum><text>New construction, disaggregated by type of new construction, including the following types of construction:</text><subparagraph id="id2f6efbae587b4acb83ad367bb88e3d6e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Major construction.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idabaca899bfce43f9a8ce7e1b3349bb46"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Minor construction.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0e61e10a142f4d719daa592ad93b7f53"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Nonrecurring maintenance.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id6e48bfb1bc0f4cd9b51a427492896cd7"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Leasing.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0d6b432c6fa24b26b0d81ac26249a5f5"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Alternative acquisition methods, such as partnerships and donations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1921998d1fe14678b4f0a343e1ca22fb"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Activation of space.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idcc88a5216d0f40deb3e07807a6c00829"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Disposal, reuse, and remediation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb7e1b09e17c442cf8d5e59cc3f2996c1"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Facility lifecycle strategy process supporting the planning, programming delivery, management, and maintenance of the current and future capital asset portfolio of the Department.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id16e5b6a4c3554ec7af13108b18173e6e"><enum>(10)</enum><text>A discussion of the negative effect of the lack of stable and predictable capital asset funding on the ability of the Department to plan, staff, and execute effective capital asset management.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id19fa2f3c0db743efb38a0d4d14d8b561"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Such other matters as the Secretary considers appropriate, including with respect to legislative or administrative action, provided such actions are subject to the availability of appropriated funds.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id12a85e1fa87d4f0d85ad73c02470d4b7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section or a report submitted under this section shall be construed to create or imply any financial or operational obligation beyond the availability of appropriated funds.</text></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7375b3a8d736475781397557d8762020"><enum>8.</enum><header>Contracting for construction project management services</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subject to the availability of appropriations, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs may contract with private entities for comprehensive construction project management services, including the provision of entire project teams. Such teams shall be led by an official designated by the Secretary, and the services shall be treated as a contracted service rather than individual personnel hires.</text></section><section section-type="subsequent-section" id="HDC3B807CCBDD49BE8BF1D0A24D31EEDE" changed="not-changed"><enum>9.</enum><header>Expansion and extension of pilot program on acceptance by the Department of Veterans Affairs of donated facilities and related improvements</header><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H506174DB0D3B4ED3B98D9C829C6098A1" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Expansion</header><paragraph id="HFF366238C499463B9A94BFDB04107DA1" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (a)(1) of section 2 of the Communities Helping Invest through Property and Improvements Needed for Veterans Act of 2016 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/294">Public Law 114–294</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/8103">38 U.S.C. 8103</external-xref> note) is amended—</text><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA5A9EE3B2ADB4911BE48097CB8915EF8" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>property</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H49DB3F8B85D049B29500FB0E1EC6FCB2" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAB1F1AFF558F4A2A913CCBBBAB42267B" changed="not-changed"><subparagraph id="H5A98F84A09E74A97B7E670217C378E31" changed="not-changed"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A minor construction or nonrecurring maintenance project of the Department.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD436A55BCC1C42C7A72B2101E8503A2F" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such section is further amended—</text><subparagraph id="HEE08D63D82DF40DFA7E71734B98FF26E" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text><clause id="HD32E2CEF1F084E128A5461469033321A" changed="not-changed"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">of property</header-in-text></quote>;</text></clause><clause id="HBB36443F3A3C472C81EFAE7CF62F2905" changed="not-changed"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by striking <quote>the donation of a property</quote> and inserting <quote>a donation</quote>;</text></clause><clause id="HF0A6F342FB2040E0887B97D2FD16A0DE" changed="not-changed"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text><subclause changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9e9cb5b383684901a2f4b62db619d22b"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting <quote>or project</quote> after <quote>property</quote> each place it appears; and</text></subclause><subclause changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6d76f92db1e5454683b069e374e9ed8c"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)(ii), by inserting <quote>or the five-year development plan of the Department</quote> after <quote>priority list</quote>; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H1A001E572980453C9FD1A2BBF4463609" changed="not-changed"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by inserting <quote>project,</quote> after <quote>improvements,</quote>;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBE9A6C95696844DABB4CCD34FC22060C" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (c)—</text><clause id="H70B700BADC4A40B6A00EA5C5F3F8A740" changed="not-changed"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text><subclause id="H74ED9F58789B4704A047AEEEF11C6658" changed="not-changed"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>real property and improvements donated under the pilot program</quote> and inserting <quote>a donation</quote>;</text></subclause><subclause id="HBADA531DFE874D93B0D3FFC9F6ED3600" changed="not-changed"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>; or</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text></subclause><subclause id="H658FB2D85B5343518EF0049A8197C027" changed="not-changed"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (B)(ii), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H7CAE815183B94EC5AEF0106AEDD7F377" changed="not-changed"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBEDD9194363C4DD28891644A5A9A6F7C" changed="not-changed"><subparagraph id="H069FA7DA89AA4F5E8C493066CE34F12E" changed="not-changed"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the performance of a minor construction or nonrecurring maintenance project of the Department.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subclause></clause><clause id="H86D692E507DE4A728352DDF3DF9A49A7" changed="not-changed"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text><subclause id="H4BBCC4F105184D4899E8784784AA8261" changed="not-changed"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>construction of the facility</quote> and inserting <quote>donation</quote>;</text></subclause><subclause id="H57AB4285BEE7484F82C1F74E8AB3A24D" changed="not-changed"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (B), by inserting <quote>maintaining,</quote> after <quote>altering,</quote>; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H4069538346D44C368F5A80F73BB43E28" changed="not-changed"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>construction of the facility</quote> and inserting <quote>donation</quote>;</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7AD334778CB9445F93663BFBDE1D44F4" changed="not-changed"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (e)(1)—</text><clause id="H8408637628274D73AF4773FD8F5439FB" changed="not-changed"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)—</text><subclause id="HB4E45B9CCE3443708278FE681FADC6FE" changed="not-changed"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>alter, maintain,</quote> after <quote>design,</quote>;</text></subclause><subclause id="H23EDBECEDE0F427CA98D77EFB90A1921" changed="not-changed"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by striking <quote>real property and improvements donated</quote> and inserting <quote>a donation</quote>; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H7A26E221B6F84B9FB94FA33F279F4AC0" changed="not-changed"><enum>(III)</enum><text>by striking <quote>of the real property and improvements</quote>; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HEE2F7CCC680441DF8CDE66CDB2649F8B" changed="not-changed"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (B)—</text><subclause changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idef6129a627294fb7ad8772c941f19b3f"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the matter preceding clause (i), by inserting <quote>alter, maintain,</quote> after <quote>design,</quote>; and</text></subclause><subclause changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2a19fa3441644762af723b27101c6136"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in clause (ii)(I), by striking <quote>construction and donation of the real property and improvements</quote> and inserting <quote>donation</quote>; and</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFCC08748344547F4964BEFC615AE76C7" changed="not-changed"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in subsection (g)—</text><clause changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida9a400c24e164f3a98a7bbc456515236"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (1)—</text><subclause changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1e80aedc71704feaa0e03d17f7f30787"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>real property and improvements donated</quote> and inserting <quote>donations</quote>; and</text></subclause><subclause changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0ce9b8a7d9a14d8d88fd503d08855980"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by striking <quote>that property</quote> and inserting <quote>that donation</quote>; and</text></subclause></clause><clause changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7b56af62c1a5485b89588a49e55ef5a6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text><subclause changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0723a974f29d431aa10be40ab77fa3a6"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>of real property and improvements conducted</quote>; and</text></subclause><subclause changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf689a7ca26144f5690ede715429b7a11"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by striking <quote>that property</quote> and inserting <quote>those donations</quote>.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8922A3C4F68D4489BEB70D5C5DE05EC0" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Extension</header><text>Such section is further amended, in subsection (i), by striking <quote>December 16, 2026</quote> and inserting <quote>December 16, 2031</quote>.</text></subsection></section><section id="id167ed388d7b849f393bcc32a6c6838f6"><enum>10.</enum><header>Reforming requirements and authorities of Director of Construction and Facilities Management of Department of Veterans Affairs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 312A of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id184f842df7524fd2aa06971d8e91e339"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (a)(4), by inserting <quote>, the Under Secretary for Health, and the Chief Acquisition Officer</quote> after <quote>Deputy Secretary</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2b7537db816d48668af1a7c0ef780fb6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id73975BDEA3684F779EE78CD0F532BF99"><subsection id="id29a6c01de0794ce9a6a33bec022283f7"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Supervision of employees</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idbf2126b8df124de3aae266beb9addeb1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>All employees of the Department engaged in the following activities shall report to the Director of Construction and Facilities Management:</text><subparagraph id="id8c8307c6fa564eab87468b895c187d6d" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Planning, design, and construction of facilities and infrastructure of the Department, including major medical facility projects and minor medical facility projects.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd7c752122be343f2b1bc5e8a8433d04b" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Developing and updating short-range and long-range strategic capital investment strategies and plans of the Department.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idef1581e43d9f47ebb008f302e1443caf" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Leasing of real property by the Department, including short-term, long-term, major medical facility leases, and minor medical facility leases.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id74edfd7bafc94899891c0e05b779b1a3" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Repair, maintenance, and operation of facilities of the Department, including custodial services, building management and administration, and maintenance of roads, grounds, and infrastructure.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id20deb49812ab483f97a00d417e3a8d99" indent="up1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Procurement and acquisition of major medical facility projects, minor medical facility projects, major medical facility leases, minor medical facility leases, operation, design, furnishing, and supplies and equipment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb28c78273e614cfeac07e0118c72f4cd"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection:</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id02076d245ef245c08616f2d8e838d939"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The term <term>major medical facility lease</term> has the meaning given such term in section 8104(a)(3) of this title.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6ba7b59a618c48f9a1679d6f6bc2cb68"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>major medical facility project</term> has the meaning given such term in section 8104(a)(3) of this title.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id00edcad82aff4a7f8c9b9f40049d1c5e"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The term <term>minor medical facility project</term> means a project for the construction, alteration, or acquisition of a medical facility that is not a major medical facility project.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id587d7000155b4652a0130e41b658c70e"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>minor medical facility lease</term> means a lease for space for uses as a new medical facility that is not a major medical facility lease.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="ide8631b110e7b4065adf463dc32595160"><enum>11.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Consolidation of construction and leasing activities of Department of Veterans Affairs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall—</text><paragraph id="id246c1a93ad964471adbd244e5a221518"><enum>(1)</enum><text>consolidate the functions of the Veterans Benefits Administration, the Veterans Health Administration, and the National Cemetery Administration described in subsection (c) of section 312A of title 38, United States Code, under the Director of Construction and Facilities Management;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide73c4f6fccd848b982a8369c9ce036e9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>consolidate the employees of the Veterans Benefits Administration, the Veterans Health Administration, and the National Cemetery Administration described in subsection (d) of such section, as added by section 3, under the Director of Construction and Facilities Management; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id22b331568bbf4a208a9d4419bbecbbef"><enum>(3)</enum><text>as a component of the regional organizational structure described in section 5(b), establish a regional organizational structure for the employees described in paragraph (2) reporting to the Director of Construction and Facilities Management.</text></paragraph></section><section id="idc318c701250349b8966f84fbb9056868"><enum>12.</enum><header>Consolidation of Department of Veterans Affairs acquisition, procurement, and logistics</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id898dacaeae6e4fd1acd910500f10edfd"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Organizational consolidation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall organizationally consolidate under the Chief Acquisition Officer of the Department of Veterans Affairs (designated in accordance with section 1702 of title 41, United States Code) the functions of the Veterans Benefits Administration, the Veterans Health Administration, and the National Cemetery Administration relating to—</text><paragraph id="id3f43f19b72ef4fa09e2d00e461cd03c2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>acquisition;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id632ecc74b7c342b5ad03c3b00baa6091"><enum>(2)</enum><text>procurement and contracting;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2c579373cc464644b535f8d0610b1e19"><enum>(3)</enum><text>logistics; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc245b2eec1f54e33bae09edfcf094218"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the administration of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/81">chapter 81</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id9549235f5da54d34954b4833f2591022"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Regional organizational structure</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3e4e8243ca184f9aa87f00d8ea3f04c9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish a regional organizational structure for the employees performing the functions described in subsection (a) reporting to the Chief Acquisition Officer of the Department.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9a90fe824a0a498b909dc68873b20267"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The regional organizational structure established pursuant to paragraph (1) shall—</text><subparagraph id="id74256fb90b7b42ff80c41f828b898a1f"><enum>(A)</enum><text>correspond in part or in whole to the boundaries of the Veterans Integrated Service Networks of the Veterans Health Administration;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id818ae5a6a4d14d7f807104c67310299c"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may include overarching or constituent organizational structures; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1d42ce10d16b46cfba86cb31a114fbe4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>may include dedicated offices for the Veterans Benefits Administration or National Cemetery Administration.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id288cc87245244276862eed69a61d9673"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Regional directors</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4ba5517b9e7447ed96544280255a7b9d"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Regional directors of acquisition, logistics, and construction</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idad9efd942f374ee1828943400848aa99"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall ensure that each region within the organizational structure established pursuant to paragraph (1) is headed by a regional director of acquisition, logistics, and construction reporting to the Chief Acquisition Officer of the Department responsible for supervising the functions described in (a).</text></clause><clause id="ide2b7bed5e80d42f984d72847bd43df59" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Career reserved positions</header><text>Each regional director described in clause (i) shall be a career reserved position, as such term is defined in section 3132(a) of title 5, United States Code.</text></clause><clause id="idfd7e677ba290467c961da66f5943ee0c" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Selection</header><text>Regional directors described in clause (i) may be selected from among current employees of the Department performing functions described in subsection (a).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id301ea7e790344c409b7e085dd59d5899" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Regional directors of construction and leasing</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that each region within the organizational structure established pursuant to paragraph (1) includes a regional director of construction and leasing who—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id91d3b8c6a8c744bcaf2ae639f0c37689"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reports to the regional director of acquisition, logistics, and construction heading the region pursuant to subparagraph (A); and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8d80849e2b7b4a39a460d4ffad52366c"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is responsible for supervising the employees for the region described in section 4(2).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id18aa8be8357b47eda43bd93a32ffdeb1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Relocation</header><text>Subsection (a) shall not be construed to require the physical relocation of employees of the Department.</text></subsection></section><section id="idfd8eea1eb7c640cc9c7f6bf4d2795803"><enum>13.</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header><subsection id="id85d4311dce684025beaac7f56884b2e6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report on use of additional authorities relating to recruitment and retention of personnel</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report detailing how the Secretary will use the authorities of section 706 of title 38, United States Code, to increase the size and performance of the acquisition workforce of the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text></subsection><subsection id="id68c00bea109a411c83c1920864a92147"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report on consolidation activities</header><text>Not later than 390 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report detailing how sections 11 and 12 were implemented.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5a9cf01440b74ee1a31de3f265fb6d3d"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id871b9c50dad14bc4a7c753496f172446"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Acquisition workforce of the Department</header><text>The term <term>acquisition workforce of the Department of Veterans Affairs</term> means personnel of the Department of Veterans Affairs occupying positions within the 1102 occupational series as defined by the Director of the Office of Personnel Management.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd0ac9434ce174e4e93c94173bf745035" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Appropriate committees of Congress</header><text>The term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="id72b412d537f34c978d39f84da9ab6bdc"><enum>14.</enum><header>General limitation on obligations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No provision of this Act shall authorize or permit the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to incur financial or operational obligations, including but costs for construction, leasing, maintenance, operations, or services, beyond the availability of funds appropriated by Congress. All agreements, contracts, or arrangements entered into under this Act shall include provisions ensuring compliance with this limitation.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

