<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF1AC4C8E64D4498CB1D0B49AB35E216C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4004 IH: No Anonymity in Immigration Enforcement Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4004</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250612">June 12, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement agents conducting immigration enforcement operations from wearing facial coverings, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H76DE4144771848D29DB1E658B113A5C0" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H65F396F596954385AF0056860B7C5908" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No Anonymity in Immigration Enforcement Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="H028135AB67DB46F9A70D7F7DA84EC63C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Requirement regarding identification of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement agents</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Except as provided in section 3, an agent conducting an enforcement operation in the United States—</text> 
<paragraph id="H45A7A25B35274C7487344DD5021FC5F4"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may not wear a facial covering; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8A7832E744F645CC91C9272F909ECA07"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall wear a garment clearly identifying the name of the agent and their affiliation with U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HDA627B815FFC4D9C8B5327268AC569AA"><enum>3.</enum><header>Exceptions</header> 
<subsection id="H107DC08783C74EF28849C0460F1FE606"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Exemption</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2 shall not apply to an agent who is responding to an imminent threat to life or serious bodily harm or is required to wear protective gear for safety or medical purposes.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HBF702255A3D0498FAC5BD9509988EE3F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 48 hours after an agent uses an exemption under subsection (a), the agent’s supervisor shall document and review the use of such exemption to determine whether it was appropriate, and if the supervisor determines that such use was inappropriate, initiate disciplinary review in accordance with the procedures under section 4(a).</text> </subsection> </section> 
<section id="H82FA84C17C604E8ABFB2E3AEF421244B"><enum>4.</enum><header>Compliance and enforcement</header> 
<subsection id="HA9632010284A4A0898A9832BB350D5CB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Procedures</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security shall establish procedures to ensure compliance with this Act, which shall include the following:</text> <paragraph id="H1974F50765C44C1EB2FA42F93BC5754F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Procedures to ensure that any agent who violates this Act shall be subject to disciplinary review and possible sanctions.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAF36D34166D944BDBF480138CD2B4688"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Procedures for the acceptance and review of complaints alleging violations of this Act by the Office for Civil Rights and Civil Liberties of the Department of Homeland Security.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HA4F0D53BF34F452DA25C7FE58521DAF8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>On an annual basis, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on—</text> 
<paragraph id="H72AA22EBEA03496E94C0916008436FAF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any disciplinary actions imposed under subsection (a)(1) during the previous year; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H308F55E518CE4A6DB0FC165B86A9B345"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any complaints received under subsection (a)(2) during the previous year, including a description of the review of each such complaint, and any action taken as a result of such a complaint.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HBD4B49C81D594B2CBE20FB103F4C9F23"><enum>5.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="HBAB8F999764343BEA4C9D97B0EE14C88"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as otherwise provided, the terms in this Act have the meanings given such terms in section 101 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDA7A68D1AD0443C488ED42BD796008CF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Agent</header><text>The term <term>agent</term> means any employee, officer, or contractor acting under the authority of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA1B6A3AEDFC047039094E795532EAA56"> <enum>(3)</enum> <header>Enforcement operation</header> <text>The term <term>enforcement operation</term> means any enforcement activity under the immigration laws, including an arrest, a detention, a questioning, a raid, or an investigation (whether on public or private property) carried out by an agent.</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H128E1FA243934142B1E2502263C771E2"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Facial covering</header><text>The term <term>facial covering</term> means any mask, garment, helmet, or other item that conceals or obscures the facial identity of an individual, including a balaclava, a tactical mask, or any face-shielding item.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCD66A8BFB74B4CB495ECD56D80C24AB4"><enum>(5)</enum><header>United States</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>United States</term> means each of the several States of the United States, the District of Columbia, and territories and possessions of the United States.</text></paragraph> </section> 
<section id="H869B73CC60974ABFA2A9D3930C6EAB70"><enum>6.</enum><header>Severability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any provision of this Act, or the application of such provision to any person or circumstance, is held to be invalid, the remainder of the Act, and the application of the remaining provisions, shall not be affected.</text></section> <section id="HAFC663D2EF2D409EAC0C03C708853686"><enum>7.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act shall take effect on the date that is 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

