<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-KEL25103-3PJ-6X-H5Y"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S551 IS: Ensuring Outpatient Quality for Rural States Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 551</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250212">February 12, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S383">Mr. Sullivan</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S353">Mr. Schatz</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S288">Ms. Murkowski</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide for the application of a cost-of-living adjustment to the non-labor related portion for hospital outpatient department services furnished in Alaska and Hawaii. </official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Ensuring Outpatient Quality for Rural States Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id44a982405c67453c8ac0f8c8a31cbe73"><enum>2.</enum><header>Application of cost-of-living adjustment to non-labor related portion for hospital outpatient department services furnished in Alaska and Hawaii</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1833(t) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395l">42 U.S.C. 1395l(t)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8F5C7C35712A479981F223BD7F759B0C"><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd34e55c05531480b9b316a3ae036e27a"><enum>(23)</enum><header>Application of cost-of-living adjustment to non-labor related portion for hospital outpatient department services furnished in Alaska and Hawaii</header><text>With respect to covered OPD services furnished on or after January 1, 2026, the Secretary may provide for adjustments to the payment amounts under this subsection for such services in the same manner that is provided under section 1886(d)(5)(H) with respect to the application of the cost-of-living adjustment to the non-labor related portion of such payment amounts to take into account the unique circumstances of hospitals located in Alaska or Hawaii. The preceding sentence shall not be applied in a budget neutral manner.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

