<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H56BD69A793BC421984CDEB24181D8446" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3988 IH: To direct the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development and the Director of the Bureau of the Census to conduct a study and submit a report about how Federal agencies identify and record cases of housing loss in the United States, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3988</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250612">June 12, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="O000176">Mr. Olszewski</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001119">Ms. Craig</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001238">Ms. McBride</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001229">Mrs. McIver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000110">Mr. Fields</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001225">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000606">Mr. Raskin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000620">Ms. Pettersen</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="E000301">Ms. Elfreth</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development and the Director of the Bureau of the Census to conduct a study and submit a report about how Federal agencies identify and record cases of housing loss in the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H1AA602D713CE4648B3C15C7892034560" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HF8EA324F0DCA422DBFF12AD84E849911" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Study on housing loss</header> 
<subsection id="H42C9856811B2402CB407A60EFD196F21"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development and the Director of the Bureau of the Census shall jointly conduct a study about how Federal agencies identify and record cases of housing loss.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HAF0022F66A2F4DA8951AF282672917F0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">When conducting the study required under subsection (a) the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development and the Director of the Bureau of the Census shall consult with—</text> 
<paragraph id="H4DEA677900274711834DAE73B8B6578A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Director of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H460A400C8CFC4663AA109C89375E444B"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>the Director of the Federal Housing Finance Agency; and</text>
                </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD4362267F5864A70A102185DB51F3698"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Under Secretary for Economic Affairs within the Department of Commerce.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE7AFF77FB8C14EE69FA80A9B6158F68B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development and the Director of the Bureau of the Census shall, not later than 6 months after the date of the enactment of this section, submit a report to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate—</text> 
<paragraph id="HDFEA1D6C98F54C33B5F0A61BE705400B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identifies and defines all of the types of housing loss experienced by persons residing in the United States on or after January 1, 2022;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2D6F11EAC5CD42B4AD68096D86DD0C42"><enum>(2)</enum><text>determines which types of housing loss identified under paragraph (1) are most common;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H47B60626E51041C8B0777719A8F900F9"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identifies data sets administered by Federal agencies that contain data that is used by Federal agencies to identify and record the number and types of cases of housing loss experienced by persons residing in the United States each year;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H52D186A5CF964C889E53CEA31AA9A76B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>describes, with respect to each data set identified in paragraph (3)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H55D13642B225407788842FEDAE724452"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the frequency at which the data in the data set is updated;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9BAC14A9825B40AB85D23E6C3EADC4B9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the policies that exist relating to the sharing of the data in the data set with Federal agencies and publically;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6D57008198F34810808FCF94642E2787"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the specificity of the data of in the data set, including whether it relates to individuals or households;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H51BC5EE728454B5E9B98062BDEE05D25"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the regions of the United States from which the data in the data set are collected; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE71541E0E41541DDAFBCC5E3A1EDB4BA"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an assessment of the accuracy and reliability of the sources of the data in the data set;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC94E621458354BE3B55DBB5FCD20836D"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommends ways in which Federal agencies can improve the identification and recording of cases of housing loss in the United States, including by collecting additional data, creating additional data sets, and consolidating data sets, if appropriate; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7BD28ED12E884E9B91FFD2BBA787487A"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identifies any resources or legislative authorities that would be required to carry out the recommendations made under paragraph (5).</text></paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="H0D2B0C0418F04F6995A733EF5435792D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definition of Housing Loss</header><text>In this Act, the term <term>housing loss</term> means any manner in which a person is displaced from their dwelling unit against their will including through—</text> 
<paragraph id="HD72C8C3615584BB7A5B71AA95F97ED24"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an eviction following a judgement entered by a court of competent jurisdiction;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5945D573445A4351A751BC3D4FAB2E8E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an informal eviction in which a person moves out of a dwelling unit under pressure from the landlord but without a judgement entered by a court of competent jurisdiction;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF096B761ED0B44D1A489A6C0386AAA1E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a foreclosure resulting from missed mortgage payments;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEA97ED545FEE484B9F0607DF65B9A4EC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a foreclosure resulting from missed tax payments; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4EE95C9747A3452394C2572FB6833A84"><enum>(5)</enum><text>displacement resulting from a natural disaster.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

