<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H63C01647142746DE927007EFFCCEBC49" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4069 IH: Downpayment Toward Equity Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4069</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250623">June 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000187">Ms. Waters</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000617">Ms. Pressley</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide downpayment assistance to first-generation homebuyers to address multigenerational inequities in access to homeownership and to narrow and ultimately close the racial homeownership gap in the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8B8ED46176804F01A830203177E6B647" style="OLC"><section id="H0CCF5B1DCE33439AA07A85617D134C15" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Downpayment Toward Equity Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H2DF10E68973145E398097226DCB29679" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>2.</enum><header>First-generation downpayment assistance program</header><subsection id="H8E92499E2BC7422B9094E55FA27F12E9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development shall carry out a program under this Act to provide grants to States and eligible entities to provide financial assistance under this Act to first-generation homebuyers to assist them with acquiring owner-occupied primary residences.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF8D81559C9D54D6095C2D1AAA5CDBFDC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Allocation</header><text>After reserving amounts as required under sections 6(d) and 8(b), any remaining amounts made available to carry out this Act shall be allocated as follows:</text><paragraph id="HD92CA8BE4A26469FBA1E053ACE8CFE01"><enum>(1)</enum><header>States</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">75 percent of such amounts shall be allocated among States in accordance with a formula established by the Secretary, which shall take into consideration best available data to provide more funding to States with a higher approximate number of potential qualified homebuyers (as such term is defined in section 10) and adjusted to reflect median area home prices.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDFDB3B3C1B754EC091943DB94AF89522"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible entities</header><text>25 percent of such amounts shall be made available only to eligible entities on a competitive basis.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H72ED5829F2654A06BFF9C5BB821090B2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Assistance</header><text>Amounts from a grant under this Act shall be used only to provide assistance—</text><paragraph id="H4B81013B26664421B34A9A8C0F2C8F7A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>on behalf of a qualified homebuyer; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H01970E4F8741494D82F8311F83EA65C1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for—</text><subparagraph id="H1FDDEDA40A7845B0B1BBA8BBD038A008"><enum>(A)</enum><text>costs in connection with the acquisition, involving an eligible mortgage loan, of an eligible home, including downpayment costs, closing costs, and costs to reduce the rates of interest on eligible mortgage loans;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H905B45B947A2490BAC7290A010DBECFE"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for subsidies to make shared equity homes affordable to eligible homebuyers by discounting the price for which the home will be sold and to preserve the home’s affordability for subsequent eligible buyers; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDDF906DC371447E3B550CA2311AE5419"><enum>(C)</enum><text>for pre-occupancy home modifications required to accommodate qualified homebuyers or members of their household with disabilities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB9DC09C8407A41EAAE97473F03427BA0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Amount</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A grant of assistance under this Act—</text><paragraph id="H226A425D7D794854AC870D8302CFD427"><enum>(1)</enum><text>may be provided on behalf of any qualified homebuyer only once; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4DFEC2C874A24E8799724AF29D5EAEE9"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may not exceed the greater of $20,000 or 10 percent of the purchase price in the case of a qualified homebuyer, not to include assistance received under subsection (c)(2)(C) for disability related home modifications, except that the Secretary may increase such maximum limitation amounts for qualified homebuyers who are socially and economically disadvantaged, except that the Secretary may increase such maximum limitation amounts in the case of qualified homebuyers acquiring residences located in high-cost areas, as determined based on median home prices or prices of residences under a shared equity homeownership program.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAB6DFD1C5D8048C5ACDC4B9E3E864475"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Layering of assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Assistance from grant amounts under this Act may be provided on behalf of a qualified homebuyer who is receiving assistance from other sources, including other State, Federal, local, private, public, and nonprofit sources, for acquisition of an eligible home.</text></subsection><subsection id="H432EF2E9305C49E793B2569E2819DF12"><enum>(f)</enum><header>State administration</header><paragraph id="HC966DB397D7A43078C417993E4A488A6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall require that each State receiving grant amounts under this Act administer the program to provide assistance with such amounts through the State housing finance agency for the State or such other housing agency of the State as the Secretary finds appropriate, except that any such agency may, at the option of the agency, contract with a nonprofit entity, including a housing counseling agency approved by the Secretary, to administer such assistance.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0005AEB727844417834AF5C24AB50EA8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Affirmatively furthering fair housing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For a State to be eligible for a grant under this Act, the State shall be in compliance with the Secretary’s regulations implementing the requirement under section 808(e)(5) of the Fair Housing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3608">42 U.S.C. 3608(e)(5)</external-xref>) to affirmatively further fair housing.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD6E1139CA1AE4FAF9C457A04A90F3C30"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Prohibition of priority or recoupment of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In selecting qualified homebuyers for assistance with grant amounts under this Act, a State or eligible entity may not provide any priority or preference for homebuyers who are acquiring eligible homes with a mortgage loan made, insured, guaranteed, or otherwise assisted by the State housing finance agency for the State, any other housing agency of the State, or an eligible entity when applicable, nor may the State or eligible entity seek to recoup any funds associated with the provision of downpayment assistance to the qualified homebuyer, whether through premium pricing or otherwise, except as provided in subsection (g) or otherwise authorized by the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H649CAECE0E4D4C3F8552A4FE00AEAA4E"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Recapture and reallocation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall require changes in a grantee’s policy or distribution of funds or recapture any amounts remaining available to a grantee, and reallocate such funds among other States and eligible entities, if the Secretary determines in his or her sole discretion that—</text><paragraph id="H798C765AD5B141D3AA813928E95F6F54"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a State or eligible entity—</text><subparagraph id="HA4D94CDB2AF249C29298DB346BC5919E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has not demonstrated the capacity to expend grant funds in a timely manner that furthers the purposes under this Act; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H67447D63D13D46878C09A2D260B5ECA5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is distributing or plans to distribute grant funds in a manner that results or will predictably result in qualified homebuyers from racial or ethnic groups that have faced historic obstacles to homeownership failing to receive the benefits of such funds in proportion to their population among qualified homebuyers in the relevant area; or</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H50445B44D4DE4B2CADDBF52CD0859B87"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">there is insufficient demand among qualified eligible entities to distribute fund.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8294E74D1C494A51A9FF049B9DAA233A"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Uniformity and program standardization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish a uniform set of requirements to which each State and eligible entity receiving grant amounts under this Act shall comply.</text></subsection></section><section id="H9500BE599E2441C4BA4B316BF7CB3C61" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>3.</enum><header>Qualified homebuyers</header><subsection id="H0C21251E7947490299D7C8A2F23D6027"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Assistance from grant amounts under this Act may be provided only on behalf of a homebuyer who meets all of the following requirements:</text><paragraph id="H861FF357652C4D7A9499FA6AD1D16B48"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Income</header><text>The household of the homebuyer has an income that does not exceed—</text><subparagraph id="HB9FECD23419C429780C884B13F4A2121"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">120 percent of median income for the area (as determined by the Secretary) within which—</text><clause id="H6620F54373E44A1D90AD785135669499"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the eligible home to be acquired using such assistance is located; or</text></clause><clause id="H25910B60E7974D6192237E759CFF4C5F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the place of residence of the homebuyer is located; or</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H97A0714B8AF04244B979C83128BF8390"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of a homebuyer acquiring an eligible home that is located in a high-cost area, as determined by the Secretary, 140 percent of the median income for the area within which the eligible home to be acquired using such assistance is located.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2DF5406E55F94CCAB81B79BB622C5A90"><enum>(2)</enum><header>First-time homebuyer</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The homebuyer, as self-attested by the homebuyer, is a first-time homebuyer, as such term is defined in section 104 of the Cranston Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12704">42 U.S.C. 12704</external-xref>), except that for the purposes of this Act the reference in such section 104 to title II shall be considered to refer to this Act, and except that ownership of heir property shall not be treated as owning a home for purposes of determining whether a borrower qualifies as a first-time homebuyer.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5103FE4A6D2845A690E0CD18678C8513"><enum>(3)</enum><header>First-generation homebuyer</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>first-generation homebuyer</term> means a homebuyer that is, as self-attested by the homebuyer—</text><subparagraph id="H60712AFD982F4DC28E865BB2C061346A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an individual—</text><clause id="H8B8E5CB98EEA42EDA74146E693DB3280"><enum>(i)</enum><text>whose parents or legal guardians do not, or did not at the time of their death, to the best of the individual’s knowledge, have any present ownership interest in a residence in any State, excluding ownership of heir property or ownership of chattel; and</text></clause><clause id="H96B5D2D0F0F34FE9905B731D3AF714AA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>whose spouse or domestic partner has not, during the 3-year period ending upon acquisition of the eligible home to be acquired using such assistance, had any present ownership interest in a residence in any State, excluding ownership of heir property or ownership of chattel, whether the individual is a co-borrower on the loan or not; or</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H68EB8CCF44B441A0B7C9EAAC0C7B828B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an individual who has at any time been placed in foster care or institutional care whose spouse or domestic partner has not, during the 3-year period ending upon acquisition of the eligible home to be acquired using such assistance, had any ownership interest in a residence in any State, excluding ownership of heir property or ownership of chattel, whether such individuals are co-borrowers on the loan or not.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF87C73D5DA4F4DC6BEFE99CE23F60B6B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reliance on borrower attestations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No additional documentation beyond the borrower’s attestation shall be required to demonstrate eligibility under paragraph (3) of subsection (a), and no creditor shall be subject to liability, including monetary penalties or requirements to indemnify a Federal agency or repurchase a loan that has been sold or securitized, for the provision of downpayment assistance under this Act to a borrower who does not meet the eligibility requirements if the creditor does so in good faith reliance on borrower attestations of eligibility required by this Act or regulation.</text></subsection></section><section id="H0ABA0CB8605A40D3806CACE2D2154C40" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>4.</enum><header>Eligible homes</header><subsection id="HB40B13BD6A9B4371986650A999EE258B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Assistance from grant amounts under this Act may be provided only in connection with the acquisition by a qualified homebuyer of a residential property that—</text><paragraph id="H6ED36F0388984559A3248D30E63A41D3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>consists of 1 to 4 dwelling units; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H324DCA17B0054B3A9C9BC803694E2275"><enum>(2)</enum><text>will be occupied by the qualified homebuyer, in accordance with such assurances and commitments as the Secretary shall require, as the primary residence of the homebuyer, subject to section 3.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H40A55D77A0D74B19A7FC3DC198027517"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Repayment of assistance</header><paragraph id="HD84C6EFDC66440C4B251DC8D86CAC93D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall require that, if a homebuyer to or on behalf of whom assistance is provided from grant amounts under this Act fails or ceases to occupy the property acquired using such assistance as the primary residence of the homebuyer, except in the case of assistance provided in connection with the purchase of a principal residence through a shared equity homeownership program, the homebuyer shall repay to the State or eligible entity, as applicable, in a proportional amount of the assistance the homebuyer receives based on the number of years they have occupied the eligible home up to 5 years, except that no assistance shall be repaid if the qualified homebuyer occupies the eligible home as a primary residence for 5 years or more.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H787A8AD5E7E14A44819F1A4CC46C5EDB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding subparagraph (A), a homebuyer to or on behalf of whom assistance is provided from grant amounts under this Act shall not be liable to the State or eligible entity for the repayment of the amount of such shortage if the homebuyer fails or ceases to occupy the property acquired using such assistance as the principal residence of the homebuyer at least in part because of a hardship, or sells the property acquired with such assistance before the expiration of the 60-month period beginning on such date of acquisition and the capital gains from such sale to a bona fide purchaser in an arm’s length transaction are less than the amount the homebuyer is required to repay the State or eligible entity under subparagraph (A).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H4EDC18A5D7CC438DA9AE226DA42E0D87" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>5.</enum><header>Eligible mortgage loans</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Assistance from grant amounts under this Act may be provided only in connection with the acquisition of an eligible home involving a residential mortgage loan that—</text><paragraph id="H2F9C56DEF5A04389A4F7BBD0444BABDF"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">meets the underwriting requirements and dollar amount limitations for acquisition by the Federal National Mortgage Association or the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H301A9F7F0A714824BB26A438E10D7A84"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is made, insured, or guaranteed under any program administered by the Secretary;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H148F6C52EDA74FF1B2AFAF9A1482D146"><enum>(3)</enum><text>is made, insured, or guaranteed by the Rural Housing Administrator of the Department of Agriculture;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H40C319BA4BCB4B8E900B118D4B73DFFE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>is a qualified mortgage, as such term is defined in section 129C(b)(2) of the Truth in Lending Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1639c">15 U.S.C. 1639c(b)(2)</external-xref>); or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAE996DE9A0E84E75BA09EB415D45029D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>is guaranteed for the benefit of a veteran.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HD65A54DE96A84DDBA7ADB40AF0028023" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>6.</enum><header>Housing counseling requirement</header><subsection id="HDC64CF412A8D48D5A2C933070B578581"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided pursuant to section 3, assistance with grant amounts under this Act may not be provided on behalf of qualified homebuyer unless such homebuyer has completed a program of counseling with respect to the responsibilities and financial management involved in homeownership before entering into a sales purchase agreement or loan application, except as provided under subsection (c), as the Secretary shall require, provided through a counseling agency approved by the Secretary. Such program may be delivered in-person, virtually, by telephone, or any other method the Secretary determines acceptable and shall include providing information on fair housing rights and on the availability of post-purchase housing counseling opportunities and instruction on how to file a fair housing complaint.</text></subsection><subsection id="H422ED9F3D655401C8D63123E0B8A5300"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Alternative requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall provide that if a qualified homebuyer is unable to complete the requirement under subsection (a) within 30 days due to housing counseling agency capacity issues, a State or eligible entity may allow such qualified homebuyer to complete alternative homebuyer education to fulfill the requirement under subsection (a), including homebuyer education that is provided through an online platform, and such qualified homebuyer shall be made aware of the availability of post-purchase housing counseling opportunities.</text></subsection><subsection id="H45860D5BD5394E02974FDB8BBD36AF21"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Referral upon mortgage denial</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall require that any qualified homebuyer who has completed a counseling program referred to in subsection (a) or alternative requirement pursuant to subsection (b), who receives a commitment for assistance with grant amounts under this Act and who applies for an eligible mortgage loan for acquisition of an eligible home and is denied such mortgage loan, shall be referred to a counseling agency described in subsection (a) for counseling relating to such denial and for requalification. An eligible homebuyer may be requalified at least one additional time in a calendar year, or more as determined by the Secretary.</text></subsection><subsection id="H4ABA42681B494F84ABB387D9CF2BB4A7"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of any amounts appropriated to carry out this Act, the Secretary shall use not less than 5 percent for costs of providing counseling referred to in subsection (a).</text></subsection></section><section id="H5EABF51F4C5A41F89F684D302F4FC1FA" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>7.</enum><header>Administrative costs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">States and eligible entities receiving grant amounts under this Act may use a portion of such amounts for administrative costs up to the limit specified by the Secretary.</text></section><section id="HBDB42566EC0142A0AF26CD5599091340" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>8.</enum><header>Reports</header><subsection id="H2311413F266A4E21AE6FA15AA280EEAE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For each fiscal year during which the Secretary makes grants under this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Congress, and make publicly available online in an easily accessible location on the website of the Department, a report that shall include—</text><paragraph id="H6D82B0E7CDF740FE8ABF342A0BBA8A6E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">demographic information regarding applicants for and recipients of assistance provided pursuant to this Act, including race, ethnicity, and gender;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H74ABADB25566461BB34607E65A4F76D0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>information regarding the types and amount of assistance provided, including downpayment assistance, assistance with closing costs, and assistance to reduce mortgage loan interest rates; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9FCC7E85C2EE4C3AADDCA2C4DF783208"><enum>(3)</enum><text>information regarding properties acquired using such assistance, including location, property value, property type, and first mortgage type and investor.</text></paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">All data shall be disaggregated by ZIP Code or census tract level, whichever is most feasible, and demographic information, including race, ethnicity, and gender, and any other data points the Secretary deems appropriate especially to observe equitable outcomes to ensure the program is affirmatively furthering fair housing.</continuation-text></subsection><subsection id="HE92A1DA6233541FF8AAE5F433B8BA325"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Capacity building</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of any amounts appropriated to carry out this Act, the Secretary shall use not more than 1 percent to assist States and eligible entities to develop capacity to meet the reporting requirements under subsection (a). The Secretary shall encourage States and eligible entities to consult with community-based and nonprofit organizations that have as their mission to advance fair housing and fair lending.</text></subsection><subsection id="HBCB9277BBE2646DD9694B9541F84D41E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Privacy requirements</header><paragraph id="HBB869FE5AB7F42C5B970A42B683882E6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each State and eligible entity that receives a grant under this Act shall establish data privacy and security requirements for the information described in subsection (a) that—</text><subparagraph id="H3BE37B5258154E69A866EC51FC286A69"><enum>(A)</enum><text>include appropriate measures to ensure that the privacy of the individuals and households is protected;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H99825B8FEAB046DFAF2309A58897EE6E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide that the information, including any personally identifiable information, is collected and used only for the purpose of submitting reports under subsection (a); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H69A8511EC1F04880A544123ACB7AD33E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>provide confidentiality protections for data collected about any individuals who are survivors of intimate partner violence, sexual assault, or stalking.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8D326DCAB6254D71B2733C4FE13B335C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Statistical research</header><subparagraph id="H907F3A6AD38A4970BB861CEA253E6D92"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary—</text><clause id="H2EAC93539FDE427D8A1C39059EB369AF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>may provide full and unredacted information provided under subsection (a), including personally identifiable information, for statistical research purposes in accordance with existing law; and</text></clause><clause id="H993DBABBD5774F7287563359352582AD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>may collect and make available for statistical research, at the census tract level, information collected under paragraph (1).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3F459D9395BC47E2A7BA590EC59A4FE8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Application of privacy requirements</header><text>A recipient of information under subparagraph (A) shall establish for such information the data privacy and security requirements described in paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HFDB907FD5E124D34919376A0F208BAB0" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>9.</enum><header>Compelling interest study</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary, in consultation with the Attorney General, shall survey and compile evidence to determine whether or not there is a sufficient history of discrimination in housing and, if so, the appropriate remedy to redress such historic discrimination. The Secretary shall make conclusions and recommendations based on the evidence and provide States and eligible entities granted awards under this Act an opportunity to modify their programs for assistance under this Act according to such recommendations.</text></section><section id="HA8A6E50F0C7642BCA18FDC0A8724F155" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>10.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For purposes of this Act, the following definitions shall apply:</text><paragraph id="H046E348C827F47A496A5BB4F8B698496"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Affirmatively further fair housing</header><text>The term <term>affirmatively further fair housing</term> has the same meaning as defined by the Secretary to implement section 808(e)(5) of the Fair Housing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3608">42 U.S.C. 3608(e)(5)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAA10FEBDEEC34A5CB5751A3FDA399C7D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible entity</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H9AA3327BB1EA44FA8C6DA1A6F9795A55"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a minority depository institution, as such term is defined in section 308 of the Financial Institutions Reform, Recovery, and Enforcement Act of 1989 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1463">12 U.S.C. 1463</external-xref> note);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEE31BD5CD02C45AE85F31BEF69B3D2EA"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a community development financial institution, as such term is defined in section 103 of the Riegle Community Development and Regulatory Improvement Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/4702">12 U.S.C. 4702</external-xref>), that is certified by the Secretary of the Treasury and targets services to minority and low-income populations or provides services in neighborhoods having high concentrations of minority and low-income populations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD4B10C57D4F049238BAD72F7BF63BC6A"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other nonprofit, mission-driven entity that the Secretary finds has a track record of providing assistance to homeowners, targets services to minority and low-income populations, or provides services in neighborhoods having high concentrations of minority and low-income populations; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB968F9EE01C046F2958A39ACA37A38EE"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a unit of general local government, as such term is defined in section 102 of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5302">42 U.S.C. 5302</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H034DD31A68AB4218BE0CED11CE99B5BC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligible home</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible home</term> means a residential dwelling, including a unit in a condominium or cooperative project or a manufactured housing unit, that meets the requirements of section 4.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA82072B2CF9E41D78C569B929EB4407B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Eligible mortgage loan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible mortgage loan</term> means a residential mortgage loan that meets the requirements of section 5.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAC70C10E21A74403BC3995B6EE98F283"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Heir property</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>heir property</term> means residential property for which title passed by operation of law through intestacy and is held by two or more heirs as tenants in common.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFDF279425DEA4E86AE71040C2EA2B78C"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Ownership interest</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>ownership interest</term> means any ownership, excluding any interest in heir property, in—</text><subparagraph id="HB977C448747D430997703C742EACB705"><enum>(A)</enum><text>real estate in fee simple;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H184D3FC171654871B0AEB4DE6CDE71CF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a leasehold on real estate under a lease for not less than 99 years which is renewable; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD15D3B9A51374CE986B10F44E5EEB67E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a fee interest in, or long-term leasehold interest in, real estate consisting of a one-family unit in a multifamily project, including a project in which the dwelling units are attached, or are manufactured housing units, semi-detached, or detached, and an undivided interest in the common areas and facilities which serve the project.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H184DB7CBCB0A405C860FDF5953E97530"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Qualified homebuyer</header><text>The term <term>qualified homebuyer</term> means a homebuyer who meets the requirements of section 3, and includes homebuyers consisting of multiple individuals, co-purchasers, and multi-member households.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7293BF397EE74FF3A2105BB9EE77A43D"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3966772D685B4C2482E716AE29B5658C" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Shared equity homeownership program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>shared equity homeownership program</term> means affordable homeownership preservation through a resale restriction program administered by a community land trust, other nonprofit organization, or State or local government or instrumentalities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H82B8843E883E48CABF0D438A480FEF1B"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Socially and economically disadvantaged individual</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>socially and economically disadvantaged individual</term> means an individual who meets the following requirements:</text><subparagraph id="H9BE498B2E6474F37AE991F42E978DDD4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Social disadvantage</header><clause id="H2FD2978E4E8A404CBB4A8C4D0D0ABE34"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The individual is a member of a socially disadvantaged group, whose members have historically been subjected to racial or ethnic discrimination within the United States because of their identity as members of such group without regard to their individual qualities.</text></clause><clause id="HC708B1FED87149418B439E8933B53611"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Presumption; rebuttal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual identifying as Black, Hispanic, Native American, or Asian-American, or any combination thereof, shall be presumed to be socially disadvantaged for purposes of clause (i). Such presumption may be rebutted with credible evidence to the contrary.</text></clause><clause id="H5C8642B8799740EC8EBA12EEFF25E740"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Burden of proof</header><text>An individual who does not identify as described in clause (ii) shall be required to establish individual social disadvantage for purposes of clause (i) by a preponderance of the evidence.</text></clause><clause id="H30EC551831304CD194202A4F518DD3E8"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Rules</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may issue regulations as necessary to establish procedures for complying with this subparagraph.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB1BDB7CC82F544B88E04A10CF99A39A5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Economic disadvantage</header><text>The individual has an income that meets the requirements under section 3(a).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2BD8E68FE2DF4F4296169D7D1D82A69E"><enum>(11)</enum><header>State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>State</term> means any State of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the United States Virgin Islands, Guam, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, American Samoa, and the tribal government of any Indian tribe, as such term is defined in section 4 of the Native American Housing Assistance and Self-Determination Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/4103">25 U.S.C. 4103</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section><section id="H6A50606B93E94DAFB2F866BDCAEBE09D"><enum>11.</enum><header>Implementation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary shall have the authority to establish by notice or mortgagee letter any requirements that the Secretary determines are necessary for timely and effective implementation of the program and expenditure of funds appropriated, which requirements shall take effect upon issuance.</text></section><section id="HDBD83E128CDA4555B2DA76B903F833F1" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>12.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated for grants under this Act $100,000,000,000, and any amounts appropriated pursuant to this section shall remain available until expended.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

