<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H597DDE9000DA4C179A5E06CC9DE1E440" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2405 IH: The White Oak Resilience Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2405</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250327">March 27, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001282">Mr. Barr</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001108">Mr. Comer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000616">Mr. DesJarlais</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000395">Mr. Rogers of Kentucky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000558">Mr. Guthrie</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001220">Mr. McGarvey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001287">Mr. Bera</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Natural Resources</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Interior to carry out activities to provide for white oak restoration, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF71186305A754E0BA7150FA12DB42F0A" style="OLC"><section id="H2423B342B09547A3B73066DF399DFF20" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>The White Oak Resilience Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H5D1153D98AD94B90803EB8BBAE6CB06E" commented="no"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H45BD33AAE06446059F1095EDF84A2B6C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Governor</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Governor</term> means the Governor or any appropriate executive official of an affected State or Indian Tribe or the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H111532210876438C87791ACFB6929634"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Indian Tribe</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Indian Tribe</term> has the meaning given that term in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H253FA40E20D2405A9373F8C187795E1A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, and each territory of the United States.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HF01444007D6841C78626D2642A26FF07" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>White Oak Restoration Initiative Coalition</header><subsection id="H4F7703A04AB640E8932A3CB524814DE7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The White Oak Restoration Initiative Coalition shall be established—</text><paragraph id="HBE59505215F74D82ABABCB202BE48719"><enum>(1)</enum><text>as a voluntary collaborative group of Federal, State, Tribal, and local governments and private and non-governmental organizations to carry out the duties described in subsection (b); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9B9323C39C11460C9505613A149444C3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in accordance with the charter titled <quote>White Oak Initiative Coalition Charter</quote> adopted by the White Oak Initiative Board of Directors on March 21, 2023 (or a successor charter).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HADE377A672664E87BF881F8E30F4B12A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>In addition to the duties specified in the charter described in subsection (a)(2), the duties of the White Oak Restoration Initiative Coalition are—</text><paragraph id="H626C1F7AC8DD42B9A59D6D248F3352A4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to coordinate Federal, State, Tribal, local, private, and non-governmental restoration of white oak in the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCA53D1CBAE0C4656A68D29A1D3E07718"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to make program and policy recommendations, consistent with applicable forest management plans, with respect to—</text><subparagraph id="HE09BFF21C1B14388968496067CD1D145"><enum>(A)</enum><text>changes necessary to address Federal and State policies that impede activities to improve the health, resiliency, and natural regeneration of white oak;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H50C92F6C49C845BE898C354B1990E1A3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>adopting or modifying Federal and State policies to increase the pace and scale of white oak regeneration and resiliency of white oak;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2521CDB934F6495A80DD7C63926A20CD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>options to enhance communication, coordination, and collaboration between forest land owners, particularly for cross-boundary projects, to improve the health, resiliency, and natural regeneration of white oak;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE2335BF9550E4C40A8CAF34DE9E21F08"><enum>(D)</enum><text>research gaps that should be addressed to improve the best available science on white oak;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0B462A9797334FE2BB14B3C6F5B99B94"><enum>(E)</enum><text>outreach to forest landowners with white oak or white oak regeneration potential; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H13A3F8FBA9AC4309BAB637707FE0FF5C"><enum>(F)</enum><text>options and policies necessary to improve the quality and quantity of white oak in tree nurseries.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD7222F477D2F41468511317117FEFA70"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Administrative support, technical services, and staff support</header><text>The Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture shall make such personnel available to the White Oak Restoration Initiative Coalition for administrative support, technical services, and development and dissemination of educational materials as the Secretaries determine necessary to carry out this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H67F67F67C972486FB6BD29C85530B230"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Private funding of white oak restoration projects</header><text>Subject to the availability of appropriations made in advance for such purpose, the Secretary of Agriculture may make funds available to the White Oak Restoration Initiative Coalition to carry out this section from the account established pursuant to section 1241(f) of the Food Security Act of 1985 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/3841">16 U.S.C. 3841(f)</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section><section id="H63EFE232204F4F7EB2CF5B3E1BF9FB20"><enum>4.</enum><header>Forest Service pilot program</header><subsection id="HC377D9B1D1D8481DAF3E93339BF280A2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Chief of the Forest Service, shall establish and carry out 5 pilot projects in national forests to restore white oak in such forests through white oak restoration and natural regeneration practices that are consistent with applicable forest management plans.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1810B5FE4EC5400586310DE954EB3B7A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>National forests reserved or withdrawn from the public domain</header><text>At least 3 pilot projects required under subsection (a) shall be carried out on national forests reserved or withdrawn from the public domain.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE95E088AA9A845EBAC0D4DF6EEDB5696"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authority To enter into cooperative agreements</header><text>The Secretary of Agriculture may enter into cooperative agreements to carry out the pilot projects required under subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="HF183703C4CA84100A006B81E62BB6F51"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>The authority under this section shall terminate on the date that is 7 years after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="H5A0DC0FB8F41480FA4F6E595711009A4"><enum>5.</enum><header>Department of the Interior white oak review and restoration</header><subsection id="HD6B17CD501844E058E43EBC4F6376766"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Assessment</header><paragraph id="H497DDB4D20BF4A34A04D7E8257614414"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of the Interior shall carry out an assessment of land under the administrative jurisdiction of the Department of the Interior, including fish and wildlife refuges and abandoned mine land, to evaluate—</text><subparagraph id="H3B87A14C229843DEA459638D43F5AC87"><enum>(A)</enum><text>whether white oak is present on such land; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF2D454F744854832BBC61BDD82B98C9E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the potential to restore white oak forests on such land.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H70BCC85C1E074988A736DD8FAFBCAA06"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of information</header><text>In carrying out the assessment under paragraph (1), the Secretary may use information from sources other than the Department of the Interior, including from the White Oak Initiative and the Forest Service.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4C9B8398F7334692A540BEF9ECE125BB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary shall submit to Congress, and make publicly available on the website of the Department of the Interior, a report regarding the results of the assessment carried out under this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1281966618DF41C082584CF7F23E7B38"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Pilot projects</header><text>After the date on which the report required under subsection (a)(3) is submitted, the Secretary shall establish and carry out 5 pilot projects in different areas of land described in subsection (a)(1) to restore and naturally regenerate white oak.</text></subsection><subsection id="HAB57AD53E21F40E2870D91C98997D51D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authority To enter into cooperative agreements</header><text>The Secretary may enter into cooperative agreements to carry out the pilot projects required under subsection (b).</text></subsection><subsection id="H3F32A8EC0B804EB4BB08CDFEF4666FA4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>The authority under this section shall terminate on the date that is 7 years after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="H49E1EF2F478C44D596500A23EC412FEC"><enum>6.</enum><header>White oak regeneration and upland oak habitat</header><subsection id="HBA9268D203694CBB903F4508769D9AB8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Agriculture shall establish a non-regulatory program to be known as the <quote>White Oak and Upland Oak Habitat Regeneration Program</quote> (in this section referred to as the <quote>Program</quote>).</text></subsection><subsection id="HB88215B73E874B91A1127293DF890880"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the Program, the Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="HA9251FD2A6C7415F9F4C892DBA8F3067"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">draw upon the best available science and management plans for species of white oak to identify, prioritize, and implement restoration and conservation activities that will improve the growth of white oak within the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H95492093216D4330BD203603BF1B307B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">collaborate and coordinate with the White Oak Restoration Initiative Coalition to prioritize white oak restoration initiatives;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAA72D7B3897B436DA69396BA26578F95"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">adopt a white oak restoration strategy that—</text><subparagraph id="HDAFCB98AEE8D4A6199FA57AFDC855E73"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supports the implementation of a shared set of science-based restoration and conservation activities developed in accordance with paragraph (1);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H819E121FEC42499FBCC1FEF16D6A899C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">targets cost effective projects with measurable results; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFFE6CFF0AB484BDF80C29EA2736B690C"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">maximizes restoration outcomes with no net gain of Federal full-time equivalent employees; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBBBD460C26A4465C9815593CABB85328"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish the voluntary grant and technical assistance programs in accordance with subsection (e).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3968A0F5E7254FD1A79DF29B03234060"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In establishing the Program, the Secretary, acting through the Chief of the Forest Service, shall consult with—</text><paragraph id="H27A04890C3E847F0B3BF7B91A872EB75"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the heads of Federal agencies, including—</text><subparagraph id="H2B971FB7D53A46BD94B71848E6994557"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H82B9B35C0A784F7AA31EE27AC75480A6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Chief of the Natural Resources Conservation Service; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD1CA39B7ACCE4D45811ADFF05F46DE1F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Governor of each State in which restoration efforts will be carried out pursuant to the Program.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC10F0E02818A4EFCBF68ECFE95D183BF"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of the Program include—</text><paragraph id="H7939D970909348EC8FC3E03E267BE096"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">coordinating restoration and conservation activities among Federal, State, local, and Tribal entities and conservation partners to address white oak restoration priorities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1A711AFA1B81413091DD4CD29DBDED95"><enum>(2)</enum><text>improving and regenerating white oak and upland oak forests and the wildlife habitat such forests provide;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H03B3F94448404555AF7FF327470F3A25"><enum>(3)</enum><text>carrying out coordinated restoration and conservation activities that lead to the increased growth of species of white oak in native white oak regions on Federal, State, Tribal, and private land;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H746BB279914E4ED48EEAE80D3B5D1874"><enum>(4)</enum><text>facilitating strategic planning to maximize the resilience of white oak systems and habitats under changing climate conditions;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3815C99FADAF4E62A448F8F999961E24"><enum>(5)</enum><text>engaging the public through outreach, education, and citizen involvement to increase capacity and support for coordinated restoration and conservation activities for species of white oak; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9A2C7DBC1EC44A7888FC292F5DE94C3F"><enum>(6)</enum><text>increasing scientific capacity to support the planning, monitoring, and research activities necessary to carry out such coordinated restoration and conservation activities.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB34E8877863744D5A3F6DECE378F7EFC"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Grants and assistance</header><paragraph id="H0346515C0A7143CF85C32E0714F4E37A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To the extent that funds are available to carry out this section, the Secretary shall establish a voluntary grant and technical assistance program (in this section referred to as the <quote>grant program</quote>) to achieve the purposes of the Program described in subsection (d).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1A65EA469A084C2899FA519CF63E0826"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administration</header><subparagraph id="H87754788A456434B9D677EF62E9AB709"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall enter into a cooperative agreement with the National Fish and Wildlife Foundation (in this subsection referred to as the <quote>Foundation</quote>) to manage and administer the grant program.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H53F39510E90B43D49F2F24122DACD9D7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to the availability of appropriations made in advance for such purpose, after the Secretary enters into a cooperative agreement with the Foundation under subparagraph (A), the Foundation shall for each fiscal year, receive amounts to carry out this subsection in an advance payment of the entire amount on October 1, or as soon as practicable thereafter, of that fiscal year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9B3DC8A883AF4F5D958048B836157996"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Application of National Fish and Wildlife Foundation Establishment Act</header><text>Amounts received by the Foundation to carry out the grant program shall be subject to the National Fish and Wildlife Foundation Establishment Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/3701">16 U.S.C. 3701 et seq.</external-xref>), excluding section 10(a) of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/3709">16 U.S.C. 3709(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2D7C8BC0B4B443098CD9EDB9BD5655DC" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>The authority under this section shall terminate on the date that is 7 years after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="HB4C349E0F23C4F90B03371B113A65BCE"><enum>7.</enum><header>Tree nursery shortages</header><subsection id="HF02DF1DA9C664D42AC83584489D66E83"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Chief of the Forest Service, shall—</text><paragraph id="H95524A4592344E409F67D71E21696F50"><enum>(1)</enum><text>develop and implement a national strategy to increase the capacity of Federal, State, Tribal, and private tree nurseries to address the nationwide shortage of tree seedlings; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDD4774AA7D074C758BABB5D493CE3031"><enum>(2)</enum><text>coordinate such strategy with—</text><subparagraph id="HFE137731633B40F4AA3EE86B984B1D0D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the national reforestation strategy of the Forest Service; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H10516FFA7E554897A7B8472792360DC7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>each regional implementation plan for National Forests.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9C319B024EEB4245A01F4D9DC4B81997"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The strategy required under subsection (a) shall—</text><paragraph id="H83A2442D396345FAB9E6BD11B997A5FA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>be based on the best available science and data; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2756DD8BFA7049B895AA8DCF3D0AEA37"><enum>(2)</enum><text>identify and address—</text><subparagraph id="HB243F65EC34E41FA8E7BF62E92591E28"><enum>(A)</enum><text>regional seedling shortages of bareroot and container tree seedlings;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H773FCF6DE62A4067926791A499CACC77"><enum>(B)</enum><text>regional reforestation opportunities and the seedling supply necessary to fulfill such opportunities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H90DDE8B878814D97BB1903E40E20EE1A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>opportunities to enhance seedling diversity and close gaps in seed inventories; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9B965115E47845F4868253BD3489AA19"><enum>(D)</enum><text>barriers to expanding, enhancing, or creating new infrastructure to increase nursery capacity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H5FA4566B003C4210BD6538D2D078BB7A"><enum>8.</enum><header>White oak research</header><subsection id="HBD578FB744BD446C9D24B7B18158D170"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Agriculture may enter into a memorandum of understanding with an Indian Tribe or institution, including a covered land grant college, to collaboratively conduct research on—</text><paragraph id="H6D7FF582768A4952A9725BB9D4114837"><enum>(1)</enum><text>white oak genes with resistance or tolerance to stress;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H49AB00B706FE4225817711BE882F7E29"><enum>(2)</enum><text>white oak trees that exhibit vigor for the purpose of increasing survival and growth;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3E4AD5BEA3B54DC8A046B90A83E8B790"><enum>(3)</enum><text>establishing a genetically diverse white oak seeds bank capable of responding to stressors;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFB683A34E247492CA50287333775C537"><enum>(4)</enum><text>providing a sustainable supply of white oak seedlings and genetic resources;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBB6FDE65ABA64E2794BDDBCDA9644AFA"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">improved methods for aligning seed sources with the future climate at planting sites;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H637EA574AF4D4E0986796113660D8AAE"><enum>(6)</enum><text>reforestation of white oak through natural and artificial regeneration; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H509A1C6AFF054D7A9C4ACCCBA97802AC"><enum>(7)</enum><text>improved methods for retaining and increasing white oak trees in forests;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF55F87550E95460ABF194253ABDD727A"><enum>(8)</enum><text>improved methods for reforesting abandoned mine land sites; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H69283192A5374EC5B482549C307E2654"><enum>(9)</enum><text>economic and social aspects of white oak forest management across land ownerships.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE22D855A1BB545C9B26EAE9187F5F278"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consult</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the research under subsection (a), the Indian Tribe or institution, including a covered land grant college, that enters into the memorandum of understanding under such subsection may consult with such States, nonprofit organizations, institutions of higher education, and other scientific bodies, as the entity subject to such memorandum determines appropriate.</text></subsection><subsection id="H7EBC3D54E57D4B0484CD0987AA41A0E0" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>The authority under this section shall terminate on the date that is 7 years after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H92DBE11C03014D9680EE37B9D62A9C05"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Covered land grant college defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>covered land grant college</term> means an 1862 Institution, an 1890 Institution, or a 1994 Institution (as such terms are defined, respectively, in section 2 of the Agricultural Research, Extension, and Education Reform Act of 1998 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/7601">7 U.S.C. 7601</external-xref>)).</text></subsection></section><section id="HDC961118BED740FCA1A0E3B09AF95DFC"><enum>9.</enum><header>USDA formal initiative</header><subsection id="H2012779F90924F0AA301A2F0A898A83B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Chief of the Natural Resources Conservation Service and in coordination with the Chief of the Forest Service, shall establish a formal initiative on white oak to—</text><paragraph id="HE1B85B40E5D74EB190E2A6F8A9461829"><enum>(1)</enum><text>re-establish white oak forests where appropriate;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4886A7EF031641F7A947071B035473C7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>improve management of existing white oak forests to foster natural regeneration of white oak;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8FA951032C2B468AADF1BBE7DED32EBE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provide technical assistance to private landowners to re-establish, improve management of, and naturally regenerate white oak;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H02F14DA1040C4114933913B0746E97D4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>improve and expand white oak nursery stock; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1DD3420DAA6F481682B4AF4056E2DE73"><enum>(5)</enum><text>adapt and improve white oak seedlings.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6952FF5D3D4B4788852D8F63E49F387A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>The authority under this section shall terminate on the date that is 7 years after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="H94BB616E0DD94531B8CBB21C1E793B5F"><enum>10.</enum><header>Authorities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">To the maximum extent practicable, the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture shall use the authorities provided under this title in combination with other authorities to carry out projects, including—</text><paragraph id="H5F1F042AC47E4AAB96D648C0A5FBF37A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>good neighbor agreements entered into under section 8206 of the Agricultural Act of 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/2113a">16 U.S.C. 2113a</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD2F0988885584DDAA1F486EC1C192450"><enum>(2)</enum><text>stewardship contracting projects entered into under section 604 of the Healthy Forests Restoration Act of 2003 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/6591c">16 U.S.C. 6591c</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

