<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H607DEC2F52F94B69BB3C892E54C88E6B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5244 IH: To provide for the authorities of the Secretary of State.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5244</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250910">September 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001216">Mr. Mills</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for the authorities of the Secretary of State.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H772DE6C5AEBB45868453FD797E1C7C36" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H6BDB997FE7E24A18AD7D86AFF2E83E47" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act—</text> <paragraph id="H38077152E2054A399BA539B1B6017B81"><enum>(1)</enum><text>except as otherwise provided, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H5DB9943B877142F7BF0F4C012E1ABF34"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H013BF037477D4D488A39A243D45FAE91"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H385C48431D7741CE8A2CEC2C157024CE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>Department</term> means the Department of State;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC9E27BA120F14305915975FD4C85A013" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>Deputy Secretary</term> means the Deputy Secretary of State; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFF93E1892B3442C68C9FCC9422736087"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of State.</text></paragraph></section> <title id="HE869D8E7BBF1463084A28E4EEF3BF466"><enum>I</enum><header>General organization</header> <subtitle id="H40DC7FF75DF247D9AEE2286C9886B73E"><enum>A</enum><header>Office of the Secretary</header> <section id="H820F3B9BD9FD4E78B736008176545381"><enum>101.</enum><header>Office of the Secretary</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary is authorized to establish in the Office of the Secretary of State of the Department positions to support the Secretary’s situational awareness and decision-making in the management of the Department. Such positions may include the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H33EE9201B395408A91BE75B49B11215C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Chief of Staff.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H49F7FC300EA245F28322DCDC0DAB192E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Counselor.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H54C1F08D23D54FF3972A4EE368185D46"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Executive Secretariat.</text></paragraph></section></subtitle> <subtitle id="HC55E0018823549E684FCE3B4823B3589"><enum>B</enum><header>United Nations</header> <section id="HB834F9E4E11D4F7FBF8C295792271885" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>111.</enum><header>United States Ambassador to the United Nations</header> <subsection id="H08037F5EA5A1486B807F598CAC1B0FA6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header> <paragraph id="H490B2C30748E420C96CB5AE3E5A7FDA7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, shall appoint a representative of the United States to the United Nations who shall have the rank and status of Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary and shall hold office at the pleasure of the President. Such representative shall represent the United States in the Security Council of the United Nations and shall perform such other functions in connection with the participation of the United States in the United Nations as the President may, from time to time, direct.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HADB4606BCABE4ABB8DA6678D3A17108B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reporting and collaboration</header><text>The United States Ambassador to the United Nations shall report to and collaborate closely with the Secretary of State through direction by the President to implement a coherent and unified strategic policy of the United States in the United Nations system.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HDC155C35B76E45D8BC97B3DCC13E483A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to the responsibilities described in subsection (a), the United States Ambassador to the United Nations shall maintain continuous observation and coordination of all matters pertaining to United States participation in the United Nations system in the conduct of foreign policy, including—</text> 
<paragraph id="H5309223A4BE84FD487B7A6EE1C2E4253"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to identify, report, and hold accountable Member States that engage in malign influence operations and United Nations employees who act inconsistently with the principals of impartiality enshrined in the United Nations Charter;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA9FB6ED9E6D8489484F76622884C8570"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to oppose the election as the head of any United Nations entity of nationals from Member States that engage in malign influence operations;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3D26CB443AA64392B2ACE2789C9B7FF7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to support Taiwan’s membership or meaningful participation, as appropriate, in relevant United Nations entities in which Taiwan has expressed an interest in participating; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2DA4582960E44B6790CA5FE280AEA752"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to support Presidential actions in response to malign influence operations.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3F57F4F41AB54042BCA7515D20B24F48"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text> <paragraph id="HE22BB096E2EE417DACC23F5F32C56ABB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>employee</term> means a staff member who is compensated in any form in the general services, professional staff, or senior management of the United Nations system, including a consultant, a contractor, or a subcontractor;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H21FA31AF4D6D4C73BCA561EC26042407"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>malign influence operations</term> means a coordinated, integrated, and synchronized application by a Member State of national diplomatic, informational, military, economic, or other capabilities, to foster attitudes, behaviors, or decisions by a United Nations entity, or within the United Nations system, that furthers the national interests and objectives of a Member State, in a manner inconsistent with the United Nations Charter;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD2508A2663654B42A227DA31069BD97F"> <enum>(3)</enum> <text>the term <term>Member State</term> means a country that is a Member State of the United Nations; and</text>
                        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD9349460746342D6A2631BF85A3D1C44"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the term <term>United Nations entity</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HCF92A92DAFEC451AA039FF06C6F61E0B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the United Nations General Assembly;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9D742BAE989A48C29AD46FC4330EE378"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the United Nations Economic and Social Council;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFA525763EA284DFD8801AA6CCD683B3F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the United Nations Security Council;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1461A76D353B409993790AE11FA8887B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the United Nations Secretariat;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB6992F1492584627B6DAEF2BBD959427"><enum>(E)</enum><text>an organization related to any of the entities referred to in subparagraphs (A) through (D);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB8DC2B06CEE44EA1858D949777BB6F81"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a specialized agency; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC5CE6585DE1440E8856EAC3A17865ADA"><enum>(G)</enum><text>a subsidiary body.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H04FBC6D33C5244949EC7A05C8829E92B"><enum>112.</enum><header>United States Mission to the United Nations</header> 
<subsection id="HE4FA951D50E34A358CABB27919DE0712"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be a United States Mission to the United Nations which shall be constituted by the United States Ambassador to the United Nations, and representatives to the principal organs and agencies of the United Nations appointed or designated and included within the United States Mission to the United Nations as designated pursuant to subsection (b), together with their deputies, staffs, and offices.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H510F5DE3D4E44A80851D98DDBC554AC4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Representatives</header> <paragraph id="HA86E1B2F3E5C4EC7899EF30B3359AD6A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, shall appoint additional persons with appropriate titles, rank, and status to represent the United States in the principal organs of the United Nations and in such organs, commissions, or other bodies as may be created by the United Nations with respect to nuclear energy or disarmament (control and limitation of armament).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC67FB315B38843D8AAE2BD3EB33C9E88"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Terms and oversight</header><text>Such persons—</text> <subparagraph id="H6117D5CD02C04D50B5047F972932E1C8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall serve at the pleasure of the President; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9287B1563D6848DF8B0A75C0F8B03D32"><enum>(B)</enum><text>are subject to the direction of the Representative of the United States to the United Nations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H538764B457964B879873863321590414"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>The United States Mission to the United Nations shall coordinate closely with the Bureau of International Organization Affairs of the Department and any bureau of the Department that provides funding for United Nations agencies, programs, or organizations at the Department and across the United States Government to implement a coherent and unified strategic policy of the United States in the United Nations system.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA96C5E8439E841528C29EFD4A70B009B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Action by representatives voting in accordance with Presidential instructions</header><text>The representatives when representing the United States in the respective organs and agencies of the United Nations, shall, at all times, act in accordance with the instructions of the President transmitted by the Secretary of State unless other means of transmission is directed by the President, and such representatives shall, in accordance with such instructions, cast any and all votes under the Charter of the United Nations.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H412092F3990D4A12AEB3090B70815E3C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Chief of Mission</header> <paragraph id="HFF8CC0D98DED47BA9FC14E476A1969D7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The United States Ambassador to the United Nations shall be the Chief of Mission in charge of the United States Mission to the United Nations.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2BDE2E1CF9304F11AFC0FF47FBAD40FB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>The Chief of Mission shall coordinate at the seat of the United Nations the activities of the Mission in carrying out the instructions of the President transmitted either by the Secretary or by other means of transmission as directed by the President.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H00FBE06B131342D7864AF45BB6413E80"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text>In addition to the responsibilities described in paragraph (2), the Chief of Mission—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H114982685E66486E9D47886A2D8EF429"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall be responsible for the administration of the Mission, including personnel, budget, obligation and expenditure of funds, and the central administrative services; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDCC4B4F9644F44569EDA8A032CE8CAED"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall discharge responsibilities under this subsection in accordance with such rules and regulations as the Secretary may from time to time prescribe.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></subtitle> 
<subtitle id="H0AB222D435BD48E2BE4585CAEA17DCFB"><enum>C</enum><header>Bureaus, offices, and other entities</header> 
<section id="H87966FCA7305438380B14B924A870B1F"><enum>121.</enum><header>Offices and bureaus of the Secretary and Deputy Secretary</header> 
<subsection id="H30C21E703FBC42FDA024CECB84191E14"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be within the Department the following bureaus and offices to support the Secretary’s and Deputy Secretary’s situational awareness and decision-making in the management of the Department:</text> <paragraph id="H5F0CE50983AB47839301D7CCB8F536D4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A Bureau of Legislative Affairs, in accordance with section 122.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5C6DD79748064AA2B42064E3CBB6A696"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A Bureau of Intelligence and Research, in accordance with section 123.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5547C9DE4BF74D129AB71A8A2CD50E9C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>An Office of Policy Planning, in accordance with section 124.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2052B2B869E947A4AD3DDBD9B3946C89"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An Office of the Legal Adviser, in accordance with section 125.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H780A7BD1845141CDB5E307664509A027"><enum>(5)</enum><text>An Office of Protocol, in accordance with section 126.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3674EBF1C21D4B7F9EB980414C0774FC"><enum>(6)</enum><text>An Office of the Spokesperson, in accordance with section 127.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HB9429BCD88FC45F4B654B951D467D7AB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Delegation</header><text>The Secretary may delegate the responsibilities for the coordination of activities across the bureaus and offices listed in subsection (a) to the Deputy Secretary to ensure that the missions of such bureaus and offices are integrated into the Department’s broader goals.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H936F83265BBC45DCB3F0A5971EF7C255" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>122.</enum><header>Assistant Secretary for Legislative Affairs</header> 
<subsection id="H64C89531F3F54F29832A7399238091D7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be in the Department an Assistant Secretary for Legislative Affairs who shall be responsible—</text> <paragraph id="HAE852CDF89F14B90A9BA4DDC0DD96068"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to the Secretary and the Deputy Secretary for matters pertaining to Congress; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H36F50B70176E4099950F0097C531B6FA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for such other related duties as the Secretary may from time to time designate.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H895A33B554F54E79A62A1655C6C86E8A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Responsibilities of the Assistant Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to the responsibilities described in subsection (a), the Assistant Secretary for Legislative Affairs shall maintain continuous observation and coordination of all matters pertaining to engagement with Congress, including, as appropriate—</text> 
<paragraph id="HC9909BD8F9634E9F91A6BCB501D9959D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the presentation of the Department’s legislative program, including developing, preparing, and submitting legislation to Congress;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5BAE2A9F226442B18C950BFC54A3E701"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">impartial coordination between the Department and Congress on all legislative related matters;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF30887BF16964CA988851E0E6F4A9756"><enum>(3)</enum><text>providing guidance and information to other Department bureaus and offices on legislative matters;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFB6EF3D6593440C38866CE8390237219"><enum>(4)</enum><text>managing correspondence and reports to Congress, as appropriate, except for—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H1461591DD6304AF0949137696F1DB698"><enum>(A)</enum><text>treaties and executive agreements, which the Office of the Legal Adviser transmits;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB10B8C8E1FE344BCBC58A3EEE1AACE4E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>anti-deficiency notifications, which the Bureau of Comptroller and Financial Services transmits;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC8004FA9E29D4D769F7C81EF141CA3B6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>reprogramming notifications for the State Operations Budget account, which the Under Secretary for Management transmits; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9F5F23DD591D45039B9A78831083D43A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>other such communications as directed by law, Executive order, or the Secretary; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H88F5C7E68051476FB8A5BBCD537A4F14"><enum>(5)</enum><text>supporting Congress in its official foreign travel and the expenditure of congressional travel funds.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H2E5DB732A8014669A9E36593AD810BBD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Bureau of Legislative Affairs</header> <paragraph id="H1AC7AF72C438431A8C91C9118B21E804"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish a Bureau of Legislative Affairs, which shall perform such functions related to the coordination of legislative activity, congressional engagements, and the development of the Department’s positions on proposed legislation, as the Secretary may prescribe.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H029C74CC6532465EA6965053D471A66D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Head</header><text>The Assistant Secretary for Legislative Affairs shall be the head of the Bureau of Legislative Affairs.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFC37A90A61E2418DA386A82B760689A7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Deputy Assistant Secretary for House Affairs</header><text>The Deputy Assistant Secretary for House Affairs shall be appointed by the President of the United States.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5D54D7267E9743C380C8DBA47D09A3D1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Deputy Assistant Secretary for Senate Affairs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Deputy Assistant Secretary for Senate Affairs shall be appointed by the President of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H8B0FCF9FADD040FD89154493A9352624" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>123.</enum><header>Assistant Secretary for Intelligence and Research</header> <subsection id="H5E0B8694AF7F4786821CA4A4D5BCFE45"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be in the Department an Assistant Secretary for Intelligence and Research who shall be responsible—</text> 
<paragraph id="HEB20A39DDCD046DB8818BAF80F5A9B29"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to the Secretary and the Deputy Secretary for matters pertaining to the intelligence and research functions of the Department; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H507B20AFE1824C8D817744CAD5BFB496"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for such other related duties as the Secretary may from time to time designate.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3868CDFF9A5A4E3AA4D95398AEE478B3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text>In addition to the responsibilities described in subsection (a), the Assistant Secretary for Intelligence and Research shall maintain continuous observation and coordination of all matters pertaining to analysis and dissemination of intelligence products in the conduct of foreign policy, including, as appropriate—</text> <paragraph id="H1CCAEBE12E5849E6927BC429995526A5"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>overseeing the Department’s coordination with the intelligence community (as such term is defined in section 3(4) of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3003">50 U.S.C. 3003(4)</external-xref>));</text>
                        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBC514B040DDA4E2E89904112F0744106"><enum>(2)</enum><text>advocating for the Department’s collection requirements; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB4294E26CBDE418D890FCA64DEF93BEF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>ensuing effective collaboration and information sharing in the Department.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H98FB4AA0FE4149B9B882248A8B8DB4DE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Bureau of Intelligence and Research</header> 
<paragraph id="HA5DFC94D7F0D4EC7B4DEB9C363FE412B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish a Bureau of Intelligence and Research, which shall perform such functions related to overseeing the collection, analysis, and dissemination of intelligence and research to inform and implement United States foreign policy, as the Secretary may prescribe.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3DA597EE4C6B4908BCA1DB217E04F74C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Head</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Assistant Secretary for Intelligence and Research shall be the head of the Bureau of Intelligence and Research.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H5FB600188B464BF7BA9C34887E2B960D"><enum>124.</enum><header>Director for Policy Planning</header> 
<subsection id="H58E2606379F64AAB94F0102363B8A259"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be in the Department a Director of Policy Planning responsible to the Deputy Secretary and Secretary of State for matters pertaining to independent policy analysis, guidance, and counsel, and such other related duties as the Secretary may from time to time designate.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H4A84F469561B4DC3B0C43D185E8724D8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text>In addition to the responsibilities described in subsection (a), the Director of Policy Planning shall maintain continuous observation and coordination of all matters pertaining to the policymaking process of the Department, including, as appropriate—</text> 
<paragraph id="H5C30C19F2172469288819256D0DD80F0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supporting the Secretary’s priorities, aligning them with engagements, policy, and planning across the Department and the interagency;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1A57404FD49445F7967B5ADD736AE938"><enum>(2)</enum><text>leading and contributing to long-term planning initiatives and functional policy reviews, agenda-setting, and coordination across the Department, the interagency, and with allies and partners through bilateral and multilateral policy planning dialogues; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF91E1885B8974371BBD49E7406D37501"><enum>(3)</enum><text>promoting the Secretary’s strategic narrative on related policy and diplomatic priorities in the Department and across the interagency.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD642D91628D44CF5B5FE6AA55A04451B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Office of Policy Planning</header> <paragraph id="H7EA84FACAE0F41DB96E3699D7F4593BC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish an Office of Policy Planning, which shall perform such functions related to the shaping, developing, and articulating the Secretary’s strategic policy and diplomatic priorities across the Department, as the Secretary may prescribe.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H00AF341CF688475AAA73325F79C76B87"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Head</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of Policy Planning shall be the head of the Office of Policy Planning.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HEE7B79D28B6C45418FEF04456BB83312"><enum>125.</enum><header>Legal Adviser</header> <subsection id="H2E508B6B74EB489391802DD1F2A7B681"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be in the Department a Legal Adviser who shall be responsible—</text> 
<paragraph id="HA3D68C4E5FDA4632AE72854CF65A9024"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to the Secretary and the Deputy Secretary for providing advice on all legal issues with respect to the mission of the Department, including but not limited to formulating international law; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDB1184F37A7246EBAC947B95C8975710"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for such other related duties as the Secretary may from time to time designate.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA67C92B9A5D84F578C722AEEA8D16C4E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to the responsibilities described in subsection (a), the Legal Adviser shall maintain continuous observation and coordination of all matters pertaining to legal implications of the Department’s intentions and activities in the conduct of foreign policy, including, as appropriate—</text> <paragraph id="H5B4B7BA2986A441D8B2E93FCB452E76A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>participating in international negotiations and represent the United States in international conferences related to legal issues, and serve as a member of delegation and legal advisor to treaty implementation commissions;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H371440F4EC7641FF80D36F9277C7DDA6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>assisting the Department regarding legal matters at interagency meetings, congressional hearings, and meetings of private organizations; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCC83C30AB8DA4E71BD9900B13BCD0DEC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provide consultation on behalf of the Department for domestic litigation that involves the Department or its interests, coordinating with other Departments when necessary, and assisting the Department of Justice relating to relevant litigation.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H79E2EA22B48B4435829DFF639627C6DC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Office of Legal Adviser</header> 
<paragraph id="HB965B509343E4050ABC55CED7C0A4B29"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish the Office of the Legal Adviser, which shall perform such functions related to representing and advising the Secretary and Department-wide missions on all legal policy issues in connection with United States foreign policy and the work of the Department, as the Secretary may prescribe.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8F684CD0132D4C368013EC851F8ABD9A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Head</header><text>The Legal Adviser shall be the head of the Office of the Legal Adviser.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H8522E8036AE2444C861917A976BD464C"><enum>126.</enum><header>United States Chief of Protocol</header> 
<subsection id="HF7A142CD247F4669AA640181D2777A5C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be in the Department a United States Chief of Protocol who shall be responsible—</text> <paragraph id="HEE2F9B98FF604D8B8F773FC730CDC762"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to the Secretary and Deputy Secretary for matters pertaining to diplomatic etiquette; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCE0ACBD1C5CC47CABF7A5AEDEA550A2F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for providing guidance to the President, the Vice President, the Secretary, and other high-ranking government officials on matters of national and international protocol.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD095719EE0AB456595E3F87F77DCF50B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Office of Protocol</header> <paragraph id="HE0BC2A272287421DB2CE8ED41BFF17AC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish an Office of Protocol, which shall perform functions related to ensuring the Department’s effective management of diplomatic and consular protocols, including the planning and coordination of official ceremonies, diplomatic visits, related diplomatic engagements, and providing guidance on matters of diplomatic etiquette, as the Secretary may prescribe.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H625DE65B693B4A979044CD9FC1471FBA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Head</header><text>The United States Chief of Protocol shall be the head of the Office of Protocol.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H10F1BB5308224A19A21AEEB00BE15B47"><enum>127.</enum><header>Spokesperson</header> <subsection id="HE17E6E71F205433B952FA41650D000F0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be a Spokesperson of the Department of State who shall be responsible—</text> 
<paragraph id="HE4B71561CF9446908D6BFF287DD45DF2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to the Secretary for matters pertaining to domestic communications; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H39ED55C736314562ACF9C318C2F282F2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for such other related duties as the Secretary may from time to time designate.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H700D966F589A409180813FA8224B28B8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text>In addition to the responsibilities described in subsection (a), the Spokesperson shall maintain continuous observation and coordination of all matters pertaining to domestic communications in the conduct of foreign policy, including, as appropriate—</text> <paragraph id="H7BEC72B9A8814A5F825095169E60741E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>directing all Department communication intended for domestic consumption;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2AB3B82DC1224B1D97BC3021FE7920F7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>communicating to the domestic press as the official domestic audience spokesperson of the Department;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H174789DA7880486FB2075816146B79B5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>advising the Secretary on all aspects of the Department’s conduct of domestic press relations; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0381F8AA210D48A7AD7EEB83E6C04D61"><enum>(4)</enum><text>supporting the Secretary in preparation for and during domestic public media engagements.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H4B28DA02DA3F436F97A9F3F2B52AA466"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Office of the Spokesperson</header> <paragraph id="H4E1281665C44429AA1086DFFFB68F1D8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish an Office of the Spokesperson which shall perform such functions related to domestic communications as the Secretary may prescribe.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE46161795A204CC0A6E901FDF0DBECF9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Head</header><text>The Spokesperson of the Department of State shall be the head of the Office of the Spokesperson.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HC3590D81BA77413C95D32CCF7D0D350D"><enum>128.</enum><header>Red Team Capability</header> <subsection id="HFE8FE51B3A1E4818BFA8E653CE84D2A8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish a Red Team Capability to inform the Department’s crisis response and contingency planning.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H09D3DC9D89E04004973336A9F0269981"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text>The individuals involved in the Red Team Capability required by subsection (a) should be convened at the direction of—</text> <paragraph id="HB982928596C141D583A57DD83FD43548"><enum>(1)</enum><text>for general meetings, the Department’s Policy Planning Staff and the Department’s Crisis Management and Strategy Unit; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H29CF31907A6349DCB13DA52BF366444A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for specific reviews as needed, the Secretary or other Department principals.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HB485C9CE173545BCA8BE15F54C24311B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text>Not later than 21 days after the individuals involved in the Red Team Capability established pursuant to subsection (a) are convened in accordance with subsection (b), such individuals shall submit to the Department’s Policy Planning Staff a report that contains the findings relating to the exercise of such Red Team Capability.</text></subsection></section></subtitle> 
<subtitle id="H99949C6E8E7E42548A5E8030E1AD7A41"><enum>D</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header> 
<section id="HAC4521959C274FB2A001F572AA4FCB0E" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>131.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header> 
<subsection id="HAE203EE44AA1445CB20EBEEA7486585B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary is authorized to receive all the funds appropriated to the Department and allocate such funds to fulfill missions and responsibilities for fiscal year 2026 and 2027.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H4963B8BFBB764844B978D55E7C2A59CE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Allocations</header><text>Of the funds authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary under subsection (a)—</text> 
<paragraph id="H39EB854DCC874FD5952CB31B20D59679"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the United States Ambassador to the United Nations shall receive the funds necessary to fulfill the United States Mission to the United Nations missions and responsibilities under subtitle A for fiscal years 2026 and 2027;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8D7B0BC33F884F7BA1A8EBC582B94A14"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">there is authorized to be made available to positions described in subtitle B the funds necessary to fulfill position missions and responsibilities for fiscal years 2026 and 2027; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7FCB457BF7BD46B4BC75614C4D85ED68"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">there is authorized to be made available to the heads of the bureaus, offices, and other entities described in subtitle C the funds necessary to fulfill bureau, office, and other entity missions and responsibilities for fiscal years 2026 and 2027.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H7689F21305154611B698763C53876DFA" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report on unfunded priorities of the Department</header> <paragraph id="H4F32E3A2D6274B45824E2DC6C7DF2AC5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 10 days after the date on which the budget for any fiscal year is submitted by the President to Congress pursuant to section 1105 of title 31, United States Code, the Secretary shall prepare and submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report on unfunded priorities.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF67F32B6890D4D95B7D49029C1995891"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header> 
<subparagraph id="HDEEA92AAA0DF474F8B869755CCC71B39"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The report required by paragraph (1) shall include, with respect to each unfunded priority covered by such report—</text> <clause id="H8D7FB1B7C46843799239C0792EF87ED2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a summary description of such priority, including the objectives to be achieved if such priority is funded (whether in whole or in part);</text></clause> 
<clause id="H2BF42DB7948847118BB341C65678D047"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the additional amount of funds recommended to be made available to achieve the objectives referred to in clause (i); and</text></clause> <clause id="H22CCD2D36BE040A582F37521A7D85C28"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>budget information with respect to such priority, including—</text> 
<subclause id="H06E2384C17E0459C9F172AC8EE395159"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the appropriation account;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H198A567A7BC44D61829FFEDB2AC01DCA"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the expenditure center; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H278381059E6C4094A1D397FAD72B1E02"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the project and, if applicable, any subprojects.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFD10B4900E02497E915D4D7683E36100"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Prioritization</header><text>The report required by paragraph (1) shall present the unfunded priorities covered by such report in overall order of urgency of priority among unfunded priorities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6F19963BEFD148CDAA81CF75CDF38233"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection—</text> <subparagraph id="H17DE064A1085495490FB7854625F5DC6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text> 
<clause id="H03E1FC93EBAD4761AF3B1858185A28E9"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives; and</text></clause> <clause id="HE554F623CCF3431F9C71D06069D1163B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC7610509FEE64D24B1DD628A1E361029"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>unfunded priority</term>, with respect to a fiscal year, means a program, activity, or mission requirement of an element of the Department that—</text> <clause id="H73B032A08E6546AD90D06AFBE5F8337F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is not funded in the budget for such fiscal year submitted by the President to Congress pursuant to section 1105 of title 31, United States Code;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HD79883B2CE9C477E8684DBF5EC81ACEB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is necessary to fulfill a foreign policy or national security objective or to satisfy an information requirement associated with a goal or objective outlined in the Joint Strategic Plan agreed upon by the Department; and</text></clause> <clause id="HC95EE47C60AF47AB9A3C78FF3CBCF53B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>would have been recommended for funding by the Secretary if—</text> 
<subclause id="H30358132BE444CB8B878EC0B00CCC1C0"><enum>(I)</enum><text>additional resources had been available for such budget to fund such program, activity, or mission requirement; or</text></subclause> <subclause id="H1BA9F5B44E71410894C61B54F8A7EC33"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the program, activity, or mission requirement has emerged since such budget was formulated.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></subtitle> 
<subtitle id="H4177724F29A24A6E98574895C0F5B1F6"><enum>E</enum><header>United States Code Classification</header> 
<section id="H8B90CAB1AB234888940AF39D0ABC037E"><enum>141.</enum><header>Classification in United States Code</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Office of Law Revision Counsel is directed to—</text> <paragraph id="H7678CB8F61C24710BBF3DE15490CC3E5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>utilize sections 6 through 35 of title 22, United States Code, to classify the sections of this title; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4C0DD70A12AE4F4DAD27F21DC7E6A5A9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>maintain the legislative history, under editorial notes, of repealed law which previously occupied the corresponding sections of United States Code.</text></paragraph></section></subtitle></title> </legis-body></bill>

