<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="HEF89C0B6630946DC96AA8396C0419ED5" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 187 RH: Of inquiry requesting the President to transmit certain information to the House of Representatives referring to the termination, removal, placement on administrative leave, moved to another department of Federal employees and Inspectors General of agencies.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">House Calendar No. 23</calendar><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 187</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 119–58]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250304">March 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000687">Mr. Mfume</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001313">Ms. Brown</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001218">Ms. Stansbury</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000598">Mr. Garcia of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000476">Mr. Frost</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000602">Ms. Lee of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001131">Mr. Casar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001130">Ms. Crockett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000621">Ms. Randall</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001230">Mr. Subramanyam</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001324">Mr. Bell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001231">Ms. Simon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001241">Mr. Min</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000617">Ms. Pressley</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250409">April 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Reported adversely, referred to the House Calendar, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Of inquiry requesting the President to transmit certain information to the House of Representatives referring to the termination, removal, placement on administrative leave, moved to another department of Federal employees and Inspectors General of agencies.</official-title></form><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H89643E3CBFC241128D96025C7E7B1D03" committee-id="HGO00"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H46D00B58CDB248CC897227504FD37A12"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the President is requested to transmit, to the extent that such documents are in the possession of the President, to the House of Representatives, not later than 14 days after the date of the adoption of this resolution, in complete and unredacted form, a copy of the following: </text><paragraph id="H05B73D1D95F643B083E7C77BA72E281B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any and all documents and communications, including notes from meetings, audio records, telephone and electronic mail records, text and other digital messages, related to each Federal employee placed on administrative leave, removed due to a reduction in force action, terminated, transferred, or reassigned to another department on orders, advice, or recommendation of Elon Musk, any individual considered to be a member of a DOGE agency team, or any official or unofficial member of the United States DOGE Service since January 20, 2025.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H97005690BC2D43CF8CA1F374AEC268D2"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any and all documents and communications, including notes from meetings, audio records, telephone and electronic mail records, text and other digital messages, related to the Office of Personnel Management’s determination that employees classified as Diversity, Equity, and Inclusion (commonly referred to as <quote>DEI</quote>), Diversity, Equity, Inclusion, and Accessibility (commonly referred to as <quote>DEIA</quote>), or employed in a position in a DEIA office, would be deemed a competitive area subject to a reduction in force notice, subject to the memorandum issued by the Office on January 24, 2025, relating to <quote>Guidance Regarding RIFs of DEIA Offices</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE4AD9DB418034D4FB5327BEB799631D8"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">All documents or communications between the Executive Office of the President, the Office of Management and Budget, the Office of Personnel Management, Elon Musk, any official or unofficial member of the United States DOGE Service, any individual considered to be a member of a DOGE agency team, or any other agency or Office of Inspector General regarding the removal or termination of agency inspectors general, including whether to notify Congress as legally required.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H873DE059CE47441188ED26167915D575"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">All documents and communications between the Office of Management and Budget or the Office of Personnel Management and Elon Musk, any member, official, or non-official representative of the Trump Campaign, Trump Transition Team, or Trump Administration regarding the removal or termination of any Inspector General of an agency, including whether to notify Congress as legally required.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date date="20250409">April 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Reported adversely, referred to the House Calendar, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></resolution> 

