<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7AD8C14945C84DBA9FCD95F05797FA17" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4009 IH: Protecting and Enhancing Public Access to Codes Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4009</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250613">June 13, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="I000056">Mr. Issa</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="R000305">Ms. Ross</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 17, United States Code, to reaffirm the importance of, and include requirements for, works incorporated by reference into law, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE45B4A3BBBE941F5840D80CDBCAB2AC1" style="OLC"><section id="HE2E20A4E491A4C598DB76DBC9BBF7FDE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting and Enhancing Public Access to Codes Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Pro Codes Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HD523D6DE07CD4384AE146BB171FE9B8E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H0783344523554066BC8655932A707CB5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Congress, the executive branch, and State and local governments have long recognized that the people of the United States benefit greatly from the work of private standards development organizations with expertise in highly specialized areas.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5CD075AEE6C948E7A13822D2339BBC0D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The organizations described in paragraph (1) create technical standards and voluntary consensus standards through a process requiring openness, balance, consensus, and due process to ensure all interested parties have an opportunity to participate in standards development.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H01FDD6A250BB483DA8912C39C5D63521"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The standards that result from the process described in paragraph (2) are used by private industry, academia, the Federal Government, and State and local governments that incorporate those standards by reference into laws and regulations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDB2BD0E0F5E042B4B24D609B7B0DA4D2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The standards described in paragraph (3) further innovation, commerce, and public safety, all without cost to governments or taxpayers because standards development organizations fund the process described in paragraph (2) through the sale and licensing of their standards.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD0929DE3F5944393973222250E830392"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Congress and the executive branch have repeatedly declared that, wherever possible, governments should rely on voluntary consensus standards and have set forth policies and procedures by which those standards are incorporated by reference into laws and regulations and that balance the interests of access with protection for copyright.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H24984AC0A759401890F1909FF53B9337"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Circular A–119 of the Office of Management and Budget entitled <quote>Federal Participation in the Development and Use of Voluntary Consensus Standards and in Conformity Assessment Activities</quote>, issued in revised form on January 27, 2016, recognizes the benefits of voluntary consensus standards and incorporation by reference, stating that <quote>[i]f a standard is used and published in an agency document, your agency must observe and protect the rights of the copyright holder and meet any other similar obligations.</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H63343C862AED4355A36736D35C13D69E"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Federal agencies have relied extensively on the incorporation by reference system to leverage the value of technical standards and voluntary consensus standards for the benefit of the public, resulting in more than 23,000 sections in the Code of Federal Regulations that incorporate by reference technical and voluntary consensus standards.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2E98723F9E2F49D598A7F8C4C8B2C005"><enum>(8)</enum><text>State and local governments have also recognized that technical standards and voluntary consensus standards are critical to protecting public health and safety, which has resulted in many such governments—</text><subparagraph id="HB516E2B89E1E4FC1BB288420189ABEF9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>incorporating those standards by reference into their laws and regulations; or </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H51400D28603541E0A584ACAA209750D3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>entering into license agreements with standards development organizations to use the standards created by those organizations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA673728A97DB4D4CA2A9D5CDA0523903"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Standards development organizations rely on copyright protection to generate the revenues necessary to fund the voluntary consensus process and to continue creating and updating these important standards.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7DD9213757A9444A952E8CF13BB0097D"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The people of the United States have a strong interest in— </text><subparagraph id="H9C5F2BC297C74550AB7B3DDE71707A08"><enum>(A)</enum><text>ensuring that standards development organizations continue to utilize a voluntary consensus process— </text><clause id="H3F4BFE1FEA774D569DDEF1A0D8DDDE58"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in which all interested parties can participate; and </text></clause><clause id="H0A3813670B90424E9C694B7B7B7580AF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that continues to create and update standards in a timely manner to— </text><subclause id="H42DAC6C5A9AA48ECB25AC0ECD65D8CA1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>account for technological advances; </text></subclause><subclause id="H4FF25D6A2B30406F80AB336C76EBA92D"><enum>(II)</enum><text>address new threats to public health and safety; and </text></subclause><subclause id="HBA8D17E51F59406CB394EA1CC91BDC32"><enum>(III)</enum><text>improve the usefulness of those standards; and</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7C2334BBD08943C7B9094DD0D2CEF10A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the provision of access that allows people to read technical and voluntary consensus standards that are incorporated by reference into laws and regulations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3E0A557B68164158BB6D43AE06C1D5A8"><enum>(11)</enum><text>As of the date of enactment of this Act, many standards development organizations make their standards available to the public free of charge online in a manner that does not substantially disrupt the ability of those organizations to earn revenue from the industries and professionals that purchase copies and subscription-access to those standards (such as through read-only access), which ensures that the public may read the current, accurate version of such a standard without significantly interfering with the revenue model that has long supported those organizations and their creation of, and investment in, new standards.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF1588A749521488E9349113DB4915E20"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Through this Act, and the amendments made by this Act, Congress intends to balance the goals of furthering the creation of standards and ensuring public access to standards that are incorporated by reference into law or regulation.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H820968CC0C39419B937C479A134C9B13"><enum>3.</enum><header>Works incorporated by reference into law</header><subsection id="H49ECF11C8CD04148834B2B493A970DE4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/17/1">Chapter 1</external-xref> of title 17, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H5A0EE07B27CB4CBEB5B0FB06AE238485" style="USC" act-name=""><section id="H62E4F79A8F5A43C09A29D18B9D3355A3" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>123.</enum><header>Works incorporated by reference into law</header><subsection id="H857572D9FC874FB3A8D361BFCB954AAA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H25DEED4176FE4FBE9D490CF4BBD1B760"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Circular A–119</header><text>The term <term>Circular A–119</term> means Circular A–119 of the Office of Management and Budget entitled <quote>Federal Participation in the Development and Use of Voluntary Consensus Standards and in Conformity Assessment Activities</quote>, issued in revised form on January 27, 2016.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFF039414BE8F491BAB0AAC07D190A714"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Incorporated by reference</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5357D9DB7641409AA150E1E2293A1988"><enum>(A)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>The term <term>incorporated by reference</term> means, with respect to a standard, that the text of a Federal, State, local, or municipal law or regulation— </text><clause id="H14D9C525970E41C787705175D1F03322"><enum>(i)</enum><text>references all or part of the standard; and </text></clause><clause id="H104B2C8F62E54CA58DB35960211BF127"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>does not copy the text of that standard directly into that law or regulation. </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA385D45DB7CF412AA2CD5512178BF555"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Application</header><text>The creation or publication of a work that includes both the text of a law or regulation and all or part of a standard that has been incorporated by reference, as described in subparagraph (A), shall not affect the status of the standard as incorporated by reference under that subparagraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD47A1E780970427DAA33D327B1403B65"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Standard</header><text>The term <term>standard</term> means a standard or code that is— </text><subparagraph id="HA3C731BE2F73403696A9F6608FD5AD0D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a technical standard, as that term is defined in section 12(d) of the National Technology Transfer and Advancement Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/272">15 U.S.C. 272</external-xref> note); or </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE2B78FDCB6384A2AB24EA65E7FD59EC6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a voluntary consensus standard, as that term is used for the purposes of Circular A–119. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE579E6BE40F9442FAF244ED9E4CCBF72"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Standards development organization</header><text>The term <term>standards development organization</term> means a holder of a copyright under this title that plans, develops, establishes, or coordinates voluntary consensus standards using procedures that incorporate the attributes of openness, balance of interests, due process, an appeals process, and consensus in a manner consistent with the requirements of Circular A–119.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H07A0AB793B86469EB9AEB6E41EAF1859"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Publicly accessible online</header><subparagraph id="HBDA97697999A46558B21C5D2D8A363D6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>publicly accessible online</term>, with respect to material, means that the material is displayed for review in a readily accessible manner on a public website that conforms with the accessibility requirements of section 508 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/794d">29 U.S.C. 794d</external-xref>), including the regulations implementing that section as set forth in part 1194 of title 36, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor regulation. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H67C0C8E9C25749F68F5FFE02BCCF26C1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>If a user is required to create an account or agree to the terms of service of a website or organization in order to access material online, that requirement shall not be construed to render the material not publicly accessible online for the purposes of subparagraph (A), if—</text><clause id="H3B783063A5CA40229B1D6EC812DBEE51"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">there is no monetary cost to the user to access that material; and</text></clause><clause id="HC19CC6261D8842C2AC8C5021C2CC9577"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>no personally identifiable information collected pursuant to such a requirement is used without the affirmative and express consent of the user.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEFD2970532EE403B9F8EE11738ECF481"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Standards incorporated by reference into law or regulation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A standard to which copyright protection subsists under section 102(a) at the time of its fixation shall retain such protection, notwithstanding that the standard is incorporated by reference, if the applicable standards development organization, within a reasonable period of time after obtaining actual or constructive notice that the standard has been incorporated by reference, makes all portions of the standard so incorporated publicly accessible online at no monetary cost and in a format that includes a searchable table of contents and index, or equivalent aids to facilitate the location of specific content. </text></subsection><subsection id="HA51781FCA9AB487DAC524F9C91DFC50B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Burden of proof</header><text>In any proceeding in which a party asserts that a standards development organization has failed to comply with the requirements under subsection (b) for retaining copyright protection with respect to a standard, the burden of proof shall be on the party making that assertion to prove that the standards development organization has failed to comply with those requirements.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H7754CC7328244883853BAA3C5371E5CE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/17/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of title 17, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4D6CB5BF34E74CE8A965531FE0ECE3BF"><toc><toc-entry level="section" bold="off">123. Works incorporated by reference into law.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="H10138F8A22024A709FBF7E962300262F" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>4.</enum><header>Study of standards cost to governments</header><subsection id="H5C83B20C20474D37B23A425B843E8188"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a study on the financial impact to Federal, State, and local governments in the United States associated with acquiring access to standards incorporated by reference into law.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2AAE8C715C14478E913E8EFD5FFB0CDB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Scope</header><text>The study under subsection (a) shall—</text><paragraph id="H37DB17CC3BA34061B43DF149885FA071"><enum>(1)</enum><text>analyze the total expenditure by government entities for accessing these standards;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2072F6E593F64D0ABF15F8C6F2A9FD8D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>assess any financial burdens or resource constraints these costs impose on governments, particularly for smaller municipalities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB9353886982A4715A99818AB2542CBF3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>evaluate the cost-effectiveness of current mechanisms for acquiring these standards; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA521E5D56C5948369CA0212A4EAB0039"><enum>(4)</enum><text>examine the impacts on public services due to the costs associated with accessing these standards.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4F5F0B0465F8429791A1406044D980D6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General shall submit a report to Congress that includes—</text><paragraph id="H8932E9EECC3A499599DE5750CB3D780C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the findings of the study conducted under subsection (a); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9AB095715707403A9434F5E1572B264A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recommendations to mitigate any adverse financial impacts identified by the study, including suggestions for legislative or administrative actions as appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

