<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" slc-id="S1-HLA25012-040-DY-HDP"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 34 ATS: Congratulating the Washington University in St. Louis Bears women’s soccer team for winning the 2024 NCAA Division III Women’s Soccer Championship.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 34</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250123">January 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S420">Mr. Schmitt</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S399">Mr. Hawley</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Congratulating the Washington University in St. Louis Bears women’s soccer team for winning the 2024 NCAA Division III Women’s Soccer Championship.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, on December 8, 2024, the Washington University in St. Louis Bears women’s soccer team (referred to in this preamble as the <quote>Bears</quote>) defeated the nationally ranked William Smith Herons, 3 to 0, to win the 2024 NCAA Division III Women’s Soccer Championship;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Bears demonstrated extraordinary teamwork, skill, and hard work throughout this victory and the entire season;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Bears attained a 23–0–2 record during this season;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Bears achieved the top ranking in the 2024 NCAA Division III Women’s Soccer season;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the coaching staff led by head coach Jim Conlon provided outstanding leadership and strategy, contributing significantly to the victories throughout the season, culminating with the end-of-year victory in the 2024 NCAA Division III Women’s Soccer Championship;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Olivia Clemons was named Offensive Player of the Year, Rookie of the Year, and All-Tournament Offensive Player, finishing the season with an impressive 22 goals and 6 assists;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas head coach Jim Conlon and assistant coaches Brandon Santel, Amanda Kesler, and Katharine Zaber were named Coaching Staff of the Year;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 4 players earned First-Team honors, 2 players earned honorable mention nods, and 4 players were selected to the All-Tournament Team; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas fans of the Bears demonstrated enthusiasm and loyalty in supporting their team throughout the 2024 NCAA Division III soccer season: Now, therefore, be it </text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="S1"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph commented="no" id="id65c68f84150c49d0b1dd63685a0ac141"><enum>(1)</enum><text>commends the Washington University in St. Louis Bears women’s soccer team on winning the 2024 Division III Women’s Soccer Championship;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id041f5e6729cf4dd082712a7eb29493e3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the achievements, contributions, and dedication of the players, coaches, management, and support staff of the Bears;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id89ed0b8ca9e64970be2108943c7698ed"><enum>(3)</enum><text>congratulates the alumni, students, and faculty of the Washington University in St. Louis;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0289c867cd54490391978f93c0ece01d"><enum>(4)</enum><text>recognizes the hard work and commitment of the staff of the Francis Olympic Field and Peter Johann Memorial Field; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6c0a5a522144462c94e89bd94b80553e"><enum>(5)</enum><text>respectfully requests the Secretary of the Senate to transmit an enrolled copy of this resolution to—</text><subparagraph id="idbb8a93265494494e8074ada3faa6429e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Chancellor of the Washington University in St. Louis, Andrew D. Martin;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7e75ab80829d42a4adaf5449ef95096f"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Director of Athletics of the Washington University Bears, Anthony J. Azama; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd9840542099a4d61abf14b8c8ad275c0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the head coach of the Washington University Bears women's soccer team, Jim Conlon. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

