<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ALL25075-CDP-L8-4JD"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S270 IS: Natural Disaster Resilience and Recovery Accountability Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 270</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250128">January 28, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S378">Mr. Lankford</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To establish a Commission on Federal Natural Disaster Resilience and Recovery to examine and recommend reforms to improve the efficiency and effectiveness of the Federal Government’s approach to natural disaster resilience and recovery, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HA0808836594E4D7D8BFC5DF6C15802EA"><section section-type="section-one" id="H53F88025011D460F86F6D5607BA33A82"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Natural Disaster Resilience and Recovery Accountability Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H0330482BC43C4AC885344CAE2FC4DB9C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Commission on Federal Natural Disaster Resilience and Recovery</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd72bdab13946480f82d302f79735980e"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H19887C93071C4F2CBA9981EF01970A5A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Commission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Commission</term> means the Commission on Federal Natural Disaster Resilience and Recovery established under subsection (b). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id856389e535a549588cd1a33c298758f8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The term <term>Director</term> means the Director of the Office.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8498002CB1DF4DAB8CBFD9DC00BE5F80"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Natural disaster</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>natural disaster</term> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide82fa06497dd4ed8a90f1bb271044f1b"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a weather event relating to cold or hot weather, flood, earthquake, tornado, hurricane, or ice storm; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6412dce4f5f34cb493f155ea75b6efd4"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an event meeting such other criteria as the Commission may determine appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H432D543733D8449DA0B2754C3A7D4FAB"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Office</header><text>The term <term>Office</term> means the Office of Management and Budget. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2B91DCA3D9E04FE194309B136349C6A0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established within the Office a Commission on Federal Natural Disaster Resilience and Recovery.</text></subsection><subsection id="H34B68513349740E783112B9AA5A5A8F2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The duties of the Commission shall be to examine and recommend administrative and legislative reforms to improve the efficiency, effectiveness, and budget funding of programs and activities of Federal agencies supporting natural disaster resilience and recovery.</text></subsection><subsection id="H820A95A696144B768462CB929DCDFE39"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Membership</header><paragraph id="H2E09CE9D62C545C3AF59B96CAAFFEB6D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall be composed of 15 members appointed by the Director—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id70b7b49824cd425aa87a811cd1401b78"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">of which 1 shall be an employee of the Office; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4d4490e81caa4d498f059913a9e86b26"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the remainder of which, to the extent practicable—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb45fd8f9aa6042959afff3e80474bac2"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall be an official, emergency manager, or emergency response provider from a State, local, or Tribal government, the private sector, or a nongovernmental organization;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id730e8668d04041bf8d5caf0cf73e9dfe"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall represent multiple geographic (including urban and rural) areas; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id19ffb76f9c074d00b841e86da38d741e"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>may include—</text><subclause id="HE417EF77AE504C418D0ABAB7D261B17F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>individuals from the emergency management field and emergency response providers, including fire service, law enforcement, hazardous materials response, emergency medical services, and emergency management personnel, or organizations representing such individuals;</text></subclause><subclause id="HD206A137C5DD412880B74EC8F7FDF379"><enum>(II)</enum><text>health scientists, emergency and inpatient medical providers, and public health professionals;</text></subclause><subclause id="HFE9AD09C37164E4290F7C9B390C818D4"><enum>(III)</enum><text>experts from the Federal Government and State, local, and Tribal governments and the private sector that represent standards-setting and accrediting organizations, including representatives from the voluntary consensus codes and standards development community, particularly individuals with expertise in the emergency preparedness and response field;</text></subclause><subclause id="H7EA5128E9583489F85B0C6DC80B4BAE8"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>State, local, and Tribal governmental officials with expertise in preparedness, protection, response, recovery, and mitigation, including adjutants general;</text></subclause><subclause id="HA57184579A784E69AF95630C0BBF07B9"><enum>(V)</enum><text>elected State, local, and Tribal governmental executives;</text></subclause><subclause id="HFC9425FEEAD6465AA0B71E7C083415C3"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>experts in public and private sector infrastructure protection, cybersecurity, and communications;</text></subclause><subclause id="HC38ABA4C317C460DAB5235200D01053F"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>representatives of individuals with disabilities and other populations with special needs; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H3061FD5DB7F94F27B3CBE3ED75A0916C"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text>such other individuals as the Director determines appropriate.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4E92DED0987747D4AB9F9713EB8E0031"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Expertise</header><text>In making appointments under paragraph (1), the Director shall give consideration to individuals with expertise in—</text><subparagraph id="H063464D24CCB4C57B49FFC8ED3D9B0A8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>natural disaster resilience and recovery;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H98EB0C591B2841AEA8D0723C72007FF8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>emergency management at the Federal, State, local, territorial or Tribal level;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA8336F2A2F014A0AA7EC468BF3706F4C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>critical infrastructure;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA39ED5D9C35449928DC107CCD005C49A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>transportation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7ED64968E21B4800B272BD295E9D9DC6"><enum>(E)</enum><text>housing; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9E4720DB9E674563A70889D6C6E78B9F"><enum>(F)</enum><text>intergovernmental relations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAC4D0625238044B3B4A7A3585E936687"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Appointment deadline</header><text>All appointments to the Commission shall be made not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of this Act. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB50585C4CB654DFB8EB0287A635BC4A2"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Chair and vice chair</header><text>The Commission shall have a chair and vice chair. The chair shall be a member of the Commission elected by an affirmative vote of not less than 8 members of the Commission, and the vice chair shall be the Commission member who is an employee of the Office.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6AA07F2A0FBD4093A0885D1D890F9249"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Compensation</header><subparagraph id="H50616C7C78C14B4F8CFE061AF5190F8D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A member of the Commission who is not an officer or employee of the Federal Government—</text><clause id="H28C76BA2E50A483C980876A981E8B4AD"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall not be considered a Federal employee for any purpose other than for purposes of—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id032c683109a14ac0a80ed644558b6f9b"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/81">chapter 81</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code (relating to compensation for injury); and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd2ce538154c84643920ad07a4dac2a9c"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">sections 2671 through 2680 of title 28, United States Code, (relating to tort claims); and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HBBCC552C6A094CBD864A86B28AA47535"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, at rates authorized for employees of agencies under subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/57">chapter 57</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, while away from their homes or regular places of business in the performance of services for the Commission.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7AB4FACE4C194949AAE639DBA988CABB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Federal employees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A member of the Commission who is an officer or employee of the Federal Government shall not receive any additional compensation for service as such a member. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB30C739399BD46FEA047FDA4028C030D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Administration</header><paragraph id="HA1C55146E8A8475A867B06D6123864D5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Meetings</header><subparagraph id="HC272C065170248E292436B8A7476A51A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>First meeting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall first meet not later than 240 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HABE4B6FBCECF4809A5590F20BF33FEA2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Other matters</header><text>The Commission may, for the purpose of carrying out this Act, meet virtually or in-person to hold hearings, sit and act at times and places, take testimony, and receive evidence as the Commission considers appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE1B6BBBB7AF441CAA1AA69BE4E24C670"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Executive branch assistance</header><text>The heads of the following Federal agencies shall advise and consult with the Commission on matters within the respective areas of responsibility of the Federal agency:</text><subparagraph id="H93E1475407DD4FE4849B4017BE96598C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Small Business Administration.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H77F8B1EB216C445B837058633ACC18CF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Department of Agriculture.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H33A7F1AF390F46729BBA8E04B48EA0C5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Department of Homeland Security.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEE7A942B2E5440D7948564921A24B14B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The Department of Labor.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7DF0C970E3C5499B8B0097CF546F2132"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The Department of the Interior.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H78A2CB5CE3A6441E9E1B1C01E2F5BC1E"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The Department of Energy.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H924D32765F9E4ADDB9E714D063D997AD"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The Department of Transportation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H369B19E8F43D4F18918EE58B31F3B2D0"><enum>(H)</enum><text>The Department of Housing and Urban Development.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HACF5FE9A2C4E43589001DFA12147C062"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The Environmental Protection Agency.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H06ECD6E6B9B344D19207A59A7271310D"><enum>(J)</enum><text>The Department of Justice.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7536E507BDF84CD7BC90C2CDB4439B84"><enum>(K)</enum><text>The Federal Emergency Management Agency.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA74C7ED170774FDCA4577BAD79CE47D0"><enum>(L)</enum><text>The United States Army Corps of Engineers.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H781028C738B94D95BD6208B281286086"><enum>(M)</enum><text>The Corporation for National and Community Service.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H208F3FC53E694CE4939ACA72A44BBCF4"><enum>(N)</enum><text>The Department of Commerce.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H80447B7F86634DEDA467D4A796DF05F2"><enum>(O)</enum><text>The Department of the Treasury.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA979F6F5EE744049AB8DB01C050BC169"><enum>(P)</enum><text>The Office.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEE74B18003AE4A8EBD1FE0B6A7C21022"><enum>(Q)</enum><text>Any other Federal agency, as determined by the Commission.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0E2145B90A6142D8ADCF36D7C609FF03"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Information from Federal agencies</header><text>The Commission may request from any Federal agency such information as the Commission considers necessary to carry out its duties. Upon request of the chair of the Commission, the head of a Federal agency shall furnish such information to the Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFD749E4E7CEE4F6CB76F7F7BDCFD601D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Postal services</header><text>The Commission may use the United States mails in the same manner and under the same conditions as other departments and agencies of the Federal Government.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4CD43319A8D4437D836D362D730B586D"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Rules of procedure</header><text>The chair and vice chair of the Commission shall, with an affirmative vote of not less than 8 members of the Commission, establish written rules of procedure for the Commission, which shall include a quorum requirement to conduct official business.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H545F2FA63C854CE58F658A51F5F4A0E5"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Staff</header><subparagraph id="HB75CBDF02D4B41DFB522EBD272577BFE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The chair of the Commission may, without regard to the civil service laws and regulations, appoint and terminate support personnel as may be necessary to enable the Commission to perform the duties of the Commission.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H17513789021C4DAB946AD5466FD94753"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Executive director</header><text>The Commission, by an affirmative vote of not less than 8 members of the Commission, shall appoint an executive director of the Commission.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H935F0A6332C84CAE81B09BEA0A4C91B2"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Compensation</header><text>The chair of the Commission may fix the compensation of the executive director and other personnel without regard to chapter 51 and subchapter III of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/53">chapter 53</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, relating to classification of positions and General Schedule pay rates, except that the rate of pay for the executive director and other personnel may not exceed the rate payable for level V of the Executive Schedule under section 5316 of such title.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB2BD686F09F74B0186491D9A8BF1E179"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Detail of Government employees</header><text>A Federal Government employee may be detailed to the Commission, without reimbursement, and such detail shall be without interruption or loss of civil service status or privilege.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF4FB0C2723A24D35A9B1677430F194DC"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Reports</header><paragraph id="HFBF17DA6ECE944A19FA7DD65BA6B00EF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Final report</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the first meeting of the Commission, the Commission shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives a report describing recommendations to improve the Federal Government’s approach to natural disaster resilience and recovery. Such report shall include the following:</text><subparagraph id="H9AD1A0AA39E34742840325A3BF08DBEF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Specific and actionable policy recommendations, including legislative recommendations, as applicable, to improve the effectiveness of the Federal approach to natural disaster resilience and recovery, including consideration of the 11 options presented in the report of the Government Accountability Office entitled <quote>Disaster Recovery: Actions Needed to Improve the Federal Approach</quote>, issued on November 15, 2022 (GAO–23–104956).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H38181A4D8ED946E8B069B254BB0DCB35"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A comprehensive review all federally funded activities, Federal financial assistance and grants, and Federal agency programs related to natural disaster resilience and recovery using, to the extent practical, data systems and metrics consistently across the Federal agencies, including budget information and the Federal program inventory established under section 1122(a)(2)(B)(i) of title 31, United States Code, in order to evaluate the effectiveness of such activities and programs to meet established goals and statutory requirements.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFFF15CB54C124828A37BF7D44804B434"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A complete list of all federally funded natural disaster resilience and recovery programs and activities and prior funding information, program goals, statutory authority of such programs and activities with relevant law citations, and reference to related financial assistance and grant programs.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBE8B7A98A2DF42FF9E86C09A9AF510D0"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Consideration of potential administrative changes to the roles and responsibilities of the various Federal agencies involved in natural disaster resilience and recovery.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7D1CB75215574DCD9956A458D8A88C81"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Policies that aim to improve the efficiency and effectiveness of the Federal Government’s approach to natural disaster resilience and recovery, to increase the access and efficacy of respective Federal programs to all impacted individuals and entities, and to recommend appropriate investments in natural disaster resilience to reduce duplication and inefficiency.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC252773EB9234E438EB17AF2D29DFB12"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Other areas of natural disaster resilience and recovery that are not described in this section, as determined by the Commission.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H572A127435944006BEDF27C1F5F49CFD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Specific policy recommendations</header><text>To the maximum extent practicable, the report under paragraph (1) shall include specific short-term and long-term legislative and administrative policy recommendations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H246AD7E06C834DF2889731F20CDF248C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Interim reports</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, and every 180 days thereafter, the Commission shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives an interim report relating to any matter described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE3EAAFD6127F4A43863F40F7DB96FD5A"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The Commission shall terminate on the date that is 60 days after the date on which the Commission submits the report required under subsection (f)(1).</text></subsection><subsection id="HC7F49C038C1C4B6495DE27B620980F53"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Use of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts used to carry out this section shall be derived solely from amounts otherwise appropriated to the Office, and no additional funds are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

