<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5B8A58CFE20B4735AE9601AD61F58E49" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 566 IH: Cleaner Air Spaces Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 566</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250120">January 20, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="J000305">Ms. Jacobs</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000191">Mr. Neguse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000620">Ms. Pettersen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001225">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000197">Ms. DeGette</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001216">Ms. Schrier</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to provide grants to air pollution control agencies to implement a cleaner air space program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8826BA19F65F4D62885334661930C703" style="OLC"><section id="H0D6EF74F28D94EEF84A09AFF8CDC767E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Cleaner Air Spaces Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HD1E1B74C5A4641F595A036B9CA6FCFDF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Cleaner air space program grant</header><subsection id="H53B73D150E5045E694B50CA401B0236E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to the availability of appropriations, the Administrator shall provide grants to air pollution control agencies to implement a cleaner air space program in accordance with this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H9A4ABC5E57E846D6A5C9064647780BB0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grant requirements</header><paragraph id="H42877AE3304547F68DED61961B9B7831"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Amounts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Under this section, the Administrator may not provide a grant to an air pollution control agency in an amount that exceeds $3,000,000.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H96F9D28D0FC34734B19717DC3F63DB23"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Grants for Tribes</header><text>The Administrator shall provide at least one grant to a Tribal agency that has jurisdiction over air quality.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD4D6EFB353D44FC083C64CD5399062EA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header><paragraph id="H2B9095AAE0654BE9A3402DA82199E37B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To apply for a grant provided under this section, an air pollution control agency shall submit to the Administrator an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Administrator determines appropriate, including a proposal for the implementation of a cleaner air space program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAAA72092EE87490FA8669CDE88452259"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Proposal for cleaner air space program requirements</header><text>A proposal for the implementation of a cleaner air space program under paragraph (1) shall include the following:</text><subparagraph id="HEF5C1F62C4D9438FB1769BC296294B67"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Certification of partnering with a community-based organization.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4598C2881F51423B807297966F4C4E07"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Details on the responsibilities of all parties involved with the cleaner air space program, including the responsibilities of—</text><clause id="H083D3331EA4348C5B7FA2C4D2F578047"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the air pollution control agency; and</text></clause><clause id="H8E8A2C727B5944CF882B8AD52153285D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any community-based organizations for which the air pollution control agency is partnering with under subparagraph (A).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H605FB5DB54534F7BBDC962D353BB0F08"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Information regarding which geographic population or community of covered households may be receiving eligible air filtration units under such cleaner air space program.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDE74969CFBA245FC97098D11301C7E64" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Information on how the air pollution control agency plans to—</text><clause id="HFF1429B4E53C4AB5B761A446691FC9EE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>distribute educational materials related to eligible air filtration units; and</text></clause><clause id="HC05802B64DCF43B68F007DD4E8BB0E7E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>advertise the availability of clean air centers.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF515051EECEE428CB28CC75AE75A10BB"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Information on how such air pollution control agency plans to establish a clean air center, including—</text><clause id="HD8720CFBC6AE482590F09E8969F1A16E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the facility in which a clean air center may be established; and</text></clause><clause id="H1F33A54CB2DB4773BF24F17AF1EE4E45"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the capacity and ventilation characteristics of such facility.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE84A15354B0C43A6BD4698D29EAB6FF3" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of the costs that may be associated with the program, including any administrative costs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0A41B9B99CB9484A92B17318DD6E1785"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Cleaner air space program requirements</header><text>Subject to partnership requirement under subsection (e), an air pollution control agency implementing a cleaner air space program pursuant to subsection (a) shall— </text><paragraph id="HFD0FCEABF78E4FBEA94E651F37B703F6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establish at least one clean air center that is—</text><subparagraph id="H957A4183A5AC404F82E5499C20C7D40D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>located in an area at risk of being exposed to wildland fire smoke; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA8A942F7BDA44CC78124F9153DC874FD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>accessible to individuals that reside in covered households; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H788109EFA6A345BFA562169BE6E2A668" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">open, accessible, and staffed during wildland fire smoke events with the option of being open, accessible, and staffed before or after wildland fire smoke events; </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD0AC999DC86C4D2E9DC62DF2557BC351"><enum>(2)</enum><text>advertise to the public—</text><subparagraph id="H37483FA526904AAC8B056954DBE2EB49"><enum>(A)</enum><text>during a wildland fire smoke event, the availability of a clean air center; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7765126523E54A77BB3B47DBBD65C2BC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the local cleaner air space program that such air pollution control agency is implementing, including information about such local cleaner air space program, the availability of free air filtration units (if applicable), eligibility requirements to receive such free air filtration unit, and information on who to contact for more information with respect to such local cleaner air space program;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDC4F59ED8BDE47C790534272D269D1B6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>at no cost to covered households—</text><subparagraph id="H998090B0AE0346278CF41CA6FCFFF7BF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>distribute a minimum of 1,000 eligible air filtration units to such covered households; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H89DD5210B227440A967063C54008194C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide one air filter replacement for each eligible air filtration unit distributed under subparagraph (A);</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H59C10DAB4EC24029A4D7F330482A6526" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>distribute educational materials that include information on how to best utilize an eligible air filtration unit to create a clean air room in a home; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H03B16E41F7474E4DB1D9C35D727A436E" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>collect, and provide to the Administrator, information on—</text><subparagraph id="H7508A43BA50E49B0A742764C56F44474" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>each type of eligible air filtration unit distributed under such cleaner air space program;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H10525F23709B44729941A204198B2685" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of eligible air filtration unit so distributed; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8D88CDCAC90F41E3921AE7A45B56FA73" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the cost of each type of eligible air filtration unit so distributed; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCF57F5BC325349C2B66D81493F5F055A"><enum>(6)</enum><text>not later than 6 months after providing an eligible air filtration unit to a covered household, conduct an anonymous survey of an individual of such covered household that received the eligible air filtration unit through the cleaner air space program on—</text><subparagraph id="HCDD378BDE9F34FC4A6C6275DDC5A2A1D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>whether such individual understood how to properly set up a clean air room and how to utilize the air filtration unit;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H00E58FF268984D0AAF10A51CADEC5885"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how often such individual utilized the air filtration unit;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4B5189127D9E4B15BD4934442B043856"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the largest barriers to properly utilizing the air filtration unit or creating a clean air room;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3A830DF99443425486CA2C2C4347FE95" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>whether such individual reported better air conditions in the clean air room of such individual compared to other parts of the home of such individual; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H10A2A8FE7611475BBA09EC56546AE5F8"><enum>(E)</enum><text>how the implementation of the cleaner air space program could improve.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H76307627A0FB41719775AB14A7698C32" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Partnership</header><text>In implementing a cleaner air space program under subsection (a), an air pollution control agency shall partner with at least one community-based organization to carry out the requirements of such cleaner air space program under subsection (d).</text></subsection><subsection id="HD8C6306313A546F7A67D0C53376B4DBA"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall submit to Congress a report that includes—</text><paragraph id="H6E66E6E56E84494F8927DC694DD398D0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>information on each cleaner air space program implemented using a grant provided under subsection (a), including—</text><subparagraph id="H7972BE44C7D34E03AFD4F46D335DE05D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the name of the air pollution control agency that received such grant; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H90A9D894CBCA4422949EFB5E9109F8AA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the information described in subsection (d)(5) collected by such air pollution control agency;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1B73A1682AAC4F699B815E10F9302B8E" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>responses from the survey described in subsection (d)(6); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H116C96A0852A4C63BF5C8B683A698DD5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recommendations on—</text><subparagraph id="H1A98E8C673F740CE856C2FEA7E966652"><enum>(A)</enum><text>whether the cleaner air space program should be expanded; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H26F405987DDF4D5E9CE2AC626EB6FFF4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>how the cleaner air space program can be improved.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE89225A947BA4D2398AC2D47402F3C81"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph id="HEB5459BD946F44789A54BD4F4F77D924"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBB12F15D6FF446F88E72934EFF55FAD0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Air pollution control agency</header><text>The term <term>air pollution control agency</term> has the meaning given such term in section 302 of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7602">42 U.S.C. 7602</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEB4911613D3144BF8EBDC9E4B07AC81D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Clean air center</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>clean air center</term> means one or more clean air rooms in a publicly accessible building.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H210F441C3E964364A0565304DC68C8CD"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Clean air room</header><text>The term <term>clean air room</term> means a room that is designed to keep levels of harmful air pollutants as low as possible during wildland fire smoke events.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD7889F7D0041452AB703CE1EFE01CBA3"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Covered household</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered household</term> means a household that—</text><subparagraph id="HAEF8A00DBC2640BF94638D000CC8D7CE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is located in a low-income community; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H94CCE0E7ADDE4908B412E8F6C2FAA3FC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes a person who—</text><clause id="HDC83B10C81A541B4B66A69CC362A5B78"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is at high risk of experiencing a wildland fire smoke event; and</text></clause><clause id="H2A046CFF365945B7A9219B84E7FF9166"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is vulnerable to negative health effects caused by wildland fire smoke due to factors such as an underlying health condition, a disability, or age.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H88988D2106184634AC86E16F96E45EB7"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Eligible air filtration unit</header><text>The term <term>eligible air filtration unit</term> means an air filtration unit that—</text><subparagraph id="HB83710FC752E4330A782C1EC70AAF3D6" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is certified by Association of Home Appliance Manufacturers to have a Clean Air Delivery Rate of at least 97 for smoke; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA5BE8C78E8C34EBAB41EA31DC93045E3"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is certified under the Energy Star program established by section 324A of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6294a">42 U.S.C. 6294a</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF7599E6A4F664565AFFD4DB74B3B94B4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>does not emit ozone; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9C25553600F645CC9CFC2391902575CC"><enum>(D)</enum><text>uses a true high-efficiency particulate air filter rated to remove 99.97 percent of particles measuring 0.3 micrometers or greater.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7D5D4957855444CC80DD5487CF8A8245"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Low-income community</header><text>The term <term>low-income community</term> has the meaning given such term in section 45D of the Internal Revenue Code (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/45D">26 U.S.C. 45D</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H81A9E7B184554C599BD700B01EA7B472"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><paragraph id="HE235260E40A04550A24821B0F112FE59"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Administrator to carry out this section $30,000,000 for the period of fiscal years 2026 through 2028.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0D830288975448C099102BDBB1937405"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administrative expenses</header><text>Of the funds made available under paragraph (1), the Administrator may use not more than 10 percent of such funds on expenses relating to administering the cleaner air space program.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

