<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6CF58710965B450C809F6F440BEEF738" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 705 IH: Expressing support for the designation of the week beginning on September 14, 2025, as “Celebrate Community Week”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 705</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250911">September 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000467">Mr. Thompson of Pennsylvania</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of the week beginning on September 14, 2025, as <quote>Celebrate Community Week</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas <quote>Celebrate Community</quote> is a weeklong initiative to promote joint community service among members of Lions Clubs International, Rotary International, Kiwanis International, and Optimist International, and the purpose is to elevate the collective social impact of the organizations and promote a spirit of worldwide volunteer collaboration;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, from September 14 through September 20, thousands of local area Kiwanis, Lions, Optimist International, and Rotary clubs will take part in service to address the needs of their communities during their second annual Celebrate Community initiative;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Kiwanis clubs change children’s lives by conducting service projects in their local communities focused on health and nutrition, education and literacy, and youth development;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas Kiwanis clubs conduct more than 7,700,000 service projects globally and raise nearly $390,000,000 annually;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Lions clubs encourage service-minded individuals to serve their communities without personal financial reward;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, since 1917, Lions 1,400,000 members have strengthened local communities through hands-on service and humanitarian projects, focused on the environment and addressing childhood cancer, hunger, diabetes, vision, and other pressing humanitarian needs presenting some of the biggest challenges facing humanity;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, carrying the motto <quote>Bringing Out the Best in Youth, in our Communities, and in Ourselves</quote>, Optimist International clubs conduct positive service projects that reach more than 6,000,000 young people each year;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Optimist International clubs conduct 65,000 community service projects each year, spending $78,000,000 in their communities and impacting over 6,000,000 youth;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Rotary’s more than 1,200,000 members believe we have a shared responsibility to take action on the world’s most persistent issues with sustainable, community-based solutions; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas more than 45,000 Rotary clubs invest hundreds of millions of dollars and countless volunteer hours to provide clean water, sanitation, and hygiene, support basic literacy and education, prevent and treat disease, support maternal and child health, support community economic development, support peacebuilding and conflict prevention, protect the environment, and end polio worldwide: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H091F61D8415B4C2D84FB652EF26B8279"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H2BA9008ECEA7416F8CCDE4424BFB46BC"><enum/><text>That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="H08D36CEBD55B4B15B7FC46D5DA0D8E79"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the designation of Celebrate Community Week;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB71BF5FB749F4A4DBDA47DF679A307D6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes Kiwanis International, Lions Clubs International, Optimist International, and Rotary International for promoting community service and humanitarian assistance;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5EF9596774744FF799B5C71E7E331C9E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>encourages Kiwanis International, Lions Clubs International, Optimist International, and Rotary International to continue to emphasize the values of community service and improving the community for all individuals, especially our youth;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H49DE9981F6284A669F48F10C725CA3C3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>applauds Kiwanis International, Lions Clubs International, Optimist International, and Rotary International for instilling in young people the value of community service; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H60FA9FB2EAAE43599EF8B502CA9EDA19"><enum>(5)</enum><text>appreciates Kiwanis International, Lions Clubs International, Optimist International, and Rotary International for the work of their members to continue to strengthen our communities through service.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

