<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7035A9C0B39446EA84A26922C8F511D7" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1185 IH: Human Trafficking and Exploitation Prevention Training Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1185</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250211">February 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001260">Mr. Buchanan</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Public Health Service Act to provide for the implementation of curricula for training students, teachers, and school personnel to understand, recognize, prevent, and respond to signs of human trafficking and exploitation in children and youth, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H1FC9212FCC2143F090E5673911335ED7" style="OLC"><section id="H50EC40A7633744E7A88FA7E136CA24F3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Human Trafficking and Exploitation Prevention Training Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H12348F054946490EA3DC47A294E352B0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="HBAC23257F8684A3083FA62AD9613E81B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>According to the National Human Trafficking Hotline, operated by the National Human Trafficking Resource Center, there is no single profile for trafficking survivors—trafficking survivors include adults and minors from rural, suburban, and urban communities across the country. Survivors of human trafficking have diverse socioeconomic backgrounds, varied levels of education, and may be documented or undocumented. According to the 2018 Trafficking In Persons Report produced by the Department of State, the Department of Justice, the National Human Trafficking Resource Center, and Youth.gov, vulnerable populations and risk factors for human trafficking include—</text><subparagraph id="H1535379A737E4DC18F89F69AEA6E6ECF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>children in the child welfare and juvenile justice systems;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5981E92574C248788C2E88BC4E23CA9A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>runaway youth;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAF1490B6529C42DF885453B610BAFE8F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>homeless youth;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA2222EAABCB4466AB47C311F8AF558BA"><enum>(D)</enum><text>youth forced to leave home by parents or caregivers with no alternate care arranged;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF05CE9C629794879AAE8AA80821C014D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>unaccompanied children;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCD18527B8FFB4B989CC15B4777AECE13"><enum>(F)</enum><text>American Indians and Alaska Natives;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCBACE18C0C5547BC8B504BB87EE5FC6F"><enum>(G)</enum><text>migrant laborers, including undocumented workers and individuals with temporary visas;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA1E60AC0131047F2B59167F1F41507E6"><enum>(H)</enum><text>recent migration or relocation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCD8937C382A4474CAADB69BF8543DEA2"><enum>(I)</enum><text>persons with disabilities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H134489F7895D4987AAB25305DC37ED2A"><enum>(J)</enum><text>LGBTI individuals;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H45C6B3131239403AAFF8EC25CFFA4229"><enum>(K)</enum><text>people of color;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAED40DE615F8412F815D8A3EB2D581BA"><enum>(L)</enum><text>those with limited-English proficiency;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H80DABA679A1C47779AF7F5DFD0FB7A52"><enum>(M)</enum><text>low literacy;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6E5CE9925259483BAFE4D73D4E0F2224"><enum>(N)</enum><text>substance abuse;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H71F921B5E21847F9991BBDFE3FD36B8E"><enum>(O)</enum><text>mental health issues;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0F82963120B349AFB3083496BE756F21"><enum>(P)</enum><text>past trauma or violence;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF7113AA387C648C6AFD39B74158B3730"><enum>(Q)</enum><text>stigma or discrimination;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H04D7F8CE409F40BBA0B51FD539A60D9F"><enum>(R)</enum><text>family conflict, disruption, or dysfunction;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4EAB2359881848EA9587D98375F4623F"><enum>(S)</enum><text>community-level risk factors such as peer pressure, social norms, social isolation, gang involvement, and living in an under-resourced school, neighborhood, or community; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB9FB853C709E434E9993AAF18F5D5DC5"><enum>(T)</enum><text>society-level risk factors such as lack of awareness of commercial exploitation and human trafficking, sexualization of children, and lack of resources.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5737838A6BF1437EA4DF0F94A40D6E05"><enum>(2)</enum><text>According to the National Human Trafficking Resource Center, human trafficking survivors have been identified in cities, suburbs, and rural areas in all 50 States, and in Washington, DC. The 3 States with the highest incidents of human trafficking cases reported via phone calls, emails, and online tips to the National Human Trafficking Hotline in 2018 were California, Texas, and Florida, respectively.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2F723D67880E4F1AA92BD746FA9E61C7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>According to the National Human Trafficking Resource Center, the top recruitment methods used by sex traffickers based on self-reported data from survivors involve an intimate partner or marriage proposition, family members, individuals posing as a benefactor, offers of employment, or individuals perpetrating fraud or offering false promises.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB0AE02DF62364DF29A2FE723137E411A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>According to the National Center on Safe Supportive Learning Environments, traffickers may systematically target vulnerable children by frequenting locations where children congregate—malls, schools, bus and train stations, and group homes, among other locations. Traffickers also use peers or classmates who befriend the target and slowly groom the child for the trafficker by bringing the child along to parties and other activities. According to Common Sense Media, nearly all children age 8 and under live in a home with some type of mobile device and use it every day. This is especially concerning given that traffickers often recruit through social media platforms and other websites.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H98B43CB24F75423E83525A2213F3BE5B"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Those within vulnerable populations are often exploited or groomed for entry into human trafficking at a very young age. According to a 2005 clinical report, <quote>The Evaluation of Sexual Abuse in Children</quote>, published by the American Academy of Pediatrics, studies have suggested that each year approximately 739,000 children experience some form of sexual abuse, resulting in the sexual victimization of 12 percent to 25 percent of girls and 8 percent to 10 percent of boys before the age of 18.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF2437EF6E12248F2A3830AE52033BE1D"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Sex trafficking and exploitation can take many harmful forms, including a lesser-known but just as damaging form of uncoerced exploitation referred to as <quote>survival sex</quote>, meaning the exchange of sex for basic needs including clothing, food, shelter, or other basic necessities. Survival sex does not involve a third-party trafficker or exploiter, and often affects youth, including those who are homeless, runaways, or housing-insecure, who lack the financial resources, job readiness, support system, or opportunity to afford or access these basic necessities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H964022A5DBC2493BA183C39CE4B8315C"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Training students, teachers, and school personnel to understand, recognize, and respond to signs of human trafficking and exploitation in children and youth is invaluable in the effort to identify and prevent human trafficking and exploitation before it occurs. According to the National Human Trafficking Resource Center, the widespread lack of awareness and understanding of human trafficking leads to low levels of survivor identification by the people who most often encounter them. Survivors of human trafficking are often forced to work or provide commercial sex against their will in legal and legitimate business settings or underground markets. It is often the case that those who are being exploited or trafficked are in plain view and may interact with community members, underscoring the urgent need for the expansion of training programs to increase awareness and prevention activities in communities across the United States.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HBC3B307014BB47FE9BBD6E995610E301"><enum>3.</enum><header>Demonstration project to train students, teachers, and school personnel To understand, recognize, prevent, and respond to signs of human trafficking and child exploitation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 582 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/290hh-1">42 U.S.C. 290hh–1</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HF72B5FE640B34FE580B5DBA6393E33BF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (j) and (k) as subsections (k) and (l), respectively;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAC91A2C156A54C7493875229163F29BC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (i) the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H30455A46E6964AF9A88F6D45331BD692" style="OLC"><subsection commented="no" id="H542C24BBF47E4BE58C591F4A62F44DE8"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Demonstration project To train students, teachers, and school personnel To understand, recognize, prevent, and respond to signs of human trafficking and child exploitation</header><paragraph commented="no" id="HEF999F6BCAE54D9B8F711D6B41F4770D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Office on Trafficking in Persons of the Administration for Children and Families (in this subsection referred to as the <quote>Director</quote>) shall carry out a demonstration project for training students, teachers, and school personnel at elementary schools and secondary schools to understand, recognize, prevent, and respond to signs of human trafficking and exploitation in children and youth.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H2D3F42AA80BB4F468880FC84B8156D22"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Project activities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the demonstration project under this subsection, the Director shall—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H26688ED524814B028B1A0BAEDE2EEDB5"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">approve vendors pursuant to paragraph (3); </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HC3F6B09B0F194D9CB40C61398BF6BCFD"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">award grants pursuant to paragraph (4);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H7C7BAB7C671D4DB2B1C910B92877CC31"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop a reliable methodology for vendors and grantees to collect, and report to the Director, in a manner that prevents disclosure of individually identifiable information consistent with all applicable privacy laws and regulations, data on the number of human trafficking survivors identified and served pursuant to this subsection, the number of students in elementary school or secondary school identified as being at risk of being trafficked or exploited, and the demographics of such survivors and students at risk; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H69D1642761D9452BA28CC98D36684F55"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assist entities that are eligible for grants under paragraph (4) in developing proper protocols and procedures to—</text><clause id="H6E8E6E1A2FF8451CAAA7FA00F0AA747C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>work with law enforcement to report, and facilitate communication with, human trafficking survivors and exploited children; and</text></clause><clause id="H0FD0FF61A3984A96A669CB4466552EF7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>refer human trafficking survivors and exploited children to appropriate social or survivor service agencies or organizations.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HD2A827A7C8AB4DBAB2B9AA2BE98D7949"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Vendors</header><subparagraph commented="no" id="H867C6F97184149489A92E929F4602CFE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the demonstration project under this subsection, the Director shall approve a list of nonprofit organizations as verified vendors—</text><clause commented="no" id="H958C8770FD7F4407A5E4AA1DC9FA5D88"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to develop or make available curricula for the training described in paragraph (1); and</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H1F2605EAF8F649E18BD270571005F6DB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to implement such training in accordance with such curricula.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H365F0048174E4F21B727312CF9385EAE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In approving vendors under this subsection, the Director shall give consideration to whether the nonprofit organization—</text><clause commented="no" id="H3EF5703A9C994E3488083D40C8AA0943"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">engages stakeholders, including survivors of human trafficking, and Federal, State, local, and Tribal partners, to develop the curricula; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="HB3454AC25F7B4B249E9FD50A186022AF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has a demonstrated expertise in—</text><subclause commented="no" id="HD3CF4C9ECBA149BD8D7607927D12992B"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">developing human trafficking and exploitation prevention curricula for students, teachers, or school personnel in elementary school and secondary school that is—</text><item id="HAF0346BF7EB6470D9DD7EA916F08B55C"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>age-appropriate;</text></item><item id="H87ADCE1EED2B4C6197DE878C032699EB"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>culturally competent;</text></item><item id="H27A31D2F6EBC4E879B4C07D30FA351B9"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>evidence based;</text></item><item id="H7C76389F3961409EB91B024F9080B375"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>validated by university research partners;</text></item><item id="H71E1C678B5D14EF38B686AB93E27EBEA"><enum>(ee)</enum><text>inclusive of K–12 students;</text></item><item id="H6677769BE338413F951A5331B054D5E8"><enum>(ff)</enum><text>adaptive to all regions;</text></item><item id="HC69E226AED51442585D36FF345228EBB"><enum>(gg)</enum><text>inclusive of all children; and</text></item><item id="H601E5F28F7084D8DB49B5FE1A98E4A06"><enum>(hh)</enum><text>based on vetted and proven materials that have been tested over a 3-year run of success;</text></item></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HFCC10F9C22B242ECBAFC5ABA4AAD7E82"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">training students, teachers, or school personnel in identification and proper response to human trafficking described in paragraph (1); and</text></subclause><subclause id="H50F130E537C446098773B203CDBBED8E"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">creating a scalable, repeatable <quote>Train the Trainer</quote> program (defined as a program that trains instructors who can teach material to other instructors) that employs appropriate technology tools and methodologies, including measurement and training curricula.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HD0C78E9CD9A948C382F82AD143F34EB4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Grants</header><subparagraph commented="no" id="HBC77BCF4012F4D5FA28B5FFD081CABEB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the demonstration project under this subsection, the Director shall award grants to eligible entities to implement the training described in paragraph (1) in accordance with the curricula developed and made available by verified vendors pursuant to paragraph (3).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HD7378736212D455AA1EE5AF2BD15FAD2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Diversity of grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In awarding grants under this subsection, the Director shall—</text><clause id="H167B49BA4A254BF39FC2F2B163990EB9"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consult with the Director of the Bureau of Justice Assistance, the Administrator for the Office of Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention, the Director of the Office for Victims of Crime, and the head of the Office of Partnership and Engagement of the Department of Homeland Security to identify the geographic areas in the United States with the highest prevalence of reported human trafficking instances for children, aged 5 through 17;</text></clause><clause id="H81FF580A0FDC41998939BE8D62688629"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consult, as appropriate, with the Secretary of Education, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, the Secretary of Labor, and the Attorney General of the United States to identify the geographic areas in the United States with the highest prevalence of at risk, vulnerable, or underserved populations, including homeless youth, foster youth, youth involved in the child welfare system, and runaways; and</text></clause><clause id="H2FCAA528759F4CA9AECBE99E831E856B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>give priority to eligible entities located in, or primarily serving, one or more areas identified pursuant to clause (i) or (ii).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H925C93B6CB364B3984249DC20972FF95"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Allocation of grant funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall ensure that all grant funds under this subsection are awarded to applicants who serve K–12 students.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5464735BB84446399301FA03CC9F1E8D"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this paragraph, the term <term>eligible entity</term> includes a nonprofit organization, an elementary school, a local educational agency, a secondary school, and a State educational agency.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H242E726ABA844297919BEECB784C9891"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Data collection and reporting</header><subparagraph commented="no" id="HB4C9E5FDE1FF4AA4830E69AAF3ED86ED"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director shall collect, and report to the Congress, data on the following:</text><clause commented="no" id="H4B1EFB452810470EA0D3C0808AD342EE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The total number of entities that received a grant under this subsection.</text></clause><clause id="H505244F07346415485200896ABF3301E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The total number of elementary and secondary schools that established proper protocols and procedures through program development.</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H58A9D899A17C408C967BA0CE76531A2C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The total number and geographic distribution of students, teachers, and school personnel trained pursuant to this subsection.</text></clause><clause id="H4C44E8C5783E452689C0EB6201237C2C"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The results of pretraining and posttraining surveys to gauge increased understanding and recognition of signs of human trafficking and exploitation in children and youth.</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H03CB479169E2465C86C2AFDFA80AE992"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number of human trafficking survivors and exploited children identified and served by vendors and grantees under this subsection, excluding any individually identifiable information about such survivors and children.</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H8E82294956D14670AEC574705D1C77D6"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number of students in elementary school or secondary school identified by vendors and grantees under this subsection as being at risk of being trafficked or exploited, excluding any individually identifiable information about such survivors.</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H11EBFD9924DB4D33B4770970239EF5F8"><enum>(vii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The demographics of human trafficking survivors, exploited children, and students at risk of being trafficked or exploited described in clauses (v) and (vi), excluding any individually identifiable information about such survivors, children, and students.</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="HFE85D67DA5B74552AF9DE731FAEFC935"><enum>(viii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any best practices identified by the grantees under this subsection.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HCF84BA0F67654104BC5274B0A4A2D4E4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>The Director shall—</text><clause commented="no" id="H0B101B1E05CA4198A12106B1C1BE72C0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>submit a report under subparagraph (A) not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this subsection and annually thereafter; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="HBA166490E800402DBD547B09BF2350E6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>prepare and submit each such report in a manner that prevents the disclosure of individually identifiable information consistent with all applicable privacy laws and regulations.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H47A7C366BF314852832901376B73A1A9"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text><subparagraph id="HFC7387D206A0404FA120F97DF6B86F63"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The terms <term>elementary school</term>, <term>local educational agency</term>, <term>middle grades</term>, <term>secondary school</term>, and <term>State educational agency</term> have the meanings given to those terms in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC7945B400B7A4E75942F816B8E7B5ABE"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>school personnel</term> includes school resource officers, school nurses, school counselors, school principals, school administrators, and other school leadership.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H1A7E333019C14CF9A5DCB1D9735EF08A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (k) (authorizing appropriations), as redesignated by paragraph (1)—</text><subparagraph id="HD3F017843BB6405CB36D95DFD1ADA15E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAF1F9DC9EB3D41E8A9B66E69C0334096" style="OLC"><paragraph id="HAFEB3709849F4F3A8A5EE5B1CCAE1ADD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section (other than subsection (j))</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA73B6B811D31449C90F3AB85BE78FF22"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF30CC54A384949229CEAFCFFC5B7F691" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H383E14BB2D0345339636F5F47D9B223E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Demonstration project funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out subsection (j) $15,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2029.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

