<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H24359495829741EB86A9B354F12DB0B7" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 604 IH: A resolution unequivocally condemning nationwide violent attacks on Federal agents enforcing America’s immigration laws.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 604</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250723">July 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="I000056">Mr. Issa</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="C000059">Mr. Calvert</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">A resolution unequivocally condemning nationwide violent attacks on Federal agents enforcing America’s immigration laws.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas after 4 years of the Biden Administration’s open borders and systematic enabling of millions of illegal migrants to enter the homeland and remain shielded from deportation, the Trump Administration is seeing that America’s laws against criminal illegals are being faithfully executed;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Trump Administration’s policies have resulted in an almost total cessation of illegal border crossings, the most significant number of deportations in recent history, and, most importantly, the apprehension of hundreds of the most-wanted criminally violent illegals;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas in many areas of the country, the brave men and women on the front lines representing Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) as well as Customs and Border Patrol (CBP) are facing violent mobs of both citizens and illegal aliens who have not only repeatedly blocked, menaced, and confronted law enforcement, but also attempted to burn and kill our ICE and CBP agents as they carried out their proper and legal duties;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on May 2, 2025, 3 San Jose-based ICE deportation officers were assaulted and injured by a Nicaraguan national while attempting to take him into custody on a warrant for his removal and deportation from the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on June 7, 2025, in Los Angeles, more than 1,000 rioters surrounded a Federal law enforcement building, assaulted numerous ICE officers, slashed tires, defaced public buildings, and destroyed private property;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on June 11, 2025, 2 assailants were arrested for assaulting Federal officers in Santa Ana, California;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on both June 14, 2025, and July 4, 2025, multiple officers were injured at a Portland, Oregon ICE office where rioters smashed windows, forcibly entered the facility, launched fireworks, set off smoke grenades, and threw rocks at Federal law enforcement;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on July 1, 2025, more than 40 individuals in Los Angeles were charged with violent crimes against ICE enforcement, including attempted murder, assaults on peace officers, rioting, vandalism, and animal cruelty;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on July 4, 2025, a group of more than a dozen rioters violently attacked the ICE Prairieland Detention Center in Alvarado, Texas, fired dozens of rounds at personnel and wounded a local police officer, while also vandalizing vehicles and equipment at the facility with threatening messages to ICE officials;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on July 7, 2025, an assailant fired dozens of rounds at the entrance of the United States Border Patrol sector annex in McAllen, Texas, wounding a local police officer and a Border Patrol agent, and as a result, the FBI has arrested 10 suspects and the Johnson County Sheriff has confirmed that each now face local charges of terrorism, aggravated assault on a public servant with a deadly weapon, or aggravated assault with a deadly weapon against a peace officer;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas House and Senate Democrats have introduced the No Masks for ICE Act, which would prohibit agents from protecting their identities by wearing face coverings during enforcement action;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas numerous law enforcement agents have repeatedly and publicly stated that they fear retaliation from criminal illegals and others who have pledged to target the agents’ families by learning their identities; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas elected Democrats have proclaimed that CBP and ICE are <quote>Donald Trump’s modern-day gestapo,</quote><quote>like a terrorist force,</quote><quote>a rogue agency that should not exist,</quote> and responsible for an <quote>unprecedented flood of extremism being unleashed on the American people</quote>: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H4758835DE849453EACF602FB1B0C1356"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HB81E44A59AC04455AAADF55C453DD6E5"><enum/><text>That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="HE426E8EBAD994361BBF955AD9854F0D1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognizes that the heroic men and women of ICE and CBP work long hours every day to enforce our laws, detain and deport criminal illegal aliens from the United States, and protect law-abiding American citizens;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD68B064739F444AC83F48E472ABF4E6F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>unequivocally condemns all acts of violence perpetrated by criminal illegals and others against Federal, State, and local law enforcement during the incidents cited in this resolution; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1B2F6B6B809A4C208DE9C6EDFCB64DD5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>calls on local, State, and Federal elected officials to support the law enforcement representatives and partners of the Federal Government as it duly and officially enforces our laws against illegal immigration and violent crime.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

