<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="H5AD31F9D1C9B42E19F2B4FB7C5D9E5D8" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Engrossed-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 488 EH: Denouncing the antisemitic terrorist attack in Boulder, Colorado.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">IV</distribution-code> 
<congress display="no">119th CONGRESS</congress> 
<session display="no">1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. RES. 488</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="yes">In the House of Representatives, U. S.,</current-chamber>
<action>
<action-date date="20250609">June 9, 2025</action-date>
</action> 
<legis-type display="yes">RESOLUTION</legis-type> 
<official-title display="no">Denouncing the antisemitic terrorist attack in Boulder, Colorado.</official-title> 
</form> 
<preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, on June 1, 2025, Mohammed Sabry Soliman, an Egyptian national illegally in the United States, committed a terrorist attack in Boulder, Colorado, against marchers peacefully demonstrating in support of the release of hostages held captive by Hamas;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, while shouting <quote>Free Palestine</quote>, Mohammed Sabry Soliman attacked the peaceful demonstrators with homemade Molotov cocktails;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Mohammed Sabry Soliman stated he planned the terrorist attack for more than a year, <quote>wanted to kill all Zionist people and wished they were all dead</quote>, and would <quote>do it [conduct an attack] again</quote>;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the terrorist attack committed by Mohammed Sabry Soliman wounded at least 14 people who suffered burns and other injuries;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, reportedly, at least one of the victims was a Holocaust survivor;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas everyone should pray for the quick healing of the victims of Mohammed Sabry Soliman’s antisemitic terrorist attack;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Mohammed Sabry Soliman was issued a tourist visa to travel to the United States;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Mohammed Sabry Soliman was admitted to the United States at Los Angeles International Airport on August 27, 2022;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, one month after his arrival in the United States and seemingly in violation of the terms of his nonimmigrant visa, which required that he not intend to remain in the United States permanently, Mohammed Sabry Soliman filed an asylum application with U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Mohammed Sabry Soliman failed to depart the United States prior to the expiration of his authorized period of stay pursuant to his visa;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the case of Mohammed Sabry Soliman highlights the need to aggressively vet aliens who apply for visas to determine whether they endorse, espouse, promote, or support antisemitic terrorism or engage in other antisemitic or anti-American activity;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the case of Mohammed Sabry Soliman demonstrates the dangers of not removing from the country aliens who fail to comply with the terms of their visas; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Colorado law enforcement officials have encountered Mohammed Sabry Soliman multiple times since 2022: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas> </preamble> <resolution-body style="OLC" id="HA3EEB0BBB3F24161A5AF4E921318FD02"> <section id="HDD5FBD4FA33344C09785CCC72EB8C658" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> 
<paragraph id="HFBD96EB2D878435DAF68FEDC7CAA9FF0"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">condemns Mohammed Sabry Soliman and his antisemitic terrorist attack on peaceful demonstrators supporting the release of the hostages held by Hamas;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD53471F4B59A430D8FB64F81905D4D8D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">affirms that free and open communication between State and local law enforcement and their Federal counterparts remains the bedrock of public safety and is necessary in preventing terrorist attacks; and </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9903278813A2453FA289B21C63CEC70D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>expresses gratitude to law enforcement officers, including U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement personnel, for protecting the homeland.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body> <attestation><attestation-group><attestor display="no">Kevin F. McCumber,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation> </resolution> 

