<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-concurrent" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" slc-id="S1-ROM25015-4PN-J2-VT7"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SCON 3 ATS: Authorizing the use of the rotunda of the Capitol for the lying in state of the remains of the late James Earl Carter, Jr., 39th President of the United States.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. CON. RES. 3</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250103">January 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S357">Mrs. Fischer</cosponsor>) submitted the following concurrent resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>CONCURRENT RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Authorizing the use of the rotunda of the Capitol for the lying in state of the remains of the late James Earl Carter, Jr., 39th President of the United States.</official-title></form><resolution-body style="OLC" display-resolving-clause="yes-display-resolving-clause"><section id="ida911198a93874e1dbd85f490e90f1c13" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Honoring James Earl Carter, Jr</header><subsection id="id2e131d57e29047bcad1c6ba1c1d6409a"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Lying in State in rotunda</header><text>In recognition of the long and distinguished service rendered to the Nation and to the world by the late James Earl Carter, Jr., the 39th President of the United States, his remains shall be permitted to lie in state in the rotunda of the Capitol from January 7, 2025 until January 9, 2025. The Architect of the Capitol, under the direction of the Majority Leader of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives, shall take all necessary steps for the accomplishment of that purpose.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id632df83745c14194b0f1a5288d834449"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of catafalque</header><text>The Architect of the Capitol is authorized and directed to transfer the catafalque which is situated in the Exhibition Hall of the Capitol Visitor Center to the rotunda of the Capitol so that such catafalque may be used in connection with services to be conducted there for the late James Earl Carter, Jr., 39th President of the United States.</text></subsection></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

