<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H45D49860E9D54299B1AECF7397C1D7F5" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 339 IH: Broadband Resiliency and Flexible Investment Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 339</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250113">January 13, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001120">Mr. Crenshaw</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Middle Class Tax Relief and Job Creation Act of 2012 to streamline the consideration by State and local governments of requests for modification of certain existing wireless facilities and telecommunications service facilities, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H73CFB7E235914EA18648DAC9DA0AE5ED" style="OLC"><section id="H50331DD986994902B07F94C47B835D16" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Broadband Resiliency and Flexible Investment Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H902B99839E6144BFA11B1FC0CE720A07" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Requests for modification of certain existing wireless and telecommunications service facilities</header><subsection id="HEB5870EE320B4B09803A3F690126DFA9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 6409(a) of the Middle Class Tax Relief and Job Creation Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1455">47 U.S.C. 1455(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H1DC401CCFA374FB7BBEFD57860DB9238"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>a State or local government</quote> and all that follows and inserting the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H5493CD9A23384C0780EDA6895BCEA811" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><text>a State or local government or instrumentality thereof may not deny, and shall approve—</text><paragraph id="HE7A33BD037964AB89142094E5B34D2D2" indent="down1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any eligible facilities request for a modification of an existing wireless tower, base station, or eligible support structure that does not substantially change the physical dimensions of such wireless tower, base station, or eligible support structure; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H40F76E128F974DA89BF7191304A813B8" indent="down1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any eligible telecommunications facilities request for a modification of an existing telecommunications service facility in or on eligible support infrastructure that does not substantially change the physical dimensions of such facility. </text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H8B8E1C653E194F6E9D6ABEF912DD7569"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by amending paragraph (2) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF1C6155677A849EDB853C29114BBCA8B"><paragraph id="HC437367FAD0E418AB7D31A01802755A5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Timeframe</header><subparagraph id="H7D91D6029504417D92AF2407BF979723"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Deemed approval</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a State or local government or instrumentality thereof does not, before or on the date that is 60 days after the date on which a requesting party submits to the government or instrumentality a request as an eligible facilities request or an eligible telecommunications facilities request (as the case may be), approve the request or make the determination and provide the written notice described in subparagraph (B) with respect to the request, the request is deemed approved on the day after the date that is 60 days after the date on which the requesting party submits the request.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H114D273611DC4286BB2CC3D265A8C01D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Determination request is not an eligible request</header><clause id="HD3A3FA63B60045D0ADE73BFA8534B7F1"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Determination described</header><text>The determination described in this subparagraph is a determination by a State or local government or instrumentality thereof that a request described in subparagraph (A) is not an eligible facilities request or an eligible telecommunications facilities request (as the case may be).</text></clause><clause id="H68307223AE0B4F23A00DFAACECB40B05"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Written notice described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The written notice described in this subparagraph is a written notice of the determination described in clause (i) provided by the government or instrumentality to the requesting party that clearly describes the reasons why the request is not an eligible facilities request or an eligible telecommunications facilities request (as the case may be) and includes a citation to a specific provision of this subsection or the regulations promulgated under this subsection relied upon for the determination.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H669BDEA25D9540839C14A2D94351F55E"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Tolling due to incompleteness</header><clause id="HF6D77BB52CC745ADA6C2C05E93C8A3ED"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Initial request incomplete</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If, not later than 30 days after the date on which a requesting party submits to a State or local government or instrumentality thereof a request described in subparagraph (A), the government or instrumentality provides to the requesting party a written notice described in clause (iii) with respect to the request, the 60-day timeframe under subparagraph (A) is tolled until the date on which the requesting party submits to the government or instrumentality a supplemental submission in response to the notice.</text></clause><clause id="H144497AA2F7140E2A8357BC0FA1AEC33"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Supplemental submission incomplete</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If, not later than 10 days after the date on which a requesting party submits to a State or local government or instrumentality thereof a supplemental submission in response to a written notice under clause (i) with respect to a request described in subparagraph (A) or a written notice under this clause with respect to a subsequent supplemental submission, the government or instrumentality provides to the requesting party a written notice described in clause (iii) with respect to the supplemental submission, the 60-day timeframe under subparagraph (A) is further tolled until the date on which the requesting party submits to the government or instrumentality a subsequent supplemental submission in response to the notice.</text></clause><clause id="H77110FF6F6E944ACBBDC915271B6A4BD"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Written notice described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The written notice described in this clause is, with respect to a request described in subparagraph (A) or a supplemental submission described in clause (i) or (ii) submitted to a State or local government or instrumentality thereof by a requesting party, a written notice from the government or instrumentality to the requesting party—</text><subclause id="H489607BB996147FE83660EA61F8B76CB"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">stating that all of the information (including any form or other document) required by the government or instrumentality to be submitted for the request to be considered complete has not been submitted;</text></subclause><subclause id="HE476DFF500774B808C91945BCF35CB6B"><enum>(II)</enum><text>identifying the information described in subclause (I) that was not submitted; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H08F640B73E7349AAAFD1B6180A28ACB0"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">including a citation to a specific provision of a publicly available rule, regulation, or standard issued by the government or instrumentality requiring that such information be submitted with such a request.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H53B26BA09C7A4D4FBE4C9DB6E851918E" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Limitation</header><subclause id="HEB011D6D561D433BA85E62B14C71E985" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Initial written notice</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a written notice provided by a State or local government or instrumentality thereof to a requesting party under clause (i) with respect to a request described in subparagraph (A) identifies as not having been submitted any information that the government or instrumentality is prohibited by paragraph (5) from requiring to be submitted, such notice shall be treated as not having been provided to the requesting party.</text></subclause><subclause id="HB3D32662A5D643DE8B003C82C8E3C905" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Subsequent written notice</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a written notice provided by a State or local government or instrumentality thereof to a requesting party under clause (ii) with respect to a supplemental submission identifies as not having been submitted any information that was not identified as not having been submitted in the prior written notice under clause (i) or (ii) in response to which the supplemental submission was submitted, the subsequent written notice shall be treated as not having been provided to the requesting party.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H621410E833A948D291D0452EC7854A0F"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Tolling by mutual agreement</header><text>In addition to any tolling under subparagraph (C), the 60-day timeframe under subparagraph (A) may be tolled by mutual agreement between the State or local government or instrumentality thereof and the requesting party.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H63BE2495F9C94AADA2FEA52E1B1D0A0E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>paragraph (1)</quote> and inserting <quote>this subsection</quote>; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H70ED2D20643B46EBBE1262A8D65C5E7B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block id="HC78AB9A73CEA46E5A9C291728FD6752A" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H447320EB99EF4434A6507AD050958F1A" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>When request considered submitted</header><subparagraph id="H317B53D2BBC845D2834EC6B31924B6E3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For the purposes of this subsection, a request described in paragraph (2)(A) shall be considered submitted on the date on which the requesting party takes the first procedural step within the control of the requesting party—</text><clause id="HE41B3920FE9A4AE491F3A0F13FCA6BA6"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to submit such request in accordance with the procedures established by the government or instrumentality for the review and approval of such a request; or</text></clause><clause id="HBAFB2542727842EC96DFDA4F4F684626"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a government or instrumentality that has not established specific procedures for the review and approval of such a request, to submit to the government or instrumentality the type of filing that is typically required to initiate a standard review for a similar facility or structure.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5A73AE0D0AC04BF6A8D9EE7AA96E76A2" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>No pre-application requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State or local government or instrumentality thereof may not require a requesting party to undertake any process, meeting, or other step prior to or as a prerequisite to a request being considered submitted.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3C176A642C454BB6A9DAF02CBAC41EAB"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Limitation on required documentation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State or local government or instrumentality thereof may require a requesting party submitting a request as an eligible facilities request or an eligible telecommunications facilities request to submit information (including a form or other document) with such request only to the extent that such information is reasonably related to determining whether such request is an eligible facilities request or an eligible telecommunications facilities request (as the case may be) and is identified in a publicly available rule, regulation, or standard issued by the government or instrumentality requiring that such information be submitted with such a request. A State or local government or instrumentality thereof may not require a requesting party to submit any other documentation or information with such a request.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA2768139C925491BB7D5F553144CE29E" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><subparagraph id="H179CBFA222004542B5B4925B8C9208BB" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A requesting party may bring an action in any district court of the United States to enforce the provisions of this subsection.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD5A77143817B46ED846686A5F144A856" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Expedited review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A district court of the United States shall consider an action under subparagraph (A) on an expedited basis.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8B7DB2A57FBC44A19A174FBF3F7BCA1F"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection: </text><subparagraph id="H67F68EB55DBA4994ACFFB6F14CB42659"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Eligible facilities request</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible facilities request</term> means any request for a modification of an existing wireless tower, base station, or eligible support structure that does not substantially change the physical dimensions of such wireless tower, base station, or eligible support structure and that involves—</text><clause id="H64A14B8C88B8436C8A320A11B5F4BDB3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>collocation of new transmission equipment;</text></clause><clause id="HF3E6572154D7494CB0EE2C7940ECD201"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>removal of transmission equipment;</text></clause><clause id="H84473D0298244FC8B4F8A1BDD70D99CA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>replacement of transmission equipment; or</text></clause><clause id="HC773A37BBD5C4C2C990F72294E64ED04"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>placement, construction, or modification of equipment that—</text><subclause id="HF68A68A7612046C4B9644AB0944B21A8"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">improves the resiliency of the wireless tower, base station, or eligible support structure; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HD4F139F8BB024CDDA9B510473CDE11FB"><enum>(II)</enum><text>provides a direct benefit to public safety, such as—</text><item id="HD4FFA186C3F34ED09EA312F9E6A5F90D"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">providing backup power for the wireless tower, base station, or eligible support structure;</text></item><item id="HA6C2B97D88EF47168FDBF184667F82AF"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">hardening the wireless tower, base station, or eligible support structure; or</text></item><item id="H6AFE991B651740DA8874DE920D4A8799"><enum>(cc)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">providing more reliable connection capability using the wireless tower, base station, or eligible support structure.</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBA6675E15FB344519D0D4C3E20EDF29C" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Eligible support infrastructure</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>eligible support infrastructure</quote> means infrastructure that supports or houses a telecommunications service facility at the time when an eligible telecommunications facilities request for a modification of such facility is submitted to a State or local government or instrumentality thereof.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5B32EB8DC75B4CFBAEF07FE557852067" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Eligible support structure</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible support structure</term> means a structure that, at the time when an eligible facilities request for a modification of such structure is submitted to a State or local government or instrumentality thereof, supports or could support transmission equipment.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3D3A79FFA10C451BAAD9AFD2F0D0B5ED"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Eligible telecommunications facilities request</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible telecommunications facilities request</term> means any request for a modification of an existing telecommunications service facility in or on eligible support infrastructure that does not substantially change the physical dimensions of such facility and that involves—</text><clause id="HC970C30F5A5F41418DBB843762761F7D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>collocation of new telecommunications service facility equipment;</text></clause><clause id="HE700D170DEB545F0B4213A5896515D61"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>removal of telecommunications service facility equipment; or</text></clause><clause id="H3B66948DEC09440ABB63F972D35296C1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>replacement of telecommunications service facility equipment. </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H833B6641E2914F9E9E302DFF41C81B2A" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Telecommunications service facility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>telecommunications service facility</term>—</text><clause id="H5D48DC9621D54C3FAAFBF0E94E188605"><enum>(i)</enum><text>means a facility that is designed or used to provide or facilitate the provision of any interstate or intrastate telecommunications service; and</text></clause><clause id="H836A2E80B53D460F9171EAAB0C0C2095"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>includes a facility described in clause (i) that is used to provide other services.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H77AB71DCA72243878411674AAF3FF4BC"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Transmission equipment</header><text>The term <quote>transmission equipment</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 1.6100(b)(8) of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of the enactment of this paragraph).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H709E32B293CD47E5ABDEE3819C6CA101"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Federal Communications Commission shall issue final rules to implement the amendments made by subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="H77841A9677DF4DC3966D0F1204C048F2" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by subsection (a) shall apply with respect to any eligible facilities request or eligible telecommunications facilities request described in paragraph (1) of section 6409(a) of the Middle Class Tax Relief and Job Creation Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1455">47 U.S.C. 1455(a)</external-xref>) that is submitted (as determined under paragraph (4) of such section, as added by subsection (a)) by a requesting party on or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

