<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6E06B18BAE4E448E840B0586FFEB91BF" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4200 IH: End DED Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4200</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250626">June 26, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000614">Mr. Roy</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="T000165">Mr. Tiffany</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000603">Mr. Gill of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001132">Mr. Crane</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001115">Mr. Cloud</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000605">Mr. Perry</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide that no Federal funds may be used for the Deferred Enforced Departure Program, or any successor program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB27B73719C7D4B4299400CC0D704F0E3" style="OLC"><section id="HEA8A5C4681714E96A966C1D242053613" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>End DED Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H023D2F48905348409E568B3CFA9BF760"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="HB85DE513F5444AEE860B3CCB8DC1CC3E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In 1990, the George H.W. Bush administration first used Deferred Enforced Departure (DED) to avoid removing aliens present in the United States whose home countries could not accept their safe return. DED has no statutory basis in the Immigration and Nationality Act and was never approved by Congress. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H81099D7601C04349B9E00C767852F81C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The <quote>constitutional powers to conduct foreign relations</quote> of the President are cited as a basis for DED. However, when the executive branch defers the removal of aliens, it is an immigration benefit, not a foreign policy function. Congress has plenary power over immigration, giving it almost complete authority to decide whether certain aliens may enter or remain in the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H734D2BC3B6394ABDA5C929BB04929794"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In 1990, Congress established Temporary Protected Status (TPS) as a part of the Immigration Act of 1990 to provide temporary protection from removal for foreign nationals whose home countries face ongoing armed conflict, environmental disaster, or other extraordinary circumstances preventing their safe return home. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H37550D4688F049CEA025630A7F08DFF9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>DED recipients are granted work authorization and may be permitted to travel outside the United States, the same as TPS holders.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H553AC78AE3B140459CB60F251F62EA7F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Since 1990, the executive branch has designated DED for certain nationals from the following nine countries: China, Kuwait, El Salvador, Haiti, Liberia, Venezuela, Palestine, Hong Kong, and Lebanon.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1604C65801034B01823110E626CD1AE5"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Article 1, section 8, clause 18 of the Constitution gives Congress clear jurisdiction on immigration matters. The use of DED through sole executive action undermines Congress's authority to regulate immigration programs in the United States. Congress created TPS to provide certain aliens relief from removal under similar life-threatening circumstances.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H82759F71F36B4632933C4BFB4A7BD0EB"><enum>3.</enum><header>No Federal funds for deferred enforced departure</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no Federal funds, resources, or fees, made available to the President of the United States, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Attorney General, the Secretary of State, or to any other official of a Federal agency, by any Act for any fiscal year, may be used to implement, administer or carry out the Deferred Enforced Departure Program, or any successor program.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

