<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA1C15619793C4DC1A9A682D59D5506CB" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2103 IH: Protect Postal Performance Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2103</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20250314">March 14, 2025</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001315">Ms. Budzinski</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="H001096">Ms. Hageman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000592">Mr. Golden of Maine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001301">Mr. Bergman</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000614">Mr. Pappas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To modify the procedures used by the United States Postal Service for the closure or consolidation of any post office or any processing and distribution center, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H8FBFA7B295024777BB9967A373149AD7" style="OLC">
<section id="HEC841AFC25DC47DE877342ACB7BDAFFF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protect Postal Performance Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H78CB22642BA44A7EB95198CD80666707"><enum>2.</enum><header>Limitation on closure and consolidations of post offices</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 404(d) of title 39, United States Code, is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="H2F8B2D53D67046FE8D7353CE5DA3F65F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)—</text> <subparagraph id="H337DEEFF73D9444FB1D0B68F2FABE7C9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>The Postal Service</quote> and insert <quote>(A) The Postal Service</quote>; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H6AF8E24D13FB4DAABB4D3C82EBC2AB06"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following: </text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="H8DF370542A1E4B2E93F73FA738E28A23" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subparagraph id="HEF1AC61ACD9B40C89DAF90C4B64C91E9"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During such 60-day period, the Postal Service shall carry out a public hearing on the closure or consolidation, which may be attended in-person or virtually by any members of the public affected by the closure or consolidation.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H78B7A4C046C44F52910D2E182B08DBFE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Not later than 7 days after such hearing, the Postal Service shall publish a summary of the hearing on the Postal Service’s public website, and include in such summary a description of any comments made or otherwise submitted at such hearing and the percentage of such comments that were in support or against the closure or consolidation.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H41716268078C4FB295EE41144B89990F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this title, the applicable post office may not be closed or consolidated until the date that is 180 days after the date the summary is published under subparagraph (C).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5970C456E8CE49F29FFD2E25E2C42F83"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="HDFD0F82268E044E0B640207425BDF20C" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="HA79FF069A2E94E9F9D98B5478E9994FF"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of this title, a post office may not be closed or consolidated if such post office—</text>
<subparagraph id="H7E02CC5DBAEC400FBC330782D49A1ECA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is not located within 15 miles of any other post office; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3A265F84A8154C2ABCB6FE3ACB6CC9FD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is the closest post office for a population of 15,000 individuals or more. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section>
<section id="HC18E18E0852241218823832C7D64B4EB"><enum>3.</enum><header>Postal Service processing and distribution centers; transportation optimization</header>
<subsection id="HF8762DB76FAC45B9BAC0993471CE3DF9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/39/4">Chapter 4</external-xref> of title 39, United States Code, is amended by adding after section 416 the following:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="HC46E536DD5004486BE6CB73A621E4A83" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <section id="H23B7585917ED407A90DFFA458A16964B"><enum>417.</enum><header>Postal Service processing and distribution centers</header> <subsection id="H539E2FF3A7924326975F4669B22C7E54"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States Postal Service may not close, consolidate, downgrade, or take any other similar action with respect to any processing and distribution center in a State if such action would result in no such center being located in that State in any geographically non-contiguous region of that State inhabited by more than 100,000 permanent residents. In this subsection, the term <quote>geographically non-contiguous region</quote> means an area of a State that is physically separated from the main body of the State by a significant body of water or land controlled by another State.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H11CB25B8C97540A7881A43E8DB2424A1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitation on changes to mail processing facilities</header>
<paragraph id="HBA98B7ED46A64FD590BC73FA368E38A7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Postal Service may not implement or otherwise carry out any changes to the operations of its mail processing facilities (including consolidation or partial consolidation, aggregation of processing, distribution, or delivery operations) until on or after the date that the Postal Regulatory Commission issues an advisory opinion on the proposed facility changes.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD55E9BD3BADC499793F516B76D42321A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Deadline</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Postal Regulatory Commission shall issue the advisory opinion required under paragraph (1) not later than 120 business days after the date the Postal Service submits to the Commission a proposed change to any such facility.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC9B327271AD14767B1EC911796F90132"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Other requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall issue an advisory opinion for each processing and distribution center at which the Postal Service has proposed changes, downsizing, and consolidations.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDE02C698CA124411BB15EDBCDBA5278F" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an advisory opinion by the Commission under this subsection determines that a proposed change will lead to slower on-time mail delivery, the Postal Service shall publish a report on the Postal Service’s public website on practices and procedures the Postal Service will implement to ensure mail delivery remains on time. No such changes may be implemented or otherwise carried out for the period of 180 days beginning on the date such report is so published. </text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H0E4E9824AD3044E39ACAE39DE7593ED2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Prohibiting on carrying out mail processing facility review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Postal Service may not carry out the United States Postal Service Mail Processing Facility Review (or any successor program), and no Federal funds (including amounts in the Postal Service Fund under section 2003) may be obligated or expended to carry out such Review.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H0504BFAE2F61475BA466173E3DFAC0B7"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limitation of the closure of processing and distribution centers in regions that are not meeting on-Time delivery benchmarks</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During any calendar year, the Postal Service may not close, consolidate, or otherwise move any operations or services from any processing and distribution center located within any Postal Service district that, during anytime within the immediately preceding calendar year, failed to meet—</text>
<paragraph id="H40E292AA9E71485CA6AA7EC74C238260"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">at least 93 percent on-time delivery rate for two-day single first-class mail; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1F8B98FACE0A42C0AFB8AE00A2D686F2"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">at least 90.3 percent on-time delivery rate for three to five-day first-class mail.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HCD389E27AC144049868B894C561A1AAB"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section—</text> <paragraph id="H350DAD91B12D468DBAA1B2E24442512E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>processing and distribution center</term> means a central mail facility that—</text>
<subparagraph id="HFDD408A666E548F9B8AD7F7DAC4864BD"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">distributes and dispatches part or all of both incoming mail and outgoing mail for a designated service area;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H88473E9729E84A3CBD7A5F5391AC9360"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provides instructions on the preparation of collection mail, dispatch schedules, and sorting plan requirements to mailers; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H7D0E91B04A59427DA0D3AE4677844A00"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is a sectional center facility, a general mail facility, or a dedicated mail processing facility without a station or branch; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFE498499FCA84A60A0EC457A5AC5826F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>State</term> means the 50 States and the District of Columbia.</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="H8D7904144FF64320B6F3A024E0DB5474"><enum>418.</enum><header>Local transportation optimization and regional transportation optimization changes</header>
<subsection id="HB6D8572489E547CCA53118478D491E34"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Postal Service may not implement or otherwise carry out any local transportation optimization (in this section referred to as <quote>LTO</quote>) and regional transportation optimization (in this section referred to as <quote>RTO</quote>) efforts that will decrease the number of times mail is either picked up or dropped off for any post office in the country.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HF43E850BC1DD4E3F9B0A41D8FD6EE400"><enum>(b)</enum><header>PRC opinion</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Postal Service may not proceed with changing drop off and pick up schedules at post offices as part of the LTO or RTO plans without requesting a Postal Regulatory Commission opinion.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HEF68BE436D9C4EC4A7CCE1FF80F38E0A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Postal Regulatory Commission does not recommend implementing these changes in an opinion under subsection (b), the Postal Service may not move forward with LTO or RTO optimization efforts anywhere in the United States.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HCA187A0C1FD54E0888183F162999B147"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for such chapter is amended by adding after the item relating to section 416 the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="USC" id="H892CDCA282BC44C6AA827408B3562E7B" display-inline="no-display-inline">
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
<toc-entry level="section">417. Postal Service processing and distribution centers.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry level="section">418. Local transportation optimization and regional transportation optimization changes.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section>
</legis-body>
</bill> 


