<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ERN25023-Y7K-5X-H6D"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S678 IS: Leveraging Integrity and Verification of Eligibility for Beneficiaries Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 678</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250220">February 20, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S404">Mr. Scott of Florida</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to require States to verify certain eligibility criteria for individuals enrolled for medical assistance quarterly, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HF921E0F6D6604E66B84E17DA346D0D70"><section section-type="section-one" id="HEFF361353B874806BDACAD9677DDA45E"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Leveraging Integrity and Verification of Eligibility for Beneficiaries Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>LIVE Beneficiaries Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H1219F8BFB6DB442E920FB88B966E6A1A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Verification of certain eligibility criteria for individuals enrolled for medical assistance</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1902 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396a">42 U.S.C. 1396a</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H70CC8AED4790446780D958C1255B561A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text><subparagraph id="HD9C880E79EA34126BE8536D7842473AA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (86), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0B3FE581762C46FAB584E5B73F11A124"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (87)(D), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBF08224965114790B5559771AE385926"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting after paragraph (87)(D) the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3ACFAAE8279B4CD8A90EF80DE68F3724"><paragraph id="H4CFD52C2B7D744218529BD011B93417A"><enum>(88)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide that the State shall comply with the eligibility verification requirements under subsection (uu), except that this paragraph shall apply only in the case of the 50 States and the District of Columbia.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFFAC6F5C6DF04B199CA85967757F9B9D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB33DC39F1F5949DFBC946C53BF9EBEC4"><subsection id="H894A67FA3DA54FC6BF0982D57BA65975"><enum>(uu)</enum><header>Verification of certain eligibility criteria</header><paragraph id="H6C47B72E0A9D48F2A84D7AFEC57C8127"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of subsection (a)(88), the eligibility verification requirements, beginning January 1, 2027, are as follows:</text><subparagraph id="HF677E80D657C4F87A7978E379A0ACD84"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Quarterly screening to verify enrollee status</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The State shall, not less frequently than quarterly, review the Death Master File (as such term is defined in section 203(d) of the Bipartisan Budget Act of 2013) to determine whether any individuals enrolled for medical assistance under the State plan (or waiver of such plan) are deceased.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3E7C08D991E3453BA356D36CEA4B2013"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Disenrollment under State plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the State determines, based on information obtained from the Death Master File, that an individual enrolled for medical assistance under the State plan (or waiver of such plan) is deceased, the State shall—</text><clause id="H3EFFDEDC671C496199FBE9F4BF39CCD0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>treat such information as factual information confirming the death of a beneficiary for purposes of section 431.213(a) of title 42, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation);</text></clause><clause id="H64DC1ECCE628461691DF3A174067916A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>disenroll such individual from the State plan (or waiver of such plan); and</text></clause><clause id="H295ADD9EE9A64FBEA8CCB438702D5C57"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>discontinue any payments for medical assistance under this title made on behalf of such individual (other than payments for any items or services furnished to such individual prior to the death of such individual).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H19C5AB827B77444C81CF89EB8670161C"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Reinstatement of coverage in the event of error</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a State determines that an individual was misidentified as deceased based on information obtained from the Death Master File, and was erroneously disenrolled from medical assistance under the State plan (or waiver of such plan) based on such misidentification, the State shall immediately reenroll such individual under the State plan (or waiver of such plan), retroactive to the date of such disenrollment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HEED60579CC704A8FB0B84598B3DD4D46"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing under this subsection shall be construed to preclude the ability of a State to use other electronic data sources to timely identify potentially deceased beneficiaries, so long as the State is also in compliance with the requirements of this subsection (and all other requirements under this title relating to Medicaid eligibility determination and redetermination).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

