<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-DAV25H52-HFV-92-Y1T">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 346 IS: Urging all members of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization to spend a minimum of 5 percent of gross domestic product on defense.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>III</distribution-code>
        <congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session display="yes">1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. RES. 346</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action display="yes">
            <action-date date="20250730">July 30, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S389">Mr. Kennedy</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S412">Mr.
                    Tuberville</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S318">Mr. Wicker</cosponsor>,
                    <cosponsor name-id="S417">Mr. Budd</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S287">Mr.
                    Cornyn</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S410">Ms. Lummis</cosponsor>)
                submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign
                Relations</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
        <official-title display="yes">Urging all members of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization
            to spend a minimum of 5 percent of gross domestic product on defense.</official-title>
    </form>
    <preamble>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) has long served as a pillar of collective security and transatlantic cooperation, ensuring stability and shared defense among member states;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas President Donald J. Trump played a leading role in securing increased defense spending commitments from NATO allies to ensure the Alliance remains capable of addressing 21st-century threats;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas the Hague Summit Declaration encouraged allies to allocate at least 5 percent of gross domestic product (GDP) to defense spending, demonstrating a commitment to sharing the burden of collective defense;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas the 5 percent GDP spending commitment will be split between spending 3.5 percent on military spending and 1.5 percent on non-traditional defense spending such as infrastructure and cyber security resilience;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas this target, if implemented with discipline and transparency, has the potential to significantly enhance NATO’s military readiness, deterrence posture, and ability to respond to evolving threats including cyber warfare;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas the imprecise language of the Hague Agreement leaves ambiguity about the requirement of all allies reaching the 5 percent of GDP goal;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas the exclusion of certain member countries from the commitment to spend 5 percent of GDP on defense undermines fidelity to the Alliance;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas the commitment to spending 5 percent of GDP on verifiable defense expenditures is important to the defense of all member nations;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas the inclusion of domestic infrastructure in allies’ calculations toward their 1.5 percent commitment to non-traditional defense expenditures contributes minimally to the Alliance’s ability to address external threats; and</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas the commitment from economies of all sizes within NATO to meet the former goal of spending 2 percent GDP on defense shows that not meeting spending commitments is a choice of will and not of circumstance: Now, therefore, be it</text>
        </whereas>
    </preamble>
    <resolution-body>
        <section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section">
 <text>That the Senate—</text> <paragraph id="id7fde560b682e4753a54369f0c84e60bd"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>congratulates President Donald J. Trump and NATO leadership on the new commitment to defense investment, and commends the Alliance for its renewed focus on collective defense;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="id1162f0fa4a0742119d94de9f9e5824af">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>lauds NATO members who spent more than 2 percent of their GDP on defense prior to the Hague Summit;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="idfc42373ff72742609dc4266319cc7311">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>strongly urges NATO leadership to compel members to adhere to the 5 percent GDP commitment to defense spending;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="idd94f0b926fc54cf38fbf0afa3e96b703">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>calls on all NATO allies to ensure their non-traditional defense expenditures are demonstrably aligned with legitimate defense objectives; and</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="id9223ab7f3eef496ca656a7a3ea0d3604">
                <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text>reaffirms the importance of NATO and the commitment of the United States Senate to maintaining a strong, capable, and united Alliance.</text>
            </paragraph>
        </section>
    </resolution-body>
</resolution>

