<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-TAM25900-X8G-HX-X5R"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2665 IS: Drug Shortage Prevention Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code>II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2665</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250801">August 1, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S252">Ms. Collins</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S366">Ms. Warren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S288">Ms. Murkowski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S394">Ms. Smith</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S380">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to provide for
            notification by manufacturers of critical drugs of increased demand, and for other
 purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H43EFDDEB9C6841F499351597787E6696"><section section-type="section-one" id="H3B69EBF5C33D4CE8845E2C84CB4D1DF3"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Drug Shortage Prevention Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HB4B8D0CA4F464D79B71EE5001C24A44E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Improving notification procedures in case of increased demand for critical
 drugs</header><subsection id="H3AC993FAE4D644CBB7547A2AE46BD401"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 506C of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/356c">21 U.S.C. 356c</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HD385368EE7B44181B161E9B673E4A231"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the section heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">Discontinuance or interruption in the production of life-saving drugs</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">Notification of issues affecting domestic supply of critical drugs</header-in-text></quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCEDED83B383243688F7FD0F325A7DF0D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking subsections (a), (b), and (c), and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCCF9698C0A6A4E349C22C949962B4520"><subsection id="H87E6A28172974AA3B8A5867F8CA1B69D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Notification required</header><paragraph id="H85BA1F8210FE457EB5DDEF7FCA67D26A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A manufacturer of a covered drug shall notify the Secretary, in accordance with subsection (b), of—</text><subparagraph id="H9CF68966A2E84D36A9C7F465736A5889"><enum>(A)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H39F1917FDFE6470D86119C423262E81D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a permanent discontinuance in the manufacture of the drug or an interruption of the manufacture of the drug that is likely to lead to a meaningful disruption in the supply of such drug in the United States; </text></clause><clause id="HF177FEF7CF2744A2BD6CB030AAC18539" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a permanent discontinuance in the manufacture of an active pharmaceutical ingredient of such drug, or an interruption in the manufacture of an active pharmaceutical ingredient of such drug that is likely to lead to a meaningful disruption in the supply of the active pharmaceutical ingredient of such drug; or</text></clause><clause id="HB29C8709041244F0A29389ADC1A371C7" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other circumstance, such as an increase in demand or export restriction, that is likely to leave the manufacturer unable to meet demand for the drug without a meaningful shortfall or delay; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H531B8DD84AED49FC839D1AC05E9B743F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the reasons for such discontinuance, interruption, or other circumstance, if known.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBF0D6B27CADF43679F37D577FDDDBD8B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Notification under this subsection with respect to a covered drug shall include—</text><subparagraph id="HC27F9A0948BA404C84720232F738694F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to the reasons for the discontinuation, interruption, or other circumstance described in paragraph (1)(A)(iii), if an active pharmaceutical ingredient is a reason for, or risk factor in, such discontinuation, interruption, or other circumstance, the source of the active pharmaceutical ingredient and any alternative sources for the active pharmaceutical ingredient known to the manufacturer;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDAF137B2CBBB496282CE67E21A480CB7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>whether any associated device used for preparation or administration included in the drug is a reason for, or a risk factor in, such discontinuation, interruption, or other circumstance described in paragraph (1)(A)(iii); </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H55AAD1E4AFE747EE8D42D422BFF47546"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the expected duration of the interruption; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEE556F859A9A423097C0FC54AE590360"><enum>(D)</enum><text>such other information as the Secretary may require.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H01C75821983D429C848E4C83CEF56F13"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Timing</header><text>A notice required under subsection (a) shall be submitted to the Secretary—</text><paragraph id="H5BC6CA01FF104319B9E753C0D30A53E4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>at least 6 months prior to the date of the discontinuance or interruption; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC714F3EFA8D54823BB83AAE01E931327"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of such a notice with respect to a circumstance described in subsection (a)(1)(A)(iii), as soon as practicable, or not later than 10 business days after the onset of the circumstance; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H946C5C1B15754562BDDA7BF39E2748ED"><enum>(3)</enum><text>if compliance with paragraph (1) or (2) is not possible, as soon as practicable.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H903DDB085CC346DB85E8B9370B2CE62D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Distribution</header><text>To the maximum extent practicable, the Secretary shall distribute, through such means as the Secretary determines appropriate, information on the discontinuance or interruption of the manufacture of, or other circumstance described in subsection (a)(1)(A)(iii) that is likely to lead to a shortage or meaningful disruption in the supply of, covered drugs to appropriate organizations, including physician, health provider, and patient organizations, as described in section 506E.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="HBC031525A43341F2BD3218E5E7EC3582"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (g), in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by striking <quote>drug described in subsection (a)</quote> and inserting <quote>covered drug</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB3E547A127D24D74B5AE55F650665706"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (j), by striking <quote>drug described in subsection (a)</quote> and inserting <quote>covered drug</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H71A34195FB0B49C084E373879C66E39A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (1) of section 506C(h) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/356c">21 U.S.C. 356c(h)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H438D521AABCC4427BB86AD6301FE2AB4"><paragraph id="HDB5335E68570432A9975DCD8BECCC8A3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>covered drug</term> means a drug that is intended for human use and that—</text><subparagraph id="HC8F2563CA36C4764B65A5D1676D972D7"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is—</text><clause id="HDC025392127247A1A1CBC94347F653CA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>life-supporting; </text></clause><clause id="H4060941E5E8643BABDC18E457E6A1C8E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>life-sustaining; or </text></clause><clause id="H1E19DC0090A84C349BB84390029050D6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>intended for use in the prevention or treatment of a debilitating disease or condition, including any such drug used in emergency medical care or during surgery or any such drug that is critical to the public health during a public health emergency declared by the Secretary under section 319 of the Public Health Service Act; </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H99E75F58CCD74A55AAC0AEB99F7FE0A5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is not a radio pharmaceutical drug product or any other product as designated by the Secretary; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide4583a7b798d498ebcd8106adfd8b714"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is not a biological product (as defined in section 351(i) of the Public Health Service Act), unless otherwise provided by the Secretary in the regulations promulgated under subsection (i);</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1c5cc281c0814475a4c8a76be06e9862"><enum>3.</enum><header>Reporting on supply chains</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 510(j)(3)(A) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/360">21 U.S.C. 360(j)(3)(A)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida334f427d95949a9bcfd3cdfd3b51bce"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>annually to the Secretary</quote> in the first sentence and inserting <quote>to the Secretary, once during the month of March each year and once during the month of September each year,</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id750e0d3f7c4b41629fafd1a7e7fe629d"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting <quote>, and the legal names of, and any additional information the Secretary may require, regarding suppliers of active pharmaceutical ingredients and intermediate and in-process materials such person used for the manufacture, preparation, propagation, compounding, or processing of such drug, and the amount of such drug manufactured, prepared, propagated, compounded, or processed using each such active pharmaceutical ingredient or intermediate or in-process material sourced from each such supplier</quote> before the period at the end of the first sentence; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc49ee2f5eaab4951a20be75869d53c36"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after the first sentence the following: <quote>In addition to the reporting required under the preceding sentence, each person who registers with the Secretary under this section with regard to a drug may voluntarily report on the information described in the preceding sentence, at such other times as the Secretary may specify.</quote>.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


