<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-HLA25644-C58-LR-MD0">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 347 IS: Expressing the sense of the Senate that the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System and the Federal Open Market Committee should take immediate steps to lower interest rates to support economic growth, job creation, and affordability for American families and businesses.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>III</distribution-code>
        <congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session display="yes">1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. RES. 347</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action display="yes">
            <action-date date="20250730">July 30, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S434">Mr. Moreno</sponsor> submitted the following
                resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
        <official-title display="yes">Expressing the sense of the Senate that the Board of Governors
            of the Federal Reserve System and the Federal Open Market Committee should take
            immediate steps to lower interest rates to support economic growth, job creation, and
            affordability for American families and businesses.</official-title>
    </form>
    <preamble>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas high interest rates increase borrowing costs for American families, small businesses, and domestic industries, limiting access to affordable credit for home ownership, education, and entrepreneurial endeavors;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas elevated interest rates contribute to higher costs for goods and services, placing financial strain on households and reducing consumer spending, which is a critical driver of economic growth;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas lower interest rates can stimulate investment and economic activity, particularly in the housing, manufacturing, and technology sectors;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas commented="no">
 <text>Whereas the Federal Reserve has a dual mandate to promote maximum employment and stable prices, and current economic conditions would benefit from a monetary policy adjustment to prioritize growth;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas President Donald J. Trump has argued that the current Federal funds rate, targeted between 4.25 and 4.5 percent, is at least 3 percentage points too high, costing the United States approximately $360,000,000,000 per point annually in refinancing the costs for the national debt;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas President Trump has stated that inflation is low and companies are increasingly investing in the United States, demonstrating that high interest rates are unnecessary to control price pressures and such rates hinder economic expansion; and</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas the Senate respects the independence of the Federal Reserve but recognizes its critical role in fostering a stable and prosperous economy for all Americans: Now, therefore, be it</text>
        </whereas>
    </preamble>
    <resolution-body>
        <section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section">
 <text>That it is the sense of the Senate that the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System and the Federal Open Market Committee should immediately take such actions as may be necessary to reduce interest rates, especially the Federal funds rate.</text>
        </section>
    </resolution-body>
</resolution>

