<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-HLA25118-KG2-WD-138"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 S1235 IS: Expanding Partnerships for Innovation and Competitiveness Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1235</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250401" legis-day="20250331">April 1 (legislative day, March 31), 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S391">Mr. Young</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S408">Mr. Hickenlooper</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S357">Mrs. Fischer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To direct the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology to establish the Foundation for Standards and Metrology, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HBA0AAFB17DEE42C6BF7F9C28E7A30840"><section section-type="section-one" id="H594C84D47F42474E923E6F52A6588948"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Expanding Partnerships for Innovation and Competitiveness Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HE49EDBE15D674B8D869A2D50C1411AB6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Foundation for Standards and Metrology</header><subsection commented="no" id="H89D217EB04844043862FD03503007B25"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subtitle B of title II of the Research and Development, Competition, and Innovation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18931">42 U.S.C. 18931 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H04CB479EACA744FB93441EC44ADC0A6E"><section commented="no" id="H1086C0B822934B4BBB5D25B226F715CB"><enum>10236.</enum><header>Foundation for Standards and Metrology</header><subsection commented="no" id="H1B9781A824A44DEFB8595DB8A6A72F58"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, acting through the Director, shall establish a nonprofit corporation to be known as the <quote>Foundation for Standards and Metrology</quote> (in this section referred to as the <quote>Foundation</quote>).</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H16853DC3D6774230B8CDBDA28D01EA29"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Mission</header><text>The mission of the Foundation shall be—</text><paragraph commented="no" id="H86B6B6DF1BAE4059A22665F764968315"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to support the Institute in carrying out its activities and mission to advance measurement science, technical standards, and technology in ways that enhance the economic security and prosperity of the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H95626056A9574F73AA516CDDCB0BE8B3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to advance collaboration with researchers, institutions of higher education, industry, and nonprofit and philanthropic organizations to accelerate the development of technical standards, measurement science, and the commercialization of emerging technologies in the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HC94997C7D85E40FFAED38FAD3A5DD1B4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Activities</header><text>In carrying out its mission under subsection (b), the Foundation may conduct the following:</text><paragraph commented="no" id="HBD6A26BD97B8487A810EF2580815D0CD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Support international metrology and technical standards engagement activities.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H5CC2E1DC60F44B5CBC05A0DBF3E1028D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Support studies, projects, and research on metrology and the development of benchmarks and technical standards infrastructure across the Institute’s mission areas.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H037FE6A642C84A80A2C42D85B38FA771"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Advance collaboration between the Institute and researchers, industry, nonprofit and philanthropic organizations, institutions of higher education, federally funded research and development centers, and State, Tribal, and local governments.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HB5F72A9758BF4299901BD74AC5F0B78D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Support the expansion and improvement of research facilities and infrastructure at the Institute to advance the development of emerging technologies.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HE576F9F4E6B6438BB20C7EB3DE708D97"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Support the commercialization of federally funded research.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HB758F4FCF58F488F8AEF361F1F2FF0C0"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Conduct education and outreach activities.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H372A631E8EA54FE290DA913C4C3BEB6F"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Offer direct support to NIST associates, including through the provision of fellowships, grants, stipends, travel, health insurance, professional development training, housing, technical and administrative assistance, recognition awards for outstanding performance, and occupational safety and awareness training and support, and other appropriate expenditures.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HD8CF055ED2904FDCA08A6B97804613EF"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Any other activity as determined necessary by the Foundation to carry out its mission.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H66CE19F74B6D4276B3167BCD3719AEAD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authority of the foundation</header><text>The Foundation shall be the sole entity responsible for carrying out the activities described in subsection (c).</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H1E5B9AB78C6E4C11B70FCDC28E44B57A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Stakeholder engagement</header><text>The Foundation shall convene, and may consult with, representatives from the Institute, institutions of higher education, the private sector, non-profit organizations, and commercialization organizations to develop activities for the mission of the Foundation under subsection (b) and to advance the activities of the Foundation under subsection (c).</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H0C4D712673A64DB594204E89C7FDCD1F"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Foundation shall not be an agency or instrumentality of the Federal Government.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H67816D5D4C4C404792385709F8BE8CEB"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Support</header><text>The Foundation may receive, administer, solicit, accept, and use funds, gifts, devises, or bequests, either absolutely or in trust of real or personal property or any income therefrom or other interest therein, to support activities under subsection (c).</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HDF96ABFBC6F346C79199D0E9CB7DBA37"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Tax exempt status</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Board shall take all necessary and appropriate steps to ensure the Foundation is an organization described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and exempt from taxation under section 501(a) of such Code.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HFC755877D3DB4A569E18062FEFF9559D"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Board of Directors</header><paragraph commented="no" id="H65D0D210ABFB4C91BBBDEDAA08572752"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Foundation shall be governed by a Board of Directors (in this section referred to as the <quote>Board</quote>).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HB274E4267C434DE78AA01868DA91F561"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Composition</header><subparagraph commented="no" id="H8B465ADCC8834113B227869EDE0F24CD"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Board shall be composed of the following:</text><clause commented="no" id="H7B54712B96F0457C994D2AC833CB9AA4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Eleven appointed voting members described in subparagraph (B).</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H1DD687120A5D4B9FA8836F77933DE95D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Ex officio nonvoting members described in subparagraph (C).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H0026D3516FFE4112B304834EF32AF212"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Appointed members</header><clause commented="no" id="H70ADEB93983D4CD693E414DDE4EA8EDF"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Initial members</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Director, shall—</text><subclause commented="no" id="H6C3DBD18363B462A84421993825A8CAB"><enum>(I)</enum><text>seek to enter into an agreement with the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine to develop a list of individuals to serve as members of the Board who are well qualified and will meet the requirements of clauses (ii) and (iii); and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H5730A0CBCD8F4A698296DA7C4CEFB49A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>appoint the initial members of the Board from such list, if applicable, in consultation with the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine.</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" id="HF8C6816218734E7DBFA453B366D26794"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Representation</header><text>The appointed members of the Board shall reflect a broad cross-section of stakeholders across diverse sectors, regions and communities, including from academia, private sector entities, technical standards bodies, the investment community, the philanthropic community, and other nonprofit organizations.</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="HA8A2423A45624622946C6888ED96C1FA"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Experience</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Director, shall ensure the appointed members of the Board have the experience and are qualified to provide advice and information to advance the Foundation’s mission, including in science and technology research and development, technical standards, education, technology transfer, commercialization, or other aspects of the Foundation’s mission.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H371EF29C42B24014A6E3F894E5631B02"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Nonvoting members</header><clause commented="no" id="H3DC3E2168EC444368AA3019597EE5F29"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Ex officio members</header><text>The Director (or Director’s designee) shall be an ex officio member of the Board.</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H7C9F244733F740E4AF06860AB123FB18"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>No voting power</header><text>The Director (or Director’s designee), as an ex officio member in accordance with clause (i), shall not have voting power on the Board.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H3A423C4C48C14385ACEAB250DA0DD448"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Chair and vice chair</header><subparagraph commented="no" id="H3E1CA250607B424A828195ADBC26B5D4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Board shall designate, from among its voting members—</text><clause commented="no" id="H03C5C6E45EA24F33A7E5513865CCFD67"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an individual to serve as the chair of the Board; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H5A44C31E109A4D6A9C5A68B2EBED820C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an individual to serve as the vice chair of the Board.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H4F252679D200438D92F5413E9FB795FD"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Terms</header><text>The term of service of the Chair and Vice Chair of the Board shall end on the earlier of—</text><clause commented="no" id="H59E7466154AF487B9AE41797EC73DCF0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the date that is 3 years after the date on which the Chair or Vice Chair of the Board, as applicable, is designated for the respective position; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="HA81797C863F8418C8E0953D407F44101"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the last day of the term of service of the member, as determined under paragraph (4)(A), who is designated to be Chair or Vice Chair of the Board, as applicable.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HE4A9167A782043298F762F872344FF4E"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Representation</header><text>The Chair and Vice Chair of the Board—</text><clause commented="no" id="HE5B973925DC048D086F644C9947083C4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>may not be representatives of the same area of subject matter expertise or the same entity, as applicable; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H616F27412FA54EDABD1A386244FF97A9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>may not be representatives of any area of subject matter expertise or any entity, as applicable, represented by the immediately preceding Chair and Vice Chair of the Board.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HB374E32293944596A88688D5FC7826D4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Terms and vacancies</header><subparagraph commented="no" id="HFD4C7EF8522C4EE3A459DD17C69F769B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Term limits</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (B), the term of office of each member of the Board shall be not more than 5 years, except that a member of the Board may continue to serve after the expiration of the term of such member until the expiration of the 180-day period beginning on the date on which the term of such member expires, if no new member is appointed to replace the departing board member.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HA3A446A70E294C6E96608B955F85B51F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Initial appointed members</header><text>Of the initial members of the Board appointed under subparagraph (A), half of such members shall serve for 4.5 years, and half of such members shall serve for 5 years, as determined by the Chair of the Board.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H917F706B95E14C3AA42ABB612E4F199C"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Vacancies</header><text>Any vacancy in the membership of the appointed members of the Board—</text><clause commented="no" id="H3FB6E3471C5F43C8BE4D59FD0E2121D9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall be filled in accordance with the bylaws of the Foundation by an individual capable of representing the same area or entity, as applicable, as represented by the vacating board member under paragraph (2)(B)(ii);</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="HFE7AB4ECB2C24299AF3B9E68AF2C0C61"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>shall not affect the power of the remaining appointed members to carry out the duties of the Board; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H3E174A8385F846C7A6A1B0C74FBA0EB8"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>shall be filled by an individual selected by the Board.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H3BCB62BDAAEA4E06B1A0AC5BCEF60EBE"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Quorum</header><text>A majority of the members of the Board shall constitute a quorum for the purposes of conducting the business of the Board.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H8A163889960E47E69484C4AC743D7D29"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Board shall carry out the following:</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H0C8B5C9825BD4420A849294FA58C61BD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Establish bylaws for the Foundation in accordance with paragraph (7).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HC2181691B35246458684941F5D025F19"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Provide overall direction for the activities of the Foundation and establish priority activities.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H95E3F4E3EB3A4466ADDD8EBF50A8189C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Coordinate with the Institute the activities of the Foundation to ensure consistency with the programs and policies of the Institute.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H81734BA298134C508FC14AA90E9CDA81"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Evaluate the performance of the Executive Director of the Foundation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H9F5D974F86444B9C926195E42AEB315C"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Actively solicit and accept funds, gifts, grants, devises, or bequests of real or personal property to the Foundation, including from private entities.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H6B722B9EE8744F4FB08A7BF1D205B84C"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Carry out any other necessary activities of the Foundation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HAAAA7B6A40BA46F0BBCE900F1D173FE7"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Bylaws</header><text>The Board shall establish bylaws for the Foundation that ensure the following:</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="HFAB81CDE572C42089CD447400DA13194"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The bylaws of the Foundation include the following:</text><clause commented="no" id="HF5D2788BC1C647CB9BF970B92E185A1D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Policies for the selection of the Board members, officers, employees, agents, and contractors of the Foundation.</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H0C5BF5AC112545DB84D3589246238DF0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Policies, including ethical and disclosure standards, for the following:</text><subclause commented="no" id="HE744BE2B90314A789316CA77EA2EF360"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The acceptance, solicitation, and disposition of donations and grants to the Foundation, including appropriate limits on the ability of donors to designate, by stipulation or restriction, the use or recipient of donated funds.</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HB5B489311E2A4D24AB761506D05784C8"><enum>(II)</enum><text>The disposition of assets of the Foundation.</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" id="H1C04EEC08B564FE78DC425F26DC4FD86"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Policies that subject all employees, fellows, trainees, and other agents of the Foundation (including appointed voting members and ex officio members of the Board) to conflict of interest standards.</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H1AEF0A3F51D84C19A7A7B42C04F52667"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The specific duties of the Executive Director of the Foundation.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H7CE3705F32424ABCA681B27C0AC6C9A6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The bylaws of the Foundation and activities carried out under such bylaws do not—</text><clause commented="no" id="HD2B26FBCD0884293B852B969E84151F6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>reflect unfavorably upon the ability of the Foundation to carry out its responsibilities or official duties in a fair and objective manner; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H1CC0C11039A64FA48CC3B47A1DB4037C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>compromise, or appear to compromise, the integrity of any governmental agency or program or any officer or employee employed by or involved in a governmental agency or program.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H55CA51F597144D66ACCE225A935EC07D"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Restriction on membership</header><text>No employee of the Department of Commerce may be appointed as a voting member of the Board.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H920B60E5E2FD411F84E14E0ABFFDB0EB"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Compensation</header><subparagraph commented="no" id="H7054A2992F15426991E84B837A203500"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Members of the Board may not receive compensation for serving on the Board.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H66AD509B1A9340E293F22604BD564F4C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Certain expenses</header><text>In accordance with the bylaws of the Foundation, members of the Board may be reimbursed for travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, and other necessary expenses incurred in carrying out the duties of the Board.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HD87159512F1D479BBBB79291238FB6DE"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Liaison representatives</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Director, shall designate representatives from across the Institute to serve as the liaisons to the Board and the Foundation.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HBAC6BEF1F59448AE914411405251DC3A"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Personal liability of Board members</header><text>The members of the Board shall not be personally liable, except in the case of malfeasance.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HB61CBD87D7F140D7B81EFEAE4BC8066E"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Administration</header><paragraph commented="no" id="HB5A5B56561AC4E37A6C0BAD6194B716D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Executive Director</header><subparagraph commented="no" id="H0C7B2B5EE6214D8FB076E3B14261C4D8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Foundation shall have an Executive Director who shall be appointed by the Board, and who shall serve at the pleasure of the Board, and for whom the Board shall establish the rate of compensation. Subject to the bylaws established under subsection (i)(7), the Executive Director shall be responsible for the daily operations of the Foundation in carrying out the activities of the Foundation under subsection (c).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H52543354C688419C8F95BF4437025F07"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text>In carrying out the daily operations of the Foundation, the Executive Director of the Foundation shall carry out the following:</text><clause commented="no" id="HAEDA351E9CD04D8EB775E5CF62AFED68"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Hire, promote, compensate, and discharge officers and employees of the Foundation and define the duties of such officers and employees.</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H43380D7FD8414976A1C1D295CB9190D3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Accept and administer donations to the Foundation and administer the assets of the Foundation.</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H026B9EB898CD48A0982F4AB90F5FD472"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Enter into such contracts and execute legal instruments as are appropriate in carrying out the activities of the Foundation.</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H0374CC56C1EB4F36B81EA467B8A3C318"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Any other function necessary to operate the Foundation.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HD7B3E78D9F2641D48838E48E662FB03C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administrative control</header><text>No member of the Board, officer or employee of the Foundation or of any program established by the Foundation, or participant in a program established by the Foundation, may exercise administrative control over any Federal employee.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H617DED8CD88A4C6E83EA33F43997C0F8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Transfer of funds to Institute</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Foundation may transfer funds and property to the Institute, which the Institute may accept and use and which shall be subject to all applicable Federal limitations relating to federally funded research.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HAE5AA16524E04FC0A68D57AD428D06CD"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Strategic plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the establishment of the Foundation, the Foundation shall submit to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a strategic plan that contains the following:</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="HA62D557EBEC742CBB13B1449A95A7DB8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A plan for the Foundation to become financially self-sustaining in the next 5 years.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H97D681086EAE496A90E8C141731390C3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Short- and long-term objectives of the Foundation, as identified by the Board.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H8D0EDDF6677C43AAA6D560F10F630593"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A description of the efforts the Foundation will take to be transparent in the processes of the Foundation, including processes relating to the following:</text><clause commented="no" id="H12DD41A05718468998284997A42FD10C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Grant awards, including selection, review, and notification.</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H1C5E9314DDD5453FA6A7A16432094B7D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Communication of past, current, and future research priorities.</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="HC0FE96872447440C83461FBA73CE0341"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Solicitation of and response to public input on the priorities identified by the Foundation.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HC4637877E3BD498FBCF79F3DF376C46F"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of the financial goals and benchmarks of the Foundation for the next 10 years.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H5459056CB07B4E9188B0833ECFC8F43F"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of the efforts undertaken by the Foundation to ensure maximum complementarity and minimum redundancy with investments made by the Institute. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HFD248E656B2F4AD992327562079F7D3A"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Report</header><subparagraph commented="no" id="H19ADC041F9814EC5B62EDD93EB260EEA"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the establishment of the Foundation and not later than February 1 of each year thereafter, the Foundation shall publish a report describing the activities of the Foundation during the immediately preceding fiscal year. Each such report shall include with respect to such fiscal year a comprehensive statement of the operations, activities, financial condition, progress, and accomplishments of the Foundation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H5DAA2C5A959E45D9A1862D0E7E8E1D4A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Financial condition</header><text>With respect to the financial condition of the Foundation, each report under subparagraph (A) shall include the source, and a description of, all support under subsection (g) provided to the Foundation. Each such report shall identify the persons or entities from which such support is received and include a specification of any restrictions on the purposes for which such support may be used.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H35EC055FC73643BB93C11FEF076B0BDD"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>The Foundation shall make copies of each report submitted under subparagraph (A) available—</text><clause commented="no" id="HFFF7D979B8D34DC3B21787D2B25A6ED4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for public inspection and shall, upon request, provide a copy of the report to any individual for a charge not to exceed the cost of providing such copy; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="HE283DEBB9BF9492DB87E1178EFBB652E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H4063865F622344C4AB3285118D86BA69"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Audits and disclosure</header><text>The Foundation shall—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="HF243297A6BC940199F0FDECB5329CC20"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide for annual audits of the financial condition of the Foundation, including a full list of the Foundation’s donors and any restrictions on the purposes for which gifts to the Foundation may be used; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H59639FF2B9F144FD999F12D549BDAC1A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>make such audits, and all other records, documents, and other papers of the Foundation, available to the Secretary and the Comptroller General of the United States for examination or audit.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HAD42ABBAAEC445129CD45CF53A229B70"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Evaluation by Comptroller General</header><text>Not later than 5 years after the date on which the Foundation is established, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate the following:</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="HB403D4E487B241B698DC54A71DB801D2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An evaluation of the following:</text><clause commented="no" id="H722747E1C4AB40BCBBF90A099F8303E2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The extent to which the Foundation is achieving the mission of the Foundation.</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H13AD6BDA702D4CF3A509F15432DCC4DC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The operation of the Foundation.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H4211DE02CF444EA98CCD9AF8042ED86B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Any recommendations on how the Foundation may be improved.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H197E30208AD64AD288FA226EDD1BA165"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Integrity</header><paragraph commented="no" id="HDA04E1B3C9F14D05A77A44D0092BF2F7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To ensure integrity in the operations of the Foundation, the Board shall develop and enforce procedures relating to standards of conduct, financial disclosure statements, conflicts of interest (including recusal and waiver rules), audits, and any other matters determined appropriate by the Board.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H56CF0276AF304D4CA596C6E1D38624A6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Financial conflicts of interest</header><text>To mitigate conflicts of interest and risks from malign foreign influence, any individual who is an officer, employee, or member of the Board is prohibited from any participation in deliberations by the Foundation of a matter that would directly or predictably affect any financial interest of any of the following:</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="HDE73DAE80A2544BEA43D1C3E2A8769CD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Such individual.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H8D51C26757364DD5BB6FBB8A34485C06"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A relative of such individual.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HE536152C5BF04817A5254359537FFFA3"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A business organization or other entity in which such individual or relative of such individual has an interest, including an organization or other entity with which such individual is negotiating employment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H43CAF9B4B6E64D7284ECECD221707510"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Intellectual property</header><text>The Board shall adopt written standards to govern the ownership and licensing of any intellectual property rights developed by the Foundation or derived from the collaborative efforts of the Foundation.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H4F44552667824EC58C386A6F36A21B8B"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Full faith and credit</header><text>The United States shall not be liable for any debts, defaults, acts, or omissions of the Foundation. The full faith and credit of the United States shall not extend to any obligations of the Foundation.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H4DB0F92B24D5410A942CE8E262F39859"><enum>(n)</enum><header>Support services</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Director, may provide facilities, utilities, and support services to the Foundation if it is determined by the Director to be advantageous to the mission of the Institute.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H0E4515EC5C3E4763804D6ABF97AEAB8D"><enum>(o)</enum><header>Nonapplicability</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/10">Chapter 10</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, shall not apply to the Foundation.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H31016DCE57BD40B7A822407A4526DA8C"><enum>(p)</enum><header>Separate fund accounts</header><text>The Board shall ensure that amounts received pursuant to the authorization of appropriations under subsection (q) are held in a separate account from any other amounts received by the Foundation.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HC21049DF53374468A43FEC5DF22EE343"><enum>(q)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, from amounts authorized to be appropriated for a fiscal year beginning with fiscal year 2026 to the Secretary of Commerce pursuant to section 10211, the Director may transfer not less than $500,000 and not more than $1,250,000 to the Foundation each such fiscal year.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H0EF764638B3647D59D954B366250A919"><enum>(r)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph commented="no" id="HBDCB364F43614A7885FA193F7509FCAF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text>The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given such term in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H803443473AFD465C96BBA2C54CAA8DCA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>NIST associate</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>NIST associate</term> means any guest researcher, facility user, volunteer, or other nonemployee of the Institute who conducts research or otherwise engages in an authorized activity with personnel of the Institute or at a facility of the Institute.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HA0C2100D138148EAB00E2244A05BFA1D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Relative</header><text>The term <quote>relative</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 13101 of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H78FDA0DFF9A04A24974BA334D96AA53A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Technical standard</header><text>The term <term>technical standard</term> has the meaning given such term in section 12(d)(5) of the National Technology Transfer and Advancement Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/272">15 U.S.C. 272</external-xref> note).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H15AAB260999D493B8D1E9F0FC7CCC53E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents in sections 1 and 10000 of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/167">Public Law 117–167</external-xref> (136 Stat. 1366) are amended by inserting after the item relating to section 10235 the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4298CA858F5E4DECB714815722D565FC"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 10236. Foundation for Standards and Metrology.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

