<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="H20D6687FC82A48D7A269C2CD858CB130" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Engrossed-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 40 EH: Electing Members to certain standing committees of the House of Representatives.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">IV</distribution-code> 
<congress display="no">119th CONGRESS</congress> 
<session display="no">1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. RES. 40</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="yes">In the House of Representatives, U. S.,</current-chamber>
<action>
<action-date date="20250114">January 14, 2025</action-date>
</action> 
<legis-type display="yes">RESOLUTION</legis-type> 
<official-title display="no">Electing Members to certain standing committees of the House of Representatives.</official-title> 
</form> 
<resolution-body style="traditional" id="H641C7576364142AEAC55B8AB6447EAEB"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H2F91DDF5E8C5471CB0E33809D22F188E"><text>That the following named Members be, and are hereby, elected to the following standing committees of the House of Representatives:</text> <paragraph id="HBA92DF5827BD4A909AFB1FF8B0CDF11C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Committee on Armed Services</header><text>Mr. Courtney, Mr. Garamendi, Mr. Norcross, Mr. Moulton, Mr. Carbajal, Mr. Khanna, Mr. Keating, Ms. Houlahan, Mr. Crow, Ms. Sherrill, Mr. Golden of Maine, Ms. Jacobs, Ms. Strickland, Mr. Ryan, Mr. Vasquez, Mr. Deluzio, Ms. Tokuda, Mr. Davis of North Carolina, Mr. Cisneros, Mr. Sorensen, Ms. Goodlander, Ms. Elfreth, Mr. Whitesides, Mr. Tran, Mr. Vindman, Mr. Bell.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H96B82D713776418EBA5FC2EB31FE76CC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Committee on Education and Workforce</header><text>Mr. Grijalva, Mr. Courtney, Ms. Wilson of Florida, Ms. Bonamici, Mr. Takano, Ms. Adams, Mr. DeSaulnier, Mr. Norcross, Mrs. McBath, Mrs. Hayes, Ms. Omar, Ms. Stevens, Mr. Casar, Ms. Lee of Pennsylvania, Mr. Mannion.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H75515B419D954FF5BE01041A11C682DF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Committee on Energy and Commerce</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Mr. Menendez, to rank immediately after Mr. Carter of Louisiana.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1B136D4887CC484FB421923BAEE2935C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Committee on Homeland Security</header><text>Mr. Swalwell, Mr. Correa, Mr. Thanedar, Mr. Magaziner, Mr. Goldman of New York, Mrs. Ramirez, Mr. Kennedy of New York, Mrs. McIver, Ms. Johnson of Texas, Mr. Hernández, Ms. Pou, Mr. Turner of Texas.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEBC6FE6372914ED792A21D5DF0B65013"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Committee on the Judiciary</header><text>Mr. Nadler, Ms. Lofgren, Mr. Cohen, Mr. Johnson of Georgia, Mr. Swalwell, Mr. Lieu, Ms. Jayapal, Mr. Correa, Ms. Scanlon, Mr. Neguse, Mrs. McBath, Ms. Ross, Ms. Balint, Mr. García of Illinois, Ms. Kamlager-Dove, Mr. Moskowitz, Mr. Goldman of New York, Ms. Crockett.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBBED5912BBF44AA085B99459AAAA200C"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</header><text>Ms. Norton, Mr. Lynch, Mr. Krishnamoorthi, Mr. Khanna, Mr. Mfume, Ms. Brown, Ms. Stansbury, Mr. Garcia of California, Mr. Frost, Ms. Lee of Pennsylvania, Mr. Casar, Ms. Crockett, Ms. Randall, Mr. Subramanyam, Ms. Ansari, Mr. Bell, Ms. Simon, Mr. Min.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H529B69E3270C479D8752C272D73135B4"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Committee on Rules</header><text>Mr. McGovern, Ms. Scanlon, Mr. Neguse, Ms. Leger Fernandez. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H29B03DB4D4724A1EB3EC2B52D55B62BC"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Committee on Small Business</header><text>Mr. McGarvey, Ms. Scholten, Mrs. McIver, Mr. Cisneros, Ms. Morrison, Mr. Latimer, Mr. Tran, Ms. Simon, Mr. Olszewski, Mr. Conaway, Ms. Goodlander.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H07C8DE36A17949929AD9112DECA50360"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</header><text>Ms. Norton, Mr. Nadler, Mr. Cohen, Mr. Garamendi, Mr. Johnson of Georgia, Mr. Carson, Ms. Titus, Mr. Huffman, Ms. Brownley, Ms. Wilson of Florida, Mr. DeSaulnier, Mr. Carbajal, Mr. Stanton, Ms. Davids of Kansas, Mr. García of Illinois, Mr. Pappas, Mr. Moulton, Ms. Strickland, Mr. Ryan, Ms. Hoyle of Oregon, Mrs. Sykes, Ms. Scholten, Mrs. Foushee, Mr. Deluzio, Mr. Garcia of California, Ms. Pou, Ms. McDonald Rivet, Ms. Friedman, Ms. Gillen, Mr. Figures.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H120AF403CA9D4CBA8583544B7473604A"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Committee on Veterans Affairs</header><text>Ms. Brownley, Mr. Pappas, Mrs. Cherfilus-McCormick, Mr. McGarvey, Mrs. Ramirez, Ms. Budzinski, Mr. Kennedy of New York, Ms. Dexter, Mr. Conaway, Ms. Morrison.</text></paragraph> </section> </resolution-body> <attestation><attestation-group><attestor display="no">Kevin F. McCumber,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation> </resolution> 

