<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HFCC474E5D59B4D3DB6D9C3AD45A57285" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1051 IH: To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to allow for the approval of an abbreviated new drug application submitted by a subsequent applicant in the case of a failure by a first applicant to commence commercial marketing within a certain period, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1051</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250206">February 6, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001315">Ms. Budzinski</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to allow for the approval of an abbreviated new drug application submitted by a subsequent applicant in the case of a failure by a first applicant to commence commercial marketing within a certain period, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H5F88CE7C08E94D8EBCDD0745E5A4EF07" style="OLC"><section id="H5EC655E9ACA1480C850687FC44FF5224" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>180-day exclusivity period</header><subsection id="H35D81784282B4602AE1ADC88A990C4F5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 505(j)(5)(B)(iv) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/355">21 U.S.C. 355(j)(5)(B)(iv)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H826462FB051A46EEA890D093C6A26AB8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subclause (I)—</text><subparagraph id="H5720593CAB664A17B151292B9B800512"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>and subclause (III)</quote> after <quote>subparagraph (D)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H21DE2576147C4C16A10146C44EE22128"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting before the period at the end the following: <quote>or an applicant whose application was approved pursuant to subclause (III). If an applicant described in subclause (III) is eligible for effective approval on the same day a tentatively approved first applicant who has requested final approval is determined by the Secretary to be eligible for effective approval by meeting all the approval requirements of this subsection, such applicant may not receive effective approval until 180 days after the first applicant begins commercial marketing of the drug</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC68150B1F8174FE29336F435AD28CEFB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subclause:</text><quoted-block id="H7C9AE84F84E54C6EADC9C282B9DD60E9" style="OLC"><subclause id="HC4ED578F028A4E6DADDD56A228AE21C0" indent="up2"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Applicant approval</header><text>The Secretary may approve an application containing a certification described in paragraph (2)(A)(vii)(IV) that is for a drug for which a first applicant has submitted an application containing such a certification, notwithstanding the eligibility of a first applicant for the 180-day exclusivity period described in subclause (II)(aa), if each of the following conditions is met:</text><item id="H8382F6695CAD4D19921B62445D503F1B"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>The approval of such application could be made effective, but for the eligibility of a first applicant for 180-day exclusivity under this clause.</text></item><item id="H63CE93ADA6DD4A05BCC471D2229E4439"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>The applicant of such application has submitted a certification to the abbreviated new drug application that there are no conditions that would prevent the applicant from commercial marketing within 75 days after the date of approval and that the applicant intends to so market the drug.</text></item><item id="HF47C173EACEB4818A2C0DB474D88EEB9"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>At least 33 months have passed since the date of submission of an application for the drug by at least one first applicant.</text></item><item id="HC6F2EA3014244A15AE02A893A2017AD7"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>Approval of an application for the drug submitted by at least one first applicant is not precluded under clause (iii).</text></item><item id="HC4F4A5F0557D4C05803CDB7FCEB7F455"><enum>(ee)</enum><text>No application for the drug submitted by any first applicant is effectively approved on the date that the conditions under items (aa), (bb), (cc), and (dd) are all met and maintained.</text></item></subclause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H53187F6998A34AC29196639163B68C06"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Special forfeiture rule for certain subsequent applicants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 505(j)(5)(D) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (21 U.S.C. 355 (j)(5)(D)) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H42FFECD921674C3888A552FF6156CB64" display-inline="no-display-inline"><clause id="H8E42D9F090D04DB3A1321861003A6B4A"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Special forfeiture rule for certain subsequent applicants</header><subclause id="H0CDC825FA4F84CEA846F4A3406C63996"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as specified in subclause (II), an application that is approved pursuant to subclause (III) of subparagraph (B)(iv) is deemed to be tentatively approved and to no longer have an effective approval pursuant to such subclause (III) beginning on the day after the end of the 75-day period specified in item (bb) of such subclause (III) if the applicant fails to commence commercial marketing as required under such item.</text></subclause><subclause id="H13B4871A39914C82A72DB1DE41569EAC"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Opportunity to cure</header><item id="HE93972C112C848228D3B77D52B278177"><enum>(aa)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the applicant of an application approved pursuant to subclause (III) of subparagraph (B)(iv) submits, pursuant to item (bb) of such subclause, a notification that it can no longer commence commercial marketing within the 75-day period specified in such item, such application is deemed to be tentatively approved and to no longer be effectively approved beginning on the date that such a notification is received.</text></item><item id="H5204517C1ABC4D378B74DF55F941FD44"><enum>(bb)</enum><header>Ineligibility for subsequent effective approval</header><text>If an applicant described in item (aa) does not commence commercial marketing within such 75-day period, the applicant shall not be eligible for a subsequent effective approval for the application involved under subclause (III) of subparagraph (B)(iv) unless, in addition to meeting each of the conditions in such subclause (III), the applicant submits a certification to its abbreviated new drug application that—</text><subitem id="HE9CA90F10FAA426DBEF455806323E865"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>an event that could not have been reasonably foreseen by the applicant prevented it from commencing commercial marketing; and</text></subitem><subitem id="H591F40C0C51949999B8937C3643811A1"><enum>(BB)</enum><text><italic></italic>it has fully resolved any issues preventing such commercial marketing from commencing as a result of such event.</text></subitem></item><item id="H96333E51C31B48B0AA256470300867AA"><enum>(cc)</enum><header>Timing for submission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An applicant described in item (aa) shall, not later than one business day after commencing marketing of the drug that is the subject of the application described in such item, submit a notification to the abbreviated new drug application confirming that such applicant has commenced commercial marketing of the drug.</text></item></subclause></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H035DB62E3BF845B899043760124705B5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>The amendments made by subsections (a) and (b) shall apply only with respect to an application filed under section 505(j) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/355">21 U.S.C. 355(j)</external-xref>) after the date of enactment of this Act that identifies a listed drug for which no certification under paragraph (2)(A)(vii)(IV) of such section was made before such date of enactment.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

