<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" slc-id="S1-RIL25587-8G9-4L-V9V"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 270 ATS: Designating June 6, 2025, as National Naloxone Awareness Day.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 270</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250610">June 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S404">Mr. Scott of Florida</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S437">Mr. Justice</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S275">Ms. Cantwell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S439">Mrs. Moody</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S316">Mr. Whitehouse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S378">Mr. Lankford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S266">Mr. Crapo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S363">Mr. King</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S323">Mr. Risch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S415">Mr. Warnock</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S372">Mrs. Capito</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S385">Ms. Cortez Masto</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S359">Mr. Heinrich</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S402">Ms. Rosen</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Designating June 6, 2025, as National Naloxone Awareness Day.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the opioid epidemic continues to devastate communities across the United States, leading to a significant loss of life and widespread societal impact;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas opioid overdoses during the 12 months preceding December of 2024 claimed a reported 54,101 lives in the United States; </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas fatal overdoses are often witnessed by a bystander;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2024 alone, the Drug Enforcement Administration seized more than 380,000,000 doses of potentially deadly fentanyl, enough to kill every individual in the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to data from the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, fentanyl-related poisonings are a leading cause of death for individuals in the United States between 18 and 44 years of age;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas naloxone is a safe and effective medication that can reverse opioid overdoses and save lives when administered promptly by rapidly reversing the effects of opioids;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas naloxone plays a vital role in preventing long-term brain damage and reducing the risk of fatality associated with opioid overdoses;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention has declared naloxone to be a key tool in preventing opioid overdose deaths;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas it is imperative to educate individuals, families, healthcare professionals, and first responders about—</text><paragraph id="ida9a3579568c6465ab8c5fd2394618113"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the benefits of naloxone, including the potential naloxone has to reduce opioid-related fatalities; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4706fc06a18e43bcb213a10bd43c018d"><enum>(2)</enum><text>how to safely administer naloxone;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas it is imperative to identify current or potential barriers, including cost, for individuals, organizations, and Federal, State, and local governments to obtain and distribute naloxone;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas increasing access to naloxone can ensure that individuals struggling with opioid use disorder have a chance at recovery and a future free from the grip of opioid use disorder;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Food and Drug Administration acted to authorize the over-the-counter sale of 4 milligram and 3 milligram doses of naloxone in 2023; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas recognizing National Naloxone Awareness Day will contribute to the ongoing efforts to educate the public, reduce the stigma associated with substance use disorder, and promote access to lifesaving naloxone: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="S1"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph commented="no" id="id10157a26fa1e4c2180e848a58ec8f4a4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>designates June 6, 2025, as National Naloxone Awareness Day;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id988a8dfa91e945b49119488c33d34a6e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the life-saving benefits of naloxone in reversing opioid overdoses and preventing unnecessary deaths;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idcc29a595f0ab41b5845de0aa2d2d1831"><enum>(3)</enum><text>acknowledges that increased access to naloxone empowers individuals, families, healthcare professionals, and first responders to intervene in emergency situations and provide immediate assistance to those experiencing an opioid overdose;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idb8660c9264d14bc193f7915dc2fc72a6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>recognizes that National Naloxone Awareness Day serves as an opportunity to educate the public about the importance of recognizing the signs of opioid overdose and equipping themselves with naloxone to save lives;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id214890027b36457199446075b5503245"><enum>(5)</enum><text>encourages Federal, State, and local governments, as well as private and nonprofit organizations, to collaborate and allocate resources towards increasing naloxone access, education, and distribution efforts; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id88cfcbae96b143d59f72e86fbd7d269e"><enum>(6)</enum><text>calls upon Federal agencies, including the Substances Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration, the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, the Office of National Drug Control Policy, the Drug Enforcement Administration, and all others engaged in the National Drug Control Strategy to continue supporting public awareness of naloxone, harm reduction, and overdose and poisoning prevention. </text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

