<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2198C6B60663452A9A69C83754B85050" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5520 IH: Portal for Appraisal Licensing Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5520</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250919">September 19, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000583">Mr. Loudermilk</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001204">Mr. Meuser</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000471">Mr. Fitzgerald</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000590">Ms. Lee of Nevada</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000191">Mr. Neguse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000620">Ms. Pettersen</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000392">Mr. Kustoff</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Financial Institutions Reform, Recovery, and Enforcement Act of 1989 to establish a Portal for Appraiser Credentialing and AMC Registration Information, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HBB9625F4AF4F457A80D9151C9C8FB83B" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H14F6D73378334BFB9A19691FE147C243" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Portal for Appraisal Licensing Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H085D814BEF9345A0959B53AE53618B76"><enum>2.</enum><header>Portal for Appraiser Credentialing and AMC Registration Information</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1103 of the Financial Institutions Reform, Recovery, and Enforcement Act of 1989 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/3332">12 U.S.C. 3332</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="H37E7AA1816AE4F7CA575E8506C853E0D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text> <subparagraph id="H24AA2EC784664B49820B492B0E482EED"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H280308628CF544BC9C45A145BBD2B229"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by striking the period on the end and inserting a semicolon;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5BEF98FEFFFD43979224C62FB8059476"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (5)—</text>
<clause id="HBBA097024E074E6CB6AD9AC5CC5B8AE9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>. The report</quote> and inserting <quote>, and which</quote>; and</text></clause> <clause id="HD2E43D8BD91C4E7FAA85D888EE5EA2DB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking the period on the end and inserting a semicolon;</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H32E25BB72816409E982828CC88898F01"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (6), by striking the period on the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3FEDBE2A9A8F423CAFFEFC6CADFAD9BF"><enum>(E)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HC27DAE884E0C40AF99A267401DD88FF6" display-inline="no-display-inline">
<paragraph id="HBA0EBA4EECAD4A909F42312F6603B34B"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish and maintain the Portal for Appraiser Credentialing and AMC Registration Information described under subsection (c).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6984EA3868464A7A81A3B83431392EB8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HD6AC95B2F18E4A8B95A58CA0A0F35730" display-inline="no-display-inline">
<subsection id="HEDEAF341EDA2417B869A67422357645A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Portal for Appraiser Credentialing and AMC Registration Information</header>
<paragraph id="H9BCFDB7F88BC4CABA2D69DF496AA5A3E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Appraisal Subcommittee shall establish and maintain a cloud-based system to be called the <quote>Portal for Appraiser Credentialing and AMC Registration Information</quote> (the <quote>Portal</quote>), which—</text> <subparagraph id="HE3AA0230353E4ED39D352E74037FBDF1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall provide appraisers and appraisal management companies a central depository for license, certification, and registration applications and renewals;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H5858B7291D524A5AA007345A91B4C924"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall provide connectivity with State appraiser certifying and licensing agencies for their access to all application and renewal information, including completed qualifying and continuing education, experience logs, examination results, background check information, where applicable, and any other information the Appraisal Subcommittee determines appropriate (after consideration of any advice from the advisory committee established under paragraph (6));</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8A33A2B1B8D545DE9E5C294BDA760BC1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall make available payment of all license, certification, and registration fees and delivery of letters of good standing to State appraiser certifying and licensing agencies; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H37AEF8DC5D13411BBFCC7285C3DBB58B"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may utilize an existing platform, if available.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H64B552FFC0834340B26B905469E4163D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Background checks</header> <subparagraph id="H2A5C1EA9AFC343FAA94FE503DE2810D3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Access to records</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not­with­stand­ing any other provision of law, in providing appraisal functions, the Attorney General shall provide access to all criminal history information to the appropriate State officials responsible for regulating State-licensed and State-certified appraisers or appraisal management companies to the extent criminal history background checks are required under the laws of the State for the licensing or certification of such appraisers and registering appraisal management companies.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HF9726998E6774BB587DCD4D15CF7D8EB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Agent</header><text>For the purposes of this paragraph and in order to reduce the points of contact which the Federal Bureau of Investigation may have to maintain for purposes of subparagraph (A), the Appraisal Subcommittee may be used as a channeling agent of the States for requesting and distributing information between the Department of Justice and the appropriate State agencies.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAE31B8B2EDB340BF96B1CA012EE3EF18"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Other persons requiring a background check</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To the extent FBI criminal history background checks are required under the laws of a State, appraisers and any other person that may require such a background check shall submit fingerprints to the Portal and authorize the Appraisal Subcommittee to process a criminal background check with the Federal Bureau of Investigation.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H5B0CF8F6B77A44A586713065F8917B25"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Treatment of background checks</header><text>Background checks completed under this paragraph shall satisfy any third-party oversight requirements imposed by Federal financial institutions regulatory agencies.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H65E5C3C5C26840048F12D06320F881F0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Additional content information</header> <subparagraph id="H37E8C1C077BF40398518765FAC7820A2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Education courses</header><text>For purposes of the education information maintained by the Portal—</text>
<clause id="H6E6ADEECD1034EC0A901D22854263628"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a State appraiser certifying and licensing agency may notify the Portal of which particular courses have been approved by the agency; and</text></clause> <clause id="H6383CA8456254823B2156A814771E5DA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">both education providers and State appraiser certifying and licensing agencies of States may submit to the Portal lists of individuals who have completed such courses.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H848CB7D1EEBB42C2845F022A45E75ECD"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Unique identifiers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Appraisal Subcommittee shall use a unique identifier to identify each individual who submits an application through the Portal or otherwise makes use of the Portal. The Appraisal Subcommittee may also use a unique identifier to identify each appraisal management company that submits an application through the Portal or otherwise makes use of the Portal.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBB78A072AC4B4DB0BBE644C73CA0F06D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>No effect on States’ rights</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">States shall retain the ability to act independently upon license, certification, and registration applications and renewals for appraisers and appraisal management companies.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8BC53B459C3649A48B93DAB38AC89E5A"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Treatment of fees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">State cre­den­tial­ing fees and any State-specific information shall continue to be provided to States by appraisers and appraisal management companies, but transmitted through the Portal via a streamlined process and application.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6DB68ACB22EB4F9EADBF1C2C376515B4"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Advisory committee</header> <subparagraph id="HA947C67D78D84EF0B6B61453BD1F6859"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Appraisal Subcommittee shall establish an advisory committee to advise the Appraisal Subcommittee on the establishment of the Portal.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H39F5F1B3055A4BA3B12B757497E3367B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Membership</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The advisory committee shall consist of representatives of industry associations, appraisers, lenders, appraisal management companies, and State appraiser certifying and licensing agencies, to be determined by the Appraisal Subcommittee.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3F930228531045148C367A62B4311905"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Funding</header> <subparagraph id="HF3CCF32C5EC74930B1B080C95D4FA0DF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>User fees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the sole purpose of paying for the cost of establishing and maintaining the Portal and carrying out the background checks required under paragraph (2)(A), the Appraisal Subcommittee may charge a reasonable fee to individuals and appraisal management companies making use of the Portal. The fee shall be revenue neutral to the costs of developing and maintaining the Portal.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H7A18F3BC7CB64C1EA936E586657C34C8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>State grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Appraisal Subcommittee shall make grants available to State appraiser certifying and licensing agencies, in accordance with policies to be developed by the Appraisal Subcommittee, to support the efforts of such agencies to connect State systems with the Portal.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

