<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H40388AE991F741B1862C440543AD93AE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1656 IH: Preserving Lawful Utilization of Services for Veterans Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1656</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250227">February 27, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001301">Mr. Bergman</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001110">Mr. Correa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001215">Mrs. Miller-Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000603">Mr. Rouzer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000806">Mr. Webster of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001240">Mr. McDowell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001101">Mr. Harrigan</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="A000379">Mr. Alford</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to permit certain fee agreements between claimants and agents or attorneys for the preparations, presentation, or prosecution of initial claims for benefits under the laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H538574726E784167B16186925FF95961" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H0CAF82EA257A4850A9D6426F05130F62"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Preserving Lawful Utilization of Services for Veterans Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>PLUS for Veterans Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H1A61720192EA4134A686A91758DE5BFF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Clarification of preparation, presentation, or prosecution of a claim under a law administered by Secretary of Veterans Affairs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 5901 of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="H81D4AC1C722B4A5A8AC17839DE46E178" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="H5854E4005FB0412A8F38699D8F9D9C87"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exclusion</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The administration of a medical examination, or the completion of a report with respect to such medical examination, as described in section 5125 of this title, shall not constitute the preparation, presentation, or prosecution of a claim under the laws administered by the Secretary.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section id="H35238577BBB7470BB20AF8B8C6FC3E98"><enum>3.</enum><header>Agents and attorneys in certain claims under laws administered by Secretary of Veterans Affairs: applications for recognition; fees allowable for representation; grounds for suspension; bars from recognition</header> <subsection id="HD09E0EB9458245A5BF94266393975A1C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 5904 of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H848BF4047D4F444EAC963EC0E38161EA" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (a)—</text> <subparagraph id="HC3EB1FA7301B4CF2BC377E2075F988D8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text> 
<clause id="H72AFECD709EF4438A27D8D1FA9F15438"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subparagraph" style="USC"><enum-in-header>(A)</enum-in-header></header-in-text></quote> before <quote>Except</quote>; and</text></clause> <clause id="HD6124D34C3C54E208D9906DA0C24BCAC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraphs:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4A2EC30002A2489FA2AC6C3537F69E62"> 
<subparagraph id="H07C1291A19B4458C93DD8688B449E3DE" indent="up2"><enum>(B)</enum> 
<clause id="H32E308855FBD4ECA8F63AD7BDAA1F53D" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(i)</enum><text>An individual desiring recognition under this section shall submit to the Secretary an application, including an application submitted by mail, fax, or electronic means, in such form, at such time, and containing such information and assurances as the Secretary has determined appropriate to recognize such individual under this section.</text></clause> <clause id="HB46AD075DE1A41EBBBBF0657D466AE11" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>If the Secretary cannot verify whether the individual satisfies the qualifications and standards prescribed under paragraph (2) before the 90-day period beginning after the date on which the Secretary receives an application under clause (i), the Secretary shall recognize the individual on a conditional and temporary basis for a one-year period.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H3F015B2EE7844D9E8CD40CAFC9EBF578" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At the end of such one-year period, the Secretary shall recognize the individual on a conditional and temporary basis for such additional one-year periods until the date on which the Secretary can verify whether the individual satisfies such qualifications and standards.</text></clause> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDFACA8E55E3C4CDFB62A26B5E4F67C73" indent="up2"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may not suspend, exclude from further practice before the Department, fine pursuant to section 5905 of this title, or refuse to recognize as an agent or attorney under this section any individual on the basis that such individual, before the date of the enactment of this subparagraph—</text> 
<clause id="HECF4B1DFC8C54635AD66283C461EDA57"><enum>(i)</enum><text>charged a claimant a fee for services rendered in the preparation, presentation, or prosecution of an initial claim; or</text></clause> <clause id="H9C9CAF43064D4F388CC7E2B607DCDDC0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>charged a claimant a fee for such services while such individual was not recognized under this section.</text></clause> </subparagraph> <after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H264F19A9503F46078091DE365AB17C2E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="HF3E0BF8B52284359B1C1A65720B8E9D7" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="HB670934F6B6E4D9DB3D2F78BC8F46E3D" indent="up1"><enum>(7)</enum> <subparagraph id="H8349586FE0624862953FEE92DD263BD8" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Secretary may charge and collect an assessment from an individual who—</text> 
<clause id="H54114396B08B40D78A670F1DC46C97ED" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">seeks recognition under this section as an agent or attorney for the preparation, presentation, and prosecution of an initial claim under the laws administered by the Secretary; and</text></clause> <clause id="H1F50C53D69C0409AA75BA9B0AA49C319" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>charges or collects fees from a claimant for services rendered in such preparation, presentation, and prosecution.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4B0ED9A2F3DA492982353D4F747F6370" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment described in subparagraph (A)—</text> <clause id="H8A544DA057894C1484992D72F1942F79"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall be in such amount as the Secretary prescribes in regulations and determines appropriate; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HEE07E19F129F4AD0AC1DEAE3BF779222"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>may not exceed $500.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7109C9DF2FEF471D8AF5D1EF8702F152" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Amounts collected under this paragraph shall be deposited in a revolving fund in the Treasury of the United States. Such amounts shall be available to the Secretary for the administration of this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB799A659057E4B5A80F2C8A00EBCD180"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text> <subparagraph id="H9488D84BC86E4D9B83533B7C55BF8CFF" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (1) through (9) as subparagraphs (A) through (I), respectively;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB939C0E9ACEF429EB1263120DE91CDE0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), as so redesignated, by inserting <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="USC"><enum-in-header>(1)</enum-in-header></header-in-text></quote> before <quote>The Secretary</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3E7F7AE51A8C423A9C3A62C22B5F87F8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), as designated by paragraph (2)—</text> 
<clause id="H3A2ED5527FF944FE9B37867CF8A0A0E1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (H), as so redesignated, by striking <quote>in accordance with subsection (c)(3)(A) ; or</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (c)(2)(A)</quote>;</text></clause> <clause id="H2DF589FAC3D14AB897475C9A59600F6F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (I), as so redesignated, by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HADF096BD579A491FB707EBD3542F9583"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="H1FD55B4C0A7F42CAA762A9A89A8A0479" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subparagraph id="HE52F7CC7CE3841B886503BF0FE73A8CD" commented="no"><enum>(J)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has failed to keep claimant data and personally identifiable information in accordance with applicable provisions of the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/191">Public Law 104–191</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1301">42 U.S.C. 1301 et seq.</external-xref>), including the data security requirements and implementing regulations of such Act.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H17780F6320C848DDABFA1A4022C911D3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="H95DEE7B6F9FE40988CBE8568BBD71BB0" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="HDB7FBD176E144EEB95DFFCA5522D21FB" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Preserving Lawful Utilization of Services for Veterans Act of 2025</short-title> and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and House of Representatives a report regarding the number of individuals suspended under this subsection or denied recognition under subsection (a), disaggregated by the reasons for such suspension or denial and whether the individual is—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H6D670F2E5CB24F429BB60A6A53A40C2F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a representative of an organization recognized under section 5902 of this title;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCDFBAE015AA043F48455F583EBC48F31"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an agent; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC662B9823B0F40439ABA8469CF2E3634"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an attorney.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8008F091442E412B91AB1CB503766210"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HCF7CAB7974414834970ECFC339827ADC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="USC">Flat fee agreements.—</header-in-text></quote> after <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="USC"><enum-in-header>(c)</enum-in-header></header-in-text></quote>;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H02A8CDD21A684AEF95ED20C64EAE1834"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (1) and inserting the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE48FB308D180454297FC6FFF2D89F577"> 
<paragraph id="HD8D76EAE8281420EB74D06D4CC2D33B7" indent="up1"><enum>(1)</enum> 
<subparagraph id="H80B2994065AB4E9F9B4F3743886A97E8" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In connection with a proceeding before the Department with respect to benefits under laws administered by the Secretary, a fee agreement between a claimant and an agent or attorney for the preparation, presentation, or prosecution of an initial claim for such benefits shall be a fee agreement described in subparagraph (B).</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE1591A5CEA6142E5BBD49FAC48FFB88F" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum> <clause id="HC89B3E4F93BC4A95A8197556499442FD" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(i)</enum><text>A fee agreement described in this subparagraph is a fee agreement—</text> 
<subclause id="H9F7AB25FB81E45D1B4D7DDEA1BDAF5CB" indent="up1"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that does not require payment from a claimant to the agent or attorney before the date on which the claimant is provided notice of the agency of original jurisdiction's initial decision under section 5104 of this title with respect to the initial claim; </text></subclause> <subclause id="H730AC18B6B4C4652B28787F08A452D34" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">under which the total amount payable by the claimant to the agent or attorney with respect to the initial claim—</text> 
<item id="HB8C1C83D5DA9448A8A6957B210F4EE77"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is contingent on whether the initial claim is resolved in a manner favorable to the claimant;</text></item> <item id="HA48C9FE088AE4B3CBF8B8C747A2CC46C"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>does not exceed the lesser of—</text> 
<subitem id="HF8225DB91D7641AC8267894CDD664634"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>$12,500 (as adjusted from time to time under subparagraph (C)); or</text></subitem> <subitem id="H906B95E788EA47C4B04086E324CE9927"><enum>(BB)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the amount equal to the product of five and the amount of the monthly increase of benefits awarded to the claimant pursuant to the claim; and</text></subitem></item> </subclause> 
<subclause id="HD16E2F1AA4F2421D808F829EA76D2031" indent="up1"><enum>(III)</enum><text>that contains an attestation by the claimant that the agent or attorney provided to the claimant the standard form under clause (iii).</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H8FCB1A35DF4447CEA9B64A30E1CC94E7" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>For purposes of this subparagraph, an initial claim shall be considered to have been resolved in a manner favorable to the claimant if all or any part of the relief sought pursuant to the claim is granted.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA22365FC5AB840CCBF431DA9FA112235" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>For use in fee agreements described in this subparagraph, the Secretary shall develop a standard form that includes the following notices:</text> <subclause id="H6579BE9F03684BBFA96348631565C376"><enum>(I)</enum><text>That organizations recognized under section 5902 of this title furnish services with respect to initial claims under laws administered by the Secretary at no cost to claimants.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H7C371CAF37964C9386E8647CAC4F2CE1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>That a claimant may select a private physician for a medical examination described in section 5125 of this title regarding the initial claim.</text></subclause> <subclause id="H59DD5B3696904393BE58303A173F77C0"><enum>(III)</enum><text>That the agent or attorney with whom the claimant is entering such fee agreement may not refer the claimant to a private physician described in such section with whom the agent or attorney has a business relationship.</text></subclause></clause> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H88BAB42952EF404E83775AC76753838D" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Effective on October 1 of each year (beginning in the first fiscal year after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Preserving Lawful Utilization of Services for Veterans Act of 2025</short-title>), the Secretary shall increase the dollar amount in effect under clause (i) of subparagraph (B) by a percentage equal to the percentage by which the Consumer Price Index for all urban consumers (U.S. city average) increased during the 12-month period ending with the last month for which Consumer Price Index data is available. In the event that such Consumer Price Index does not increase during such period, the Secretary shall maintain the dollar amount in effect under such clause during the previous fiscal year.</text></subparagraph> </paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA6128749E45D4E7F806FF40C4F7F034A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text> 
<clause id="HD9E08A03E20A4BC28375A4D831EC4B24"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>in a case referred to in paragraph (1) of this subsection</quote>; and</text></clause> <clause id="HFDD3EF80CC5749B29F7B7C6EAD39A656"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>in a case</quote> after <quote>represents a person</quote>;</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE2139E7E172440D49FE7008EBB96C7EA"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)(A), by striking <quote>paragraph (2)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraph (1) or (2)</quote>.</text></subparagraph> </paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="HB5BA95A9C9DA4CF3AB88612C2315EA44" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall prescribe regulations to carry out the amendments made by this section. </text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H62B82B052BC2487F9EE1719AAFA4EC55"><enum>4.</enum><header>Reinstatement of penalties for charging veterans unauthorized fees relating to claims under laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs</header> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF9DBB2945C8643199461C29D844F0DEF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 5905 of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H39EFE74A0D944661B972A8EB4061E5CE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="USC">Penalty</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="USC">Penalties</header-in-text></quote>;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAD80FC540AD649809EDD364D578F8B8E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="USC"><enum-in-header>(a)</enum-in-header></header-in-text><header-in-text level="subsection" style="USC"> Withholding of benefits.—</header-in-text></quote> before <quote>Whoever</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H77D32BC487A847118DEB66B14D04D013"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8CF43E0B5F1D4B9486BE543EC70AECEE"> 
<subsection id="H45F48B54449A486CA7EA86E2E016C67C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Charging of unauthorized fees</header><text>Except as provided in sections 5904 or 1984 of this title, whoever directly or indirectly solicits, contracts for, charges, or receives, or attempts to solicit, contract for, charge, or receive, any fee or compensation with respect to the preparation, presentation, or prosecution of any claim for benefits under the laws administered by the Secretary shall be fined as provided in title 18, or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H887952EF07F14F379E900F529486C48F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Violations during conditional and temporary recognition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an individual recognized as an agent or attorney on a conditional and temporary basis pursuant to clause (ii) or (iii) of section 5904(a)(1)(B) of this title violates any law or regulation administered by the Secretary under this chapter on or after the date on which such individual is so recognized—</text> 
<paragraph id="HFD14DF0219EB42358876DCFC591B5744" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Secretary shall, after notice, revoke the conditional and temporary recognition of the individual; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8731ED05E94648C5BA7B9786F866FDFE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>such individual, after notice and opportunity for a hearing, shall be—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H91D052124FDD4E50AA99E3FB451DCF72"><enum>(A)</enum><text>fined $50,000; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H235F372FC53449B189CE414D5DB156D2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>barred from recognition under section 5904 of this title—</text> 
<clause id="H7FE5FF9389B44807B0DC27B746C75A66"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for a period of one year beginning on the date of the first violation; and</text></clause> <clause id="H3043A24B1BEF42B08394CE8C5D9A68A2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for a period of 10 years beginning on the date of each subsequent violation.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="HBAF51922772E4C90AF558E4192BBBA6D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Deposit of fines</header><text>Any amount received by the Federal Government from a fine imposed under subsection (b) or (c) shall be deposited in the fund established by section 5904(a)(7)(C) of this title.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDC945BDC129545FD8C247B3829EDD8F9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of chapter 59 of such title is amended by striking the item relating to section 5905 and inserting the following new item:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4D391DF66C494E06879EB4DE06413E44"> 
<toc> 
<toc-entry level="section" bold="off">5905. Penalties for certain acts.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H53E511474D5E45A3858F74E4D4CEE0AA" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall take effect on the date that is 90 days after the date on which the Secretary prescribes the regulations required by subsection (b) of section 3. </text></subsection></section> <section id="HC1CD4ED9CA8D41279213B84D89A67B4D"><enum>5.</enum><header>Federal preemption</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act, and the amendments made by this Act, supersede any State law that is inconsistent with the statutory rights established by this Act, or such amendments, and preclude the implementation of such a law, whether statutory, common law, or otherwise, and whether adopted before or after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

