<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF3BE9FC561FE4337BF212F311FDF0729" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3973 IH: Ukraine War Risk Insurance Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3973</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250612">June 12, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide temporary war risk insurance for certain commercial vessels operating importing goods to, or exporting goods from, Ukraine.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H3195846CC66C4638B3B628DBE53E5EF3" style="OLC"><section id="H3234436BB603497486AB4B72E90674B6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Ukraine War Risk Insurance Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H50B0574739F5475A987E1E3363A5CBEA"><enum>2.</enum><header>Finding</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that the transportation in the waterborne commerce importing cargo to, or exporting cargo from, Ukraine is in the interest of the national defense or national economy of the United States.</text></section><section id="H94055CBF20B6488E817967CF529D6B76"><enum>3.</enum><header>War risk insurance eligibility for certain commercial vessels operating in Ukraine</header><subsection id="HBBB73581F8264FC8BF71A2AA08E82BF4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>Notwithstanding section 53902 of title 46, United States Code, for the period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act, and ending 5 years after such date, a covered vessel shall be deemed to be eligible for insurance or reinsurance under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/46/539">chapter 539</external-xref> of title 46, United States Code, if such vessel is engaged in transportation in waterborne commerce importing cargo to, or exporting cargo from, Ukraine.</text></subsection><subsection id="HAB617F18DA9547B1978F4110FD2B5BA8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Expansion of cargo</header><text>Subparagraphs (B) through (D) of section 53903(a)(3) of title 46, United States Code, shall not apply to cargo imported or exported to or from Ukraine.</text></subsection><subsection id="H80E3F909EC334FC486D744D575C0C1B2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H1E9E199033FF499B82B59908EFB2EC46"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered vessel</header><text>The term <term>covered vessel</term> means a vessel that is owned by a citizen of—</text><subparagraph id="HBDB68D39426D4AE8A52FC4F534F5C991"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a member country of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD95D8F6C0D414FADBFEBE05B9C420A1E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Ukraine; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H57153A6D2B6E4F07977D06DFE1BC9B5C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any other country the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of Transportation, determines, in the interest of national security, shall be considered eligible for insurance or reinsurance under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/46/539">chapter 539</external-xref> of title 46, United States Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB067D24D7A5E44D3A373D1B75DBA2513"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Owned by a citizen</header><text>The term <term>owned by a citizen</term> means ownership by an entity that is considered to be a citizen of a country in the same manner as an entity is deemed to be a citizen of the United States under section 50501 of title 46, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HCDDD7084D35046D185040BB47B1C490B"><enum>4.</enum><header>Insurance for Ukraine initiative</header><subsection id="H6390DFAF10B6478ABCACF91F5E4CCC48"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established in the Department of State an entity to be known as the Insurance for Ukraine Initiative.</text></subsection><subsection id="H8C54C45B90B3497AB49EFB9F63C778BD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Objectives</header><text>The objectives of the Insurance for Ukraine Initiative are the following:</text><paragraph id="H0081DD6F05444F7882887C5399E07C12"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Bolster confidence in Ukraine’s eventual economic recovery from Russia’s full-scale invasion through the provision of war risk insurance.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H90967DDEBEA548BA8893305C93C40189"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Encourage European allies and partners to finance and invest in Ukraine’s economic recovery, including through the provision of war risk insurance.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF688F2FC07894876884F17DF4007BEC4"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Promote closer economic integration between Ukraine and other countries in Europe as well as the United States and further Ukraine’s accession to the European Union.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFBBF72559D8C41FAA60E2D6AA2046FB1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Coordinate dialogue and fora for extensive outreach with private sector insurance companies relating to the provision of war risk insurance to Ukraine.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDB2B83AB814F4194A857375B5986BC5B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Work with Ukraine, international organizations, and Middle Eastern and African allies and partners to ensure the bountiful and affordable shipment of grain and other food commodities from Ukraine.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H724E46175B2E4963964A4F3763E66443"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter for the following 3 years, the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that includes assessments of—</text><paragraph id="H5EDEC4BE13A64931A15A666D5EE82420"><enum>(1)</enum><text>progress towards the achievement of each of the objectives set forth in subsection (b); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7968EDD0B5F44275A928AB16FB056181"><enum>(2)</enum><text>legislative proposals that would further the objectives set forth in subsection (b); and</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H92B6345605984F0C888C0F7A05C9D6EE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><paragraph id="H1D40AC2191464EF6869998AA1A4880E3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0CBFF74E63D44BE6BC922FAA8BEB38A0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HD7A68E007CFD4B1D8D294102C659CDAC"><enum>5.</enum><header>Diplomatic and political support</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of State, in coordination with the heads of other relevant Federal departments and agencies, shall seek to provide diplomatic and political support to countries that provide or provide support for war risk insurance for Ukraine, including by using the diplomatic and political influence and expertise of the Department of State to build the capacity of such countries.</text></section><section id="HA6C856FBFC494EAB893D79E36935CE80"><enum>6.</enum><header>Voice, vote, and influence of the United States at the U.N. Food and Agriculture Organization</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of State shall direct the United States Representative to the Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations to use the voice, vote, and influence of the United States at such Organization to seek to develop a multilateral insurance mechanism to protect the shipment of grain and other commodities from Ukraine.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

