<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HFA2513D132CD4682A7AC8BB4A6C9D43D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1826 IH: Child Care Workforce Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1826</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250304">March 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001112">Mr. Carbajal</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000629">Ms. Davids of Kansas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001133">Mr. Ciscomani</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To implement or strengthen programs that increase the supply of quality child care services by enhancing the wages of child care workers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H537D41E94A784C679C3D20A77E4911C6" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HA4F40C0F340049C1A901B3E0103658CB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Child Care Workforce Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H99E8B26328494008AC568263FC24E64A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purpose of this Act is to establish a pilot program to increase the supply of quality child care services by providing funding to States, Indian Tribes, and Tribal organizations to implement or strengthen programs to supplement the wages of eligible child care workers, in order to—</text> 
<paragraph id="H1B0106EB07F54ACDB6612CD3A2E988A1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>attract and retain eligible child care workers; </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFE3534FD3F13447E8C4066F71D2D1593"><enum>(2)</enum><text>improve eligible child care worker well-being;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2D5041F9C06A41429AD3655131C405E6"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">improve the quality of child care services; and </text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCF9597A7F94E4C4CB2BC53105FAB9271"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">increase the availability of affordable child care services.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H492EAE3457214959ABF26C9BF4C3F264" commented="no"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE381F145B1634DD79E571A553143A528"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Child care worker</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>child care worker</term> means any individual whose primary and daily focus of work is—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD5EE4124F8574CE0A8F96E10B89EB6E5"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">providing child care services, including direct care and education services, to children for a family child care provider or other child care provider, or a provider of early childhood education, that is in compliance with any licensing or registration standards, or regulations, of the State, Indian Tribe, or Tribal organization involved; and </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0622D396E9AA402D9624139AA300C879"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">providing the child care services in a center-based or home-based setting. </text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8D79DE3AA5634FB5A25ED3A119852995"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Indian Tribe</header><text>The term <term>Indian Tribe</term> has the meaning given the term in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>). </text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA6A537E4C0A848CA8B9FC1035D9F47AC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>State</term> means any of the several States, the District of Columbia, the Virgin Islands of the United States, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB56C683635FA459DB2783753716E327D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Tribal organization</header><text>The term <term>Tribal organization</term> has the meaning given the term <term>tribal organization</term> in section 658P of the Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9858n">42 U.S.C. 9858n</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HEF6013FC81E042179824405631CBDC90"><enum>4.</enum><header>Pilot program</header> <subsection id="H74D9127428C844319061717175E56981"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services (referred to in this Act as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall establish a pilot program to award competitive grants to States, Indian Tribes, and Tribal organizations to supplement the wages of eligible child care workers.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H38984E5A4D664A1CB48244939619FDDF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In selecting States, Indian Tribes, and Tribal organizations to receive grants under this section, the Secretary shall consider—</text> <paragraph id="HC89B1E8A2FDD46C59C35225865ADD28F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the number of children under the age of 5 residing in the State or on the Tribal land of the Indian Tribe or Tribal organization;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEAE6527077E04E0784112C7066645393"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of child care workers working in licensed, regulated, or registered programs in the State or on the Tribal land;</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H71E3918B0C2542B18D87764CCDDC07BC"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the average wage of child care workers working in the State or on the Tribal land;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9E735C79263C4A2FA4B1308383A72ECD"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the percentage of families in the State or on the Tribal land who are eligible for child care subsidies under the Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9857">42 U.S.C. 9857 et seq.</external-xref>) but do not receive the subsidies; and </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC0ACBE34D9C94722AE1BEB22C55827AD" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the need for additional child care workers in the State or on the Tribal land. </text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HAC752088C46146F3B74882374D6BC41C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>To be eligible for a grant under this section, a State, Indian Tribe, or Tribal organization shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require, including—</text> <paragraph id="H2B8769001DA1445B8B6AB2525A3D17E8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>information showing a significant need for increased numbers of child care workers and increased wages among child care workers;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBB0EC509D4E741D9BAC0CDB6A6E82F76"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a commitment to using the grant funds to supplement the wages of low-wage eligible child care workers;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6563AF3CAB7E455691F986097708EF40" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a plan for using the grant funds to supplement the wages of eligible child care workers, including— </text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3F3DE2C9EE5346A6A13ACA4A1AC4B171"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the criteria that will be used to determine which child care workers are eligible to receive the wage supplements; </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8062314D830F4104B2C57F8DECFDA98E" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of how funds will be prioritized for areas with greatest need, including areas with overall staffing challenges, underserved geographic areas, areas with shortages of programs that serve low-income children and families, and areas with shortages of programs that serve infants and toddlers, that serve children with disabilities, or that offer child care services during nontraditional hours; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE67C11493E6A443185BF73E240A36667" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a description of how the wage supplements will be provided to eligible child care workers (directly, through the employer, or through a trusted intermediary) and how the supplements will be provided in a timely manner;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFB0DB177A4FD4F2E87629C3464A7CCD9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a plan to engage in a public awareness campaign directed at eligible child care workers;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H87E2FA324F1545B5A1C27D90332261F6"><enum>(5)</enum><text>a description of the measures that will be used to assess the impact of the wage supplement pilot program on attraction and retention of eligible child care workers, eligible child care worker well-being, child care services quality, and availability of affordable child care services, provided by eligible child care workers;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC191B1DC65B7411FA72755C5FA55DAE3"><enum>(6)</enum><text>a description of how the pilot program will contribute to the State’s or Tribe’s overall plan for increasing eligible child care worker compensation; </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5AC980CF7F1B40638ACD68E584DB6068"><enum>(7)</enum><text>a description of the plan for addressing and minimizing any destabilization that may occur after the grant funds are expended; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEFFF5F694C264E988984EFE3C58EAD80"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such other information as the Secretary may require. </text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H44E4C2CC7AF14C689EB862B0F361423F"><enum>5.</enum><header>Use of funds</header> 
<subsection id="H04E1B6B08CC6492A81CED00DF4979259"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (c), a State, Indian Tribe, or Tribal organization that receives a grant under section 4 shall use the grant funds solely to supplement the wages of eligible child care workers. </text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H40571C27185446D4AAC242121E764B2F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out subsection (a), a State, Indian Tribe, or Tribal organization shall—</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1EBCEF0F75CF4B51BC362E66B0AE417E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">disburse the wage supplements to eligible child care workers not less frequently than quarterly;</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5252B87EDCAB45039158432EE4527E2D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">target grant funding based on the areas described in section 4(c)(3)(B); </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCD4CE4DFC19A442FA2BEA2384DFA7C69"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provide to eligible child care workers education on any effect the wage supplements may have on taxes or public benefit eligibility; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H132096C6BA294FFAA0BD8327BA1C7E28"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">inform eligible child care workers that acceptance, of the wage supplements, is voluntary. </text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7914EDA5B54B4612B3F1E1830190E6E1" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Administrative costs</header><text>The State, Indian Tribe, or Tribal organization may use not more than 10 percent of the grant funds to pay for administrative costs associated with the administration of payments to eligible child care workers, financial counseling for eligible child care workers, including as described in subsection (b)(3), and public awareness campaigns to make child care workers aware of the availability of such payments.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H6CC9737E92924C2FB97344AC36E2FA15"><enum>6.</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary shall conduct an evaluation of the pilot program to assess its effectiveness in—</text> 
<paragraph id="H15A799CFE8974484996E4B99F3C39BA7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>attracting and retaining eligible child care workers; </text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H83494BCFB3A84090B2CA9A9101652BAE"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">improving eligible child care worker well-being and the quality of child care services; and </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2B1290D5709A42BA89AEEEE41E7A67BD"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">increasing the availability of affordable child care services.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H0FF529D8A9B54C39AD5B0ACD023D8E50"><enum>7.</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"> Not later than 2 years after the date on which the pilot program is implemented, the Secretary shall submit a report to Congress containing the results of the evaluation.</text></section> 
<section id="HD9D320A639FC4C0FAF6D92C188832278"><enum>8.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act such sums as may be necessary for fiscal year 2025 and each subsequent fiscal year.</text></section> <section id="H29380C7073B04160846470661FAE807B"><enum>9.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act shall take effect 75 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

