<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H411C2C1D540E4837B6DE24C98FF083A1" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 127 IH: Of inquiry requesting the President and directing the Secretary of the Treasury to transmit, respectively, certain documents to the House of Representatives relating to the Department of Government Efficiency’s access to the Treasury payment systems and confidential taxpayer information.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 127</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250212">February 12, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000399">Mr. Doggett</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="N000015">Mr. Neal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000557">Mr. Larson of Connecticut</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001156">Ms. Sánchez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001296">Mr. Boyle of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001190">Mr. Schneider</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000585">Mr. Gomez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001066">Mr. Horsford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000610">Ms. Plaskett</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001201">Mr. Suozzi</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Of inquiry requesting the President and directing the Secretary of the Treasury to transmit, respectively, certain documents to the House of Representatives relating to the Department of Government Efficiency’s access to the Treasury payment systems and confidential taxpayer information.</official-title></form><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H0ABF085775B941C794BEDDA6CB192D63"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HDC848E65B51042AD8CEA83FE97E5DE26"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the President of the United States is requested, and the Secretary of the Treasury is directed, to transmit, to the extent that such documents are in the possession of the President or the Secretary, to the House of Representatives, not later than 14 days after the date of the adoption of this resolution, copies of any document, record, audio recording, memorandum, call log, correspondence (electronic or otherwise), activity logs, audit trails, audit logs, written agreements, or other communication or any portion of any such communication, that refers or relates to the following:</text><paragraph id="H1815858039AE4039BAA9436E542967D7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Access to, or usage of, the Treasury payment systems by the Department of Government Efficiency (hereafter referred to as <quote>DOGE</quote>), Elon Musk, or any member of his team. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5A716CC568EE42F1957B1A8957F52649"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Access to, or usage of, confidential tax returns or return information (within the meaning of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6103">section 6103</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, and including, but not limited to, social security numbers, names, addresses, type of tax, tax year, and tax debt owed) by DOGE, Elon Musk, or any member of his team.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC50E383358CC4511ABB9D9204E795D84"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Screenshots taken of Treasury payment systems data or records by DOGE, Elon Musk, or any member of his team.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

