<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-RIL25976-J9X-16-TNG"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 380 IS: Urging the protection of Medicare from the devastating cuts caused by H.R. 1.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 380</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250909">September 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S316">Mr. Whitehouse</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Urging the protection of Medicare from the devastating cuts caused by H.R. 1.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the Congressional Budget Office (referred to in this preamble as <term>CBO</term>) has estimated that the Act entitled <quote>An Act to provide for reconciliation pursuant to title II of H. Con. Res. 14</quote>, approved July 4, 2025 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/119/21">Public Law 119–21</external-xref>; 139 Stat. 72) (commonly known as the <term>One Big Beautiful Bill Act</term> and referred to in this preamble as <term>H.R. 1</term>) will add $4,100,000,000,000 to the deficit between 2025 and 2034;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas such an increase to the deficit will automatically trigger across-the-board spending cuts, called <quote>sequestration</quote>, under the Statutory Pay-As-You-Go Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/931">42 U.S.C. 931 et seq.</external-xref>) (referred to in this preamble as <term>S-PAYGO</term>);</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas sequestration will impose indiscriminate, across-the-board spending cuts to social safety net programs that millions of families in the United States rely on;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Medicare program established under title XVIII of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395">42 U.S.C. 1395 et seq.</external-xref>), a critical lifeline for the people of the United States, is not exempt from sequestration under S-PAYGO;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas CBO has estimated that $45,000,000,000 will be cut from Medicare by sequestration in 2026 alone;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas CBO has estimated that a total of $536,000,000,000 will be cut from Medicare by sequestration through 2034;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas these Medicare sequestration cuts compound nearly $1,000,000,000,000 in health care reductions under H.R. 1, stripping coverage from 15,000,000 people of the Untied States and further undermining the financial stability of health care providers;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, more than 67,000,000 people of the United States relied on Medicare for their health care coverage in 2024;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas cuts of this magnitude will jeopardize the financial stability of community health centers, hospitals, providers, and many others who rely on Medicare payments to serve seniors, people with disabilities, and those with end-stage renal disease;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Republicans’ partisan bill expanded the national debt by $4,100,000,000,000, and the Republicans chose not to protect the people of the United States from these cuts; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the people of the United States have paid into Medicare throughout their working lives with the expectation that their earned benefits will be protected: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That— </text><paragraph id="id268cc1deed994b569d1f023d88cdd6cc"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Senate should protect the Medicare program established under title XVIII of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395">42 U.S.C. 1395 et seq.</external-xref>) from devastating cuts caused by the Act entitled <quote>An Act to provide for reconciliation pursuant to title II of H. Con. Res. 14</quote>, approved July 4, 2025 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/119/21">Public Law 119–21</external-xref>; 139 Stat. 72) (commonly known as the <term>One Big Beautiful Bill Act</term> and referred to in this resolution as <term>H.R. 1</term>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbe47b566557a4f9382cfcd69036db156"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Senate should safeguard seniors’ Medicare benefits and essential social services that are jeopardized by the cuts triggered by H.R. 1; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3e9c2cc8452f436e835adcc1c5e4277c"><enum>(3)</enum><text>seniors who have paid into Medicare throughout their working lives should be protected from reckless, across-the-board cuts to their health care.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

