<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H55795ECBEB00493CB3DB522FAA2BCD71" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 285 IH: Condemning the wave of domestic terrorism attacks targeting Tesla cars and dealerships.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 285</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250401">April 1, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B000825">Ms. Boebert</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="N000026">Mr. Nehls</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000175">Mr. Ogles</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001214">Mr. Steube</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000194">Ms. Mace</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001302">Mr. Biggs of Arizona</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000603">Mr. Gill of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001212">Mr. Moore of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000032">Mr. Donalds</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000596">Mrs. Luna</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Condemning the wave of domestic terrorism attacks targeting Tesla cars and dealerships.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas members of the Democratic Party have made calls for their supporters to incite and engage in domestic terrorism by attacking Tesla vehicles and facilities to protest Elon Musk;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas anti-Tesla incidents have happened in at least 9 States involving arson, gunfire, and vandalism;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas at least 80 reported cases of vandalism or arson of Tesla vehicles have taken place throughout the United States and Canada;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas at least 10 Tesla dealerships, charging stations, and facilities have been hit by vandals;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, on February 11, 2025, in Loveland, Colorado, a man attacked a Tesla dealer on multiple occasions, including throwing Molotov cocktails and spray-painting words on vehicles and windows, including the word <quote>Nazi</quote>;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, on March 2, 2025, in Washington, DC, 2 people defaced Tesla vehicles, twice writing political hate speech on the vehicles before fleeing;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, on March 3, 2025, in Boston, Massachusetts, 7 Tesla charging stations in a mall outside the Massachusetts capital were set on fire;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, on March 6, 2025, in Portland, Oregon, at least 7 gunshots were fired into a Tesla showroom in the middle of the night, windows were shattered, and 3 cars were damaged, and 1 bullet went through an office wall and into a computer monitor;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, on March 7, 2025, in North Charleston, South Carolina, a 24-year-old man threw 5 Molotov cocktails at a Tesla charging station, and witnesses reported seeing a man spray-paint an expletive against Trump and <quote>Long Live Ukraine</quote> in red paint in the parking lot;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, on March 7, 2025, in Loveland, Colorado, a man ignited an incendiary device and hurled it at a Tesla dealership, which landed between 2 cars and created a fire that put lives at risk, and rocks were also thrown, damaging both the building and multiple vehicles;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, on March 18, 2025, in Las Vegas, Nevada, a person dressed in black shot at Tesla cars at a repair shop and ignited 2 of them with Molotov cocktails, and the word <quote>Resist</quote> was spray-painted on the front doors of the shop;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, on March 24, 2025, the Austin police discovered multiple incendiary devices that had been placed at a Tesla showroom in Austin, Texas; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, on March 24, 2025, the Federal Bureau of Investigation created a task force to work in conjunction with the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives to investigate violent Tesla attacks: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H6BE8204E38344633BA5EC8E50EB51E25"> <section id="HF2FEBC768E874A0690B45C7936A167AA" section-type="undesignated-section" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives condemns the wave of domestic terrorism attacks targeting Tesla cars and dealerships.</text></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

