<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6FF3F7CFC6174447B58744A81A6675E1" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4792 IH: Protecting Air Ambulance Services for Americans Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4792</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250729">July 29, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000298">Mr. Estes</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to revise payment for air ambulance services under the Medicare program.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H698429C08FF3462A9F1B831EB717C855" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H720A727FC5AA4381BC5C38362E5C1113"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting Air Ambulance Services for Americans Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HAB392C74A1AD44E7B6FDF747DD33050F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Improvements to Medicare payment system for air ambulance services</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1834(l) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395m">42 U.S.C. 1395m(l)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H10BEC27E440640B586A2254AD5C43E18"> 
<paragraph id="H3DB157867654411A9A5F2CF17C14E1CC"><enum>(18)</enum><header>Improvements to Medicare payment system for air ambulance services</header> 
<subparagraph id="HB44D36B3B82845D3A3774DC1330253DA"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may revise the fee schedule otherwise established under this subsection for air ambulance services based on data described in subparagraph (B) and data collected under subparagraph (C).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6E95D785D4E94C4698EAD6943AB5943F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Data described</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A), the data described in this subparagraph is data collected pursuant to the provisions of, and amendments made by, section 106 of division BB of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/260">Public Law 116–260</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6FC8C7DE98E24E0F9A06B61B401F2CBD"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Additional data collection</header><text>The Secretary shall require, once every 3 years, providers of services and suppliers furnishing air ambulance services to submit to the Secretary—</text> <clause id="H859A06D9ECFB40A4B321244F7F8CC955"><enum>(i)</enum><text>data relating to the fixed and operated costs per air ambulance base attributable to furnishing air ambulance services to individuals enrolled under this part and data relating to the utilization of such services by such individuals;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H83858AFEAF1946AE8E6AC69D401CB9E8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>data relating to the revenue obtained by such providers and suppliers under this part attributable to the furnishing of such services; and</text></clause> <clause id="H4842EA18560243F4AB7A2DFB82271C3E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any other information determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5BD6399790AE43AF96F69A83E5BC569C"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In the case that the Secretary elects to revise the fee schedule for air ambulance services under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall consider stakeholder input in a process that is transparent and appropriately considers data described in subparagraph (B) and data collected under subparagraph (C).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section id="HAE18E8981D2A4E198B6409CECFF163C1"><enum>3.</enum><header>Timely finalization of air ambulance data collection rule</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall finalize and publish a final rule implementing the air ambulance data collection requirements under section 106 of division BB of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/260">Public Law 116–260</external-xref>).</text></section> 
<section id="H31D6E381DE1B41E6A34E468F8E6A4F8F"><enum>4.</enum><header>GAO study on emergency air ambulance costs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date on which data begins to be collected pursuant to the provisions of, and amendments made by, section 106 of division BB of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/260">Public Law 116–260</external-xref>), the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the Committee on Finance of the Senate and the Committee on Ways and Means and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives, a report detailing—</text> <paragraph id="H6C0EFA336C88463BB1754DAD4FD819A7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the average annual operating costs per air ambulance base;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H84AB621A30A748D48F3873C3DBB25DF6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the average cost per transport by air ambulance;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD30E61CA198542009A949BEB23183A1B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the payor mix for air ambulance services;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE30D487788DA4234973532AC58EC5F9D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the adequacy of Medicare payments for such services;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H06D6D43964FB4121A3E421412CBC7584"><enum>(5)</enum><text>geographic variations in the cost of furnishing such services; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF103FC24B08747079DF3E729731DC65D"><enum>(6)</enum><text>recommendations on improving the fee schedule under section 1834(l) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395m">42 U.S.C. 1395m(l)</external-xref>) for air ambulance services.</text></paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

