<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ROS25095-SG8-6F-YJW"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S145 IS: Dismantle Iran’s Proxy Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 145</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date>__________</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S323">Mr. Risch</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S318">Mr. Wicker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S374">Mr. Cotton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S252">Ms. Collins</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S293">Mr. Graham</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S266">Mr. Crapo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S407">Mr. Hagerty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S404">Mr. Scott of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S376">Ms. Ernst</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S411">Mr. Marshall</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S373">Mr. Cassidy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S343">Mr. Boozman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S416">Mrs. Britt</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S381">Mr. Rounds</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the redesignation of Ansarallah as a foreign terrorist organization.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Dismantle Iran’s Proxy Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idaab22ceb4c3c4c17a7a6acd5919382d2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Redesignation of Ansarallah as a foreign terrorist organization</header><subsection id="id573dc7872fb24ffabf4a22ff08a559ca"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Imposition of sanctions with respect to Ansarallah</header><paragraph id="id8316fc6317fd45df9ccf9fe1872c6b47"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall—</text><subparagraph id="idad97deca7f044f049bb6ebafe16d86ac"><enum>(A)</enum><text>designate Ansarallah as a foreign terrorist organization pursuant to section 219 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1189">8 U.S.C. 1189</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5a8f26d2eee3408099e4e3da3ba7f5ad"><enum>(B)</enum><text>impose, with respect to Ansarallah and any foreign person the President determines is an official, agent, or affiliate of Ansarallah, the sanctions applicable with respect to a foreign person pursuant to Executive Order 13224 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note; relating to blocking property and prohibiting transactions with persons who commit, threaten to commit, or support terrorism).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id27a9c1680eb94848a731e70b6cec7693"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Determination required</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the President makes the designation required by subparagraph (A) of paragraph (1) and imposes the sanctions required by subparagraph (B) of that paragraph, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a determination regarding whether the following foreign persons are officials, agents, or affiliates of Ansarallah:</text><subparagraph id="idf215a2f7dfa5474383f60cc70108b9f5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Abdul Malik al-Houthi.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idcbd9f044218342ffaf04cd1ba9ca4941"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Abd al-Khaliq Badr al-Din al-Houthi.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id382314a106ab4d2c9c53d3f0732f6450"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Abdullah Yahya al-Hakim.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id79ebc3220a8748918261c1d631372cba"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Strategy To degrade Ansarallah capability in Red Sea</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a strategy—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7c1ddc07eb5b4dd38ffee9fe0f707f44"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to restore freedom of navigation in the Bab al Mandeb Strait, the Red Sea, and adjacent waterways; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idde744aab375d42e39cd5d1fbdc7cccce"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to take appropriate steps to degrade the offensive capabilities of Ansarallah, including with respect to command and control, key leaders, intelligence sources supporting attacks by Ansarallah, lethal aid, training, and materiel support.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id24525cf86ec3485b985e8c486da03919"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report on obstacles to provision of humanitarian aid in areas of Yemen under de-Facto Ansarallah control</header><paragraph id="id6a96c2b7a4b04f8ab0aa6af65b058ca5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on obstacles to the provision of humanitarian aid by international organizations and nongovernmental organizations in areas of Yemen under the de-facto control of Ansarallah.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id72f1e7b9f49847baa9aa967c97cb4fa0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Matters to be included</header><text>The report required by paragraph (1) shall include the following:</text><subparagraph id="idc68f0fec6b8d453682a43af8eeb3154b"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An identification of challenges to distribution of humanitarian aid created by rules, regulations, and bureaucracy of Ansarallah with respect to access and freedom of movement, and an assessment of the overall impact such rules, regulations, and bureaucracy have on the ability of the international community to distribute humanitarian aid in a manner consistent with basic humanitarian principles.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id61a64430ed4b428a9265e7545c1574db"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An assessment of attempted interference by Ansarallah in the delivery of humanitarian aid, including the manipulation or undue influence of beneficiary lists or related data for political or military purposes, and the implications of any such interference on civilian needs and aid distribution.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9d0bf3eba5b84c599ca3d761023b8939"><enum>(C)</enum><text>An evaluation of the use of violence and intimidation by Ansarallah against humanitarian workers and diplomats, including current and former locally employed staff of the United States embassy.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8be90d65c74c4e7dbf149638f807e405"><enum>(D)</enum><text>An overview of the steps the United States and its partners are taking to ensure humanitarian aid is delivered unhindered and consistent with basic humanitarian principles, including how organizations supported by the United States respond to attempted diversion or interference by Ansarallah.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idd186fa4c3ce544bebc5201307ff253e8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="idb8b66bb3cb534392a07a782263fb911e"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Ansarallah</header><text>The term <term>Ansarallah</term> means the movement known as Ansarallah, the Houthi movement, or any other alias. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id91273cbdb58b4bbfa1c1dc0d8de9aaa1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="id87927d6dcd2a457495a4081f41f3914f"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8a4933a680fd4345bbba9233497b412d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id7eb8d96b3d9b4a3c88511b8f2e50305a"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Foreign person</header><text>The term <term>foreign person</term> means a person that is not a United States person.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc23f3c94b49c42d7a3ce4af9d729194f"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Person</header><text>The term <term>person</term> means an individual or entity.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfbfa606cf336408eb72b33633d2519d7"><enum>(5)</enum><header>United States person</header><text>The term <term>United States person</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="id6cab88e1e4304949b41456d02d523087"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a national of the United States or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence in the United States (as those terms are defined in section 101 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref>)); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4c8211d5bbfb409592d678535384a562"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an entity organized under the laws of the United States or of any jurisdiction within the United States, including a foreign branch of such an entity. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

