<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" dms-id="HED27265339AE4ADAB996A54019E690A1" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 579 EH: Recruiting Families Using Data Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 579</legis-num>
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To amend parts B and E of title IV of the Social Security Act to improve foster and adoptive parent recruitment and retention, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H8E1624458F6740D3B385C89D77470FBA" style="OLC">
<section section-type="section-one" id="H042F26FF9148489EBFCF254E511B3EB4"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Recruiting Families Using Data Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H283FE2F7A7D6445988DB22C42781CE8C"><enum>2.</enum><header>State plan amendment</header> <subsection id="HB4211336D547446CAE233EE03FC3D86C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 422 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/622">42 U.S.C. 622</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="H4348B0AFA09D42EBB2F7934FC9FD915E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (b)(7), by inserting <quote>through the development and implementation of a family partnership plan which meets the requirements of subsection (d) for identification, recruitment, screening, licensing, support, and retention of foster and adoptive families</quote> after <quote>are needed</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3651D478794440A988EB9D5810EEFE40"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H399A3B643585482BB0279D3C34B2048F">
<subsection id="HC188B01A46CC46AAAD9F8A1ACA4178A0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Family Partnership Plan Requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of subsection (b)(7), the requirements for a family partnership plan (in this subsection referred to as the <quote>plan</quote>) are the following:</text> <paragraph id="HC7BC7F8F602042B6B43E7ED097005045"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The plan is developed in consultation with birth, kinship, foster and adoptive families, community-based service providers, technical assistance providers, and youth with lived experience with foster care and adoption.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2962090A7D7B4B2AA5F1880ED231A1BE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The plan describes—</text> <subparagraph id="H99EDA00BF486492096336C154D9C1617"><enum>(A)</enum><text>how the State plans to identify, notify, engage, and support relatives (and others connected to the child) as potential placement resources for children; </text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H340F9D5A8B23482D8707BAB60FC848FD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>how the State plans to develop and implement child-specific recruitment plans for every child in or entering foster care who needs a foster or adoptive family; </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H60941B74DEF84E1ABADEA06828D848D7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>how the State plans to authentically engage children and youth in recruitment efforts on their behalf; </text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4051DDB25FDA4524BE411439F1FF08A3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>how the State plans to use data to establish goals, assess needs, measure progress, reduce unnecessary placements in congregate care, increase permanency, improve placement stability, increase the rate of kinship placements, improve recruitment and retention of families for teens, sibling groups, and other special populations, and align the composition of foster and adoptive families with the needs of children in or entering foster care; and </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H18E1C769723C4B3E8638066CAF04E71C"><enum>(E)</enum><text>how that State will stand up or support foster family advisory boards for the purpose of improving recruitment and retention of foster and adoptive families.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB3BA283258AA494989690C0DFF777087"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The plan provides that, not less than annually, the State shall collect and report on the State’s actual foster family capacity and congregate care utilization, including the number, demographics, and characteristics of licensed foster families, including prospective adoptive families, the number of such families that haven’t received a placement or are not being fully utilized and the reasons therefor, and the number, demographics, and characteristics of children placed in congregate care in-State and out-of-State. </text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H65E530A25C2C4DCA929336C52B98031B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The plan includes, and shall update not less than annually, a summary of the most recent feedback from foster and adoptive parents and youth regarding licensure, training, support, and reasons why parents stop fostering or why adoptive or legal guardianship placements out of foster care fail or foster and such adoptive of legal guardianship families struggle to meet children’s needs. </text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H692AFD35B3D5480FB9FAEE01E1B402E5"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The plan includes, and shall update annually, a report on the State’s analysis of specific challenges or barriers to recruiting, licensing, and utilizing families who reflect the racial and ethnic background of children in foster care in the State, and the State’s efforts to overcome those challenges and barriers. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6667787DAC21416B9061244FB33074E9"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The plan includes such other information relating to foster and adoptive parent recruitment and retention as the Secretary may require.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HE272E1B76D4548B18871970834B01CFA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header>
<paragraph id="H1CD94A8470E941A7ACFE5C301D8E9984"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the amendment made by this subsection shall take effect on October 1, 2026.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8C29BC5C80E8403F8AAFA04EBB93FFEB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Delay permitted if state legislation required</header><text>In the case of a State plan approved under subpart 1 of part B of title IV of the Social Security Act which the Secretary of Health and Human Services determines requires State legislation (other than legislation appropriating funds) in order for the plan to meet the additional requirements imposed by this subsection, the State plan shall not be regarded as failing to comply with the requirements of such part solely on the basis of the failure of the plan to meet such additional requirements before the first day of the first calendar quarter beginning after the close of the first regular session of the State legislature that begins after the date of enactment of this subsection. For purposes of the previous sentence, in the case of a State that has a 2-year legislative session, each year of such session shall be deemed to be a separate regular session of the State legislature.</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="HC5371346AE74448E95CA2E3E5DDB4B99"><enum>3.</enum><header>Inclusion of information on foster and adoptive families in annual child welfare outcomes report to Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 479A(a) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/679b">42 U.S.C. 679b(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H35B145F09BFC4AFD87724130C528F8B2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (6)(C), by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H380464D0686C4F1E87AE1649CAD83B23"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (7)(B), by striking the period and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H35F9527035F045B0A31967B3863CA1F8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H331D1E405EDF4250BA9969FF36CD8B8E">
<paragraph id="HBE6A72B7897B49EEB3B2E30E58E774A6"><enum>(8)</enum><text>include in the report submitted pursuant to paragraph (5) for fiscal year 2025 or any succeeding fiscal year—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6B703256E4A641F9A2DEDD8F286EF75C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>State-by-State data on the number, demographics, and characteristics of foster and adoptive families in the State, and the number of potential foster and adoptive families not being utilized in the State and the reasons why;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H026158095F9246C39CEBA7984B78CFD0"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a summary of the challenges of, and barriers to, being a foster or adoptive parent, including with respect to recruitment, licensure, engagement, retention, and why parents stop fostering, adoptions disrupt or dissolve, or foster or adoptive families struggle, as reported by States based on surveys of foster and adoptive parents; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H48A5DFFF435D4127BC983CAF62609F34"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a summary of the challenges and barriers States reported on efforts to recruit a pool of families that reflect the racial and ethnic background of children in foster care in the State, and efforts to overcome those barriers.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section>
</legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20250304" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives March 4, 2025.</attestation-date><attestor display="no">Kevin F. McCumber,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation>
<endorsement display="yes"></endorsement>
</bill> 


