<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H59FD39E0C8944B94A9D58360B1258C4D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2127 IH: Expel Illegal Chinese Police Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2127</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250314">March 14, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001091">Mrs. Hinson</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="M001194">Mr. Moolenaar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000055">Mr. Aderholt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001306">Mr. Balderson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000628">Mr. Dunn of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000193">Mr. Nunn of Iowa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000740">Mrs. Bice</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001133">Mr. Ciscomani</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To impose sanctions with respect to police departments in the People&#8217;s Republic of China and other persons seeking to establish a Chinese police presence in the United States.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H090ADFCE608C4563BEF6E79A642591CA" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H096899CD6BF141A8B9DA5D41E00B0750"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Expel Illegal Chinese Police Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H4AF5498EFAB84EC4B782AA6F605378C7"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sanctions with respect to police departments in the People's Republic of China</header> <subsection id="H832A2F1690E947A1B07F30B4208CA2B3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On and after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall impose—</text>
<paragraph id="HEB20C97908C8498FA73F10008158CB31"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the sanctions described in subsection (b)(1) with respect to any foreign person the President determines is—</text> <subparagraph id="H902D28AC94B94CDC9206617E3F2DD324"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a provincial, municipal, or other jurisdictional police department or law enforcement institution in the People's Republic of China, including the provincial police departments of Xinjiang Uyghur Autonomous Region and Fujian; </text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0E267A3053C54721AC306BD4F5842E20"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a member of the senior leadership of a department or institution described in subparagraph (A); </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H947FD0DEDCB44A2782FC9241D06A0449"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">directly associated with establishing or maintaining a Chinese police presence in the United States; </text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H784CF597622D4250AD498B9A16377C37"><enum>(D)</enum><text>acting under the direction and control of a provincial, municipal, or other Public Security Bureau or law enforcement institution in the People’s Republic of China; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFE9FB7183CD44779AACF6A35398E922C"><enum>(E)</enum><text>acting under the direction or control of the United Front Work Department with the intention of covertly monitoring or intimidating individuals living in the United States; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HCEAEE84AAB8E4B0AAC208D4C1556866B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the sanctions described in subsection (b)(2) with respect to an alien the President determines is—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE963AE7B3F484201B50D75E525901A5F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an employee of a department or institution described in paragraph (1)(A) or foreign person described in paragraph (1)(E); </text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1F8A4C29C0AC4E598E5D42B38C27B4E4"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an immediate family member of such an employee; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H16E91D46DA7C4C8582B382A19A47FA86"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">directly associated with establishing or maintaining a Chinese police presence or a presence of the United Front Work Department in the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H99CF68A29BC347AF907AF2AE208C6980"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sanctions described</header><text>The sanctions described in this subsection with respect to a foreign person described in subsection (a) are the following:</text> <paragraph id="HB6C60ADAD90143F187D180AD43623B6C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Property blocking</header><text>The President shall exercise all of the powers granted by the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>) to the extent necessary to block and prohibit all transactions in all property and interests in property of any foreign person described in subsection (a)(1) if such property and interests in property are in the United States, come within the United States, or are or come within the possession or control of a United States person.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD49D36F35E4043FFBE6D9420E9F5281E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Aliens inadmissible for visas, admission, or parole</header>
<subparagraph id="HE7A36C5D00104EAA9E6236A3D6CCF38B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Visas, admission, or parole</header><text>In the case of an alien described in subsection (a), the alien is—</text> <clause id="H6CB1108F73994372B0536B23B9628CC6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>inadmissible to the United States;</text></clause>
<clause id="HEE71946D9C164147852FFF81A844791C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>ineligible to receive a visa or other documentation to enter the United States; and</text></clause> <clause id="H20BA0651EE3F4517B2E36043594F3E89"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>otherwise ineligible to be admitted or paroled into the United States or to receive any other benefit under the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HB6EF72B715CF48C7A79029D241684A29"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Current visas revoked</header>
<clause id="HE7821EEC0B5D4499B073E75430848560"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The visa or other entry documentation of an alien described in subparagraph (A) shall be revoked, regardless of when such visa or other entry documentation was issued.</text></clause> <clause id="H234E9CB3BD4D40DDA00B2372CCCAC1E9"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Immediate effect</header><text>A revocation under clause (i) shall—</text>
<subclause id="H26B347DACAB14C2CB3BBAF5FD91E9ABE"><enum>(I)</enum><text>take effect immediately; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H018F2127CB1443DA82F1B2AE04FEE584"><enum>(II)</enum><text>automatically cancel any other valid visa or entry documentation that is in the alien’s possession.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HEE4E5532ACB442E2BEA08D54008C6F59"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Waiver</header>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA5A13D4659794E4798526D9E8B8AC16C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may, on a case-by-case basis and for periods not to exceed 30 days, waive the application of sanctions under this section with respect to a foreign person if the President certifies to Congress not later than 15 days before the waiver is to take effect that the waiver is vital to the national security interests of the United States. </text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFB2EB75757FD4257B2CEB167BE1E2D40"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Form of certification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may submit a certification under paragraph (1) to Congress in classified form if the President determines it is necessary to do so. </text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H2B7649D152454BC49D695EFEEBA31170"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Implementation; penalties</header>
<paragraph id="H7B2C9D64FE894C789EC81B2B7B499AD2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>The President may exercise all authorities provided under sections 203 and 205 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1702 and 1704) to carry out this section.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF382F55DA1004264A0AB85ADED0C5447"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text>A person that violates, attempts to violate, conspires to violate, or causes a violation of this section or any regulation, license, or order issued to carry out this section shall be subject to the penalties set forth in subsections (b) and (c) of section 206 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1705">50 U.S.C. 1705</external-xref>) to the same extent as a person that commits an unlawful act described in subsection (a) of that section.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H0B047DB43B16488CB8F61FC4EDAEC342"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Prohibition on participation in certain investigations</header><text>The President shall direct all Federal agencies not to participate in any investigation that is not initiated by the United States Government into any foreign person described in subsection (a) unless the President determines that participating in such an investigation is vital to health, safety, and well-being of United States citizens. </text></subsection> <subsection id="HE3E6D3F110C34E539596ED1A47F207B7"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text>
<paragraph id="HA2F8C28D481846D290348467E75DB10B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Admitted alien</header><text>The terms <term>admitted</term> and <term>alien</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 101 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6EB6D67F88924052B3C5DCFF88A4A6E1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Foreign person</header><text>The term <term>foreign person</term> means a person that is not a United States person.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF556597A12E5433BB8B8E13D161CF8BB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Immediate family member</header><text>The term <term>immediate family member</term>, with respect to a foreign person, means the spouse, parent, sibling, or adult child of the person.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0F46014FE65D456AA4AB564FC6DBC472"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Person</header><text>The term <term>person</term> means an individual or entity, including a governmental entity.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H24E4C9BA7E694291B41E1D6726BBF823"><enum>(5)</enum><header>United states person</header><text>The term <term>United States person</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HEC74F7FC782F443A9FC9D8F5AE10EE44"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an individual who is a United States citizen or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence to the United States;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE4B8C986E9874B9D8E0262DB26673EA2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an entity organized under the laws of the United States or any jurisdiction within the United States, including a foreign branch of such an entity; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7C8C0564DA2A40019A101E108E0F16CB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any person in the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

