<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H268D047E5AD64476B59008E0AE3D0310" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 614 IH: Strengthening Awareness and Funding Education for Grilling Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 614</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250122">January 22, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Consumer Product Safety Commission to develop and implement a public awareness campaign with respect to grill safety, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA8A2B583A7B04004A6878125E307ABFD" style="OLC"><section id="H2544F1F8D6D944359621EBEEC1855FFF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Strengthening Awareness and Funding Education for Grilling Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SAFE Grilling Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H9B81DDAACF0843D8901AABF022EEB20F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that, according to the National Fire Protection Association and the Consumer Product Safety Commission, during the years 2017 through 2021—</text><paragraph id="H0F6385A3E7A045EDB5E4FCCD6E1A46C5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an average of 22,155 individuals each year went to an emergency room due to injuries involving grills;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2F466E2B38124679B3C2C550CEDAC93B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">gas grills were involved in an average of 9,079 home fires each year, with 4,454 structure fires and 4,625 outdoor fires averaged annually;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H08E3C5C911A84098B2E764ADF2801667"><enum>(3)</enum><text>leaks or breaks were a significant problem with gas grills, as 6 percent of structure fires related to gas grills and 15 percent of outdoor fires related to gas grills were caused by leaks or breaks;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE0ECD3499F874D65ACD7561AABE593B0"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">more than 25 percent of structure fires related to grills began on an exterior balcony or open porch, 8 percent began when an outside wall caught fire, and 4 percent began with some type of structural member or framing;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE11C9F28DA8842999C0D9B56F47AC46A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>July was the peak month for fires related to grills (16 percent of such fires), followed by June (14 percent), May (12 percent), and August (11 percent); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5A05ECD999DD4F55AFA0AEB8B179913C"><enum>(6)</enum><text>a grill that had not been cleaned was involved in roughly 20 percent of fires related to grills.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HF033840614A14D03A550CA235D4EE7BC"><enum>3.</enum><header>Public awareness campaign with respect to grill safety</header><subsection id="H6059908253244A8483C25A2CDB9129A5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Consumer Product Safety Commission shall develop and implement a public awareness campaign to educate the public with respect to—</text><paragraph id="H701E950CB1B644E7814F20875735638A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>dangers associated with cooking using a grill; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H64AB03750D2F426DBEBAF51873520558"><enum>(2)</enum><text>best practices for using a grill safely to prevent injuries and fires.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H80FFE7F25B9A4F30A1F3BD273DEE1984"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated $5,000,000 to carry out this section.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

