<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF90C6346104E42CD82919E9E63241324" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3210 IH: Artificial Intelligence Literacy and Inclusion Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3210</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250506">May 6, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Lieu</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and Workforce</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HSM00">Small Business</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the National Science Foundation to make awards for artificial intelligence literacy programs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H60A8185C9A0C4C4A8662208BEB603CD9" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H435CDA461B1E4B1A8E159C884FA36CD5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Artificial Intelligence Literacy and Inclusion Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HF5E4C4560CBE42B7A30D99D587CE4861"><enum>2.</enum><header>Awards for artificial intelligence literacy programs</header> <subsection id="HC5002E95CB8B4A6E9F7D7CA853D8D926"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Awards</header> <paragraph id="HC723EFA4BCE54C038FCA4FC6DC5451CA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the National Science Foundation (NSF) may make awards to eligible entities, including nonprofit organizations, educational institutions, or consortiums of such entities, to develop, implement, and evaluate programs that promote AI literacy at the local level allowing communities to learn about AI from local, trusted sources.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7F60F74448E14F809C34D3FD56780182"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>Awards made under this subsection may be used for the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HDE12DA68F0CC42E2944FF51F75873F7F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>To develop curricula, educational materials, and resources focused on AI literacy, including relating to understanding the basics of AI, its applications, ethical considerations, and the societal impacts of AI.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HB14D01CA69F947FAA053107BCF7B222C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To provide AI literacy education and training to marginalized communities, with priority given to communities of color, low-income populations, rural areas, senior citizens, people with disabilities, and other underserved groups.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H16F0336FD0654E9D851307729A5D2D23" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>To conduct outreach and engagement activities to raise awareness of AI literacy and encourage participation in AI literacy programs.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA30D7E3F4F584B9CADC755FA2C8B9AA4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>To evaluate the effectiveness of AI literacy programs and share best practices and lessons learned with other organizations and institutions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H10E2CB31A30E47088690D5523DAD5E9B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Prioritization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In making awards under this subsection, the Director of the NSF may encourage applications that—</text>
<subparagraph id="HBCA41DC3F593463991E78D06780A11AE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>demonstrate a strong commitment to serving marginalized communities, including senior citizens;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H181ED5479E094ECD8226AF7C82BB71BA" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>have experience launching technology education local programs working with target populations; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H88E66F987DFA44838C640243D1046FCB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>propose innovative and scalable approaches to AI literacy education.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEC2BB1C37CCC478B9CA98E2B09821076"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text>Each recipient of an award made under this subsection shall submit to the Director of the NSF an annual report that may include the following:</text>
<subparagraph id="H3DA2600C97284A0EB62E16C470042337"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A description of the AI literacy programs funded by the award.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H85558656E9974DD2B84D2FE13258C606"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Information relating to the number and demographics of individuals served by the award.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H35C0E82AB8AB4320BFDB7514DAA089F6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>An assessment of the impact of the award on participants’ understanding of AI and its implications.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H98193CED034D45B19A962A868C6035F4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Interagency coordination, reporting, and award identification</header> <paragraph id="H67E0EBEA85AE49A3924CB1FF2DBB7BDA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the heads of the following Federal agencies shall each submit to Congress a report detailing how the respective agency can more effectively advance AI literacy:</text>
<subparagraph id="H264439DFCB734E60AC04D6C22D5A69CE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Secretary of Labor shall assess how AI literacy can be integrated into workforce development programs, with a focus on preparing workers for the jobs of the future and maintaining the United States competitive advantage and national security through artificial intelligence.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC6704412FF944F2FB0F98183FEA5BD03"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Secretary of Commerce shall evaluate how AI literacy can enhance the competitiveness of United States businesses, particularly small and medium-sized enterprises, in the global AI economy, and contribute to maintaining the United States competitive advantage and national security through artificial intelligence.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H68F38FF197CA4E13A29D32B744087332"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Administrator of the Small Business Administration shall evaluate opportunities to support AI literacy among small business owners and entrepreneurs, with an emphasis on underserved communities, to maintain the United States competitive advantage and national security through artificial intelligence.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H53E2EAEFD6ED43DAA63A26C0EBCE4C96"> <enum>(D)</enum> <text>The Secretary of Education shall identify strategies for incorporating AI literacy into K–12 and higher education curricula, ensuring that all students have access to quality AI education, and that AI literacy contributes to maintaining the United States competitive advantage and national security through artificial intelligence.</text>
          </subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0965453037974AB9919622B49D8CC7ED"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Award identification and modification</header><text>The head of each agency specified in paragraph (1) shall also include in the respective reports required under such paragraph the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H53C6FBADADE14B2D8EB54AD6BE0E08C2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An identification of existing awards under the jurisdiction of the respective agency that can be modified to include AI literacy as an eligible use of funds.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE7F4C93C339A4A70B2793FFAF1221B2D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Recommendations on how such awards can be adapted to support AI literacy initiatives, particularly in the context of workforce development, business competitiveness, education, and national security.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0C545F8322BE4DE3A3011B95ED22002D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Specific examples of award programs that could be modified and the potential impact of such modifications.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H3418E3CF4FBE46938EB8CB01BFD21360"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In preparing the reports and recommendations required under this subsection, the head of each agency shall consult with relevant stakeholders, including educators, industry representatives, community organizations, and AI experts.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7F3D1439D5764EA7814AC0D48BEE50F5"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The reports required under this subsection shall be made publicly available on the websites of the respective agencies.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HFA89356C4CA842F2838338391AD23C30"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HF66AA537AC044695BE34CAD9566F412F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>AI</header><text>The term <quote>AI</quote> means artificial intelligence.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H607DE6D7DEDE495B8EDEF7437724886A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Artificial intelligence</header><text>The term <quote>artificial intelligence</quote> means an engineered system that can generate output for a given set of human-defined objectives, such as content, predictions, recommendations, or decisions that influence people or environments.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDC90FF63EE634444BAC8858B50E2BAC4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Artificial intelligence literacy; AI literacy</header><text>The terms <quote>artificial intelligence literacy</quote> and <quote>AI literacy</quote> mean the ability for humans to understand, evaluate, and effectively use artificial intelligence technologies, including understanding artificial intelligence basics and knowing what artificial intelligence can do, how artificial intelligence works, and being aware of the effects on society of artificial intelligence.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2ABFEAF7318F45A19FECFB5A824C9D6B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Ethical artificial intelligence</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>ethical artificial intelligence</quote> means the practice of designing, developing, deploying, and using artificial intelligence systems to align with ethical principles and human values, considering the potential impact on society of such systems.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

