<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE51423D92F524C5EA9E405712F814BCC" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 667 IH: Honoring the members of the Armed Forces who served in the war in Afghanistan.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 667</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250829">August 29, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000133">Mr. Van Drew</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Veterans' Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Honoring the members of the Armed Forces who served in the war in Afghanistan.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the war in Afghanistan, from October 7, 2001, to August 30, 2021, was the longest armed conflict in the history of the United States;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas more than 800,000 members of the Armed Forces deployed to Afghanistan over the course of two decades in defense of the Nation and its interests;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas 2,461 of such members laid down their lives in service, and more than 20,000 others were wounded, with scars both physical and invisible;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas thousands of members continue to live with the lasting effects of post-traumatic stress, traumatic brain injuries, and other service-connected conditions;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Gold Star families, military spouses, children, and parents bore immeasurable burdens and made enduring sacrifices in support of the Nation; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the final chapter of the conflict culminated in a terrorist attack at Abbey Gate of Hamid Karzai International Airport on August 26, 2021, in which 13 such members were killed during the evacuation of American citizens and Afghan allies: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H48F3D1AC0DB74D6FB050075AD02072EC"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H6BA8A6E2DB654BB7B23E4681FF82AAB8"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="HFF59AAD0AE614F638C1B0EE9277E31DE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>honors the courage, service, and sacrifice of all Americans who served in the war in Afghanistan;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB345D260B637439CA8DA5D83B4649C96"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">solemnly remembers the 2,461 members of the Armed Forces who gave their lives in the conflict, including the 13 who were killed on August 26, 2021, during the final days of the withdrawal;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H310B8DA9ECE642ABB70E22AA274AAF7F"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">expresses profound gratitude to all veterans of the Afghanistan war, to their families, and to the Gold Star families whose loved ones gave everything in defense of the Nation; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6488C444CCCE4481A0E28FBDA5B57F1A"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reaffirms the continuing need of the Federal Government to provide veterans of Afghanistan and their families the timely and comprehensive support, care, and recognition for their service.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

