<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-RIL25857-Y0P-D1-2T1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 370 ATS: Commending the Superdome on the occasion of its golden jubilee and its years of service to the State of Louisiana and the United States.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 370</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250802">August 2, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S389">Mr. Kennedy</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S373">Mr. Cassidy</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Commending the Superdome on the occasion of its golden jubilee and its years of service to the State of Louisiana and the United States.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, in 1966, the voters of Louisiana approved a constitutional amendment that created the Louisiana Stadium and Exposition District, paving the way for the construction of the Superdome;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 1975, the Superdome opened to the public just under 4 years after construction began;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 1978, the Superdome hosted its first Super Bowl in a game between the Dallas Cowboys and the Denver Broncos;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 1978, Muhammad Ali fought for and won the heavyweight title in a 15-round bout against Leon Spinks in front of a record-breaking indoor attendance for boxing, making Ali the first 3-time heavyweight champion of the world;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 1980, Sugar Ray Leonard defeated Roberto Durán after Durán famously uttered the concession, <quote>no más</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 1981, the Rolling Stones played in front of 87,500 attendees in what remained the largest indoor concert for more than 30 years;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Michael Jordan made a game-winning shot in the 1982 National Collegiate Athletic Association College Basketball National Championship;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Pope John Paul II visited the Superdome and addressed a youth group before enjoying a mini-Mardi Gras parade;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Frank Sinatra, Liza Minnelli, and Sammy Davis Jr. performed for the Ultimate Event Tour;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Stevie Wonder headlined the First Annual Essence Music Festival;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 1998, Tulane University completed a perfect, undefeated season with the Superdome as its home;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 1998, the Superdome housed thousands of Louisianians during Hurricane Georges;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Louisiana State University (referred to in this preamble as <quote>LSU</quote>) Tigers were victorious in the Sugar Bowl against Oklahoma, thereby making the Tigers the college football national champions of the 2003–2004 season;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2004, the Superdome was open for over a 1,000 elderly Louisianians, as well as those with special needs, during Hurricane Ivan;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2005, the Superdome housed 30,000 Louisianians during Hurricane Katrina;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Steve Gleason blocked a punt in the New Orleans Saints’ first game back in the Superdome since Hurricane Katrina, a play that continues to serve as a symbol of the city’s resilience;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2008, LSU won the National Collegiate Athletic Association College Football National Championship over Ohio State for the 2007–2008 season;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2010, shortly after a divisional round victory that took place in the New Orleans Superdome, the New Orleans Saints won the Super Bowl for the 2009–2010 season;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2015, the United States Women’s National Team defeated China in the final game for Abby Wambach who held the international goal scoring record;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas George Strait performed for the 2018 Bayou Country Superfest;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2020, LSU won the National Collegiate Athletic Association College Football National Championship, led by Joe Burrow; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2024, $560,000,000 renovations of the Superdome were completed: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id1a4165f7f476493aa19a56bdd27d4758"><enum>(1)</enum><text>commends the New Orleans Superdome, now Caesars Superdome, on the occasion of its 50th Anniversary and its years of service to the State of Louisiana and the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5843884dd2274bd1b51c5e3fdfa15d6e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the New Orleans Superdome for being home to a multitude of invaluable events whose purposes ranged from the entertainment of the people to the protection of Louisianians; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id45cc09b9089343268a262be3a4859212"><enum>(3)</enum><text>respectfully requests that the Secretary of the Senate transmit an enrolled copy of this resolution to—</text><subparagraph id="idf40762d6394f4e068554f48ce7039d44"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the owner of the New Orleans Saints of the National Football League, the Honorable Gayle M. Benson;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id71c6bcbb3eaf43a3b003a082319da17a"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the family of the late founder of the New Orleans Saints, the Honorable David F. Dixon; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idcb4ba6b4700e48c5a22cb163e6329d84"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the lead architect who oversaw the Superdome’s post-Katrina renovations, the Honorable Victor F. Trahan.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

