<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H24915A8DC2924063A129133D7CAAFD1C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4633 IH: Upending Secret Postal Shutdowns Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4633</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250723">July 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001295">Mr. Bost</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000546">Mr. Graves</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000578">Mr. LaMalfa</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 39, United States Code, to establish procedures for post offices that suspend operations due to an emergency, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H02105369C841473ABA74ACE75FA58E89" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HD8CF8AD253D94FA7A0A6335E50C4EB3A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Upending Secret Postal Shutdowns Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>USPS Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H6E18B11F42814A11A90EA6B713719EC8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Post office emergency closure procedures</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 404 of title 39, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="H345ED91109904AA396C84C2852965C5D" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="H44A74ADEE123469CB0B2CAF3E1AE740A"><enum>(f)</enum> <paragraph id="H3DEB04DDF6E948D789B65B72F540D361" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If any post office temporarily suspends operations due to an emergency—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H455C67058AC74D09B3075BC3E1D59CE2" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">on the first day of such suspension, the Postal Service shall place a sign or other physical notice of the suspension at the post office and publish a notice of the suspension on the Postal Service public website; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC3E0031BD564438A9607E294457798DC" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 5 days after the first date of such suspension, the Postal Service shall notify relevant public officials.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD3D6765949FD4E0993B46D6350D07F74" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>For purposes of paragraph (1)(B)—</text> <subparagraph id="HCC04E0CCE7194324ABB223155E257956"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the notice required under such paragraph shall include the reasons for the suspension, the interim solution for mail delivery, and expected end date of the suspension; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H03D6F977C02946C4AA8FDF83FED11931"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <quote>relevant public officials</quote> means, with respect to a post office—</text> <clause id="H7FCCCC8FB647435F9B50FA8349DA4FA5"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">each Member of the House of Representatives (including a Delegate or Resident Commissioner to Congress) representing a congressional district which includes all or part of the geographic area served by such post office;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H4513F92D950047F39CA0C3DB4A36663A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">each Senator representing a State which includes all or part of the geographic area served by such post office; and</text></clause> <clause id="HA9E6CACF054B49739FFF7F7B2E3BE1CC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the head of each unit of local government with jurisdiction over all or part of the geographic area served by such post office.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC752EE1C39164F28A19431D5F3C4CF07" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum> 
<subparagraph id="HBA2F7C6BE7A64B5AAEF15BF20762D9E1" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a suspension of operations due to an emergency lasts for 30 days, the Postal Service shall open a 30-day public review period under which individuals served by the post office and or relevant public officials may provide comments to the Postal Service.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H73C1F3A79B03407F84CEC3EFFCFF58B9" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>If a suspension of operations due to an emergency lasts for 60 days—</text> 
<clause id="HE78ABE24CAB4400E97E281BAD940DC7C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Postal Regulatory Commission shall conduct a review of the suspension; and</text></clause> <clause id="H8E00E8EF9809412E8F7F73946EFF8EA8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Postal Service shall begin the process to relocate the operations of the suspended post office, consistent with the procedures for post office relocation under this title.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEBE798B8A5E443449BEEA24803374310" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>In carrying out any relocation under subparagraph (A)(ii), the Postal Service shall—</text> <clause id="HA7F65FDCF2EF4D30BE73FACEF4169273"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">solicit input from the head of each unit local government with jurisdiction over all or part of the geographic area served by such post office; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H05706E8574634F07954440597D6ECEA2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>open a 30-day public comment review period for a new proposed location.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3095B2DC7782430CA863BC16520EABCC" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In consultation with the Postmaster General, the postmaster for each post office shall promulgate and establish an action plan in the case of an emergency suspension of post office operations.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H79B8538DC3AB4594BFFEDAF950AFCA94" indent="up1"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than January 1 of each calendar year beginning with calendar year 2026 the Postal Service shall submit a report to Congress on emergency suspensions of operations of post offices during the most recently ended calendar year. Such report shall include, for each instance of an emergency suspension of operations of a post office, the location of the post office, the duration of the emergency suspension, and the reason for the emergency suspension.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6E478C0C4C864ED9A1C9D810DBCC4E89" indent="up1"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, the term <quote>emergency</quote> means a natural disaster, termination of a lease or rental agreement, lack of qualified personnel to operate the office, irreparable damage when no suitable alternate quarters are available in the community, severe damage to, or destruction of a post office, health and safety concerns, mold, challenges to the sanctity of the mail, or the lack of adequate measures to safeguard the post office or its revenue.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

