<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H15E9FBBDA545464E8C4E28FD79984EED" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4803 IH: Easy Returns Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4803</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250729">July 29, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000310">Ms. Johnson of Texas</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require certain sellers of goods to provide return labels as part of the delivery of such goods, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD02368DFB82749B6BC39DEB29CF7836A" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H34F43250D8D8468CA4E3FA8CF3C5426B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Easy Returns Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HE8730669D70647F3AB6C386A5117ED7B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Provision of return labels</header> 
<subsection id="H5D0C4EE0A8C14959994CF04FA302B5EF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No person described in subsection (b) may sell to a consumer a physical good that requires subsequent delivery to such consumer without including, as part of such delivery, a physical label appropriately addressed for purposes of the return of such good.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H4BC0F2F8A7544E0FA8B46AE09FAC3FEC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Covered persons</header><text>A person is described in this subsection if such person employed, in the preceding year, at least 500 employees.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H222B30CDD6B24AEF8CD3AE2AD664CE14"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Limitations</header><text>Subsection (a) does not apply with respect to the sale of a physical good—</text> <paragraph id="H811BAEBCDEC64A57B18F84B5E6FA2067"><enum>(1)</enum><text>that is perishable and not typically returned by a consumer after delivery;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCEC42F0E5B5D4C59926A0DB899B77688"><enum>(2)</enum><text>that is custom made or personalized in a manner that prevents resale to another consumer if returned; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H861470D2E2B24C328BBC804B61C1B42D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>with respect to which the person selling the good offers an accessible and convenient return method other than return by means of shipping, including a scheduled, at-home pickup service that is available without cost to a consumer.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H77FF10700F92491DA6F8985F4019867F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Federal Trade Commission shall promulgate, under section 553 of title 5, United States Code, regulations to carry out this section.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H998F38608D3F4EA3AC596227122CA63A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Enforcement by Federal Trade Commission</header> <paragraph id="H380CA6CED2724BDD90063294A0759BC8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Unfair or deceptive acts or practices</header><text>A violation of this section or a regulation promulgated under this section shall be treated as a violation of a regulation under section 18(a)(1)(B) of the <act-name parsable-cite="FTCA">Federal Trade Commission Act</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/57a">15 U.S.C. 57a(a)(1)(B)</external-xref>) regarding unfair or deceptive acts or practices.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF52AABF6ABFE494A989F9FB5E978192B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Powers of Commission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal Trade Commission shall enforce this section and the regulations promulgated under this section in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though all applicable terms and provisions of the <act-name parsable-cite="FTCA">Federal Trade Commission Act</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>) were incorporated into and made a part of this section. Any person who violates this section or a regulation promulgated under this section shall be subject to the penalties and entitled to the privileges and immunities provided in the Federal Trade Commission Act.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H014C4A0A1D994525A4B6305D76A5AD72"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>This section shall apply to sales occurring on or after the date that is 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0F4B8EB5D00F4277896C3049F91AC9B2"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to limit any right or remedy available to a consumer under any other provision of law.</text></subsection> </section> </legis-body></bill>

