<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H8161701AD6544C3E926650F893703246" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 547 IH: Recognizing the significance of “National Caribbean American Heritage Month”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 547</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250626">June 26, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000476">Mr. Frost</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000309">Mr. Jackson of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001103">Mr. Hernández</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001218">Mr. McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001229">Mrs. McIver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001231">Ms. Simon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000610">Ms. Plaskett</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing the significance of <quote>National Caribbean American Heritage Month</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas people of Caribbean heritage are found in every State of the Union;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas emigration from the Caribbean to the American colonies began as early as 1619 with the arrival of indentured workers in Jamestown, Virginia;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, during the 17th, 18th, and 19th centuries, a significant number of slaves from the Caribbean were brought to the United States;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas millions of people have emigrated from the Caribbean to the United States;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the current population of people in the United States who were born in or have ancestry from the Caribbean is estimated at 13,200,000;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, like the United States, the countries of the Caribbean faced obstacles of slavery and colonialism and struggled for independence;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, also like the United States, the people of the Caribbean have diverse racial, ethnic, cultural, and religious backgrounds;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas independence movements throughout the Caribbean and the consequential establishment of independent democratic countries in the Caribbean strengthened ties between the Caribbean and the United States;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Alexander Hamilton, a Founding Father of the United States and the first Secretary of the Treasury, was born in the Caribbean;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas many influential Caribbean Americans have contributed to the rich history of the United States, including—</text>
<paragraph id="H94DDF6B5092F42ABAE055F4D1D607E15"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Jean Baptiste Pointe du Sable, the pioneer settler of Chicago;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC71F2F5EE6F44B59902B02C998164339"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Claude McKay, a poet of the Harlem Renaissance;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB6B925E01C3646789886A75DAECFA2B1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>James Weldon Johnson, the writer of the Black National Anthem;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD4A18C16925842A580C0B7D5B19012D5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Celia Cruz, the world-renowned queen of Salsa music;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HFA0D44F5D38A415EBC23D94C556ED404"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Sylvia Winter, influential feminist, writer, and human rights activist;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2F325F081A5B4907BCA5DA47E8A79A8C"><enum>(6)</enum><text>John Brown Russwurm, co-founder of Freedom’s Journal, the first Black-owned newspaper;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF584727BF17549E28F76011DF453D108"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Harry Belafonte, a legendary musician, actor, and activist;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9FFB0398E4CF41C79CCF1123163D40BB"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Sir Sidney Poitier, the first Black actor to win the Academy Award for Best Actor, film director, and diplomat;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H88D08C48B0E447AD976499A61CCE524C"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Mervyn Dymally, the first African-American Lieutenant Governor of California and first Caribbean immigrant to serve in Congress; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H461E39F21C8F45CB8EC9B651052C79B6"> <enum>(10)</enum> <text>Shirley Chisholm, the first African-American Congresswoman and first African American to run for a major party’s presidential nomination;</text>
      </paragraph></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the many influential Caribbean Americans in the history of the United States also include—</text> <paragraph id="HA7AA2E6F737D473E8D1D4AD46ED365F5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Kamala Harris, the first African-American Vice President;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9AEB28C710C541E0B9A48FA8ADF532B4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Colin Powell, the first African-American Secretary of State;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB603CAB69D744383A459EF4576AF1504"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Eric Holder, the first African-American Attorney General;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H3A33A45C2A97438185C8233ED17294FB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Karine Jean-Pierre, the first African-American White House Press Secretary;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE1F2A925CF044522B4E027374C110909"> <enum>(5)</enum> <text>Deval Patrick, first African-American Governor of Massachusetts;</text>
      </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HACA2EBC40D604CDB906E225A9BE12A9C">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
 <text>David Paterson, first legally-blind and first African-American to serve as Governor of New York State;</text>
      </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB7D70FD9BA5049F9893C2B1DDAFE5D7B">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
 <text>Wes Moore, the first African-American Governor of Maryland;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H9942972539864B698728A73EBCABAF11"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Patrick Gaspard, labor union organizer and social justice advocate;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H21553DB3B2994E8D87AEB7418E53E82D"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Earl Graves, Sr., Founder of Black Enterprise; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0B99AECF5B84475A98600B6D79716762"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Kareem Abdul Jabbar, basketball great and social activist;</text></paragraph></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Caribbean Americans have played an active role in the civil rights movement and other social and political movements in the United States;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Caribbean Americans have served with distinction in the military of the United States and include—</text>
<paragraph id="H7E43C7E1688A4E94AA693AB5CB39199E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>John Estrada, 15th Sargeant Major, United States Marine Corps;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC70B6BF8D5314B77AE0E84ABC366AA6B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Clive <quote>Tony</quote> Powell, United States Navy Command Master Chief, White House;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H13D4DDA6B4E4474DA4575ADEF3E96089"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Brigadier-General Lorna Mahlock, first Black female two-star general in the Marine Corps; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCA4B8636164A4D05BE8B1FCD620523C3"> <enum>(4)</enum> <text>Navy Captain Janice G. Smith, first African American woman to lead the Military Sealift Command Atlantic;</text>
      </paragraph></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Caribbean Americans have contributed to every aspect of United States society, including greatly to the fine arts, education, business, literature, journalism, sports, fashion, politics, government, the military, music, science, medicine, engineering, technology, and other fields in the United States;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Caribbean Americans share their culture through festivals, carnivals, music, dance, film, food, and literature, which enrich the cultural landscape of the United States;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the countries of the Caribbean are important economic partners of the United States;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the members of the Caribbean diaspora have established a solid, centuries-old track record of significant contributions to economic prosperity in the United States, as well as to the sustainable economic development of the Caribbean countries themselves, through, among others, monetary and social remittances that represent significant percentages of their GDP;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Institute of Caribbean Studies, headquartered in the District of Columbia, is widely acknowledged as the leading Caribbean American diaspora organization, that for over 30 years since its founding, has encouraged civic engagement through research, advocacy, education, and action, and is recognized as the cradle of the celebration of June as National Caribbean American Heritage Month;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Dr. Claire A. Nelson, Founding President of the Institute of Caribbean Studies, is recognized as the chief architect and driving force of the movement for the official proclamation of June as National Caribbean American Heritage Month, and has convened a network of volunteer leaders through the National Caribbean American Heritage Month Commemorative Committee to serve as a leadership community to ensure continuity of the official recognition for the month of June as Caribbean American Heritage Month;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the countries of the Caribbean represent the United States third border;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the people of the Caribbean share the hopes and aspirations of the people of the United States for peace and prosperity throughout the Western Hemisphere and the rest of the world; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, since the passage of H. Con. Res. 71 in the 109th Congress by both the Senate and the House of Representatives, a proclamation has been issued annually by the President declaring June National Caribbean American Heritage Month: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HCBC587CC7A5C40059193333944CD6ED2"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HA98F9F0D3D5F40D9A6F63BFEF03E72F0"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> 
<paragraph id="H9A66223B0CB7428694DEA240806009A2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the goals and ideals of <quote>National Caribbean American Heritage Month</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDAABDABC4EE9428E8BBBE4A43D52A3FE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>encourages the people of the United States to observe Caribbean American Heritage Month with appropriate ceremonies, celebrations, and activities; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H85F0E5C692FF4C5185960587D20F9385"><enum>(3)</enum><text>affirms that—</text> <subparagraph id="H679C928799CD40CDB6EA6988F550BE9B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the contributions of Caribbean Americans are a significant part of the history, progress, and heritage of the United States; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H83541017AF3D4FBD839BDFCDDBD53452"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the ethnic and racial diversity of the United States enriches and strengthens the Nation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

