<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ROM25158-571-D3-12W"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1347 IS: Making Education Affordable and Accessible Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1347</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250408">April 8, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S380">Mr. Peters</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S343">Mr. Boozman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to make college affordable and accessible by expanding access to dual or concurrent enrollment programs and early college high school programs.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Making Education Affordable and Accessible Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id3a5ab918c62d4de8a9d68471c0b32cfa"><enum>2.</enum><header>Dual or concurrent enrollment programs and early college high school</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part B of title VII of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1138">20 U.S.C. 1138 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="id87398b7d402f4ef6900962aeba81d186"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating section 745 as section 746;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id180c08b4dd8748c1b30f783998660f51"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 746, as redesignated by paragraph (1), by striking <quote>fiscal year 2009</quote> and inserting <quote>fiscal year 2025</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd158ba83bef44de9b2d4ad38e769bf0e"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after section 744 the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb70632c3df2041c695bb3c3f85c00b9e"><section id="id7e0bd417ff5d4cda93a9823606c56505"><enum>745.</enum><header>Dual or concurrent enrollment programs and early college high school</header><subsection id="id810833e76ebc45aca4b65c7329259cb9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of this section is to expand access for high school students to the opportunities offered in dual or concurrent enrollment programs and early college high school programs established through partnerships between local educational agencies and institutions of higher education that enable such students to earn postsecondary credits while enrolled in a public high school.</text></subsection><subsection id="id52ed9537d04940d8a1b5757f3102ef1f"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph commented="no" id="id7c007027003847fdad3aa8b25d4e260e"><enum>(1)</enum><header>ESEA definitions</header><text>The terms <term>dual or concurrent enrollment program</term>, <term>early college high school</term>, <term>high school</term>, and <term>parent</term> have the meanings given to those terms in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id8ee1c085cd0244fb9c9d4b021757777a"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible institution</header><text>The term <term>eligible institution</term> means an institution of higher education that carries out or plans to carry out a dual or concurrent enrollment program or an early college high school program.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id47fd8995a8d4452cac7a11c27fc6ec5d"><enum>(3)</enum><header>First-generation college student</header><text>The term <term>first-generation college student</term> has the meaning given the term in section 402A(h).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcd462e9a7e3147d688e80d60fc344b38"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Rural school</header><text>The term <term>rural school</term> means a school designated with a locale code of 41, 42, or 43, as determined by the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id428763350d504fc395b24e37270e531c"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Grants authorized</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd198a0f187d64521bd22af6e1478bab3"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>The Secretary may award grants to eligible institutions to carry out dual or concurrent enrollment programs or early college high school programs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id908407c9ad72412eac794418679f9d2e"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>A grant awarded under this subsection shall be for a period of not more than 5 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb432b7aed3ae4f44a5bcf28d017ad00b"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Renewal</header><text>The Secretary may renew a grant awarded to an eligible institution under this subsection if the Secretary determines that the eligible institution demonstrated sufficient positive outcomes under the program carried out under the grant, based on the reports submitted under subsection (h).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id03508645453745f5ad6168c18e6b1ed9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Application</header><text>An eligible institution that desires to receive a grant under this section shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require. Such application shall include a description of—</text><paragraph id="id2b84411fd9fb472c9b171718ea822b66"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the partnership between the eligible institution and each local educational agency involved in carrying out the dual or concurrent enrollment program or early college high school program; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3b147c2b67344aa3b66e0c90cb7ff4d6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>how the eligible institution will expand student access to a dual or concurrent enrollment program or an early college high school program, especially for students described in subsection (e).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id17d8d51d8e7245b3868d306f0589a7aa"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall give priority to eligible institutions that will use grant funds for dual or concurrent enrollment programs or early college high school programs that serve students from low-income families, students who attend rural schools, or first-generation college students.</text></subsection><subsection id="idc06d9527ee1043ec99ee3b9bd2418d74"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>An eligible institution that receives a grant under this section shall use the grant funds to carry out a dual or concurrent enrollment program or an early college high school program for students enrolled in a public high school, which may include activities such as—</text><paragraph id="id4a711abf254d4c448160b13e42b54eca"><enum>(1)</enum><text>providing educators, principals, counselors, and other school leaders with professional development activities, trainings, and certifications that enhance or enable the provision of postsecondary coursework through a dual or concurrent enrollment program or an early college high school program;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide4e2ac527e9b4baa98824200a6fbd2ab"><enum>(2)</enum><text>designing the sequence of courses for a dual or concurrent enrollment program or an early college high school program—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7e9c8aed2e584226b0088fdbcd1fce21"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to match the academic standards and rigor of a corresponding postsecondary course; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id881f53af90344c4e9a861c17f64f422e"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in collaboration with educators from the local educational agency and faculty from the eligible institution;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id59e03206a473400dacae2e2c8229317c"><enum>(3)</enum><text>establishing a course articulation process for defining and approving courses for high school and postsecondary credit or credentials for both 2-year and 4-year institutions of higher education in the State;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida10ddcb6a46943e39c52af08c7599584"><enum>(4)</enum><text>establishing outreach programs to provide elementary school and secondary school students, especially those students in middle grades, and their parents, educators, school counselors, and principals with general information about a dual or concurrent enrollment program or an early college high school program, including the eligibility requirements and academic preparation needed for the program;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc79e347ec80c4c7686b164f8f0d31e5f"><enum>(5)</enum><text>helping students meet eligibility criteria for postsecondary courses and ensuring that students understand how credits earned will transfer to institutions of higher education in the State; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd9bd3191271648ea94259cd1409e4148"><enum>(6)</enum><text>coordinating high school transition with academic calendars.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4389cee942f0486abf3f5cefebc7a58b"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Flexibility of funds</header><paragraph id="idee3257abc0cd48beb763cf1aedca54ed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2), an eligible institution that receives a grant under this section may use grant funds for any of the costs associated with carrying out a dual or concurrent enrollment program or an early college high school program, including the costs of—</text><subparagraph id="ide95851db9b484cdda5ce88c916bd315e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>tuition and fees, books, and required instructional materials for the program so that students will not be required to pay tuition or fees for postsecondary courses; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id31f1db34dd464a3980a66de156c75b62"><enum>(B)</enum><text>transportation to and from the program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9195c96242714d55a79a0a83152b4e44"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>An eligible institution may use not more than 20 percent of grant funds received under this section for transportation costs described in paragraph (1)(B).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id554f3bbb23dd4c0daeae97c97ed92eeb"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Evaluation and reports</header><paragraph id="idd4ecc6bb591941b786ca34197fa578c3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each eligible institution receiving a grant under this section shall—</text><subparagraph id="id8a5330842a0d4f7c8a97f0279c7b4f45"><enum>(A)</enum><text>conduct an independent evaluation regarding the effectiveness and rigor of the activities as carried out by such eligible institution under this section, which shall include—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7adab59355de4ac6a5ab50a4e13a228e"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">data on course-specific student enrollment; and </text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0889e67ff45b4b9d95314d32cd6ddcd9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of resulting postsecondary credits earned by students through dual or concurrent enrollment programs or early college high school programs supported under the grant that are transferred to institutions of higher education; and </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1904771425ab47989a0f168ad58705a1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>prepare and submit to the Secretary a report containing the results of the evaluation described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9148f61c56bb45248bf1f38a299226e1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The Secretary may establish additional requirements for the program evaluations required under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida723740ee04546228cdd19612b27e060"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Making Education Affordable and Accessible Act of 2025</short-title>, and every 2 years thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a summarized report that describes the findings of the evaluations conducted under paragraph (1)(A).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

