<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-GAI25471-Y8S-51-6T4"><form><distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1536</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250430">April 30, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S406">Mr. Kelly</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S391">Mr. Young</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S288">Ms. Murkowski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S354">Ms. Baldwin</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S418">Mr. Fetterman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to support the national defense and economic security of the United States by supporting vessels, ports, and shipyards of the United States and the United States maritime workforce through tax policy.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4192cc55da7543538f3780c6606f6e39"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Building Ships in America Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id54bc8ef1979640dcbdd518b5ceb7a26c"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents of this Act is as follows:</text><toc><toc-entry level="section" idref="S1">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idC4BEDD8C645E4AA4BA61387BD23E2733">Sec. 2. United States vessel investment credit.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id75601C75203F4190A7C7F2CB5319EB2C">Sec. 3. Certain payments for maritime security excluded from gross income.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id75CE5E9B353F4AB5806FA7A3F75E056D">Sec. 4. Elimination of 30-day limitation on domestic operations.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idC834C3C6EA974B69A5E7A15B4A3B479F">Sec. 5. Qualifying shipping activities.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idD52B54E8FD474E8E8AF62C9336645BFD">Sec. 6. Qualifying vessel.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id6C900C3466C046FB8B93ECA245048C53">Sec. 7. Credit for construction of shipyard facilities.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idBAB280C34D624E3E82202C0E4988D356">Sec. 8. Tax incentives relating to merchant marine capital construction funds.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id4A52ABDCF1F3432DA373B81980ADDEAD">Sec. 9. Exemption of student incentive payment agreements from gross income.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idAC1116E4506B488FBFF67BF8071112F0">Sec. 10. Maritime fuel tax parity.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id6eee4da2365f4e60b4b94adbca7f12d5">Sec. 11. Treatment of maritime prosperity zones as opportunity zones.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section><section id="idC4BEDD8C645E4AA4BA61387BD23E2733"><enum>2.</enum><header>United States vessel investment credit</header><subsection id="id39D436B13A9C48D49D64C23F97FFB5E7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subpart E of part IV of subchapter A of chapter 1 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting after section 48E the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id95CC82A7B5654235A20E954C1AFA32C3"><section id="id513B97BB8A334CCE92982546684C9E22"><enum>48F.</enum><header>United States vessel investment credit</header><subsection id="id43756C2617DF4824B912BE0195061EEA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of section 46, the United States Vessel Investment credit for any taxable year is an amount equal to the applicable percentage of any qualified investment for such taxable year with respect to any qualified vessel.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idF4B66C9C49A24E54BDEA8DC2DFC4A930"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicable percentage</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of subsection (a), the applicable percentage with respect to any qualified vessel shall be an amount equal to the sum of—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id79CF9F790EB0463CBC9330EF42CD3388"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">33 percent, plus</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6BB10BF7AFF441B48E13DD51DDCAD333"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the case of any qualified vessel for which the owner of such vessel will, as part of the agreement described in subsection (d)(1)(F) and for the duration of such agreement, obtain protection and indemnity insurance with respect to such vessel from an insurance company that is domiciled and headquartered in the United States and is an underwriter that is approved by the Maritime Administrator, 5 percent, plus</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id919262A81751457A989C251657A2CF7C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in the case of any qualified vessel which is classified by and designed in accordance with the rules of the American Bureau of Shipping or any other classification society headquartered in the United States and recognized by the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating in accordance with section 3316 of title 46, United States Code, 2 percent.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4C507D34F5444C96B32DAB44B62D2EF7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Qualified investment</header><text>For purposes of subsection (a), the qualified investment with respect to any qualified vessel is equal to the amount paid or incurred by the taxpayer in connection with the construction, repowering, or reconstruction of such vessel—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id48606A513C474425A7C3DE59865DA1BF"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in a shipyard of the United States, and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4F2EF58DC7C94AFD98B62447391BC44F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by an entity which is not a foreign entity of concern.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5ED27ED9257D42CAA3FBB774DABE5868"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Qualified vessel</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id324582A415854CB1A1802FB4921F28E2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the term <term>qualified vessel</term> means a cargo vessel—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idCB3473A2C3F2416FA1BD80178379B23F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">which is a United States flag vessel (as defined in section 1355),</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB43FDBE95D684DFCA621FD11B5A47F9B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>which, in the case of any repowering or reconstruction of such vessel, was originally constructed in the United States,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id60F86A667A494441B1465ECF48C46F0A"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">which operates in providing transportation in the United States foreign trade (as such term is defined in section 1355(a)),</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id670E698621E340FEBC2E8FF73336DEA5"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">which is not a passenger vessel, as defined in section 2101 of title 46, United States Code,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idED41826AA67D4D879BEFC1085F8EEF29"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">which is—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id97A175BF70A74C08AA5560093725F1FB"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a bulk carrier vessel,</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idECEB95B1D8AD43019E4BBBB11EA0F63C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a tanker vessel,</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8C3E91B9453746B582938EC06C548454"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a roll-on/roll-off vessel,</text></clause><clause id="id382C0A9D19734755B4DA6979032855FB"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a container vessel,</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idDEAC768338214CC48BE337E6DF3171E8"><enum>(v)</enum><text>a multi-purpose vessel,</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idF3E976717CB440809CAA8389590D0924"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>a cable vessel,</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1DC22838B29546A283F01B9B538A01A9"><enum>(vii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a heavy-lift vessel, or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id91035CED04854DADAE41F8792DB089F6"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>any other type of vessel determined appropriate by the Maritime Administrator,</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id26E86164848F41DF9AFCBF7AE5263C88"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">which, pursuant to an agreement between the taxpayer and the Maritime Administrator, operates as a vessel of the United States for a period of not less than 10 years,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4DE150E9AF2E436D80BBCAC51C265FE9" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><text>which has entered into an emergency preparedness agreement under section 53107 or 53407 of title 46, United States Code, or a contingency agreement under section 53207 of such title, or has otherwise entered into a voluntary agreement and plan of action with the Administrator of the Maritime Administration as authorized under section 708(c) of the Defense Production Act of 1950 (50 U.S.C. 4558(c)), and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idE9D30002B8184FABB0E939DD95DAE665"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the construction of which begins before January 1, 2033.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id78A48179AFAA42EEB42CC1473B2C3AAB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exclusion related to foreign entities of concern</header><text>The term <term>qualified vessel</term> shall not include a vessel which—</text><subparagraph id="id7D0C7D93E9F94DFAAFF561A59D666026"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is, or was previously, owned or operated by a foreign entity of concern,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2F5B301381664B9D9A7E5FC5EDAA68E0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>was constructed, repowered, or reconstructed in a shipyard which is owned or operated by a foreign entity of concern, or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id12BC03E2C45440D2A5901F1C1D6D1D0A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>was registered as a vessel of a foreign country of concern at any time prior to being placed in service by the taxpayer.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id36E282A4042A4D0C8B0D3F58F0EF006B"><enum>(e)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text><paragraph id="id8eb0129717b443e6b501d84a3fd402d5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Foreign country of concern</header><text>The term <term>foreign country of concern</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="idcd814cca2f8f40ac9f75e0a610352493"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a country that is a covered nation (as defined in section 4872(d) of title 10, United States Code), and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0cf042610e8d4b3d94089f54ecce716a"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any country that the Maritime Administrator, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of State, the Director of National Intelligence, and the Chair of the Federal Maritime Commission, determines to be engaged in conduct that is detrimental to the national security or foreign policy of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id0a0a6e9447c1413eb27a8e55f1140a7d"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Foreign entity</header><text>The term <term>foreign entity</term>—</text><subparagraph id="ide7dca2f4100a429ba83053f6ba9ecbc3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means—</text><clause id="idc5e3116816804daba39c0aa0f5203123"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a government of a foreign country or a foreign political party, as those terms are defined in section 1 of the Foreign Agents Registration Act of 1938, as amended (22 U.S.C. 611),</text></clause><clause id="id47e9ef8c5e1f4ab7bd217707795ce68b"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a natural person who is not a lawful permanent resident of the United States, a citizen of the United States, or any other protected individual (as such term is defined in section 274B(a)(3) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (8 U.S.C. 1324b(a)(3))), or</text></clause><clause id="id5641284180a045b6a1fe20b6459c0f35"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a partnership, association, corporation, organization, or other combination of persons organized under the laws of or having its principal place of business in a foreign country, and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id169cd1a30fae455ebe883508882bc1a7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes—</text><clause id="id0458bc715ce94a049b631eebcc7f2406"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any person (including an owner or operator of a vessel) owned by, controlled by, or subject to the direction of an entity listed in subparagraph (A),</text></clause><clause id="id3adb764e696b448a8afe917aa7c95516"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any person, wherever located, who acts as an agent, representative, or employee of an entity listed in subparagraph (A),</text></clause><clause id="idb9910d0629614eeb8eeef8fb4671fa4f"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any person who acts in any other capacity at the order, request, or under the direction or control, of an entity listed in subparagraph (A), or of a person whose activities are directly or indirectly supervised, directed, controlled, financed, or subsidized in whole or in major part by an entity listed in subparagraph (A),</text></clause><clause id="id8ad45872dd004835904814b1a5f9e503"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>any person who directly or indirectly through any contract, arrangement, understanding, relationship, or otherwise, owns 25 percent or more of the equity interests of an entity listed in subparagraph (A),</text></clause><clause id="idf9eb5a0b38584b74877f1e4166005fb2"><enum>(v)</enum><text>any person with significant responsibility to control, manage, or direct an entity listed in subparagraph (A),</text></clause><clause id="id6f3865eb580d4252a94ab486781cb6c1"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>any person, wherever located, who is a citizen or resident of a country controlled by an entity listed in subparagraph (A), or</text></clause><clause id="id06607cb610bb4881b351e9c5a70b190e"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>any corporation, partnership, association, or other organization organized under the laws of a country controlled by an entity listed in subparagraph (A).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id76601bbad0c848159fa4a31e3ef56468"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Foreign entity of concern</header><text>The term <term>foreign entity of concern</term> means any foreign entity that is—</text><subparagraph id="idd4e5c933a64b49ca93686c0a20a44b5a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>designated as a foreign terrorist organization by the Secretary of State under section 219 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (8 U.S.C. 1189),</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb8e71567ddc547deabac52c2177f4056"><enum>(B)</enum><text>included on the list of specially designated nationals and blocked persons maintained by the Office of Foreign Assets Control of the Department of the Treasury,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf8f2865b3b224f00a764e0036b237967"><enum>(C)</enum><text>owned by, controlled by, or subject to the jurisdiction or direction of a government of a foreign country of concern,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1352c0d578b14540b088f2df90fbd316"><enum>(D)</enum><text>alleged by the Attorney General to have been involved in activities for which a conviction was obtained under—</text><clause id="id55d33607004a42e18d50f2e4d1207d4a"><enum>(i)</enum><text>chapter 37 of title 18, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Espionage Act</quote>) (18 U.S.C. 792 et seq.),</text></clause><clause id="ide00ca2f976c9489fbfd4b4e11dbddc3e"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>section 951 or 1030 of title 18, United States Code,</text></clause><clause id="id21ae1496fc554b59a7857a7e71121816"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>chapter 90 of title 18, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Economic Espionage Act of 1996</quote>),</text></clause><clause id="idbe3aecfa55c24d04b28d9111a334d28d"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the Arms Export Control Act (22 U.S.C. 2751 et seq.),</text></clause><clause id="idcdc3498536b64964b69e93775d9a876b"><enum>(v)</enum><text>section 224, 225, 226, 227, or 236 of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 (42 U.S.C. 2274, 2275, 2276, 2277, and 2284),</text></clause><clause id="iddf556e20fda04e25897d645827536a8e"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 (50 U.S.C. 4801 et seq.), or</text></clause><clause id="id00da7e3625d14e269977384cc86f2148"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.),</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3e3a1dae0bb4479cbc40d6b25c53aa5c"><enum>(E)</enum><text>designated by the Federal Maritime Commission as a controlled carrier under chapter 407 of title 46, United States Code,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd13ee8cb5c124268a7d00311969209a3"><enum>(F)</enum><text>found by the Federal Maritime Commission to be practicing unfavorable conditions in foreign trade under chapter 421 or 423 of title 46, United States Code, or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id26d42599bd8d4b5cb1d18250f82499f6"><enum>(G)</enum><text>determined by the Maritime Administrator, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of State, the Director of National Intelligence, and the Chair of the Federal Maritime Commission, to be engaged in unauthorized conduct that is detrimental to the national security or foreign policy of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8275C569C01049B6A663652A938AC9EC"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Certain progress expenditure rules made applicable</header><text>Rules similar to the rules of subsections (c)(4) and (d) of section 46 (as in effect on the day before the date of the enactment of the Revenue Reconciliation Act of 1990) shall apply for purposes of subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id42B178CF14D54727BAA662B7C12E8576"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in consultation with the Maritime Administrator, shall issue such regulations or other guidance as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section, including any regulations or guidance which may be necessary or appropriate to recapture the benefit of any credit determined under this section with respect to any qualified vessel, or any increase in the applicable percentage under subsection (b) with respect to any qualified vessel, in the case of any taxpayer which fails to comply with the terms of the agreement described in subsection (d)(1)(F) with respect to such qualified vessel.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="id48EB780B40FC4131B90D368F2F15AE24"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><paragraph id="idCE23DE052127401CAF8657861AA7B100"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Section 46 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as amended by section 13702(b)(1) of Public Law 117–169, is amended—</text><subparagraph id="id43F1FDD7D35B442AB3E7C366682D6189"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (6), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8FC8D79001244A66A5A629F98F9AECB6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (7), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>, and</quote>, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1D3551B17547493F93A19DAB5257AB69"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id49656D52E94D461795924A3F64FC73A1"><paragraph id="idDB804E47F7734BAEA7F989ECE5493378"><enum>(8)</enum><text>the United States Vessel Investment credit.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id945031479138467784B91D041285CBC5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Section 49(a)(1)(C) of such Code, as amended by section 13702(b)(2) of Public Law 117–169, is amended—</text><subparagraph id="idF85EDA0F1B4A4290B18BF89C3CEB15DC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in clause (vii), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8C51422EF2B84E2895E9935936189DF2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in clause (viii), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>, and</quote>, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7E11BB7FE4404C47A38E54108F8AE411"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idEF6A16271D264D04BB515F5451F6833D"><clause id="id3DB24053A607464FBE631DF80ACB6DB4"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>with respect to any qualified vessel (as defined in section 48F(d)), the portion of the basis of such vessel attributable to amounts paid or incurred by the taxpayer in connection with the construction, repowering, or reconstruction of such vessel.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id596E9D630BDA4AE8BD23FB7F1ABD3A6A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The table of sections for subpart E of part IV of subchapter A of chapter 1 of such Code is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 48E the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7DF71CE2250D4A0FB7328A7AB70A82AB"><toc><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">Sec. 48F. United States Vessel Investment credit.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
        id="id568F172AAC304C46AD5D8BE89F09B639">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Recapture for failure To operate as a vessel of
          the United States</header>
        <text>Section 50(a) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended—</text>
        <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
          id="idE50E4210910F4B608516339703CF0290">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (4), by striking <quote>or any
              applicable transaction to which paragraph (3)(A) applies</quote> and inserting
              <quote>any applicable transaction to which paragraph (3)(A) applies, or any violation
              to which paragraph (6)(A) applies</quote>,</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
          id="id89053A4DDF124F96AE6771B3AA0003FE">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating paragraph (6) as paragraph
            (7),</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
          id="id29882D9366C849BBA3919994A110C0D7">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>by inserting after paragraph (5) the following new paragraph:</text>
          <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline"
            id="id2B200EBB5AC04C7FAF0E02C6E9F3A994">
            <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
              id="id0A06044F2380459F88401624FAF81264">
              <enum>(6)</enum>
              <header>Failure to operate qualified vessel as a vessel of the United States</header>
              <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                id="id6E03B191ACB847EAA144EB583DA65A17">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
                <header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header>
                <text>If an applicable taxpayer violates any of the requirements of the agreement
                  described in section 48F(d)(1)(F) during the duration of such agreement with
                  respect to any investment credit property which is eligible for the United States
                  Vessel Investment credit under section 48F(a), then the tax under this chapter for
                  the taxable year in which such violation occurs shall be increased by 100 percent
                  of the aggregate decrease in the credits allowed under section 38 for all prior
                  taxable years which would have resulted solely from reducing to zero any credit
                  determined under section 46 which is attributable to the United States Vessel
                  Investment credit under section 48F(a) with respect to such property.</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                id="id205726F81A1147478A1E7634087CBED5">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
                <header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Exception</header>
                <text>Subparagraph (A) shall not apply if the applicable taxpayer demonstrates to
                  the satisfaction of the Secretary and the Maritime Administrator that the taxpayer
                  is in compliance with the agreement described in section 48F(d)(1)(F) within 30
                  days of a determination and notice by the Secretary.</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                id="id5CA42AD037B44DB2BAFB23CFE55132FF">
                <enum>(C)</enum>
                <header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Regulations and guidance</header>
                <text>The Secretary shall issue such regulations or other guidance as the Secretary
                  determines necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this paragraph,
                  including regulations or other guidance which provide for requirements for
                  recordkeeping or information reporting for purposes of administering the
                  requirements of this paragraph.</text>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <after-quoted-block>, and</after-quoted-block>
          </quoted-block>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
          id="id7939416E2252410A8EC76B21C940D7F1">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>in paragraph (7) (as redesignated by paragraph (2))—</text>
          <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
            id="id75D2969A4F834CD29DDFC4F798FE388C">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>or
                (3)</quote> and inserting <quote>(3), or (4)</quote>, and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
            id="id7272A78705DE4D04B94C12EF75335F8B">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking subparagraph (E) and inserting the
              following:</text>
            <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline"
              id="id21C81B2299254A7991BE2B3B26163A4B">
              <subparagraph id="id0944028D9EC249D29B7F9D108B087971">
                <enum>(E)</enum>
                <header>Applicable taxpayer</header>
                <text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>applicable taxpayer</term>
                  means any taxpayer who has been allowed—</text>
                <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                  id="id00B8663936A2411E9429EE2EC1177075">
                  <enum>(i)</enum>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for purposes of paragraph (3), a credit
                    under section 48D(a) for any prior taxable year, or</text>
                </clause>
                <clause id="id840F7132F44746B5ACEA137C3F56F73D">
                  <enum>(ii)</enum>
                  <text>for purposes of paragraph (6), a credit under section 48F(a) for any prior
                    taxable year.</text>
                </clause>
              </subparagraph>
              <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
            </quoted-block>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id409A120885A74A2594EBE6C9660AAFE0"><enum>(d)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Elective payment and transfer of credit</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idEA81FF404E48494883D7357BD57E1367"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Elective payment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 6417 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6A91E70DB2F54370A990827F506F8FFE"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (b), by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id32C48CFAD34A45F59182D8DA967C65C2"><paragraph id="id1EA86110392B44CFAC05446BE93DB4C4"><enum>(13)</enum><text>The United States Vessel Investment credit under section 48F.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>, and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD687953D4B5D470CB1C66AFF88664E59"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (d)(1)—</text><clause id="id51C90ECC4A044B888366FE05B69B8963"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (E), by striking <quote>(C), or (D)</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>(C), (D), or (E)</quote>,</text></clause><clause id="id16C07D7B9F3E450686390CDB62C59A61"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (E) (as amended by clause (i)) as subparagraph (F), and</text></clause><clause id="id02AF9AAC75A64ED7AA8E5A93C6B9D5A1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (D) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id83D6502BC66B4EDE801A954922477ABC"><subparagraph id="id9270CA1E4F3B494C828A874CB7E4E0E5"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Election with respect to United States vessel investment credit</header><text>If a taxpayer other than an entity described in subparagraph (A) makes an election under this subparagraph with respect to any taxable year in which such taxpayer has made a qualified investment with respect to any qualified vessel (as defined in section 48F), such taxpayer shall be treated as an applicable entity for purposes of this section for such taxable year, but only with respect to the credit described in subsection (b)(13).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2520C446864A46C897456E4AECA64BDF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Transfer</header><text>Section 6418(f)(1)(A) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id219287B27B964B3FB4EF8DB54E674396"><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idC25BE0846ACD49B3AC3C102CC29D73B9"><enum>(xii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States Vessel Investment credit under section 48F.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idD398538408FD4254A0F9DCDD0873245B"><enum>(e)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Exception relating to alternative tax on qualifying shipping activities</header><text>Section 1357(c) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idBC6128C223CE458FAB773F219E64A6FE"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>paragraph (2)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraph (2) or (4)</quote>, and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4B0229D8BFA1479BB3F3484543C8FC85"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4ED3135FEBF04F88AE56A2FD8505D8D5"><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7E1F7823736346658A8899AFEFA80747"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Exception for United States vessel investment credit</header><text>Paragraph (1) shall not apply with respect to any credit allowed to the taxpayer under section 48F.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id11A2897A06A646FBA277B2A6A0DE5166"><enum>(f)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to property placed in service after December 31, 2025.</text></subsection></section><section id="id75601C75203F4190A7C7F2CB5319EB2C"><enum>3.</enum><header>Certain payments for maritime security excluded from gross income</header><subsection id="idF528A2C8812E475BACB09F7F3116FA52"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Part III of subchapter B of chapter 1 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting after section 139I the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id881E2E59C4544CD2A7AE83C8D8498103"><section id="id40E3A74AEDE54606A505FCA01EF257A1"><enum>139J.</enum><header>Maritime security payments</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB397994AE2504DDAA586CD2F279F6ECE"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Gross income shall not include any payment made pursuant to—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idDDC50A3AF8A846A88DC95F49C68B8396"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">section 53106 of title 46, United States Code,</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2AA6A74573B24CA1B49E4FD7CB45095D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">section 53206 of such title,</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idAB949CA971A34B46B52F0752D130BE90"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">section 53406 of such title,</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3CDC88F18106406B825F2565EC2E9537"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">section 54101 of such title, or</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id21F33EFB4C1F441AB4D7749C003C394C"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">section 54301 of such title.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id17AC40F69BDF4B849646935AF6FFA23E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Denial of double benefit</header><text>No deduction or credit shall be allowed for, or by reason of, any expenditure to the extent of the amount excluded under subsection (a) for any payment which was provided with respect to such expenditure. The adjusted basis of any property shall be reduced by the amount excluded under subsection (a) which was provided with respect to such property.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idDC89DA95880A41C7848AC543C98B3D88"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for part III of subchapter B of chapter 1 of such Code is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 139I the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="id62F270452E2E4AA1A19FE7EB4CDD8B9E"><toc><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 139J. Maritime security payments.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8D0735FA36FB44DAA381A9885A98C97C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="id75CE5E9B353F4AB5806FA7A3F75E056D"><enum>4.</enum><header>Elimination of 30-day limitation on domestic operations</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0CBFEDF672894D86A43E0AE800DC6857"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1355 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idAAD3A89AF768410ABED332E4781E5509"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (f), by striking paragraph (4), and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idCF53EEEFB5B647598425A4C4476627D3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (g)(2), by striking subparagraph (D).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id93352AEBF8A64B048B07CC6A8D1458FE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="idC834C3C6EA974B69A5E7A15B4A3B479F"><enum>5.</enum><header>Qualifying shipping activities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1356(b) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (relating to qualifying shipping activities) is amended by striking <quote>activities in operating</quote> and inserting <quote>the carriage of goods (as defined in section 1 of the Carriage of Goods by Sea Act (46 U.S.C. 30701 note)) by</quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="idD52B54E8FD474E8E8AF62C9336645BFD"><enum>6.</enum><header>Qualifying vessel</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1355(a) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id708F4F1044EC47018F615D8272B35206"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking paragraph (4) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idAB8E82731FCD4095B9593A327EF00AF1"><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idD8636FC6DD1849ECB576BAC736438315"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Qualifying vessel</header><text>The term <term>qualifying vessel</term> means a vessel which is—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id19F5CE8FEFD24BAEB0A51AA2CD8FC98A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">self-propelled (or a combination self-propelled and non-self-propelled),</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idAB657FCDCA684ED1B90AC83A4C5AD245"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a United States flag vessel or a United States-owned foreign flag vessel,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id98590F43F5E945D8A6F010AA28698212"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">either—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7bda6728237040b5b544b64bca7bb6bb"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a vessel designed primarily for use on the high seas which has a draft of more than 12 feet, or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id453b1dc6a49b4865a344e3df3888e38f"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not less than 6,000 deadweight tons, and </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1C325797D5A248459274E6038128D0AA"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">used exclusively in the United States foreign trade during the period that the election under this subchapter is in effect.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>, and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="id5AF0131C2EB24EE4A0AC3BCCF4C27F61"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id73AEA8DD99BF406E8A61B6688E174E75"><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idD7F58FB51F6447D68A5BBE4073B418D2"><enum>(8)</enum><header>United States-owned foreign flag vessel</header><text>The term <term>United States-owned foreign flag vessel</term> means any vessel which—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idF9E131059EDC4923AE6957C4031BDC5F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is documented under the laws of a country (other than the United States) or a foreign registry which is not a foreign country of concern (as defined in section 48F(e)),</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id941A5BDEF28C42D9AE8A19E223368038"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is owned by a person which—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7CA45080F9824C0F9B793776C58DC56F"><enum>(i)</enum><subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id3049E384E9E4476DB8EF393F78FF6F4B"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is a citizen of the United States (as determined under section 50501 of title 46, United States Code), or</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="idBF45F10E0CB340F282C6558AADB4BD4B"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is controlled (within the meaning of section 954(d)(3)) by a citizen of the United States (as so determined), and</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id544A120F94AA4D4689582E03C1B81E21"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">owns a fleet of United States flag vessels, </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc19d7202301745e9a14208b2deb1d853"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is strategically and commercially managed from within the United States, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idcad04b2d81ca4ac99aa126ac292a4e50"><enum>(D)</enum><text>has entered into an emergency preparedness agreement under section 53107 or 53407 of title 46, United States Code, or a contingency agreement under section 53207 of such title, or has otherwise entered into a voluntary agreement and plan of action with the Maritime Administrator as authorized under section 708(c) of the Defense Production Act of 1950 (50 U.S.C. 4558(c)).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="id6C900C3466C046FB8B93ECA245048C53"><enum>7.</enum><header>Credit for construction of shipyard facilities</header><subsection id="idBF8805E973AD401AA605FCD555E0835F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subpart E of part IV of subchapter A of chapter 1 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as amended by section 2(a), is amended by inserting after section 48F the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8342F2B56DEE438ABE2306C58A1A30DE"><section id="idC2ACFD8D385C40F79BDEAF4FCB493F29"><enum>48G.</enum><header>Credit for construction of shipyard facilities</header><subsection id="id1BE14494FA404159AD24EB6CBDA5C784"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of section 46, the shipyard investment tax credit for any taxable year is an amount equal to 25 percent of the qualified investment for such taxable year with respect to any qualified shipyard facility of a taxpayer described in section 48D(c)(1).</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB4101E36E4484165A9E4D0200EC648B6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Qualified investment</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idDCA319EE40374E849A7D4B3201F1449B"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>For purposes of subsection (a), the qualified investment with respect to any qualified shipyard facility for any taxable year is the basis of any qualified property placed in service by the taxpayer during such taxable year which is part of a qualified shipyard facility.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id976694541D0D492097492DB28E95CD27"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualified property</header><text>The term <term>qualified property</term> shall have the same meaning given such term in section 48D(b)(2), except that subparagraph (A)(iv) of such section shall be applied by substituting <quote>qualified shipyard facility</quote> for <quote>advanced manufacturing facility</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id86D33A921D394DA9A9CA8AC4D260BD02"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Qualified shipyard facility</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>qualified shipyard facility</term> means a facility—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id99029F87A66147569F02C4E1359EA06C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">which is located within the United States (including any territory or possession of the United States), and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id46F9E9EB64ED480CB0E3E49C1524CFA1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for which the primary purpose is—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id73F44C33ABEB4510B4F464412D32B01C"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">constructing or repairing commercial or military oceangoing vessels,</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id30FBE67127DB41AABA6A255DFA44598B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>manufacturing components which are critical (as determined by the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of the Navy and the Maritime Administrator) to the operation of commercial or military oceangoing vessels, or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id841ABFE04C0D4E5DB1FAFBFEA3B68420"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">manufacturing equipment which is used to produce or repair commercial or military oceangoing vessels.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id38FBCD82D8464D4787BB4B6286366319"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Certain progress expenditure rules made applicable</header><text>Rules similar to the rules of subsections (c)(4) and (d) of section 46 (as in effect on the day before the date of the enactment of the Revenue Reconciliation Act of 1990) shall apply for purposes of subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idF1C4F19FBFF54DF3BF21CCC1B89BDBA3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Denial of double benefit</header><text>This section shall not apply to any property placed in service by the taxpayer during the taxable year if a credit was allowed under section 48F to such taxpayer during such taxable year.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id82F62E46762F4BA0A0B26ECF4D61FFAF"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall issue such regulations or other guidance as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id356E2DAE845B42CF864290369A7EE34C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Termination of credit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The credit allowed under this section shall not apply to property placed in service after December 31, 2032.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="idB864D568CCBB40B2944DE66B3275E8EA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><paragraph id="id503812612A8D4FE19B0A2C60D0E82BC6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Section 46 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as amended by section 2(b)(1), is amended—</text><subparagraph id="idC33E462A41124A81B346889B51A122A0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (7), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idF081DCEAC65F4AB3A4C82788EC7B2BA8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (8), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>, and</quote>, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id719D6FB076624B7DA9A1F5CA8C5B30F7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idC3850033D13C4F16906EBE46410220F1"><paragraph id="idF4E73DB513C741CFBDCEE25280AB72F9"><enum>(9)</enum><text>the shipyard investment tax credit.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idCE63558DC013439EA67960C60DBB1153"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Section 49(a)(1)(C) of such Code, as amended by section 2(b)(2), is amended—</text><subparagraph id="id5072574CED7D403CB34118748A2CB51C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in clause (viii), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5324D74E86A5411D922CB1668C8A2445"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in clause (ix), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>, and</quote>, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id52E7B4ED27DA42BD9B72C81F6544586E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2811115167EE489A98AD068666F7B1F7"><clause id="idEF4FD6ADA7F44D72ACDB41849BC6B4D4"><enum>(x)</enum><text>the basis of any qualified property (as defined in subsection (b)(2) of section 48G) which is part of a qualified shipyard facility (as defined in subsection (b)(3) of such section).</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idA4469B838F134899A4916D8B8D68E062"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Section 50(a)(2)(E) of such Code, as amended by section 13702(b) of Public Law 117–169, is amended by striking <quote>or 48E(e)</quote> and inserting <quote>48E(e), or 48G(b)(4)</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id023BDBA0E8CC44F09013401E5E221CDA"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The table of sections for subpart E of part IV of subchapter A of chapter 1 of such Code, as amended by section 2(b)(3), is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 48F the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7A8470FD9D9E4AF09B9B56A00C317971"><toc><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">Sec. 48G. Shipyard investment tax credit.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idAFFBF9FFA30144549BF94514B58B00A6"><enum>(c)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Elective payment and transfer of credit</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id41FB46BB80AF41D1AF26C3C1F4065930"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Elective payment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 6417 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as amended by section 2, is amended—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idA0EA17BE6DDF418B8C4F2AE07C43517D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (b), by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id96F98E739B294E2394E726923796524A"><paragraph id="id06F8C1FDD3604BD9AF4AE5BE5A7D27A8"><enum>(14)</enum><text>The shipyard investment tax credit under section 48G.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>, and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB118E2B7166441F38822332317E90BB7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (d)(1)—</text><clause id="id618C1EB030D04667B60CFFDD2EDF46E8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (F), by striking <quote>(D), or (E)</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>(D), (E), or (F)</quote>,</text></clause><clause id="id213724EC82F54BB682995D1DBCD04706"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (F) (as amended by clause (i)) as subparagraph (G), and</text></clause><clause id="id4C4CFF66004B436181A7F803E81301FF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (E) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4CBCE23BE63B4FD49682344376AD8825"><subparagraph id="idC6E52E5B1C9F485A9FA2188CF9672BF8"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Election with respect to the shipyard investment tax credit</header><text>If a taxpayer other than an entity described in subparagraph (A) makes an election under this subparagraph with respect to any taxable year in which such taxpayer has placed in service any qualified property which is part of a qualified shipyard facility (as defined in section 48G), such taxpayer shall be treated as an applicable entity for purposes of this section for such taxable year, but only with respect to the credit described in subsection (b)(14).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id752D02B95D854D5899A25846AE8FD7C6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Transfer</header><text>Section 6418(f)(1)(A) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as amended by section 2, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idF80B59DAA8114A36B30813922B99DAE2"><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id56D7FA6E633448B4A3723219B9106733"><enum>(xiii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The shipyard investment tax credit under section 48G.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idA2DD5B07C11C4AB3A1B2DEBC1D446B42"><enum>(d)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Exception relating to alternative tax on qualifying shipping activities</header><text>Paragraph (4) of section 1357(c) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, section 2(e), is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idBDF6ED63B9094959825FE1C56B2B93F2"><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idBA2AFB276C334BEDB17E727FE999B14C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Exception for United States vessel investment credit and shipyard investment tax credit</header><text>Paragraph (1) shall not apply with respect to any credit allowed to the taxpayer under section 48F or 48G.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2AD3BAD943474CBEA8DE86A087018B61"><enum>(e)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to property placed in service after December 31, 2025.</text></subsection></section><section id="idBAB280C34D624E3E82202C0E4988D356"><enum>8.</enum><header>Tax incentives relating to merchant marine capital construction funds</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idF47E7158E0A14806BD7E8157F75B5DF6"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>Section 7518 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id65E7E596BF724FFF9F6D7798F2AF95B0"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (a)—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idF9140CBBEFEA48F78E2100EFB389DCFA"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking paragraph (1) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1DDC29018C5E471CA3E5C2E86774C70A"><paragraph id="idF3628019D5C94C35B7CBC0A7110893A1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The amount deposited in a fund established under chapter 535 of title 46 of the United States Code (hereinafter in this section referred to as a <term>capital construction fund</term>) for a taxable year may not exceed the amount specified in the agreement under section 53503(a) of such title, which shall be an amount that is related to a commitment to invest the revenue from the capital construction fund into funding the construction of new vessels or funding cargo handling equipment.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>,</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE9ADE0507DC344C4971BE185A93EE7FA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>paragraph (1)(B)</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>paragraph (1)</quote>, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0E1F177BF0974ABDAAAE361FFEFBDC4C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7A0438F418924FEF9C1AE6050F9001ED"><paragraph commented="no" id="idBE31D1B6EF92429BB4405434F3DFEFD0"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Revenue</header><text>For the purposes of paragraph (1), the revenue from the capital construction fund may include—</text><subparagraph id="id06C4AEA7AE6D419AA36FCF27AE9A1F81"><enum>(A)</enum><text>income attributable to the operation of any agreement vessel in foreign commerce or domestic trade or fisheries or the operation of a marine terminal in the United States,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7BC825AEB52A4F9294AF9572D5739324"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the net proceeds from the disposition of an agreement vessel or cargo handling equipment or insurance or indemnity attributable to the vessel or cargo handling equipment,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4A1F747BAB954200B6C61A9F75D5A780"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the receipts from the investment or reinvestment of amounts held in the fund, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idAB21917B05764CF286CD4C28D819E6CE"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the amount allowable as a deduction under section 167 for the taxable year with respect to the agreement vessels or cargo handling equipment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>,</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1E1602B2BE3D44EE99BD2D6CC45507C9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(2), by striking <quote>Amounts in any capital construction fund</quote> and all that follows through <quote>(not in excess of 60 percent)</quote> and inserting <quote>An agreed percentage</quote>,</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id273A127A51D444EDA7D97741D7192B09"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (e)—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9D81874D5E404923B714873CBA85E527"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking paragraph (1) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6EFBB46E62574A11841866F0E7F22ACF"><paragraph id="idC1331AA41F294493959D7FD4C33B8F9D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A qualified withdrawal from the fund is one made in accordance with the terms of the agreement but only if it is for—</text><subparagraph id="id8FDE5FD5E4A64A2C8554A4FA25FEAF14"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the acquisition, construction, repowering, or reconstruction of—</text><clause id="id0411ECAAECEB4F19A0C7FB3524CF25C4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a qualified vessel or a barge or container that is part of the complement of a qualified vessel, or</text></clause><clause id="id9527CE1AA8A340F1B390F5F6929ECD5E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>cargo handling equipment, or</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB28A45405D994DC9BD627D0C6852F947"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the payment of the principal on indebtedness incurred in the acquisition, construction, repowering, or reconstruction of—</text><clause id="id7AE7696E6FAC4FDFBEC79B0186AEFFDD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a qualified vessel or a barge or container that is part of the complement of a qualified vessel, or</text></clause><clause id="idA476637C0A60469FAA371FFEA8B03380"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>cargo handling equipment.</text></clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">Except to the extent provided in regulations prescribed by the Secretary, subparagraph (A), and so much of subparagraph (B) as relates only to barges and containers, shall apply only with respect to barges and containers constructed in the United States.</continuation-text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>,</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idCA2D867DEAE240FEAE398EE4A4E00EE4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (2) as paragraph (4), and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC412BC984FE5452BB1E3B394C28C4C25"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (1) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id91881F4BCCA24686B45728BB751C8DE8"><paragraph id="idB2B09D8A9BBF410F8DB8D2EE0B1A5679"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Fully automated cargo handling equipment</header><text>No withdrawals may be made from a capital construction fund to purchase fully automated cargo handling equipment that is remotely operated or remotely monitored with or without the exercise of human intervention or control, if the Secretary determines such equipment would result in a net loss of jobs within a marine terminal.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idE30D3E7C33E345ECB396C33932A2D491"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Prohibition on people's republic of china cranes</header><text>No withdrawals may be made from a capital construction fund to purchase cranes manufactured in the People's Republic of China.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>,</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idA87025E2F8E74349BA52D90EB269AE96"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (f)—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0823936B9554454F80B0A8F7AE452960"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (2), by inserting <quote>cargo handling equipment,</quote> after <quote>barge,</quote> both places the term appears,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3DF4B01764D142F496088B669F8BCEC5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by inserting <quote>cargo handling equipment,</quote> after <quote>barge,</quote> both places the term appears, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0332D9115B1C40718BC5BD690C4DD36E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by inserting <quote>cargo handling equipment,</quote> after <quote>barges,</quote>,</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idECB9A570F2A24CC3AFD68AD072A7B11A"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (g)—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id49106B2E55D54A4895A36E6418416B62"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the flush matter at the end of paragraph (2), by inserting <quote>cargo handling equipment,</quote> after <quote>advanced</quote>, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id373ADC8396B1434D93D5DE10822F812B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (5)(A)—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idEC315648DADA497F84A2E1027D9EDB68"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="tax">25 years</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="tax">15 years</header-in-text></quote>,</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7987BECCE3474116A6CD10F28DE378FA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>26th, 27th, 28th, 29th, or 30th taxable year</quote> and inserting <quote>following specified taxable year</quote>, and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idA5014D55E8FC4F30B98D89E16D21086F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by striking the table contained therein and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idA0E39FD5B6F9497E801A7EB7A432F708"><table table-type="Leaderwork" table-template-name="Tax (No Calculation) 1 text, 1 num (9 chars) and extra long heads" align-to-level="section" frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0" line-rules="no-gen" rule-weights="0.0.0.0.0.0"><tgroup cols="2" rowsep="0"><colspec coldef="txt" colname="column1" min-data-value="55" colwidth="275pts"/><colspec align="justify" coldef="fig" colname="column2" min-data-value="9" colwidth="138.94pt"/><thead><row><entry align="left" morerows="0" namest="column1" colname="column1"><bold>If the amount remains in the fund at the close of the-</bold></entry><entry align="justify" morerows="0" namest="column2" colname="column2"><bold>The applicable percentage is-</bold></entry></row></thead><tbody><row><entry align="left" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr" colname="column1">16th taxable year</entry><entry align="right" rowsep="0" colname="column2">20 percent</entry></row><row><entry align="left" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr" colname="column1">17th taxable year</entry><entry align="right" rowsep="0" colname="column2">40 percent</entry></row><row><entry align="left" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr" colname="column1">18th taxable year</entry><entry align="right" rowsep="0" colname="column2">60 percent</entry></row><row><entry align="left" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr" colname="column1">19th taxable year</entry><entry align="right" rowsep="0" colname="column2">80 percent</entry></row><row><entry align="left" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr" colname="column1">20th taxable year</entry><entry align="right" rowsep="0" colname="column2">100 percent</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table><after-quoted-block>, and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1178F414DA054F2997DF8B9A00BAB7B6"><enum>(6)</enum><text>in subsection (i), by striking <quote>as in effect on the date of the enactment of this section</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="idF7D08F9A6F084BDBAC36ADCC50A1BA33"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2025.</text></subsection></section><section id="id4A52ABDCF1F3432DA373B81980ADDEAD"><enum>9.</enum><header>Exemption of student incentive payment agreements from gross income</header><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB683E91FC0AA441DBD64097AD5D630EB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Part III of subchapter B of chapter 1 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as amended by section 3, is further amended by inserting after section 139J the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2BAB53B829964DF8B28B30AB7BC0DB03"><section id="id94CC04E5AA8D4B9BA115C537D7A70D0E"><enum>139K.</enum><header>Student incentive payment agreements</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In the case of an individual who has entered into an agreement described in section 51509 of title 46, United States Code, gross income does not include any student incentive payments made to such individual pursuant to such agreement.</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="id17FA230466574F23B37BA4C0CCDC417A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for part III of subchapter B of chapter 1 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as amended by section 3, is further amended by inserting after the item relating to section 139J the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id89FC30E0B65144028CEE409B4E926D03"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 139K. Student incentive payment agreements.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="id363CC8E34AAF4EA5A73093811A4D3C63"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply with respect to payments made after December 31, 2025.</text></subsection></section><section section-type="subsequent-section" id="idAC1116E4506B488FBFF67BF8071112F0"><enum>10.</enum><header>Maritime fuel tax parity</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8f81b4a304664866b7cd80759f1de08f"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 4041(g) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new sentence: <quote>For purposes of subsection (a)(2), the exemption under paragraph (1) shall also apply to fuel sold for use or used by a vessel which is both described in section 4042(c)(1) and actually engaged in trade between the Atlantic or Pacific ports of the United States (including any territory or possession of the United States).</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddd4426115ad945f8b64e2acb9bd70c93"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by this section shall apply to fuel sold for use or used after December 31, 2025.</text></subsection></section><section section-type="subsequent-section" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6eee4da2365f4e60b4b94adbca7f12d5"><enum>11.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Treatment of maritime prosperity zones as opportunity zones</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id74CD26E64004477098AF0B0901F5DE4D"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter Z of chapter 1 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB86974DAB2EA4F8A883C58247D3F236B"><section id="id673F95ED9392415EB7B9EC20D2455D8A"><enum>1400Z–3.<?LEXA-Enum 1400Z–3.?></enum><header>Treatment of maritime prosperity zones as opportunity zones</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB665D092C8C64A67ABC5557A6F533F0C"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A maritime prosperity zone shall be treated as a qualified opportunity zone.</text></subsection><subsection id="id0A9456AAC8D64F1AAC0AA0C41E81B86B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Special rules</header><text>In applying this subchapter to any maritime prosperity zone which is a qualified opportunity zone solely by reason of this section—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id43CBD04A0E264D4BBBE5A4B9C12EACE5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of determining—</text><subparagraph id="id7E6FE5BB317B48E495406DB8C085C936"><enum>(A)</enum><text>whether any property which would not be qualified opportunity fund business property without regard to this section is qualified opportunity fund business property, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC2383AFCBEAF49A18D76F5DC22A4E701"><enum>(B)</enum><text>whether any corporation or partnership which is not a qualified opportunity fund business without regard to this section is a qualified opportunity fund business,</text></subparagraph></paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">section 1400Z–2(d) shall be applied with the modifications described in paragraph (2).</continuation-text><paragraph id="id24E9EDE9592641AEACA0540EDCFDBF0A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Modifications</header><text>The modifications described in this paragraph are as follows:</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7E4C2E1F1BFB424F99A9DFECE1F7BBDF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Start date</header><text>Subparagraphs (B)(i)(I), (C)(i), and (D)(i)(I) of section 1400Z–2(d)(2) shall each be applied by substituting <quote>the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Building Ships in America Act of 2025</short-title></quote> for <quote>December 31, 2017</quote>.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2CC8B729E40E4F4EBBBC471192766A02" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Qualified business property</header><text>Property shall not be treated as qualified opportunity zone business property unless such property is substantially used in an industry which is assigned a code under the North American Industrial Classification System which is described in paragraph (3).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE7E713D9C58F4C829A9DB49A867F7D17" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Qualified business</header><text>A trade or business shall not be treated as a qualified opportunity zone business unless such trade or business operates in an industry which is assigned a code under the North American Industrial Classification System which is described in paragraph (3).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB35FA706335B4D4EAF49FC4718D11611"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligible north American industrial classification system codes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The following codes under the North American Industrial Classification System are the codes described in this paragraph:</text><subparagraph id="id6F2AAB72EBAF45D4B95A94E2E9D4C570"><enum>(A)</enum><text>48311 (deep sea freight transportation).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id10F1857F9A3F4B2F9C5167AEF0187A13"><enum>(B)</enum><text>483113 (coastal and Great Lakes freight transportation).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idC2D03DC6FB3B4606AC531D3ACA249C06"><enum>(C)</enum><text>483211 (inland water freight transportation).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7CFE9E3B9C164AF68CDC2101A9FE8D45"><enum>(D)</enum><text>4883 (support activities for water transportation).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id32F99C39B63A4C6894FEEF34A8302168"><enum>(E)</enum><text>3366 (ship and boat building).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id5956304C944548C4BB5AD33AB8CBF794"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Maritime prosperity zone</header><text>For purposes of this chapter—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0AFBB317D193442DB69C5FC260E4F906"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>maritime prosperity zone</term> means any population census tract that—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb62ebe02a96f46d4ad4cc8ad08ba98fa"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">contains or is determined by the Maritime Administrator to be a viable site for—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idE1761243B7D243E392C8530E22E66581"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a shipyard of the United States,</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idA07C651906E347029027ECD71D940F40"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a port, or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idD7B8DB14BF8A42A1B6C2F45D1D58C9EB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a harbor facility, and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0448476d6e61417d90318e5bf6e64988"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is designated as a maritime prosperity zone under paragraph (2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idE0234969318D443AB5A3CC4C18110181"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Designation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A population census tract is designated as a maritime prosperity zone under this paragraph if—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idEBEE739288E64E8B9740181071ED7665"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Maritime Administrator, in consultation with the Secretary of the Navy, nominates the tract for designation as a maritime prosperity zone and notifies the Secretary in writing of such nomination, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idDCA6CF7C52474199967245092706E18C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary certifies such nomination and designates such tract as a qualified maritime prosperity zone.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idE2F36284CF664F189E84C4ADF3269DFD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Number of population census tracts designated</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not more than 100 population census tracts may be designated as maritime prosperity zone.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3A483CA71AF94D4E9881EC464102C2C6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Period for which designation is in effect</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in paragraph (2), a designation as a maritime prosperity zone shall remain in effect for the period—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6A25377F7C5F4D7E99BC380E4A2B80A1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">beginning on the date of the designation, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6763C741E432441AACAEE4D81A798D42"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ending at the close of the 5th calendar year beginning on or after such date of designation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB20E60E39EFE4247B97183ECF7D120D7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for subchapter Z of chapter 1 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="id2C0F45007FAD433DBB86216E316BD0E5"><toc><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 1400Z–3. Treatment of maritime prosperity zones as opportunity zones.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="idE4A48721437145F2B8687ADA3C05D712" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>
