<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H53A4AB4AC2574D938EE433BDE45875CD" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 519 IH: Federal Subaward Reporting System Modernization and Expansion Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 519</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250116">January 16, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000600">Mr. Langworthy</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="H001085">Ms. Houlahan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000230">Mr. Davis of North Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001119">Ms. Craig</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000591">Mr. Guest</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Inspector General to submit a report on the Federal subaward reporting system, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC902EA3B2A7B437B99DC0CA5EE72DCB6" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HE32EA8C0EC514D018C2ADEEECD835BCF" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Federal Subaward Reporting System Modernization and Expansion Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H2AD481543E9846A682A7ED74ED787C17" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>FFATA Federal subaward reporting system</header> <subsection id="H90F9BCE5DD4147C182D25582D4CB7BC6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report on Federal subaward reporting system</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Inspector General of the General Services Administration shall submit to Congress a report that contains the following:</text>
<paragraph id="HA94F18DD9BDE4F06B227C3F3BCE7DFCA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A comprehensive review of the FFATA subaward reporting system to identify problems within the system that contribute to inaccurate and incomplete subaward reporting and provide specific recommendations for improvements.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H56842ABA67BE48909195B0F787C9F9B6"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of the effectiveness and efficiency of the system, including the following:</text>
<subparagraph id="H041F4F32CBA547EAB2F50194DF2F6A99" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Accuracy and completeness of subaward data reported through the system.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2C7E02DE4DC0477D85EFE388AD7F6456"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Consistency of reporting requirements across Federal agencies.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H09FE88CFAD24484C914C7CD6792A5495"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Burden on Federal award recipients to comply with reporting requirements.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAEB04D57E1D14C8D8662F6342FAB1634"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Accessibility and availability of subaward data to the public and stakeholders.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HF551BBE8A5C0420ABDADECB92AEEE646"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Adequacy of enforcement mechanisms to ensure compliance with reporting requirements.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB2354B0D3CA14809B2CD8A6BFFA29DAD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Recommendations for improving the system.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H968FE2AD3518427C9C69A15901109FF4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Plan and report for improving the Federal subaward reporting system</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter until the plan is fully implemented (as determined by the Administrator), the Administrator, in consultation with the Director and the Secretary, shall implement and submit to Congress a plan to update the FFATA subaward reporting system to ensure that the system provides accurate, timely, and comprehensive information on the first tier of any subaward made under a prime Federal award that includes the following:</text> <paragraph id="H959782088FE9471A931DA1264A24B44D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Measures to improve the accuracy and completeness of subaward data reported through the system.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0860BB25DD0E4CF09DE4CD23944464C2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Standardized reporting requirements across Federal agencies, including a requirement that any prime recipient of a Federal award that does not make a subaward certifies that a subaward was not made.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0BA87D5ACD4D42B4B893E6404C3CC1B8"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Provisions to reduce the burden on Federal award recipients to comply with reporting requirements under the Federal Funding Accountability and Transparency Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/31/6101">31 U.S.C. 6101</external-xref> note).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H081A991EFAC14FB4B876D7668DFB5887"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Mechanisms to increase accessibility and availability of subaward data to the public and stakeholders.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H140680C6DF5243BFBBB045866C49FDE0"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Adequate enforcement mechanisms to ensure compliance with reporting requirements under the Federal Funding Accountability and Transparency Act of 2006.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H0ACA7FF2FE524D7BAD1A973CCD16CF11"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Expand Federal subaward reporting system</header>
<paragraph id="HC9684FB46DAF4B79BB6EC36EC8B0D06E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Subaward expansion data</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning not later than 1 year after the date on which the first plan is submitted pursuant to subsection (b), the head of each Federal agency shall collect information on the first 2 tiers of a subaward from a Federal award that includes the data elements required to comply with the Federal Funding Accountability and Transparency Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/31/6101">31 U.S.C. 6101</external-xref> note), as prescribed by the Director.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H99AD230137B649259D1E9B43C76DAA41" display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Plan for subaward reporting expansion</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator, in consultation with the Director, shall issue reporting rules for Federal agencies under the Federal Funding Accountability and Transparency Act of 2006 and develop a plan to implement the requirements described in paragraph (1) with input from stakeholders and the public that includes the following:</text>
<subparagraph id="HE2C940E0F0934A9BB55F009E8DD8F4C5" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Measures to improve the accuracy and completeness of subaward data reported through the system including the final recipient of a subaward under a Federal award.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H91D5EFA1CF594B2FA399999F90D084B7" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Standardized reporting requirements across Federal agencies.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H58A402CA0AB344C1BC7C0ED75C9195CD" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Provisions to reduce the burden on Federal award recipients to comply with reporting requirements under the Federal Funding Accountability and Transparency Act of 2006.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8BA945C2DD024AC28B4BE11FB1564926" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Mechanisms to increase accessibility and availability of subaward data including the final recipient of a subaward under a Federal award to the public and stakeholders.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H1CC6F64B3CCD4BCBBC2E71632861F053" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Adequate enforcement mechanisms to ensure compliance with reporting requirements under the Federal Funding Accountability and Transparency Act of 2006.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5DD13272F8654041B009477A94D8F826" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Subaward reporting expansion by Federal agencies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the head of each Federal agency shall begin implementing the plan described in paragraph (2).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA13B3F43C4C646688E0C7F78D0E49536"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Report on subaward expansion plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter until the plan is fully implemented (as determined by the Administrator), the Administrator, in consultation with the Director shall submit to Congress a report on the plan described in paragraph (2). </text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HFF9CC91DE4AD44CDAB15C7D9113F7CEC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text>
<paragraph id="H1EE3A0616AD147619BE79CB63D05C955"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of General Services. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAD2D0EED85D04A6EA82ADD193028DC8D" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Director; Federal agency; Federal award; Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <term>Director</term>, <term>Federal agency</term>, <term>Federal award</term>, and <term>Secretary</term> have the meaning given those terms in section 2(a) of the Federal Funding Accountability and Transparency Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/31/6101">31 U.S.C. 6101</external-xref> note). </text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6166FE2B2E15472F8E57D5539630228D" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>FFATA subaward reporting system; system</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <term>FFATA subaward reporting system</term> and <term>system</term> mean the subaward reporting system described in section 2(d)(2) of the Federal Funding Accountability and Transparency Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/31/6101">31 U.S.C. 6101</external-xref> note). </text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

