<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H84C6674BFE3A447E8ED09E047FDFE14C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1204 IH: Sue Victimizers and Offenders who Yield Explicit Unconsented Recordings Surreptitiously Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1204</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250211">February 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000194">Ms. Mace</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize a civil right of action for individuals affected by video voyeurism, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD48EF35B5E2E461F93C42403B599CFCA" style="OLC"><section id="HCD62DB8D941D42EA8F409F6402F87F58" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Sue Victimizers and Offenders who Yield Explicit Unconsented Recordings Surreptitiously Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Sue VOYEURS Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="HF639E2B36F9A4FFA9F41A774FBC9B3A9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Intimate visual depictions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title XIII of division W of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2022, is amended by inserting after section 1309 the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H5FDB16E8CFC742F5ACF8683B20993014" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="HABC211FF949E4063BB377A14DAD61EEE"><enum>1309A.</enum><header>Civil action relating to capture of intimate images</header><subsection id="HABDEB1FA979D40BBB1BD6A1D0892365D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Civil action</header><paragraph id="H23B7362974024EB4B6A314FF7C69DCF0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Right of action</header><subparagraph id="HE09FB0E07A8E44F99A0D4C9F805E9E74"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (3), an individual whose intimate visual depiction is captured, in a circumstance described in paragraph (4), without the consent of the individual, where such capture is done by a person who knows that, or recklessly disregards whether, the individual has not consented to the capture, and does so under circumstances in which the individual has a reasonable expectation of privacy, may bring a civil action against that person in an appropriate district court of the United States for relief as set forth in paragraph (2).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1E946015D26642FEBA234855631E77EC"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Rights on behalf of certain individuals</header><text>In the case of an individual who is under 18 years of age, incompetent, incapacitated, or deceased, the legal guardian of the individual or representative of the individual’s estate, another family member, or any other person appointed as suitable by the court, may assume the individual’s rights under this section, but in no event shall the defendant be named as such representative or guardian.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3BFD1DFC13674FDA8806BB94BFCF347E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Relief</header><subparagraph id="HB81C91B4792D49849838C4AEE9626D5C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In a civil action filed under this section—</text><clause id="H984A50301AC04D098DA2C912DB521F3E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an individual may recover the actual damages sustained by the individual or liquidated damages in the amount of $150,000 for each intimate visual depiction captured of the individual, and the cost of the action, including reasonable attorney’s fees and other litigation costs reasonably incurred; and</text></clause><clause id="HA1A16A00A2A84733BFF97762E7A00755"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the court may, in addition to any other relief available at law, order equitable relief, including a temporary restraining order, a preliminary injunction, or a permanent injunction ordering the defendant to cease display or disclosure of the visual depiction.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFEF2867D3EC64028898A704DDA575A1E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Preservation of anonymity</header><text>In ordering relief under subparagraph (A), the court may grant injunctive relief maintaining the confidentiality of a plaintiff using a pseudonym.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEB34DCD20ADF4AAC83754B139ABF1324"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>An individual may not bring an action for relief under this section relating to the actions of a law enforcement officer or agency, conducting surveillance pursuant to a lawfully issued warrant.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4C7816DDC9304CC7B9D0CF148BB572CC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Circumstance described</header><text>For the purposes of paragraph (1), the circumstances described in this paragraph are that—</text><subparagraph id="H5FCD9854E0B847D99E1FAF32C79B8295"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the individual traveled in interstate or foreign commerce, or traveled using a means, channel, facility, or instrumentality of interstate or foreign commerce, in furtherance of or in connection with the conduct described in paragraph (1);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBF0F7196E53C45DDB0E932BF324DE1C1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the individual used a means, channel, facility, or instrumentality of interstate or foreign commerce in furtherance of or in connection with the conduct described in paragraph (1);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7B956212C3DF4467ADEF6C952F4A2DEE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any payment of any kind was made, directly or indirectly, in furtherance of or in connection with the conduct described in paragraph (1) using any means, channel, facility, or instrumentality of interstate or foreign commerce or in or affecting interstate or foreign commerce; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0F5DE6AFC021457C98B67DA07185B445"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the individual transmitted in interstate or foreign commerce any communication relating to or in furtherance of the conduct described in paragraph (1) using any means, channel, facility, or instrumentality of interstate or foreign commerce or in or affecting interstate or foreign commerce by any means or in manner, including by computer, mail, wire, or electromagnetic transmission; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA27076ED2A1A4FE8A6EB0A793A724C73"><enum>(E)</enum><text>any equipment, item, or other object that has traveled in interstate or foreign commerce was used to perform the conduct described in paragraph (1);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA95AB45508D74A92950A49B788D6E375"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the conduct described in paragraph (1) occurred within the special maritime and territorial jurisdiction of the United States, or any territory or possession of the United States; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2FA718EEA71A443DA1BF6A9B470B9EBD"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the conduct described in paragraph (1) otherwise occurred in or affected interstate or foreign commerce.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H970BD806A0B1499487F3A9A2B6B465EB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HF3878D378A004A27B397CC32BEB76C27"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Broadcast</header><text>The term <quote>broadcast</quote> means to electronically transmit a visual image with the intent that it be viewed by a person or persons.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC88D8F241AF341A6A0FD8B55C86D922F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Capture</header><text>The term <quote>capture</quote>, with respect to an image, means to videotape, photograph, film, record by any means, or broadcast.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H458291B359474EFC91329F30F3A54FBC" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Consent</header><text>The term <quote>consent</quote> means an affirmative, conscious, competent, and voluntary authorization made by the individual free from force, fraud, misrepresentation, or coercion.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA51770B1F3E944F0A14491431CAEA0C4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Intimate visual depiction</header><text>The term <quote>intimate visual depiction</quote>—</text><subparagraph id="H59385A5042BB4691AA76AE646CE809A3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means a visual depiction, as that term is defined in section 2256(5) of title 18, United States Code, that depicts—</text><clause id="H8242FD952721458BA13A155F864608B7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the naked or undergarment clad private area of an individual; or</text></clause><clause id="HE86226A0FF984B349CD93FDDC6A65467"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the display or transfer of bodily sexual fluids—</text><subclause id="HD73BDC410C5147D0BB5BA9ED6833C7D3"><enum>(I)</enum><text>on to any part of the body of an individual;</text></subclause><subclause id="H1CA5A68F408A4A2482BF6953FD2E44A6"><enum>(II)</enum><text>from the body of an individual; or</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H68D60A8A57FB4A0C84B37FA35EAF41E1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>an individual engaging in sexually explicit conduct; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC2482284AA4F4F0EAD93CFD1FE347AF8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes any visual depictions described in subparagraph (A) produced while the individual was in a public place only if the individual did not—</text><clause id="HAA42E81963DF4CE9A33258C87FB87CF2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>voluntarily display the content depicted; or</text></clause><clause id="H63362DC540FC4274901BA8238BC1D58F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>consent to the sexual conduct depicted;</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAA08A451AD0E4B8FBC1B40DE91E9CD6F"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Private area</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>private area</quote> means, with respect to an individual, the genitals, pubic area, anus, buttocks, or female nipple of that individual.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFBEE9B59322048E390D53BC71E7B75A5"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Sexually explicit conduct</header><text>The term <quote>sexually explicit conduct</quote> has the meaning given to the term in subparagraph (A) of section 2256(2) of title 18, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5477BA434B3F4B958FA4B568D75C1D9F"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Under circumstances in which that individual has a reasonable expectation of privacy</header><text>The term <quote>under circumstances in which that individual has a reasonable expectation of privacy</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="H6ED7DAA00DDF40F3A6C064CFCA2524C0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>circumstances in which a reasonable person would believe that he or she could disrobe in privacy, without being concerned that an image of a private area of the individual was being captured; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H91D52E8B330A4868B4A792F1DFC63AFC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>circumstances in which a reasonable person would believe that a private area of the individual would not be visible to the public, regardless of whether that person is in a public or private place.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

