<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H89CED0CF13254251B26C855A790847A0" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 451 IH: Fostering Autonomy in Independent Returns by Prohibiting Redundant and Extralegal Programs Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 451</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250115">January 15, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001172">Mr. Smith of Nebraska</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="E000246">Mr. Edwards</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000597">Mr. Garbarino</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001205">Mrs. Miller of West Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000478">Ms. Tenney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001082">Mr. Hern of Oklahoma</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000379">Mr. Alford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001260">Mr. Buchanan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000809">Mr. Womack</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000134">Ms. Van Duyne</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to prohibit certain activities constituting preparation of tax returns by the Secretary of the Treasury, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H017E8589A1064E538617CCFE44E43B02" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="H9A2BBA7D5D7D4BB48016BE5F98D01EB5"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Fostering Autonomy in Independent Returns by Prohibiting Redundant and Extralegal Programs Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>FAIR PREP Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4E9C057C3268428B8E2B9A1EAD3ABC7C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition of certain return preparation</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB1D9636FA5DB47678D27082C674EA156"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6020">Section 6020</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H813DBF988509434493A32813DD471671"><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1D346D1C723C49FA8BF875F66119A51C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Prohibited preparation by Secretary</header><paragraph id="HE79C036BCDC74B1BB8B1856926F6F5DB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in section 6014 and subsections (a) and (b) of this section, the Secretary shall not prepare any return of tax imposed by this title or any claim for refund of tax imposed by this title.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9918BCAE40084E5A94B6D1763A17A7BB"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Prohibition of direct file and comparable programs</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (1), any return or claim for refund prepared using an electronic tax preparation service operated by the Secretary shall be treated as if such return or claim were prepared by the Secretary.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2B04C7BADEA940FAB19F4B093A22D86F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Qualified return preparation programs and IRS Free File partnership</header><text>Paragraph (2) shall not apply to any return or claim for refund solely because such return or claim for refund was prepared via, or with the assistance of—</text><subparagraph id="H83B45D9E27B44F779552CBF8CAB164C8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a qualified return preparation program (as defined in section 7526A(e)), or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H42FA242BA47D40698C1EC080325E38AE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the IRS Free File Program as established by the Internal Revenue Service and published in the Federal Register on November 4, 2002 (67 Fed. Reg. 67247), including any subsequent agreements and governing rules established pursuant thereto.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H14C31BD56A6E455BA2160A22CF76A982"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection—</text><subparagraph id="H963DB7010ADD48C79678FEED5F8B5C19"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Tax return preparation</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9A8DF63FE9A445E484ACB6143CAD65C9"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>prepare</term> with respect to any return or claim for refund means—</text><subclause id="H7AC6FD35EFC14F8CB11DFFD0DAAA801A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the completion of any form and schedule needed to compute and report any tax imposed by this title or any claim for refund of such a tax, and</text></subclause><subclause id="H9B3C7C24090342189341FF53D809A718"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the filing of any such return or claim for refund, regardless of whether such return or claim is submitted electronically or on paper.</text></subclause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="clause">For purposes of the preceding sentence, the preparation of any portion of a return or claim for refund shall be treated as if it were the preparation of such return or claim for refund. </continuation-text></clause><clause id="H14C4269411164EA3946F7E223ED71A10"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Computation and correction of errors, etc</header><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H787B0686836944509C8025167ECAD507"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such term shall not include any computation authorized by section 6102 or any other computation or correction of mathematical or clerical errors required or authorized by any provision of chapter 63.</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE3ABC945E7DE4D0FAB4E4220A1C4CBED"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Fillable forms</header><text>Such term shall not include the provision of fillable forms by the Secretary merely because such forms include an automated calculation feature.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H68AADE347A2A4118875196B3563CB642"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Electronic tax preparation service</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>electronic tax preparation service operated by the Secretary</term> means the free direct e-file tax return system as established by the Internal Revenue Service and published in the Federal Register on December 15, 2023 (88 Fed. Reg. 87057), and September 5, 2024 (89 Fed. Reg. 72699), and any successor program of the Internal Revenue Service which provides an electronic tax preparation service option.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HD7D585373813426B831E47913B5CDA74"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by this section shall apply to returns filed after the date which is 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H91396FE1DDC24B88BD50B5E6F2CE66CB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>No inference</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendment made by this section shall not be construed to create any inference with respect to the authority of the Secretary of the Treasury (or any delegate of such Secretary) to develop and offer for use any electronic tax filing or tax preparation service option, or otherwise engage in the preparation of any return of tax or any claim for refund of tax imposed by the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, with respect to any taxable year beginning on or before the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="H083D38C258AA41348EEB76BCA053B7FE"><enum>3.</enum><header>Limitation on further expenditures circumventing congressional authority</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury (or any delegate of such Secretary) may not award or make payment of grants or enter into or maintain any contract, other transaction, or reimbursable agreement for the development or operation of an electronic tax preparation service option after the date of the enactment of this Act unless otherwise authorized by law. </text></section></legis-body></bill> 

