<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-CAN25A02-F79-0V-0R2"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 399 IS: Congratulating the people of North Macedonia on the 34th anniversary of their independence and celebrating the 30th anniversary of diplomatic relations between North Macedonia and the United States.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 399</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250917" legis-day="20250916">September 17 (legislative day, September 16), 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S422">Mr. Welch</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S384">Mr. Tillis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S423">Mr. Ricketts</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Congratulating the people of North Macedonia on the 34th anniversary of their independence and celebrating the 30th anniversary of diplomatic relations between North Macedonia and the United States.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the Republic of North Macedonia peacefully asserted and achieved independent statehood on September 8, 1991, and has since become a secure, democratic, and prosperous country and a key United States ally and strategic partner in the Western Balkans;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas North Macedonia affirmed its commitment to joining the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) in 1993, adopted major defense reforms, built a modern, professional defense force, and became the 30th NATO alliance member on March 27, 2020;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 1993, the State of Vermont and North Macedonia established a partnership under the National Guard State Partnership Program;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas, in 1995, the United States and North Macedonia established full diplomatic relations;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2008, the United States signed a Declaration of Strategic Partnership and Cooperation with North Macedonia;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in June 2022, North Macedonia held a strategic dialogue with the United States, marking a significant bilateral milestone and step toward implementation of the Declaration of Strategic Partnership and Cooperation;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on May 29, 2025, United States Secretary of State Marco Rubio met with North Macedonia Minister of Foreign Affairs and Foreign Trade Timčo Mucunski, commended the strong relationship between the two countries, and highlighted mutual interests in regional stability, economic cooperation, and NATO;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas North Macedonia has demonstrated its importance to the European Union and the United States as a security partner and NATO ally, providing Ukraine with humanitarian aid and considerable military equipment, voting in favor of United Nations Security Council and General Assembly resolutions against Russian aggression, and adopting all European Union sanctions on the Russian Federation;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the resolution of the naming dispute between Greece and North Macedonia paved the way for North Macedonia’s NATO membership and candidacy for membership in the European Union;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Government of North Macedonia has demonstrated its commitment to Euro-Atlantic integration through alignment with the Common Foreign and Security Policy of the European Union; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas September 8, 2025, marks the 34th anniversary of the independence of North Macedonia, a moment to reflect on the country’s achievements in establishing and maintaining a resilient democracy in the service of the freedom and prosperity of the people of North Macedonia: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="idb517f9012fd74a07a886a788a9e8e80d"><enum>(1)</enum><text>extends congratulations and best wishes to the people of North Macedonia as they celebrate the 34th anniversary of their independence;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id44b925acd5f945b1babef787361de258"><enum>(2)</enum><text>honors the bond of friendship between the United States and North Macedonia and the shared values of freedom, democracy, and good governance;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3a89e60b49cf497ab846e709c2144581"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recognizes the cooperation between the State of Vermont and North Macedonia and the partnership between the Vermont National Guard and the Army of the Republic of North Macedonia;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd34375cb48ba45ad9e5c044e065ed995"><enum>(4)</enum><text>appreciates North Macedonia’s continued commitment to the Prespa Agreement;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7f9478cec076473b86784d33515ed573"><enum>(5)</enum><text>honors five years of shared security, collective defense, and joint military alliance with North Macedonia as a member of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1d0bb6d6eea94a00aa44093be2a0516e"><enum>(6)</enum><text>appreciates North Macedonia’s active role in fostering peace and stability in Eastern Europe and the Western Balkans and advancing democratic reforms and Euro-Atlantic integration, and its alignment with positions of the European Union and the United States on security and foreign policy; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida122c5b661c9485086b19e27165c023a"><enum>(7)</enum><text>looks toward many more decades of shared prosperity, peace, cooperation, and friendship.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

