<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H29F0B6914F224DD1BDDCC4D155CD451F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2253 IH: Puppy Protection Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2253</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250321">March 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000610">Mr. Reschenthaler</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Animal Welfare Act to provide for the humane treatment of dogs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HFD6EB39ACF494F7D88D8974DBB23CE34" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H62AFE46E77A34D1C8A89B0F133357C92" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Puppy Protection Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HC4992189D59C489C9E6CF68839D6F540"><enum>2.</enum><header>Additional requirements for dealers</header> <subsection id="H868938408279415E82D19D1E1326D2D1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Humane treatment of dogs by dealers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 13(a) of the Animal Welfare Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2143">7 U.S.C. 2143(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFA772A4A53FD4BCAB208616DBAA10CDE" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="HB9195FF18A094ED487554C3540E1598B" indent="up1"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to the requirements under paragraph (2), the standards described in paragraph (1) shall, with respect to dealers, include requirements—</text> <subparagraph id="H08B41766E4864D9891FD8B9FDDC451E1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that such dealer provide adequate housing for dogs that includes—</text> 
<clause id="HD0DD1A9D5DA04AE3B89B9D8EC3B399AC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>completely solid flooring;</text></clause> <clause id="H5DB4123360FF4CE8A9423FE99F0C3D8B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">indoor space sufficient to allow the tallest dog in an enclosure to stand on its hind legs without touching the roof of the enclosure;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H1D10651A14374F6FA79F041EEE9E26D8"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to dogs over 8 weeks in age, primary enclosures that, with the length of the dog measured from the tip of the nose to the base of the tail, provide at least—</text> <subclause id="HFDABD82C962A48B5B3B6EA2AEDE5F262"><enum>(I)</enum><text>12 square feet of indoor floor space per each dog not more than 25 inches long;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H68876A40264B46988178FF2BC7513208"><enum>(II)</enum><text>20 square feet of indoor floor space per each dog more than 25 but not more than 35 inches long; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H6DAD7D92EC034153B5F49364929EF6C7"><enum>(III)</enum><text>30 square feet of indoor floor space per each dog more than 35 inches long;</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause commented="no" id="H85095AC1FFD7436FBC62D212EE63BB2F"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">enclosures that are not stacked or otherwise placed on top of or below another enclosure; and</text></clause> <clause commented="no" id="H1356A33DE59645E3B762AC4A14D103D8"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">temperature control that—</text> 
<subclause commented="no" id="HBCAE24A3306544098EDFCB7E01245043"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is appropriate for the age, breed, and condition of the dogs in the enclosure; and</text></subclause> <subclause commented="no" id="HFE5CB13F2FE54291B37083041969E2A3"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is between 45 and 85 degrees Fahrenheit, when dogs are present in the enclosure;</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF06172B638B3492EA24F95DE39D3B7EA"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that appropriate and nutritious food be provided to each dog at least twice per day, in an amount sufficient to maintain the good health and physical condition of each such dog, except when fasting is directed by a licensed veterinarian in the provision of appropriate veterinary care;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFECF5ABBDF35464F9E0ADCF2F6B515A6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>that each dog has continuous access to potable water that is not frozen and is free of feces, algae, and other contaminants;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H74E03E5DF8F6494A8EE1F45CC7CC39AA"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that each dog has adequate exercise, including—</text> <clause id="H84E563C7582346B9BF24BB7A4FEC3E74"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for dogs over the age of 12 weeks, an outdoor exercise area that—</text> 
<subclause id="H8F64BC2DFD644F2F902001FF5F6EFEA7"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is freely accessible from the primary enclosures of such dogs; </text></subclause> <subclause id="HFB81DAD413D642159796F6C893DDFF33"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is at ground-level;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HB2CE5831A2C940EA9D77E8CBF3B3529C"><enum>(III)</enum><text>is a solid surface;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H7907A7DF47D44C6C8DFB63ADE2C48234"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>is enclosed (by a fence or other structure);</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H9A895D4026B046168B7E52EA51A6336A"><enum>(V)</enum><text>is properly controlled for the safety of the dogs; </text></subclause> <subclause id="H0D31D8D1E3064CC49F65EC4A5D2FDD6C"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>allows the dog to extend to full stride, play, and engage in other types of mentally stimulating and social behaviors; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HF4A3E8DC1943418CB727811A714A35D0"><enum>(VII)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is restricted only during nighttime hours (between sunset and sunrise) or during severe inclement weather; or</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H23F8615624594B7DBD5B3AE4B061F85E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the dealer obtains a certification from the attending veterinarian stating that the dog should not have unrestricted access to an outdoor exercise area for a specific medical reason, an alternative exercise plan prescribed by the veterinarian for the dog that meets the requirements under section 3.8(a) of title 9, Code of Federal Regulations as in effect on the date of enactment of this paragraph;</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFDF8D521C6E241E0A3B913DE351AB73E"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that each dog has meaningful socialization with humans and compatible dogs for at least 30 minutes each day that—</text> <clause id="H79CBA3C26436414D8B7D73A0DEDC6396"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes positive interaction with a human such as petting, stroking, grooming, feeding, playing with, exercising, or other touching of the dog that is beneficial to the well-being of the dog; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HB6E51A4EE2474E579D6616AB36578240"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>does not include time spent in veterinary care;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0BD52D4447C64068821DCB282C9C55A7"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that each dog receives adequate veterinary care and that each dealer maintain updated records of all instances of such care, including—</text> 
<clause id="H30399BF6CE3145F6993CBF4E2F88A562"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prompt treatment by the dealer of any minor or shallow cuts, scrapes, and abrasions; </text></clause> <clause id="H0298A5DB894041E392DDEC23B8231683"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prompt diagnosis and treatment by a licensed veterinarian in any case where symptoms of any transmissible disease or infection or any illness or injury are significant, visible, or evident in the behavior, affect, appetite, or activity level of the dog;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HF8DEA4CD6C9E4562A9F130EAA77176F1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a thorough hands-on examination by a licensed veterinarian at least once each year, which shall include a basic dental exam;</text></clause> <clause id="H12C8701B6AD54A28A4E92221B791C4C2"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">core vaccinations recommended by the most recent version of the American Animal Hospital Association Canine Vaccination Guidelines as in effect on the date of enactment of this paragraph; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H83F9FEC0E8F84FACA6FCB403265B3F81"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">medications to prevent intestinal parasites, heartworm disease, fleas, and ticks that are approved by a licensed veterinarian for canine use;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7F20A223BFD54E2C9727D4DCEC379A49"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to safe breeding practices for dogs, including—</text> 
<clause id="H8118C1EF599A4E33A8A3BA379BA86DD9"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a screening program for known prevalent inheritable diseases that may be disabling or likely to significantly affect the lifespan or quality of life of the mother or her offspring;</text></clause> <clause id="HD53A5F9946DD4FA6BF89ABFE0E7A736D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prohibiting breeding, unless each dog bred has been screened by a veterinarian prior to each attempt to breed and is found to be free from health conditions that may be disabling to, or likely to significantly affect the lifespan or quality of life of, the mother or her offspring (as documented by a licensed veterinarian upon examination);</text></clause> 
<clause id="H043F563F2D0D4A95B754BD410EAFE783"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prohibiting the breeding of a female dog to produce—</text> <subclause id="HD1BC152AC0A44C9EAE679ABA669D334E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>more than 2 litters in any 25-month period; or</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HE86C6866BFFE43F8BE721B09C5484460"><enum>(II)</enum><text>more than 6 litters in the lifetime of such dog;</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HE97FD2F0F39245348F9FE3AA9F93FD24"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that female dogs of small breeds, having a maximum weight range at maturity that is below 40 pounds, not be bred—</text> 
<subclause id="HEBF93FF3394B4EF9BC9DE8B1DE6118A4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>before reaching the age of 18 months; or</text></subclause> <subclause id="H458C3F51034044429B44C506F9CCDA24"><enum>(II)</enum><text>after reaching the age of 9 years;</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H51D4E7945E074B758F3D9FCCDD8728C3"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that female dogs of large breeds, having expected weight ranges at maturity that include 40 or more pounds, not be bred—</text> <subclause id="H8CD0498335AB4D759905AF8BF994D79D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>before reaching the age of 2 years; or</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HE236E2135EAE4ACC8EC570E68EF12244"><enum>(II)</enum><text>after reaching the age of 7 years; and</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HF71A61E7E5D54C1A97CC7D5255900D71"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that any canine caesarian section be performed by a licensed veterinarian;</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H42DCF982439344C1B9EC3F9B9153DF21"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that dogs be housed with other dogs, unless health conditions identified by a licensed veterinarian or behavioral issues make group housing unsafe; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA2C7DF228A054B56AFE89F3FB1FCA6F9"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to make all reasonable efforts to find humane placement for retired breeding dogs (such as with an adoptive family, rescue organization, or other appropriate owner for that dog, and not including selling at auction or otherwise placing a retired breeding dog with another breeder for breeding purposes).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6B1036DAB8FE4FA08587933681708694"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 13(a)(2)(B) of the Animal Welfare Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2143">7 U.S.C. 2143(a)(2)(B)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>subject to paragraph (9),</quote> before <quote>for exercise of dogs</quote>.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H00619E5DBF5A4C8D95D76D4FDF477E23"><enum>3.</enum><header>Regulations</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall issue final regulations establishing the standards for the care of dogs by dealers, as required by this Act and the amendments made by this Act.</text></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

