<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MDM25436-WXV-1S-0SN"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 S703 IS: Contraband Awareness Technology Catches Harmful Fentanyl Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 703</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250225">February 25, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S287">Mr. Cornyn</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S388">Ms. Hassan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S378">Mr. Lankford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S437">Mr. Justice</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S406">Mr. Kelly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S359">Mr. Heinrich</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S409">Mr. Luján</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S434">Mr. Moreno</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S384">Mr. Tillis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S372">Mrs. Capito</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To establish a pilot program to assess the use of technology to speed up and enhance the cargo inspection process at land ports of entry along the border.</official-title></form><legis-body><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short titles</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Contraband Awareness Technology Catches Harmful Fentanyl Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>CATCH Fentanyl Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id8a965690dac84124917ef1c56ffa9774"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="id9dbba12d305a41859a73964397f902b9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id01b36cc4210c4714b626b701a8f4179c"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate</committee-name>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idee7df4c918544fd9a7c4f21f37b1a89f"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives</committee-name>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id80940bbf3e354100a0bc19a7d06d944f"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Artificial intelligence; AI</header><text>The terms <term>artificial intelligence</term> and <term>AI</term> have the meaning given the term <quote>artificial intelligence</quote> in section 238(g) of the John S. McCain National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2019 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/232">Public Law 115–232</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/4061">10 U.S.C. 4061</external-xref> note).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id828f312c30e843459e79b33a136a47d2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>CBP innovation team</header><text>The term <term>CBP Innovation Team</term> means the U.S. Customs and Border Protection Innovation Team within the Office of the Commissioner.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7d909272a8de4c79a6a6a693a9cce357"><enum>(4)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nonintrusive inspection technology; NII technology</header><text>The terms <term>nonintrusive inspection technology</term> and <term>NII technology</term> means technical equipment and machines, such as X-ray or gamma-ray imaging equipment, that allow cargo inspections without the need to open the means of transport and unload the cargo.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id785f90941d464d96b80f0df2e467b2cf"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Pilot projects</header><text>The term <term>pilot projects</term> means the projects required under section 3(a) for testing and assessing the use of technologies to improve the inspection process at land ports of entry.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf8a241cbccac4d97b8d71687e8425ed2"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Homeland Security.</text></paragraph></section><section id="idf985a2053d3f40b7bee9e6c804991482"><enum>3.</enum><header>Pilot projects allowing additional technology providers to participate in inspecting cars, trucks, and cargo containers at certain ports of entry</header><subsection id="idc21327f04bbd4201ad630ab59b9716bb"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><paragraph id="id0e975add9eea47b999000f4697ae62fb"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary, acting through CBP Innovation Team, and in coordination with the Office of Field Operations and the Department of Homeland Security Science and Technology Directorate, shall begin the implementation of pilot projects for testing and assessing the use of technologies or technology enhancements to improve the process for inspecting, including by increasing efficiencies of such inspections, any conveyance or mode of transportation at land ports of entry along the borders of the United States. The technologies or technology enhancements tested and assessed under the pilot projects shall be for the purpose of assisting U.S. Customs and Border Protection personnel to detect contraband, illegal drugs, illegal weapons, human smuggling, and threats on inbound and outbound traffic, in conjunction with the use of imaging equipment, radiation portal monitors, and chemical detectors. </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3eeac32bcb95496bae0e8b7c97ee24ad"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id766702fa463a4700a1b7a260bc01a8e6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In implementing the pilot projects at ports of entry, the CBP Innovation Team, in coordination with the Department of Homeland Security Science and Technology Directorate, shall test and collect data regarding not fewer than 5 types of nonintrusive inspection technology enhancements that can be deployed at land ports of entry. The CBP Innovation Team shall test technology enhancements from at least 1 of the following categories: </text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2c3e7db4b2ba43069e9628cc0ae0de36"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Artificial intelligence.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbe9279a312e447dbb7e9844f86ed5352"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Machine learning.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id76c5b01861904971afdc2c513252aadb"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">High-performance computing.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7682149519a64668a1e03eae002bb55c"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Quantum information sciences, including quantum sensing.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide8f7ae94b75a427e9cc54552cb518d02"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Other emerging technologies.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idcbfd498011d948a8941e9ca9d603383e"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Identification of effective enhancements</header><text>The pilot projects shall identify the most effective types of technology enhancements to improve the capabilities of nonintrusive inspection systems and other inspection systems used at land ports of entry based on—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7b789b29a3ab43488c2d1ae4b979b69f"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the technology enhancement's ability to assist U.S. Customs and Border Protection accurately detect contraband, illegal drugs, illegal weapons, human smuggling, or threats in inbound and outbound traffic;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idca9043c6f18046c4950fd409bb822665"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the technology enhancement's ability to increase efficiencies of inspections to assist U.S. Customs and Border Protection address long wait times;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id57314021354441e5881b32749985435c"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the technology enhancement's ability to improve capabilities of aging detection equipment and infrastructure at land ports of entry;</text></clause><clause id="id8f646bcd5c894d90ac824df0bc31fb63"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the technology enhancement’s safety relative to As Low As Reasonably Achievable (ALARA) standard practices;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6285c645dff640c8835e0474af89da41"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the ability to integrate the new technology into the existing workflow and infrastructure;</text></clause><clause id="id56e49cdb68464fbabfd7929288779ee1"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the technology enhancement’s ability to incorporate automatic threat recognition technology using standard formats and open architecture;</text></clause><clause id="id1f349b36d7624f08a47e48987d968ea4"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>the mobility of technology enhancements; and </text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb5d2b6537c9745948dc7c7158dfba753"><enum>(viii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">other performance measures identified by the CBP Innovation Team.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id05aafe2f9be14328b8db74a6d4c3f06f"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Private sector involvement</header><text>The CBP Innovation Team may solicit input from representatives of the private sector regarding commercially viable technologies. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5754abba69b341fb8b31d5bab2b955a7"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Cost effectiveness requirement</header><text>In identifying the most effective types of technology enhancements under subparagraph (B), the pilot projects shall prioritize solutions that demonstrate the highest cost-effectiveness in achievement the objectives described in clauses (i) through (ix) of subparagraph (B). Cost effectiveness shall account for improved detection capabilities, increased inspection efficiencies, reduced wait times, and total cost of implementation (including infrastructure upgrades and maintenance expenses). </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4d8bf476a19a4811992d8d3614a0346b"><enum>(3)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nonintrusive inspection systems program</header><text>The CBP Innovation Team shall work with existing nonintrusive inspection systems programs within U.S. Customs and Border Protection when planning and developing the pilot projects required under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1c50056eaba94185a9728b70944020e1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Data privacy protections</header><text>In implementing the pilot projects and utilizing new technologies, the Secretary shall safeguard the privacy and security of personal data collected during inspections through appropriate measures, including—</text><subparagraph id="id04a2136e7a724127b8bbd6dc9795b346"><enum>(A)</enum><text>adherence to relevant privacy laws and regulations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9a44ddb57de54d05a951c77e0c4d3959"><enum>(B)</enum><text>implementation of data anonymization techniques, if applicable; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddfc1d5cacde340058eec6cd2ab263d42"><enum>(C)</enum><text>regular audits to assess compliance with data privacy standards. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddabfe784ff0148e4aa9fee528cc49c7c"><enum>(5)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Science and technology directorate</header><text>The CBP Innovation Team shall work with the Department of Homeland Security Science and Technology Directorate to align existing nonintrusive inspection research and development efforts within the Science and Technology Directorate when planning and developing pilot projects required under paragraph (1). </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ida58b9a886c0d45cfa045d2cb6ebf97bb"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The pilot projects shall terminate on the date that is 5 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id143e69e4cc77481983bdf48fc29692b2"><enum>(c)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Reports required</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, and 180 days after the termination of the pilot projects pursuant to subsection (b), the Secretary shall submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees that contains—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id70b3b87e0c1849439fe7ff1c0b8551df"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an analysis of the effectiveness of technology enhancements tested based on the requirements described in subsection (a)(2);</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbd9c67d9a9de4415a55806fcaab82fd8"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any recommendations from the testing and analysis concerning the ability to utilize such technologies at all land ports of entry;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9de02e3f8b1a460b97ec9ed044dcbc9c"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a plan to utilize new technologies that meet the performance goals of the pilot projects across all U.S. Customs and Border Protection land ports of entry at the border, including total costs and a breakdown of the costs of such plan, including any infrastructure improvements that may be required to accommodate recommended technology enhancements;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd73bbc07aaaf4bedbd1f5792250632b8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a comprehensive list of existing technologies owned and utilized by U.S. Customs and Border protection for cargo and vehicle inspection, including—</text><subparagraph id="idf91c2bc12fae4f3bbaec9338755e6cea"><enum>(A)</enum><text>details on the implementation status of such technologies, such as whether the technologies have been fully installed and utilized, or whether there are challenges with the installation and utilization of the technology;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb7e90a8eee6c4a7d927783457f941217"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an evaluation of the compatibility, interoperability, and scalability of existing cargo and vehicle inspection technologies within U.S. Customs and Border Protection’s physical and information technology infrastructure; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide204b9c1c56740f4ab0e513117e2a105"><enum>(C)</enum><text>identification of any obstacles to the effective deployment and integration of such technologies; and </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id46e95447ffa24575a919d5e2c6fea4ac"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the analysis described in subsection (d).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id997bfcc7b1e643f3b97f73f1bacd9eb1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Areas of analysis</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report required under subsection (c) shall include an analysis containing—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7f865bc90f5d4321bf6ce5914b797285"><enum>(1)</enum><text>quantitative measurements of performance based on the requirements described in subsection (a)(2) of each technology tested compared with the status quo to reveal a broad picture of the performance of technologies and technology enhancements, such as—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida0cd62fb11a44f4fa28bc0fa288c3525"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the probability of detection, false alarm rate, and throughput; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3377b278a1a446daa147e4f8bedc3412"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an analysis determining whether such observed performance represents a significant increase, decrease, or no change compared with current systems;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2589960aba9848de8e74c940d1ade893"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an assessment of the relative merits of each such technology;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf2f449a6e7e9410fafe51faf50443459"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any descriptive trends and patterns observed; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5f1c3d1a118d4a519e8e37832629c476"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">performance measures for—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id77812ae0b6e449699f0d385eeaa49883"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the technology enhancement's ability to assist with the detection of contraband on inbound and outbound traffic through automated (primary) inspection by measuring and reporting the probability of detection and false alarm rate for each NII system under operational conditions;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3c4679bcf9744d5ab0150697db9d9a34"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the throughput of cargo through each NII system with a technology enhancement, including a breakdown of the time needed for U.S. Customs and Border Protection—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide2c2d9c4d2e24c6cadac51a50706f0b4"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to complete the image review process and clear low-risk shipments; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9ba512613b3c44b9be20acffa9e5b83b"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to complete additional inspections of high-risk items;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf59e5cf4f2794b2a980a0f0b1a59cb2c"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">changes in U.S. Customs and Border Protection officer time commitments and personnel needs to sustain high volume NII scanning operations when technology enhancements are utilized; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id033627cae60f485aad4b15a04027bc76"><enum>(D)</enum><text>operational costs, including—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id72dedc358a2a4740b90644e7631feb8b"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">estimated implementation costs for each NII system with technology enhancements; and </text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idde4df138d8f84943a17aecd0bed3cb85"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">estimated cost savings due to improved efficiency due to technology enhancements, if applicable. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idcd23a1e7607f4d20be59e0c5e801c799"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Privacy and civil liberties reports</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with the CBP Innovation Team and other appropriate offices—</text><paragraph id="iddbd15ebf3d7b4694bd220329ceacdbd9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>prior to the implementation of the technologies referred to in this section, shall submit—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfa13cc9b0e03402880e9891e78a5401b"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a report or reports to the appropriate congressional committees regarding the potential privacy, civil liberties, and civil rights impacts of technologies being tested under the pilot projects pursuant to this section, including an analysis of the impacts of the technology enhancements on individuals crossing the United States border; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida097ae10cd5d4540b816bce67ad43cfd"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommendations for mitigation measures to address any identified impacts; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id8cbdf65da2ca410f953f1286fbbc1096"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not later than 180 days after the termination of the pilot projects pursuant to subsection (b), shall submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees containing—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id104acdb629a14649b6de08fe2de3fda6"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">findings on the impacts to privacy, civil rights, and civil liberties resulting from the pilot projects;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id02a85a6fab6f41339525d668d3771910"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommendations for mitigating these impacts in implementation of approved technologies; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfe71bec02e2a4a6aa4a3adc8e9b24a48"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any additional recommendations based on the lessons learned from the pilot projects.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id7490a347ece44b069ef53d29e0f24788"><enum>4.</enum><header>Prohibition on new appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No additional funds are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

