<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H04268C3FCEA4496E8AE4A5A5D9EF882C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2607 IH: Asylum for Farmers and Refugees In Krsis And Necessary Emigration Resettlement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2607</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250402">April 2, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000026">Mr. Nehls</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To designate residents of South Africa as Priority 2 refugees of special humanitarian concern, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H581AC456412C42CB8A6B244A95DD4B31" style="OLC"><section id="HF97D977D1E8B415685C3805A95A631BD" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Asylum for Farmers and Refugees In Krsis And Necessary Emigration Resettlement Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>AFRIKANER Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H0345B99DB2CB4F999C1EA3E89A32CD34"><enum>2.</enum><header>Designation of certain residents of south africa as priority 2 refugees</header><subsection id="HA45460A362144A87A2202A1F99391BAC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of Homeland Security, shall designate as Priority 2 refugees of special humanitarian concern the following categories of aliens:</text><paragraph id="HF35A59F89D3D421495FBFB5D4CE6D4EA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Residents of South Africa who are members of the Caucasian minority group and have suffered persecution, or have a well-founded fear of persecution, on account of their race, ethnicity, or ancestry.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA9D4DA3D51484C9289FA8AA2231C4493"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The spouses, children, and parents (as such terms are defined in subsections (a) and (b) of section 101 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref>)) of individuals described in paragraph (1), except such parents who are citizens of a country other than South Africa.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5679FE25248D4C7B82FA59D6D92579CF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Processing of south african refugees</header><text>The processing of individuals described in subsection (a) for classification as refugees may occur in South Africa or in a third country.</text></subsection><subsection id="H8D35850F7B5B408AB04A419BA8488FE3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligibility for admission as refugees</header><text>An alien may not be denied the opportunity to apply for admission as a refugee under this section primarily because such alien—</text><paragraph id="H9B387E283F224EA9BA47F3A31E6CA8AE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>qualifies as an immediate relative of a citizen of the United States; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5EC1407318AD4B2988F07DE016686014"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is eligible for admission to the United States under any other immigrant classification.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB0E14F7055754FCCBC456ED3CE855C0E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Facilitation of admissions</header><text>An applicant for admission to the United States from South Africa may not be denied primarily on the basis of a politically motivated arrest, detention, or other adverse government action taken against such applicant as a result of the applicant’s race, ethnicity, or ancestry.</text></subsection><subsection id="H791B59767BD2478C95ED6186F659C301"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Exclusion from numerical limitations</header><text>Aliens provided refugee status under this section shall not be counted against any numerical limitation under section 201, 202, 203, or 207 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1151">8 U.S.C. 1151</external-xref>, 1152, 1153, or 1157).</text></subsection><subsection id="H9A05941077C3435E84592997B0086E4E"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header><paragraph id="H5BBE50D2464349FDAD7667FAA30186C3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and every 90 days thereafter, the Secretary of State and the Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit a report on the matters described in paragraph (2) to—</text><subparagraph id="HF43CED4DE1854179AEFFC014C35B97CB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on the Judiciary and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE7EFFD8C56EC4A57B6A2D3BC0A6150C2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on the Judiciary and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6A26D3490A9C459CA3BF1D4046AD926E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Matters to be included</header><text>Each report required by paragraph (1) shall include—</text><subparagraph id="HC69A5FA98C844FEC9EFC30202ABC81AB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the total number of applications that are pending at the end of the reporting period;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2E1BCC6392064B0792D6A091DF75667F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the average wait-times for all applicants who are, as of the date of the report, awaiting—</text><clause id="HD624E2D6B43C46038CCA4953DE192CA8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>employment verification;</text></clause><clause id="H0F53305B11284F7B91546576B36302A0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a prescreening interview with a resettlement support center;</text></clause><clause id="H91B6D75A8A05425E93753BD40CF2D35C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>an interview with U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services; and</text></clause><clause id="H460BB0C641C7470792122B16509B6487"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the completion of security checks; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H22FBF0134FCD4C1F833136AECE81B2A1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the number of denials of applications for refugee status, disaggregated by the reason for each such denial.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5198D2FFA49B4FC9AA620EE8172292B2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Form</header><text>Each report required by paragraph (1) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5CF786B800B64B4CABC8594A31CC15F3"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Public reports</header><text>The Secretary of State shall make each report submitted under this subsection available to the public on the internet website of the Department of State.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H88FF12EBA08C483E9DBAD02E009EC826"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Satisfaction of other requirements</header><text>Aliens granted status under this section as Priority 2 refugees of special humanitarian concern under the refugee resettlement priority system shall be considered to satisfy the requirements under section 207 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1157">8 U.S.C. 1157</external-xref>) for admission to the United States.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

