<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" dms-id="H3274E4D7DCA04706BFC13141E6C125CA" public-private="public" key="G" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 789 : Transparency and Predictability in Small Business Opportunities Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 789</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250604">June 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSSB00">Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Administrator of the Small Business Administration to issue rules for cancelled covered solicitations, to amend the Small Business Act to provide assistance to small business concerns relating to certain cancelled solicitations, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9C5CFF41AC3D43DE9E5514AA58588433" style="OLC"><pagebreak></pagebreak><section id="H30A26716EDE04AA4A4356896638D6E8D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Transparency and Predictability in Small Business Opportunities Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H563D58AA4FB94FD5B111A498A6CFBB15" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Small Business Administration rules for cancelled covered solicitations</header><subsection id="H02462869F38E4525A9DD9E86CD6A15F2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Small Business Administration shall issue rules as follows:</text><paragraph id="HE3B9831BB5094E8D964658E0AFC7CA0C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Requiring disclosure of information about a covered solicitation that was issued and cancelled that includes the following:</text><subparagraph id="HD2E571DB7278490CAA6F159EBAB2E59A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A justification for the cancellation of such covered solicitation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1571737F76324D21B9D24965B49F400F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Available information about any plans to reissue such covered solicitation and any associated timeframes for such reissuance.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1EB3A9854A0046C18C358E52687E8BE3"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Available information about any plans to include the requirements of such covered solicitation in another contract or task order of the Federal agency.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H07191D8FCA68482184BCC0FDD0355935"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to a cancelled covered solicitation which the Federal agency does not intend to reissue, establishing procedures for the referral of a small business concern (as defined under section 3 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/632">15 U.S.C. 632</external-xref>)) that prepared a bid for such covered solicitation to the Director of Small and Disadvantaged Business Utilization (as defined in section 15(k) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/644">15 U.S.C. 644(k)</external-xref>)) of the Federal agency for assistance in identifying similar contracting opportunities.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAA4FD556934344038FC2D4D29EA491E2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Publication</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The information required under subsection (a) shall be made publicly accessible on the single, Government-wide point of entry described under section 1708 of title 41, United States Code.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5FA98C510CC24F5EB365D1A7EA2211EA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Covered solicitation defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>covered solicitation</term> means a solicitation of a Federal agency for a procurement for which two or more small business concerns were eligible to submit a bid.</text></subsection></section><section id="H44782CBE2CFB40D39547DC782AE43F4F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Duties for Directors of Offices of Small and Disadvantaged Business Utilization relating to certain cancelled solicitations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 15(k) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/644">15 U.S.C. 644(k)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H045B2469F17C44FC83E07A9A9923FC7A" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (21), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBC96537A213C495AA256E6B7E51A2F4C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HDDC13ECE24234C7AB949B51036101083" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H4299F61A0E4B4499B081A6733004DCDC"><enum>(22)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall, when notified by a small business concern that a Federal agency cancelled a solicitation for which such concern prepared a bid and such Federal agency does not intend to reissue such solicitation, assist such concern with identifying similar contracting opportunities.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="H9B9B4C00DAD54B8FAA3BA74FA4DCF1FB"><enum>4.</enum><header>No additional funds authorized</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No additional funds are authorized to carry out the requirements of this Act and the amendments made by this Act. </text></section></legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20250603" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives June 3, 2025.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Kevin F. McCumber,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation></bill> 

