<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-DAV25249-043-R4-7MH"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S935 IS: To prohibit sales and the issuance of licenses for the export of certain defense articles to the United Arab Emirates, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 935</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250311" legis-day="20250310">March 11 (legislative day, March 10), 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To prohibit sales and the issuance of licenses for the export of certain defense articles to the United Arab Emirates, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="idf33686c4eb6f4a129038692055a99fc9"><enum>1.</enum><header>Limitation on sales and exports of covered defense articles to the United Arab Emirates</header><subsection id="id7a94e4f82156448f9af2f1f8f95470c1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, the President may not sell or issue a license for the export of covered defense articles under the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2751">22 U.S.C. 2751 et seq.</external-xref>) to the United Arab Emirates, or any agency or instrumentality of the United Arab Emirates, until the President certifies to the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives that the United Arab Emirates is not providing materiel support to the Rapid Support Forces in Sudan.</text></subsection><subsection id="id22ba3261d26b475ab65922465e22e59a"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Covered defense articles defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>covered defense articles</term> means articles listed under Category I, II, III, IV, V, VI, VII, VIII, XIV, XVI, XVII, or XVIII of the United States Munitions List in part 121 of title 22, Code of Federal Regulations. </text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

