<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H04E056EDC87D41BE92766CA183A9F2F1" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5486 IH: Tyler Clementi Higher Education Anti-Harassment Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5486</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250918">September 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="A000380">Mr. Amo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001318">Ms. Balint</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001324">Mr. Bell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001066">Ms. Castor of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001119">Ms. Craig</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001130">Ms. Crockett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000629">Ms. Davids of Kansas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000631">Ms. Dean of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000399">Mr. Doggett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000454">Mr. Foster</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000462">Ms. Lois Frankel of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000598">Mr. Garcia of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001066">Mr. Horsford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000402">Mr. Kennedy of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000602">Ms. Lee of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001223">Mr. Magaziner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001232">Mrs. McClain Delaney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001227">Ms. McClellan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001220">Mr. McGarvey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001206">Mr. Morelle</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001217">Mr. Moskowitz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001214">Mr. Mrvan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000172">Ms. Ocasio-Cortez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000617">Mrs. Ramirez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000579">Mr. Ryan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001226">Ms. Salinas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001221">Ms. Scholten</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001207">Ms. Sherrill</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001231">Ms. Simon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000510">Mr. Smith of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001230">Mr. Subramanyam</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000788">Ms. Williams of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001208">Mrs. McBath</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001229">Mrs. McIver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="U000040">Ms. Underwood</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prevent harassment at institutions of higher education, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HAEFBA0BB43BD4C0785C522D18A36B6E7" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="HCB4D70FF115C47BD8D6C4022F9AD80FF"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Tyler Clementi Higher Education Anti-Harassment Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HBBE8D6D616194826BD881F88E6F90F4C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Institutional and financial assistance information for students</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 485(f) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1092">20 U.S.C. 1092(f)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H8B7711689405417DBB2D62901308CE5C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking the subsection heading and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Disclosure of campus security and harassment policy and campus crime statistics.</header-in-text></quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC46BC96CB7E84B6CB32BC49891B5A2A7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (6)(A)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HBB5F477742AF45BB84250BF2E3D8FD91"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating clauses (iii), (iv), and (v) as clauses (vi), (vii), and (viii), respectively; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5727B64B236A45C2AE79A0D97ECC1FB4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting after clause (ii) the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE7D731CD8EDF44C28262D9DA10DA96C4"> 
<clause commented="no" id="H03576A8C26DC4B1D883959E096030EA6" indent="up2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The term <quote>commercial mobile service</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 332(d) of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/332">47 U.S.C. 332(d)</external-xref>).</text></clause> <clause commented="no" id="H7300A6507E8A49B9837E5EA92590F609" indent="up2"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The term <quote>electronic communication</quote> means any transfer of signs, signals, writing, images, sounds, or data of any nature transmitted in whole or in part by a wire, radio, electromagnetic, photoelectronic, or photooptical system.</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" id="H962DFAFABC4047BF8F5FD0FEBBF4315E" indent="up2"><enum>(v)</enum><text>The term <quote>electronic messaging services</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 102 of the Communications Assistance for Law Enforcement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1001">47 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>).</text></clause><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9FDA2462FB1B4E76B0FA279952842727"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (9) through (18) as paragraphs (10) through (19), respectively; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC8E9C58CCAEC4183AEF813593CA1C6C3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (8) the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H06B00C3B7FEF48F488177E7EA9A69FDC"> <paragraph id="H95715A35F4EF4E4E9039B052E329952D" indent="up1"><enum>(9)</enum> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HADF18EFBF39D4DA895B691C54AB2DC3C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Each institution of higher education participating in any program under this title, other than a foreign institution of higher education, shall develop and distribute as part of the report described in paragraph (1)—</text> 
<clause id="HBC9132D3FCCF4649BC51B11278A01916" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a statement of policy regarding harassment on the basis of a student’s actual or perceived race, color, national origin, sex (including sexual orientation, gender identity, pregnancy, childbirth, a medical condition related to pregnancy or childbirth, a sex stereotype, and sex characteristics, including intersex traits), disability, or religion, which shall include—</text> <subclause id="H9062FE035B144B8892A34CEF1B59AFE9"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a prohibition of such harassment of enrolled students by other students, faculty, and staff—</text> 
<item id="H45D8336281484E249F193DFBA523FB41"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>on campus;</text></item> <item id="H31E6F84E49304BBDA8A109631FB2A833"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>in noncampus buildings or on noncampus property;</text></item> 
<item id="H4EA07CA74A6F4E1CB663F8C65A4712FF"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>on public property;</text></item> <item id="HB8E9D9E943D64791BD539683A82B52F8"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>in dormitories or other residential facilities for students on campus;</text></item> 
<item id="H1BFE7468A8C84B008485C03873A44391"><enum>(ee)</enum><text>through the use of electronic mail addresses issued by the institution of higher education;</text></item> <item id="H67AB50A4471A46CB98C0AACEF1EA4E54"><enum>(ff)</enum><text>through the use of computers and communication networks, including any telecommunications service, owned, operated, or contracted for use by the institution of higher education or its agents; or</text></item> 
<item id="H088E5A8D8F7447F9AAD7E1F0DE9C2B00"><enum>(gg)</enum><text>during an activity sponsored by the institution of higher education or carried out with the use of resources provided by the institution of higher education;</text></item></subclause> <subclause id="H7A7A78C015604C688865447D4D6BB8A6"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a prohibition of such harassment that is carried out in whole or in part through the use of electronic messaging services, commercial mobile services, electronic communications, or other technology;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H06286B0A757A4EBAB1655AA93771BA25"><enum>(III)</enum><text>a description of the institution's programs to combat harassment, which shall be aimed at the prevention of harassment;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H1CE8D3702BAB479A97F6B5BFDDAC0FC0"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>a description of the procedures that a student should follow if an incident of harassment occurs; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HD436B1F58ACB457E9E7C769EB11A128B"><enum>(V)</enum><text>a description of the procedures that the institution will follow once an incident of harassment has been reported; and</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HAFDE727D416248DF80A119999F2CE35F" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a detailed description of each occasion in which a pattern of harassment occurs based on one or more of the characteristics described in clause (i) and the actions taken by the institution of higher education.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAB2A01918FE54E568A5EC561E03D2708" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The statement of policy described in subparagraph (A)(i) shall address the following areas:</text> <clause id="H7A8D5846C5A64F59A08AC71FB5A8B83E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Procedures for timely institutional action in cases of alleged harassment, which procedures shall include a clear statement that the accuser and the accused shall be informed of the outcome of any disciplinary proceedings in response to an allegation of harassment.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H328B85E296E84C51AD5E0BDBC65AE995"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Possible sanctions to be imposed following the final determination of an institutional disciplinary procedure regarding harassment.</text></clause> <clause id="H7218BC12C0B24043BC74D6E891CD613B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Notification of existing counseling, mental health, or student and employee services for victims or perpetrators of harassment, both on campus and in the community.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H1EA315621D1C46288A8A59DC7A36E64B"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Identification of a designated employee or office at the institution that will be responsible for receiving and tracking each report of harassment by a student, faculty, or staff member.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> <section id="HB513553FA37E4FBF9A2FBAEC2EBA113E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Anti-harassment Competitive Grant program</header> <subsection id="H64E0B2B5F90441A498CCC870AA4ABA47"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="HAFFD4F4FB30844358A2B929835F7A67D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <quote>eligible entity</quote> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H3C0962AC2D114706AEB0CF49D2E931CC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an institution of higher education, including an institution of higher education in a collaborative partnership with a nonprofit organization; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0421B2FEA2AE490085BAF18E27A5ECF3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a consortium of institutions of higher education located in the same State.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H213F780AD6B740A3AFD768E57FE8A7F4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of Education.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0D9BD2D2817443F78958D8A3688280D5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Program authorized</header><text>The Secretary is authorized to award grants, on a competitive basis, to eligible entities to enable eligible entities to carry out the authorized activities described in subsection (d).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H84C75ADCE64943B2BBA09078FF262FC4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Amount of grant awards</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that each grant awarded under this section is of sufficient amount to enable the grantee to meet the purpose of this section.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HBF8BA3DB956948679E4B9B574AE7B123"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorized activities</header><text>An eligible entity that receives a grant under this section shall use the funds made available through the grant to address harassment on the basis of one or more of the characteristics described in section 485(f)(9)(A)(i) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1092">20 U.S.C. 1092(f)(9)(A)(i)</external-xref>), as amended by section 2 of this Act, by initiating, expanding, or improving programs—</text> <paragraph id="HA0DC48752AEB4192A42B82C093DC3F46"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to prevent the harassment of students at institutions of higher education;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3ED05932FA854E2BBE82B03E67EE5056"><enum>(2)</enum><text>at institutions of higher education that provide counseling or redress services to students who have suffered such harassment or students who have been accused of subjecting other students to such harassment; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF3DB8843F5A5438EA0819628488612D7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>that educate or train students, faculty, or staff of institutions of higher education about ways to recognize and prevent harassment or ways to address such harassment if it occurs.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6AED071362FF4642ABB8DFA8EDFDA706"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Application</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, an eligible entity shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information, as the Secretary may require.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="HEC855661DA784C18951945E4099CB21F"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Duration; renewal</header><text>A grant under this section shall be awarded for a period of not more than 3 years. The Secretary may renew a grant under this section for one additional period of not more than 2 years.</text></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" id="HFE1B480AEA774FD28B3D0BD7A9D3AA1E"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Award considerations</header><text>In awarding a grant under this section, the Secretary shall select eligible entities that demonstrate the greatest need for a grant and the greatest potential benefit from receipt of a grant.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H8FCEB4E552594F2F9C3FC922934E53A2"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Report and evaluation</header> <paragraph id="H0B815AD0F44C426AAB3F9ABF03E28076"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Evaluation and report to the Secretary</header><text>Not later than 6 months after the end of the eligible entity's grant period, the eligible entity shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE88D85BDE4FE4D96B3671CBDA8FFF070"><enum>(A)</enum><text>evaluate the effectiveness of the activities carried out with the use of funds awarded pursuant to this section; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1B2E147F632A41A6AC79D33BF95D12E9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>prepare and submit to the Secretary a report on the results of the evaluation conducted by the entity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H893CD2D7A6C243CB8AE39BDCD205C654"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Evaluation and report to Congress</header><text>Not later than 12 months after the date of receipt of the first report submitted pursuant to paragraph (1) and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall provide to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate and the Committee on Education and Workforce of the House of Representatives a report that includes the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H3EA2D917896547DF92759DF3578444CA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The number and types of eligible entities receiving assistance under this section.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H11799212A2A24BBFA6ACE409192EE79E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The anti-harassment programs being implemented with assistance under this section and the costs of such programs.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H87B42E260236412F97C54FB7B5119118"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Any other information determined by the Secretary to be useful in evaluating the overall effectiveness of the program established under this section in decreasing incidents of harassment at institutions of higher education.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H37E73958678649789D02EBB2B2C9E250"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Best practices report</header><text>The Secretary shall use the information provided under paragraph (1) to publish a report of evidence-based best practices for combating harassment at institutions of higher education, which shall be based on scientific research that meets nationally recognized standards. The report shall be made available to all institutions of higher education and other interested parties.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H83154B4DB6784704B7268AACD92C4892"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $50,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2031.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H89610FF1D56E48DDBD511547104E857C"><enum>4.</enum><header>Effect on other laws</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed to invalidate or limit rights, remedies, procedures, or legal standards available under any other Federal law or law of a State or political subdivision of a State, including title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d">42 U.S.C. 2000d et seq.</external-xref>), title IX of the Education Amendments of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1681">20 U.S.C. 1681 et seq.</external-xref>), section 504 or 505 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/794">29 U.S.C. 794</external-xref>, 794a), or the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12101">42 U.S.C. 12101 et seq.</external-xref>). The obligations imposed by this Act are in addition to those imposed by title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d">42 U.S.C. 2000d et seq.</external-xref>), title IX of the Education Amendments of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1681">20 U.S.C. 1681 et seq.</external-xref>), section 504 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/794">29 U.S.C. 794</external-xref>), and the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12101">42 U.S.C. 12101 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></section> </legis-body></bill>

