<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H55CFDF1B87EC40A49D577B444A622B5E" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 563 IH: Expressing support for the designation of July as “American Pride Month”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 563</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250630">June 30, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001095">Mr. Hunt</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of July as <quote>American Pride Month</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble>
<whereas><text>Whereas the purpose of American Pride Month is to celebrate, memorialize, and increase awareness of the monumental achievements of the United States of America and the countless number of patriots throughout her history which have made this Nation the last best hope of earth;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas President Ronald Reagan said in his farewell address to the Nation, we’ve got to teach history based not on what’s in fashion but what’s important;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas the purpose of American Pride Month is to bring American exceptionalism back into the spotlight and to teach our children what it means to be an American;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas we recognize the brave patriots of the American War of Independence and their courage in the fight for self-government;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas their sacrifices laid the groundwork for the prosperous Nation we have today;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas we recognize the Founding Fathers of our Nation and the Framers of the Constitution by which our country was founded;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas we recognize a Nation that fought a civil war to preserve its union and free four million Americans from the original sin of slavery;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas we recognize the sacrifices made of the American patriots who served in World War I;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas it was considered the war to end all wars, until the next one, when another generation of young men were called to serve and if necessary, lay down their lives to preserve freedom;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas we recognize the achievements made by the Greatest Generation during World War II, the efforts of brave American patriots across our country to mobilize the war effort, the struggle to free Europe from the fascist grip of Hitler, and war in the Pacific to defeat the Empire of Japan with the full might of the United States Military;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas we recognize the bold and daring American Astronauts who won the space race, walked on the moon, ended a Cold War, and the brilliant men and women of NASA who supported them;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas we honor and salute the American Troops who lost their lives in Vietnam, those who returned and did not receive the hero’s welcome they deserved, and those who never returned;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas America owes them a debt of gratitude we can never repay, but their devotion to our Nation, often paid in blood, deserves remembrance;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas we recognize the many civil rights leaders, activists, faith leaders, college students, high school students, shop owners, and others who risked their lives to fight for equal rights for all Americans;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas we recognize the significance of the terror attacks on the American homeland on September 11, 2001, and the resilience, patriotism, and unity shown by the American people in the wake of the worst attack on our Nation since Pearl Harbor;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas we honor the fearless men and women who volunteered to serve this country in every conflict fought home and abroad since the founding of our Nation;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas we recognize the explorers, entrepreneurs, and historical figures who embodied the American ethos and who have inspired generations of Americans to follow in their footsteps;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas we memorialize the efforts of trailblazers like Lewis and Clark, Davy Crockett, Daniel Boone, Albert Einstein, Thomas Edison, the Wright Brothers, Amelia Earhart, and President Theodore Roosevelt;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas we remember and learn from the example set by great patriotic leaders like Patrick Henry, John Adams, Thomas Jefferson, Alexander Hamilton, Betsy Ross, Benjamin Franklin, George Washington, Ulysses S. Grant, General Dwight D. Eisenhower, Susan B. Anthony, Rosa Parks, Paul Revere, Booker T. Washington, Harriet Tubman, the Buffalo Soldiers, Clara Barton, Samuel Adams, and so many more; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas we understand that preserving America for the next generation starts and ends with teaching its history: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HAD344B7663FE435E90743945FD525577"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H1F331ADF0F344FF28506496C9C1E7944"><text>That the House of Representatives expresses support for the designation of <quote>American Pride Month</quote>.</text></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

