<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-WAL25255-KP0-G7-5L4"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1213 IS: Protect Elections from Deceptive AI Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1213</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250331">March 31, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S399">Mr. Hawley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S252">Ms. Collins</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S330">Mr. Bennet</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSRA00">Committee on Rules and Administration</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To prohibit the distribution of materially deceptive AI-generated audio or visual media relating to candidates for Federal office, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="idd34ed65d-1e5b-4397-b7a6-888e67f04b55" changed="not-changed"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protect Elections from Deceptive AI Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section section-type="subsequent-section" id="id80440be2-7e51-40ff-8d79-d96c06268098" changed="not-changed"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on distribution of materially deceptive AI-generated audio or visual media prior to election</header><subsection id="id8bc54852-6759-4ca1-9935-7d3e50b72e5f" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title III of the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/30101">52 U.S.C. 30101 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc0e004ab-b752-4fce-8a68-806c50ab7f9b" changed="not-changed"><section id="ide851b2f4-b0f6-4166-b7d4-5fc907719d74" changed="not-changed"><enum>325.</enum><header>Prohibition on distribution of materially deceptive AI-generated audio or visual media</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc7f42993-09e5-460b-8ce5-e5e36a366137" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id21f2ae08-5f31-4c24-80bb-50a5ddc2274f" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Covered individual</header><text>The term <quote>covered individual</quote> means a candidate for Federal office.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1af53433-e8a8-4ca3-a02c-03c064526214" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Deceptive AI-generated audio or visual media</header><text>The term <quote>deceptive AI-generated audio or visual media</quote> means an image, audio, or video that— </text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9fc4b001-6d93-461c-9a4f-c5b760aaeeba" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is the product of artificial intelligence technology that uses machine learning (including deep learning models, natural learning processing, or any other computational processing techniques of similar or greater complexity), that— </text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddf41df20-c7c5-41da-8e3e-dfe02b3ccfe7" changed="not-changed"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">merges, combines, replaces, or superimposes content onto an image, audio, or video, creating an image, audio, or video that appears authentic; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8a7e88fb-ec8c-4310-9a0d-754d63f8e901" changed="not-changed"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>generates an inauthentic image, audio, or video that appears authentic; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id065e2872-e06c-4f7e-8eb1-29025270c636" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a reasonable person, having considered the qualities of the image, audio, or video and the nature of the distribution channel in which the image, audio, or video appears—</text><clause id="id2700172c-072d-4733-bd75-da996a00aeba" changed="not-changed"><enum>(i)</enum><text>would have a fundamentally different understanding or impression of the appearance, speech, or expressive conduct exhibited in the image, audio, or video than that person would have if that person were hearing or seeing the unaltered, original version of the image, audio, or video; or</text></clause><clause id="id1b14f35d-fb73-4f1d-aee4-0c70d72a9089" changed="not-changed"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>would believe that the image, audio, or video accurately exhibits any appearance, speech, or expressive conduct of a person who did not actually exhibit such appearance, speech, or expressive conduct. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc732d034-1490-4f1a-beb3-4e2367573139" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Federal election activity</header><text>The term <quote>Federal election activity</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 301(20)(A)(iii). </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id3d3a4595-3856-4f17-9b8b-ad10e424f669" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subsection (c), a person, political committee, or other entity may not knowingly distribute materially deceptive AI-generated audio or visual media in carrying out a Federal election activity or of a covered individual for the purpose of—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id568b02a4-02ff-420a-aad4-837e0aa5e0e1" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">influencing an election; or</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idabc7a4b9-a866-4f22-97a5-e26d9ad34f41" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">soliciting funds. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idb241dd81-5dd8-4a5b-ace5-1d7a52887e1d" changed="not-changed"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Inapplicability to certain entities</header><text>This section shall not apply to the following:</text><paragraph id="id7027fcc8-499c-40ad-866c-0d0951fcae97" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A radio or television broadcasting station, including a cable or satellite television operator, programmer, or producer, or a streaming service that broadcasts materially deceptive AI-generated audio or visual media prohibited by this section as part of a bona fide newscast, news interview, news documentary, or on-the-spot coverage of bona fide news events, if the broadcast clearly acknowledges through content or a disclosure, in a manner that can be easily heard or read by the average listener or viewer, that there are questions about the authenticity of the materially deceptive AI-generated audio or visual media.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id16d48e11-7cb3-4625-bb34-e1726fa7cda2" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A regularly published newspaper, magazine, or other periodical of general circulation, including an internet or electronic publication, that routinely carries news and commentary of general interest, and that publishes materially deceptive AI-generated audio or visual media prohibited under this section, if the publication clearly states that the materially deceptive AI-generated audio or visual media does not accurately represent the speech or conduct of the covered individual.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7a062f58-f9b7-48a5-9303-707fc3637212" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Materially deceptive AI-generated audio or visual media that constitutes satire or parody.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id3651d291-f696-4306-9b4c-3c461de7a5c3" changed="not-changed"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Civil action</header><paragraph id="ideec8e30a-8b89-40a4-8926-d96604e755c9" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Injunctive or other equitable relief</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4bc70121-bb8c-44c5-835f-8f0d343d6bd3" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A covered individual whose voice or likeness appears in, or who is the subject of, a materially deceptive AI-generated audio or visual media, including content distributed as part of a Federal election activity, distributed in violation of this section may seek injunctive or other equitable relief prohibiting the distribution of materially deceptive AI-generated audio or visual media in violation of this section. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6f67fce7-32c6-40c6-b6f5-f9a458109109" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Precedence</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An action under this paragraph shall be entitled to precedence in accordance with the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="iddf3f702d-3984-4e48-9591-c5bea06c5730" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Damages</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idea2f457e-60be-4c1b-98ec-b579819c236c" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A covered individual whose voice or likeness appears in, or who is the subject of, a materially deceptive AI-generated audio or visual media, including content distributed as part of a Federal election activity, distributed in violation of this section may bring an action for general or special damages against the person, committee, or other entity that distributed the materially deceptive AI-generated audio or visual media. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idea0728c9-d29d-4894-8e44-0dc233a6b799" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Attorney's fees and costs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to any damages awarded under subparagraph (A), the court may also award a prevailing party reasonable attorney’s fees and costs. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1fb68ac6-0a9a-460d-a7c7-04fd580e9878" changed="not-changed"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed to limit or preclude a plaintiff from securing or recovering any other available remedy.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id00cc29c7-0d9b-40b4-ae89-98d065093775" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Burden of proof</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In any civil action alleging a violation of this section, the plaintiff shall bear the burden of establishing the violation through clear and convincing evidence.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idad7d615c-59bf-4afa-9458-1b38e77a51a5" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Severability</header><text>If any provision of this Act, or an amendment made by this Act, or the application of such provision to any person or circumstance, is held to be invalid, the remainder of this Act, or an amendment made by this Act, or the application of such provision to other persons or circumstances, shall not be affected. </text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

