<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ALL25670-NT5-LS-1CT"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2573 IS: Foreign Property Ownership Transparency Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2573</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250731">July 31, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Comptroller General of the United States to conduct a study on the purchase of residential real estate in the United States by foreign individuals, entities, and governments, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Foreign Property Ownership Transparency Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3acd92cf4ef04484a0ee2c82b121e1da"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="id1e5cae499be64fc78dc34718397ada43"><enum>(1)</enum><text>There has been a marked increase in foreign purchases of residential real estate in the United States in recent years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idcc211a2e474b4481b8f5d7ee7f9ead56"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Some foreign purchases of residential real estate are made through shell companies or trusts, raising concerns about transparency and beneficial ownership.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id642356f5af5f42b490f4e082241a722c"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Foreign ownership of residential real estate may impact housing affordability, particularly in high-demand urban and coastal markets.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9b08c6d0f243463aafe7365a654c9940"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Federal Government currently lacks a comprehensive, coordinated understanding of the extent and impact of foreign residential property ownership.</text></paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6b123cec9ceb4fff871352a331f62dce"><enum>3.</enum><header>Study on foreign residential real estate purchases</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id098df42df557489e86ef7f37710f2a90"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>The Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a study on the purchase of residential real estate in the United States by foreign individuals, entities, and governments.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id441cc01a197c4af1a1bd50b4c8434dde"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Scope</header><text>The study conducted under subsection (a) shall include—</text><paragraph id="idae1fcadfaa0e4b52a7e45addb31fa54c"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an analysis of the volume and geographic concentration of foreign residential real estate purchases in the United States since January 1, 2015;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddc03097a858f41c2a68bcfa18cd24c83"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an assessment of the ownership structures used in the purchases described in paragraph (1), including shell companies and trusts;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc4a7fe94d7d0409db5435d8479871a36"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an evaluation of the implications of the purchases described in paragraph (1) on housing affordability and availability for residents of the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7e954ed9b6364cc89e4c43957f7ea07c"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a review of Federal, State, and local data collection efforts on foreign property ownership and any gaps in that data; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1f21f109872c44038c0171950a9a0d0d"><enum>(5)</enum><text>a review of relevant national security concerns relating to the purchases described in paragraph (1), including proximity of properties to sensitive sites.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id549f1b64c1004355a8fce627737875d0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the Committee on Finance of the Senate a report of the study conducted under subsection (a).</text></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7f76f5f88f0841d59e5cbc9ed3f0fe77"><enum>4.</enum><header>HUD assessment and recommendations</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3b73e00742324e4ead1d0484c354f067"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, in coordination with the Comptroller General of the United States, shall—</text><paragraph id="idd2aecd8f0b17499b8521a5c4c47858dd"><enum>(1)</enum><text>review the findings of the study required under section 3(a);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id638e36e54b8d4e25bb4e8aad3a776306"><enum>(2)</enum><text>evaluate the impact of foreign real estate investment on housing markets and affordability in the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8307e81c76354107964665d97d025c2f"><enum>(3)</enum><text>consult with State and local housing authorities on trends in the foreign purchase of residential real estate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id21df8301c0d844bc9d8fd4ab467c8d0b"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Policy Recommendations</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of submission of the report under section 3(c), the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development shall submit to Congress a report that includes—</text><paragraph id="id633f39f2c8064c6fa13ec7dc00027814"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recommendations for improving the transparency of foreign ownership in residential property transactions in the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf7dfbfc1bf83447fb74d21f2683fa4c8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recommendations for protecting access to residential real estate transactions for residents of the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6025e13ae9fe415cbe4066dfb7829596"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any legislative or regulatory actions determined necessary to carry out the recommendations described in paragraph (1) and (2).</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

