<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HEDBDB5118F214F7FBA95F97C8C7B8282" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4329 IH: Building Civic Bridges Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4329</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250710">July 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001085">Ms. Houlahan</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="B001282">Mr. Barr</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001208">Mrs. McBath</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000467">Mr. Thompson of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001112">Mr. Carbajal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000397">Mrs. Kim</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001213">Mr. Moore of Utah</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the National and Community Service Act of 1990 to establish an Office of Civic Bridgebuilding within the Corporation for National and Community Service, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF27D32A8F989430990CC8DA9BA8DDA3D" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="H0ABAB6CC73BE4BD79306B97AAD42ACC1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Building Civic Bridges Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H119C01FD211E4F8E813898047DD833F9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Civic Bridgebuilding</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subtitle H of title I of the National and Community Service Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12653">42 U.S.C. 12653 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDA72D2B5359949E49B2DD49512CA5617"><part id="HAA777D10094D4F27BB36F443B4F27A96"><enum>VI</enum><header>Civic Bridgebuilding</header><section id="H37C9BD8F19174C68B0A4A6411034D187"><enum>198T.</enum><header>Office of Civic Bridgebuilding</header><subsection id="HC8EB403DA4734D2BACE6B05903A2A0AB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There shall be in the Corporation an Office of Civic Bridgebuilding (in this section referred to as the <quote>Office</quote>). The Office shall be headed by an Officer of Civic Bridgebuilding, who shall be designated by the Chief Executive Officer pursuant to section 195(b).</text></subsection><subsection id="HA5CDE33A876843DABC5099C00DA8DC2C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Officer of Civic Bridgebuilding shall carry out each of the following:</text><paragraph id="H94A47E30C3614E9C826F5ABF839E70A3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Administer the grant program described in subsection (d) to support civic bridgebuilding across the United States, including by establishing standardized criteria (based on principles of scientific research and input through the consultation process under subsection (c)) to track the effectiveness of projects and activities funded under such program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H48D062FE42AB4D5DA0DD75EED3E3A05A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Support the Corporation in providing training in skills and techniques relevant to civic bridgebuilding (based on principles of scientific research and input through the consultation process under subsection (c))—</text><subparagraph id="H385949882D2348169F56112656E5987D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for participants (including individuals who have been selected to be participants) of a program receiving funding under the authority of the national service laws; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7B9AD96080CD451780D5767665F9A6DD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>upon request by an organization that receives funding under the authority of the national service laws or that is carrying out a program in which participants described in subparagraph (A) are participating, for such organization.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H59087C4235ED423795A41C47D5F605CD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Support research and evaluations on civic bridgebuilding and the dissemination of related information, including through—</text><subparagraph id="HA9354D9FC9244BC8A37E35A1D346B87F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>evaluation and oversight of the grant program described in subsection (d);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H19CBB4BB7E934A84B83AD0026535CE45"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">as the Corporation determines necessary, collaboration (including through the evaluation of the activities of the Corporation relating to civic bridgebuilding and civic engagement) between the Office and—</text><clause id="H80C7F0C914144FCEB029696A13E140C2"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">other offices (such as the Office of Research and Evaluation), teams, or individuals within the Corporation; and</text></clause><clause id="HE110D03E896B46128E08A456DB5E6F7D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>other Federal agencies, including the Community Relations Service of the Department of Justice, the United States Agency for International Development, and the United States Institute of Peace; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H42718865115E459887A10E68CA189932"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the establishment of a publicly available collection of publications for a research base for the purpose of assembling research focused on evaluating the extent to which civic bridgebuilding and civic engagement activities strengthen or weaken other civic bridgebuilding and civic engagement activities and outcomes in the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCE5857992006455A98CC8B2F3F98E0F5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Activate and sustain a public conversation about the importance of civic bridgebuilding by convening and coordinating civic bridgebuilding programs and providing resources, networking, and collaboration opportunities to individuals and entities in the civic bridgebuilding field for the purpose of disseminating and refining best practices based on principles of scientific research and input through the consultation process under subsection (c).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H006DF8DF7EAF4DDA97CD7B1ECA7E0DEF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consultation process</header><paragraph id="HF327E0F540E9442EB2088089F07B1C7D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the duties under this section, the Officer of Civic Bridgebuilding shall consult with members of the civic bridgebuilding field, including for purposes of—</text><subparagraph id="H8B7E70DED872458F86D2DF94D1CAF729"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identifying strategic priorities for the Office;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAC7AA5D48B9044C1BB894C3DA307F7F2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>developing the standardized criteria required under subsection (b)(1);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H70E0E4CBBC704A0384D2FA0C54CE4161"><enum>(C)</enum><text>supporting the development and dissemination of research under subsection (b)(3);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H612C3FE55DC94329ABF0D4DCBD76FF0D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>developing best practices for civic bridgebuilding under subsection (b)(4); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6987204B5D1C455F99514316B6EF8079"><enum>(E)</enum><text>administering the grant program described in subsection (d).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H81BE1DBDCF0B4769AFD254114CCF744C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Diversity in consultation</header><text>In carrying out the consultation under paragraph (1), the Officer of Civic Bridgebuilding shall consult members of the civic bridgebuilding field who represent diverse ideological, religious, racial, regional, professional, or ethnic communities, including such members—</text><subparagraph id="H1A34FF642DB143CFA0492FD1B791D4B0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>who represent eligible entities engaged in civic bridgebuilding;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC23DFEDE4D2B4D259E044FCE064F6C92"><enum>(B)</enum><text>who represent existing or potential programs and grantees receiving funding under the authority of the national service laws, including State Service Commissions;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H866575B8A6DE40189B64BB2173DD54E4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>who are researchers producing work based on principles of scientific research related to civic bridgebuilding in the United States and internationally; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3ADB45F255EC4509B05043F2E3B52EF7"><enum>(D)</enum><text>who represent other Federal agencies or public institutions engaged in or supporting work related to civic bridgebuilding in the United States and internationally, such as—</text><clause id="HE3EF3B461A3F49B695B7D48672C7BB21"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Community Relations Service of the Department of Justice;</text></clause><clause id="HEC40C06CB73F47B0A83314FC3F94C5A8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the United States Agency for International Development; and</text></clause><clause id="HDCF9DD61EA6147BBB03F23DF5A3DBDC3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the United States Institute of Peace.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H71D9B60F869340BF8C10339088FFD625"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Civic bridgebuilding pilot grant program</header><paragraph id="H4F61AEBE3DB745488A77D8858C81BADE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Corporation (acting through the Officer of Civic Bridgebuilding with input through the consultation process under subsection (c))—</text><subparagraph id="H2376B7566FE84AA3A8C6482520444D08"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall carry out a pilot program for a 3-year period to award grants, on a competitive basis, to eligible entities to support civic bridgebuilding programs across the United States for purposes of—</text><clause id="H6235670B0DFD446DABB7F7A33DF994C0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>reducing conflict and improving social cohesion; and</text></clause><clause id="H6F04F36307F94D2E99EF1AF1DD3BC78F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>addressing a public concern such as unmet human, educational, health care, environmental, or public safety needs; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H601D8A6C55844191AB7A775A67B9BFE2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may carry out such a pilot program for additional 3-year periods.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB6FB505D6F7843E698BBC0989E75E392"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Grant period</header><text>A grant awarded under this subsection shall be for a 1-year period. Grants shall be awarded under this subsection in 3 grant cycles for each 3-year period of the pilot program carried out under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA1B742B9393F485F96310C686D52F331"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Application</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under this subsection, an eligible entity shall submit an application to the Corporation at such time, in such manner, and containing such information and assurances as the Corporation may require, including—</text><subparagraph id="H8DF5FED08ACD477C864B49AC433F04A9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of the project that will be funded with the grant;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H706CB812E94D4175B678AC9BF91DF0AD"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an explanation of how that such project will—</text><clause id="HD640C589187748ACBCB5A2428D5CF35D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>engage communities across lines of polarization;</text></clause><clause id="HEA66566D1A1F4ACDACF303A400A90695"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">facilitate the establishment or continuation of civic bridgebuilding and social cohesion, which may include addressing the root causes of polarization and conflict as described in the publicly available collection of publications for a research base established under subsection (b)(3)(C);</text></clause><clause id="H7838617E38C646AC97539FB07E6B1BED"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reflect research supporting the efficacy and impact of the proposed approach for the project; and</text></clause><clause id="H8D594F2C769848EA94479148EBA8571D"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure physical, social, and psychological well-being and safety for all participants involved in the project, including for such participants from historically marginalized communities;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H13A184B856094478A765667D55B4A8B0"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of best practices grounded in principles of scientific research for how such safety will be achieved; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9F286617E2E847DE97231541557C5B3E"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an assurance that the eligible entity will report outcomes of such project to track effectiveness based on standardized criteria established by the Office of Civic Bridgebuilding under subsection (b)(1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC9AEB82C226842F0A2C5CD3CA72A9244"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Uses of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity receiving a grant under this subsection shall use the grant funds to carry out a project to advance civic bridgebuilding in communities across the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H6F920F3D364646CDBE15AFB4FE62A4CE"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Comptroller General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Comptroller General of the United States shall, not later than 18 months after the end of the 3-year period of the program carried out under subsection (d)(1)(A) and, as applicable, not later than 18 months after each 3-year period of the program carried out under subsection (d)(1)(B), submit to Congress a report, which summarizes and assesses the effectiveness and impact of the activities carried out under grants awarded under subsection (d).</text></subsection><subsection id="HED2E2C180DD8427CA06C39ACAADAD478"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph id="H5E905022C728439C9376E815B314AF64"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Civic bridgebuilding</header><text>The term <term>civic bridgebuilding</term>—</text><subparagraph id="HFCAE897399F04C369642ED9CDE7CFC01"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means an activity, grounded in principles of scientific research, that—</text><clause id="H47EAF60906AE4B5B977F77383325BFB4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>fosters respect between diverse communities;</text></clause><clause id="HCEAFA51516A54441AAF16F7A4A61626F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>supports social cohesion and diminishes polarization;</text></clause><clause id="HB9767E816FCD4C17AB0F4E6340B83143"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>forges a sense of common civic purpose; and</text></clause><clause id="H99A5D5FED74B40A6AA720C413A0E526A"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>seeks to address a public concern such as unmet human, educational, health care, environmental, or public safety needs; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9DEBF006E53E4E84B776C9588C550019"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes—</text><clause id="H76E6D106B738472FAD0F09A5E33A8549"><enum>(i)</enum><text>activities that take place in local communities, where individuals and institutions come together to build empathy and social cohesion, strengthen belonging, and address local issues; and</text></clause><clause id="HBD5E9C2A7DCF410BB2C2AC50A85A8360"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>activities at the field level, where civic bridgebuilding leaders work together to share research and best practices, learn from one another, and grow other civic bridgebuilding.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H380EC69132D4423CAC6ACF06A8FC1394"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Civic bridgebuilding field</header><text>The term <term>civic bridgebuilding field</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H8D06433CC2A84A1CB018CDE127B156C3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the programs, leaders, and community groups involved in civic bridgebuilding activities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H36ED830384CA42CB8C7F570E2B96D4D8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>researchers producing work based on principles of scientific research related to civic bridgebuilding in the United States and abroad; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H24B15D3C55744F19BEBA9B245ED75D19"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Federal agencies and public institutions engaged in or supporting work related to civic bridgebuilding in the United States and internationally.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4483738005C34BAE91DB11BD0C4CD7B4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Civic bridgebuilding leader</header><text>The term <term>civic bridgebuilding leader</term> means an individual who leads civic bridgebuilding programs or efforts.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H646758B4A25346C8B10FE1D6598E2005"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Civic engagement</header><text>The term <term>civic engagement</term> means an individual or collective action designed to address a public concern such as an unmet human, educational, health care, environmental, or public safety need.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3C30C8118B224F34988E69E37A501787"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means a nonprofit entity, community- or faith-based organization, institution of higher education (as defined in section 101(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001(a)</external-xref>)), public institution, or consortium of any such entities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H160B1CF19F9D4AFA811DAE9BD94043A2"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Public institution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>public institution</term> means a library or unit of State, local, or special purpose government.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8B20293011DA4C268DB3F0BC9BEC5C4F"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Research base</header><text>The term <term>research base</term> means any publications that contain observations, analysis, and conclusions based on principles of scientific research with respect to the challenges of political and social polarization in the United States, and practical approaches to strengthen social cohesion, foster a sense of national connection, or improve intergroup relations in divided communities.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2378825B1DD14ABCAE40C09D0B5CA7E8"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No Federal funds are authorized to be made available to carry out this section. Such section shall be carried out exclusively using amounts donated under section 196.</text></subsection></section></part><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H34DE8D13946A458CBFCB76081396C3A5"><enum>3.</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The table of contents in section 1(b) of the National and Community Service Act of 1990 is amended by inserting at the end of the item relating to subtitle H of title I, the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6C4AA0FE197B478BB6FF034564614B01"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="part">Part VI—Civic Bridgebuilding</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 198T. Office of Civic Bridgebuilding.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

