<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="HC2FE17179DD6423DA8653C17DDD5B53E"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>106 HR 309 IH: National Law Enforcement Officers Remembrance, Support and Community Outreach Act.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 309</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250109">January 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000026">Mr. Nehls</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001212">Mr. Stauber</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000578">Mr. LaMalfa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001077">Mr. Higgins of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000194">Ms. Mace</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000129">Mr. Valadao</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001291">Mr. Babin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001133">Mr. Ciscomani</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000369">Mr. Amodei of Nevada</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000614">Mr. Pappas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000376">Mr. Kelly of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000579">Mr. Ryan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001119">Ms. Craig</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000597">Mr. Garbarino</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000191">Mr. Neguse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001194">Mr. Moolenaar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001091">Mrs. Hinson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000546">Mr. Graves</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001067">Mr. Hudson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000598">Mr. LaLota</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000470">Mrs. Fischbach</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to provide funding for the National Law Enforcement Museum, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HFD5235716E9942A88C0473B81E7F5505"><section id="H42C6E7B15F1847FC9AEC9E12B2EBF2FC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"> This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>National Law Enforcement Officers Remembrance, Support and Community Outreach Act.</short-title></quote></text></section><section id="H40EFAD92DBB940D8AEF880EC46E98FAB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"> The Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H9C42892665DA46268D4D87ADD0C8FD32"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The National Law Enforcement Officers Memorial and the National Law Enforcement Museum in Washington, DC represent the only law enforcement campus in the United States and serves a critical national mission of honoring and remembering those law enforcement officers who have died in the line of duty, educating the public about the important role of law enforcement in a democratic society and working to reduce the number of line of duty deaths and injuries among law enforcement.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC49B5E9396404F03AFBCD79791DA4F30"><enum>(2)</enum><text>It is in the national interest to ensure that the unique education and outreach programs of the National Law Enforcement Museum be maintained and enhanced.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6B23D4B8A0484864AF35D900034FAFDF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In 1984, Congress passed and President Ronald Reagan signed into law a joint resolution to authorize the Law Enforcement Officers Memorial Fund, Inc., to establish a National Law Enforcement Heroes Memorial (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/98/534">Public Law 98–534</external-xref>) in Washington, DC.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEC2FE597F9E34EBE936A65E52D5BD9E6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Dedicated on October 15, 1991, the National Law Enforcement Officers Memorial honors Federal, tribal, State, and local law enforcement officers who have made the ultimate sacrifice for the safety and protection of our Nation and its people. The National Law Enforcement Officers Memorial is centered in the 400 block of E Street, NW, Washington, DC and is the nation’s monument to law enforcement officers who have died in the line of duty. The Memorial was built entirely with private funds.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA50B35141BDA4EF88FF5AAA04D149437"><enum>(5)</enum><text>In 2000, Congress passed and President William J. Clinton signed into law the National Law Enforcement Museum Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/106/492">Public Law 106–492</external-xref>), which authorized the National Law Enforcement Officers Memorial Fund, Inc. to build and operate the National Law Enforcement Museum on Federal land in the District of Columbia to honor and commemorate the service and sacrifice of law enforcement officers in the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBCB1F89250C147B6B8849EE659F21E91"><enum>(6)</enum><text>In April 2016, construction began on the National Law Enforcement Museum in the District of Columbia across the street from the National Law Enforcement Officers Memorial in Judiciary Square. In October of 2018 the National Law Enforcement Museum was completed and formally opened. No Federal funds were used to build the Museum.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE141E35B0CDA4B3FB24AE67450922215"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The National Law Enforcement Museum’s mission is—</text><subparagraph id="H133189D1297C452CBFFF20462EEDCD75"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to honor and commemorate the extraordinary service and sacrifice of America’s law enforcement officers;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5432C70AD82B458C8788F4F36ACA35F2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to serve as an important bridge between law enforcement’s past and present, between the heroes of yesteryear and those who have followed in their footsteps, and between America’s peace officers and the public they serve; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA98CE8C710F945048F7F6FD1945FE5D4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to increase public understanding and support for law enforcement and to promote law enforcement safety.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2D5C4A26BB4C4283AF75CD28D5E325C2"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The programs of the National Law Enforcement Museum play a critical role in educating the public about the vital importance of law enforcement in a democratic society, the critical role law enforcement plays in protecting and serving the public, and the sacrifices law enforcement officers have made to serve in this role.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7540F69C376F4E66BE273CB2DDA8EB55"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The community education and outreach programs, activities, and special exhibits within the National Law Enforcement Museum help bring local law enforcement agencies closer to the communities they serve, and help to foster a better understanding between law enforcement and communities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H92AA2ECDD1CF4E6C99AEDAE94964FF35"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The National Law Enforcement Museum’s Officer Safety and Wellness education and outreach programs and activities help provide local, State and Federal law enforcement agencies with critical information on best practices to reduce the number of line of duty deaths and injuries and provide communities and the public with education concerning the sacrifices made. These programs, activities, and special exhibits are vitally important at a time when annual line of duty deaths among law enforcement officers remain at an historically high level.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB88E69FCAA0E40108DDE6BFB6B50C8F0"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Since the establishment in 1991 of the National Law Enforcement Officers Memorial, and the dedication of the National Law Enforcement Museum in 2018, the National Law Enforcement Officers Memorial Fund and the National Law Enforcement Museum have worked cooperatively with local, State and Federal law enforcement agencies to properly honor the sacrifices made by law enforcement, and provide key programming to reduce the number of law enforcement fatalities and injuries, and foster better understanding between law enforcement and the communities they serve.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H40FFFABC6C4148B29D64D40278B9CEF7"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Law enforcement agencies around the country are dedicated to continuous improvement and innovation in officer and community safety, and to building trust through community-based engagement and interventions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H06C2BF1B48B34678B904E91217DC7561"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Since 2020, there has been a significant increase in the number of law enforcement officers resigning or retiring. According to the Police Executive Research Forum, over the past three years there has been an almost 24-percent increase in the number of law enforcement officers retiring, and more than 47-percent increase in the number of law enforcement officers resigning.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB9512807A1634A84ABB09F5092DCCF18"><enum>(14)</enum><text>A number of law enforcement agencies across the country remain under-staffed, and many law enforcement agencies have been forced to declare personnel emergencies and require mandatory overtime.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC8A2C3EC29804C1F8212BD7ADBBD8566"><enum>(15)</enum><text>The resulting deficit in confidence and support jeopardizes public safety. There is a critical need to enhance public understanding and appreciation of law enforcement, and to improve the safety and wellness of officers who serve our communities. Fostering a more informed and positive relationship between law enforcement and the public is essential for societal safety and cohesion. A sustained national effort to restore confidence and understanding in law enforcement is urgently needed.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H8EBCE4D9530349C39DAA8B58982DA83D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Support for the national law enforcement museum</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">During the first seven fiscal years beginning after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Interior shall award a grant to the National Law Enforcement Officers Memorial Fund for the expenses associated with operating and enhancing the community outreach, public education, and officer safety and wellness programs of the National Law Enforcement Museum, including programs to:</text><paragraph id="H8B00CB047B934D489E0664D9C349BA7E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Memorialize law enforcement heroes who die in the line of duty and compile statistics on law enforcement fatalities and injuries.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H55791D4CE0D74E2BB71059074E4E8758"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Honor and commemorate the extraordinary service and sacrifice of America’s law enforcement officers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC28726AF7495410BADCFE0F589A0542B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Develop and make available accurate, relevant, and accessible resources to promote the understanding of law enforcement history and officer safety and wellness training, which include digital resources and other types of resources, such as print resources and traveling exhibitions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H33401109F35746288166499809E42EA7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Increase technical resources to better engage the public in person and via online platforms to educate and inform the public about community policing and officer safety and wellness.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC1C0ACC4C80242D0B0AC9A87ABE958A4"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Create, expand and disseminate scholarly work through research, curricula, in-house and traveling exhibitions, publications, and other outreach initiatives.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3411AB50DABD47E28BEF8D384EC40240"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Expand the collection acquisition and collection processes, including staffing, conservation, processing, and digitization.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEC7405E9BE2A47CB84375E0EB167CABB"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Augment law enforcement history and officer safety and wellness education activities, including the development, dissemination, and implementation of principles of sound pedagogy for teaching about law enforcement history and officer safety and wellness.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H91DE783A5EF447338FF93BE0A71242F2"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Promote professional development including local, regional, and national workshops; teacher trainings; and partnerships with appropriate entities to better educate and inform the public about law enforcement history and officer safety and wellness education.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H777AD88BF221410C9EB80184A92728CA"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Engage with local and independent educational agencies and expand teacher engagement to cultivate and support the development of leaders in the teaching of law enforcement history and officer safety and wellness education.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3E72557094444C7DB798ED2C29870759"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Engage with State and local education leaders to encourage the adoption of resources supported under this Act into curricula across diverse disciplines.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H358777E030BD417EA475AA44F017EC10"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Create, develop, implement, replicate, or take to scale entrepreneurial, evidence-based, field-initiated innovations for museum and officer safety and wellness improvement, and rigorously evaluate such innovations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBFC9378B92BB48FDB81211D594E95898"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Provide for the free admission to National Law Enforcement Museum for active and retired law enforcement officers and family members of fallen officers; and dedicated free admission hours for the general public at least once a week.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H741176B1AB894B21A5EB6E702E89D014"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Develop online Law Enforcement History and Officer Safety and Wellness Education Resources for the general public and scholarly research.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H5D41025D6824475D8F98C96C35CB7D8B"><enum>4.</enum><header>Progress reports; certifications</header><subsection id="HF665E58648FD4BD482F7CD9F6777BF60"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Progress report</header><text>For each of the first seven fiscal years the National Law Enforcement Officers Memorial Fund shall submit a report to the Secretary of the Interior that—</text><paragraph id="H68692DA213664EB1BE2612CA70970D14"><enum>(1)</enum><text>documents, consistent with the funding provided from the Department, the progress in delivering public education, community outreach and officer safety and wellness programming; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H94602CE1ABDA45CA9370F823DFE3894E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provides a formal accounting of total amounts of Federal funds expended during the fiscal year.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9A96067D1FFD4105AE9AC0AAD23E5B27"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Submission to congress</header><text>The Secretary of the Interior shall share this report with Congress every fiscal year and make the report available on the U.S. Department of Interior website.</text></subsection></section><section id="HD58BCAA619724DB9870524C330854848"><enum>5.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><paragraph id="HCD4F4CD8E3D7400499750836E746F2B7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of the Interior to carry out this section $6,000,000 for each of the first 7 fiscal years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6FF1EDFF75E84A4FACBAE2063458F559"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>If in any fiscal year the amount appropriated pursuant to the authorization under paragraph (1) is not the full amount provided by such paragraph, the Secretary may transfer such sums as may be necessary from the National Park Service, up to the amount specified in paragraph (1), to carry out this section.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H5EEB3B430EA443529A9A700E1D441867"><enum>6.</enum><header>Continuation of activities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">To the extent that the National Law Enforcement Museum is engaged in an activity described on the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary may use the funds appropriated under section 5 to continue that activity.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

