<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H39775913C98D4F95BD37A5E6596293A2" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 793 IH: Expressing support for the designation of October 2025 as “National Learning Disabilities Awareness Month”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 793</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251008">October 8, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="H001093">Mrs. Houchin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001208">Mrs. McBath</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001231">Mr. Mannion</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001231">Ms. Simon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001119">Ms. Craig</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001229">Mrs. McIver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of October 2025 as <quote>National Learning Disabilities Awareness Month</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas section 602 of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1401">20 U.S.C. 1401</external-xref>) defines a specific learning disability as—</text> <paragraph id="H1F3947EE20184966A10771EA1A98F3B1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a disorder in 1 or more of the basic psychological processes involved in understanding or in using language, spoken or written, which may manifest itself in the imperfect ability to listen, think, speak, read, write, spell, or do mathematical calculations;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9345BCE339134720AB3CF6FCB5AAD0CC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>including such conditions as perceptual disabilities, brain injury, minimal brain dysfunction, dyslexia, and developmental aphasia; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0797E355D7B74F408360360E1CAE55BD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>not including a learning problem that is primarily the result of visual, hearing, or motor disabilities, of intellectual disabilities, of emotional disturbance, or of environmental, cultural, or economic disadvantage;</text></paragraph></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas a specific learning disability is the most prevalent disability of students who are served under the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1400">20 U.S.C. 1400 et seq.</external-xref>), affecting 32 percent of all students who received special education services; </text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the National Assessment of Educational Progress indicates that more than 96 percent of students in grade 4 and students in grade 8 with a specific learning disability were not proficient in reading in academic year 2023–2024;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the National Assessment of Educational Progress indicates that more than 92 percent of students in grade 4 and students in grade 8 with a specific learning disability were not proficient in math in academic year 2023–2024;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas National Assessment of Educational Progress math and reading scores indicate that Black and Hispanic students with a specific learning disability experience even greater opportunity gaps than their White and Asian peers;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas research shows that students with specific learning disabilities can achieve commensurate with their peers, if given appropriate instruction and support;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas developmentally appropriate universal screening should begin as early as possible to assess which students demonstrate the most pervasive risk factors for specific learning disabilities; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas research rooted in the science of reading establishes an evidence base of effective instructional methods for developing reading skills for students with and at risk for specific learning disabilities: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H9A7505C1D44B4484BCC186CD94C97C00"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H49B8188FE0BE429EB6316DE130BAD333"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> 
<paragraph id="HB9DAB2BD194E4415BA48A83A1114D46C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the designation of <quote>National Learning Disabilities Awareness Month</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H77EEE981C4DE4225A458D199BBA7C591"><enum>(2)</enum><text>calls on State educational agencies and local educational agencies to continue to meet the needs of students with specific learning disabilities through a free appropriate public education.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

