<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H34D776B5C1884DFA9AA74638BEA7B5CD" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 897 IH: Aviation-Impacted Communities Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 897</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250131">January 31, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000510">Mr. Smith of Washington</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000191">Mr. Neguse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Federal Aviation Administration to provide funding for noise mitigation, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H53C8E809C9294BE6A66EF56F8A79B865" style="OLC"><section id="HAA1A852C7C3A43588BE9BD23C2BEA6A9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Aviation-Impacted Communities Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HDC7F079B713E4D46A4B35DE23B230AC7"><enum>2.</enum><header>Noise mitigation for vertical fenceline communities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, aviation-impacted communities that are not currently within the 65 DNL standard as measured by the Federal Aviation Administration shall be eligible for the Airport Improvement Program noise mitigation program funds and for grants under section 7, and shall also be granted status under section 5 to establish community boards to address airport noise in their communities.</text></section><section id="HD31BC0F87C984931AC69CC85BE60FF3D"><enum>3.</enum><header>National Academy of Sciences study, framework, and diagnostic tool</header><subsection id="HBD849F442D36415DB8D3C5045E9BF132"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator shall enter into a contract with the National Academy of Sciences to conduct a study that—</text><paragraph id="HAC1897FE2E814E2E9CBCA1F16DB51DD6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>summarizes the relevant literature and studies done on aviation impacts worldwide; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H90D1381C195C47D8BE332285D73E9090"><enum>(2)</enum><text>focuses on large hub commercial airports and surrounding communities, including communities currently outside of the 65 DNL contour in—</text><subparagraph id="H4AA6060AF31A450592B989641F448216"><enum>(A)</enum><text>King County, WA;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFAD4ED92ABED4A14B4E821A82707A72F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Boston;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7982C6B9B827414C96F8C4D13D75BDE2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Chicago;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB82370582488467DA6CC30F28B2A1C8B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>New York City;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA8723564577E4C9E973F3E7E4F8257AD"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the Northern California Metroplex;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE1C7F016B50D44B2844B5CC260F09A5E"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Phoenix;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4C3CCEBEB1CA4AEF9BC7D2E9A873E51F"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the Southern California Metroplex;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5B1DEFB7214B4534826897C286471C90"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the District of Columbia;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H27451FAD23B24FCBB735C326634E6EAF"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Atlanta; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H73C4AA5C5D4245B2881794B87AC260E8"><enum>(J)</enum><text>any other metropolitan large hub airport identified by the Administrator.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HABDC768DD8754E259DE70F6D77051B70"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The study described in subsection (a) shall examine—</text><paragraph id="H0145D59CDDE846B9A214225C8079C123"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the collection and consolidation of quantifiable, observational, experiential, anecdotal, or other data from—</text><subparagraph id="H6132D50DA24C40968580E26C41B41466"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Federal Aviation Administration;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H884F9A58E18446C1BC951D11EAAE0E2C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>airport operators;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCC0628E8133B4DA2B14DCEA074E4D476"><enum>(C)</enum><text>valid acoustic instrumentation on the ground;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7808EBB46B1F4FB6A74584B31CADD12C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>testimonials and other evidence from community members; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9489D8312D044CA7A61A3905B7634D79"><enum>(E)</enum><text>organizations in the community;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1CA6D46F76AA47758F7DF16873E735E0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Day-Night Average Sound Level, using measured data or modeled data (or other noise metrics, as applicable);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1866422BC141404F9AC9C2D233E6A01A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any other existing or supplemental noise metrics from data collected by noise monitor stations;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H582DF206284F4C24AD6CA3BA27749BE6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>emissions generated by individual and cumulative takeoffs and landings, including emissions that impact the ground level;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC8176332C5CE4621B6E8A47FFD3CFAE0"><enum>(5)</enum><text>lateral trajectory and altitude of flight paths as demonstrated by actual and comprehensive radar flight track data in addition to published routes;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC0EB25E179944AB4831A8FE45208A72B"><enum>(6)</enum><text>how aviation impacts communities surrounded by multiple airports;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2DFDCDC5F41F455BAB61780784A6331A"><enum>(7)</enum><text>how aviation impacts communities with unique geography, including communities situated at higher elevation or near large bodies of water;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5C69B57113C44A2AA6690EC0FB7F37D7"><enum>(8)</enum><text>any other data requested by the impacted community in order to give a comprehensive understanding of the impacts on such community, including comparative data for equity analysis; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H64741F2EEA354D7984343D61A0DBAE76"><enum>(9)</enum><text>recommendations on actions or mitigation that can be taken to alleviate—</text><subparagraph id="HA20D174BAA9A4EF7AB826A96286E7E7E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>concerns raised during community outreach; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB1473DBA41EA407DAE9FB910E5F21D27"><enum>(B)</enum><text>effects that are determined in the study; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA5D61C8FA0694075AE377F80D9D804A9"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other data or information determined to be relevant by the National Academies in analyzing aviation impacts.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4ACEFBEBA2AF4B71AA965FEBAAB2929D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Framework and diagnostic tool</header><paragraph id="HC64228C6E2F34516A62A1BA6F721DA47"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Using findings from the study, the National Academy of Sciences shall provide the FAA with a framework and diagnostic tool for—</text><subparagraph id="H928744EDCC4A4D5D8E362C43CC81175C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>conducting appropriate community assessments upon request of community boards (including as described in section 5(f)); </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7C855831A1B3461F9B6969409B0373ED"><enum>(B)</enum><text>measuring the impact on communities of—</text><clause id="H99C654C133504C14990F7DD6A40BE85F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>high frequency of overhead flights;</text></clause><clause id="H71D330D737C04E599F5ECC1EBBA7C81D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an increase or change in flight operations due to adoption of new flight procedures;</text></clause><clause id="HBAB66B5185F341FA9E8B296E3EF951C8"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>high frequency or an increase in night time aircraft noise; and</text></clause><clause id="H7CAFF13D847F4F22A6D08CB0DA4267A0"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>decreased dispersion of flight path utilization; and </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFF4AF4A651F247FFAE09674920CDEFD8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>developing a scientifically based strategy for evaluating structures subject to increases described in subparagraph (A)(ii) that should be eligible for noise mitigation. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA69D83EAA6A241638A15CF06A42D5E22"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>In developing the framework and diagnostic tool under paragraph (1), the National Academy of Sciences shall—</text><subparagraph id="H4894A70F43E4425395C19C9CE3BDDB9F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>seek appropriate community input and feedback from community boards as well as open community meetings; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4373888E32CC44B5AD5C154DA4127C03"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensure, to the extent practicable, that such framework and diagnostic tool is understandable to, and useable by, the community boards and the general public. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HD03C7BBB9E5A4A04B5C7E332AE5E7304"><enum>4.</enum><header>Designating of communities</header><subsection id="H62C3E9C7A8D644098B47100268C06724"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Outreach</header><paragraph id="H578BAA47C0A346198F93AE506FAD98FF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall conduct outreach to State, regional, and local elected officials of aviation-impacted communities to inform them of the opportunity to be a designated community.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF882F7613E1C46F0B80806CE2622835C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The outreach described in paragraph (1) shall—</text><subparagraph id="HFA2AC894916F4FEB8A2DEFD320185FF8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be conducted in local print and electronic media (including social media, local foreign language media, ethnic radio, newspapers, and television); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC4F7F8906CC14D788B5670AD9BF43C5C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>reflect languages regularly encountered in the aviation-impacted community in any signs, materials, and multimedia resources. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9EC11C89BF30402A822F45C1AC3E70EB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Request</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The State, regional, or local elected officials (or designee thereof) of an aviation-impacted community may request to be a designated community, and the Administrator shall—</text><paragraph id="H21DD4B8A34D74A9C9688770D27802DAB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognize such community as a designated community upon request; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEA9E564E5E0141C98685A9CE364F0976"><enum>(2)</enum><text>acknowledge each community requesting designation on the website of the Federal Aviation Administration. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5F83121ACF1D4BD6949219D8CFDBB0F2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Portions of community</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The State or local elected officials (or designee thereof) of a designated community, representatives, or a group of representatives chosen by a community, shall select the portions or the entirety of such community considered aviation-impacted, including designating the community as a whole should such community so choose.</text></subsection></section><section id="HE68CE7C2A1384820A1B340F7EE59F268"><enum>5.</enum><header>Community boards</header><subsection id="H3E2B14C7BDB748FB8D6058DDA0CF90B4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 6 months after the date on which an aviation-impacted community becomes a designated community pursuant to section 4, such designated community shall—</text><paragraph id="H0C9F6EC2A6D34162A4D9FC328426DC2F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>select a community board comprised of individuals that equally represent—</text><subparagraph id="HB2F4A6BDDE1E41B9ADA162947CEBE20D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">State, regional, or local elected officials or city managers (or designees thereof);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDB8F896A976F490D8C70AF5C6169B738"><enum>(B)</enum><text>local airport operators;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5DB280310A3A4B4B8308D90A65A7E180"><enum>(C)</enum><text>impacted community residents; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3B091F2C3A1C4A57A5DA65967B87C7AA"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the public health and environment; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1CA303DD614643119D991BA5B3FC1A47"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the case where such designated community decides to maintain an existing group of primarily elected local officials that has previously been constituted for purposes of working on aviation-related issues, designate such existing group as a community board pursuant to this section, so long as—</text><subparagraph id="H9A8488BC277D4B1F89DBBE1435D9323F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>affected community members who are not airport employees or elected officials have representation on the board; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF251B6468660479F893F3D8A52157C7D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>health and environmental representatives are added as needed. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H54ACC6BBE432412EB28348116AD6D867"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text>A community board shall meet at times and places chosen by the members of such board.</text></subsection><subsection id="H67EFE2D44C954E47BB3A4DF127C89A9B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purpose of a community board is to provide information to airport operators and the Federal Aviation Administration concerning aviation impacts. </text></subsection><subsection id="H0640BFAF4A0E453284DDA58D39C327BD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Collaboration</header><text>The Administrator shall—</text><paragraph id="H350F7BA1025B41DA863DC992A19068E0"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">designate an FAA designee; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8F8F3E4DB2F24CF5990157B8911C29EC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>ensure that representatives of and, when appropriate and upon request of a community board, relevant experts from the Federal Aviation Administration participate in meetings of a community board.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8D98462992E842A383A521EC65E331F1"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Community reports</header><paragraph id="H32554ACFE24A4DD0B1B37A10A6B421DC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A community board may draft a community report detailing the community’s concerns and issues related to aviation impacts.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0448F3C578B94087A1EB1DBB7D2C035D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>A community report may be comprised of, or include, community information, documents, or locally conducted assessments. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCAE76BF19F114032809E3A79E525CB28"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Community assessments</header><paragraph id="H3EEA2C4F1E2A468DAA748FBA68B1724C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A community board may petition the Administrator to conduct a community assessment, which shall be conducted based on the framework and diagnostic tool established by the National Academy of Sciences under section 3 and the community reports described in subsection (e).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H676AEDFE3C9947F0B8A36B6ADE81CEA0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>A community board may petition the Administrator to conduct not more than 1 community assessment under paragraph (1) every 3 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF0C0DA96295C49A8B7D79AEE0AC236E9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding paragraph (2), a community board may petition the Administrator to conduct an additional community assessment during the 3-year period described in paragraph (2) if—</text><subparagraph id="HD8DAF29E2FFE4F26B97ED4CAF463E86D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a study described in part 150 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, is commissioned by an airport with flight paths that affect the community represented by the community board; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCFF706D4EA4B42E5B92F4782DEB622B8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if airport operations increase substantially above of projected increases. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA73CE8D59B3E48DAB149B4975ECE0F2B" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Instrumentation</header><text>Upon request of a community board, the Administrator shall provide additional noise measurement instrumentation to measure aircraft noise.</text></subsection><subsection id="H64CFA275F1BA44249A384905C4BCE3FE"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Collaboration</header><text>The Administrator and each community board that petitions for a community assessment shall collaborate on the scope of such community assessment.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD36B1740EA5046538E00482B8EC4AB8F"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Regional assessment</header><text>Upon the request and approval of not less than 2 community boards located in the same region, the FAA may conduct a regional assessment based on the framework and diagnostic tool established by the National Academy of Sciences under section 3. </text></subsection><subsection id="HA9010DA1EBD449A7B9BCA3FCFD8483F1"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Accessible format</header><text>The Administrator shall ensure the community assessment is culturally and linguistically accessible given the needs or requests of the community.</text></subsection></section><section id="H829284BD8D74440C808711BACF5DCD98"><enum>6.</enum><header>Action plans</header><subsection id="HFCEF0B2F37F14D7BBFFEF1F6458E1392"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 6 months after the date of completion of a community assessment described in section 5(f), the Administrator shall, in collaboration with community boards, devise an action plan that seeks to alleviate or address the concerns raised in such community reports or such community assessments.</text></subsection><subsection id="HFB15AF0267064A61BC219D963726F0CA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Content</header><text>An action plan shall—</text><paragraph id="H633517C963C545C3919A24AA49D38203"><enum>(1)</enum><text>include a long-term regional plan that focuses on reducing and minimizing aviation impacts for the designated community or communities, including sound insulation or other noise mitigation infrastructure, air filtration systems, and changes in flight paths or procedures; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H35516788A8284B7D84050DFFC91869E2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>require the appropriate district office of the Federal Aviation Administration and air traffic control facility to consider the implementation of changes to flight operations, flight paths, and vertical guidance if the community assessment described in section 5(f) indicates that such changes would decrease the impacts on the designated community, including examining the population density in the communities described in such report and assessment in considering such implementation.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H742B4E0878604FFE9936EB05B498CDC1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>In implementing the action plan, the Administrator will consider the implementation of changes to flight operations, flight paths, and vertical guidance if the community assessment described in section 5(f) indicates that such changes would decrease the impacts of flights on a designated community (or communities). </text></subsection><subsection id="H45319A3FB1004FA1849933ECA4CFC2A3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Statement concerning certain changes</header><text>If the Administrator determines that changes to operations, flight paths, and vertical guidance that a community study indicated would decrease the effects on the designated community would not be effective in decreasing community impacts, the Administrator shall explain the rationale for this determination in the action plan.</text></subsection><subsection id="H6F030D9D140845018693F5FB81345030"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Appeals process</header><paragraph id="HF17DB725E7C1498FA92CD80FF4ED2751"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator shall establish an appeals process, through which a community board may appeal the determination by the Federal Aviation Administration not to implement a change under subsection (c) to an independent panel comprised equally of independent public health experts, environmental experts, and aviation experts.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8BF641229A37445AB1C6C6A09A1CA5A2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Recommendations</header><text>In carrying out paragraph (1), the Administrator shall seek recommendations from the National Academy of Sciences for panel experts described in such paragraph.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H45DD6B793D744E33B9B44C28A2B49C58"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Requirement to convene</header><text>An independent panel convened pursuant to paragraph (1) shall convene not later than 6 months after the receipt of an appeal pursuant to such paragraph and shall respond to such appeal not later than 3 months after the date on which such panel convenes. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD537BA2BDD5247FABDF515818A8ACF13"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Dissemination</header><text>The panel described in subsection (e)(1) shall submit any findings for an appeal described in such subsection—</text><paragraph id="HDC2343EC5DA7490ABDF101868981209F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to the public in a culturally and linguistically appropriate fashion given the needs or requests of the community at issue;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H62E61743AFDC46749556900CCD5FFB81"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to the offices of the Members of Congress and Senators representing the community at issue;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD272783B6E1846F2A660E17318FA02B9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to the relevant committees of the House of Representatives and the Senate; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HACC8A7F7C1A3411685CD241EB9F8A440"><enum>(4)</enum><text>upon request, to appropriate State, regional, and local elected officials.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HE7CE7C3150E5440689A4C3EADCF70742"><enum>7.</enum><header>Mitigation funding</header><subsection id="HA1895C80392D4940B930C0BD6D7C40C2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the release of an action plan pursuant to section 3, the Administrator shall make grants for necessary noise mitigation in a designated community for—</text><paragraph id="H0E5E2B58C20A4883B1B9EBE9C8F73E56"><enum>(1)</enum><text>residences;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1C1BE4F4F6B74DFCAD98EE9FB29E26AF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>hospitals;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2F729D563C964B1BB7B797FA08B600F1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>nursing homes and adult or child day care centers;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7659CA19A1A34AA0BD439194F12E0F9A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>schools; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2707960386FA451CA25F3B997C7C499F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>places of worship; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4A6ADDB7F3EB41E2B3B7A653A61AC2E9"><enum>(6)</enum><text>other impacted facilities indicated by a community assessment under section 5(f). </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBC82C8AE3F6E43DF970B2658C0EEBC30"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Standards</header><text>Using the framework and diagnostic tool developed by the National Academy of Sciences under section 3, the Administrator shall develop standards to determine which of the structures in designated communities described in subsection (a) are eligible for mitigation funding.</text></subsection><subsection id="H64A55C79F63247D99542600A84FB827D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Mitigation defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>noise mitigation</term> means any form of mitigation that reduces the noise burden for communities, including—</text><paragraph id="HA863218988664ACFA23D6EE44637F8EF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>sound insulation of structures;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB207A85DAB63487DB179465AEFEC06AE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>construction of noise barriers or acoustic shielding to mitigate ground-level noise; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF1C1E0B6BD9F40EEAC4BD6BC3E1B702F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>other mitigation as indicated by a community assessment under section 5(f) or an action plan under section 6 using the diagnostic tool developed by the National Academy of Sciences under section 3. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD611410E4A804F27993833940B2D5A29"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Sound insulation for communities subject to high flight frequency</header><paragraph id="H3674FF7B080848768371045EF6A352B3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Using the framework and diagnostic tool developed by the National Academy of Sciences under section 3, in carrying out an action plan described in section 6, the Administrator shall develop standards for determining which communities are subject to significant frequency of overhead flights, which shall be eligible for noise mitigation funding.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB0493AFD177F408AA5C216008743A583"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Noise mitigation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out an action plan described in section 6, the Administrator and airport operators shall provide grants for noise mitigation for aviation-impacted communities that are subjected to a high frequency of flight operations or from the adoption of new flight procedures (as determined by the Administrator through the use of the framework and diagnostic tool developed by the National Academy of Sciences under section 3).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0816015F9CE8459C98F8809E9F2968D4"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Sound insulation for residences impacted by significant night time aircraft noise</header><text>In carrying out an action plan described in section 6, the Administrator and airport operators shall provide noise mitigation for a neighborhood within a 55 or higher DNL contour (or a community that has quality-assured noise measurement data that demonstrate 55 DNL impacts occurring outside the model contour of the aviation environmental design tool of the FAA) in which an airport operator or the Administrator determines, through the use of the framework and diagnostic tool developed by the National Academy of Sciences under section 3, that significant numbers of flight operations are conducted between 10:00 p.m. and 6:00 a.m.</text></subsection></section><section id="HFA0A0CC14C8645BCA211AAF3FD7399C6"><enum>8.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><subsection id="HAA3FD472A37647F386D8C93B3BA65D10"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated out of the Airport and Airway Trust Fund (established under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/9502">section 9502</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986) to carry out this Act—</text><paragraph id="HD970A4612C164E2A82B36F3B5AFAEDB7" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a total of $750,000,000 for fiscal years 2025 through 2034; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB7ACA71341AF4017ABDA8D71C1FE7C06" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>such sums as necessary, but not to exceed 0.25 percent of the annual change in uncommitted balance of such Trust Fund in a fiscal year, for fiscal years after fiscal year 2034. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H49538B436D1D41F4B634BD7260881C90"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>Of any amounts appropriated for a fiscal year to carry out this Act, the Administrator shall use such funds—</text><paragraph id="H42D2F7A4EC394C34A17411968A62062A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to make grants under section 7;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD4E247FCD80444958BE4EBD6A8A7E49A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in an amount of not more than 5 percent, to support FAA expenditures required for the administration this Act; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3AF33EEBBCFA4E16A5F7307CF138133C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any amounts not expended under paragraph (1) or (2), to make grants described in section 47117(e)(1)(A) of title 49, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H1047EC9075B94E60B886BD3796F172F5"><enum>9.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="HC768161577E54264BA52B7B285F6C700"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3FCFA932DAD64AA3B9103D5D8C237B80"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Aircraft operation</header><text>The term <term>aircraft operation</term> means a landing or take-off of an aircraft flight.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCB89C01ABAD44D269A2E192044733651"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Aviation-impacted community</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>aviation-impacted community</term> means a community that is located not greater than 1 mile from any point at which a commercial or cargo jet route is 3,000 feet or less above ground level.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H353249D1C65C4D1799BA97C8C922BF96"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Commercial or cargo jet route</header><text>The term <term>commercial or cargo jet route</term> means a route that is departing or arriving at a large hub or metroplex airport, as such terms are defined by the Administrator. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H506B3E358BD249DF8A9CA7DA6AA110DD"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Community</header><text>The term <term>community</term> means any residential neighborhood, locality, municipality, town, or city.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H03A8C814159C491FB18E0664C4159E06"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Designated community</header><text>The term <term>designated community</term> means an aviation-impacted community that has chosen to be designated pursuant to section 4.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDC352599A1314BAB93B64269EF5482EA"><enum>(7)</enum><header>FAA</header><text>The term <term>FAA</term> means the Federal Aviation Administration.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8D1E49736C0A48CDAB4AAE7C4C711A90"><enum>(8)</enum><header>FAA designee</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>FAA Designee</term> means a community engagement manager or Regional Ombudsman (as described in section 180 of the FAA Reauthorization Act of 2018) that—</text><subparagraph id="H5C7E73BE6FEF407D8473C2ED968DF156"><enum>(A)</enum><text>works with each community board;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H323C5D597EDE4A6E9D76DFEE914F3F00"><enum>(B)</enum><text>engages in meaningful, solution-driven dialogue with the community board; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDF93AE3A04E84456965D583598397537"><enum>(C)</enum><text>serves as the liaison between the FAA and the community board.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H34D070AD7CAC4D7A9F22475B61567E75"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Impact</header><text>The term <term>impact</term> means noise, air pollution emissions, or any other aviation-related impact identified by a community coming from an aircraft and that is affecting a community or its residents.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HED521246BE064CE99B08D5142176D712"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Route</header><text>The term <term>route</term> includes both the lateral trajectory and altitude of flight paths as demonstrated by actual and comprehensive radar flight track data in addition to published routes.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

