<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" slc-id="S1-RIL25931-69Y-08-X23"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 372 IS: Honoring the life of Kansas City, Kansas police officer Hunter Simoncic.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 372</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250903">September 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S347">Mr. Moran</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S411">Mr. Marshall</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Honoring the life of Kansas City, Kansas police officer Hunter Simoncic.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas Hunter Simoncic was a brave law enforcement officer who sacrificed his life to keep his local Kansas community safe;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Hunter Simoncic was born on April 16, 1999;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas Hunter Simoncic grew up in Galesburg, Kansas;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas Hunter Simoncic graduated from Erie High School in 2018 and earned a bachelor of science degree in sociology from Pittsburgh State University in 2021 and a master's degree in forensic sciences from Oklahoma State University in 2023;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas Hunter Simoncic graduated from the Kansas City, Kansas Police Academy in November 2023;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas Hunter Simoncic served as a big brother with Big Brothers Big Sisters of Kansas and volunteered to read to local children each week through the Lead to Read program at Banneker Elementary School;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Hunter Simoncic is survived by his father Ron Simoncic of Franklin, Kansas, his mother Christine Brungardt of Galesburg, Kansas, and his brother Fischer Simoncic of Wichita, Kansas; </text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas Officer Simoncic was killed on August 26, 2025, while on duty in Kansas City, Kansas, when he was struck by a driver fleeing law enforcement while he attempted to disable the fleeing vehicle;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas Hunter Simoncic is an American hero, whose bravery, integrity, and steadfast dedication as a faithful civil servant have made a lasting impact; and</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas Mr. Simoncic’s legacy will endure, inspiring his family, community, and a thankful Nation: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="S1"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id304581609d6f4950b8e6ba41229a9b01" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>highly respects and appreciates all that Hunter Simoncic did to protect and serve his Kansas community;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id01bf16e5df794e0daca315565aae29da" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>offers condolences to the family of Hunter Simoncic;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0db4b3ee6c34409c9619abc1ad10a594" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>pays tribute to Mr. Simoncic's noble sacrifice in the line of duty; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2f1635156ba6457580b6c99aef822291" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>calls on all levels of government to support the family of this fallen officer.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

