<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6177632147F7465DB627F42367BF0982" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 197 IH: Lake Winnibigoshish Land Exchange Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 197</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250103">January 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001212">Mr. Stauber</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="F000475">Mr. Finstad</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for a land exchange in the Chippewa National Forest, Minnesota, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB51CD1EF121144EB916AC4A83617A287" style="OLC"><section id="HB0288D51B48A48F8A29A565F64AD9E30" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Lake Winnibigoshish Land Exchange Act of 2025</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="HFE5CB975B63343F19518A5B712E1C99B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H3B9AA556D6954217A17EBA5F991D3B8C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>BWLT</header><text>The term <term>BWLT</term> means Big Winnie Land and Timber, LLC, a Minnesota Limited Liability Corporation. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3BD35B1BD2584BFA84FBC87FA6D03AE8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Map</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Map</term> means the map entitled <quote>Heig Land Exchange</quote> and dated December 14, 2023.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5ECF64C1A0194FE69786DEF5A09A492B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Federal land</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Federal land</term> means the approximately 17.5 acres of Federal land in Itasca County, Minnesota, generally depicted as the <quote>Federal Parcel</quote> on the Map.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2E488965C20A4E5884B25FFE7F8F748B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Non-Federal land</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>non-Federal land</term> means the approximately 36.7 acres of non-Federal land in Itasca County, Minnesota, generally depicted as the <quote>Non-Federal Parcel</quote> on the Map.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB414B9F8FF364E73B1CD3BC7E59B387C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Chief of the Forest Service.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H5B53556CD64F4A04BB51C2E8A3F68DB4"><enum>3.</enum><header>Exchange of land</header><subsection id="H22C3F9537A4B4F4EB6A194D8FEB910CA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Exchange authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to the provisions of this Act, if BWLT offers to convey the non-Federal land to the United States, the Secretary shall, not later than 1 year after the date on which such offer is made—</text><paragraph id="HDF585948CBE24360B0C0C4202136A314"><enum>(1)</enum><text>accept the offer; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H96136B15DAD34BA98ACA612B80C664CF"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">convey to BWLT all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to the Federal land, excepting and reserving an easement for road access to National Forest System land west of the Federal Parcel; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF50F71F3D96C46B7A51366548AF2ABCE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>accept from BWLT all right, title, and interest of BWLT in and to the non-Federal land.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCF1A7FE7DBCB454793297D5506CB08BE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The exchange under subsection (a) shall be—</text><paragraph id="H29F132820D604476A3DC008D8EF0C9DB"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conditioned on title approval for the non-Federal land by the Secretary in accordance with subsection (e);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD7CB147F85DD4D3AB7A3ADE515580B1E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>conditioned on a cash equalization payment made by BWLT to the United States in accordance with subsection (c) if, under the appraisals conducted in accordance with this Act, it is determined that the value of the Federal land exceeds the value of the non-Federal land;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3BD0ED8D9A064925A4C1F7C166979764"><enum>(3)</enum><text>conditioned on the satisfactory completion of a Phase I Environmental Site Assessment by BWLT, provided to the Secretary, in advance of the acceptance of the non-Federal parcel;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA0D22EF7AB1A49E79B44244F56BC6F75"><enum>(4)</enum><text>subject to valid existing rights; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF3862F1FDD1448B7BCF7FC0F47AC9DA5"><enum>(5)</enum><text>subject to any other terms and conditions the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H35AD814EFBF64674A564BE1C42871ADC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Equal value and cash equalization</header><paragraph id="HA6C050207ACB49F182572D9121F65D99"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the exchange under subsection (a) shall be for equal value or the values shall be equalized by a cash payment.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9B9287B9A97C46D1B9AE145465FBE16B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, if the appraised value of the non-Federal land to be conveyed to the United States exceeds the appraised value of the Federal land, a cash equalization payment by the United States to BWLT is hereby waived and the amount of such waived payment shall be considered a donation by BWLT to the United States for all purposes of law. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4033444FE3054B7AB79904F8F71ACD4B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Appraisals</header><paragraph id="H30B14F0F927045ADADA0D1E6A43E2FCE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The value of the land to be exchanged under this Act shall be determined by appraisals conducted by an independent and qualified appraiser mutually agreed to by the Secretary and BWLT. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF7305DC5318148998BC32D1A47534ABD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appraisal standards</header><text>The Secretary shall complete appraisals of the land to be exchanged under this Act in accordance with—</text><subparagraph id="HA591B98CBFDF4D9FBCD5A3DE6618C7FD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Uniform Appraisal Standards for Federal Land Acquisitions; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6298B70EC0214F58A0411D86A73F9330"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Uniform Standards of Professional Appraisal Practice. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H36B21B4BF45E4572B803BACF6138EFD3"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Format</header><text>Title to the non-Federal land to be conveyed to the United States under this Act shall be found sufficient by the Secretary pursuant to section 3111 of title 40, United States Code.</text></subsection><subsection id="HCAD70F75A4CF4254AA8D624C0F907AE6"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Management of acquired land</header><text>The non-Federal land acquired by the United States under subsection (a) shall be—</text><paragraph id="H3086AF9ADC2642B3B495ACE2EF23D0D2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>added to, and managed as part of, the Chippewa National Forest; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCF14005D789B4C0E868095D444D5B5B7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>managed in accordance with the laws, rules, and regulations pertaining to National Forest System lands.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0B42A99FD5D148FF97B4443E0D1B9B4E"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Map and legal descriptions</header><paragraph id="HDC48FE76CEF34076B820F0A77B6C8B6F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>As soon as practicable after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall finalize the Map and legal descriptions of all land to be conveyed under this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5BF555D117EE4D0488CFED8F5A23533B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Controlling document</header><text>In the case of a discrepancy between the Map and a legal description, the Map shall control. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H112B2D55C3F441A6839AED82F92006EA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Corrections</header><text>The Secretary and BWLT, by mutual agreement, may correct any minor errors in the Map or in the legal descriptions, including with respect to the boundaries of the Federal land and the non-Federal land.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAFE9DFE82F7D4F0783528E827422D326"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Map on file</header><text>The Map and legal descriptions shall be on file and available for public inspection in appropriate offices of the Forest Service.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA36D754C70DF4B3B9D56F48B50FFB653"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Closing costs</header><text>As a condition for the exchange under subsection (a), BWLT shall pay all closing costs associated with the exchange, including for—</text><paragraph id="H893153A22BD74C04A52F2DCF961A2121"><enum>(1)</enum><text>title insurance and title search;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H29F484EE09B842F7BBB8311ACA863470"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any applicable inspection fees, escrow fees, attorneys fees, and recording fees; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB5A85A7A7B4C460EB879CE63A19DAA80"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any environmental analysis or resource survey required under Federal law, regulation, or policy, including a Phase I Environmental Site Assessment of the non-Federal land.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA2A575469F66466ABBC958C6B0824746"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Survey</header><paragraph id="HE167199829CC44C394744F477627214B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The exact acreages and legal descriptions of the Federal and non-Federal land to be exchanged under subsection (a) shall be determined by surveys satisfactory to the Secretary.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA5172D97007E403FA2F45E6DD3BCC3CC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Costs of survey</header><text>BWLT shall bear all costs associated with the surveys under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

