<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5AF25BB247B146E899978BE014D9AA05" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4025 IH: Energy Transitions Initiative Authorization Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4025</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250617">June 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001055">Mr. Case</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Energy to establish an initiative to provide grants to fund the development of resilient energy systems in remote communities, island communities, and Tribal communities, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H7CD7DAC73E074798A576F81DEB067ECA" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H82D6AB61687B421C9B4267E15F47E8C0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Energy Transitions Initiative Authorization Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HA2776FD001C34AF9BA58C642CD31232D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> <paragraph id="H69ED66B9FECE4814B2A71F817614E01F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Remote communities, island communities, and Tribal communities are commonly characterized by the unique challenges arising from isolation and the resultant difficulties in achieving economies of scale in the delivery of critical goods and services.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8A6F555BBD834BE59ECAA55F6C201B8B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to energy, such challenges include high energy costs, limited and non-resilient energy infrastructure, and increased vulnerability to natural disasters.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB48AEDAEDEA14B4781038080B6AEE778"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Self-sufficient renewable energy solutions are required to ensure energy security for these communities.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3E4D48D1BB3D4CD9B4ABE55C69BF88AE"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">These communities require specialized assistance, which they have difficulty procuring on their own, in acquiring and building necessary infrastructure, such as energy storage, solar energy facilities, hydropower plants, distributed energy resources, microgrids, and necessary transportation.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H075206E257A34172A0341B8080E919DC"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such specialized assistance should be provided in partnership with remote communities, island communities, and Tribal communities because their unique expertise and deep knowledge of local challenges and needs are necessary for the success of resulting solutions.</text></paragraph> </section> 
<section id="HA6D19250AF9D461BB9390ACC25CABB53"><enum>3.</enum><header>Energy Transitions Initiative grant</header> 
<subsection id="HC044B2D316654147800A703DEAEE6B06"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Energy shall establish an initiative to provide grants to eligible entities to fund eligible projects for the development of resilient energy systems in remote communities, island communities, and Tribal communities.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H60233F7259A74A1B924044342A86D78C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Terms</header> <paragraph id="HB0C20EE1BFE545409227483C98C81032"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the initiative, the Secretary may make a grant of not more than $5,000,000 to an eligible entity for an eligible project.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF7654413DDA443E6A8EB732E4107E0B2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Cost-share</header><text>The Secretary may not make a grant under this section in an amount that is more than 90 percent of the cost of an eligible project.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HEDA5E96583FD43AAB2FD5CB37E06DE8F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon the request of a grantee, the Secretary shall provide technical assistance to such grantee for a period of not less than 1 year and not more than 2 years through the Energy Transitions Initiative Partnership Program.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H73AAFFFFC9AE4A6084FDD67177C70A2F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>GAO audit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the establishment of the initiative described in this section, and annually thereafter, the Comptroller General of the United States shall—</text> <paragraph id="HBC24176525A141B0A04E351A6C9844D4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct an audit of the initiative established under this section to ensure proper use of funds and compliance with applicable regulations; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H57FBAE51BF1444228503EB391BA9CAA1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submit a report that includes the results of such audit and recommendations for improving the efficiency and effectiveness of the initiative to—</text> <subparagraph id="H28EC592F4DCB45368DBCDFC83355C4C8"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H028380C7A2F3483A959EE001AC36AE73"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6B839B8D81CD4D80BF2BCB8FC12826A8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Committee on Energy and Public Works of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H87AD7A3974264066974C34EE605E4F0C"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF1187CCCEC224876BE57B3A9EC9CBDD1"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of Appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary $31,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030 to carry out this section.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HCB0B288E607E41E0AE392523D0FD8A0B"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section:</text> <paragraph id="H151D312EA14A4918B9E63359DDC60237"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Alaska Native Corporation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Alaska Native Corporation</term> has the meaning given the term <term>Native Corporation</term> in section 3 of the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1602">42 U.S.C. 1602</external-xref>).</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAA79FDAC8C714A8999F79944570812B1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible entity</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HD7FBEFB29B64425093235BA95FAED634"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a State that includes a remote community, an island community, or a Tribal community;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H26804CFD532A43AD98FDF7CD72EEE583"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a unit of local government serving or that includes a remote community or an island community;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB5B140F52DC742E38BCF87C93584F61D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a Tribal community; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1F1CFC5ECEC147A495EB08949905521A"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a community organization that serves a remote community, an island community, or a Tribal community.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC9C2BF8857DC403F9D926A676ED3FC1D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligible project</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible project</term> means any of the following projects:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HDD55BE3CC2E944318BC600C94FE60AEC" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A project to implement energy efficiency measures in buildings.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7B0848234BEC4801A16746887C8FADCC"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A project for a resilient energy system that is a project to develop—</text> 
<clause id="H18019C2FF9DF4E2D8C5A3C589C986381"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a hydropower, solar power, wind energy, geothermal energy, tidal power, or wave energy system;</text></clause> <clause id="H09F5514A69284D4CA11EF9CA9A0A7FF7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a microgrid; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H1E1BE8E5938D4E5681C3853386A8363F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">infrastructure necessary for the transmission and distribution of electricity.</text></clause></subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HFF38BD8ADE3242089B13E80CEB4576AC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Federally recognized Tribe</header><text>The term <term>federally recognized tribe</term> has the meaning given the term in section 102(2) of the Federally Recognized Indian Tribe List Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5130">25 U.S.C. 5130(2)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H63EABC4FD4FA46D3A27BDD0FD2629ABB"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Island community</header><text>The term <term>island community</term> means a group of individuals living on an area of land isolated from the mainland by oceans or lakes, that is not connected to a larger regional grid network, and experiences resilience challenges, including energy disruptions or threats to infrastructure from natural disasters.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF533B64DEEA24068890B0FE5721157E3"> <enum>(6)</enum> <header>Native Hawaiian Organization</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Native Hawaiian Organization</term> means an organization listed by the Department of the Interior in the Native Hawaiian Organization Notification List maintained by the Office of Native Hawaiian Relations.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H04564CF1EA7B401780E1825CC2F72091"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Remote community</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>remote community</term> means a group of individuals living in an area isolated from a larger regional grid network, with limited access to centralized energy sources due to environmental or geographical impediments.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3A46770F3B88455DA3CFBB5007DCDBFD"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Resilient energy system</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>resilient energy system</term> means a facility or equipment that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H4B457E23F1CD40C59CEDAA036A689EDC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>can generate and deliver energy; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9C352C5567FA46D598B262911E911BD5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>can withstand or quickly recover from an energy disruption.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCD5E2E9897A74749A2D1ECE2F8C5F5FE"><enum>(9)</enum><header>State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>State</term> means each of the 50 States, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, and the Northern Mariana Islands.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB9D7CB929CDD4BC895B2BD2EDC12BCE0"> <enum>(10)</enum> <header>Tribal community</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Tribal community</term> means a federally recognized Tribe, an Alaska Native Corporation, or a Native Hawaiian Organization.</text>
        </paragraph> </subsection> </section> 
</legis-body></bill>

