<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H60575845111F4436B8529DF916A5E488" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3063 IH: Rural Hospital Stabilization Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3063</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250429">April 29, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000481">Mr. Figures</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="J000311">Mr. Jack</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Public Health Service Act to authorize the Secretary of Health and Human Services to make grants to assist rural hospitals, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H2BD911E370C34180952E26C69F5053C6" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HCD1C7D3BF45F4643A81E98CA51530C4E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Rural Hospital Stabilization Act of 2025</short-title></quote> .</text></section> <section id="H8CFA0922D9734A59822121CE034166DE"><enum>2.</enum><header>Grants to assist rural hospitals</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/201">42 U.S.C. 201 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 330A–2 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/254c-1b">42 U.S.C. 254c–1b</external-xref>) the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H09674D3AFB7F49D5812030BC06DA6DE3" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="H4A4B4AF4F3E943E281791034D6820233"><enum>330A–3.</enum><header>Grants to assist rural hospitals</header> 
<subsection id="HEC5BD87223364081AFC34E7FFF2E4AF8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority To make grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, acting through the Director of the Office of Rural Health Policy of the Health Resources and Services Administration, may make grants under this section to rural hospitals—</text> <paragraph id="H64D4FEA28BA048BB8574546F37430576"><enum>(1)</enum><text>for projects to acquire, repair, and upgrade the systems, facilities, and equipment of rural hospitals; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H22870325866543A2AEA65A7ADF778D88"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to provide financial assistance to be used toward the operational costs of rural hospitals, including payroll expenses (except payroll expenses associated with hospital leadership positions) and debt payments.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE8ED6B215AC240969D8932C64CAFF798"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, a rural hospital shall submit to the Secretary an application, at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require, including—</text> 
<paragraph id="H38984CCD0C0C488EB77164BB13BEE826"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a description of the projects and expenses that will receive funding under the grant;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H973F845E5F8E42DBB3A04C0D5AD9841B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of the manner in which the projects and expenses funded under the grant will address the financial needs of the hospital;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEDA03AEF885543AA8C67C845EA2F3385"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of how the projects and expenses funded under the grant will help ensure that residents of rural areas maintain access to hospital services;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H632CA773D85E4B48B82DBD01D8810831"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a plan for sustaining projects and covering expenses at the hospital after Federal support under this section has ended; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD11112CE4D994F4FAE7ED8068A52E8D9"><enum>(5)</enum><text>such other information as the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H0C548F5C885B4DC2861790485FF99C60"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Maximum aggregate grant amount</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A rural hospital may receive not more that $5,000,000, in the aggregate, in grant funds under this section for any five-year period.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5208E22862ED49D08EF6979A26223E42"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Maintenance of effort</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Funds made available under this section shall be used to supplement and not supplant other Federal, State, local, and Tribal funds available for the grant purposes described in subsection (a).</text></subsection> <subsection id="HB0BE63C916CB4D5A82ED660AA88A0727"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate, and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate a report on the activities and outcomes of the grant program carried out under this section, including the impact of projects funded under this section on improving the financial viability of the grant recipients and ensuring that residents of rural areas maintain access to hospital services.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD6A7E9B9A2D448689EFAA71921365492"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H300E298833C3443D8E1ED4EAA4289819"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Rural hospital</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>rural hospital</quote> means a hospital that is located at least 15 miles from the nearest hospital and at least 20 miles from the nearest urbanized area (as defined by the Bureau of the Census). Such term includes public and private hospitals.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H435A9ABD2F26481684B82859FA047102"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Hospital leadership position</header><text>The term <quote>hospital leadership position</quote> has such meaning as the Secretary may prescribe by regulation.</text></paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="H91F1C759F376494BAE9DD8167F2FDABC"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $500,000,000, in the aggregate, for fiscal years beginning after September 30, 2025. </text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </section> 
</legis-body></bill>

