<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H613840B0798E43D5A30284F121737BC9" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2957 IH: Services and Trauma-informed Research of Outcomes in Neighborhoods Grants for Support for Children Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2957</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250417">April 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000617">Ms. Pressley</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Public Health Service Act to support the development and implementation of programs using data analysis to identify and facilitate strategies to improve outcomes for children in geographic areas with a high prevalence of trauma from exposure to adverse childhood experiences, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H102FE2C0A31A4596A5A3DDA9354B94F6" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H234C41D0A17F40E6905383064AF45C76" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Services and Trauma-informed Research of Outcomes in Neighborhoods Grants for Support for Children Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>STRONG Support for Children Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HA0D8C8EAF7FB49D88C55EE836F58A70B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Data analysis and strategy implementation to prevent and mitigate childhood trauma</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title XXXI of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300kk">42 U.S.C. 300kk</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H48A0A70440484A9FB6333E035CC7E897" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="HB1ABB477D9B64706803C50C749C37AAD"><enum>3102.</enum><header>Data analysis and strategy implementation to prevent and mitigate childhood trauma</header> 
<subsection id="H61AE30A3FF1C49CE9E9EBDF84ED5918F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish a program—</text> <paragraph id="H7E830FDB673A497080D3A4889FF52BF5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to support the development and implementation of programs that use data analysis methods to identify and facilitate strategies for early intervention and prevention, in order to prevent and mitigate childhood trauma and support communities and families, including— </text> 
<subparagraph id="H685ECA018C9244AE9AEA0E4961DEB542"><enum>(A)</enum><text>improving connections through care coordination;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7CF29BDE4C054FCEBC9ABD5C60DA0958"><enum>(B)</enum><text>aligning community initiatives in targeted areas of need; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2F1876299B5C4621A0E532424BE59AE4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>expanding community capacity through cross-sector collaboration; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H233C9053C94A4BE795869303EB5C97A7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to evaluate the effectiveness of these programs in improving outcomes for children.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H305F5EC314BB4D00B2FD8673A5C944AA" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall award grants to up to 5 eligible entities to carry out the activities described in subsection (a).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H26E8D62B1DB24903BE17A7800BEFF24B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A grant for activities under this section shall be used to support the development and implementation of programs that use data analysis methods to identify and facilitate strategies for early intervention and prevention, in order to prevent and mitigate childhood trauma and support communities and families, including as follows: </text> 
<paragraph id="H4DF64549730F44F7AC477A6AC8656004"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Utilize data analysis methods to—</text> <subparagraph id="H3B8AEA0358164CB5BD3DA1EC81F50150" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identify specific geographic areas, such as census tracts, with a high prevalence of adverse childhood experiences and significant risk factors for poor outcomes for children (such as increased risk of experiencing adverse childhood experiences), including areas with high rates of—</text> 
<clause id="HA5A7524C3AEC4713A5B5C5BE618C21E6" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>poor public health outcomes including illness, disease, suicide, and mortality;</text></clause> <clause id="HB13C0CD0436C470BB407A15163EF7C3F" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">exclusionary discipline practices, including suspensions, expulsions, and referrals to law enforcement, as well as low graduation rates;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HED16AA69548342A999D12C516298DD84"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>substance use disorders;</text></clause> <clause id="HCC05EF16959541168DC97D322B8FAC72"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>poverty;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H67D59CA195D344CC9EBDEA730506DF91"><enum>(v)</enum><text>foster system involvement or referrals;</text></clause> <clause id="HAA798A063C6A4CF292EA4460A4DAA90F"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>housing instability and homelessness;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HEE4160C226084E9E97B600D25D303711"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>food insecurity;</text></clause> <clause id="HDCDCA2535C3E4A4395955A28040996BA"><enum>(viii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">inequity, including disparities in income, wealth, employment, educational attainment, health care access, and public health outcomes, along lines of race, sex, sexuality and gender identity, ethnicity, or nationality;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H3CB203E5F440429A888F95CF601F514C"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>incarceration rates; or</text></clause> <clause id="HFC623D26835A4AE789AEFBB5E6B4B8ED"><enum>(x)</enum><text>other indicators of adversity as defined by the Secretary; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H20F976DAAD8647C099D47BA9C5C97502"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identify strategies to improve outcomes for children aged 0 through 17 that build on strengths in communities that could be further supported, including—</text> <clause id="H1C393B56BDAE45C388CDF1FE2324F5D6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>existing support networks for families; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HAEAC6285B193480CB9AFE752615300EA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>enhanced connections to community-based organizations.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF0E8633CB1FE4A80AAEF08BC2CFD6549"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Implement strategies identified pursuant to paragraph (1)(B) to facilitate outreach and involvement of children and their caregivers in Federal, State, or local programs that provide reparative, gender-responsive, culturally specific, and trauma-informed prevention services, and for which children and their caregivers are eligible, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H9FA70F6F1AE74CB0A8A9C7816CB86D1D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>home visiting programs;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9E8C25133BF0469B8ADEA51658224A3C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>training and education on parenting skills;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H33B8453591C446A695C4E6EB9B663CA1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">substance use disorder prevention and treatment that is voluntary and noncoercive;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEDA27243E9F64A4BA5379885344DA34E"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">mental health supports and care that is voluntary and noncoercive;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5D353AFF427943489E05DD4B744CF5E5"><enum>(E)</enum><text>family and intimate partner violence prevention services;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3184FEC54728444EB7AFC6C46141A406"><enum>(F)</enum><text>child advocacy center programming;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H18D4FB01554748FCA57520170E4B5F9E"><enum>(G)</enum><text>economic and nutrition support services;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HADE683D5645F43FE9AA2F167A58B86A9"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">housing support services, including emergency and temporary shelter for those experiencing homelessness and housing insecurity, as well as stable, long-term housing;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEDE432626E46449AA48976EA0EC31DB2" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">voluntary, noncoercive, gender-responsive, and culturally specific mental health supports in school and early childhood education center-based settings; </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H475C0322D9C645228EE8C11E6F63D677"><enum>(J)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">wraparound programs for transitioning youth and youth currently in the foster system;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8C16079710184CE3824C86F384DC32C0"><enum>(K)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">programming to support the health and well-being of lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, and intersex children and their families; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H08033C9CFAA04543893DD06ABCC7576A"><enum>(L)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">family resource center services.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFB0479C6AF7747CF9B6A6BB07A7CEADD" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Special rules</header> 
<paragraph id="HCCF821C7357A4042A3290F500F531A50" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Primary payer restriction</header><text>The Secretary may not award a grant under this section to an eligible entity for a service if the service to be provided is available pursuant to the State plan approved under title XIX of the Social Security Act for the State in which the program funded by the grant is being conducted unless the State and all eligible subdivisions involved—</text> <subparagraph id="H349863C5611A40669564B595E00024E4" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>will enter into agreements with public or nonprofit private entities under which the entities will provide the service; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7351A7FB45594462BD5860FB45F70DF3" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>demonstrate that the State and all eligible subdivisions will ensure that the entities providing the service—</text> <clause id="H7314508681C84C669C60BA7003C5D97D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>will seek payment for each such service rendered in accordance with the usual payment schedule under the State plan; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H02FE08D3A2374EE285E09E0D297AC164"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the entities have entered into a participation agreement and are qualified to receive payments under such plan.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD3AFB33D66D54CF391EE6024E97385CD" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity that receives a grant under this section may use— </text> 
<subparagraph id="HA44C988947C54AA284FB6162DB272FF5" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not more than 25 percent of the amounts made available through the grant for the first 24 months of the grant period to utilize data analysis methods to—</text> <clause id="H13E17199E6874824A62DB48419FB1429"><enum>(i)</enum><text>identify specific geographic areas where care coordination, prevention and early intervention, and facilitation services will be provided; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HBFFAD2C755F7479E8761FF2A22F28A69"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>identify support and intervention services to improve outcomes for children located in a geographic area identified under subsection (c)(1)(A); and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6E3C1D4EB8154851A5B7D3DB6274C944" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not more than 10 percent of the grant in each subsequent year to continue data analysis activities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB869D2E088B346F9A7EBC18D4B59A103" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Administration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity that receives a grant under this section may not use more than 5 percent of amounts received through the grant for administration, reporting, and program oversight functions, including the development of systems to improve data collection and data sharing for the purposes of improving services and the provision of care.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H819B373EB54C4E3489FE00B435F5E73F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Priority</header> <subparagraph id="H4B634BD423E344F4B6BCD4C1CCA90130"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall give priority, to the extent practical, to eligible entities that use community-based system dynamic modeling as the primary data analysis method.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H095FCFD6B9404B328D08625C2C6B92EF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>System dynamic modeling defined</header><text>The term <term>system dynamic modeling</term> means a method of data analysis and predictive modeling that includes—</text> <clause id="HD8C1E1A162794D14A8797E3AD28BA164"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">utilization of community-based participatory research methods for involving community in the process of understanding and changing systems and evaluating outcomes of grants;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HAB50FEF1AACA4C3F9D6F1CD802C48186"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>consideration of a multitude of environmental risk factors and ascertainment of the significance of contributing community risk factors for purposes of identifying strategies to reduce adverse child outcomes, including—</text> <subclause id="H4088C71990AF4EE9BB69016173F94231"><enum>(I)</enum><text>maltreatment cases;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H29FD68C418FE49E3AD18C42C54DE48C8"><enum>(II)</enum><text>involvement with the juvenile criminal legal system or foster system; </text></subclause> <subclause id="HA9A4DFA5880041458F3A0CEA57D3BC6D"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">exclusionary school discipline; or</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HB54EEADAA751482E9E3A6DE185FF7DFF"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">exposure to violence; and</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HBC93A7A87C9240968A3FCF206C8670CA" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identification of cross-sector responses involving reparative, trauma-informed, culturally specific, gender-responsive, and community-based organizations to reduce adverse child outcomes.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFFA98038686B41ABBEE71F12525D48A2"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Subgrant</header> 
<subparagraph id="HE1CE8F964DAF45AA8096BE678D0B5F84"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity that receives a grant under this section shall use at least 25 percent of the total amount of the grant to make subgrants to organizations that aide in implementing the strategy identified under subsection (c)(1)(B) for preventing and mitigating childhood trauma and supporting communities and families.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD00F6A420D6540AF900F83FF61B61F0A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>To be eligible to receive a subgrant under this paragraph, an organization shall prepare and submit to the eligible entity an application in such form, and containing such information, as the eligible entity may require, including evidence that the—</text> 
<clause id="H5AADF29DDDBB44BC89B9FA77F9E12240"><enum>(i)</enum><text>needs of the population to be served are urgent and are not met by the services currently available in the geographic area; and</text></clause> <clause id="H2B2EC29F35DF4F9EA1A5EA565E341C44"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the organization has the capacity to provide the services listed in subsection (c)(2).</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2433F63088E44BD9816CB31438AF7F16"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Supplement not supplant</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subgrant funds received pursuant to this paragraph by an organization shall be used to supplement and not supplant State or local funds provided to the partnership organization for services listed in subsection (c)(2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HFA311FD374C545B698E930B42D4F5EA7"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, an eligible entity shall submit to the Secretary an application in such form, and containing such information, as the Secretary may require, to include the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H3D84EB72F80843F88A01A6C6B8A2F63E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A demonstration that—</text> <subparagraph id="HC74BF1C0D2F84E24B47E20782A2678F3"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the applicant utilizes trauma-informed, culturally specific, and gender-responsive practices, including a demonstration of the extent to which the applicant has trained staff in these practices; </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H03ED9FBC8A3349329F1E4043C2FA63AF"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the applicant has the capacity to administer the grant, including conducting all required data analysis activities; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3C8636D19E1E44A8BCEC2D005E359B0F"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">services will be provided to children and families in an accessible, culturally relevant, and linguistically specific manner consistent with local needs. </text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H359E803C9E524A34B5BF00A978AABEC7"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A preliminary analysis of how the applicant will use the grant to—</text> <subparagraph id="H739E707999B54B99865049B0B915E46F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identify the geographic area or areas to be served using data analysis methods; </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB058B6BFE4584DE3AC064D22B6BD4A23"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">utilize data analysis methods to identify strategies to improve outcomes for children in the geographic area;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC88674872F854AFF997193C0905F281E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>facilitate strategies identified through care coordination efforts; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H06AC10B97C6B459A8B5BB4B6FD538C74"><enum>(D)</enum><text>track data for evaluation of outcomes.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9ECE7B5E1DB34649B652CDBA2EF5A84F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A detailed project plan for the use of the grant that includes anticipated technical assistance needs.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2D021E4322304F87B4E7D8E87D107FC9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Additional funding sources, including State and local funds, supporting the prevention and mitigation of adverse childhood experiences. </text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD58CD00DE24C424CB805AA6AE8A92F9F" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Grant amount</header><text>The amount of a grant under this section shall not exceed $9,500,000.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD5A2F5A6F3B5435CA7EE48E6F8916AED"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Period of a grant</header><text>The period of a grant under this section shall not exceed 7 years.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H15438052F9B24CD590E00CB2829A3791" commented="no"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Service provision without regard to ability To pay</header><text>As a condition on receipt of a grant under this section, an eligible entity shall agree that any assistance provided to an individual through the grant will be provided without regard to—</text> 
<paragraph id="H07C3D991CB3B41FBA47F3E5CE33AB850" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the ability of the individual to pay for such services; </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBDECBD02DF9D4DF291913261DE7AA26D" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the current or past health condition of the individual to be served;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H18B3A87E0F1845DA8A81C9065FD2BD46" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the immigration status of the individual to be served; </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBF7E16C90E8B4FB98602928721D779B8"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the sexual orientation and gender identity of the individual to be served; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1CE45F379E634F42A0BF0A30B3384AD3"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any prior involvement of the individual in the criminal legal system.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H34CD0FBE819A4007A8C8B8BC58F42A8B" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Prohibitions</header><text>In addition to any other prohibitions determined by the Secretary, an eligible entity may not use a grant under this section to—</text> 
<paragraph id="HEE0061D4D4C84591BD8BD7FA637272FA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">use data analysis methods to inform individual case decisions, including child removal or placement decisions, or to target services at certain individuals or families; </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2DB9E5E9CC7D432CA3B4434B53E2F502"><enum>(2)</enum><text>require any individual or family to participate in any service or program as a condition of receipt of a benefit to which the individual or family is otherwise eligible;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H25765C777C334D83BDED3EF72D2F028B"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">increase the presence or funding of law enforcement surveillance, involvement, or activity in implementing the strategies identified under subsection (c)(1)(B); or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3DD398C7CAF748ACB5BA80865582193B"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">enable the practice of conversion therapy.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HAEFCCB81FE7C4FB08CD21EDBAAB2D198" commented="no"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Evaluation</header> 
<paragraph id="H6AA324FCBC714EA58CE0AB1F2793D4E5" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Data model evaluation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 36 months after the date of enactment of this section, the Assistant Secretary for Planning and Evaluation of the Department of Health and Human Services, in coordination with the grantees receiving a grant under this section, shall complete an evaluation of the effectiveness of the data model accuracy of the grant program under this section to address each of the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HB63D18C4D6E140C4968847F6B832403C" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Determining the effectiveness of the grantees’ use of data analysis methods to identify geographic areas pursuant to subsection (c)(1). </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3E3F2C2C921D4701A396BB962AB3694C" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Examining the grantees’ development and utilization of data analysis methods.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFD6DA8A3D1094A049474DDA684F68CD7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Examining the grantees’ ability to effectively utilize data analysis methods in future prevention work.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE9477F2BB6C54EC788B3679F5F260C6C" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Establishing a method for rigorously evaluating the activities of grantees and comparing the reduction of child and family exposure to adverse experiences in other communities with similar demographics.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB23E1953CBCD4B10AE68A7D840528FDD"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Examining the grantees’ utilization of community-based system dynamics modeling methods and other community engagement methods.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFC17D435496348A88A8FC3258130E1FB" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Program evaluation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 6 years after the date of enactment of this section, the Assistant Secretary for Planning and Evaluation of the Department of Health and Human Services, in coordination with eligible entities receiving grants under this section, shall complete an evaluation of the effectiveness of the grant program under this section.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFD90D49AA1FB4432B883D35C940C8309"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Data collection</header> <subparagraph id="H9E6768E6B70B45F989CB26BDA6908711"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Assistant Secretary for Planning and Evaluation of the Department of Health and Human Services and each eligible entity receiving a grant under this section shall collect any relevant data necessary to complete the evaluations required by paragraphs (1) and (2) to include—</text> 
<clause id="H538F45C338A748C79084732B02C29611" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the activities funded by the grant under this section, including development and implementation data analysis methods;</text></clause> <clause id="H04EC60442FF3440C9FC3ED1C853BCD2D" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the number of children and of families receiving coordination and facilitation of care and services; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H997C792A524844ACB15DCE100ECF1690" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the effect of activities supported by the grant under this section on the local area serviced by the program, including such effects on—</text> <subclause id="H2E1B51D52DFB4AF58C51643F13C55F6E"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">children and adolescents’ health and well-being;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H14BC0560620E4CB490B4E680BBA7199F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the number of children who enter into or depart from foster services; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HFD4D0B825B3641E2922E8D92A3FDEE59"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">homelessness and housing insecurity.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA4BF769CB7474C6D96FD2021BD78FD79" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Study</header> 
<clause id="H76C877823A3A4337B36A103DFE76BACC"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 7 years after the date of enactment of this section, the Assistant Secretary for Planning and Evaluation of the Department of Health and Human Services shall—</text> <subclause id="H94CDCC8927834FDBB27AC7D3D78B1A81"><enum>(I)</enum><text>complete a study on the results of the grant program under this section using the community-based participatory action research method, which focuses on social, structural, and physical environmental inequities through active involvement of community members, clients, organizational representatives, and researchers in all aspects of the research process; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HE5938682A5B64553996CEDCCC1EF13F9"><enum>(II)</enum><text>submit a report on the results of the study to the Congress.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H4A76B23310D74D72AF2D80C40B2D42F1"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Partners</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In conducting the study under clause (i), the Assistant Secretary for Planning and Evaluation of the Department of Health and Human Services shall ensure that partners and persons that have participated in the grant program under this section on every level, especially those such partners or persons receiving services and support through the program, have an opportunity to contribute their expertise to evaluating the strategy and outcomes.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H40CF792C87F4426B8A5C95D8F7F71D0C" commented="no"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than three months after the completion of the evaluation required by subsection (j)(2), the Assistant Secretary for Planning and Evaluation of the Department of Health and Human Services shall submit to Congress and make available to the public on the internet website of the Department of Health and Human Services a report based upon the evaluation under subsection (j)(2), to include— </text> <paragraph id="H35B0F26CDDD5470CA395D4650B3CB124" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the impact of the program under this section on homelessness and housing insecurity, substance use disorder and drug deaths, incarceration, foster system involvement, and other child and family outcomes as identified by the Assistant Secretary for Planning and Evaluation of the Department of Health and Human Services;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3C9F5DD875BD421DA5080500429E5319" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an analysis of which elements of the program should be replicated and scaled by governmental or non-governmental entities; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6B1AD8C343E84746AE3A3407D934C849" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such recommendations for legislation and administrative action as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7991DB8676F241A49DC13A249D70AEAA"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H8CA9F9C4A89F4F9BA7C572B1427C1B4E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>adverse childhood experience</term> means a potentially traumatic experience that occurs in childhood and can have a tremendous impact on the child’s lifelong health and opportunity outcomes, such as any of the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF9B657EDF5BD486A9649B40057E7081C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Abuse, such as any of the following:</text> <clause id="H10DA46E95F5E47519D9AB8CA35E78990"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Emotional and psychological abuse.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HB19974CC4717475789C4E66910B52FB4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Physical abuse.</text></clause> <clause id="H420C469AA68C4DF18807F612A92D2EC9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Sexual abuse.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC59ACC76D7DF448BB9259C40D830ACD7"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Household challenges such as any of the following:</text> <clause id="H672B6DC717584BF798B8EF1E4C8939AC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>A household member is treated violently.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H4536DBAAAD0A4D958F8DBF3C68CE612F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A household member has a substance use disorder.</text></clause> <clause id="HDBFF4EAD6B1F48B6AFB0101CC4C3D478"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>A household member has a mental health condition.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H775973629A414F09ADC348C862D18EA8"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Parental separation or divorce.</text></clause> <clause id="HFA7D6BE9D4A3474A89F58CDFDA1E3B7D"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A household member is incarcerated, placed in immigrant detention, or has been deported.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H645CCFC5FDF240ACA8D015923FA6E084"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A household member has a life-threatening illness such as COVID–19.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4A2674BECDD34E8FA71D21BD0DE56AF7"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Neglect.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDC585DE9EF8641519C5C6ACF242BA235" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Living in—</text> <clause id="H8B9749D5102E494BA8DCCC3318A3AEC0" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>impoverished communities that lack access to human services;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HAC02559E99174CAEA5DF65CC27746C93" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">areas of high unemployment neighborhoods; or</text></clause> <clause id="H562383FDBB5746D3B713C06A7F6E61C5" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">communities experiencing de facto segregation.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA3D21BFB1F0E4E6A90DB1E8FCB3D73B8" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Experiencing food insecurity and poor nutrition.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H492E8B044B954CDC8E14BC028D91DFED" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Witnessing violence.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAF68918007C547CE9BB98FBF78F6A1C0" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Involvement with the foster system.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9D596EA8610B4598BF899B70ED51EF8C" commented="no"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Experiencing discrimination.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H32C16EC86B114FC6821398E0CE9937E6" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Dealing with historical and ongoing traumas due to systemic and interpersonal racism.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H795B92E548354E13896820454ECF3F39" commented="no"><enum>(J)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Dealing with historical and ongoing traumas regarding systemic and interpersonal sexism, homophobia, biphobia, and transphobia.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H84DEF526F46C4A7AAF533193E04E6D7B"><enum>(K)</enum><text>Dealing with the threat of deportation or detention as a result of immigration status.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H248752EC0A2A4C37A3FDC0B2CB2881CC"><enum>(L)</enum><text>The impacts of multigenerational poverty resulting from limited educational and economic opportunities.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB05AEB3540764E0D9041C64970CE47A9"><enum>(M)</enum><text>Living through natural disasters such as earthquakes, forest fires, floods, or hurricanes.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE8C15C7C203F40F5A4B0E19314F9F1BE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means a State or local health department.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6B755C79C2C84EEB92B919722F040182"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>practice of conversion therapy</term>—</text> <subparagraph id="HB3EC06218505418EB1A143B5BBE8A7CB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means any practice or treatment by any person that seeks to change another individual’s sexual orientation or gender identity, including efforts to change behaviors or gender expressions, or to eliminate or reduce sexual or romantic attractions or feelings toward individuals of the same gender, if such person receives monetary compensation in exchange for any such practice or treatment; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEA41B3C6EB3C4F5F9180766A33E1A070"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include any practice or treatment that does not seek to change sexual orientation or gender identity and—</text> <clause id="H8988AC3E641940E4838A6AD015FFA6E0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>provides assistance to an individual undergoing a gender transition; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H37A628A149B04251978ACACEEA795BC4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provides acceptance, support, and understanding of a client or facilitation of a client’s coping, social support, and identity exploration and development.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HED8F34C674D34975A089854450190261"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section for the period of fiscal years 2025 through 2032—</text> 
<paragraph id="HC330EFB6631D41BDA9F5C1953B7F4F9D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to carry out subsection (a)(1) through the award of grants under subsection (b)—</text> <subparagraph id="HF1AF8CF6CD9C461685B4B375962338C3"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$47,500,000 for grants; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE3FB1F1E7F4444C5A8DB74E22E9E55CB"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such sums as may be necessary for the administrative costs of carrying out such subsection; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H117BA88BD62245449C62057F656CD04E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$7,500,000 to carry out the evaluation under subsection (a)(2). </text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
<section id="H024B5898B16E408299931B8D5DCD75F3"><enum>3.</enum><header>Care coordination grants</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part E of title XII of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300d-51">42 U.S.C. 300d–51 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HBB897419DD4E4167B5756651DC1CD89C" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <section id="H2FE4B3D79DF04440AE3101D9982988ED"><enum>1255.</enum><header>Care coordination grants</header> <subsection id="H96748FB2112D472D8831115373039341"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall award grants to eligible entities to establish or expand trauma-informed care coordination services to support—</text> 
<paragraph id="H5BDD8B3455694793A4AAE9667CA49F14"><enum>(1)</enum><text>children aged 0 through 5 at risk of adverse childhood experiences; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H28783852F2D24CAABBB8D3895EA8C689"><enum>(2)</enum><text>their caregivers, including prenatal people of any age.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF1A433D4D45247A78FBC5016F3983B12"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Number of grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to the availability of appropriations, the Secretary shall award not fewer than 9 and not more than 40 grants under this section.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H53052CE177C54E00B1619596B24A46C3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Amount of grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to the availability of appropriations, the amount of a grant under this section for a fiscal year shall be—</text> 
<paragraph id="H1E9074F1DF314B46AB14BAE62FFAD9B1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not less than $250,000; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA638FF61C885435CA87EE64AFCA3B830"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not more than $1,000,000.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9CF3734C41624D598DC3212AA92C5FF0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Eligible entities</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, an entity shall be a local government or Indian Tribe, acting through the public health department thereof if such government or Tribe has a public health department.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HDA10BFABCE644BDB93962DA6D157F287"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Priority</header> <paragraph id="H9CCEE66E5DF74015A7A8BC24225CBA3D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall give priority to eligible entities proposing to serve communities with a high need for trauma-informed care coordination services, as demonstrated by indicators such as—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF55C48AB1CA04713B654E596B52A5AA0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>pregnant people who face barriers to prenatal care;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H09A720557A964C92A69E0103106207FE"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">mortality or morbidity of people giving birth or infants;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H41980EF891D14B8AB11167ECBD652A39"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">caretakers and parents who are living with a mental health condition or substance use disorder;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD59F9D89330B48AD919FB78BF2029C46"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a high prevalence of community violence, including domestic violence, as demonstrated by instances of homicide and public health statistics, including treatment of injury or trauma;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8A6F25E6ABDF4B2FBABC3C1202EFA78E"><enum>(E)</enum><text>high proportions of low-income children;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAA53F5AC4AFC4FE6BDAAD78D19314759"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a high prevalence of child fatalities or near fatalities related to child abuse and neglect;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8FB8615BEB414C87910D47A39430A907"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">significant disparities in health outcomes for people giving birth and infants;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8A5C95BFACF74B27BC98C8A072618991" commented="no"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a high rate of exclusionary discipline and referrals to law enforcement; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD617D6E45D794E5A881B149FFBA65E36"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a high rate of homelessness and housing instability.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5CF7109E8E624B28B7ECD3BDAA719F25"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Data from Tribal areas</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, acting through the Director of the Indian Health Service, shall consult with Indian Tribes to establish criteria to measure indicators of need, for purposes of paragraph (1), with respect to Tribal areas.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HABC8F264E02D4B97B3B99BFC865BF50F"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Use of funds</header> 
<paragraph id="HE2B504B03C99497FB48480766EC62F83"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Required uses</header> 
<subparagraph id="H035CF91E0FFA439C8546722A14CF66A3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A grant received under this section shall be used to establish or expand gender-responsive, culturally specific, trauma-informed care coordination services, including by instituting and conducting risk and needs assessments including—</text> <clause id="H6917691DABB1461A81F9046FC66DE3D6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>using strengths-based approaches focused on protective factors for children and their caregivers, including prenatal people of any age; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HE3E10A07CD6540E6A4EC80113D7DBACC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>inputting screening results into a centralized intake system to promote a single point of access system across providers and services.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD1241E8863364DFA8ABBBBA4CF43E61F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Training</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A grant received under this section shall be used to ensure that individuals employed through the grant funds, in whole or in part, have received sufficient and up-to-date training on trauma-informed care and strategies that are reparative, culturally sensitive, gender-responsive, and healing-centered.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3167BD1729C74FF9A841740CF585F078"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Permissible uses</header><text>A grant received under this section may be used for any of the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H994D8D9039EC48BA8039310F839A9709"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Employing care coordinators, case managers, community health workers, certified infant mental health specialists, and outreach and engagement specialists to work with children and their caregivers, including prenatal individuals, to prevent and respond to adverse childhood experiences by connecting clients with culturally specific, trauma-informed care treatment services, including economic, social, food, and housing supports.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7A3DA1824EA14D269A4362B495FEADDF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Providing training described in paragraph (1)(B) to community health providers and community partners.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE73A6FB1A3F544B7B8A7FB3D823C9A76"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Expanding, enhancing, modifying, and connecting the existing network of community programs and services to achieve a more comprehensive and coordinated system of care approach, including—</text> 
<clause id="H6F8DFDF125264576AAF32783F218139E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>developing local infrastructure to bolster and shape community support systems and map and build access to services in a coordinated and comprehensive way; and</text></clause> <clause id="H4454055110C24660BD8F26FC06533482"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">creating infrastructure to conduct outreach to children and families, including those experiencing homelessness and housing instability, so they acquire access to the services and supports they need and the benefits to which they are entitled.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6EE94ABF1B754F408E6AEFCFA7CD1385" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Compiling information on resources (including any referral services) available through community-based organizations and local, State, and Federal agencies, such as—</text> <clause id="H59B6EF27B08941CEA00D9C0B524C0130"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">programs addressing social determinants of health, including—</text> 
<subclause id="HB460EB1B9DE5412FB33AC8C5A2D06DE9"><enum>(I)</enum><text>emergency, temporary, and long-term housing;</text></subclause> <subclause id="HAF5CF9F3B5EA4274BBE3C1F003564742"><enum>(II)</enum><text>programs that offer free or affordable and nutritious food;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HBA154C810E49408F89507F96D7EF3593"><enum>(III)</enum><text>vocational and workforce development; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HF1F077B99012460AA68E1E96124E4682"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>transportation supports;</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="HFAE4E58BE2804AFEB28429EEBDB7CB04" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>home visiting programs for new parents and their infants;</text></clause> <clause id="H0DBA547874B547F491B90A7C7FFE0ACC" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>workforce development programs to support caregivers in skill building;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H589D464526464547861619C80826324B" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>trauma-responsive, parenting skills-building programs;</text></clause> <clause id="H376CB71281A54243B3D9AB87AD4361CE" commented="no"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the continuum of substance use prevention, intervention, and treatment programs and mental health support programs, including programs with trauma-informed, gender-responsive, and culturally specific counseling; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA7BF8D86D27C4EC4A25FD9DC3ACA026F" commented="no"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">childcare support and early childhood education, including Head Start and Early Head Start programs.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDDF39176AA804FD1951CA021F52FDD98"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to subsection (g)(2), establishing or updating a database that compiles data used to track the effectiveness of the care coordination services funded through the grant.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8CAFEAAB2E3945CA990286D296978D49"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Developing and implementing referral partnership agreements with community-based organizations, parent organizations, substance use disorder treatment providers and facilities, housing and shelter providers, health care providers, mental health care providers, and Federal and State offices and programs that implement practices to support children ages 0 through 5 who are at risk of adverse childhood experiences and their caregivers, including prenatal people. Such practices shall include—</text> <clause id="HC2076D1328024624B2099D7337F05112"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a bilateral <quote>warm handoff</quote> system whereby a grantee understands the needs of the children and their families, and families are involved in addressing these needs; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HE4511A18C74248629BDC5BE43F7F797B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an active service connection whereby the children and families are each actively connected with a resource in a well-coordinated way that ensures availability and direct contact.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H54CB26C8E3DC44DF91EBD823A27CE461"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Supporting cross-system planning and collaboration among employees who may work in emergency medical services, health care services, public health, early childhood education, and substance use disorder treatment and recovery support.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H11C1C0E65A7D437C9487AD4B66EC3203"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Providing or subsidizing services to address barriers that children, prenatal individuals, and caregivers face to utilizing community resources and services, such as by providing or subsidizing transportation or childcare costs as applicable and within reasonable amounts.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6B4C349C8A4841DBAAE75A45ADE2A248"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Creating or expanding infrastructure and investing in technology, including the provision of communications technology and internet service to children and their caregivers, to enable increased telemedicine capabilities to reach participants. </text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB40CE496860A4F4BB273B94DD7595DD2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Indian tribes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an eligible entity that is an Indian tribe, the Secretary may waive such provisions of this subsection as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4EB63922386F41469A4F685D8529AE1B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Prohibitions</header><text>In addition to any other prohibitions determined by the Secretary, an eligible entity may not use a grant under this section to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H98DD773925394EA6B11BEED39486BB31"><enum>(A)</enum><text>use data analysis methods to inform individual case decisions, including child removal or placement decisions, or to target services at certain individuals or families;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFA9ADD33FF744A11A55051AAC6231689"><enum>(B)</enum><text>require any individual or family to participate in any service or program as a condition of receipt of a benefit to which the individual or family is otherwise eligible; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFC1DAE8968754CEC8C493FB61B3A8C49"><enum>(C)</enum><text>increase the presence or funding of law enforcement surveillance, involvement, or activity in connection with trauma-informed care coordination services supported pursuant to this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H690832C624A04A838752278E230251C0"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>As a condition on receipt of a grant under this section, an eligible entity shall agree to each of the following funding conditions:</text> 
<paragraph id="HB2A850873F294C5FA0118BED6D01CDC4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Restriction of funding allocation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The eligible entity will not use more than 30 percent of the funds made available to the entity through the grant (for the total grant period) to establish or update a database pursuant to subsection (f)(2)(E).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA9E9EEF8A7B2490B9F475530E31120A9" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Accessible setting</header> <subparagraph id="H44164D3DA60341E0B2C0A1B047B9BD89" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The eligible entity will ensure that all care coordination services provided through the grant are provided in a setting that is accessible, including through mobile settings, to—</text> 
<clause id="H4918EF88FF224A91B0CCF048EEC69B2E" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">low-income or no-income individuals, including individuals experiencing homelessness or housing instability; and</text></clause> <clause id="HA5435BD7227C4FA383C879AB0FD66607" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>individuals in rural areas.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9E1F9C0E62164E6B87F219EA2420F059" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Community outreach</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In complying with subparagraph (A), the eligible entity will ensure that at least 50 percent of the care coordination services provided through the grant occur in community settings that are convenient to the children and caregivers who are being served, such as homes, schools, and shelters, whether for initial outreach or as part of long-term care.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5EBB4A878CA04834B2E6B710BC73C3DF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Supplement not supplant</header><text>The grant will be used to supplement not supplant other Federal, State, or local funds available for care coordination services.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEEA147F7E9684B0FA5B682C0455CDB98"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Confidentiality</header><text>The eligible entity will maintain the confidentiality of individuals receiving services through the grant in a manner consistent with applicable law.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5217DA49D4A841EA92A8C5E853E6DC18"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Partnering; risk stratification</header><text>In providing care coordination services through the grant, the eligible entity will—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H2933127BAF3C4B1CAFF92BC879782A84"><enum>(A)</enum><text>partner with community-based organizations with experience serving child populations prenatally through age 5;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9F812309F11243A9985BF0BCC889951D"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">coordinate with the local agency responsible for administering the State plan approved under title XIX of the Social Security Act; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H86B3DA27F4464C869C80F3BA2472C4CA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>employ risk stratification to develop different effective models of care for different populations based on their needs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H7438BCA7420248A28A3EDCA89341C274"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Application</header> <paragraph id="H37E3A20F664A41B7A64637F5FBD842DB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To seek a grant under this section, an eligible entity shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information, as the Secretary may require.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H10D191A5A6E14A9CA00315CD1EF4F4B8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>An application under paragraph (1) shall, at a minimum, contain each of the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HC5C81BDFEDF947A6B8F982672CF4B13C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Goals to be achieved through the grant, including the activities that will be undertaken to achieve those goals.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H16F0FD9D3D5F4B43B2513E19E052AAF2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The number of individuals likely to be served through the grant, including demographic data on the populations to be served.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3FCBFC3B2EC54352A2180EE6DBE8C042"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Existing programs and services that can be used to significantly increase the proportion of children and families who receive needed supports and services.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2C9D9E1FAB224A72A28534B1759F7EF5"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A plan for expanding, coordinating, or modifying the existing network of programs and services to meet the needs of children and families for preventing and mitigating the traumatic impact of adverse childhood experiences. </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAD2499AE44B446B8A78BC0169475D15C"><enum>(E)</enum><text>A demonstration of the ability of the eligible entity to reach the individuals to be served, including by partnering with local stakeholders.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H58CC2EA96B4B4DB89BBCBA811008AA21"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An indication of how the personnel involved are reflective of the communities to be served.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9CA5E1B091464D67A2D81EF1F377741B"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A list of stakeholders with whom the entity plans to partner or consult.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9A3DD800CC8C43EF8DD96B9CAE77998B"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Reporting by grantees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 4 years after the date of enactment of this section, an eligible entity receiving a grant under this section shall submit to the Secretary a report on the activities funded through the grant. Such report shall include, at a minimum, a description of—</text> <paragraph id="H4DD9BE3F19F74EEDA4251A93FCF17C8B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the number of individuals served through activities funded through the grant, including demographics as applicable;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBD0176A576DD4F9188BAABA08CD8F99E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the number of referrals made through the grant and the rate of such referrals successfully linked or closed;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2FD02D5F40A34F31B120D9BCAC79C3C3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a qualitative analysis or number of collaborative partnerships with other organizations in carrying out the activities funded through the grant;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H36D4ACC93CAE49A182D36CFC11B4FF68"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the number of services provided to individuals through the grant;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H41C622B1F6EF493792D03F6A73A8D735"><enum>(5)</enum><text>aggregated and de-identified outcomes experienced by individuals served through the grant such as—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HFA96A5E415024BE0919FC81D027E840B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the rate of successful service connections;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8766C8C18EE24E02B1CBBB7321749705"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any increases in development of protective factors for children;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC05F8B04050D4E539DA5C2E44FEAC397"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any increase in development of protective factors for the caregivers;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H098F0ADEAFFE4CFDB24D551D00CC8DFF"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any mitigation of the negative outcomes associated with adverse childhood experiences or decreased likelihood of children experiencing an adverse childhood experience as evidenced by—</text> 
<clause id="HD150B7AA7EAA4E6BB64922B2A33CC2DF"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">decreased presence of law enforcement or other punitive State surveillance in the community;</text></clause> <clause id="HDFA8C4E7B25C4915ADDC394FDCAC59A5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a parent completing substance use treatment;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HD0670C25452A4D56AF8DEBE07C5EE110"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a parent receiving voluntary treatment for mental health-related conditions;</text></clause> <clause id="HF0EEF4151D1142BFA112A6CCADC927B7"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a family entering into or maintaining a stable housing situation;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H3EAFAE2145074A18845D391A98F54440"><enum>(v)</enum><text>a family achieving or maintaining economic security; </text></clause> <clause id="H4C0E1288A01642BE85BC4CBC5AC6BF74"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a parent achieving or maintaining job stability; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H6996A80A39364ED4AB5C02E9B41B587F"><enum>(vii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a child meeting developmental markers for school readiness; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA13E9CC9C007489BA74971E55E2B527C"><enum>(E)</enum><text>reports of satisfaction with the coordination of care by people served; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDC502EB5ADB24797BF35805704A48C5A"><enum>(6)</enum><text>any other information required by the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H9AC7B2AF70D2452FAF6D07605A15A83D" commented="no"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Convening participants for sharing lessons learned</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After the period of all grants awarded under this section has concluded, the Assistant Secretary for Planning and Evaluation of the Department of Health and Human Services shall provide an in-person or online opportunity for persons participating in the programs funded through this section to share with each other—</text> 
<paragraph id="HE69E412EC21346DFA8BCF023EC3A611B" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>lessons learned;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6EE7019C84CC4780BECB1F8C342E96CA" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>challenges experienced; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6F57055491284055908B3D0FD0ED8999" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>ideas for next steps and solutions.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H4293C20A48F845139966FA4AD2DE68B5"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Compiling findings and conclusions</header><text>After providing the opportunity required by subsection (j), the Secretary shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="HA9F33D6DD43646A7BF675C47634965E3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>compile the findings and conclusions of grantees under this section on the provision of care coordination services described in subsection (a);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA9C4D1D9E1C94305BB913F81F6669283"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submit a report on such findings and conclusions to the appropriate congressional committees; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA9DD5D520C07432089C74A5D1E42F379"><enum>(3)</enum><text>make such report publicly available. </text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H7FDD4A0E3E2548B7B86796A71386ADE0"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H98FDB674257E44C1807B721275A58291"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Adverse childhood experience</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>adverse childhood experience</term> means a potentially traumatic experience that occurs in childhood and can have a tremendous impact on the child’s lifelong health and opportunity outcomes, such as any of the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HF32260B649634B409A87751C5555EE84"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Abuse, such as any of the following:</text> 
<clause id="HD38CAC5D18B5433A8F00EE8D22DAE9F6"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Emotional and psychological abuse.</text></clause> <clause id="HED67E3A162424F8C87E9AB689090DE8B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Physical abuse.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H45896FCEF2DF46D09BC10DF4CB144246"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Sexual abuse.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD6F5148C53A84B00979571DF2643B4EF"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Household challenges such as any of the following:</text> 
<clause id="H1E13B002ECA64561BFE19EF8412EE69F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>A household member is treated violently.</text></clause> <clause id="H71C459385C584A1C91EFD874750E0C44"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A household member has a substance use disorder.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H418A78850B3740A3A9A32A3F08A344FD"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>A household member has a mental health condition.</text></clause> <clause id="HCEAD37B936BC4B6A9EB6441F3AE5A9D6"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Parental separation or divorce.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HAF6BBCC7F0854A94BBFDDFB51AAACB51"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A household member is incarcerated, placed in immigrant detention, or has been deported.</text></clause> <clause id="HA4F9B93AEAE0429FB0E6A6CC48E9FE81"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A household member has a life-threatening illness such as COVID–19.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H08F7A9204CAE43FC9817109841448461"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Neglect.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H54BCF7E58FC74FC2A37413B7DD3B7D80" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Living in—</text> 
<clause id="H499CDB6DFAA0474D9DB471E169CD542B" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>impoverished communities that lack access to human services;</text></clause> <clause id="H854D644061F04CC188E7ED507067E7CE" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">areas of high unemployment neighborhoods; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H6837F45A475C4BE3954A79FB4515B161" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">communities experiencing de facto segregation.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H367201098A034E5495EDA79A6F7D3EF7" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Experiencing food insecurity and poor nutrition.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7E6BD5189BCC48AB836EA74B4A5AE241" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Witnessing violence.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB627BB25B72B4FD4BB22F8BFDD698445" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Involvement with the foster system.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H231A5F0B35494A499133F18A3D67B5E9" commented="no"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Experiencing discrimination.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAA56ACC2CCB845C58869B86C419BEE73" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Dealing with historical and ongoing traumas due to systemic and interpersonal racism.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCB79957BEE304821BD16167C74A71F42" commented="no"><enum>(J)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Dealing with historical and ongoing traumas regarding systemic and interpersonal sexism, homophobia, biphobia, and transphobia.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD28BF604B8204CB294E3192736AA8809"><enum>(K)</enum><text>Dealing with the threat of deportation or detention as a result of immigration status.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCDFDB3A4F03B4B6CAC135C1C10C6A37A"><enum>(L)</enum><text>The impacts of multigenerational poverty resulting from limited educational and economic opportunities.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA372CCAEE5AD44DF9DECD4CE787D628B"><enum>(M)</enum><text>Living through natural disasters such as earthquakes, forest fires, floods, or hurricanes.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H314A97A187934D20842FAD418F7830FB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Care coordination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>care coordination</term> means an active, ongoing process that—</text> <subparagraph id="H3E946BB919F34A8784E2257A8885CA84"><enum>(A)</enum><text>assists children ages 0 through 5 at risk of, or who have experienced, an adverse childhood experience, and their caregivers, including prenatal people of any age, to identify, access, and use community resources and services;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H550135E877F34C1494364CD53687B88E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is client-centered and comprehensive of the services a child or caregiver may need; </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H382F853350F84B8DBB1DE9C59FE3590B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>ensures a closed loop referral by obtaining feedback from the families served; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H206DC82090AF4445881558350BEF40E9"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">works across systems and services to promote collaboration to effectively meet the needs of community members.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB430B5D4E8A14E5AAD816E0245750AF6" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Indian Tribe</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Indian Tribe</term> has the meaning given such term in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H68EA4F006900472E96542259869093EA"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Protective factors</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>protective factors</term> refers to any supportive element in a child or caretaker’s life that helps the child or caretaker to withstand trauma such as a stable school environment or supportive peer relationships.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H56F1356CC9254192BC5B22F4981B2F7E"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header> <paragraph id="H6837C1E498A5496BBD7DBC51D5924B17"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To carry out this section, there is authorized to be appropriated $15,000,000 for each of the 5 fiscal years following the fiscal year in which this section is enacted.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0E076B1655FF4921994EE21D33CDEA1D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Grants to Indian tribes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the amount made available to carry out this section for a fiscal year, the Secretary shall use not less than 10 percent of such amount for grants to eligible entities that are Indian tribes.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H63B0C3D5DD16492D9A590C1CCE66CF73"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Administrative expenses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the amount made available to carry out this section for a fiscal year, the Secretary may use not more than 15 percent of such amount for administrative expenses, including the expenses of the Assistant Secretary for Planning and Evaluation of the Department of Health and Human Services for compiling and reporting information.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAB340D6319FE482A8374A91F6C9B0768"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the amount made available to carry out this section for a fiscal year, the Secretary may reserve up to 5 percent of such amount to provide technical assistance to eligible entities in preparing and submitting applications under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> </legis-body></bill>

