<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H49065C911B744D988C9E9AFE6BF384D5" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1518 IH: New Era of Preventing End-Stage Kidney Disease Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1518</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250224">February 24, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001257">Mr. Bilirakis</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001205">Mrs. Miller of West Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001306">Mr. Balderson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001190">Mr. Schneider</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Public Health Service Act with respect to preventing end-stage kidney disease, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H24352DF1F5CA487CB2AA0AB53BEDD005" style="OLC"><section id="HDBB87D1AAAED453BB676735104319DB8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>New Era of Preventing End-Stage Kidney Disease Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H2CBD69101905405CAC51F9BF134867A5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Centers of Excellence on Rare Kidney Disease Research in the National Institute of Diabetes and Digestive and Kidney Diseases</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subpart 3 of part C of title IV of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/281">42 U.S.C. 281 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 426 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/285c">42 U.S.C. 285c</external-xref>) the following new section:</text><quoted-block id="H07DD2EC9A7BE424CA5D13F2F02A8602E" style="OLC"><section id="H722D269F87004B498BA41D646DE0DCF2"><enum>426A.</enum><header>Centers of Excellence on Rare Kidney Disease Research in the National Institute of Diabetes and Digestive and Kidney Diseases</header><subsection id="H01C846D26FB94D70B205B8F492C375F9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Cooperative agreements and grants</header><paragraph id="H7568BC030A894E7C8A5C1F227AB1A151"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Institute may enter into cooperative agreements with, and make grants to, public and private nonprofit entities to pay all or part of the cost of planning, establishing, or strengthening, and providing basic operating support for, regional centers of excellence for rare kidney diseases, including primary glomerular disease. Such centers of excellence shall be known as NIDDK Centers of Excellence on Rare Kidney Disease Research (referred to in this section as <quote>Centers of Excellence</quote>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H12EF1E9B4141408BB7CF90596F685348"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Purposes of centers</header><text>The purposes of the Centers of Excellence funded pursuant to paragraph (1) shall be—</text><subparagraph id="HC3D4B59CDCF84F6CA3E4F48827EDE01D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to conduct research on the causes, etiology, symptoms, diagnosis, progression, and treatment of rare kidney diseases, including glomerular diseases;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H250668FB61CF4BDD8447B4A370FE2226"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to increase public awareness of rare kidney diseases, particularly in rural and underserved communities; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H742C0F2C51B34A24B1167652F051DD5B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to develop resources for clinical research into, training in, and demonstration of diagnostic, prevention, control, and treatment methods for, rare kidney diseases.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H189A2CA6159C44BBB4C3212A4F665824"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Policies</header><text>A cooperative agreement or grant under paragraph (1) shall be entered into in accordance with policies established by the Director of the National Institutes of Health.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8BF97593D8EA4C38B0E84ACDFC9AC784"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Coordination with other institutes</header><text>The Director of the Institute shall coordinate the activities under this section with similar activities that are related to rare kidney disease and conducted by other national research institutes, centers, and agencies of the National Institutes of Health and by the Food and Drug Administration.</text></subsection><subsection id="HDC817140D4D648B3BCC4D8668DC06450"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>An entity that enters into a cooperative agreement or receives a grant under subsection (a) may use funds received through such agreement or grant—</text><paragraph id="HDA2A97F90D72488FBC1D01D11497FA49"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to cover patient care costs required to conduct research described in subsection (a)(2)(A);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF17D25E4865C4ECBA75707DFE0CA31EA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to provide, for the purpose described in subsection (a)(2)(B)—</text><subparagraph id="HDD95C38CE96A4B70A4F91EF988940882"><enum>(A)</enum><text>clinical training and continuing education for health professionals and related personnel with respect to rare kidney diseases; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H03995FF590544C4294644DAB7BB38D1B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>information programs for the public, with respect to rare kidney diseases; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB414017E913642CF952AEF41317E190A"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to provide, for the purpose described in subsection (a)(2)(B)—</text><subparagraph id="HA6E6E31FDA744CFD823881BBECBE8588"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for education of members of the public, particularly through outreach to rural and underserved communities, on the diagnosis (including through routine urinalysis and through genetic testing), prevention, control, and treatment of rare kidney diseases; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0EF9CE7E43384E50B3147FD71F69C8F4"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for education of individuals diagnosed with rare kidney diseases on renal diet and lifestyle, genetic testing, and programs to promote urinalysis, and on mental and emotional health resources for families of rare kidney disease patients.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB0C95242B5AB42E39E24F507D7E3C1E1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Research funded</header><text>Research conducted using funds awarded through a cooperative agreement or grant under this section—</text><paragraph id="H50BE267ADF88456EAC1D9B861B51DAAD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall include study of genotype-phenotype relation to disease progression; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA1E2B247D2AC4DB8AB69A560905065C7"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect the populations studied in such research, may not include any consideration of quality-adjusted life years or disability adjusted life years, or other similar mechanisms that discriminate against individuals with disabilities in value and cost-effectiveness assessments.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD28924746A8A427F8ED154D10F64BE6F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Period of support; additional periods</header><text>The period of support for a center of excellence under subsection (a) may not exceed 5 years, except that such period may be extended by the Director of the Institute for additional periods of not more than 5 years for each center if—</text><paragraph id="H1823BEB4D9334FA7992F3E5883854ED5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the operations of such center have been reviewed by an appropriate technical and scientific peer review group established by the Director of the Institute; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9A447C998C70448A8334BB2A201834B3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>such group has recommended to the Director of the Institute that such period should be extended.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFC136B50907C4AEBB6701A6324792BEC"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>To carry out this section, there are authorized to be appropriated $6,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="HD3578FF7E0A147AEB53F3A5E63848899"><enum>3.</enum><header>Understanding and Slowing the Progression of Rare Kidney Disease Through Early Intervention, Testing, and Treatment</header><subsection id="HF1F0A475AAC64F3F98C02161C3C5A22A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services (in this section referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall conduct a study on testing, preventative care, precision medicine, and treatment, with respect to rare kidney disease. Such study shall review—</text><paragraph id="HC37FDA949B774D4CBE9E8848DF571DFA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the impact of routine urinalysis on the timely diagnosis of rare kidney disease and on the quality of patient care following a diagnosis of such disease;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H96CF324094AF4CB7BE5F4D8DFC0AF50F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the quality and reliability of kidney biopsy in the diagnosis of rare kidney disease;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H64F73AA071E6416E82BDA2816C1BC908"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the utility and appropriate use of genetic and genomic tests in detecting kidney disease, including—</text><subparagraph id="H4AF691BEA689474CB22217F3D0B572F0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>advances in genetic and genomic testing, and in particular testing of the APOL1 gene, and whether such testing may improve the diagnosis and treatment of rare kidney disease;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEF86BE14B4954617AADDDAC92B1EDE0C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">barriers to genetic and genomic testing, such as diagnostic, predictive, presymptomatic testing, and DNA sequencing clinical services, including an analysis of any existing barriers related to health insurance coverage of such testing and access to genetic counselors, pathologists, and other relevant professions; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9525656FA6924A44A5761FE55BFD2FF1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">strategies to increase routine urinalysis and other diagnostic testing and to improve technologies to diagnose such disease, including genetic testing, and to improve access to health insurance coverage of such diagnostic testing and technologies;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6FD2E290E0B342A8ADFE8714884016CA"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the social, behavioral, and biological factors leading to rare kidney disease;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HADB9757DA9674A8D95C533848DC421DB"><enum>(5)</enum><text>treatment patterns associated with providing care, under the Medicare program under title XVIII of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395">42 U.S.C. 1395 et seq.</external-xref>), the Medicaid program under title XIX of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396">42 U.S.C. 1396 et seq.</external-xref>), and through private health insurance, to populations that are disproportionately affected by such disease;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA2E3414394AC4E07B6E9076D770308DC"><enum>(6)</enum><text>access to nephrologists among populations that are disproportionately affected by such disease;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6263E260E8FC45CA853C7EC682AC2338"><enum>(7)</enum><text>ongoing efforts and recommendations to slow the progression of end-stage kidney disease in populations that are disproportionately affected by rare kidney disease; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8C49E8602F7C49DB95CDD84BF2FA780A"><enum>(8)</enum><text>patient trust of treating providers among populations that are disproportionately affected by such disease.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCBFD8006F99E45DBB0B7A08F05159CB9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><paragraph id="H46547B300D1E4220846E18D7095D9208"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Congress a report on the results of the study under subsection (a), together with such recommendations as the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H84CC81DC43BB4AE5B993B2A2BF0CBC39"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In conducting the study under subsection (a) and developing the report required by paragraph (1), the Secretary shall consult with relevant stakeholders, including health care providers, medical professional societies, State-based societies, public health experts, health educators, health professional organizations, drug and device manufacturers, patient organizations, pharmacists, payors, State and local public health departments, State medical boards, and other entities with experience in health care, public health, nephrology, and rare disease, as appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD7C3C584F6E848019C73E36B3E72FAE1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>In carrying out the activities under subsections (a) and (b), the Secretary shall coordinate with the Director of NIH, the Administrator of the Center for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services, the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration, and the Director of the Center for Medicare and Medicaid Innovation.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA84360F503FD4569A18B52C79D26C85F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To carry out this section, there is authorized to be appropriated $1,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030.</text></subsection></section><section id="H56CAA2894D3E4DAC9CDF943C932A17EC"><enum>4.</enum><header>Provider education</header><subsection id="HBFFD2E82EBD54F4DB1943A9F51B7C396"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Primary care training</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 747(b)(3)(E) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/293k">42 U.S.C. 293k(b)(3)(E)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H9902C1E8B3C5499EBC89B0BD42007992"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and individuals</quote> and inserting <quote>, individuals</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H634F919C4EAE4DC4BB6347F9A7958430"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, and individuals with kidney disease (including rare kidney disease)</quote> after <quote>disabilities</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8EBAC772203748A598C392D71D5E9170"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Nephrology fellowships</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 736(b) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/293">42 U.S.C. 293</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H32A7AE0D84FB48CCA47698573BFDB2B1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (7) as paragraph (8); </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC14D5E7596464E0898E914EF8799278C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (6)(B), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a semicolon; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H641912F70E0C4E2E96377F3E75CF90E8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (6) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HB8D357347C3E4EBFBF56AC68440E5159" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H75A40B63761D4517B6B69C2A15EBE59E"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to award fellowships, which may include stipends, for postgraduate training in the field of nephrology, for the purposes of—</text><subparagraph id="HAEB2368D4AC744E8875BADC94C642CAD"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">increasing providers’ knowledge of issues related to prevention, diagnosis, and treatment of rare kidney disease for populations disproportionately impacted by the disease, including the prevalence of the gene APOL1;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEE7F332FB5E8459EB73DEFEF2DE93B42"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">improving the quality of rare kidney disease prevention, diagnosis, and treatment delivered to racial and ethnic minorities; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H13EF25BCA43847B4A7AFA8ED848B5A89"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">increasing the number of nephrologists trained to provide care to such populations; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H3169CA9AA15340A58BF7B93107C502E3"><enum>5.</enum><header>Delaying kidney disease impact</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1881(f) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395rr">42 U.S.C. 1395rr(f)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HBEDE4A3DB3D845BB962B29AD357FAD64" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H42140C2CD61C4A4F8370BFBDC54067A9" indent="up1"><enum>(9)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H39FBE3BD618D4BCBA791A07DF641497F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall conduct experiments to evaluate methods for treating rare kidney disease, giving particular attention to treatments that would delay or eliminate the need for dialysis and transplant.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9DF920B26BBC412C8EAFEE85DFD7B6B8" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall conduct a comprehensive study of methods to increase public awareness of rare kidney disease.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2CACBF192FBE451499ADC15183A928BB" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall submit to Congress, not later than 24 months after the date of the enactment of the New Era of Preventing End-Stage Kidney Disease Act, a report on the experiments and study conducted under subparagraphs (A) and (B). Such report shall include recommendations for legislative changes that the Secretary finds necessary or desirable as a result of such experiments and study.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

