<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCB7E3FD7861840E38B7590117F88FE57" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1753 IH: Community News and Small Business Support Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1753</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250227">February 27, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000478">Ms. Tenney</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide tax incentives that support local media.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE0B41619F3B446AAA7295331AFEA5FED" style="OLC"><section id="H60422E25BD674AEFBA09B2DAD3421309" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Community News and Small Business Support Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H165E52630BE54C4E81E01C514856911E" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Credit for advertising in local media</header><subsection id="H528A7B7C122B47B3B2C2792047DF14D8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subpart D of part IV of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE47844F294C54413A64DC06A4CBCFEDA" style="OLC"><section id="H7D53DA09924247B2BF807894E8A28626"><enum>45BB.</enum><header>Advertising in local media</header><subsection id="H06CAA15108364E17A95590E4447B3262"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of section 38, in the case of any eligible small business, the local media advertising credit determined under this section for any taxable year is an amount equal to the applicable percentage of the qualified local media advertising expenses paid or incurred by the taxpayer during such taxable year.</text></subsection><subsection id="H32776BE8C04E4AB4AFDADD9280464DC8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The credit allowed under subsection (a) to any taxpayer for any taxable year shall not exceed—</text><paragraph id="HBBB7796825034247AF55B6C97CCBB522"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the case of the first taxable year to which this section applies, $5,000, and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H85097A0B912F48E88983F50EDDE021B1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the case of any subsequent taxable year, $2,500.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAD524A6F31B44366AAF2F985D55E6A64"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applicable percentage</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>applicable percentage</term> means—</text><paragraph id="H4DC645700D2141C1A6F23D3F9E508149"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the case of the first taxable year to which this section applies, 80 percent, and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5381F570097B4FAEB630A6C48C301E3D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the case of any subsequent taxable year, 50 percent.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEE00100BDBE44803815AD81F1EE9BB9C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Eligible small business</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the term <term>eligible small business</term> means any person for any taxable year if the average number of full-time employees (as determined for purposes of determining whether an employer is an applicable large employer for purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/4980H">section 4980H(c)(2)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986) employed by such person during such taxable year was less than 50.</text></subsection><subsection id="H6005B2946934438ABF23AB82D939FFEF"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Qualified local media advertising expenses</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>qualified local media advertising expenses</term> means amounts paid or incurred in the ordinary course of a trade or business for—</text><paragraph id="H944B6198617E4A2F81D551DF00375E79"><enum>(1)</enum><text>advertising in a local newspaper, or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB0EE3A6CD4E14F9EAB24C453F141B5CE"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">advertising on any broadcast radio or television station licensed by the Federal Communications Commission to serve a local community.</text></paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">For purposes of this subsection, the term <quote>advertising</quote> includes sponsorships. </continuation-text></subsection><subsection id="H2329FC33E84E412CBCAB383F0024503E"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Local newspaper</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text><paragraph id="H37B6D695E63841DFBCA7958BD1974D8F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>local newspaper</term> means any print or digital publication if—</text><subparagraph id="HD7DF3F061CC64EAEAB1F9AB743B842DB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the primary content of such publication is original content derived from primary sources and relating to news and current events,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCE4B715E431D421E881A041D62FE3346"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such publication primarily serves the needs of a regional or local community,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3D133CCCC9EF4D30B80F0FFD4EEA1AB7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the publisher of such publication—</text><clause id="H31DECA57C4964FDA86821EEAB942576E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>employs at least one full-time local news journalist who resides in such regional or local community,</text></clause><clause id="H22240256CF694725A6014675D5EDB8CB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>employs not greater than 750 employees, and</text></clause><clause id="HD2BC93F2D39F4A519843417825D7A6A5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>is not—</text><subclause id="HA5ACEF2A79A446ACAAEE7B9DD98BACD6"><enum>(I)</enum><text>an organization described in paragraph (4), (5), or (6) of section 501(c),</text></subclause><subclause id="H30EB4A7BC76B4DF6B64680682AA1940F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a political organization (as defined in section 527(e)),</text></subclause><subclause id="HE631E15C3DA647AAB28889FC5790EA81"><enum>(III)</enum><text>any organization controlled by one or more organizations described in subclauses (I) or (II), or</text></subclause><subclause id="HD8F89D0E16944AE5AE2EC45F04030CD1"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>any organization that received more than $100,000 (in the aggregate) from organizations described in subclauses (I), (II), or (III) during the taxable year or any preceding taxable year.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H73A46AB1C7F34BE8A570823664A49692"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Local news journalist</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of paragraph (1)(C)(i), the term <term>local news journalist</term> means any individual who regularly gathers, prepares, produces, collects, edits, photographs, records, directs the recording of, writes, presents, or reports news or information that concerns local events or other matters of local public interest.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4F7EFD8A4DEC4E769F18D4A27CF616A0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Aggregation rule</header><subparagraph id="HE770523879CF46C39817AAEBAEE7AF1E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of clauses (ii) and (iii) of paragraph (1)(C), all persons treated as a single employer under subsection (a) or (b) of section 52, or subsection (m) or (o) of section 414, shall be treated as one person.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H10846C018A5340A0B4F00F53A928D1D0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Subparagraph (A) shall not apply unless such persons are involved in the production of the same print or digital publication.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1FBBB857AD2E4EB7A9A64FF17E301111"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Continuous qualification</header><text>The requirements of paragraph (1)(C) shall not be treated as met unless such requirements are met at all times during the period beginning on the date which is 1 year before the date of the enactment of this section and ending on the date that the subscription described in subsection (a) is paid or incurred.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1BC0FEB027AF43DA85A61820D89F62AB"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Special rules</header><paragraph id="HDC9D2D0A5E794BD58FC789AFB05CD4FE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Denial of double benefit</header><text>No deduction shall be allowed for any qualified local media advertising expenses otherwise allowable as a deduction for the taxable year which is equal to the amount of the credit determined for such taxable year under subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H47D768FB2A54480F9FE518FF22610072" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Aggregation rule</header><text>All persons treated as a single employer under subsection (a) or (b) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/52">section 52</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, or subsection (m) or (o) of section 414 of such Code, shall be treated as one person for purposes of applying subsection (b).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H639D836CFB6E43CB95583FF3DED37A26"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>No credit shall be allowed under this section for any amount paid or incurred in a taxable year ending after the close of 5-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H97B3550B55604359A74A799E294AC898" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Credit allowed as part of general business credit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 38(b) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>plus</quote> at the end of paragraph (40), by striking the period at the end of paragraph (41) and inserting <quote>, plus</quote>, and by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4B37C35C714E4A83AAF8CBA406DFA000" style="OLC"><paragraph id="HE4922D423FEA4A2CBDCB89B38F9687BD" commented="no"><enum>(42)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of an eligible small business, the local media advertising credit determined under section 45BB(a).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H5F1A7BED1B464A70BC8929F481F7E656"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for subpart D of part IV of subchapter A of chapter 1 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H28EC09126FF545CF88D3E94CC830D053" style="OLC"><toc container-level="quoted-block-container" idref="HE47844F294C54413A64DC06A4CBCFEDA" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration"><toc-entry idref="H7D53DA09924247B2BF807894E8A28626" level="section">Sec. 45BB. Advertising in local media.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HA3ADCD75B20D489DAD7062E413A03308"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to amounts paid or incurred in taxable years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="H7675BF8BDC0F4FAFAB6CFD3792C17D95"><enum>3.</enum><header>Payroll credit for compensation of local news journalist</header><subsection id="HB9F37495520B435FA816D848118B4385"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter D of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/21">chapter 21</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H1DC7151739644DB3953CBAF7034FA53B" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="H0515866141D144AB9CE664A90A0CBFA6"><enum>3135.</enum><header>Local news journalist compensation credit</header><subsection id="H59A96140672B4C2C848F6E0AE4D88E1E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an eligible local news journalist employer, there shall be allowed as a credit against applicable employment taxes for each calendar quarter an amount equal to the applicable percentage of the wages paid by such employer to local news journalists for such calendar quarter.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1BAED8B5F54645BF991C5A8B29890E3F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitations and refundability</header><paragraph id="H0309F3E21B454658A8A16073484587F6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Limitation on number of local news journalists taken into account</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number of employees of any eligible local news journalist employer which are taken into account as local news journalists under subsection (a) for any calendar quarter shall not exceed 1,500.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE6B74957ED22476687E98AEDD6AA71B9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation on wages taken into account</header><text>The amount of wages paid with respect to any individual which may be taken into account under subsection (a) during any calendar quarter by the eligible local news journalist employer shall not exceed $12,500.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCCC0D13F23AE47E0AC82790281E54EEE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Credit limited to employment taxes</header><text>The credit allowed by subsection (a) with respect to any calendar quarter shall not exceed the applicable employment taxes (reduced by any credits allowed under sections 3131, 3132, and 3134) on the wages paid with respect to the employment of all the employees of the eligible local news journalist employer for such calendar quarter.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDE39EE986D4841D4BC7A0D1242FCB549"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Refundability of excess credit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the amount of the credit under subsection (a) exceeds the limitation of paragraph (3) for any calendar quarter, such excess shall be treated as an overpayment that shall be refunded under sections 6402(a) and 6413(b).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDC67C32313BB4558AB6508E2F13FD618"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text><paragraph id="H38E819585061462FB51775C6AD5EE83D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Applicable percentage</header><text>The term <term>applicable percentage</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H3B6905AD31B54083A4C92B9A8E966445"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case of each of the first 4 calendar quarters to which this section applies, 50 percent; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6B048BEE9FCC41E1AF4D055D9A9443CB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of each calendar quarter thereafter, 30 percent.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0D17690F18154D16A907EA5D6CA1E9E9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible local news journalist employer</header><text>The term <term>eligible local news journalist employer</term> means, with respect to any calendar quarter, any employer if substantially all of the gross receipts of such employer for such calendar quarter are derived in the trade or business of publishing local newspapers (as defined in section 45BB(f)).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC3625CD05E874EC19156CC0AFB391CC2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Local news journalist</header><text>The term <quote>local news journalist</quote> means, with respect to any eligible local news journalist employer for any calendar quarter, any individual who provides at least 200 hours of service as a local news journalist (as defined in section 45BB(f)(2)) during such calendar quarter to such eligible local news journalist employer.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAA841D65194C402891A95A30F30423A7"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Applicable employment taxes</header><text>The term <quote>applicable employment taxes</quote> means the following:</text><subparagraph id="HEDC4F5A8681243FC96324FB56AED5F0D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The taxes imposed under section 3111(b).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2166D23565A94BD9B80768708D993363"><enum>(B)</enum><text>So much of the taxes imposed under section 3221(a) as are attributable to the rate in effect under section 3111(b).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5DF7F561AAC14DB2BEB6B600FFAC837E" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Aggregation rule</header><paragraph id="HD58FAF542B1741E49011CEEC7768CC95"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>All persons treated as a single employer under subsection (a) or (b) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/52">section 52</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, or subsection (m) or (o) of section 414 of such Code, shall be treated as one employer for purposes of this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD7D7A3D9FA894A919A752C48EB9284DD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Paragraph (1) shall not apply unless such persons are involved in the production of the same print or digital publication.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD046743061BA4734842B6BEDC0E75FEF"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Certain rules to apply</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section—</text><paragraph id="H7D6FEFE325CD464396764AF492F5382D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Rules similar to the rules of sections 51(i)(1) and 280C(a) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 shall apply.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H32E9462E725A4C6A8B147F33D9D0D029"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception to related party rules</header><text>In the case of an eligible local news journalist employer which employs fewer than 15 local news journalists during the calendar quarter, paragraph (1) shall be applied without regard to the reference to section 51(i)(1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA3ACAD72EC904AF7B56C6ADD0902C732" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Certain governmental employers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This credit shall not apply to the Government of the United States, the government of any State or political subdivision thereof, or any agency or instrumentality of any of the foregoing.</text></subsection><subsection id="H3BC366F06CDF4C098D0BBDD072DAEFF0"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Election to have section not apply</header><text>This section shall not apply with respect to any eligible local news journalist employer for any calendar quarter if such person elects (at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may prescribe) not to have this section apply.</text></subsection><subsection id="H86AD5C20855E40339EDCFD712FDAA762"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Special rules</header><paragraph id="HB0E8E71E5B6446BDB0C4F1D79959188A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Employee not taken into account more than once</header><text>An employee shall not be included for purposes of this section for any period with respect to any employer if such employer is allowed a credit under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/51">section 51</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 with respect to such employee for such period.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB7CAD4BE1BF241DBB5551B34A2DF32CD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Denial of double benefit</header><text>Any wages taken into account in determining the credit allowed under this section shall not be taken into account for purposes of determining the credit allowed under section 41, 45A, 45P, 45S, or 1396.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H36D292424FE64331AE26FA8D64D8EB22"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Third-party payors</header><text>Any credit allowed under this section shall be treated as a credit described in section 3511(d)(2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H91928E466E47484FA68B9BE45C3C88A2" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Treatment of deposits</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall waive any penalty under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6656">section 6656</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 for any failure to make a deposit of any applicable employment taxes if the Secretary determines that such failure was due to the reasonable anticipation of the credit allowed under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD057A2315B5747F69F4BE36B45B40D27"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Extension of limitation on assessment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 6501, the limitation on the time period for the assessment of any amount attributable to a credit claimed under this section shall not expire before the date that is 5 years after the later of— </text><subparagraph id="HE698EBDC48524F34AC58C2D2F648D203"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the date on which the original return which includes the calendar quarter with respect to which such credit is determined is filed, or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0728FA8D79C34D2689A4CC0B62B07AA6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the date on which such return is treated as filed under section 6501(b)(2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6A3FDB9A8609435F8403289BFA74128A"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Regulations and guidance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall issue such forms, instructions, regulations, and guidance as are necessary—</text><paragraph id="H5133799C299D43679DCBE9697DA69D85"><enum>(1)</enum><text>with respect to the application of the credit under subsection (a) to third-party payors (including professional employer organizations, certified professional employer organizations, or agents under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/3504">section 3504</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986), including regulations or guidance allowing such payors to submit documentation necessary to substantiate the eligible employer status of employers that use such payors, and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H574B4A01672F4E6B88FD82D18E78364D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to prevent the avoidance of the purposes of the limitations under this section, including through the leaseback of employees.</text></paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">Any forms, instructions, regulations, or other guidance described in paragraph (2) shall require the customer to be responsible for the accounting of the credit and for any liability for improperly claimed credits and shall require the certified professional employer organization or other third party payor to accurately report such tax credits based on the information provided by the customer.</continuation-text></subsection><subsection id="H85FFD8CD4C4248AD9D75BE1159CA2705"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section shall not apply to any calendar quarter beginning more than 5 years after the date of the enactment of this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HC01D1D7DF623449B8DE7D5080704EB29"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><paragraph id="H317799A0500644B69D5236C376AC157F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1324(b)(2) of title 31, United States Code, is amended by inserting <quote>3135,</quote> after <quote>3134,</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H75941D45821C4858AAFA261431645A0A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections for subchapter D of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/21">chapter 21</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H7DC93736444643D98B1659A0CE9D4548" display-inline="no-display-inline"><toc container-level="quoted-block-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" idref="H1DC7151739644DB3953CBAF7034FA53B" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"><toc-entry idref="H0515866141D144AB9CE664A90A0CBFA6" level="section">Sec. 3135. Local news journalist compensation credit.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H44AF415E2E0B45169F489EF8B6580B43"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to calendar quarters beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

