<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-AEG25181-S9G-LX-99F"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1078 IS: Mississippi River Basin Fishery Commission Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1078</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250314">March 14, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S318">Mr. Wicker</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S354">Ms. Baldwin</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S343">Mr. Boozman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEV00">Committee on Environment and Public Works</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To establish the Mississippi River Basin Fishery Commission, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4032cf66a9794b3d862464f86b8d72c7"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Mississippi River Basin Fishery Commission Act</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="idfb53b44d3a284eaa82a372fce6662600"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows: </text><toc><toc-entry level="section" idref="S1">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id3ce927f5c45d4db5868c0c7f74d79c37">Sec. 2. Findings.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="ida355662bcf21464ba4d15bf90c64f21e">Sec. 3. Definitions.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="ide3849bfa91474918a7fe71dbd717b644">Sec. 4. Establishment of Mississippi River Basin Fishery Commission.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idab84449e0cf84557956c3b7e81fb7b37">Sec. 5. Commission governance.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id4b6767051b01416a8f4c2b1b0d95b2ef">Sec. 6. Commission management duties.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idf55519c8e03246c18a076d218ec8ebb7">Sec. 7. Commission grant program.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idf2607d4987f4435e83cd27aa55ff9f77">Sec. 8. Nonbinding authority.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id57d2a0faef78485f9a0dafe3d4c2bec1">Sec. 9. Withdrawal from the Commission.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id236e7efd5560416085316f58610591fc">Sec. 10. Report to Congress.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id8f42d8ae4f8e4b16b9cca4f2e99d15e0">Sec. 11. Appropriations.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section><section id="id3ce927f5c45d4db5868c0c7f74d79c37"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="id6329469cb2d34eada6f1b0b7868e1b1f"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Management of the inland fishery resources of the Mississippi River Basin are shared by 31 States, multiple Federal agencies, and 2 Canadian provinces.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id91a56e49982b47d5bc7d8f318a7b1f40"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Mississippi River Basin is the fourth largest watershed in the world, and the largest watershed in the Nation, draining all or part of 31 States and 2 Canadian provinces. The watershed measures approximately 1,200,000 square miles, and covers 41 percent of the continental United States. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id224f306778be4e7ab783a140f5e80224"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Mississippi River and its tributaries comprise 1 of the largest and most valuable ecosystems in the world.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id139c85d3da07495ebbd439a67d73cfb9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Mississippi River Basin supports economically and culturally significant subsistence, commercial, and recreational fisheries.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idffbea3ba1e734cfe9ec00e387dea9b0b"><enum>(5)</enum><text>States within the Mississippi River Basin have formed multiple regional interstate partnerships, and 1 basin-wide partnership, to promote cooperation and communication among the conservation agencies to manage the interjurisdictional fishery resources of the basin. Twenty-eight Mississippi River Basin State fishery agencies, the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, the Bureau of Reclamation, the United States Geological Survey, the Tennessee Valley Authority, the Chippewa-Cree Tribe, and the Chickasaw Nation ratified the Mississippi Interstate Cooperative Resource Agreement in 1990 and formed the Mississippi Interstate Cooperative Resource Association (MICRA) in 1991 to improve the management of interjurisdictional fishery resources in the basin.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3cc4a12aeb3c4a00800fad20ce60b221"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Recognizing the economic, ecologic, and cultural value of the diverse interjurisdictional fishery resources in the Mississippi River Basin and the complexity and severity of issues facing resource management agencies, Congress acknowledges the need for the establishment of a Mississippi River Basin Fishery Commission for basin-wide, inter-agency collaboration in the establishment of shared management objectives, and the collaborative planning, implementation, and evaluation of management actions to provide for the long-term biologic and economic sustainability of interjurisdictional fishery resources in the basin. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id125296d39b1a4ccfa3ee3f361a09d8cf"><enum>(7)</enum><text>As long-term sustainability of interjurisdictional fishery resources is dependent on the control of aquatic invasive species within the Mississippi River Basin, it is the further purpose of this Commission to provide for coordinated, inter-agency, basin-wide management, control, and removal of invasive carps and other prioritized aquatic invasive species within the basin. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id671c30a76b4c47f8bb866633e37359fb"><enum>(8)</enum><text>By consent of Congress, and as directed by Federal law under the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1801">16 U.S.C. 1801 et seq.</external-xref>) and the Interjurisdictional Fisheries Act of 1986 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/4101">16 U.S.C. 4101 et seq.</external-xref>), sustainable fisheries within the United States coastal waters of the Pacific, Atlantic, and Caribbean Oceans, and the Gulf of Mexico, have been managed by multi-state commissions and fishery councils for many decades.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3dfabf3c4cde4189bc6f984169499d55"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The interjurisdictional and international fishery resources of the Great Lakes are cooperatively managed by the Great Lakes Fishery Commission, operating through the 1954 Convention on Great Lake Fisheries. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9a9207b0abd944eb9f2c737a0f2fadc2"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The Mississippi River Basin Fishery Commission will improve the management and utilization of sustainable interjurisdictional fisheries resources in the Mississippi River Basin through the development of a multi-agency program for the joint management and protection of such fisheries.</text></paragraph></section><section id="ida355662bcf21464ba4d15bf90c64f21e"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="ideb674cf4484e4f9db001964c0cc0a2b8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Aquatic invasive species</header><text>The term <term>aquatic invasive species</term> means a nonindigenous species that threatens the diversity or abundance of native species in, or the ecological stability of, infested waters, or commercial, agricultural, aquacultural, or recreational activities dependent on such waters.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4c349044ee734649a9a46ed1c44d3630"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Mississippi River Basin Fishery Commission established under section 4. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="ideaa6eae522bd41cb8d865e4a8b88693e"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Director of fisheries</header><text>The term <term>director of fisheries</term> means the individual in a State who is the highest designated officer in charge of fisheries management employed by the State, regardless of the formal title of such individual.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idff0a616b25a74894924acb09a5a7896d"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> includes—</text><subparagraph id="idd2be2fce4c5848ffb2dbb32d60dca465"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any political subdivision, agency, or department of a Mississippi River Basin State that regulates Mississippi River Basin fisheries; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id365e6c9431444d11bca723c88e3bac0d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an Indian Tribe (as defined in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>)) or an entity controlled by an Indian Tribe that manages Mississippi River Basin fisheries; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb40a91c68cbb400087ec3ff61742a725"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the United States Geological Survey;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id75afa06dbb7a4a1884f56c4bfaa50c21"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the United States Fish and Wildlife Service:</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9126c66eafd8453bb5f14c30c8f213c7"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the United States Army Corps of Engineers;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc16a3dac3ffd4a1894206d46d219694e"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the Engineer Research and Development Center of the United States Army Corps of Engineers; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd94f4c12dde743c8abeba2c0d3a96b9c"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the Tennessee Valley Authority. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id87a1caf2058b44b4bf2f4987102c6cdc"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Fishery resource</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>fishery resource</term> means finfish, mollusks, crustaceans, and any other form of animal or plant life, other than mammals or birds. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="idff46cd71f9b448cc8eb6c454b3a26ebb"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Interjurisdictional fishery resource</header><text>The term <term>interjurisdictional fishery resource</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="idcf94a79b40c641aca71e422f4281b173"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a fishery resource located in a fishery in waters under the jurisdiction of 2 or more Mississippi River Basin States; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id589fa88ad14b43efbdd445e3fe89c252"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a fishery resource for which there exists an interstate fishery management plan; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6350f94b3b644939a7dd4fb1b8dbb72a"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a fishery resource that migrates between the waters under the jurisdiction of 2 or more Mississippi River Basin States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idcb184a7f4da94fe0a3ce84d7da291a22"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Invasive carp</header><text>The term <term>invasive carp</term> means an aquatic invasive species of finfish that—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0a02dfccec1246c094d8114b3b11caca"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">originated in Europe and Asia;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0977a7ed62f047a1a1727dce4ed56335"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">spread quickly once they are established in a body of water or waterway; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id12a1bee601a744cf9dd6584c93b4725b"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">cause serious damage to the native fish populations, as well as economic and physical harm to humans; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5f644bc4c0f74098899c8ed1e258cea1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>include the bighead carp, black carp, grass carp, and silver carp. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idd8ea99a1984145338340992d63c9795e"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Member entity</header><text>The term <term>member entity</term> means an eligible entity that maintains an active membership in the Commission. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id649a69fb01d44cbfb6e018c6fdad8813"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Mississippi River Basin State</header><text>The term <term>Mississippi River Basin State</term> means a State whose borders include waters that drain into the Mississippi River Basin, including Alabama, Arkansas, Colorado, Georgia, Illinois, Indiana, Iowa, Kansas, Kentucky, Louisiana, Maryland, Michigan, Minnesota, Mississippi, Missouri, Montana, Nebraska, New Mexico, New York, North Carolina, North Dakota, Ohio, Oklahoma, Pennsylvania, South Dakota, Tennessee, Texas, Virginia, West Virginia, Wisconsin, and Wyoming. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6d769e0270c1489fae3b1d6672d4b838"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text></paragraph></section><section id="ide3849bfa91474918a7fe71dbd717b644"><enum>4.</enum><header>Establishment of Mississippi River Basin Fishery Commission</header><subsection id="id2eb70fbbf5f34022801921749f2ba264"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is established in the Department of the Interior the Mississippi River Basin Fishery Commission. </text></subsection><subsection id="id5ff0d03e8507425abc127f5da0ec4c76"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Members of the Commission</header><text>Any eligible entity may join the Commission by notifying the executive director and existing members of the Commission in writing of its intent to join the Commission. </text></subsection></section><section id="idab84449e0cf84557956c3b7e81fb7b37"><enum>5.</enum><header>Commission governance</header><subsection id="id751b8416274946028d1b40d3ab5a13c8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Voting delegates</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id385f1dd88ffa43d6b2336f419aeef5fe"><enum>(1)</enum><header>States</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to each eligible entity described in section 3(4)(A) that joins the Commission, the director of fisheries of such eligible entity shall serve as the voting delegate to represent such entity's interests on the Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id184f0c4d0a524a25b69174ec4d7a93b3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federal agencies and indian tribes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to each eligible entity described in any of subparagraphs (B) through (G) of section 3(4) that joins the Commission, such entity shall appoint 1 individual to serve as the voting delegate to represent such entity's interests on the Commission.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id916e1dba01474fc59a0b5bece4dbf3fd"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Body corporate</header><text>The Commission shall be a body corporate with the powers and duties described in this Act. The member entities shall establish a governance structure for the Commission. </text></subsection><subsection id="id3882a4f092a346d58e13a853f3611a30"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Executive director and staff</header><text>The Commission shall—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddeefa95c70f24aefbf7ab720cee12cc5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">appoint a full-time executive director and staff as needed to carry out the administrative duties of the Commission, who shall—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide8894ed09c0b48a0802456c6f30f4ebf"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide advice to, and carry out operational duties of, the Commission; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida0fe2024858b44ba88a41ff4f34a6ff9"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have no voting rights on the Commission; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2fc1599db238472b875ad78a579f2bea"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">at its pleasure, appoint, remove, or discharge such executive director and staff, as may be needed, and fix and determine their duties, qualifications, and compensation. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id64af0e2664f841259044293bd8c4deea"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Chair and vice chair</header><text>The Commission shall elect a Chair and a Vice Chair of the Commission from the member entities. </text></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="id11a99076abfa406f805b9fa1f82368fa"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Rules and regulations</header><text>The Commission shall adopt rules and regulations for the conduct of its business.</text></subsection><subsection id="idcf1358bf78354cbab785b130bbe5c545"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Offices and meetings</header><text>The Commission—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb89b28252c8d49658690ffa118f7fe7e"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may establish and maintain 1 or more offices for the transaction of its business, which shall be located within the Mississippi River Basin; and </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida6a1c25c5cbd4b698538f5ac5cbcb40b"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may meet at any time or place but not less often than annually. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id7f632776963e427283f196db15f0c9d4"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Decision making</header><text>The Commission may make a recommendation or take an action regarding its general affairs only by an affirmative vote of a majority of the member entities. The Commission shall strive for unanimity in its decisions but shall operate by consensus in its decision making.</text></subsection><subsection id="id0a83c8fd620f48358c9cde726423afb4"><enum>(h)</enum><header>FACA not To apply</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/10">Chapter 10</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, shall not apply to the Commission. </text></subsection></section><section id="id4b6767051b01416a8f4c2b1b0d95b2ef"><enum>6.</enum><header>Commission management duties</header><subsection id="id59a6ff088e8d428d9d48768aae5b1dfa"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Overseeing sub-Basin fishery management</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2fcb148824354016923f3326fff312f3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall oversee the management plans and the implementation and evaluation of the effectiveness of management actions of the 6 Mississippi River sub-basins described in paragraph (2) to provide for the long-term biologic and economic sustainability of interjurisdictional fisheries in the Mississippi River Basin. </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id580d38471d18448cb4afaaeb77d1eaf2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sub-basins</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The 6 Mississippi River sub-basins are the Arkansas-Red-White, the Lower Mississippi, the Missouri, the Ohio, the Tennessee-Cumberland, and the Upper Mississippi.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4d4a7ef16dd24d3f80a9faaafb14b411"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Commission management plan</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id10cedc4d44c341189d38f91080184168"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>As the framework for a management plan for the Commission, the Commission shall adopt and use the MICRA Joint Strategic Plan for Management of Mississippi River Fisheries, which—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida058946f304b4091840002c558326464"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">was adopted and approved by 28 States in the Mississippi River Basin; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbbe9d3d4979f46e7b2659882ccac4563"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establishes a formal commitment to a set of strategic procedures for a coordinated, inter-agency approach to cooperatively managing self-sustaining interjurisdictional fishery resources in the Mississippi River Basin.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idfb416e866df249d2b1dc7ee9275f9a2b"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Best methods, practices, and conditions</header><text>The Commission shall work to research and implement the best scientific methods, best practices, and best conditions to bring about the conservation and sustainable management of interjurisdictional fisheries in the Mississippi River Basin. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf219124934354b01b95efe827af82576"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Strategies to control invasive species</header><text>The Commission shall—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0c738c7df4d94dd08be10bbaf24d5497"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop and coordinate inter-agency and inter-basin strategies to prevent the introduction and control the abundance and spread of invasive carps and other prioritized aquatic invasive species within the Mississippi River Basin; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4cbf16c57b1343ddb56fdbc2c7498229"><enum>(B)</enum><text>draft and recommend to the appropriate management agencies strategies and approaches for dealing with the conservation of interjurisdictional fisheries and the management and control of aquatic invasive species within the Mississippi River Basin.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id7da7cfbb4faa4dd38fec567d6f38904b"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Consultation and advice</header><text>The Commission shall consult with and advise the pertinent administrative agencies party to the Commission regarding problems connected with the fisheries in the Mississippi River Basin and recommend the adoption of such regulations as it determines advisable.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id82d4d38838b9447292a7dac00487a889"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Reexamination and evaluation of joint strategic plan</header><text>Not later than 30 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Commission, in consultation with the Secretary, shall—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide9f35f118c9648ee83dd6554ce48d49f"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reexamine and evaluate the Joint Strategic Plan described in paragraph (1) to—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id821a6269ac464911a4cccfcc78fcf73e"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">determine which portions of the Plan have been completed and which need updating; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddf344683c1f94983b6cea2f3018033b3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">add new objectives, if any, to the Plan; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3375635805b141dab097966d52c71495"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">issue a report to Congress on the status of interjurisdictional fishery populations and the state of the ongoing work to eradicate, manage, and control aquatic invasive species in the Mississippi River Basin in accordance with the management plan of the Commission. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idf55519c8e03246c18a076d218ec8ebb7"><enum>7.</enum><header>Commission grant program</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id386b2d19cc9b456199d0feb16193e7d9"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Establishment of grant program</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Commission, in consultation with the Secretary, shall establish—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide47fb7dcdb4645f388794f965dfc9abb"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a competitive grant program to award grants to entities to carry out an eligible project; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide909064a16f54226a4c134ebd4d26565"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a formula grant program to award grants to State member entities to carry out eligible interjurisdictional fisheries projects carried out in accordance with the recommendation of the Commission or the Joint Strategic Plan described in section 6(b)(1). </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="idf3648448d2b749f4b2d7e03cff5f058c"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Entities eligible To receive grants</header><text>The Commission may provide—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id16f1f753b4314a898698f384bf68c15e"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">formula grants and competitive grants to State member entities; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4ba6fe6b999f41edb7a60c0f845a8dbd"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">competitive grants to private entities, Federal agencies, nongovernmental organizations, public and private institutions of higher education, and partnerships between entities described in this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id6f8ba9e32ea64ed0b33ccea1490412f5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Competitive grants</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id644f855b449a4f61b89448be227ea312"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Applications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An entity desiring a competitive grant under this section shall submit to the Commission an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Commission may require. </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id9c91634ea60848848a195e1699654b3a"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Priority for entities providing matching funds</header><text>In awarding competitive grants under this section, the Commission shall give priority to entities that will provide matching funds from non-Federal sources of not less than 10 percent of the grant award, which may be provided in cash or in-kind. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id729f2a5253a94b108b3d10fe1e746ef5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Formula grant program</header><text>The Commission shall determine the amount that each State member entity shall receive annually under the formula grant program. </text></subsection><subsection id="id748f88f0254d46509c2bb10c0ef5c678"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>An entity that receives a grant under this section shall use the grant funds—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb4ef3a2e8a3f4d97be444f04c53af5fa"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd6b84ee39b5d498c9672d3ab8fe2ff05"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a competitive grant, in accordance with the goals and objectives of the Joint Strategic Plan described in section 6(b)(1) and each of the interjurisdictional fisheries management plans of the 6 Mississippi River sub-basins described in section 6(a)(2); and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id20edc4ad193d41cc962c05e0db7b9b21"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a formula grant, to carry out eligible interjurisdictional fisheries projects carried out in accordance with the recommendation of the Commission or the Joint Strategic Plan described in section 6(b)(1); and </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id02a1706802a34ef29d96620b9a775dc5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>only for projects, research, personnel, work, and programs located wholly or partially in a Mississippi River Basin State. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="id15bd54f0261f415f92bf72bcd7300cb3"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Administrative costs</header><text>An entity awarded a grant under this section may use not more than 5 percent of the grant funds for administrative costs relating to the grant.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="idbbe14aac276948af844204b8cbc509db"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Report requirements</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the disbursement of grant funding under this section, the Chair of the Commission shall submit to Congress a report on—</text><paragraph commented="no" id="id1102a44ea95b4e52a3993086fdc8da36"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the entities awarded grants under this section;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="ida294c88db8f542679606dc3ce303a1ad"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the amount each such grant;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id7e6a4b7f5fd547b9b6d2489da630e5c3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>how such entities used the grant awards; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id51c8e2f10ceb423ab950ba79554af708"><enum>(4)</enum><text>how such grant awards enhanced the management and sustainability of the interjurisdictional fisheries of the Mississippi River Basin.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idf2607d4987f4435e83cd27aa55ff9f77"><enum>8.</enum><header>Nonbinding authority</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc5f153d80fe248e7ae80042cde7f1f68"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The authority of the Commission shall be nonbinding.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcb22c68964a442638b4fe9db249c6e78"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9be3a0180628456dabb02ed02087bff9"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to limit the powers of any member entity that is a State to repeal or enact State laws; </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfc6bf0ab81674de89677d5827b2cc073"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to limit the enforcement of any requirement by any member entity that is a State imposing additional conditions and restrictions to conserve its fisheries within the borders of the State; or</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id94f6be40152a4e418041f404b79b2591"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to impede, supersede, or alter the authority of the Great Lakes Fishery Commission, States, or Indian tribes under the Convention on Great Lakes Fisheries between the United States of America and Canada signed at Washington, September 10, 1954 or the Joint Strategic Plan for Management of Great Lakes Fisheries. </text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id57d2a0faef78485f9a0dafe3d4c2bec1"><enum>9.</enum><header>Withdrawal from the Commission</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">A member entity that intends to withdraw from the Commission shall submit a notice of intent to withdraw in writing not later than 6 months before the date of the withdrawal to—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id08a2fd2e21fc48cabcfdbb5223e23c6d"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Commission; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0daab23f215b4ffb9ebb9c6b1efb392c"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">each of the other member entities of the Commission. </text></paragraph></section><section id="id236e7efd5560416085316f58610591fc"><enum>10.</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than September 1 of each year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Commission shall submit a report to Congress which shall set forth the activities of the Commission during the previous year. </text></section><section id="id8f42d8ae4f8e4b16b9cca4f2e99d15e0"><enum>11.</enum><header>Appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated—</text><paragraph id="idfc5cc3c0c630406081b3b2b7778e094d"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$1,000,000 for fiscal year 2026 to carry out the initial administrative steps necessary to set up operations, house, and administer the Commission; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8c8b8eef2941487b80872badd0c4ba41"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to carry out sections 6 and 7—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0574adb67d7b46f5b02d6881b820f745"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$30,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2031, to remain available until expended; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idea00ca5b41144b45bdd260fcc0d1e80e"><enum>(B)</enum><text>$50,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2032 through 2036, to remain available until expended; and </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id6acc95ada41540139b6e8241b2b9718f"><enum>(3)</enum><text>$500,000 for each of fiscal years 2025 through 2035 to the Secretary of the Interior for housing the Commission, to remain available until expended. </text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

