<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H233C11F2E0FD4185BA92B7B50231FD7A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2622 IH: Russia-North Korea Cooperation Sanctions Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2622</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250403">April 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="W000795">Mr. Wilson of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001127">Mrs. Cherfilus-McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000463">Mr. Turner of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001156">Ms. Sánchez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000380">Mr. Amo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000600">Mrs. Radewagen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for the imposition of sanctions with respect to North Korea’s support for Russia’s illegal war in Ukraine.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE50EA39290DC49C9BDB6A3B4C54D59B9" style="OLC"><section id="H4BB8173E75AB415FAD67355F4FF6FE68" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Russia-North Korea Cooperation Sanctions Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H988E030592724A74A7B0C2D3C371A36F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings: </text><paragraph id="H59C6675C8C0F4E2ABB03DDAE6B2E8499"><enum>(1)</enum><text>On February 24, 2022, the Government of the Russian Federation, led by Vladimir Putin, launched an unprovoked, full-scale invasion of Ukraine.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF567D261452242FD8527F2A807484410"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On September 13, 2023, the Supreme Leader of the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea (North Korea), Kim Jong Un, met with Russian Federation President Vladimir Putin to discuss the transfer or sale of conventional arms to Russia to be used in invasion of Ukraine’s sovereign territory in exchange for economic assistance and support for North Korea’s space, nuclear, and missile programs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H03849E91682E48FCA83C79D495EEFCCC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Kim Jong Un’s trip to Russia will be his first known travel outside North Korea since the COVID–19 pandemic and subsequent lockdown of North Korea in early 2020.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE04EA6CC976A4B32B6DE68FE8F1D0300"><enum>(4)</enum><text>North Korea maintains an arsenal of artillery shells, rockets, and other conventional military equipment that it may provide to Russia.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA37D021E0C7A4EA2BEA047971700C967"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If Russia or Russian State-backed entities are acquiring arms and related materiel from North Korea, such actions would violate United Nations Security Council resolutions, which were supported by Russia to prohibit North Korea from exporting such items.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H71623FC9397F4715880CF80F54191892"><enum>(6)</enum><text>On August 16, 2023, the Department of the Treasury imposed sanctions on three entities tied to a sanctions evasion network attempting to support arms deals between Russia and North Korea. </text></paragraph></section><section id="H9FA6B8D7035D428FAA2C7F3EBC22790F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sanctions</header><subsection id="H1BE922DF6A4F479CB00361CDC302B499"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall impose sanctions described in subsection (b) with respect to the following:</text><paragraph id="HB2D2B179B5144D94B193E13DE11DA387"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Any foreign person that is responsible for or facilitates the transfer or sale of arms or material support from North Korea to be used in Russia’s illegal war in Ukraine. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H302D97A646874F2F879F94D121C67652"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any foreign person that knowingly, directly or indirectly, imports, exports, or reexports to, into, or from North Korea any goods services or technology for weapons that may be used by Russian forces or their proxies in Russia’s illegal war in Ukraine. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF6D4E2D75D10470DA6DA4EA09B78A75A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Any foreign financial institution that knowingly facilitates a significant transaction or provides significant financial services for a foreign person described in paragraph (1) or (2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H10AE9D2E27294F5A8A10B33776CD8D3E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Any foreign person that engages in a significant transaction related to the transfer or sale of arms or material support with a foreign person described in paragraph (1) or (2) or foreign financial institution described in paragraph (3).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7B03B520599B43FD9F52D2D125A2B89E"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any foreign person assisting in the logistical supply and movement of North Korean arms or material support to be used in Russia’s illegal war in Ukraine. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H698E0A4AEB874D49A38AFBE9EECA1677"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sanctions described</header><text>The sanctions described in this subsection are the following:</text><paragraph id="HDAFB2BF06D394622AF6ABF0E9C67CA64"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Blocking of property</header><text>Notwithstanding the requirements of section 202 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref>), the President may exercise of all powers granted to the President by that Act to the extent necessary to block and prohibit all transactions in all property and interests in property of the foreign person if such property and interests in property are in the United States, come within the United States, or are or come within the possession or control of a United States person.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H847D078BB3044194910B7498D9B4905E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Visas, admission, or parole</header><subparagraph id="H8AA711BE73D34431861F362190CA93E1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An alien who the Secretary of State or the Secretary of Homeland Security (or a designee of one of such Secretaries) knows, or has reason to believe, is described in subsection (a) is—</text><clause id="HFFD72FB176614AC1B953E158A4FC8FF5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>inadmissible to the United States;</text></clause><clause id="HD8AE51CD575F475CB844DD250976C29C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>ineligible for a visa or other documentation to enter the United States; and</text></clause><clause id="H50370AEEC7DB4F76B0EBBAE9C878091C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>otherwise ineligible to be admitted or paroled into the United States or to receive any other benefit under the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H45CAB80FB4904C87BA2A56B3F2EA6F85"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Current visas revoked</header><clause id="HC4B30494E2094EA4BB051FB897753694"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The issuing consular officer, the Secretary of State, or the Secretary of Homeland Security (or a designee of one of such Secretaries) shall, in accordance with section 221(i) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1201">8 U.S.C. 1201(i)</external-xref>), revoke any visa or other entry documentation issued to an alien described in subparagraph (A) regardless of when the visa or other entry documentation is issued.</text></clause><clause id="H0F01CF8307D64D0F813B70E89608889A"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Effect of revocation</header><text>A revocation under clause (i)—</text><subclause id="HD7733703A68A4EC9A5148FE9732023DE"><enum>(I)</enum><text>shall take effect immediately; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HD3704E1E7C7145DCAD7E6EDDE518CE0A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>shall automatically cancel any other valid visa or entry documentation that is in the alien’s possession.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCE5F911A7CCF4FB994F8F41E56E5A0ED"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Implementation; penalties</header><paragraph id="HADF7A3591692451FB75A7659045C2BFA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>The President may exercise all authorities provided to the President under sections 203 and 205 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1702 and 1704) to carry out this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1BD7F7E9EB534220AE4EAECA28119DFC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text>The penalties provided for in subsections (b) and (c) of section 206 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1705">50 U.S.C. 1705</external-xref>) shall apply to a person that violates, attempts to violate, conspires to violate, or causes a violation of regulations promulgated to carry out this section to the same extent that such penalties apply to a person that commits an unlawful act described in section 206(a) of that Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFF9607C0CF7E41B6A2A271C0EC535165"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>The President may waive the application of sanctions imposed with respect to a foreign person or foreign financial institution under this section if the President certifies to the appropriate congressional committees not later than 15 days before such waiver is to take effect that the waiver is vital to the national security interests of the United States.</text></subsection><subsection id="HFEE64D881EA744C2A03F520C0E24BA69"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Exception for humanitarian assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An internationally recognized humanitarian organization shall not be subject to sanctions under this section with respect to—</text><paragraph id="H328E7074AD9D4470A1571CF502759E7B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>engaging in a financial transaction relating to humanitarian assistance or for humanitarian purposes pursuant to a waiver issued under subsection (d);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H19099A51BF8C40CBAEBADDE5FD699834"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">transporting goods or services that are necessary to carry out operations relating to humanitarian assistance or humanitarian purposes pursuant to such a waiver issued under subsection (d); or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0AB0E00828454D2587AFDCE6BC0C4C2F"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">having merely incidental contact, in the course of providing humanitarian assistance or aid for humanitarian purposes pursuant to a waiver issued under subsection (d) with individuals who are under the control of a foreign person subject to sanctions under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HE0A856034C4B400C8C0983622D18A909"><enum>4.</enum><header>Expansion of North Korea Sanctions and Policy Enhancement Act of 2016</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The North Korea Sanctions and Policy Enhancement Act of 2016 is amended as follows:</text><paragraph id="H9B1A36C4AF2641029EA788011F91ED78"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In section 401(a) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/9251">22 U.S.C. 9251(a)</external-xref>)—</text><subparagraph id="H886EE6ABCA5F4BE2843541779E775665"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (5), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H164CC90FD7BB48929AC5667EA5042799"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (6), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H34BACFD2E37E4032B5323315F6654FA5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HDA238741EF4C446CB64E024BEBB0ED3A" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="HD56385A2EBC843EE9C4E972538970E6E"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">halting material support (as such term is defined in section 6 of the Russia-North Korea Cooperation Sanctions Act) for Russia’s illegal war in Ukraine.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8AA1A87F97A44B51AED6009ADB9160D7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In section 402(2) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/9252">22 U.S.C. 9252(2)</external-xref>)—</text><subparagraph id="HDF856E7B2979482DA0BC272AEDDCAA22"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HED5C7E40DAA54C59A51E7BC6A0E509E7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (E)(ii), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H335AFA7DD1734A468F06853D307DC2CD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H94FEC853F4AA44A69A0DE13CF8A7862C" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="H37B51E31D87B4DFB821066F7BC03CE01"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">halting material support (as such term is defined in section 6 of the Russia-North Korea Cooperation Sanctions Act) for Russia’s illegal war in Ukraine.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="HFC00C33328A649159B854AA6EC55F0DF"><enum>5.</enum><header>Report</header><subsection id="H8D0D7389EC7E46FBAD4D1E6D9AFFC599"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and every 180 days thereafter, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that describes significant activities by the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea to support the Russian Federation and its proxies in Russia’s illegal war in Ukraine. </text></subsection><subsection id="H95C4458F39B944A79C588F483AD61A3A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Matters To be included</header><text>The report required by this section shall include the following:</text><paragraph id="H9AFB6ED36CEC485CA702F260F40A7BD1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The identity and nationality of foreign persons and foreign financial institutions that are subject to sanctions under section 3. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC5D2A14A08F14A87B13375F3DAE48B31"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A description of the conduct engaged in by such persons and institutions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H43075877B3184C8B837E3E7501D4A46F"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of the extent to which a foreign government has provided material support to the Government of North Korea or any person acting for or on behalf of that Government to conduct significant activities to materially support Russia’s illegal war in Ukraine.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H57AB9832E6D14884B5AE389D5AAD268F"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A United States strategy to counter North Korea’s efforts to conduct significant activities to support Russia’s war in Ukraine, that includes efforts to engage foreign governments to halt the capability of the Government of North Korea and persons acting for or on behalf of that Government to conduct significant activities supporting Russia’s illegal war in Ukraine.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBFA488B4852E467F875A63814E6409DE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required by this section shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</text></subsection></section><section id="H3C0C0F2B57744726A465456655B98728"><enum>6.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H4E649B3C6BF64841AD13799F573A460D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDBFFBD007EEB4448BB31AF0DF51EBEA1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Foreign financial institution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>foreign financial institution</term>—</text><subparagraph id="H80A72FBA833846A6A7F1E71BA5B9A518"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has the meaning given that term in section 1010.605 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB7C52E5A0BB34BEEB82EF82EEC5D67E5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes a foreign central bank.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB385B6AB0B9A480796DA4816AF0D0357"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Material support</header><text>The term “material support” has the meaning given the term <term>material support or resources</term> in section 2339A of title 18, United States Code.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

