<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H68BA27DED47C49E995BD6005D9449429" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2342 IH: State-Managed Disaster Relief Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2342</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250325">March 25, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000603">Mr. Rouzer</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish alternate procedures for lump sum payments for certain covered small disasters, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE28184658D164A53A9D624BB5B071A0A" style="OLC"><section id="H48D9A5C8B2E14721A98B928C57E71773" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>State-Managed Disaster Relief Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HBFB0BF661CE84678BF5D72347EFD00C5" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Alternative procedures for covered small disasters</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5121">42 U.S.C. 5121 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H6147AB4148704BD0B568B8A56F0900AC" display-inline="no-display-inline"><title id="H2DDDD250DEFD4210B4C2DFF4C2402D9A"><enum>VIII</enum><header>Alternative Procedures for Covered Small Disasters</header><section id="H741602A3012E462D9E68A61999DBC365"><enum>801.</enum><header>Alternative procedures for covered small disasters</header><subsection id="H6CEF7B4F10934B689EABEFD21B23110E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Governor of a State or the governing body of an Indian tribal government for the area in which a covered small disaster occurs may request a lump sum payment of the estimated damages calculated under subsection (b) for such disaster in lieu of any assistance under the Public Assistance Program for such disaster.</text></subsection><subsection id="H14581155F2D44209B4E7CCB35B0FED0E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Calculation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding the requirements of section 206.47(b) of title 44, Code of Federal Regulations, a payment under subsection (a) shall be equal to the amount that is 80 percent of the total estimated cost of assistance under the Public Assistance Program for a covered small disaster in the area of jurisdiction of the State or Indian tribal government requesting such payment. </text></subsection><subsection id="H062C9EAC006C450DAAEAE923D8DBFAFF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Limitations</header><paragraph id="HF0ECFC1C1AC942D59926256A813565B1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State or Indian tribal government receiving a payment under this section may not receive assistance under the Public Assistance Program with respect to the covered small disaster for which a payment was accepted under this section. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB383EB7329394060BA521FB6BDF74F1A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Final payment</header><subparagraph id="H41D6DDE00EF24521BB5A6CDED1E6A7A8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A payment under this section may not be increased or decreased based on actual costs calculated for a covered small disaster.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H618E52F96B34461BB987DF87B3FD0640"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Notwithstanding subparagraph (A), the Administrator may adjust a payment under this section in the event of unforeseen circumstances at no fault of the applicant. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE2A901B71A2F4EBDAB942001F0AC778F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Selection of option</header><text>A State or Indian tribal government may designate to the Federal Emergency Management Agency on an annual basis the interest of such State or Indian tribal government in participating in the small disaster authority.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2DBAB511584842B9848A434F12ABE14A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Indication</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State or Indian tribal government shall indicate at the time of the submission of a request for a major disaster declaration that such State or Indian tribal government is requesting assistance for such incident under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0E47826A9AA64D46845975D1020DB305"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Timing requirement</header><text>The Administrator and the State or Indian tribal government shall—</text><subparagraph id="HE04F7232E1C646429A270DDD3EA47527"><enum>(A)</enum><text>reach an agreement on the amount under subsection (b) not later than 90 days after the incident; or </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5E0063D6C7FE45B18F8F8582C365E041"><enum>(B)</enum><text>administer the incident under the procedures and authorities for the Public Assistance Program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H984278E0CF2E41BB9FB1311A0F7235EA"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Administrative plan</header><text>To be eligible for assistance under this section, a State or Indian tribal government shall have an approved administrative plan in place at the time of the obligation of funds provided under this section. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6C7CDB3E268C48AE8EF5B4DA17CED203"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State or Indian tribal government receiving a payment under this section may use such payment for recovery for the covered small disaster in any manner determined appropriate by the respective Governor or governing body of such State or Indian tribal government if such funds—</text><paragraph id="HD6CE207D21AF4F318C8D4AC5B3B560E6"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">address impacts and needs resulting from the declared disaster incident; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE51DD7EC269F4D2DB88ABCC4C4D47427"><enum>(2)</enum><text>are provided to State, Indian tribal government, territorial and local government agencies, and private non-profit entities eligible for Public Assistance Program funding; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE475FAAC7B36486A89F7219A3E3848C2"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are used in a manner that complies with applicable environmental, historic preservation, and civil rights laws (including the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>) and the National Historic Preservation Act of 1966 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/54/300101">54 U.S.C. 300101 et seq.</external-xref>)) and any applicable resiliency standards under section 203. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5261E139866A42E7A76269D3A54BA472"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Compliance with other laws and regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State or Indian tribal government shall be responsible for ensuring compliance under subsection (d)(3).</text></subsection><subsection id="HAC31BA3816794D3AA09032533BE8C135"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to affect the eligibility of a State or Indian tribal government for assistance under section 404. </text></subsection><subsection id="HE1457A79103545E59B70134D9B099892"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Report to FEMA</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State or governing body of an Indian tribal government shall submit to the Federal Emergency Management Agency an annual report of expenses for a covered small disaster in the area of jurisdiction of the respective State or Indian tribal government. </text></subsection><subsection id="H8B73BC47A5104899A612C00C9E5B4811"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Savings clause</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to affect any program in title IV or V that is not a Public Assistance Program. </text></subsection><subsection id="HD5B36CC28F40430C85CB655022B42A9A"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section: </text><paragraph id="H0B15A2A7E6FE4A2E865242E47A67D13D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered small disaster</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>covered small disaster</quote> means a major disaster declared under section 401 or an emergency declared under section 501 with estimated damage eligible under the Public Assistance Program of less than or equal to 125 percent of the State’s per capita indicator. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H33B1BEBB2AAF4D649AACA9FEA370BD71"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Public Assistance Program</header><text>The term <quote>Public Assistance Program</quote> means the programs under sections 403, 406, 407, and 502. </text></paragraph></subsection></section></title><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

