<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" slc-id="S1-NEW25317-J5R-11-38C"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 162 IS: Honoring the memory of Jereima “Jeri” Bustamante on the seventh anniversary of her passing. </dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 162</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250408">April 8, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S404">Mr. Scott of Florida</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Honoring the memory of Jereima <quote>Jeri</quote> Bustamante on the seventh anniversary of her passing. </official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas Jereima <quote>Jeri</quote> Bustamante (referred to in this preamble as <quote>Jeri Bustamante</quote>) lived the American Dream;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, after moving from Panama to the United States with her family, Jeri Bustamante—</text><paragraph id="id35947528cea8496fb7d5a5868ccd237b"><enum>(1)</enum><text>attended Miami Beach Senior High School; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id677ec04291a94a09b8f246b50b56a414"><enum>(2)</enum><text>earned a Bachelor’s Degree in Communication and Media Sciences and a Master’s Degree in Public Administration from Florida International University;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Jeri Bustamante had a tireless work ethic and a passion for communication and paid for her education by working while enrolled in school;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas that tireless work ethic propelled Jeri Bustamante to professional success, beginning with an internship at a Miami television station and culminating in a period of service as press secretary to Governor Rick Scott;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the enthusiasm, compassion, tenacity, and vibrant energy of Jeri Bustamante are greatly missed by her family, friends, and coworkers;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the spirit of Jeri Bustamante lives on through the Jereima Bustamante Memorial Scholarship, which aims to help graduates of Miami Beach Senior High School achieve their goals and pursue the American Dream through a college education; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas April 8, 2025, marks 7 years since the life of Jeri Bustamante was tragically cut short in a fatal boating accident: Now, therefore, be it </text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="S1"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id2c3d6e1310224567a6e6cc2f8662796f"><enum>(1)</enum><text>honors the life and memory of Jereima <quote>Jeri</quote> Bustamante (referred to in this resolution as <quote>Jeri Bustamante</quote>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id87877140448449bdb49ce4b3ae91a435"><enum>(2)</enum><text>offers heartfelt condolences to the family, loved ones, and friends of Jeri Bustamante;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida8a67d1d9d6b4d88938b79a4a232bbe9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recognizes that living the American Dream remains possible for any individual who, following the example of Jeri Bustamante, works hard to pursue and achieve a goal; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id517cc8e9d76444d99f6d2e42f173b6c8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>encourages the recipients of the Jereima Bustamante Memorial Scholarship to carry on the legacy of Jeri Bustamante. </text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

