<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H731EF566A2EA4AB0B5790C30139E1A12" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5518 IH: Integrated Cross-Border Law Enforcement Operations Expansion Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5518</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250919">September 19, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000600">Mr. Langworthy</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="A000379">Mr. Alford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001196">Ms. Stefanik</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001148">Mr. Simpson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001212">Mr. Stauber</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001120">Mr. Crenshaw</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000478">Ms. Tenney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Z000018">Mr. Zinke</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000133">Mr. Van Drew</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000596">Mrs. Luna</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Homeland Security to negotiate an agreement with the Government of Canada for integrated cross-border aerial, land, and maritime law enforcement operations, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H98C94E9A6C1C43A6A8CC3D22FB9FA85A" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H074E867F52F74009AEB47E3741A842D8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Integrated Cross-Border Law Enforcement Operations Expansion Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HA9374339C58541D49A5D20A7D29A511F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that to the greatest extent practicable and consistent with the foreign policy objectives of the United States, the Secretary of Homeland Security should seek to utilize the authorities granted in this legislation to, among other things, negotiate or amend existing agreements with the Government of Canada, as appropriate, for integrated cross-border aerial, maritime, and land law enforcement operations.</text></section> 
<section id="H246B622A5FF04B0AA319962B81EDE136"><enum>3.</enum><header>International law enforcement cooperation</header> 
<subsection id="HDB162CA33EC64969B2AD8DE29AA67A58"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Amendments to the tariff act of 1930</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Part V of the Tariff Act of 1930 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1581">19 U.S.C. 1581 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HC4D0E366716D49E8A98F516091A9CF0F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 629(g), by adding after the period at the end the following: <quote>The Secretary of State, in coordination with the Secretary of Homeland Security, may enter into a treaty or agreement with any foreign country to extend to an officer of such country that is designated as an officer of the Customs Service pursuant to section 401(i) of this Act the same privileges and immunities as an officer of the Customs Service with respect to any actions taken by the designated person in the performance of such duties.</quote>; and</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0AB384482605460EB2370E78CC6782B7"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting after section 629 the following new section:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H247C8B859B3C4548AD3449F5D29AC811" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <section id="H437BE281DD7C4423B04676325EAB3812"><enum>629A.</enum><header>Operations in foreign countries and support to foreign authorities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security may use funds appropriated or otherwise available to U.S. Customs and Border Protection for operations and support to pay a tort claims, in the manner authorized in the first paragraph of section 2672 of title 28, United States Code, when such claim when arises in a foreign country in connection with U.S. Customs and Border Protection operations.</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H07BA18AD15054A7983E6A2FC1738352F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Amendment to the homeland security act</header><text>Subtitle H of title VIII of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/451">6 U.S.C. 451 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H253E97EF0BF34027937ABA249955AB00"> <section id="H04832A5BB127473E8D53ECDB0AF22613"><enum>890E.</enum><header>Stationing of foreign law enforcement officials and other personnel</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary or the Attorney General, or both as appropriate, may station or deploy United States law enforcement officers and associated personnel in a foreign country, and may accept the stationing or deployment of foreign law enforcement officials and other persons assigned by a foreign government in the United States, for the purpose of enhancing border security or law enforcement cooperation or operations, including for purposes of conducting joint operations in the land, air, and maritime domain, with that country. The Secretary of State, in coordination with the Secretary or the Attorney General, or both as appropriate, may enter into treaties or agreements with any foreign country to extend to foreign law enforcement officials and other persons assigned by the foreign government who are stationed in the United States such privileges and immunities as are necessary to carry out their functions.</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection> 
<subsection id="HDEBC2D421E19487496CD7F59D9D70D0E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections for the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/101">6 U.S.C. 101 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 890D the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HDE9A14A207FD4BA1BEEE2AAD14E514FA" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 890E. Stationing of foreign law enforcement officials and other personnel.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

