<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H26DC27E903424D8AADF0343EBAB744CE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5136 IH: Dollar Dominance Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5136</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250904">September 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000626">Mr. Davidson</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish the Office of Strategic Currency Diplomacy in the Department of State.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC634F4F803214D33B16F80C6D08FF900" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H520C1EE5D74644729105DBC350754173" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Dollar Dominance Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section>
<section id="H8F445ECB824049B5A4977EAE45F326F2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Office of Strategic Currency Diplomacy</header> 
<subsection id="HBEFB91DAD2024F9888B7499EF7892BC8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There shall be in the Bureau for Commercial Diplomacy of the Department of State an Office of Strategic Currency Diplomacy, which shall be responsible to the Assistant Secretary for Commercial Diplomacy for all matters pertaining to—</text> <paragraph id="H5E98E97B321F42D4881B8B60F6697B14"><enum>(1)</enum><text>combatting efforts by strategic rivals and adversaries to undermine the use of the United States dollar as the world’s reserve currency;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5C7FF9EB939F478C8B49DAB2E2F9EA4B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>partnering with allies to ensure the strength and integrity of U.S.-dollar denominated payment and financial systems;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBA98DE4A9D594C9DA31E44D79D8B5D35"><enum>(3)</enum><text>evaluating the implications of virtual assets for United States foreign policy and national security;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7005D15E33684B7B987C1CC7A49D758D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>aligning United States foreign policy, and in particular the use of sanctions to advance foreign policy and national security objectives, with national monetary security;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9897118D883044D1A6087D66EADDE9AD"><enum>(5)</enum><text>where appropriate, leading the coordination of programs carried out abroad by Federal departments and agencies, including the Department of the Treasury, the Department of Commerce, and the Office of the Director of National Intelligence, that relate to the matters for which the Office of Strategic Currency Diplomacy is responsible under this section; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H350B880613B14AC39CF19AD30FD5784D"><enum>(6)</enum><text>such other related duties as the Assistant Secretary for Commercial Diplomacy may from time to time designate.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H576E298AFD6245B7BBE4B4B14533E223"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text>In addition to being responsible for the matters described under subsection (a), the Office of Strategic Currency Diplomacy shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H6DD1F88EE4854CDFB91E6702DF2E3FE5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>serve as the principal advisor to the Assistant Secretary for Commercial Diplomacy regarding the development and implementation of policies to prevent a reduction in the use of the United States dollar as the primary reserve currency in international markets;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6F5C9C16E8534E8FBEDD32D4F4286015"><enum>(2)</enum><text>coordinate with the Department of the Treasury, the Department of Commerce, the Office of the Director of National Intelligence, and other Federal departments and agencies to develop—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H18D09AA30470486DA5037B8C71FEE335"><enum>(A)</enum><text>strategic plans to protect the preeminence of the United States dollar in international markets, with findings to be included in the Department of State’s Biannual Economic Security Report; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC28A7C9AC65F4E9089F468772A6DF8AD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>programs and policies that expand the percentage of—</text> 
<clause id="HEF0C2D4F32D545F49E252F89104427FE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>central bank foreign currency holdings in United States dollars; and</text></clause> <clause id="HF45A93A2340743738C74F4153C62BB7B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>international transactions denominated in United States dollars;</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAB42B7A9C9E6475C958D4834785E857D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>act as the representative of the Secretary to Federal departments and agencies in international engagements and bilateral and multilateral engagements related to expanding the use of virtual assets and virtual asset service providers (including United States dollar payment stable coins);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD5BBE8F8AEB04EE280C40F3900366E29"><enum>(4)</enum><text>monitor and develop strategies to counter the proliferation and adoption of Central Bank Digital Currencies in other nations to protect the preeminence of the United States dollar and national economic security; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAE1AE952C50B48A68CD63EEE5E1E159A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>perform each other related duty as the Assistant Secretary for Commercial Diplomacy may from time to time designate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

