<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6EC51138AB3F4675B8146614346161A9" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3464 IH: State Border Security Assistance Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3464</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250515">May 15, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000614">Mr. Roy</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000048">Mr. Pfluger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001120">Mr. Crenshaw</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000071">Mr. Ellzey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000592">Mr. Golden of Maine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001224">Mr. Moran</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001157">Mr. McCaul</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish the State Border Security Reinforcement Fund and the State Criminal Alien Prosecution and Detention Fund, to make appropriations to each of these funds, and to authorize the use of such amounts for grants to eligible States, State agencies, and units of local government for specified purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H3E0004BF92D344848B350FFF603A0C41" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H700634A9169C41888E1096B03ECDF3BF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>State Border Security Assistance Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H961741A42E784142BDACFB0F4A965EAA"><enum>2.</enum><header>State border security reinforcement fund</header> <subsection id="H244AAAD75B7C4149B69A0F86A8271BCF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment of fund</header><text>There is established, in the Department of Homeland Security, a fund, which shall be known as the <quote>State Border Security Reinforcement Fund</quote> (referred to in this section as the <quote>Fund</quote>). The Secretary of Homeland Security shall use amounts appropriated or otherwise made available for the Fund for grants to eligible States, State agencies, including National Guard units, and units of local government for any of the following purposes:</text> 
<paragraph id="H2A4B792802B44AA79CDEC11D61B7C8E9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Construction or installation of a border wall, border fencing, or other barriers or buoys along the southern border of the United States, which may include planning, procurement of materials, and personnel costs related to such construction.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H317B10F293694E6E8EF789B1E80DE568"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Any work necessary to prepare the ground at or near the United States border to allow construction or maintenance of a border wall or other barrier fencing or effective surveillance.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE66D50AF58F744C4822A239EC918F9CF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Information-gathering and surveillance to detect and interdict the unlawful entry of persons or contraband across the United States border.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6B16BB6E024048F0960DC417FF5A4838"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Relocation of aliens who are unlawfully present in the United States from small population centers.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H497DF40DDEE64B4EAECBE1DA0C365BF1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Appropriation</header><text>In addition to amounts otherwise available for the purposes described in paragraphs (1) through (4) of subsection (a), there is appropriated in fiscal year 2025, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, to the Department of Homeland Security for the Fund, $11,000,000,000, to remain available until September 30, 2034, for qualified expenses that meet the purposes described in subsection (a).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H5500777577DA4EE29EAC55E4F9A0323B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Grant eligibility of completed, ongoing, or new activities</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security may provide grants under subsection (a) to State agencies and units of local government for expenditures they made for completed, ongoing, or new activities determined to be eligible for such grant funding that occurred on or after January 20, 2021.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF999F476B4A64EB38B9812FC08731E83"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>The Fund shall terminate on January 20, 2029, and any unobligated amounts remaining in the Fund on that date shall be returned to the Treasury of the United States for deficit reduction purposes.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HD4E5793F1E6E49B2819B4B9DC400A1CE"><enum>3.</enum><header>State criminal alien prosecution and detention fund</header> <subsection id="H1BBF5E7B748141B0BF6998861BAB518D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment of fund</header><text>There is established, in the Department of Justice, a fund, which shall be known as the <quote>State Criminal Alien Prosecution and Detention Fund</quote> (referred to in this section as the <quote>Fund</quote>). The Attorney General shall use amounts appropriated or otherwise made available for the Fund for grants to eligible States, State agencies, including National Guard units, and units of local government for any of the following purposes:</text> 
<paragraph id="H8D9207633D0F48A58E2B46619E208C46"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Locating and apprehending aliens who are unlawfully present in the United States or have committed a crime under Federal, State, or local law.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8CB57F0469D240EB8A9C993FE6EBAF91"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Intelligence and information-gathering to counter gang activity.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9787077BA719405B905237CB4FFBDB46"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Investigating and prosecuting crimes committed by aliens and drug and human trafficking crimes.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD724C93AD1DF48E99A1E035B7079E423"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Court operations related to the prosecution of crimes committed by aliens and drug and human trafficking crimes.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6DE5AAC5EC2F4FEBB0929A6E64DBF643"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Temporarily detaining aliens, including costs related to facility operations, personnel, and health and safety related services.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1EEEA33AE0CB4F2BAFD673CC8AA77B97"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Transporting aliens described in paragraph (1) to locations related to their apprehension, detention, and prosecution.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCBCBD6904A944E228F96FE253C536257"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Vehicle maintenance, logistics, transportation, and other support provided to law enforcement agencies by a State agency to enhance their ability to locate and apprehend aliens who have unlawfully entered the United States or have committed crimes under Federal, State, or local law.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD5EA35561183474AAA47D43FFFA79695"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Appropriation</header><text>In addition to amounts otherwise available for the purposes described in paragraphs (1) through (6) of subsection (a), there is appropriated in fiscal year 2025, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, to the Department of Justice for the Fund, $3,500,000,000, to remain available until September 30, 2034, for qualified expenses that achieve any such purposes.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H59410E27595F4F408BF91EB7AF5A7F66"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Grant eligibility of completed, ongoing, or new activities</header><text>The Attorney General may provide grants under subsection (a) to State agencies and units of local government for expenditures they made for completed, ongoing, or new activities determined to be eligible for such grant funding that occurred on or after January 20, 2021.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H2865DAC770A14D4CA2842D4BB3E8F467"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>The Fund shall terminate on January 20, 2029, and any unobligated amounts remaining in the Fund on that date shall be returned to the Treasury of the United States for deficit reduction purposes.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

