<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5BC2660B2732449D91EC74560F466128" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 89 IH: Prescription Freedom Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 89</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250103">January 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001302">Mr. Biggs of Arizona</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To repeal the authority of the Food and Drug Administration to require that drugs be dispensed only upon prescription, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0DF06606866043E894A17CE3352B9EB4" style="OLC"><section id="H50DB0CBFC2B34EE9B92BB4D94C2ED3F7" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Prescription Freedom Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H27DF89D5C00E4B309B80ED132A42CCB1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Repeal of FDA authority to require prescriptions</header><subsection id="H2000F792C799426E8B7C3E1DA2F362C3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Repeal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Effective as of the date that is 6 months after the date of enactment of this Act, subsection (b) of section 503 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/353">21 U.S.C. 353</external-xref>) is repealed.</text></subsection><subsection id="H06435DD2BD8D456CACD168A61C7742B7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>References</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning on the effective date described in subsection (a), any reference in a Federal statute, regulation, or guidance—</text><paragraph id="H4280A161E32C41F6954D2B541AC910EE"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to prescribing, a prescription, a prescription drug, or a drug subject to section 503(b) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act is deemed to be a reference to prescribing, a prescription, or a prescription drug, respectively, under applicable State law; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5887BF7CB0694FC7A97D594BB520F8FF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to any requirement or provision of section 503(b) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act is deemed to be a reference to the corresponding requirement or provision, if any, in applicable State law, as determined by the Federal official or officials responsible for administering the respective Federal statute, regulation, or guidance.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1D43B3EAC2BA4079812CBD16514BB75D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding subsections (a) and (b), the Secretary of Health and Human Services may continue to exercise the authority vested by subsection (b) of section 503 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/353">21 U.S.C. 353</external-xref>), as in effect on the day before the effective date described in subsection (a), with respect to any drug that is intended for use in terminating a pregnancy.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

