<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF3FA705E25704E9DA373EE1340E06D2B" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 622 IH: Honoring the contributions of small manufacturers of firearms to the economy, culture, and recreational heritage of the United States and supporting the designation of August 2025 as “National Shooting Sports Month”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 622</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250729">July 29, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000829">Mr. Wied</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSM00">Committee on Small Business</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Honoring the contributions of small manufacturers of firearms to the economy, culture, and recreational heritage of the United States and supporting the designation of August 2025 as <quote>National Shooting Sports Month</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas locally owned and operated small businesses that manufacture handguns, rifles, shotguns, ammunition, and accessories (referred to in this preamble as <quote>small manufacturers of firearms</quote>), are the backbone of the shooting sports community and a critical part of the manufacturing base of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas small manufacturers of firearms serve as anchors in rural and small-town communities across the United States, preserving the craftsmanship, entrepreneurship, and innovation of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas small manufacturers of firearms contribute significantly to the national and local economy and support 380,000 jobs in the broader firearms industry, with more than $91,000,000,000 in annual economic output;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas small manufacturers of firearms are essential conduits for the exercise of Second Amendment rights by individuals in the United States and provide products, training, and community engagement to sportsmen in the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas shooting sports, including target shooting, hunting, and competitive marksmanship, are time-honored traditions in the United States and are enjoyed by millions of law-abiding citizens;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas shooting sports promote safe and responsible firearm handling, outdoor stewardship, and civic engagement through local clubs, ranges, and competitions; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas small manufacturers of firearms in the United States play an indispensable role in preserving these recreational traditions: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H211A67001C1140B38A3D98EAF9252EE5"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H949CB6B9BAB84F47A861E7EE1038F20D"><enum/><text>That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="H18EE7A83227E44809B3F17B752E8DD97"><enum>(1)</enum><text>celebrates the role of small businesses that manufacture firearms in supporting domestic manufacturing and economic opportunity in communities across the United States; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5CAF7485A97640CD82EBB36DDA5FD8BA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>supports policies that strengthen the ability of such small businesses to innovate, grow, and preserve the recreational shooting traditions of the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3ED67B72F076417A991F76F89A838BDA"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recognizes <quote>National Shooting Sports Month</quote>.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

