<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-OTT25055-6C6-10-R4R"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S439 IS: Incentivizing Readiness and Environmental Protection Integration Sales Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 439</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250206" legis-day="20250205">February 6 (legislative day, February 5), 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S417">Mr. Budd</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to exclude from gross income gain from the sale of qualified real property interests acquired under the authority of the Readiness and Environmental Protection Integration (REPI) program administered by the Department of Defense pursuant to section 2684a of title 10, United States Code, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="id22a4448454db4b06a79ff32a551b03df"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Incentivizing Readiness and Environmental Protection Integration Sales Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section section-type="subsequent-section" id="id55e7c111647e4b339ac55aef45ec6246"><enum>2.</enum><header>Exclusion of gain from sale of qualified real property interests acquired for purposes related to the readiness and environmental protection integration program</header><subsection id="id3ea3de4ab0f44f1c965394506b5687cd"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Part III of subchapter B of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting after section 139I the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide79389bc44884b40aca24d2e1f28a4b8"><section id="id9bfd570a79144a3a951a861e55b8cc68"><enum>139J.</enum><header>Gain from sale of qualified real property interest for purposes related to the readiness and environmental protection integration program</header><subsection id="id2dfdfa19c3394e75a22b1200db0f5369"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Gross income shall not include any gain from the sale of qualified real property interest to a qualified organization for REPI purposes.</text></subsection><subsection id="id30b58a7e770244538fa863368827803a"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text><paragraph id="id73057864e8b94a1c8405dd5bff65f177"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Qualified real property interest</header><subparagraph id="id86c1478ff54e4c93aa44bfcceed867ec"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>qualified real property interest</term> means any of the following interests in real property:</text><clause id="idb39f8ead23ca4af2b9c3a32a2a9feb2a"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The entire interest of the taxpayer.</text></clause><clause id="id3c8804e4a63f4aedb0772c406dabb2e0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A remainder interest.</text></clause><clause id="iddff8df0534dd4089869d0ffbc6be3adc"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>A restriction (granted in perpetuity and created pursuant to State real property law) on the use which may be made of the real property.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id37d1ed1393fe4d73bfa0c7a8edf2690d"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Special rule for mineral interests</header><text>An interest in real property shall not fail to be treated as a qualified real property interest solely by reason of a retention of a qualified mineral interest (as defined in section 170(h)(6)), but only if the right to access such mineral interest is not accomplished by any surface mining method.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id86f40511abf64816bc9b9312938dd4ed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualified organization</header><text>The term <term>qualified organization</term> has the meaning given such term by section 170(h)(3).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id66409f1837784c97a24d85ff1105be2c"><enum>(3)</enum><header>REPI purposes</header><text>A sale of qualified real property interest shall be treated as being for REPI purposes if such sale is pursuant to the authority of the Readiness and Environmental Protection Integration (REPI) program administered by the Department of Defense under section 2684a of title 10, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id931c134ba56b4b62a8e4c76f5eca8563"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Limitation</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id00d0f181f59147dda0e69ec16214a985"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a pass-through entity, no amount shall be excluded from gross income under subsection (a) with respect to a sale if such entity acquired the qualified real property interest by sale within 3 years of the date of the sale described in subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfba75271932d4607abdf654cd1ee65bd"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception for family partnerships or family pass-through entities</header><subparagraph id="idba87fbacaebd49b29e48ea213a081ed0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Paragraph (1) shall not apply with respect to any sale made by any partnership if substantially all of the partnership interests in such partnership are held, directly or indirectly, by an individual and members of the family of such individual.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id359d28a6ac824a0ca4208edbeebcf76a"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Members of the family</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>members of the family</term> means, with respect to any individual—</text><clause id="idccc81d2601554dc395d84d2919b1bad5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the spouse of such individual, and</text></clause><clause id="idc4136422f4864b96845847f82bbfc25a"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any individual who bears a relationship to such individual which is described in subparagraphs (A) through (G) of section 152(d)(2).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfc2383104065487ab0338e295dfb16b5"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Application to other pass-through entities</header><text>Except as may be otherwise provided by the Secretary, the rules of this paragraph shall apply to S corporations and other pass-through entities in the same manner as such rules apply to partnerships.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="idf6a3a0faf9f0463bae8174ca73fc21de"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for part III of subchapter B of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 139I the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="id94a537a8-9265-47fd-a59c-7bcfdc2a4c18"><toc><toc-entry level="section" idref="id9bfd570a79144a3a951a861e55b8cc68">Sec. 139J. Gain from sale of qualified real property interest for purposes related to the readiness and environmental protection integration program.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="idcb6b56036f974158984caa48ac1a042d"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

