<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H77DD7B3872E84CE7847515966DF537E5" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4058 IH: Enhancing Stakeholder Support and Outreach for Preparedness Grants Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4058</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250620">June 20, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to enhance outreach for the Urban Area Security Initiative and the State Homeland Security Grant Program of the Department of Homeland Security, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H4562D873ACDD418CAE2638A2E875B0B5" style="OLC"><section id="HC51E764DB8574675B57C06DA1B3929EB" section-type="section-one" commented="no"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Enhancing Stakeholder Support and Outreach for Preparedness Grants Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H00DF400B20974535BE9B6269D9849E0C"><enum>2.</enum><header>DHS grant outreach</header><subsection id="HF3C3D1B50FFF4C6DA035F3B1F83DC3C4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Urban Area Security Initiative</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2003 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/604">6 U.S.C. 604</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block id="HEB60EF66F8284FCD90B184BB73CA0A41" style="OLC"><subsection id="HAB13FEA344CF42B28896A18ECB706A3C"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Outreach and technical assistance</header><text>The Administrator shall, on an ongoing basis, provide stakeholder outreach, engagement, education, technical assistance, and support, prior to, during, and after the awarding of grants under this section, including relating to the following:</text><paragraph id="H2CBCB755C43D48F5AE58A2F06595BBAD"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Conducting annual surveys to collect feedback from State, local, Tribal, and territorial stakeholders on the awarding of such grants and the effectiveness of the Administrator’s outreach efforts.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H22E3F563B7F6469BBE52A5CC502BA9AD"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Summaries of the surveys conducted pursuant to paragraph (1) and other State, local, Tribal, and territorial feedback and how such feedback was incorporated into subsequent grant notices of funding opportunities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1D792059C59A45D1B3803A912B02107A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Other feedback mechanisms that the Administrator determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HD9F39DC8D04247C8860E59409766ACE3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>State Homeland Security Grant Program</header><text>Section 2004 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/605">6 U.S.C. 605</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block id="HA73246302DC541799B35CD38ED96F440" style="OLC"><subsection id="HA244AC96A17142708BD2A59C64386ED0"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Outreach and technical assistance</header><text>The Administrator shall, on an ongoing basis, provide stakeholder outreach, engagement, education, technical assistance, and support, prior to, during, and after the awarding of grants under this section, including relating to the following:</text><paragraph id="HF62D60877E284931BCAF49AD921DBA77"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Conducting annual surveys to collect feedback from State, local, Tribal, and territorial stakeholders on the awarding of such grants and the effectiveness of the Administrator’s outreach efforts.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H59F43886ABB9452F824DADCAC17E7115"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Summaries of the surveys conducted pursuant to paragraph (1) and other State, local, Tribal, and territorial feedback and how such feedback was incorporated into subsequent grant notices of funding opportunities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3ECA68E5B6A3482FB2BB0969FDE921A8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Other feedback mechanisms that the Administrator determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HF3BAD92CB87747AA9A8F16E17D36588B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Comptroller General review</header><text>Not later than two years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency and the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a report on the effectiveness of the Federal Emergency Management Agency’s stakeholder outreach, engagement, education, technical assistance, and support, prior to, during, and after the awarding of grants under the Urban Area Security Initiative and State Homeland Security Grant Program, in accordance with subsection (f) of section 2003 and subsection (g) of section 2004, respectively, of the Homeland Security Act of 2002, as added by subsections (a) and (b), respectively.</text></subsection><subsection id="HED062EB6C4804CA5A0B85EC17A0BE8F3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than three years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a report regarding the actions taken pursuant to subsection (f) of section 2003 and subsection (g) of section 2004 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002, as added by subsections (a) and (b), respectively, including with respect to the surveys and summaries required under paragraphs (1) and (2) of each of such subsections (f) and (g).</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

