<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1E29210BA554413DA9BD05098B4565AD" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2105 IH: Preventing Illegal Weapons Trafficking Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2105</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250314">March 14, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001117">Mr. Casten</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001205">Ms. Scanlon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001215">Ms. Stevens</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000191">Mr. Neguse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000468">Mrs. Fletcher</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001223">Mr. Magaziner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001318">Ms. Balint</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Vel&#225;zquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000601">Mr. Landsman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001130">Ms. Crockett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001313">Ms. Brown</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000148">Mr. Auchincloss</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000477">Mrs. Foushee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001216">Ms. Schrier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To address the importation and proliferation of machinegun conversion devices.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD2A90B5C6B914EDE9E11B3A1C6650666" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H32909CE08E69499BB85E05E4C4965268"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Preventing Illegal Weapons Trafficking Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HADF59BC98C2D407783675FEDA5164DEC"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act—</text> 
<paragraph id="HF152CCEB220F468ABA3046CE5AF3475D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>machinegun</term> has the meaning given the term <quote>machine gun</quote> in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/5845">section 5845</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H06FA456D830D43DD8ADB3648CA15601E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>machinegun conversion device</term> means any part designed and intended solely and exclusively, or combination of parts designed and intended, for use in converting a weapon into a machinegun.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H6DE124C898304C2E9A7ECA4469FDB835"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prevention and interception strategy</header> 
<subsection id="HF4776D65C1044DA8954CD0073E4FE508"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Strategy</header> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA3B8FFF703BC444C922BEEFC695D6136"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and the Secretary of the Treasury shall develop and implement a strategy to prevent or intercept the importation or trafficking of machinegun conversion devices.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H41BA7F726718420EBC2774A777E9466B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The strategy described in paragraph (1) shall include plans to optimize—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE88AFFD2B6E743BF802F6155721DA8F8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the capacity of Federal law enforcement agencies to detect, intercept, and seize machinegun conversion devices;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC67B528509FA4273A24D2A7F653EADEC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the coordination between State and local law enforcement agencies and Federal law enforcement agencies, including the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives, the Federal Bureau of Investigation, Homeland Security Investigations, and U.S. Customs and Border Protection, when machinegun conversion devices are seized at ports of entry;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H790AD117953E4207995187F968E67338"><enum>(C)</enum><text>efforts by the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives to collaborate with State and local law enforcement agencies to identify and trace machinegun conversion devices used in crimes, including identifying the source of the device, whether from a foreign country or the United States;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3122A8208D3A45DD93CE74C2E409F627"><enum>(D)</enum><text>training programs provided by Federal law enforcement agencies to aid State and local law enforcement agencies in identifying machinegun conversion devices;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE2946BF47C164F43911C0014DF6645F3"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the investigation and collection of data regarding the origins of machinegun conversion devices that are seized at ports of entry or recovered by law enforcement agencies in the United States in order to identify patterns and detect vulnerabilities; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H541B559E38684234A3C49649542E7B31"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the capacity of Federal law enforcement agencies, including the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives, the Federal Bureau of Investigation, and Homeland Security Investigations, to detect, intercept, and seize domestically produced machinegun conversion devices, including machinegun conversion devices produced using 3D printing technology.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9889BAE7FD2D43E4BDEF50B889B8AFFC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reports</header> 
<paragraph id="H464325CE5FD94AE28E636E44886C3E40"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial report</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and the Secretary of the Treasury shall submit a report on the strategy developed and implemented under subsection (a), which shall include relevant statistical information, to—</text> <subparagraph id="HC458F2117DB345BFBEF005B9C33FE435"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H45A67C4999D44D60926FF29B34AD6DA6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2D4E4FE09B2D41E8B17B197CF0663F7D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H31DB64CE79A0469BA696947D83DB7720"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H712881A4C3C349EA821FBA5E2060A1A4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Periodic updates</header><text>Not less frequently than once every 2 years, the Attorney General, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and the Secretary of the Treasury shall submit to the congressional committees described in paragraph (1) an update to the report submitted under that paragraph that describes progress made on the implementation of the strategy developed under subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H02BDB105FE2B43468A6B0FA5FE8B7FB2"><enum>4.</enum><header>Forfeiture of proceeds from machine gun violations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/5872">Section 5872</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H0F83BEE1B2EA42BEA0D48B7A05EDE2D4"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (a), by inserting <quote>, and any proceeds derived from the illegal trafficking of a machine gun,</quote> after <quote>provisions of this chapter</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD9BF967D755C4E54A448C17E282CDEE4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEDDEE96C427B49B798660CDF0ADF38C1"> <subsection id="HA9FC85ED9E3E445596E9E730F3F914C7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Illegal trafficking of a machine gun</header><text>For purposes of subsection (a), the term <term>illegal trafficking of a machine gun</term> means the making, manufacture, importation, exportation, or transfer of a machine gun in violation of the provisions of this chapter or any regulations prescribed under this chapter.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H0707D0C913064E5EA069A1F3B4DFCEBB"><enum>5.</enum><header>Gun trafficking report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Attorney General shall include information about machinegun conversion devices in the annual firearms trafficking report announced by the President on April 7, 2021, including—</text> <paragraph id="H020B4374B85F47269646CDBEF12B6387"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the number of crimes in which machinegun conversion devices are used; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H530FC571D87D4B8E9ACFD59612220883"><enum>(2)</enum><text>whether the machinegun conversion devices recovered from crimes described in paragraph (1) are manufactured in the United States or a foreign country.</text></paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

