<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H809CF6946B84421881C37E8CECDE2DF8" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 444 IH: Calling upon all Americans on this Memorial Day, 2025, to honor the men and women of the Armed Forces who have died in the pursuit of freedom and peace.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 444</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250523">May 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000591">Mr. Guest</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="D000032">Mr. Donalds</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000578">Mr. LaMalfa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000459">Mr. Fleischmann</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001120">Mr. Crenshaw</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001219">Mr. Moylan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001205">Mrs. Miller of West Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001236">Mr. Moore of North Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001214">Mr. Steube</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001098">Mr. Hamadeh of Arizona</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000795">Mr. Wilson of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000600">Mr. Langworthy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001133">Mr. Ciscomani</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001115">Mr. Cloud</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000190">Mr. Norman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001226">Ms. Salinas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001225">Mr. Sorensen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000798">Mr. Walberg</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000250">Mr. Sessions</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001233">Mr. Messmer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000397">Mrs. Kim</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000467">Mr. Thompson of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000299">Ms. Escobar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001194">Mr. Moolenaar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001055">Mr. Case</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000059">Mr. Calvert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000546">Mr. Graves</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001220">Mr. Strong</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Calling upon all Americans on this Memorial Day, 2025, to honor the men and women of the Armed Forces who have died in the pursuit of freedom and peace.</official-title></form><preamble>
<whereas><text>Whereas the preservation of basic freedoms and world peace has always been a valued objective of this Nation;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas more than one million United States men and women have selflessly given their lives in sacrifice in service as peacemakers and peacekeepers;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas the American people should continue to demonstrate the appreciation and gratitude these patriots deserve and to commemorate the ultimate sacrifice they made in service to our Nation; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Memorial Day is the day of the year to remember the sacrifices made by these defenders who now lie in hallowed ground throughout the world and serves as an expression of our faith in democracy, our faith in our values, and our faith that those who fight for freedom will defeat those whose cause is unjust: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H1CE80019E8F84753B1038A141249B950"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HF7499DBB6D684B658F33FE919BBC181F"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="H4E3D7BF449DB492EB3266EF6A3920FD6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>calls on the people of the United States to observe Memorial Day as a special day of remembrance to honor the men and women of the United States who died in the pursuit of freedom and peace; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H34DD7E2F411746EBB4E3F04E3D073863"><enum>(2)</enum><text>believes this should be done as an expression of the respect, pride, and admiration felt by every American and by every person liberated through the courageous sacrifice and valiant toil of the forces of the United States and its allies in this noble struggle.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

