<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H402610A4CF8242D0BDBA723BBA9E30CC" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2363 IH: Data Of Government health Entities must be Protected from Overreach by Unelected Nonsecure Disruption Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2363</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250326">March 26, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000197">Ms. DeGette</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000617">Ms. Pressley</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001156">Ms. Sánchez</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the authorization of certain individuals to access certain systems containing individually identifiable health information.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H3912F163C24A47468BDFD6E9A334BA57" style="OLC"><section id="H93EA00D3C60748C1B78F009BE6A2D5CA" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Data Of Government health Entities must be Protected from Overreach by Unelected Nonsecure Disruption Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>DOGE POUND Act of 2025</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H30DCA9CAE3BF4D22B7FA83609984C8A8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibiting the authorization of certain individuals to access certain systems containing individually identifiable health information</header><subsection id="HEC0FFD7066A34A0596C2553162995636"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no individual may be authorized to use, exercise administrative control over, or otherwise access any specified system (as defined in subsection (d)), or any data from any such system, unless—</text><paragraph id="HDD8EFA3FFE74405598D7DAE7B7F308E7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>such individual is an officer, employee, or contractor of the Department of Health and Human Services who—</text><subparagraph id="H77ABA2A6D503424F8A1996D7B10C6CC9" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text>was otherwise eligible to access such system or data prior to January 20, 2025; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC3F7A9EEBDBE4FE7852B3BC0B9FBF696"><enum>(B)</enum><text>continued to be otherwise eligible to access such system or data between January 20, 2025, and the date of access to such system or data; or</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H27A0E275953A4B0286B0E38D96BDF8BB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the case of an individual not described in paragraph (1)—</text><subparagraph id="HCE77AADED0A54A859C7230A8C53A0E81" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such individual holds a security clearance at the appropriate level with respect to such system or data and such clearance was granted pursuant to the procedures established under section 801 of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3161">50 U.S.C. 3161</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDDBF1F6CD1294D5BBC02F20028A9B737" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such individual’s access to such system or data, or use thereof, does not constitute a violation of section 208 of title 18, United States Code (determined after the application of subsection (b));</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H94B6FA6F9EF04AA4B3518C83E38D29BE" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such individual is not a special Government employee (as defined in section 202 of title 18, United States Code); </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6AE0FEEDF64D4F1089EF67D9BE6E52C1" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(D)</enum><text>such individual’s current continuous service in the civil service (as that term is defined in section 2101 of title 5, United States Code) as of the date of such access is for a period of at least 1 year; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAF19DE0A589449EC96FDE14C359533C3"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such individual has completed any required training or compliance procedures with respect to privacy laws and cybersecurity and national security regulations and best practices; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H564E4B75CBC14B67A32B4091621EEE6C"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such individual has signed a written ethics agreement with either the Department of Health and Human Services or the Office of Government Ethics.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9C36895772BC42129E0116926EAF6E1A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application of penalties</header><paragraph id="HCA7875FD09CB408A9E7F68A21E58399F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whoever knowingly—</text><subparagraph id="H8FB14A769ABF467C8216D7DBDF008067"><enum>(A)</enum><text>uses, exercises administrative control over, or otherwise accesses any system or data described in subsection (a) in violation of such subsection, or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6A9BB7B857784726AEA7B96CEFBEDA49"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">authorizes the use, exercise of administrative control over, or other access to any system or data described in subsection (a) in violation of such subsection,</text></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">shall be imprisoned not more than 5 years or fined under title 18, United States Code, or both.</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6275BCA6F7F448D2B4B5802F455920A6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Statute of limitations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 3282 of title 18, United States Code, no person shall be prosecuted, tried, or punished for any offense under this subsection unless the indictment is found or the information is instituted not later than 10 years after the date on which the offense was committed.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC34167263234476E98FC636E5D0FA1ED"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reports on unauthorized use</header><text>The Inspector General of the Department of Health and Human Services shall investigate, and submit a report to Congress on such investigation, each instance of unauthorized use or other access of any specified system. Any such report shall be submitted not later than 30 days after any such instance and shall include—</text><paragraph id="H1D5A893CEBDC4ED69D9E00A6C29F5D4E" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a detailed description of the unauthorized use or access, including any actions the individual carried out; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3FD0578BABD445C09DBAE781724AE7C5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a risk assessment of any threat to privacy, national security, cybersecurity, or the integrity of the applicable system as a result of such unauthorized use or access; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD33C1BC426F24D898396295E0A7064E7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a detailed description of any stopped payments during the unauthorized use or access.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA20CB61C17C34D2FBAA3264A970E2CD9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Specified system</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the term <quote>specified system</quote> means any system maintained by the Department of Health and Human Services that contains individually identifiable health information (as defined in section 1171(6) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1320d">42 U.S.C. 1320d(6)</external-xref>)). </text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

