<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-NEW25355-HJL-T8-1SD"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 179 ATS: Recognizing and supporting the goals and ideals of National Sexual Assault Awareness and Prevention Month.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 179</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250410">April 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S153">Mr. Grassley</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S252">Ms. Collins</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S385">Ms. Cortez Masto</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S376">Ms. Ernst</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S418">Mr. Fetterman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S229">Mrs. Murray</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S409">Mr. Luján</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing and supporting the goals and ideals of National Sexual Assault Awareness and Prevention Month.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the Senate is committed to the awareness, prevention, and deterrence of sexual violence affecting individuals in the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, 2 in 5 women and 1 in 4 men experience sexual or physical violence, or stalking, by an intimate partner;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to the 2023 Child Maltreatment Report of the Department of Health and Human Services, child protection service agencies throughout the United States substantiated, or found strong evidence to indicate, that 546,159 children under 18 years of age were victims of sexual abuse or neglect that year;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to the 2016/2017 National Intimate Partner and Sexual Violence Survey, 1 in 3 women and 1 in 4 men who have experienced a completed or attempted rape experienced it for the first time between the ages of 11 and 17;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas sexual violence is a burden for many individuals who serve in the Armed Forces, and the Department of Defense estimates that approximately 29,061 members of the Armed Forces, including approximately 15,201 women and 13,860 men, experienced some form of contact or penetrative sexual assault during 2023;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas sexual assault does not discriminate on any basis and can affect any individual in the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas sexual violence may take many forms, including—</text><paragraph id="id67d4f00d88c342bbab982aae34183841"><enum>(1)</enum><text>acquaintance, stranger, spousal, and gang rape;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida0f721005545477cb5d9f56276ac4d5e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>incest;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4008a035bdff456d9cec82ac5ba2d438"><enum>(3)</enum><text>child sexual abuse;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id69fd5b75b354435cb5a6a661d160ca23"><enum>(4)</enum><text>elder sexual abuse;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id76616a2ed3da408aa59f5c22fc0edfcb"><enum>(5)</enum><text>sexual abuse and exploitation of underserved communities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id864145db4c344add83220e95467a4b12"><enum>(6)</enum><text>commercial sex trafficking;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id78b77aadc2e8456db11dd33c32418498"><enum>(7)</enum><text>sexual harassment; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idefe2a95532964e46a8623de2cf0a6e5e"><enum>(8)</enum><text>stalking;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas studies have suggested that survivors of color face unique challenges and more should be done to better understand the impact of sexual violence on communities of color;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas studies have suggested that the rate at which American Indians and Alaska Natives experience sexual violence is significantly higher than for other populations in the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to the National Alliance to End Sexual Violence, in addition to the immediate physical and emotional costs, sexual assault has numerous adverse consequences, which can include post-traumatic stress disorder, substance abuse, major depression, homelessness, eating disorders, and suicide;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to a 2019 Centers for Disease Control and Prevention survey, the average cost of rape is $122,461 for each victim over the lifetime of the victim, totaling a $3,100,000,000,000 economic burden for survivors of rape in the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas many sexual assaults are not reported to law enforcement agencies, and many States have restrictive criminal statutes of limitations, which enable many perpetrators to evade punishment for their crimes;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas advances in deoxyribonucleic acid (commonly known as <quote>DNA</quote>) technology have enabled law enforcement agencies to identify and prosecute the perpetrators in tens of thousands of previously unsolved sexual assault cases;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas incarceration of sexual assault perpetrators can prevent perpetrators from committing additional crimes;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to a 2023 survey by the National Alliance to End Sexual Violence, 48 percent of rape crisis centers lack a therapist on staff, and 70 percent of programs had an increased demand for services in the past year;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas national, State, territorial, and Tribal coalitions, community-based rape crisis centers, culturally specific sexual assault organizations, and other organizations across the United States are committed to—</text><paragraph id="id66d87804ffdc478f90fba58cb92f2c34"><enum>(1)</enum><text>eliminating sexual violence through prevention and education; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc9a980c6005c4a829ebc1ce656b096ad"><enum>(2)</enum><text>increasing public awareness of sexual violence and the prevalence of sexual violence;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas thousands of volunteers and staff at rape crisis centers, State coalitions against sexual assault, culturally specific sexual assault organizations, and nonprofit organizations across the United States play an important role in making crisis hotlines and other services available to survivors of sexual assault;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas important partnerships have been formed among criminal and juvenile justice agencies, health professionals, public health workers, educators, first responders, and victim service providers;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas free, confidential help is available to all victims and survivors of sexual assault through—</text><paragraph id="id9bb46923cbc54419b966e15daa8bd84d"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the victim service programs of the Rape, Abuse &amp; Incest National Network (commonly known and referred to in this preamble as <quote>RAINN</quote>), including the National Sexual Assault Hotline—</text><subparagraph id="idd7c509be39eb4151b43dfd64a008935f"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by telephone at 800–656–HOPE; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5479ead6173d490ea911c5da06b1a8fd"><enum>(B)</enum><text>online at https://hotline.rainn.org; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id89b7d95e11634cdc836c42384f61a867"><enum>(2)</enum><text>more than 1,500 local rape crisis centers across the United States;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the victim service programs of RAINN, including the National Sexual Assault Hotline, help more than 300,000 survivors and their loved ones each year on average;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Department of Defense provides the Safe Helpline, Safe HelpRoom, and Safe Helpline mobile application, each of which provide support and help to members of the Department of Defense community—</text><paragraph id="id8f4f713b607143ac93115f21f11bfc29"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by telephone at 877–995–5247; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id737ee903dd9b42a89b8febc7b1224308"><enum>(2)</enum><text>online at https://SafeHelpline.org;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas individual and collective efforts reflect the dream of the people of the United States—</text><paragraph id="id192866ca4e114745b0bc05bc1e2c447e"><enum>(1)</enum><text>for individuals and organizations to actively work to prevent all forms of sexual violence; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4ea8fcc242e6485aa3e09c3b075bfcbd"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for no victim of sexual assault to be unserved or feel that there is no path to justice; and</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas April 2025 is recognized as <quote>National Sexual Assault Awareness and Prevention Month</quote>: Now, therefore, be it </text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That—</text><paragraph id="idfd4abc4d1a2f423f88942247b2eedca1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>it is the sense of the Senate that—</text><subparagraph id="id7f1e17415653451ca1f1a2dc024c485f"><enum>(A)</enum><text>National Sexual Assault Awareness and Prevention Month provides a special opportunity—</text><clause id="id965f7c0b3ba24bfca967e3caa71e3201"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to educate the people of the United States about sexual violence; and</text></clause><clause id="idca55fa946c7242058e095a3883827b92"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to encourage—</text><subclause id="idaa581f366a0145f7bbee63a61ac00fa4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the prevention of sexual assault;</text></subclause><subclause id="idde7b05bd0f9e43bb833ab2d7ebb11a89"><enum>(II)</enum><text>improvement in the treatment of survivors of sexual assault; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id7198182493a9456689f87173a213fc0d"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the prosecution of perpetrators of sexual assault;</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1f8f36880cfc4497b3ac29e7f3a809e8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>it is appropriate to properly acknowledge survivors of sexual assault and to commend the volunteers and professionals who assist those survivors in their efforts to heal;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idab734465cd4143c0ac38935c09a7e545"><enum>(C)</enum><text>national and community organizations and private sector supporters should be recognized and applauded for their work in—</text><clause id="id3a5ce0a572874b9e8097365aabf18e7c"><enum>(i)</enum><text>promoting awareness about sexual assault;</text></clause><clause id="ida91dfdc383d74eeaa375200446a06329"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>providing information and treatment to survivors of sexual assault; and</text></clause><clause id="id4f807bc081a74da59c22f5b580e8fb21"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>increasing the number of successful prosecutions of perpetrators of sexual assault; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id45bca180ac094fa9a4a3af35760df2e6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>public safety, law enforcement, and health professionals should be recognized and applauded for their hard work and innovative strategies to ensure perpetrators of sexual assault are held accountable; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idbb0db5e24b6940779433dcdef4040ab3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Senate supports the goals and ideals of National Sexual Assault Awareness and Prevention Month.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

