<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H05AE7B2C27CB472485D131DA3B16E57B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5715 IH: October 7 Gold Medal Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5715</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251008">October 8, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000399">Mr. Doggett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001157">Mr. David Scott of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000602">Ms. Gillen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000606">Mr. Latimer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001201">Mr. Suozzi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001211">Mr. Stanton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000601">Mr. Landsman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001217">Mr. Moskowitz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001063">Mr. Cuellar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000598">Mr. LaLota</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001223">Mr. Magaziner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001200">Mr. Soto</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H000874">Mr. Hoyer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To award a Congressional Gold Medal, collectively, to the American hostages and victims of the October 7th, 2023 attacks, in recognition of their profound suffering and sacrifice.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC7C2D187CEAA400FBE659DCD1398B41B" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H7F42200D223A422382A020EAF584B761" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>October 7 Gold Medal Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H4DF28758A6194558929BB120F2E7DDFD"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HE000A9FA0A60480F9D443DB052CB00C0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>On October 7, 2023, Hamas terrorists launched a brutal, unprovoked attack from Gaza into Israel, killing more than 1,200 people, including at least 30 Americans, according to the Israeli military and the United States Department of State.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBC9B4C3690E04860AD1FCFD04299EACF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In the early morning hours of that day, Hamas forces stormed across the border, infiltrating Israeli towns and communities, slaughtering civilians, including women, children, and the elderly; ambushing music festival attendees; and attacking Israeli Defense Forces bases.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H365DBD679727467481081CFB97ACAAD8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>251 individuals were taken hostage during the attack, including 12 American citizens—some of whom were killed during abduction or later died while in captivity.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB3E1EF588F2D4DDEBA6CE659455FACD6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Among those kidnaped were children, seniors, and young adults, many of whom were dragged from their homes and communities to be held in brutal conditions inside Hamas’s labyrinth of tunnels underneath Gaza, in clear violation of international humanitarian law and the Geneva Conventions.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF55CA22CA5FE4C45BC012EAB11F0C0AA"><enum>(5)</enum><text>These hostages, including Americans, endured unspeakable conditions in captivity—denied medical care, isolated from their families, and endured psychological abuse during their imprisonment.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0A84F6C081884CE3B052C9A88D8A8856"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Despite the horror of that day, countless civilians and Israeli soldiers responded with extraordinary courage, risking and sacrificing their lives to protect others. First responders, community members, and soldiers fought valiantly to repel terrorists, rescue hostages, and save lives in neighborhoods under siege.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H68795ECB06614E2DB7C838B7BDB9C3C2"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Among those who fell that day or shortly thereafter were true heroes—civilians who shielded children, soldiers who died defending their comrades, and neighbors who gave their lives in acts of selfless bravery.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC52196486123490A8CE130A826FEDDC6"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The families of American hostages, both those who were freed and those who remain in captivity, have demonstrated relentless courage, resilience, and unity in advocating for their loved ones—exemplifying the best of the American spirit and values.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H329D60B3427047A99FF03A6FDB7B4992"><enum>(9)</enum><text>On May 12, 2025—584 days after the October 7 attacks—the final living American hostage was released from Hamas captivity.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H92161D53AC414C51892B482B646559E5"><enum>(10)</enum><text>As of the date of this resolution, hostages still remain in captivity, including 2 Americans. The United States Congress continues to call for their immediate and unconditional release.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H422E44E1EA2042758065E3B5874ADB6B"><enum>(11)</enum><text>The bravery of American hostages, the fallen, and their families deserves recognition by the Nation. Their suffering, sacrifice, and perseverance in the face of terrorism reflect the strength and resilience of the American people.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H2BB60E22221D44D98CFB1EF337C8C6D2"><enum>3.</enum><header>Congressional gold medal</header> <subsection id="HC861717C9F37498D8C87E0280C9F016D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Presentation authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President pro tempore of the Senate shall make appropriate arrangements for the presentation, on behalf of Congress, of a gold medal of appropriate design, to the American hostages and victims of the October 7th, 2023 attacks, in recognition of their profound suffering and sacrifice.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H41A22BFB75164E45ABC7D8FD070B036D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Design and striking</header><text>For purposes of the presentation referred to in subsection (a), the Secretary of the Treasury (referred to in this Act as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall strike a gold medal with suitable emblems, devices, and inscriptions, to be determined by the Secretary.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H4EE74F8408E54066A83F7AC7C520085A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Disposition of medals</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Following the award of the gold medal under subsection (a), the medal shall be displayed and made available for research, as appropriate, at the Weitzman National Museum of American Jewish History in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania.</text> </subsection></section> 
<section id="H1EAEF93B2FE84BFC8CB66A2D427FBDFC"><enum>4.</enum><header>Duplicate medals</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary may strike and sell duplicates in bronze of the gold medal struck pursuant to section 3, at a price sufficient to cover the cost thereof, including labor, materials, dies, use of machinery, and overhead expenses.</text></section> <section id="H8100BFF325C8448089DBCA6D88F36D25"><enum>5.</enum><header>Status of medals</header> <subsection id="H75676080A4404C21ACB4411E2ED684E8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>National medals</header><text>The medals struck pursuant to this Act are national medals for purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/51">chapter 51</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6AD78F2623FB4264827A524BF5DCA44B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Numismatic items</header><text>For purposes of sections 5134 and 5136 of title 31, United States Code, all medals struck under this Act shall be considered to be numismatic items.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H538199045D36490586737B01316F21FA"><enum>6.</enum><header>Authority to use fund amounts; proceeds of sale</header> <subsection id="H00F10FBD715E4F7F9E99A5E333C1CF9D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority To use fund amounts</header><text>There is authorized to be charged against the United States Mint Public Enterprise Fund such amounts as may be necessary to pay for the costs of the medals struck under this Act.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H38F27DC7685A4076AE2DC800EED93448"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Proceeds of sale</header><text>Amounts received from the sale of duplicate bronze medals authorized under section 4 shall be deposited into the United States Mint Public Enterprise Fund.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

