<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MDM25B94-244-7X-MHR"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1731 RS: Combating PRC Overseas and Unlawful Networked Threats through Enhanced Resilience Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><calendar>Calendar No. 96</calendar><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1731</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250513">May 13, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S423">Mr. Ricketts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S287">Mr. Cornyn</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S436">Ms. Slotkin</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00" added-display-style="italic" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><action stage="Reported-in-Senate"><action-date date="20250618">June 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Reported by <sponsor name-id="S323">Mr. Risch</sponsor>, with an amendment</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Secretary of State and the Secretary of Defense to develop a strategy in response to the global basing intentions of the People’s Republic of China.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one" changed="deleted" reported-display-style="strikethrough" committee-id="SSFR00"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short titles</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Combating PRC Overseas and Unlawful Networked Threats through Enhanced Resilience Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>COUNTER Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id190dabadc6a040699c291c56ee1ca0ed" changed="deleted" reported-display-style="strikethrough" committee-id="SSFR00"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">According to multiple sources, including the 2024 annual report to Congress, titled <quote>Military and Security Developments Involving the People’s Republic of China</quote> and known informally as the <quote>China Military Power Report</quote>—</text><paragraph id="id802c12d8a5e146afa21a2f1f4d8f921d"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the PRC is seeking to expand its overseas logistics and basing infrastructure to allow the PLA to project and sustain military power at greater distances;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide457efb1a0b4491f877d8d8ec03ee0bd"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a global PLA logistics network could disrupt United States military operations as the PRC’s global military objectives evolve; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd996ca28a4be4e39bcefa1f245dfd951"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in August 2017, the PRC officially opened the first overseas PLA military base near the commercial port of Doraleh in Djibouti;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8c0a1161e291421db574269d1b242efa"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in June 2022, the PRC and Cambodia hosted a ceremony to mark the groundbreaking on PRC-built upgrades to Ream Naval Base, including a joint logistics and training center and a pier to accommodate larger ships; </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0abbb1d2aa0845919598659005d24cc5"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">officials from Cambodia and the PRC officially inaugurated expanded port features at the Ream Naval Base in April 2025; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9027ea8e5e7943cd9b61c9c07aa74ea5"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in addition to the base in Djibouti and the PRC's access to the port at the Ream Naval Base in Cambodia, the PRC is likely pursuing access to additional military facilities to support naval, air, and ground forces projection in many countries, including Angola, Bangladesh, Burma, Cuba, Equatorial Guinea, Gabon, Indonesia, Kenya, Mozambique, Namibia, Nigeria, Pakistan, Papua New Guinea, Seychelles, Solomon Islands, Sri Lanka, Tajikistan, Tanzania, Thailand, and the United Arab Emirates. </text></paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="id345f65e13b614fcabc45875917c3a102" changed="deleted" reported-display-style="strikethrough" committee-id="SSFR00"><enum>3.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">While the executive branch has undertaken case-by-case efforts to forestall the establishment of new PRC bases in several countries, it is the sense of Congress that future efforts to counter the PRC's global basing intentions must—</text><paragraph id="id132ee296909d491092dbc99144f33aa9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>proceed with the urgency required to address the strategic implications of the PRC’s actions;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idda9911541baf4c9bb67b647ff4dfd351"><enum>(2)</enum><text>reflect sufficient interagency coordination with respect to a problem that necessitates a whole-of-government approach;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6f6917a86d5744a19ece2f6dbc65f656"><enum>(3)</enum><text>ensure that the United States Government maintains a proactive posture rather than a reactive posture in order to maximize strategic decision space;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1e781a02dbd546048decc6c49febea4c"><enum>(4)</enum><text>identify a comprehensive menu of actions that would be influential in shaping a partner’s decision making regarding giving the PRC military access to its sovereign territory;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd9ba5df299454dfe8329d88df70b2155"><enum>(5)</enum><text>appropriately prioritize the subject of the PRC's global basing intentions within the context of the overall United States strategic competition with the PRC;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id03fbd9a3cfb745ed84cb449c7f4796d8"><enum>(6)</enum><text>factor in the potential contributions of key allies and partners to help respond to the PRC's pursuit of global basing, many of which—</text><subparagraph id="id53495f6a22ca4f3ea2afa249026c5348"><enum>(A)</enum><text>have historic ties and influence in many of the geographic areas the PRC is targeting for potential future bases; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id920b6e0329c04e4da77d55a64240d878"><enum>(B)</enum><text>rely on the same basic intelligence picture to form our baseline understanding of the PRC’s global intentions;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idfe7e044375bc47c782ddd859996afeb7"><enum>(7)</enum><text>establish and ensure sufficient resourcing for enduring organizational structures to effectively address the issue of PRC global basing intentions; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc570f725266b483195a5c204bfe690f3"><enum>(8)</enum><text>ensure that future force posture, freedom of movement, and other interests of the United States and our allies are not jeopardized by the continued expansion of PRC bases.</text></paragraph></section><section id="ide8d4e7cd8900453286c4333937a441e5" changed="deleted" reported-display-style="strikethrough" committee-id="SSFR00"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2823af44ee8149988af22b83c1796b3b"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0bc90512f441494cb0f4e349a1580c54"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id798308a514e14f079f77ddd71dfa4c4f"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <committee-name committee-id="SSAS00">Committee on Armed Services of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf6f2c9c0c167416bb68623343d61b118"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <committee-name committee-id="SLIN00">Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id57ea11aa384344c289f12d94617d52d1"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <committee-name committee-id="SSAP00">Committee on Appropriations of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcfec0fe467874c7f8d6b6413e51cde5f"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id797ba95295304c24b5684ffc847163fb"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5d70a082b3fd406e9954c69435c029d0" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <committee-name committee-id="">Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives</committee-name>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5a545f371f7f47cfae62d2f808d9a773"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives</committee-name>. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id712d2c5104f14349adf95339f7b7673c"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">PLA</header><text>The term <term>PLA</term> means the People's Liberation Army of the PRC.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id721e0cb925124fe9841fee02d8481411"><enum>(3)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">PRC</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>PRC</term> means the People's Republic of China.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id036480a8a32940b3917dbb0a278452cb"><enum>(4)</enum><header>PRC global basing</header><text>The term <term>PRC global basing</term> means the establishment of physical locations outside the geographic boundaries of the PRC where the PRC maintains some element of the People’s Liberation Army, PRC intelligence or security forces, or infrastructure designed to support the presence of PRC military, intelligence, or security forces, for the purposes of potential power projection.</text></paragraph></section><section id="id86a7fdfad90c4a3aaaa390df88b8d296" changed="deleted" reported-display-style="strikethrough" committee-id="SSFR00"><enum>5.</enum><header>Assessment of executive branch's C–PRC global basing strategy</header><subsection id="idf383e4df39ab4727994ef41ce61392b9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Assessment</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of National Intelligence shall submit an intelligence assessment, in classified form, if needed, to the appropriate congressional committees. The assessment shall analyze the risk posed by PRC global basing to the United States or to any United States allies with respect to their ability to project power, maintain freedom of movement, and protect other interests as a function of the PRC's current or potential locations identified pursuant to subsection (b)(2)(A).</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id443e99e4dc5f48818f625563e607405b"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Strategy</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idce611bf4e0614444ba5e4b7d95b25d19"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State, in coordination with the Secretary of Defense and other appropriate senior Federal officials, shall submit a strategy to the appropriate congressional committees that contains the information described in paragraph (2).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1d25c32a6fcd40a1a3cc97cedf64123e"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The strategy required under paragraph (1) shall—</text><subparagraph id="id158ad71fa5e74fe9a20e275b8f959bed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identify not fewer than 5 locations of chief concern where the PRC maintains a physical presence, or is suspected to be seeking a physical presence, which could ultimately transition into a PRC global base;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb68a2d87808d45239804edd42c0a41f1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>include a comprehensive listing of executive branch entities currently involved in addressing aspects of PRC global basing, including any resource or personnel constraints limiting the ability to effectively address the issue of PRC global basing intentions;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9c94a507a3c749e1bd00d496aa1f4d4c"><enum>(C)</enum><text>describe in detail all executive branch efforts—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbe1b844d8db5469b8a613cee83fd7e24"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to mitigate the impacts of the locations referred to in subparagraph (A); or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddd131b32180343e194869cdae3c59d6c"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to prevent the PRC from establishing new global bases; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id106cc62a4d1148b69ff6ddb350e8569b"><enum>(D)</enum><text>for each of the locations referred to in subparagraph (A), identify the actions by the United States or its allies that would be most effective to enable the respective foreign governments to terminate plans for hosting a PRC base.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id500749d4b3c64f7283053d4a1c1d8189"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Task force</header><text>Not later than 90 days after submitting the strategy described in subsection (b), the Secretary of State, in coordination with the Secretary of Defense and other appropriate senior Federal officials, shall establish an interagency task force—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id435d25e19c86414c8acc1a51974398d7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to implement the strategy described in section (b) to counter the PRC’s efforts at the locations of chief concern; and </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaaccf71ccc1341a882bc905ab25dc1e6"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to identify mitigation measures that would prevent the PRC from establishing new bases in locations beyond the locations of chief concern identified pursuant to subsection (b)(2)(A).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8ff72615688644c5948bb22bc21ae4aa"><enum>(d)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Quadrennial reviews and reports</header><text>Not later than 4 years after the submission of the strategy required under subsection (b), and not less frequently than once every 4 years thereafter, the Secretary of State, in coordination with the Secretary of Defense, the Director of National Intelligence, and other appropriate senior Federal officials, shall—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5683a7ad7e2b494ead706c362b3b4cb4"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conduct a review of the Executive Branch’s strategy and overall approach in response to the PRC global basing intentions; and </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8351b24b3f7c454aaa655520eb1b11f3"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submit the results of such review, including the information described in subsection (b)(2), to the appropriate congressional committees.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body><legis-body display-enacting-clause="no-display-enacting-clause"><section id="idc4bc8179-d1a8-4b44-8a16-f0c78f462c8f" section-type="section-one" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="SSFR00"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short titles</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Combating PRC Overseas and Unlawful Networked Threats through Enhanced Resilience Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>COUNTER Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id4cb2c4ac-5695-4964-8d61-b552f3fdbd73" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="SSFR00"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">According to multiple sources, including the 2024 annual report to Congress, titled <quote>Military and Security Developments Involving the People’s Republic of China</quote> and known informally as the <quote>China Military Power Report</quote>—</text><paragraph id="id482d327b-4ab4-43da-9b09-7e651609ab98"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the PRC is seeking to expand its overseas logistics and basing infrastructure to allow the PLA to project and sustain military power at greater distances;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id98fe2b1c-eb20-4e71-a46a-feb1b545682b"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a global PLA logistics network could give the PRC increased capabilities to surveil or disrupt United States military operations; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida02f599b-60ee-4bd1-9954-193478d74147"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in August 2017, the PRC officially opened the first overseas PLA military base near the commercial port of Doraleh in Djibouti;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc1c98abe-3538-44e4-ad91-12d90ffa9368"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in 2019, the PRC also attempted to acquire strategically important port infrastructure at Subic Bay in the Philippines, but was stopped by the Governments of the United States, the Philippines, and Japan, and by private investors;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id731170a3cdcb40b1bd5a467964473967"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in April 2025, officials from the PRC and Cambodia officially inaugurated the China-Cambodia Ream Naval Base Joint Support and Training Center and celebrated the expansion of port facilities at Ream Naval Base, some of which appear to have been reserved for the use of PRC ships that have been continuously stationed at Ream Naval Base since December 2023; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ideb3abedc-6069-42c4-ae71-df879399bcfd"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in addition to the base in Djibouti and the PRC's access to the port at the Ream Naval Base in Cambodia, the PRC is likely pursuing access to additional military facilities to support naval, air, and ground forces projection in many countries. </text></paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="id59ceb9d1-9f9c-4efa-82f7-f6f76c2105a5" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="SSFR00"><enum>3.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">While the executive branch has undertaken case-by-case efforts to forestall the establishment of new PRC permanent military presence in several countries, it is the sense of Congress that future efforts to counter the PRC's global basing intentions must—</text><paragraph id="id7a9f7af2-adbf-4bb7-a574-940361c3a988"><enum>(1)</enum><text>proceed with the urgency required to address the strategic implications of the PRC’s actions;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd00a19f8-0214-41b8-b9eb-86ce6efcde9f"><enum>(2)</enum><text>reflect sufficient interagency coordination with respect to a problem that necessitates a whole-of-government approach;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id88062c8c-dc74-4137-9ebb-c002197a6273"><enum>(3)</enum><text>ensure that the United States Government maintains a proactive posture rather than a reactive posture in order to maximize strategic decision space;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7f800740-1f4b-4335-8c1c-c55f6e299204"><enum>(4)</enum><text>identify a comprehensive menu of actions that would be influential in shaping a partner’s decision making regarding giving the PRC military access to its sovereign territory;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd34c1d30-e394-4768-b757-ca4f6ade68e1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>appropriately prioritize the subject of the PRC's global basing intentions within the context of the overall United States strategic competition with the PRC;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id39822a47-592c-4f71-b6c7-9fdd6367bfa0"><enum>(6)</enum><text>consider how the PRC uses commercial and scientific cooperation as a guise for establishing access for the PLA and other PRC security forces in foreign countries;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id43f678add7484cc8a4e29375ce4490d2"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">factor in the potential contributions of key allies and partners to help respond to the PRC's pursuit of global basing, many of which—</text><subparagraph id="id4d0ea932-a7df-4781-ade6-4564df6180a7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>have historic ties and influence in many of the geographic areas the PRC is targeting for potential future bases; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id19d71438-0b00-467a-8867-46c2166273d2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>rely on the same basic intelligence picture to form our baseline understanding of the PRC’s global intentions;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id0d9d5738-90f2-4402-99d2-5e1f571d8469"><enum>(8)</enum><text>establish and ensure sufficient resourcing for enduring organizational structures and security and foreign assistance and cooperation efforts to effectively address the issue of PRC global basing intentions; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id06bfdd8f-0556-45f0-8b23-ababd2ab35ef"><enum>(9)</enum><text>ensure that future force posture, freedom of movement, and other interests of the United States and our allies are not jeopardized by the continued expansion of PRC bases.</text></paragraph></section><section id="id7b94e012-5683-4048-a63c-0243a931ea6b" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="SSFR00"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9bac6dd6-13c0-46a2-ace4-c935d0e326d9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id62a0a2b1-54ca-4852-b879-fc6efaaca02d"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4ea20be1-7863-4c83-a78a-997e978a49e2"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <committee-name committee-id="SSAS00">Committee on Armed Services of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0169dc70-2f47-49eb-b093-725bbafd4383"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <committee-name committee-id="SLIN00">Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idffd3cd7d-6af7-4d61-96dc-749bed67655e"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <committee-name committee-id="SSAP00">Committee on Appropriations of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id06318d58-c5fe-4e7e-9685-c25eb96007d3"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida6314781-22b6-44b5-941d-68c119ce23de"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ided6821a2-0de8-42aa-bea6-ee6eea7238bd" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <committee-name committee-id="">Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives</committee-name>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id71c7f15f-6ae6-4266-bdcf-c1ff1882422d"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives</committee-name>. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id907243c3-93b0-4a5e-addd-d9ddfc5b9fd5"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">PLA</header><text>The term <term>PLA</term> means the People's Liberation Army of the PRC.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddaf08e15-d808-47d1-bfed-152265f12d05"><enum>(3)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">PRC</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>PRC</term> means the People's Republic of China.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2840d556-ae43-4735-a8a6-47f989abf77a"><enum>(4)</enum><header>PRC global basing</header><text>The term <term>PRC global basing</term> means the establishment of physical locations outside the geographic boundaries of the PRC where the PRC maintains some element of the People’s Liberation Army, PRC intelligence or security forces, or infrastructure designed to support the presence of PRC military, intelligence, or security forces, for the purposes of potential power projection.</text></paragraph></section><section id="idd013813f-42a6-482b-81d6-f1c8da732719" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="SSFR00"><enum>5.</enum><header>Assessment of executive branch's C–PRC global basing strategy</header><subsection id="id1b8308fa-9ef7-4177-badf-9a629046b855"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Assessment</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of National Intelligence shall submit an intelligence assessment, in classified form, if needed, to the appropriate congressional committees. The assessment shall analyze the risk posed by PRC global basing to the United States or to any United States allies with respect to their ability to project power, maintain freedom of movement, and protect other interests as a function of the PRC's current or potential locations identified pursuant to subsection (b)(2)(A).</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc5609245-2ea8-4309-8314-2fdf29141364"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Strategy</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6ae687bb-ed43-4395-88d4-0f5a8d39e26a"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State, in coordination with the Secretary of Defense and other appropriate senior Federal officials, shall submit a strategy to the appropriate congressional committees that contains the information described in paragraph (2).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8856f9e2-45c4-4316-9fa7-78840aaa2fc7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The strategy required under paragraph (1) shall—</text><subparagraph id="id3a817616-5e27-48eb-8857-4136d83a3071"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identify not fewer than 5 locations that pose the greatest potential risks, as identified in the assessment required under subsection (a), where the PRC maintains a physical presence, or is suspected to be seeking a physical presence, which could ultimately transition into a PRC global base;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id863ba2f0-237d-462f-b219-5a8894b84c8c"><enum>(B)</enum><text>include a comprehensive listing of executive branch entities currently involved in addressing aspects of PRC global basing, including estimated programmatic and personal resource requirements on an agency-by-agency basis to effectively address the issue of PRC global basing intentions, and any relevant resource constraints;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id53d264a9-a418-44ce-bcca-526d908af9dd"><enum>(C)</enum><text>describe in detail all executive branch efforts to mitigate the impacts to the national interests of the United States and partner countries of the locations referred to in subparagraph (A) and prevent the PRC from establishing new global bases, including with resources described in subparagraph (B); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf42d247e-4eed-4fef-8844-7469ad14d6cb"><enum>(D)</enum><text>for each of the locations referred to in subparagraph (A), identify the actions by the United States or its allies that would be most effective in ensuring the respective foreign governments terminate plans for hosting a PRC base.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0e6030d3-056e-4d0b-abbd-5308086ac1c1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Task force</header><text>Not later than 90 days after submitting the strategy described in subsection (b), the Secretary of State, in coordination with the Secretary of Defense and other appropriate senior Federal officials, shall establish an interagency task force—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8e6e7b6c-ca3e-4076-9ecf-d4e653fb3617"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to implement the strategy described in section (b) to counter the PRC’s efforts at the locations of chief concern; and </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idef52a82d-0058-4596-87ea-029011037a7f"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to identify mitigation measures that would prevent the PRC from establishing new bases in locations beyond the locations of chief concern identified pursuant to subsection (b)(2)(A).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9f9f733b-e4a3-41f0-be03-aa9e351299d2"><enum>(d)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Quadrennial reviews and reports</header><text>Not later than 4 years after the submission of the strategy required under subsection (b), and not less frequently than once every 4 years thereafter, the Secretary of State, in coordination with the Secretary of Defense, the Director of National Intelligence, and other appropriate senior Federal officials, shall—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc7a52724-48bb-40a6-a47d-4553f9f07907"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conduct a review of the Executive Branch’s strategy and overall approach in response to the PRC global basing intentions; and </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6a069d77-6efd-4620-b478-c8773a86a9d0"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submit the results of such review, including the information described in subsection (b)(2), to the appropriate congressional committees.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body><endorsement><action-date date="20250618">June 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

