<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5B3A31C5150A4DCE94CA9A627E8E2974" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 219 IH: Improving Menopause Care for Veterans Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 219</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250107">January 7, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000601">Mr. Landsman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000617">Mrs. Ramirez</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001205">Ms. Scanlon</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Comptroller General of the United States to conduct a study on menopause care furnished by the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H223AF368B2F14A66A92DA6DDD5719486" style="OLC"><section id="H9511EA0E53A346BD8EA829881CF5AF68" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Improving Menopause Care for Veterans Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H0942F9EDA81E484B888A159E30E1C0B2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Comptroller General study and report on menopause care furnished by Department of Veterans Affairs</header><subsection id="H859C1D5FCD0A4D7382CBCE03764EFAC9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Comptroller General of the United States shall carry out a study on the medical services furnished by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs under sections 1703 and 1710 of title 38, United States Code, for veterans experiencing perimenopause, genitourinary syndrome of menopause, and menopause stages.</text></subsection><subsection id="H32FFC1F065F544FB89C3983AD0226519"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><paragraph id="H3FB65049E3A9484C9D32722D5D34C46B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General shall make publicly available a report on the study carried out under subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA0758ED3DF5C40C784A7B6DD8A2EA532"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report required under paragraph (1) shall include each of the following:</text><subparagraph id="H648AD247175C4FEDA2A2B2CFE3DC62BF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A description of the menopause care furnished by the Department of Veterans Affairs, as of the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H077F913D751B445184F91D211996C6FB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A review of the established guidelines and protocols of the Department of for—</text><clause id="HD13E34F5D9434209ABDE3FF3C0B76320"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the training of medical providers of the Department;</text></clause><clause id="H05126DBA5D9D4509B90E011D92D0147F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the diagnosis and treatment of perimenopause, genitourinary syndrome of menopause, and menopause in women veterans; and</text></clause><clause id="HF03275E0FC6C4753AC2FCB47FB1BFFE0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the referral of veterans seeking menopause care to non-Department medical providers.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFB09166272BF47C4ABBD7C05092608C7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>An evaluation of the adequacy of the access of veterans to interdisciplinary care to treat the effects of perimenopause, genitourinary syndrome of menopause, and menopause.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC07B1D28B37D4EDA8B8E9155BA22CAF2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A review of the educational initiatives and outreach of the Department to ensure that veterans are aware of the perimenopause, genitourinary syndrome of menopause, and menopause care available under sections 1703 and 1710 of title 38, United States Code, including treatment options and potential benefits and risks.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB9E172B91DB140BC9B6FDC0BFE66CC05"><enum>(E)</enum><text>An evaluation of the quality of menopause care provided under sections 1703 and 1710 of title 38, United States Code, including—</text><clause id="HA37E9CB7E3004BEC802F3B51D2087B33"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a review of feedback about menopause care collected from veterans;</text></clause><clause id="H691382FEFBF4424E92487127D0770F61"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an examination of the efficacy of the menopause care furnished by the Department; and</text></clause><clause id="HABCC2EC67FA54A6AAF38A8FAFA058E07"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>an evaluation of the extent to which the Department has established mechanisms for veterans to address and resolve any concerns or issues regarding menopause care.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H108E340A77CB4ABC95AFFA64D47D8E26"><enum>(F)</enum><text>A review of how, if at all, the Secretary is leveraging research, conducted within the Department or by other entities, to improve menopause care for veterans, including through the development of new treatments or protocols.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCAF59B9C1D4C476FA0C5A2956D86930E"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Recommendations for the improvement of the menopause care furnished by the Department.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HECB952DCAB2F4F87BF58C87DC0269611"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Plan To implement recommendations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 6 months after the date on which the Comptroller General makes the report required under subsection (b) publicly available, the Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and House of Representatives a strategic plan to—</text><paragraph id="HC300BA18DAE747248396C4C577E4BE5A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>implement the recommendations contained in the report;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAC3F8C794A1942FFBD5D26273BCF5708"><enum>(2)</enum><text>improve the quality of menopause care furnished under sections 1703 and 1710 of title 38, United States Code; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB2009C404E2F481C979D4B5C124D8CAA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>improve the access of veterans to menopause care.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

