<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3CF1A25B0A16467A90369ECE8E9DBFF4"
  public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
  <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4435 IH: Cosmetic Hazardous Ingredient Right to Know Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
    <distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
    <congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session display="yes">1st Session</session>
    <legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4435</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
    <action display="yes">
      <action-date date="20250716">July 16, 2025</action-date>
      <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor
          name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs.
          Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>,
          <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms.
          Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor
          name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson
          Coleman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the
          <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and
        Commerce</committee-name></action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
    <official-title display="yes">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to increase
      transparency with respect to cosmetic ingredients, and for other purposes.</official-title>
  </form>
  <legis-body id="H56B0F429BBB6499087EEAA0FF2E10F6C" style="OLC">
    <section id="HCE22D48837274342B0AED57D532FBFAB" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Cosmetic Hazardous Ingredient Right to Know Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text>
    </section>
    <section id="H2A6C12581EC944B3AA8947142EEBA1A7">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Cosmetic regulation</header>
      <subsection id="H4108D11CE9C44FA08D01CE566C428430">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Definition</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 201(i) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/321">21 U.S.C. 321(i)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following: <quote>Such term includes such an article that is intended for consumer sale or professional use (as defined in section 617).</quote>.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H7856BA2088514F76910ABB5095223C44">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Regulation</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Chapter VI of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/361">21 U.S.C. 361 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
        <paragraph id="H9E8D5A8B219C475BA11DEED58E03336A">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>by inserting before section 601 the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HC98EFF99F7EF48C680D49871043D0077" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subchapter id="H04638A358D634492A3CD5D35FBB10290"> <enum>A</enum> <header>Adulterated and Misbranded Cosmetics</header> </subchapter> <after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block> </quoted-block> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HA8D56E8BA93649C0AF387894BFB36906"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 602, by adding at the end the following:</text>
          <quoted-block style="traditional" id="HFE8ED579B4974727AFE072D91EA6498E"
            display-inline="no-display-inline">
            <subsection id="HE2A94AA63E5B4F11A3BBD3AB0E6FC362">
              <enum>(g)</enum>
 <text>If the fragrance and flavor ingredient information required to be disclosed pursuant to sections 615 and 616 is not disclosed in accordance with such sections.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H28BCD11532E843F89BB6CC3450C63BF2">
              <enum>(h)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If its packaging fails to include any fragrance or flavor ingredient present in such cosmetic or the website of the brand owner of such cosmetic fails to disclose any such fragrance or flavor ingredient.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H7AB8248E4B6649DB9C39795572A33D76">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the website of the brand owner of the cosmetic fails to include a link to the Uniform Resource Locator (referred to in this chapter as a <quote>URL</quote>) for any list specified in section 616(b) on which each ingredient present in such cosmetic appears.</text>
            </subsection>
            <after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block>
          </quoted-block>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HBB1E5B9571894F8BBB79C13C79E45407">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>in section 614, by amending subsection (b) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H11C2594CE282460F80E67A335BEC781D" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="HDA06EE2F59B44EDC982D662C424662CA"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Limitations</header> <paragraph id="HF2FB944E2F7641929BA25807B3B220F4"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding subsection (a), nothing in this section shall be construed to prevent any State (or a political subdivision thereof) from—</text>
                <subparagraph id="HF8F0F3DC5F6B4F7585C80AA4ED7E8997">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>prohibiting the use or limiting the amount of an ingredient in a cosmetic product;</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="HF10EAA02CDDA43A4B78B0C33CCD08280">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">continuing to implement a requirement of such State (or a political subdivision thereof) that is in effect at the time of enactment of the Modernization of Cosmetics Regulation Act of 2022 for the reporting to the State (or a political subdivision thereof) of an ingredient in a cosmetic product; or</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H6A40DE8E259A437588F286005065E2E9">
                  <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">implementing a requirement of such State (or a political subdivision thereof) that provides for greater transparency, disclosure, or protection with respect to a cosmetic ingredient than the requirements established under the amendments made by the <short-title>Cosmetic Hazardous Ingredient Right to Know Act of 2025</short-title> (or continuing to implement any such requirement that is in effect as of the date of the enactment of such Act).</text>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H570C7CEF75F249F483F3CCAD595D0641">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <header>Modernization of Cosmetics Regulation Act of 2022</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in the amendments to this Act made by the Modernization of Cosmetics Regulation Act of 2022 shall be construed to preempt any State statute, public initiative, referendum, regulation, or other State action, except as expressly provided in subsection (a). </text>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
          </quoted-block>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H4888BE6D109A45D7A1B00A31EED7C6A1">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H1B42D1BE90A14C76A17F739CF19173EA" style="OLC"> <subchapter id="H7D80F0382D4C44A3A669F703AA6F90C5"> <enum>B</enum> <header>Fragrances and Flavors</header> <section id="H96E2355CBFC74FFC846D103B30FE4031"> <enum>615.</enum> <header>Website disclosure of ingredients</header> <subsection id="HDAD3E27D0FC949A18A20AEC37F0E4967"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Effective beginning on the date that is 1 year after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Cosmetic Hazardous Ingredient Right to Know Act of 2025</short-title>, a brand owner shall disclose in an electronically readable format on the website of the brand owner, and make available to any relevant internet vendor, with respect to each cosmetic sold or offered for sale in interstate commerce by such brand owner, the following information:</text>
                  <paragraph id="H0277781B0A694EA9AAD71BF941477ABA">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A full listing of each ingredient present in such cosmetic, including each fragrance or flavor ingredient present in such cosmetic, in descending order of predominance.</text>
                  </paragraph>
                  <paragraph id="H00D6DC08BFAB40EEB52B2514B1F85AD5">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any ingredient present in such cosmetic, listed in descending order of predominance, followed by a link to the URL of any list under section 616(b) on which such ingredient appears. </text>
                  </paragraph>
                  <paragraph id="HF548A01119E04B36BFD9DF81E1BC57FC">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The functional purpose served by each such fragrance or flavor ingredient.</text>
                  </paragraph>
                  <paragraph id="HF03007058B1244859D53907D9F2D610C">
                    <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>A link to the hazard communication safety data sheet for any such cosmetic intended for professional use.</text>
                  </paragraph>
                </subsection>
                <subsection id="HB5D1E1255D8D4C148E6E3BE5CDAAA08E">
                  <enum>(b)</enum>
                  <header>Updates</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an update to any of the lists specified in subsection (b) or (c) of section 616 with respect to a cosmetic sold or offered for sale in interstate commerce by a brand owner, the brand owner shall revise the disclosure made under subsection (a) to reflect such update not later than 7 months after the date on which such update is formally noticed by the authoritative body who administers the list.</text>
                </subsection>
              </section>
              <section id="H517AC2EE921E41CABBB540864053AE02">
                <enum>616.</enum>
                <header>Cosmetic ingredient product label disclosure</header>
                <subsection id="HFBB4A616B69B43339EF43E9E94E6CD20">
                  <enum>(a)</enum>
                  <header>In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Effective beginning on the date that is 2 years after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Cosmetic Hazardous Ingredient Right to Know Act of 2025</short-title>, for purposes of section 602(h), the packaging or labeling of a cosmetic shall include—</text>
                  <paragraph id="H9EA24BA05920405AB18F831FB2BB8128">
                    <enum>(1) </enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A full listing of each ingredient present in such cosmetic (including each fragrance or flavor ingredient), listed in descending order of predominance.</text>
                  </paragraph>
                  <paragraph id="H63452B4A9E2E41B5825F2ABF95C15CB9">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a cosmetic in which any ingredient specified in subsection (b) is present, the following statement: <quote>For health impacts related to any ingredients in this product, visit: www.____.</quote>, with the uniform resource locator of the website of the brand owner placed in the blank space.</text>
                  </paragraph>
                </subsection>
                <subsection id="H90E74BA6E2C74EA1A38F9BDAE79EEFB1">
                  <enum>(b)</enum>
                  <header>Ingredients specified</header>
 <text>The ingredients specified in this subsection are the following chemicals (including chemicals included in any list specified in this subsection after the date of the enactment of this subchapter):</text>
                  <paragraph id="H004BA92B43A24AF9B0E7ED056D9081F3" commented="no">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>Chemicals for which a reference dose or reference concentration has been developed based on neurotoxicity in the Environmental Protection Agency’s Integrated Risk Information System.</text>
                  </paragraph>
                  <paragraph id="H8647DDE4946E4B958808E3766F898D1A" commented="no">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>Chemicals that are identified as carcinogenic to humans, likely to be carcinogenic to humans, or as group A, B1, or B2 carcinogens, in the Environmental Protection Agency’s Integrated Risk Information System.</text>
                  </paragraph>
                  <paragraph id="H78EB94A705424958815EB65C9EA44E1E" commented="no">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>Persistent, bioaccumulative, and toxic Priority Chemicals identified by the Environmental Protection Agency’s National Waste Minimization Program as of February 22, 2016.</text>
                  </paragraph>
                  <paragraph id="HD9602249F00846439AA7C4911C93FB26">
                    <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Chemicals that are identified in volumes 1 through 4 of the Reports on Human Exposure to Environmental Chemicals issued by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (and any updates to such reports).</text>
                  </paragraph>
                  <paragraph id="H282F97F2CF8B43008B9C8C4ABC06596D" commented="no">
                    <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Toxic pollutants listed under section 20 307(a)(1) of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act and priority pollutants identified in appendix A to part 423 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).</text>
                  </paragraph>
                  <paragraph id="HCCD25EC112E34A24A4770D4370AC8FC9" commented="no">
                    <enum>(6)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Chemicals classified as <quote>Persistent, Bioaccumulative and Toxic</quote> by the Toxics Release Inventory published by the Environmental Protection Agency pursuant to section 313 of the Emergency Planning and Community Right-to-Know Act of 1986.</text>
                  </paragraph>
                  <paragraph id="H2DCF8FFA4A004EFAB013B2102A3A0345" commented="no">
                    <enum>(7)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Chemicals that are identified in the Agency for Toxic Substances and Disease Registry’s Toxic Substances Portal.</text>
                  </paragraph>
                  <paragraph id="H862B615E4F84425F83B88B9580D18A56" commented="no">
                    <enum>(8)</enum>
 <text>Chemicals that are hazardous substances, as such term is defined in section 101(14) of the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980.</text>
                  </paragraph>
                  <paragraph id="H0338D0E13D8A46B2A1EB5A04A5246DAA">
                    <enum>(9)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Reproductive and developmental toxicants identified by monographs issued by the National Toxicology Program Center for the Evaluation of Risks to Human Reproduction.</text>
                  </paragraph>
                  <paragraph id="H1471637100684B8BA2DB3643EB6964E5">
                    <enum>(10)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Chemicals that are identified as known to be, or reasonably anticipated to be human carcinogens by the most recent Report on Carcinogens prepared by the National Toxicology Program pursuant to section 301(b)(4) of the Public Health Service Act.</text>
                  </paragraph>
                  <paragraph id="H22BF6EAC0A8745F6B3F5A9B0E2799FD7">
                    <enum>(11)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Chemicals identified as persistent, bioaccumulative, and toxic (PBT) chemicals by the Department of Ecology of the State of Washington (WAC 173–333 (2006)).</text>
                  </paragraph>
                  <paragraph id="H34F9D11F4B374C7FBAA2224336E95EEF" commented="no">
                    <enum>(12)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Chemicals specified in Chapter 6.6 of the California Safe Drinking Water and Toxic Enforcement Act of 1986 (sections 25249.5 through 25249.14 of the California Health and Safety Code), List of Reproductive and Developmental Toxicants and Carcinogens.</text>
                  </paragraph>
                  <paragraph id="HB86F7269FBDB43968688B17FC7CE3815" commented="no">
                    <enum>(13)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Chemicals for which primary maximum contaminant levels have been established and adopted under section 64431, 64444, or 64444.5 of division 22 of title 26 of the California Code of Regulations and chemicals for which notification levels, as defined in section 116455 of the California Health and Safety Code, have been established by the California State Water Resources Control Board.</text>
                  </paragraph>
                  <paragraph id="HD8652D8CEFC243FCB32FD15717DA01B0" commented="no">
                    <enum>(14)</enum>
 <text>Chemicals identified as toxic air contaminants under section 93000 or 93001 of title 17 of the California Code of Regulations.</text>
                  </paragraph>
                  <paragraph id="HA22B17ED896A493B96B123347A1E96F6">
                    <enum>(15)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Substances classified as carcinogens, mutagens or reproductive toxicants in Appendices 1 through 6 of Annex XVII to Regulation (EC) No. 1907/2006 of the European Union’s Registration, Evaluation, Authorisation and Restriction of Chemicals (REACH) law, as revised by the Commission Regulation (EU) 2020/2096 of 15 December 2020.</text>
                  </paragraph>
                  <paragraph id="H1301C3C561DD4E06B2061075B6C96563">
                    <enum>(16)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Chemicals included in the European Union Candidate List of Substances of Very High Concern in accordance with Article 59 of the REACH Regulation (EC) No. 1907/2006 on the basis of fulfilling the criteria defined in Article 57(f) for endocrine disrupting properties.</text>
                  </paragraph>
                  <paragraph id="HF4F11A67976B473CACEA2D980FD030E7">
                    <enum>(17)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Chemicals included in such European Chemicals Agency Candidate List of Substances of Very High Concern on the basis of fulfilling the criteria defined in Article 57(d), Article 57(e), or Article 57(f) for persistent, bioaccumulative and toxic, or very persistent and very bioaccumulative, properties.</text>
                  </paragraph>
                  <paragraph id="H5DFA13358AB241489D34DC9B42449C06">
                    <enum>(18)</enum>
 <text>Chemicals classified by the European Union in Annex VI to Regulation (EC) No. 1272/2008 as respiratory sensitizer category 1.</text>
                  </paragraph>
                  <paragraph id="H5B1E433360C44999A7D34A5466E2AF5F">
                    <enum>(19)</enum>
 <text>Chemicals that are identified as persistent, bioaccumulative, and inherently toxic to the environment by the Canadian Environmental Protection Act Environmental Registry Domestic Substances List pursuant to subsection 66(1) of the Canadian Environmental Protection Act, 1999.</text>
                  </paragraph>
                  <paragraph id="HDE125F12A99A469CBF5572BFA6CE5858">
                    <enum>(20)</enum>
 <text>Group 1, 2A, or 2B carcinogens identified by the International Agency for Research on Cancer of the World Health Organization.</text>
                  </paragraph>
                  <paragraph id="HA88F846B500C419083CC3567EE3CD9AA">
                    <enum>(21)</enum>
 <text>Chemicals that are identified on Part A of the list of Chemicals for Priority Action prepared by the Oslo and Paris Conventions for the Protection of the Marine Environment of the North-East Atlantic.</text>
                  </paragraph>
                  <paragraph id="H2DAA8366FAAC48C191C82B0153B357E5" commented="no">
                    <enum>(22)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Chemicals that are skin sensitizers and irritants classified by Regulation (EC) No 1272/2008 of the European Parliament and of the Council of 16 December 2008 on classification, labelling and packaging of substances and mixtures, amending and repealing Directives 67/548/EEC and 1999/45/EC, and amending Regulation (EC) No 1907/2006.</text>
                  </paragraph>
                </subsection>
                <subsection id="HDE57504EE6D442C0BC1A3BDE901812FE">
                  <enum>(c)</enum>
                  <header>Master list</header>
                  <paragraph id="HD848288B8476428BB0892CC83F39720B">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                    <header>In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 6 months after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Cosmetic Hazardous Ingredient Right to Know Act of 2025</short-title>, the Secretary shall—</text>
                    <subparagraph id="H296A8DAC7DF1413E8A3DFB0D88FF099F">
                      <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>establish a master list of the chemicals that appear on the lists specified in subsections (b) and (c);</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H3C59E84EDF384EC2AF40525708E93E30">
                      <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>post such master list on a publicly available website of the Food and Drug Administration; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H81774EE4261648399241FFB934CC7CBF">
                      <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>establish a voluntary electronic distribution list to which cosmetic manufacturers and other interested parties may subscribe to receive a copy of the master list and any subsequent updates.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                  </paragraph>
                  <paragraph id="HBA5610A601D44A4D9726E4D5A1D253D2">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Updates</header>
                    <subparagraph id="H23C5CA748758434F8304387829427DAC">
                      <enum>(A)</enum>
                      <header>In general</header>
 <text>The Secretary shall maintain the master list established under paragraph (1) and make updates to such list as necessary.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="HD8F0FE9B95C141B78AA5DBE360651089">
                      <enum>(B)</enum>
                      <header>Notification</header>
 <text>Not later than 30 days after making an update pursuant to subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall notify subscribers to the electronic distribution list referred to in paragraph (1)(C) of that update.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H396E439F85F34FB19499EAACCEB28B19">
                      <enum>(C)</enum>
                      <header>Semi-annual updates</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not less frequently than twice per year, the Secretary shall publish on a publicly available website of the Food and Drug Administration a list of updates to the master list made during the preceding 6-month period that includes summaries of any chemicals added to or removed from the lists specified in subsections (b) and (c).</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                  </paragraph>
                </subsection>
              </section>
              <section id="H3C10E33AD45E4715B966FB524C4CB1C5">
                <enum>617.</enum>
                <header>Definitions</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this subchapter:</text> <paragraph id="HB9316A93A73444DE8A2ABC7703FF362E"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>Brand owner</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>brand owner</term> means the entity responsible for bringing a cosmetic to market for retail consumer sale or professional use.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H8DC67C8BBF9B49638969A3C07DFF4316">
                  <enum>(2)</enum>
                  <header>Electronically readable format</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>electronically readable format</term> means, with respect to information, that the information provided—</text>
                  <subparagraph id="H209BA547CB5746CD876E6CD19A2A2331">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>is machine readable by automated systems, including, web browsers, accessibility software to aid the disabled, automated scripts, and other software programs or applications;</text>
                  </subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="H890EDA79771A44EFB28C43E240382885">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>is not restricted from access by search engines;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF3DDAEED1F004A898A4891A10AF21FCD"> <enum>(C)</enum> <text>is not restricted from access by a requirement for registration, the provision of personally identifiable information, or the use of CAPTCHA or similar challenge response test technologies, whether visual, auditory, or otherwise; and</text>
                  </subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="H53ED9CC1166D4DBEB882543E731D4792">
                    <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>conforms to the most current version of the Web Content Accessibility Guidelines adopted by the Web Content Accessibility Guidelines Working Group of the World Wide Web Consortium.</text>
                  </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H73B6E4241AB64C1694DE7FA793849A39">
                  <enum>(3)</enum>
                  <header>Flavor ingredient</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>flavor ingredient</term> means, with respect to a cosmetic, any intentionally added substance or complex mixture of aroma chemicals, flavor chemicals, natural essential oils, and other functional ingredient or ingredients, including the constituent ingredients of botanicals, for which the purpose is to impart a flavor or taste, or to counteract a flavor or taste.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H2A27EBCAED67436A8AAF3BC2D23E4990">
                  <enum>(4)</enum>
                  <header>Fragrance ingredient</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>fragrance ingredient</term> means, with respect to a cosmetic, any intentionally added substance or complex mixture of aroma chemicals, natural essential oils, and other functional ingredient or ingredients for which the purpose is to impart an odor or scent, or to counteract an odor.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H6C885968731D4FB693C03E9EC4FCB9C2">
                  <enum>(5)</enum>
                  <header>Ingredient</header>
 <text>The term <term>ingredient</term> means a chemical in a cosmetic, including—</text>
                  <subparagraph id="H086F89EADE7943BC910405EA10C7DFBC">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>a chemical that has a technical or functional effect in the cosmetic, including the breakdown products of an intentionally added chemical that also have a functional or technical effect in the cosmetic;</text>
                  </subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="H49A98D98C6A24BF3A3CCA17E6E27746E">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>a substance that is present by reason of having been added to a cosmetic during processing for the substance’s technical or functional effect;</text>
                  </subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="H9A09F203C8164DD6B1487BCD376C87F7">
                    <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>a fragrance, flavor, preservative, or colorant (and the components thereof); and</text>
                  </subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="H19FA20E1E7604980BBFEFA67325F5C0B">
                    <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>any individual component that the Secretary deems to be an ingredient for purposes of this subchapter.</text>
                  </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H1DB19DB8A0CC4687A8732D69CE67FCA4">
                  <enum>(6)</enum>
                  <header>Professional use</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>professional use</term> means—</text>
                  <subparagraph id="H0D0324D69651401CBE2D8472461AAB95">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>the application of a cosmetic to a human customer or client that is intended only for use by an employee or contractor, in settings such as cosmetology, nail care, barbering, esthetics, spa, and other professions as determined by the Secretary through regulation; or</text>
                  </subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="H9ED09D4441CE44E0BE9B96EB54C5EC81">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the use by, or application to, a human of a cosmetic purchased from a hair salon, nail salon, beauty salon, spa, or other establishment that provides cosmetic treatment services for humans.</text>
                  </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
              </section>
            </subchapter>
            <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
          </quoted-block>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>


