<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-KEL25265-PDX-DK-TLG">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1717 IS: Ensuring Patient Access to Critical Breakthrough Products Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>II</distribution-code>
        <congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session>1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. 1717</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action>
            <action-date date="20250512">May 12, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S391">Mr. Young</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was
                read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on
                    Finance</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title>To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to ensure prompt coverage of
            breakthrough devices under the Medicare program, and for other
            purposes.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause">
        <section section-type="section-one" id="S1">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Ensuring Patient Access to Critical Breakthrough Products Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section section-type="subsequent-section" id="H8675688E49334E448D6B40E5E0D342A0">
            <enum>2.</enum>
            <header>Ensuring prompt coverage of breakthrough devices under the Medicare
                program</header>
            <subsection id="HD77826AC3BED42AB90880994B456D1AA">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>Ensuring coverage through a transitional coverage period</header>
                <paragraph id="H796B10067BFF4F4F8C06D0FEE113078D">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                    <header>In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1862(a)(1) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395y">42 U.S.C. 1395y(a)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
                    <subparagraph id="H5C22F7D452934E84B6173DCE6CA2BD47">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>in subparagraph (O), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H17371F2629BE417C8C4A966CDC16B4F3"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>in subparagraph (P), by striking the semicolon at the end and inserting <quote>, and</quote>; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H096C4261BD3B49A29BB4EAE846746DB9">
                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>by inserting after subparagraph (P) the following new subparagraph:</text>
                        <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H05D5D9DDE8094AE4A1AD1F3B14166836">
                            <subparagraph id="HC04CAE926B8F4F30A5315266B523CE99" indent="up1">
                                <enum>(Q)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a breakthrough device (as defined in section 1861(nnn)) furnished during the transitional coverage period (as so defined) with respect to such device, which is not furnished in accordance with the Food and Drug Administration-approved labeling for such device or that the Secretary determines, based on a review of clinical data, presents an undue risk of harm that outweighs the potential clinical benefits for individuals entitled to benefits under part A or enrolled under part B;</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
                        </quoted-block>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H63C6055531734B2D9F4092D9AC16938A">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Definitions</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1861 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
                    <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDA855459763F4D068A4CDDBBCD3E3AAF">
                        <subsection id="HE979481592734D1CADDFBD8AC05CC94A">
                            <enum>(nnn)</enum>
                            <header>Breakthrough device</header>
                            <paragraph id="H67335890CE374B36B4C3B933364767C1">
                                <enum>(1)</enum>
                                <header>In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>breakthrough device</quote> means a device so designated by the Secretary under section 1899C.</text>
                            </paragraph>
                            <paragraph id="H7D0891210713443CBCC57D613227081D">
                                <enum>(2)</enum>
                                <header>Transitional coverage period</header>
 <text>The term <quote>transitional coverage period</quote> means, with respect to a breakthrough device, the 4-year period that begins on the date that such device is so designated by the Secretary under section 1899C.</text>
                            </paragraph>
                        </subsection>
                        <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
                    </quoted-block>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H7B0D665072704E9E8E0AF5C2A9F9AFCA">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
                    <header>Breakthrough device determinations</header>
 <text>Part E of title XVIII of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
                    <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H88528130D5554CB5998307AEF37960DC">
                        <section id="HE6299405C76248069E84C7F4608593DC">
                            <enum>1899C.</enum>
                            <header>Designation of breakthrough devices</header>
                            <subsection id="H59D82025103B4BC6AE5C5635DF10710D">
                                <enum>(a)</enum>
                                <header>In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning 18 months after the date of the enactment of this section, upon application of a manufacturer of a device (as defined in section 201 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act) that is cleared, classified, or approved under section 510(k), 513(f)(2), or 515 of such Act on or after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary shall designate such device as a breakthrough device if the Secretary determines that such device meets the criteria specified in subsection (b).</text>
                            </subsection>
                            <subsection id="H46AB5806CD7F4E1C88D235335E904356">
                                <enum>(b)</enum>
                                <header>Criteria</header>
 <text>For purposes of subsection (a), the criteria specified in this subsection is, with respect to a device, that the device is provided with priority review pursuant to section 515B of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act.</text>
                            </subsection>
                            <subsection id="H1FF41B82A2014A2CB5F74A1F12AA4691">
                                <enum>(c)</enum>
                                <header>Determination process</header>
                                <paragraph id="HE5A18872DD514193A1B22DD69EF3CFCE">
                                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                                    <header>In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall make a determination with respect to a device that is the subject of an application described in subsection (a) not later than 6 months after such application is submitted to the Secretary.</text>
                                </paragraph>
                                <paragraph id="HB57692C6A3B048ED841ABE8B640E2D83">
                                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                                    <header>Explanation required in case of determination that
                                        device does not meet criteria for designation</header>
 <text>In the case that the Secretary determines that a device that is the subject of an application described in subsection (a) does not meet the criteria specified in subsection (b), the Secretary shall notify the manufacturer of such device of such determination and include in such notification an explanation identifying the specific criterion or criteria that such device failed to meet.</text>
                                </paragraph>
                            </subsection>
                            <subsection id="H16BCBFD8B2AA47CAB66901E8CA495C42">
                                <enum>(d)</enum>
                                <header>Reports</header>
 <text>The Secretary shall submit to Congress on an annual basis a report specifying—</text>
                                <paragraph id="H7D193F97D84D471E9AAECB3182D87228">
                                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>the number of applications received under this section during such year;</text>
                                </paragraph>
                                <paragraph id="H6359D2E9941C4C27AAF40D9B459C2DC6">
                                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>the number of devices designated as breakthrough devices under this section during such year; and</text>
                                </paragraph>
                                <paragraph id="H8A868D2EFA4B4702BA02CD9ECA4AE9EE">
                                    <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of applications for a designation for a device under this section with respect to which the Secretary determined that such device did not meet the criteria specified in subsection (b) during such year.</text>
                                </paragraph>
                            </subsection>
                        </section>
                        <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
                    </quoted-block>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection commented="no" id="HCD73E0C12943460EA8326FDF68200DD5">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Ensuring issuance of national coverage determination during transition
                    period</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1862(l)(2) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395y">42 U.S.C. 1395y(l)(2)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new flush sentence:</text>
                <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC30F7FF267BE4BDFAF4ACA604A5289A1">
                    <quoted-block-continuation-text quoted-block-continuation-text-level="paragraph">In the case of a request for a national coverage determination with respect
                        to a breakthrough device (as defined in section 1861(nnn)), the Secretary
                        shall ensure that a final decision is made on such request prior to the end
                        of the transitional coverage period (as so defined) for such device if such
                        request was submitted to the Secretary before the date that is 9 months (or
                        12 months, in the case such request is a request to which subparagraph (B)
                        applies) before the last day of such
                        period.</quoted-block-continuation-text>
                    <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
                </quoted-block>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H4105A3577A07477F8255E20A9BB07425">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Funding</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to amounts otherwise available, there are appropriated to the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services Program Management Account, out of any monies in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2031, to remain available until expended, to carry out the amendments made by this section.</text>
            </subsection>
        </section>
    </legis-body>
</bill>

