<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ROS25B84-D3D-8S-9G6"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2193 IS: Expanding Access to Military Child Care Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code>II</distribution-code> 
<congress>119th CONGRESS</congress> <session>1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>S. 2193</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20250626" legis-day="20250624">June 26 (legislative day, June 24), 2025</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S376">Ms. Ernst</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To establish a pilot program to expand early child care options for members of the Armed Forces and their families.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HE1E1B6D0281C4007B10A4409106E19E4"> 
<section id="id0cf59d3681ab4246a7df3c5a9c6a712c" section-type="section-one"> <enum>1.</enum> <header>Short title</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Expanding Access to Military Child Care Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section section-type="subsequent-section" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide1d4ba5ee78a4433888584a038fd7459"> <enum>2.</enum> <header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Pilot program to expand early child care options for members of the Armed Forces and their families</header> <subsection id="id89b2858fb8ce4498af981c29ee829cd6"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>Pilot program</header> <paragraph id="idce89ee516d8240bb9ef62a10f44ff5de"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text>The Secretary of Defense shall direct the Secretaries of the military departments to carry out a pilot program to improve the access of members of the Armed Forces and their families to high quality early child care opportunities by establishing partnerships with eligible child care providers—</text> 
<subparagraph id="idb01746440aff4279b8aa13758718368f"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>to increase the capacity of those providers;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id5ab1f72523984d68bccdf9a27a23a11b"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>to improve early child care workforce development; and</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="id315c19262daf47f28cb3d851e7880e16"> <enum>(C)</enum> <text>to increase recruitment and retention of employees for eligible child care providers.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="id3ad98c1401f8403b9665785f47841d87"> <enum>(2)</enum> <header>Selection of eligible child care providers and networks of such providers</header> <subparagraph id="id8f1f32e19ee94250b998442466642cd2"> <enum>(A)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text>Under the pilot program required by paragraph (1), the Secretary shall direct the Secretaries of the military departments to enter into a total of 12 partnerships with eligible child care providers, or networks of such providers, to, in communities under the jurisdiction of such Secretaries—</text> 
<clause id="id0d2bc7e5850f4d4caa2bb83d1fed1b38"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>increase the number of early child care slots available to members of the Armed Forces and their families;</text> </clause> <clause id="id6bd78f931f334f01a3b18ec42ecf2dc1"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>facilitate recruitment and retention of employees for eligible child care providers; and</text> </clause> 
<clause id="idca46685e54ad4c05ae6c7a4c2cb15e80"> <enum>(iii)</enum> <text>provide additional professional development opportunities for such employees.</text> </clause> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idaff348e814aa4c559a4850b6098b58cd"> <enum>(B)</enum> <header>Limitation</header> <text>The Secretary may direct the Secretaries of the military departments to enter into not more than one partnership with each eligible child care provider, or network of such providers, under the pilot program required by paragraph (1).</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="id1f2c4f667ec34de2ba7d4dec5cd7efe3"> <enum>(C)</enum> <header>Locations</header> <text>In selecting eligible child care providers or networks of such providers with which to enter into partnerships under the pilot program required by paragraph (1), the Secretary—</text> <clause id="id6c15d9bbedd84fa5ab86782f3c4e0df9"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>shall direct the Secretaries of the military departments—</text> 
<subclause id="id152ed312441a40aa8083cd360ce61d28"> <enum>(I)</enum> <text>to ensure that—</text> <item id="id7b80bad4d37c4380a3e150f4ec843de9"> <enum>(aa)</enum> <text>each partnership is based at a different military installation; and</text> </item> 
<item id="id9023196685c34f6bbe3119d241b3d228"> <enum>(bb)</enum> <text>at least one partnership is based at—</text> <subitem id="id8d65caebae204c02989b6cd5b812ce25"> <enum>(AA)</enum> <text>a Navy installation that is not a Marine Corps installation;</text> </subitem> 
<subitem id="id73b52967d712444fb53bae208970bf6e"> <enum>(BB)</enum> <text>a Marine Corps installation;</text> </subitem> <subitem id="id350f23db61754b24a1fcff57780047e9"> <enum>(CC)</enum> <text>an Army installation;</text> </subitem> 
<subitem id="id1c80829e99ab44dcbadbec6618143334"> <enum>(DD)</enum> <text>an Air Force installation that is not a Space Force installation;</text> </subitem> <subitem id="id746507beea4b46f7ae21eda09f9048b1"> <enum>(EE)</enum> <text>a Space Force installation; and</text> </subitem> 
<subitem id="id8880e89deebe4ba9ac8496dd503167ad"> <enum>(FF)</enum> <text>a joint military installation; and</text> </subitem> </item> </subclause> <subclause id="idaa6d75607def42c482669dd2b48e7da7"> <enum>(II)</enum> <text>to consider—</text> 
<item id="id94d5de0dd4ec40a78e29b9939442923f"> <enum>(aa)</enum> <text>geographic diversity and population demographics to reflect the inclusion of multiple communities across the United States;</text> </item> <item id="id27a0a296286e4477aac1a8713f225282"> <enum>(bb)</enum> <text>the appropriate qualifications, consistent with Department of Defense regulations and training requirements and under applicable State and local laws, to provide services to meet the needs of eligible children; and</text> </item> 
<item id="idf936debd824149c79ca6bddc70197261"> <enum>(cc)</enum> <text>existing resources available to the eligible child care providers or networks of such providers to train and support employees for eligible child care providers; and</text> </item> </subclause> </clause> <clause id="id10e9637bfc5b421ebf8e38c23d140f0e"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>may authorize the Secretaries of the military departments to establish partnerships in communities near military installations with military child development centers or other existing early child care programs of the Department of Defense, including the Military Child Care in Your Neighborhood program.</text> </clause> </subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="id1d25b9b447b1444cafcb1e50b98b77e2"> <enum>(3)</enum> <header>Authorized functions</header> <text>In carrying out the pilot program required by paragraph (1), the Secretary may—</text> <subparagraph id="idc11a7a7eda2446f9a350e3d7b6aa6957"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>direct the Secretaries of the military departments—</text> 
<clause id="id127c6f8b7311480aa17d827f174c30e2"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>to identify gaps between existing early child care needs and available eligible child care providers in communities where such Secretaries are considering establishing the pilot program;</text> </clause> <clause id="id599d915866be4b44b9a634baf217f741"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>to use resources of the Department of Defense to support eligible child care providers in recruitment and retention of employees, including military spouses, including through professional development and financial incentives for such employees; and</text> </clause> 
<clause id="id07bca85b74a0415a8279c56b5bca2e68"> <enum>(iii)</enum> <text>to seek to enter into an interagency partnership with a Federal agency with the ability to place national service participants and volunteers trained in education services, including senior volunteer programs, at military child development centers, including such a center at an installation selected for a partnership under paragraph (2)(C), in accordance with applicable national service laws and with all the benefits accorded to such participants and volunteers; and</text> </clause> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idea305242bcf64a409300e0962a0c1073"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>provide training and resource subsidies to eligible child care providers and networks of such providers participating in partnerships established under paragraph (2).</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="ide1e52f54d7e84a9389aa755221b38fe6"> <enum>(4)</enum> <header>Requirements for participating providers</header> 
<subparagraph id="id7ee6eb178cbe4ef28f44b1196e158aa8"> <enum>(A)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text>An eligible child care provider or network of such providers participating in a partnership established under the pilot program required by paragraph (1) is required—</text> <clause id="id1a4573e9f4a44fa0b02b4bf71669e36e"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>to provide assurances that the provider or network will not—</text> 
<subclause id="id776554f36ffb4b1d9de1b211a9dde9ef"> <enum>(I)</enum> <text>reduce early child care slots for nonmilitary families after entering into the partnership; or</text> </subclause> <subclause id="idabb03137f05f461eac7943194a747d71"> <enum>(II)</enum> <text>enter into the construction of new child care facilities; and</text> </subclause> </clause> 
<clause id="id3b20ae1efcd3499b817c2d95f07587b1"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>not later than 150 days after the establishment of the partnership, and every 180 days thereafter while the partnership continues, to submit documentation to the Secretary that the provider has complied with such assurances.</text> </clause> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id4fa8c3ba89774ba1bc44194c02758baa"> <enum>(B)</enum> <header>Assessments</header> <text>Not later than 180 days after the pilot program commences under subparagraph (A)(i) of paragraph (8), and every 180 days thereafter until the pilot program terminates under that subsection, the Secretary shall—</text> 
<clause id="id8b69f4fa65e14602a1db396d30e728f9"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>assess whether each eligible child care provider or network of such providers with which the Secretary of a military department entered into a partnership under paragraph (2)—</text> <subclause id="id2d9aedb3417d47ada3ecd9eac420ff67"> <enum>(I)</enum> <text>is providing the assurances required by clause (i) of subparagraph (A); and</text> </subclause> 
<subclause id="id4acbe56f695f43e392f8662f0ff5bfa2"> <enum>(II)</enum> <text>has submitted adequate documentation under clause (ii) of that subparagraph of compliance with such assurances; and</text> </subclause> </clause> <clause id="id99cf72622bca4badaafc7182ad80f5ef"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>if the Secretary determines that the provider or network of providers is not providing such assurances or has not submitted adequate documentation of compliance with such assurances—</text> 
<subclause id="id7e5f1ff70b5b4e469af6d8e8f66a4b0e"> <enum>(I)</enum> <text>notify the provider or network that the provider or network has 90 days to comply with the assurances; and</text> </subclause> <subclause id="id4a44c39593c244dcae2a3f25f797cbc6"> <enum>(II)</enum> <text>if the provider or network does not comply with the assurances during that 90-day period, terminate the partnership.</text> </subclause> </clause> </subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="ide7ae35ec660340b3b444425ddeea50dd"> <enum>(5)</enum> <header>Location of pilot program</header> <text>The Secretary shall direct the Secretaries of the military departments to ensure that, pursuant to a partnership entered into under the pilot program required by paragraph (1), the program is administered at or near the site of the eligible child care provider or network of such providers with which the Secretary entered into the partnership at or near a military installation.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="idda601eb21ebf4cda88f8a7368e86c385"> <enum>(6)</enum> <header>Administration</header> <text>Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall direct the Secretaries of the military departments to develop one centralized administrative system to carry out the pilot program required by paragraph (1), which may include information on—</text> 
<subparagraph id="id47c0ef2bcaa34846a3d1a66d5562a9a5"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>available military child development centers at military installations at which partnerships are established under the pilot program;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id899cb848c43445cda628134e016af735"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>the number of early child care education slots available or needed at such installations;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="iddb669133ea244a1d829f241ff4b93fc3"> <enum>(C)</enum> <text>the fees and costs associated for parents participating in the pilot program; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id53e6ef66e56148d1bb6748e2a2540b88"> <enum>(D)</enum> <text>other relevant administration and technical assistance matters.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="id86aa8024938e44668b32e8281c34e42d"> <enum>(7)</enum> <header>Reporting requirements</header> 
<subparagraph id="id02f6acccce314b9cb67120be42395d9f"> <enum>(A)</enum> <header>Briefings by Secretary of defense</header> 
<clause id="id62431c20e39f4ffc8fc0cf588ec00d38"> <enum>(i)</enum> <header>Initial briefing</header> <text>Not later than 180 days after the pilot program required by paragraph (1) commences under paragraph (8)(A)(i), the Secretary shall direct the Secretaries of the military departments to provide a briefing to the appropriate committees of Congress on the implementation of the pilot program, including—</text> <subclause id="ide4d86c71fe614fc6801a2fc64743440c"> <enum>(I)</enum> <text>the demonstrated need for eligible child care providers in the locations of the pilot program, including—</text> 
<item id="id3579b21a0cc1490a997ee08f37c5fbd6"> <enum>(aa)</enum> <text>the number of such providers present at the start of the pilot program relative to the number of eligible children requiring care; and</text> </item> <item id="idef7fd28326ac437dad21a7eaf044134f"> <enum>(bb)</enum> <text>data on children served through the pilot program, disaggregated by criteria such as—</text> 
<subitem id="id8b6308fc9dcd403bb23c1a7458783c80"> <enum>(AA)</enum> <text>the number of infants and toddlers served;</text> </subitem> <subitem id="id521a8f56c56c4eef91764fef31270ad3"> <enum>(BB)</enum> <text>providers offering early child care during nontraditional or extended hours;</text> </subitem> 
<subitem id="id4e84e420b59b4b52860df8a46616b5ef"> <enum>(CC)</enum> <text>early child care in rural communities; and</text> </subitem> <subitem id="id25c9b94400aa4baa9b386b47a3ff1934"> <enum>(DD)</enum> <text>inclusive early child care services for children with disabilities;</text> </subitem> </item> </subclause> 
<subclause id="idb185e52129fb46edbdfc4a55640ae09d"> <enum>(II)</enum> <text>the change in the number of eligible child care providers as a result of the pilot program;</text> </subclause> <subclause id="id38c992102eec4631bcd00e4c29ad114e"> <enum>(III)</enum> <text>the change in early child care education capacity for members of the Armed Forces and their families and an assessment of unmet need for such education;</text> </subclause> 
<subclause id="idac5b5f7ce13847b8b475d9261150d6c6"> <enum>(IV)</enum> <text>an assessment of the efficacy of the pilot program; and</text> </subclause> <subclause id="id8911a418986c4c8a8ebc7f74c50592f3"> <enum>(V)</enum> <text>an assessment of the compliance of child care providers participating in partnerships established under the pilot program with the assurances required by paragraph (4)(A).</text> </subclause> </clause> 
<clause id="id6c7aa5eddc15432d90efbb8ce62632e4"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <header>Annual briefings on progress</header> <text>Not later than one year after the pilot program required by paragraph (1) commences under paragraph (8)(A)(i), and annually thereafter until the termination of the pilot program under paragraph (8), the Secretary shall direct the Secretaries of the military departments to provide a briefing to the appropriate committees of Congress on the progress of the pilot program.</text> </clause> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id8a4defb48e874b3a988e957974c35a86"> <enum>(B)</enum> <header>Final report by Secretary of defense</header> <text>Not later than 120 days after the termination under paragraph (8) of the pilot program required by paragraph (1), the Secretary shall direct the Secretaries of the military departments to submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a final report on the pilot program.</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idbf33ca46dd444348b30d9723fd62a9e0"> <enum>(C)</enum> <header>Reports by government accountability office</header> 
<clause id="id626aa6cf629c47f18564ac2306a9d91d"> <enum>(i)</enum> <header>Progress report</header> <text>Not later than 4 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress an interim report on the progress of the pilot program required by paragraph (1).</text> </clause> <clause id="ide79615afda3d47b19d7b3e298b0aa201"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <header>Final report</header> <text>Not later than 120 days after the termination under paragraph (8) of the pilot program required by paragraph (1), the Comptroller General shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a final report on the pilot program.</text> </clause> </subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="id8d4f537dfb874f62a9e1a3add039f820"> <enum>(8)</enum> <header>Duration of pilot program</header> 
<subparagraph id="id97466948e46c4968a3e90e249c49072b"> <enum>(A)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text>The pilot program required by paragraph (1) shall—</text> <clause id="id1f0bbad6a676426f96dc88dd3da94781"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>commence not later than January 1, 2026; and</text> </clause> 
<clause id="id146f45a1b9674d5c9f08adfae11582d7"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>unless extended in accordance with subparagraph (B), terminate on December 31, 2030.</text> </clause> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id29341c41c8664c20b12048b92058d7ce"> <enum>(B)</enum> <header>Extension</header> <text>The Secretary may direct the Secretaries of the military departments to extend the pilot program required by paragraph (1) to terminate not later than December 31, 2032, if the Secretary notifies the appropriate committees of Congress not later than June 30, 2030, of the intention of the Secretary to extend the pilot program, along with a description of the benefits of extending the pilot program.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="ida8631641e96d425baefc381a6bdae1f7"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Report on unmet need for child care in areas with significant populations of members of the armed forces</header> 
<paragraph id="idcc74a2da45a44213931c5ee59ec79f07"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text>Not later than September 30, 2027, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report on the unmet need for child care in areas with populations of members of the Armed Forces that includes—</text> <subparagraph id="id11235a44d4404c22987676adb8cc04d4"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>a description of—</text> 
<clause id="id8eb75fb58be04afcaeb28992515aa1f8"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>the unmet need for each military installation; and</text> </clause> <clause id="id05d8b5856056454a805e5e33b1ba4fa9"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>the fees and costs for parents or guardians seeking child care in those areas;</text> </clause> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="id398959fa66714cc49eae681c6a0e152b"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>a review of the efforts of the Department of Defense to recruit and retain eligible child care providers; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id3722a3bdb8f94438b884030f0a23d318"> <enum>(C)</enum> <text>a plan for meeting the unmet need for child care.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="idd16c7b0d96934155a5bbb0e14c7226a6"> <enum>(2)</enum> <header>Assessment of child care in civilian communities</header> <text>In assessing the unmet need described in paragraph (1), the Secretary shall assess—</text> <subparagraph id="id52dc3bb17f214430a79ee8b2f86b6ba5"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>the availability of child care in civilian communities surrounding military installations; and</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idf79223db8df94c41823d6dcbd84d43e3"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>opportunities to provide additional professional development opportunities to eligible child care providers serving both civilian and military families in child care centers.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="id48b3ae28af774e99b3f248660a3b6b56"> <enum>(3)</enum> <header>Use and inclusion of data</header> <text>The Secretary shall use in preparing the report required by paragraph (1), and shall include in the report, for each military installation, data on the number of members of the Armed Forces living on and off the installation with children under the age of 5, disaggregated by—</text> 
<subparagraph id="id2372f0893bfa4121a40769e5058bd224"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>the ZIP Code for the location where the members reside; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id836f9df076684cb28ad78374da88d1a7"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>household status of the members, including—</text> 
<clause id="id2a06e4d1ee464219a02cdb793f13ad45"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>the number of parents and guardians present in the household;</text> </clause> <clause id="id0aae4768a0704a7eafe8b817f3bfa2cd"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>the work status of the parents and guardians; and</text> </clause> 
<clause id="idd78e5f0952aa43ee8c1526d797b299cd"> <enum>(iii)</enum> <text>the total number of children under the age of 5 in the household.</text> </clause> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="iddeea75fb20e748008e4c8bd05df94e96"> <enum>(4)</enum> <header>Collaboration</header> <text>In preparing the report required by paragraph (1), the Secretary shall consider collaborating with a nongovernmental organization with—</text> 
<subparagraph id="id644471ba112a491faa51c75be3d1d348"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>access to, and a strong understanding of, State licensing systems for child care; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id0d57a01e8b1f4e66afdcc0d769951f10" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>a proven track record of working with States to map child care gaps utilizing a distance-based methodology.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="id746c66d8ac734048906d8962c10bf570"> <enum>(c)</enum> <header>Definitions</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> <paragraph id="ide522bfeef74846b081a95a56a03857eb"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>Appropriate committees of congress</header> <text>The term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="idfee8af2f85a743d1b075ac908ac98040"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idabb219a75db9446382395765aaff3f5e"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="id8151cde16893473480df907b7e637ccf"> <enum>(2)</enum> <header>Child care employee</header> <text>The term <term>child care employee</term> has the meaning given that term in section 1800 of title 10, United States Code.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="id7dbd1c6097f74f00be68763c9ccfaa06"> <enum>(3)</enum> <header>Eligible child</header> <text>The term <term>eligible child</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="id92ed6c2aa45640ed9e6ba15073982286"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>an infant or toddler;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id225f8a44cf7f4395a78eb85459a99442"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>a three- or four-year-old; or</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idca6cc882674b466393e0875fadda728f"> <enum>(C)</enum> <text>a school-aged child.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="idc0ba89e60a5b4533878202e1081903de"> <enum>(4)</enum> <header>Eligible child care provider</header> <text>The term <term>eligible child care provider</term> has the meaning given that term in section 658P of the Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9858n">42 U.S.C. 9858n</external-xref>).</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="id1cb7a8940467414690aeebc63c05e037" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <enum>(5)</enum> <header>Military child development center</header> <text>The term <term>military child development center</term> has the meaning given that term in section 1800 of title 10, United States Code.</text> </paragraph> </subsection> </section> </legis-body> </bill> 

