<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-BIN25109-G1X-RL-TW8"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 328 ATS: Congratulating Louisiana State University in Shreveport for the first undefeated season in collegiate baseball history and for winning the 2025 National Association of Intercollegiate Athletics Baseball World Series.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 328</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250721">July 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S389">Mr. Kennedy</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S373">Mr. Cassidy</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Congratulating Louisiana State University in Shreveport for the first undefeated season in collegiate baseball history and for winning the 2025 National Association of Intercollegiate Athletics Baseball World Series.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, on May 30, 2025, the Louisiana State University Shreveport (referred to in this preamble as <quote>LSU Shreveport</quote>) baseball team won the championship of the National Association of Intercollegiate Athletics, held annually at Harris Field in Lewiston, Idaho, among the top 46 teams in the Association;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas LSU Shreveport defeated Southeastern University, of Florida, in the championship game with a score of 13–7, capturing the first national title in program history in any sport;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Pilots of LSU Shreveport celebrate a historic season with an undefeated record of 59 wins and 0 losses, becoming the first team in college baseball history to achieve a perfect season;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Pilots broke the record for winning percentage in the National Association of Intercollegiate Athletics of .935, set in 1996 by Mount Vernon Nazarene University, of Ohio;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the success of the team was the result of outstanding contributions from the entire roster, including standout performances by the Most Valuable Player of the tournament, Isaac Rohde, with a 2.09 earned run average, .93 walks and hits per innings pitched, and 107 strikeouts;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas pitcher Isaac Rohde was named the Most Valuable Player of the tournament;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas outfielder Cooper Huspen was named the Hustle Award recipient for the tournament;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas infielder Jose Sallorin was named the Golden Glove Award winner;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas head coach Brad Neffendorf was named Perfect Game Coach of the Year of the National Association of Intercollegiate Athletics and is in his 6th season as head coach of the LSU Shreveport baseball team; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Pilots of LSU Shreveport demonstrated extraordinary skill, consistency, and resilience throughout the season, bringing great pride and recognition to—</text><paragraph id="id7d5e23b105d94a6b8ca5b351eb6a1321"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Louisiana State University Shreveport;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id58d34cb746b145eba79afbd9c00f202b"><enum>(2)</enum><text>its students, faculty, alumni, and fans; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf28cf89fbd8b4bf5bfd05e9ad4493a68"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the entire State of Louisiana: Now, therefore, be it</text></paragraph></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="ide481f415a0d7490b9b4b2182daee84a4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>congratulates Louisiana State University Shreveport and the Pilots baseball team, including the athletes and coaching staff, for completing an undefeated 59–0 season and winning the 2025 National Association of Intercollegiate Athletics World Series National Championship;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0c5e12ff6dd440459f4ca69f38243ffd"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes Louisiana State University Shreveport for its continued commitment to academic and athletic excellence; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd762bd7f5c974cf5a2f2b23aa664c6ed"><enum>(3)</enum><text>respectfully requests that the Secretary of the Senate transmit an enrolled copy of this resolution to—</text><subparagraph id="id811e5db30d8241659b752bfea8ac5716"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Chancellor of Louisiana State University Shreveport, Dr. Robert Smith;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8c888e743651425c8c1413a5e680abc5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Director of Athletics, Lucas Morgan; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idec065fef48254947b335711a915bc4f9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Head Coach of the Pilots of Louisiana State University Shreveport baseball team, Brad Neffendorf.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

