<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7A66CE518FEE48E1BCF518D0AEBA19FE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5569 IH: Preventing and Identifying Lasting Operational TBI Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5569</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250926">September 26, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001121">Mr. Crow</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="L000603">Mr. Luttrell</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Defense to submit to Congress a report on traumatic brain injuries among certain pilots serving on active duty.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H25C607FC74564CAAB2F2CFF0D0757450" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H602D876EF9624778ADCFFDE8F65FA613" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Preventing and Identifying Lasting Operational TBI Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>PILOT Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HECF95BFA5CE54F2FB4C24B73F5AAAFEE" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Report on traumatic brain injuries among certain pilots serving on active duty</header> 
<subsection id="H596D2F913E7D48488AB269CFF9F8DA38"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report that contains a study determining whether, and to what extent, members of the Armed Forces serving on active duty as pilots suffer from traumatic brain injury resulting from the cumulative effects of high-speed maneuvers, catapult launches, and other repetitive actions potentially harmful to brain health as a result of such service.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HB188ABAB4EEE430A85AF3D9469DF8742"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Matters included</header><text>The report under subsection (a) shall include the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HB62443DBDDDF46A7844A3DADADFD9188"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The results of the study under subsection (a).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB5EA495CAD0B4EA698F711B9E3E98D4E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A summary of existing policies and procedures of the Department of Defense, as of the date of the report, for identifying, documenting, and treating mild, moderate, and severe traumatic brain injury among pilots.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC07312D3DB7A4C30B90BBCBB93795858"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A strategy to better identify, document, and treat mild, moderate, and severe traumatic brain injury among pilots.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9BC49F19E99C4D0A996E597C141FA29B"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Recommendations of the Secretary with respect to potential regulatory and legislative actions to address challenges in identifying, documenting, and treating mild, moderate, and severe traumatic brain injury among pilots.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

