<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-KAT25131-PS3-F4-M4X"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S550 IS: To provide for the equitable settlement of certain Indian land disputes regarding land in Illinois, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 550</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250212">February 12, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S419">Mr. Mullin</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SLIA00">Committee on Indian Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To provide for the equitable settlement of certain Indian land disputes regarding land in Illinois, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="idC4991C26E5AA43D29CBACDD2F24965D2"><enum>1.</enum><header>Settlement of claims</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcdab611747a14a1786c4023aa4139d10"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Jurisdiction conferred on the United States Court of Federal Claims</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id14436521b8c84afbb0fec32949a3b87f"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the United States Court of Federal Claims shall have jurisdiction to hear, determine, and render judgment on a land claim of the Miami Tribe of Oklahoma under its Treaty with the United States of America signed at Grouseland August 21, 1805 (7 Stat. 91) (commonly known as the <quote>Treaty of Grouseland</quote>), without regard to the statute of limitations, including section 2501 of title 28, United States Code, and any delay-based defense, no matter how characterized.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8c091f9959994cb797d9476fad13fc38"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Jurisdiction expiration</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the jurisdiction conferred to the United States Court of Federal Claims under paragraph (1) shall expire unless the Miami Tribe of Oklahoma files a land claim under that paragraph.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id296d7d7b20fa41749f3c5d93f5fb5e32"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Extinguishment of title and claims</header><text>Except for a claim filed under subsection (a)(1), all other claims, including any and all future claims, of the Miami Tribe of Oklahoma, or any member, descendant, or predecessor in interest to the Miami Tribe of Oklahoma, to land in the State of Illinois are extinguished.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

