<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H22B76CA8034B4DCDBB8EB933F6E714A9" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4481 IH: Accelerate Revenue for Manufacturing and Sales Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4481</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250717">July 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="A000055">Mr. Aderholt</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001217">Mr. Moskowitz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="Z000018">Mr. Zinke</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Arms Export Control Act to modify the authorities relating to the Special Defense Acquisition Fund.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H2EE9D73CC9CD48B4A146F6E04480C710" style="OLC">
<section id="H408734635E1F4AE18185A56029F8AC84" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Accelerate Revenue for Manufacturing and Sales Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>ARMS Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H332BFBEAB777433AB57E5D63B768275D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
<paragraph id="H100DAD4F2F5F45549FCB561A9366CE9D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The United States defense industrial base plays a critical role in advancing both security and prosperity.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H47821AA856FA4AE1A07E9A6367732FC2"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>There is increasing global demand for United States manufactured defense capabilities, highlighting the need to maintain a strong, agile, and scalable defense production capacity.</text>
            </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1D46D7F6E25940E9844C85662B03AFD5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In recent years, the combined value of Foreign Military Sales (FMS) and Direct Commercial Sales (DCS) has significantly exceeded domestic defense procurement budgets, with international demand for United States defense products approaching two-to-one over domestic acquisition.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3606CF06191B41839DA2A65DA1854DF0"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Delays in delivering defense articles to allied and partner nations expose vulnerabilities in the current acquisition and sales process that risks undermining United States strategic credibility abroad.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H216AF19E075541A0BCB5DD28F22FFD17"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Special Defense Acquisition Fund (SDAF) has demonstrated effectiveness in reducing delivery times and enabling advanced contracting for high-demand defense items prior to the completion of formal agreements.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H86AE1FAD1C0446E8B883FE288C373D24"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Strengthening and expanding the SDAF would increase the efficiency and predictability of defense article deliveries to foreign partners, support the United States defense industrial base, and improve economies of scale.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4C4646F723794BBABDAC28E63AE5E016"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Timely access to United States defense systems by allies and partners strengthens interoperability, improves coalition readiness, deters shared threats, and reinforces long-standing strategic relationships.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6B081A695985420D99C9BA28CDDF672E"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Enhancing SDAF authorities and capacity aligns with United States national interests and supports continued leadership in the global defense market.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H93FB0F1D9A7D48E0B12C1640AB0F4244" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Modifications to Special Defense Acquisition Fund</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 51(b)(1) of the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2795">22 U.S.C. 2795(b)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>sales made under</quote> and all that follows through <quote>the actual value</quote> and inserting <quote>sales</quote>.</text></section> </legis-body></bill>

