<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HAD16DFD29EA04C64BCF526E359F6A839" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-joint" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HJ 87 IH: Providing congressional disapproval under chapter 8 of title 5, United States Code, of the rule submitted by the Environmental Protection Agency relating to “California State Motor Vehicle and Engine Pollution Control Standards; Heavy-Duty Vehicle and Engine Emission Warranty and Maintenance Provisions; Advanced Clean Trucks; Zero Emission Airport Shuttle; Zero-Emission Power Train Certification; Waiver of Preemption; Notice of Decision”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IA</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. J. RES. 87</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250402">April 2, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000307">Mr. James</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="J000302">Mr. Joyce of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000469">Mr. Fulcher</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000019">Mr. Obernolte</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000401">Mr. Kiley of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000578">Mr. LaMalfa</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001136">Mrs. McClain</cosponsor>) submitted the following joint resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>JOINT RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Providing congressional disapproval under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/8">chapter 8</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, of the rule submitted by the Environmental Protection Agency relating to <quote>California State Motor Vehicle and Engine Pollution Control Standards; Heavy-Duty Vehicle and Engine Emission Warranty and Maintenance Provisions; Advanced Clean Trucks; Zero Emission Airport Shuttle; Zero-Emission Power Train Certification; Waiver of Preemption; Notice of Decision</quote>.</official-title></form><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HEA5D6A606B93427AB5652F8E503AF571"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H9F5993B3C01A41309186764685171BD4"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That Congress disapproves the rule submitted by the Environmental Protection Agency relating to <quote>California State Motor Vehicle and Engine Pollution Control Standards; Heavy-Duty Vehicle and Engine Emission Warranty and Maintenance Provisions; Advanced Clean Trucks; Zero Emission Airport Shuttle; Zero-Emission Power Train Certification; Waiver of Preemption; Notice of Decision</quote> (88 Fed. Reg. 20688 (April 6, 2023)), and such rule shall have no force or effect.</text></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

