<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-KEL25659-N8D-2X-TS8">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2830 IS: Wellness and Education for Longer Lives for Seniors Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>II</distribution-code>
        <congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session>1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. 2830</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action>
            <action-date date="20250917" legis-day="20250916">September 17 (legislative day,
                September 16), 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S363">Mr. King</sponsor> introduced the following bill;
                which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title>To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to improve the annual
            wellness visit under the Medicare program.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H7D82746E35754AE1B526E0BD70039201">
        <section section-type="section-one" id="S1">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Wellness and Education for Longer Lives for Seniors Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>WELL Seniors Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section id="id9ffa1232db4e4a469ca484f25d73011e">
            <enum>2.</enum>
            <header>Improvements to the Medicare annual wellness visit</header>
            <subsection id="iddf8ad37e0f964dfb9b088347526d12b9">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>Additional elements</header>
                <paragraph id="id1f03520a0dc047d5898c7903db482f8a">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                    <header>In general</header>
 <text>Section 1861(hhh)(2) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x(hhh)(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
                    <subparagraph id="idb36b463bd20248cea4a9ba074f74b07c">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>in subparagraph (F), by striking <quote>and nutrition</quote> and inserting <quote>nutrition, mobility, food security, housing security, transportation access, social support, and other social determinants of health as determined by the Secretary</quote>;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="idf7b3dd2e92de42b1b1df49caa697476f">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>by moving subparagraphs (G) and (H) 2 ems to the left;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idc137440e801d4e57bd523de354bfafcd"> <enum>(C)</enum> <text>by redesignating subparagraph (I) as subparagraph (J); and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="ida5e37ec6094e46fea7de9dafc0e48cc0">
                        <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>by inserting after subparagraph (H) the following new subparagraph:</text>
                        <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id56637972a3d3413ea89df16623e237c7">
                            <subparagraph id="id1e91df4f4d854208b4e311e345e43622" indent="up1">
                                <enum>(I)</enum>
 <text>Screening for balance to identify risk for falls and referral for treatment as appropriate.</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
                        </quoted-block>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id0a70d5d21d09485fb17e81c6cf586107">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Effective date</header>
 <text>The amendments made by paragraph (1) shall apply to items and services furnished on or after January 1, 2026.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id30f2cfb2d4944d73bddf617079735c3c">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Incentive payments</header>
 <text>Section 1833 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395l">42 U.S.C. 1395l</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
                <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id216c349053164c2388dc4b70e585c665">
                    <subsection id="id3153399459cf430dbff8729edc0dffb2">
                        <enum>(ee)</enum>
                        <header>Incentive payments for annual wellness visits that include certain
                            elements</header>
                        <paragraph id="idc98aadaaa99f4e8c919f27396bf6533e">
                            <enum>(1)</enum>
                            <header>In general</header>
 <text>In the case of personalized prevention plan services (as defined in paragraph (1) of section 1861(hhh)) that are furnished on or after January 1, 2026, and that include the element described in subparagraph (F) of paragraph (2) of such section 1861(hhh) and at least 2 additional elements described in subparagraphs (A) through (E) and (G) through (J) of such paragraph (2), in addition to the amount of payment that would otherwise be made for such personalized prevention plan services under this part, there also shall be paid an amount equal to 10 percent of the payment amount for the service under this part.</text>
                        </paragraph>
                        <paragraph id="id4faf0c33baa54f8f8648c358fa94fd98">
                            <enum>(2)</enum>
                            <header>Coordination with other payments</header>
 <text>The amount of the additional payment for a service under this subsection and subsection (m) shall be determined without regard to any additional payment for the service under subsection (m) and this subsection, respectively. The amount of the additional payment for a service under this subsection and subsection (z) shall be determined without regard to any additional payment for the service under subsection (z) and this subsection, respectively.</text>
                        </paragraph>
                    </subsection>
                    <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
                </quoted-block>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="idb1dcfe1122a045988f95f93c81b3e991">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Education and outreach</header>
                <paragraph id="id4e0aa6623b26438ebcbb02b4a80f937c">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                    <header>In general</header>
 <text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services (in this section referred to as the <term>Secretary</term>) shall conduct education and outreach activities regarding the coverage of annual wellness visits under the Medicare program, including changes to such visits under the amendments made by subsections (a) and (b).</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4ff5fe40aa594ba787b5a74dff8d88bd">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>National outreach campaign</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall conduct a national outreach campaign to educate beneficiaries on the annual wellness visit under the Medicare program. In conducting such outreach campaign, the Secretary may prioritize education and outreach to low-income beneficiaries, non-physician providers, and to providers working and beneficiaries living in rural areas or health professional shortage areas.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id86ae2a6071504df587f4aa14c4beb9a1">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
                    <header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
 <text>There is authorized to be appropriated for fiscal years 2026 through 2030 such sums as may be necessary to carry out this subsection.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection commented="no" id="idf18a42bf13fa4ff8a14c16df6928b456">
                <enum>(d)</enum>
                <header>Inclusion as telehealth service</header>
 <text>Section 1834(m)(4)(F)(i) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395m">42 U.S.C. 1395m(m)(4)(F)(i)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new sentence: <quote>Such term includes, with respect to telehealth services furnished on or after January 1, 2026, an annual wellness visit (as defined in section 1861(hhh)).</quote></text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="idca628406f8ba49078f70cc2af5bee049">
                <enum>(e)</enum>
                <header>Provider eligibility</header>
                <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id94ad6e26a98c4938b4f3d7844d3983cb">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                    <header>In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1861(hhh)(3) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x(hhh)(3)</external-xref>) is amended:</text>
                    <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id230e1f1606174c248976c864f0bb0be8">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end of subparagraph (B);</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id7dbdc0b631aa4ae0a05b90d1765f77b8"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>by redesignating subparagraph (C) as subparagraph (D); and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id93467321fc294a66bbd9fa567e100af7">
                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>by inserting after subparagraph (B) the following new subparagraph:</text>
                        <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id32174C13A1F04A27833A48C4575E35CC">
                            <subparagraph id="id906c067f9d1b459a81c3e6b7444b9a6b" indent="up1">
                                <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>a physical therapist, an occupational therapist, or a pharmacist; or</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
                        </quoted-block>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida4cd42c18ba347aaa445a8b2dde18a0d">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Effective date</header>
 <text>The amendments made by paragraph (1) shall apply to items and services furnished on or after January 1, 2026.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="idcae04a5078964bd4b180ab0ab9799128">
                <enum>(f)</enum>
                <header>Guidance revision</header>
 <text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall issue guidance amending section 410.15 of title 42, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation), to include guidance on processes, oversight, and standards for the post-visit follow-up to ensure consistency and compliance with the Health Risk Assessment, personalized prevention plan, and referrals.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="idbe62eab6e006459f8eaa4b238f33a43e">
                <enum>(g)</enum>
                <header>Research and evaluation</header>
                <paragraph id="id21f78b3edb2445edb017773cb085b87f">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                    <header>Report</header>
                    <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0f3b4a903e82490aac8272bad541223b">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
                        <header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header>
 <text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary, acting through the Administrator of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (in this subsection referred to as the <term>Administrator</term>), shall analyze and publish a report on the prevalence in use of the annual wellness visit (as defined in section 1861(hhh) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x(hhh)</external-xref>)) by Medicare beneficiaries, including current practices and recommendations for increasing the use and effectiveness of the annual wellness visit under the Medicare program under title XVIII of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395">42 U.S.C. 1395 et seq.</external-xref>). Such report shall include—</text>
                        <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaf777992f30348a69dbc629778eaa617">
                            <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information regarding the interviews conducted under subparagraph (B);</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7c435af0cbe84e76a86875d8ec6e2605">
                            <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>data on the prevalence of annual wellness visits furnished to Medicare beneficiaries via telehealth during the COVID–19 public health emergency; and</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbf1a6e083f784c319b6141c1f5ca05a7">
                            <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>utilization and claims data for annual wellness visits over the preceding 10 years broken down by State, demographic groups (including age, race, ethnicity, income, and education), the type of provider furnishing the annual wellness visit, and whether the beneficiary is enrolled for benefits under the original Medicare-fee-for-service program under parts A and B of title XVIII of the Social Security Act or the Medicare Advantage program under part C of title XVIII of the Social Security Act.</text>
                        </clause>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide19276e82d8749a7b277f0b31dd40508">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
                        <header>Interviews with stakeholders</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall conduct interviews with stakeholders, including provider groups, on their concerns regarding billing for and using the annual wellness visit under the Medicare program, including whether and to what extent personalized prevention plan services and appropriate referrals and follow-up are taking place for beneficiaries who are at particular risk and which referral models are most effective.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id4795ae6c7be44675b04203e8fb109d03">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Focus group study</header>
 <text>Not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary, acting through the Administrator, shall conduct a focus group study among providers, community-based organizations, and beneficiaries towards increasing use of the annual wellness visit by Medicare beneficiaries. The Secretary shall work with beneficiary and stakeholder groups to develop the interview questions for such focus group study, and shall include questions on—</text>
                    <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcd2879c48850407ba830ba96bf7a9632">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">improving referrals to community services;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id47e9a65f68aa408e93f6136052a79122">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">barriers to utilization and recommendations to increase uptake; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idae08f3ce3adf49aa995f53a47cd852a7">
                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the types of providers in practices that furnish the visits.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id0f43aa3c687841b59dff4d137bb5a262">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
                    <header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
 <text>There is authorized to be appropriated for fiscal years 2026 through 2030 such sums as may be necessary to carry out this subsection.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
        </section>
    </legis-body>
</bill>

