<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC517FD3A233E455B986214F12E878CA9" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 837 IH: To require the Secretary of Agriculture to convey the Pleasant Valley Ranger District Administrative Site to Gila County, Arizona.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 837</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250131">January 31, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001132">Mr. Crane</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Agriculture to convey the Pleasant Valley Ranger District Administrative Site to Gila County, Arizona.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD839DBFC501D4780BAF99525CA3E71F9" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="H18C563B68E63480FA7F1B79A7212CC9F"><enum>1.</enum><header>Conveyance of Pleasant Valley Ranger District Administrative Site to Gila County, Arizona</header><subsection id="HD03D80593A614901BC9B1E6956AE1704"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H8FD5EE03DF714F8CAB9C2060C9B9A772"><enum>(1)</enum><header>County</header><text>The term <term>County</term> means Gila County, Arizona.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3BA950ACF93B4403910FCEA61EC11E94"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Map</header><text>The term <term>map</term> means the map entitled <quote>Pleasant Valley Admin Site Proposal</quote> and dated September 23, 2021.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFA14EA694C994A3AA0819769EB037072"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Chief of the Forest Service.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBE22FE3A8207463C9EEF6B15DB0CDA73"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conveyance required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to this section, if the County submits to the Secretary a written request for conveyance of the property described in subsection (c) not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall convey to the County all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to the property described in subsection (c).</text></subsection><subsection id="HD3B2702C6C8647B9BDE71189FDEDAE51"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Description of property</header><paragraph id="H5636DF1F46D14B2BA3F51707157DD082"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The property referred to in subsection (b) is the parcel of real property, including all land and improvements, generally depicted as <quote>Gila County Area</quote> on the map, consisting of approximately 232.9 acres of National Forest System land located in the Tonto National Forest in Arizona.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9F835F7A746949B687E127BE4F4CA460"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Map</header><subparagraph id="H399C6AA527DE4ACBB8BA5B24ABB05A0B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Minor errors</header><text>The Secretary may correct minor errors in the map.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD5011F782465430FA0EE0D090A535159"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>A copy of the map shall be on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of the Forest Service.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAFC5C651DCF34B8FA28DFA4598540D67"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Survey</header><text>The exact acreage and legal description of the National Forest System land to be conveyed under subsection (b) shall be determined by a survey satisfactory to the Secretary. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5857AA68D22C4F309F669682BA2FC62E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Terms and conditions</header><text>The conveyance under subsection (b) shall be—</text><paragraph id="HFEDA80A00ACA499EA78520F9F12A0524"><enum>(1)</enum><text>subject to valid existing rights;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD2ECD2F9C2964D6F88062C6099669665"><enum>(2)</enum><text>made without consideration;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE5D6D0E4F1F94EAAACBEA88AAADCE60F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>made by quitclaim deed; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9FF7FABE806F429AB702B54203D6B2CA"><enum>(4)</enum><text>subject to such other terms and conditions as the Secretary considers to be appropriate to protect the interests of the United States. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1B643076FDBC4DAE993D2AE6471B5C0D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Costs of conveyance</header><text>As a condition of the conveyance under subsection (b), the County shall pay all costs associated with the conveyance, including the cost of—</text><paragraph id="HADD2133118A24ACE937D9854ABD8B5BD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a survey, if necessary, under subsection (c)(3); </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA9FBA9A11FB34296903E115C98DF3E6D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any environmental analysis or resource survey required under Federal law; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDFC77A6A830B4BCD92715D9B002C6A9D" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any analysis required to comply with division A of subtitle III of title 54, United States Code (commonly referred to as the <quote>National Historic Preservation Act</quote>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0F21A7FE0F4149F187E89023A34D1244" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Environmental conditions</header><text>Notwithstanding section 120(h)(3)(A) of the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9620">42 U.S.C. 9620(h)(3)(A)</external-xref>), the Secretary shall not be required to provide any covenant or warranty for the land and improvements conveyed to the County under subsection (b).</text></subsection><subsection id="H470146E017ED4117A5DD4C80E7987A29"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Use of land</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The land conveyed to the county under subsection (b) shall be used by the County only for the purposes of serving and supporting veterans of the Armed Forces.</text></subsection><subsection id="H976627DBF313432EBB5326A8D6712359" commented="no"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Reversion</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If any land conveyed under subsection (b) is used in a manner that is inconsistent with the requirements of subsection (g), all right, title, and interest in and to the land shall revert to the United States, at the discretion of the Secretary. </text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

