<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-HEN25365-YLG-SD-G41"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S917 IS: To designate the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 620 East Pecan Boulevard in McAllen, Texas, as the “Agent Raul H. Gonzalez Jr. Memorial Post Office”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 917</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250310">March 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S287">Mr. Cornyn</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S355">Mr. Cruz</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To designate the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 620 East Pecan Boulevard in McAllen, Texas, as the <quote>Agent Raul H. Gonzalez Jr. Memorial Post Office</quote>.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H3D304DF227C84EFF9ED1C4F5223EEBC5"><section section-type="section-one" id="H93094AACBB0E46A48C99A764DFDD359A"><enum>1.</enum><header>Agent Raul H. Gonzalez Jr. Memorial Post Office</header><subsection id="H1CD9A7966AA847A68EABA61A59C8AA2E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The facility of the United States Postal Service located at 620 East Pecan Boulevard in McAllen, Texas, shall be known and designated as the <quote>Agent Raul H. Gonzalez Jr. Memorial Post Office</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H225BF4500A1043FAB668BB16CD874A5E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>References</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any reference in a law, map, regulation, document, paper, or other record of the United States to the facility referred to in subsection (a) shall be deemed to be a reference to the <quote>Agent Raul H. Gonzalez Jr. Memorial Post Office</quote>.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

