<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE08BC4AD96C24190A0E9E2EB4CBD4FD2" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1631 IH: Safe Access to Cash Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1631</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250226">February 26, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000612">Mr. Rose</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="I000058">Mr. Ivey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000471">Mr. Fitzgerald</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001204">Mr. Meuser</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000454">Mr. Foster</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000175">Mr. Ogles</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000392">Mr. Kustoff</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 18, United States Code, to clarify that ATMs are in the care, custody, control, management, or possession of, any bank, credit union, or any savings and loan association regardless of whether the ATM is located on the physical premises of such an institution.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8320194109F9439A8A83593486E71396" style="OLC"><section id="H0F738C230FA34EA0B1925DB3C2A705BA" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Safe Access to Cash Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H28358EEA1BB748928BF7B30A46774D6A"><enum>2.</enum><header>ATM Robbery</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2113 of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="USC" id="HB3903A6A7D2F48168BF5309F5443CD68" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H90F7E56D9C544CC9A56177788060FCB5"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>ATM</term> means any network-connected automated teller machine terminal that is connected to one or more of the global, national, or regional electronic financial networks that allow a depositor of any bank, credit union, or savings and loan association, by use at such ATM of a card or other access device, as defined in subsection (e)(1) of section 1029 of this title, issued or authorized by such depository institution, to access such depositor’s account for the purpose of making withdrawals from or deposits to such account, or making inquiry as to the balance in such account, and includes any ATM owned, operated, or sponsored by a bank, credit union, or any savings and loan association.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA43B0596C72544C8BE18F709BCE79615"><enum>(j)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, an ATM, and any cash that is in transit to or being loaded into or unloaded from an ATM, shall be considered in the care, custody, control, management, or possession of, any bank, credit union, or any savings and loan association, regardless of whether—</text><paragraph id="HDD6F8B165453491AB499F6202D978AC7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the ATM is located on the physical premises of such an institution; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H304EAE70E8254D0393F5F20ABFAED865" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the ATM is owned or operated by such an institution. </text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

