<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-BAI25143-4XC-S4-26M"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S389 RS: Setting Consumer Standards for Lithium-Ion Batteries Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><calendar>Calendar No. 133</calendar><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 389</legis-num><associated-doc role="report">[Report No. 119–50]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250204">February 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S331">Mrs. Gillibrand</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S357">Mrs. Fischer</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S270">Mr. Schumer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><action stage="Reported-in-Senate"><action-date date="20250729">July 29, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Reported by <sponsor name-id="S355">Mr. Cruz</sponsor>, with an amendment</action-desc><action-instruction>Insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To establish consumer standards for lithium-ion batteries. </official-title></form><legis-body><section id="ide164bd067bf54c8b87a8a7c7b9d0a7cf" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Setting Consumer Standards for Lithium-Ion Batteries Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idd9f8669d97804c6e9b9c00983045d88f"><enum>2.</enum><header>Consumer product safety standard for certain batteries</header><subsection id="id0c8732798c4045989b9662b1882ecb27" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Consumer product safety standard required</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Consumer Product Safety Commission (referred to in this section as the <quote>Commission</quote>) shall promulgate, under section 553 of title 5, United States Code, the provisions of ANSI/CAN/UL 2271–Standard for Batteries for Use in Light Electric Vehicle Applications, ANSI/CAN/UL 2849–Standard for Safety for Electrical Systems for eBikes, and ANSI/CA<italic>N</italic>/UL 2272–Standard for Electrical Systems for Personal E-Mobility Devices, as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act, as final consumer product safety standards.</text></subsection><subsection id="id77066ec677cd4dfa99cfb1ed8fafe348"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consumer Product Safety Commission determination of scope</header><text>In adopting the standards under subsection (a), the Commission shall limit the application of such standards to consumer products as defined in section 3(a)(5) of the Consumer Product Safety Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/2052">15 U.S.C. 2052(a)(5)</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection id="idcbe4136afd8f452fa09b61a5285941cc"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Revision of voluntary standards</header><paragraph id="ida4e14c9a48ec45a295b762a9bb807eae"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Notice to Commission</header><text>If the provisions of ANSI/CAN/UL 2271–Standard for Batteries for Use in Light Electric Vehicle Applications, ANSI/CAN/UL 2849–Standard for Safety for Electrical Systems for eBikes, or ANSI/CAN/UL 2272–Standard for Electrical Systems for Personal E-Mobility Devices, are revised following the enactment of this Act, the organization that revised the requirements of such standard shall notify the Commission after the final approval of the revision.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7eea109512444e22b7d969cfaa10efae"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Treatment of revision</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The revised voluntary standard shall be considered to be a consumer product safety standard issued by the Commission under section 9 of the Consumer Product Safety Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/2058">15 U.S.C. 2058</external-xref>), effective 180 days after the date on which the organization notifies the Commission (or such later date specified by the Commission in the Federal Register) unless, within 90 days after receiving that notice, the Commission notifies the organization that it has determined that the proposed revision, in whole or in part, does not improve the safety of the consumer product covered by the standard and that the Commission is retaining the existing consumer product safety standard. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id932a56d38d374aa8a41ea52306b6e9d7"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Treatment of standard</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A standard promulgated under this section, including a revision of such standard adopted by the Commission, shall be treated as a consumer product safety rule promulgated under section 9 of the Consumer Product Safety Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/2058">15 U.S.C. 2058</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection id="id05fdf6f485144144b31b80a41a05a560"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><paragraph id="id0cb775414d6146c592f89bfd9a1477d0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 5 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Commission shall submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives, a report regarding fires, explosions, and other hazards relating to lithium-ion batteries used in micromobility products during the period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act and ending on the report date.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5ae3d47cc63d499aa24cf41803a184a5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Content</header><text>The report required by paragraph (1) shall describe, at a minimum—</text><subparagraph id="id43917faf032d4041b3bf9bb03e489314"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the source of the information that was provided to the Commission regarding the fire, explosion, or other hazard;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9cfeb8d302194545902004b4d54b92f5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the make and model of the lithium-ion battery and micromobility product that resulted in a fire, explosion, or other hazard, if known;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc152fad3489c4bb688627df8c1ea4cd3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>whether a lithium-ion battery involved in a fire, explosion, or other hazard complied with the standard required by this section, if known; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9a130fbf253a41b3887ee5b891afb464"><enum>(D)</enum><text>if known, the manufacturer and country of manufacture of a lithium-ion battery that resulted in a fire, explosion, or other hazard.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body><endorsement><action-date>July 29, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

