<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-LIP25178-7TS-RW-W8C"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1604 IS: No Regional Transportation Optimization Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes"></distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1604</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250506">May 6, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S399">Mr. Hawley</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To prohibit implementation of the Regional Transportation Optimization initiative, or similar initiative from being implemented by the United States Postal Service if the Postal Regulatory Commission has determined the initiative will negatively affect rural communities, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No Regional Transportation Optimization Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>No RTO Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9f4c0d6a4f5448f3a4cb08b9f06d68fd"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The United States Postal Service shall not implement its Regional Transportation Optimization initiative, or any similar initiative, if the Postal Regulatory Commission has determined in an advisory opinion, pursuant to section 3661 of title 39, United States Code, that such implementation will negatively affect rural communities.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

