<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H81691DFE220242B583952DB1B6A523E8" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3847 IH: SPORTS Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3847</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250609">June 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001136">Mrs. McClain</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="B001326">Ms. Bynum</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To protect the name, image, and likeness rights of student athletes, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0CF48C9CBB1F4E9BA469D6AB6E020AA2" style="OLC"><section id="HDAE37A80E8FE4B40A3355E017D4A6654" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header><subsection id="HFE6E08C0439C454594583BE49833F105"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Student-athlete Protections and Opportunities through Rights, Transparency, and Safety Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote>SPORTS Act</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD6EEAA52CCA14F949861362F34EAC0A8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text><toc container-level="legis-body-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"><toc-entry idref="HDAE37A80E8FE4B40A3355E017D4A6654" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H9C0ABAE97BA04BA0A2A2595D5D1A0004" level="section">Sec. 2. Definitions.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H7EE853C506D44C2ABB5BD05610750611" level="section">Sec. 3. Protection of name, image, and likeness rights of student athletes.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H2A91CBA1AF8347D7AB921D930B643320" level="section">Sec. 4. Modifications to Sports Agent Responsibility and Trust Act.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H6B81194C8037436D85070DAD3C154BDD" level="section">Sec. 5. Roles of conferences and interstate intercollegiate athletic associations.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HC4E7DCCB75ED45B79F3EC08DA4230FF9" level="section">Sec. 6. Determination of NIL market value.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H8E520D2858C94D6FA2744A5C01432FC1" level="section">Sec. 7. Eligibility for certain Department of Education funding.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HB0BACBE4940E448692EF5FD05C2A9679" level="section">Sec. 8. Limitation on liability.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HEDE2B487AF1446BBAD6F88FD272139BE" level="section">Sec. 9. Preemption.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section><section id="H9C0ABAE97BA04BA0A2A2595D5D1A0004"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="HFEF28CD1D4384D43A37267410A31E211"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Compensation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>compensation</term>—</text><subparagraph id="HD22E26D392384C779A0F9C39F7DB6133"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means any form of payment or remuneration, whether provided through cash, benefits, awards, or other means, including payments for—</text><clause id="H959093F6D2D64B64AD16E654B9BC0282"><enum>(i)</enum><text>licenses relating to, or the use of, name, image, and likeness rights; or</text></clause><clause id="HA5F91447E7184C07B6BA23F47817E442"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>licenses relating to, or the use of, any other Federal or State intellectual or intangible property right; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0B40D938E7FF4207A922F08F9374FC21"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include—</text><clause id="H74FF79A8E68740498B85BEBCFEDB3AC8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>grants-in-aid;</text></clause><clause id="H2205DB5E1E8143B68ADCE8ADF186F116"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Federal Pell Grants and other Federal or State grants unrelated to and not awarded with regard to participation in intercollegiate athletic competitions;</text></clause><clause id="H96B9318F71984A3B9C7E9A5F74A9F57B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>health insurance and payments for the costs of health care, including health insurance and payments for the costs of health care wholly or partly self-funded by an institution, conference, or interstate intercollegiate athletic association;</text></clause><clause id="H1070A76EA67D44D7AF99F513F22315A2"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">disability and loss-of-value insurance, including disability and loss-of-value insurance that is wholly or partly self-funded by an institution, conference, or interstate intercollegiate athletic association;</text></clause><clause id="H6B2D024BB82E410DB1A65B1F2D123521"><enum>(v)</enum><text>career counseling, job placement services, and other guidance available to all students at an institution;</text></clause><clause id="HD5458C38A47844FA8B41E88D1ED8301F"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>payment of hourly wages and benefits for work actually performed (and not for participation in intercollegiate athletic competitions) at a rate commensurate with the going rate in the relevant locality for similar work; or</text></clause><clause id="HCB32E5880E3046F186B2189A78567818"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>any program to connect student athletes with employers and facilitate employment opportunities, if—</text><subclause id="H6041D0CBC8114D9DA73E699FA63D7345"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the financial terms of such employment opportunities are consistent with the terms offered to similarly situated individuals who are not student athletes; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H49076E11A1C0475E9C611679A58EC2B9"><enum>(II)</enum><text>such program is not used to induce a student athlete to attend a particular institution.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD2806F93AEC44ECE9DA187F6E0A1389C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conference</header><text>The term <term>conference</term> means an entity that—</text><subparagraph id="H418013F154E343F4B915A89CC9C1068E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>exclusively has as members 2 or more institutions; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE6514F77582D4B8985971CD8177F062A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>arranges championships and sets rules with respect to intercollegiate athletic competitions for members.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDB849EA22D774A2DBAA90696AB3E1DA3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Cost of attendance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>cost of attendance</term>—</text><subparagraph id="HF39EDF1CDC6742E78CBA2F03C87CDF8D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has the meaning given such term in section 472 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087ll">20 U.S.C. 1087ll</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8B5F6F94A9A94F29AAF113B0431F5E01"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is calculated by the financial aid office of an institution using the same standards, policies, and procedures for all students.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA760B5BBAC8F462B85805E45F4E26F76"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Grant-in-aid</header><text>The term <term>grant-in-aid</term> means a scholarship, grant, stipend, or other form of financial assistance, including the provision of tuition, room, board, books, or funds for fees or personal expenses, that—</text><subparagraph id="HEDF2FADE3C9C48079E31094C6959A052"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is paid or provided by an institution to a student for the undergraduate or graduate course of study of the student; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2FD2F044C3CC4B34A8FA289E890A084E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is in an amount that does not exceed the cost of attendance for such student at the institution.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCDE524E9589C448788465AD31AC7BA42"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Image</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>image</term> means, with respect to a student athlete, a picture or video that identifies, is linked to, or is reasonably linked to such student athlete.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF3BD53875E014CE7A487D5D54C7F8730"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Institution</header><text>The term <term>institution</term> has the meaning given the term <term>institution of higher education</term> in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA62CA705092E44CE9BA4FEC6ABA96A6F"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Intercollegiate athletic competition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>intercollegiate athletic competition</term> means any contest, game, meet, match, tournament, regatta, or other event in which varsity sports teams of more than 1 institution compete.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9CDC60BD48D640A0A88A68EB1A4415C6"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Interstate intercollegiate athletic association</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>interstate intercollegiate athletic association</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H49F1B7DD929F4BF38418778F47CDBD51"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any entity organized in the United States that—</text><clause id="HC2C8792180234077B9333434FF58616D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>sponsors or arranges intercollegiate athletic competitions between institutions and conferences;</text></clause><clause id="H3897D606D8B749A8A519ECFE100A6FEA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>sets common rules, standards, procedures, or guidelines for the administration of intercollegiate athletic competitions; and</text></clause><clause id="H078CED2D94C14D18A6108175E45475E3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>is composed of 2 or more conferences with member institutions located in more than 1 State; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H36891E26C7684CA0B59AC453B81FBB08"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include an entity affiliated with professional athletic competitions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H197FF7A4C8CA4591A388E0788AA9159C"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Likeness</header><text>The term <term>likeness</term> means, with respect to a student athlete, a physical or digital depiction or representation that identifies, is linked to, or is reasonably linked to such student athlete.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H77B25C49EFD646708510C31615F33950"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Name</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>name</term> means, with respect to a student athlete, the first or last name, or the nickname, of such student athlete if used in a context that identifies, is linked to, or is reasonably linked to such student athlete.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFA2B8211E13B45DFAF7062DE7531F488"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Name, image, and likeness agreement</header><text>The term <term>name, image, and likeness agreement</term> means a contract or similar agreement between a student athlete and a third party regarding the commercial use of the name, image, or likeness of the student athlete.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0B8CCAAF9144450EB012F4D9E4DDD975"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Name, image, and likeness rights</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>name, image, and likeness rights</term> means rights recognized under Federal or State law that allow an individual to control and profit from the commercial use of the name, image, and likeness of such individual, including all rights commonly referred to as <quote>publicity rights</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H40AA745021204EB2A05474EB806F5CC5"><enum>(13)</enum><header>NIL representation</header><text>The term <term>NIL representation</term>—</text><subparagraph id="H4CDCD21255DD4E65813DA1CBBDA82D63"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means representation of a student athlete by an individual or entity with respect to a name, image, and likeness agreement; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9715C6E1008F4C8C8ECC4F3365B6DB58"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include such representation if carried out by an immediate family member of the student athlete.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H111B1228ABAB493B8707DAA1523EF35F"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Student athlete</header><text>The term <term>student athlete</term> means an individual who—</text><subparagraph id="H4F67E71E26A54473A37BB3B74865FCA0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is enrolled at an institution; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H84E957E6B9FD4942BDC1A238E0116C5B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>participates in a varsity sports team of such institution.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5CB4996A562E44BA97FB41D4900EDE67"><enum>(15)</enum><header>Third party</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>third party</term>—</text><subparagraph id="H428492FCE8614FE0A340CC605EAC326E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means any individual or entity that licenses name, image, and likeness rights from any current or prospective student athlete or any group of such athletes; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7EF18640C7C340949E9D698F13D4C43F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include an institution, conference, or interstate intercollegiate athletic association.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H970212F496EC4E048D3D3703EB34C9AD"><enum>(16)</enum><header>Varsity sports team</header><text>The term <term>varsity sports team</term> means an entity composed of an individual or group of individuals enrolled at an institution that is organized by such institution for the purpose of participation in intercollegiate athletic competitions.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H7EE853C506D44C2ABB5BD05610750611"><enum>3.</enum><header>Protection of name, image, and likeness rights of student athletes</header><subsection id="H6E1A03264AA34018891428CD7ED9BE02"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Right To enter into name, image, and likeness agreements</header><paragraph id="HADDFD65690E34480A34E1DA4227A6BFC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), no institution, conference, or interstate intercollegiate athletic association may restrict the ability of a student athlete to enter into a name, image, and likeness agreement.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H88AEDFAAF053438E86C1B1EAF893474E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>An institution, conference, or interstate intercollegiate athletic association may restrict the eligibility of a student athlete for intercollegiate athletic competitions if such student athlete enters into a name, image, and likeness agreement that—</text><subparagraph id="H362A86F1CFFD49C3BB5988BEA10E2924"><enum>(A)</enum><text>violates the code of student conduct of the institution at which the student athlete is enrolled;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H813E14B6700E46F2A98DBECA476C0C6C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>negatively impacts the reputation or public image of such institution; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD8E02B1603A34C4C8F837FF9CB8160D8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>conflicts with the terms of an existing contract or agreement of such institution.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H64B83274937A431A8E954F0BF0821585"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Disclosure</header><subparagraph id="H6D5EF3D866814133A6177546EDB0F8AB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date on which a student athlete enters into a name, image, and likeness agreement, such student athlete shall disclose the terms of such agreement to the institution at which such student athlete is enrolled.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6A8EB8FDE8364E8389E73D45F0BDA600"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Release of information</header><text>Except as provided in section 6, an institution may not release any information provided by a student athlete in a disclosure provided under subparagraph (A) without the express written consent of such student athlete or the NIL representation of the student athlete.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF4174C1048D04B7F9717A8352A4C4368"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Right to representation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No institution, conference, or interstate intercollegiate athletic association may prohibit the participation of a student athlete in an intercollegiate athletic competition, or events relating to an intercollegiate athletic competition, on the basis that the student athlete has obtained NIL representation.</text></subsection><subsection id="H858B440414024E8990B9CBC43B9B8E26"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Requirements for name, image, and likeness agreements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A name, image, and likeness agreement is void from the inception of such agreement if such agreement does not satisfy the following requirements:</text><paragraph id="H7DE18E4215AB43C59766A380887F2E98"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The agreement is in writing.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0FC28D424D7E448285847B4C4808066E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The agreement contains—</text><subparagraph id="H692B934F0F404F9CA792B27B08CB09EB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of any services to be rendered under the agreement;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8056CC0E580C4700A2D53B5E8C2BC463"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the names of the parties to the agreement;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFA8429980DEF4EA9A1A7AC504BE1CA72"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the term of the agreement;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7AF6C1011EC947E5A87BB497F63C1316"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the amount of compensation to be provided to the relevant student athlete under the agreement; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2B7A915B30C44161B6BD6CAD4AA0A937"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a provision specifying under what circumstances or events the agreement may be terminated on account of non-performance of obligations by the relevant student athlete.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H2A91CBA1AF8347D7AB921D930B643320"><enum>4.</enum><header>Modifications to Sports Agent Responsibility and Trust Act</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Sports Agent Responsibility and Trust Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/7801">15 U.S.C. 7801 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H0BBDA5AD868B482D86BADAE9F192BBAE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 3(b)(3), by striking <quote>Warning to Student Athlete: If you agree orally or in writing to be represented by an agent now or in the future you may lose your eligibility to compete as a student athlete in your sport.</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4109CD2A2BDB4A9FB863E40A005C2846"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HD930D289FFB64195A3EB913D5B7B5AF3" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="HEF4AFA0039404894AE40E86400B35E98"><enum>9.</enum><header>Disclosure and consent relating to name, image, and likeness agreements</header><subsection id="H84B07407D8A54802A44E61542C04479E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An athlete agent who assists a student athlete with an endorsement contract shall disclose to the student athlete—</text><paragraph id="H541DEB2A87C34CC1AE6D38B2231CF50C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether the athlete agent is registered with an interstate intercollegiate athletic association (as defined in section 2 of the SPORTS Act); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3FE3053B2D564A0CA0AF658CFA79A36A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>if registered with such an association, whether such association has as a member the institution (as defined in section 2 of the SPORTS Act) at which the student athlete is enrolled.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5E07DFC121654C3298DCC6987F8959B0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consent</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an athlete agent that is not registered with an interstate intercollegiate athletic association (as defined in section 2 of the SPORTS Act), the athlete agent may only assist a student athlete with an endorsement contract if such student athlete (or, in the case of a student athlete who is under 18 years of age, the parent or guardian of such student athlete) provides to the athlete agent written consent for such assistance after receiving a written disclosure from the athlete agent that the athlete agent is not registered with such an association.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="H6B81194C8037436D85070DAD3C154BDD"><enum>5.</enum><header>Roles of conferences and interstate intercollegiate athletic associations</header><subsection id="H06484A65AABC4E5BB32F625F0668B8E0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each interstate intercollegiate athletic association shall—</text><paragraph id="HA7AFFE9D26E940C98936F74842AF2F31"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establish a process by which an individual or entity seeking to represent a student athlete with respect to a name, image, and likeness agreement may register with such interstate intercollegiate athletic association for purposes of NIL representation; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE10A125DE8C74A6D8346DAE293BDE0DA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>establish and maintain a publicly accessible, searchable database to assist student athletes and the NIL representation of such athletes to estimate the fair market value for name, image, and likeness agreements based on the information provided under section 6.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H57594529404A421482F5E7B8028415DD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Other roles</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each conference or interstate intercollegiate athletic association may—</text><paragraph id="H50D6951983B84E3CAF16E1C55829FA15"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establish and enforce rules relating to—</text><subparagraph id="H07C35C5ABF6F4F8A98BF74012F99B3BB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the manner and timing for the recruitment of an athlete before and during the period of eligibility of such athlete for intercollegiate athletic competitions; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H354D8AC1259B4EB7B3A5329AD408DB43"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the transfer of student athletes between institutions, including prohibiting or limiting compensation to student athletes by institutions and conferences for the purposes of inducing a student athlete to transfer institutions;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2C88B7179CE348719A44D2665E0382DC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide student athletes and the parents and guardians of student athletes with educational materials relating to name, image, and likeness rights;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAC9F96A652894178A720EE231592A18B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>organize championships; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF3664936BEE24ABE9CF81A091F13E002"><enum>(4)</enum><text>establish bylaws governing membership under which a conference or interstate intercollegiate athletic association may, if in compliance with this Act—</text><subparagraph id="H74836596C7864617828A8903A8BA1694"><enum>(A)</enum><text>remove member institutions;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3672372FB8B442F3A30962C8290B4E07"><enum>(B)</enum><text>restrict participation in intercollegiate athletic competitions for institutions or student athletes; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF4BAC542D8D944B688752C2931590C7A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>restrict eligibility of student athletes for intercollegiate athletic competitions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HC4E7DCCB75ED45B79F3EC08DA4230FF9"><enum>6.</enum><header>Determination of NIL market value</header><subsection id="HE7D3C8C1D57E4103A911078D6704141C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Disclosure requirements</header><paragraph id="HE38063B0EDCA4BFAB39943CAF39E253F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than July 1 of the first year beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, each institution shall provide, in an anonymized manner, to any interstate intercollegiate athletic association of which such institution is a member the following data with respect to each name, image, and likeness agreement disclosed to the institution under section 3(a)(3) during the preceding year:</text><subparagraph id="H3E596148FEB84A0499C2489A9020C5A4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A description of services rendered by the student athlete under such agreement.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBF8B3940663643889060DBEE6AB2A286"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The amount of compensation to be provided to the student athlete under such agreement.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF15AA1CF84074364A8A1BB3B782D07D3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Protection of personally identifiable information</header><text>In providing data under paragraph (1), an institution shall ensure that no personally identifiable information of a student athlete is transmitted.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H74D970E8129148058A0F8D79AA5833FE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Database</header><paragraph id="HE52A9C9E077B4994A59A07E7339E8BC6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Data provided to an interstate intercollegiate athletic association under subsection (a) shall be used by such association to establish and maintain a publicly accessible, searchable database for student athletes and the NIL representation of such athletes to estimate the fair market value for name, image, and likeness agreements.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBCD64CDF36C04F6395FE476688AA0C54"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Privacy</header><text>An interstate intercollegiate athletic association shall take reasonable measures to ensure that data available in the database described in paragraph (1) is unable to be used to identify a student athlete.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H8E520D2858C94D6FA2744A5C01432FC1"><enum>7.</enum><header>Eligibility for certain Department of Education funding</header><subsection id="HFA555B5E982C42488215C342697BDE00"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An institution is not eligible for any Federal funding made available by the Department of Education unless such institution satisfies the requirements of this section, including any requirement included in a regulation promulgated under subsection (e).</text></subsection><subsection id="H0F57DDD6CA684001800075FE1B164118"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Education and training</header><text>An institution shall provide, to each student athlete who receives a grant-in-aid from such institution in relation to participation in a varsity sports team, education and training with respect to the following:</text><paragraph id="HCBBE4CA96F9E4363878F69662694B70C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Career preparation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3E47AC1059BF47E0AD4F7AE3C8B3F0D2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Financial literacy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFB930FB9BAB14E388B3D5C719AF83A43"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Mental health.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H929A04C444004C94B65D681B95814459"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Name, image, and likeness opportunities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H25432A2C3E6C4BA28B60D95AC978A555"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Nutrition.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF2F623EFF81844D386DC3AB97BB49273"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Sexual violence prevention.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF789EBDCE2CF492797DFE5AC0DE20ADC"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Strength and conditioning.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA8969D4B556F48C79009454BDD10A324"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The process for transferring to another institution.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBD32A5CE5F284035801CEAB241BE4D67"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Medical care</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the 4-year period beginning on the date on which an individual graduates or otherwise separates from an institution in which such individual was enrolled, such institution shall pay all the medical costs of such individual in relation to any injury of such individual that occurred—</text><paragraph id="HE9A752B8CCA14395800F6BD5A99DB0E0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>while the individual was a student athlete at such institution; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7B031A29E9CC49868C6F3EAF63D0AAA7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>as a result of participation in a varsity sports team.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0CD132596315493D8B43E8B4F9003F42"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Grants-in-Aid</header><text>An institution that provides a grant-in-aid to a student athlete in relation to participation in a varsity sports team—</text><paragraph id="H9C326DB8F8464227BA2F01BA3984596F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>may not reduce the amount of or cancel such grant-in-aid for any reason relating to—</text><subparagraph id="HB8F2B25DE99943E497FD2E8DD4EB31AC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>athletic ability or performance;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0D7A716231C3438794CC54710B78B41D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>contribution to team success;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3BB3AA6EF759421599CD5CD285F9FAEA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>injury;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE9030E4C91F34DD785E8257903AE80BF"><enum>(D)</enum><text>physical or mental illness; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD45B7B896EED45C0BC9BFF76841A333B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>roster management decisions; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H30E0DEF5FA6F4FC2ABD5D30F26099033"><enum>(2)</enum><text>during the 10-year period beginning on the date on which such grant-in-aid is initially agreed to by such institution, shall make such grant-in-aid available to such student athlete for purposes of degree completion without regard to whether such student athlete continues to participate in a varsity sports team.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H70965D9E265D4E7C9DA37FDECC8DE426"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary of Education may promulgate, in accordance with section 553 of title 5, United States Code, such regulations as may be necessary to carry out this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H28CC9D9955714365A9EF1438D1E3B11F"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>This section shall apply with respect to Federal funding made available on or after the date that is 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="HB0BACBE4940E448692EF5FD05C2A9679"><enum>8.</enum><header>Limitation on liability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">An institution, conference, or interstate intercollegiate athletic association that complies with this Act, including the amendments made by this Act, may not be treated as violating any law or regulation, and may not be subject to liability under any law or regulation, on the basis of—</text><paragraph id="HED7AE022A0244E8F993D8E258B9FFABD"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the adoption of, agreement to, enforcement of, or compliance with any rule or bylaw of an institution, conference, or interstate intercollegiate athletic association that limits or prohibits a student athlete from receiving compensation from an institution, conference, or interstate intercollegiate athletic association;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0AF0911DE5574D08B81D4E318D08FCCF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a restriction on the eligibility, with respect to intercollegiate athletic competitions, of a student athlete who violates a rule of an institution, conference, or interstate intercollegiate athletic association that is reasonably contemplated under this Act; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEAB8A6B54E2A48BB99FF57048FA3ECFD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>compliance with any agreement, understanding, rule, or bylaw adopted by an institution, conference, or interstate intercollegiate athletic association that is reasonably contemplated under this Act.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HEDE2B487AF1446BBAD6F88FD272139BE"><enum>9.</enum><header>Preemption</header><subsection id="H2A65B2A4BC4845ACA3CA13B8C7D48591"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No State or political subdivision of a State may enforce any law, regulation, rule, requirement, or standard that—</text><paragraph id="HF1F83E4662534F178549414660F8ACFC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conflicts with this Act, including any amendments made by this Act; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H877D24651C1A4009B86A0065EC7929ED"><enum>(2)</enum><text>governs or regulates, with respect to intercollegiate athletic competitions or varsity sports teams, the compensation, employment status, or eligibility of a student athlete, including any law, regulation, rule, requirement, or standard that governs or regulates the commercial use of the name, image, or likeness of a student athlete.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC80178F9ACD54FCAB6213335BC073624"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Student athletes not employees</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a student athlete may not be considered an employee of an institution, conference, or interstate intercollegiate athletic association, on the basis of the participation of such student athlete in a varsity sports team.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

