<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="H3190F66AAEFC425B869CE570B04CE8B3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1608 RH: Department of Homeland Security Vehicular Terrorism Prevention and Mitigation Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 180</calendar><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1608</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 119–222]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250226">February 26, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000593">Mr. Gimenez</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="G000590">Mr. Green of Tennessee</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250808">August 8, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsor: <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250808">August 8, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on February 26, 2025</action-instruction><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Homeland Security to produce a report on emerging threats and countermeasures related to vehicular terrorism, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HHM00" reported-display-style="italic" id="H24015E6FF1EE45D3A2E0927AC1A9BBD7"><section id="HD99951460A2B479DA6B42B1AE9DEACA7" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Department of Homeland Security Vehicular Terrorism Prevention and Mitigation Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H96F40C049F4243F098D2273533E8185B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="HBB74C78F25514F159B8073272164586E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>On January 1, 2025, a devastating vehicular terrorist attack occurred on Bourbon Street in New Orleans, Louisiana, when an assailant inspired by the Islamic State drove a vehicle into a crowd and engaged in a shootout with law enforcement. This tragic incident resulted in the loss of 14 lives and injuries to at least thirty-five others, including two police officers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5B7AFEE8DA014043BC7928D11A2271A1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Vehicle-ramming attacks and other vehicular terrorist incidents represent an enduring and evolving threat to public safety in the United States and around the world, targeting innocent civilians and first responders.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3494E4CEF8284E11A4D1CF6CD0C3F13E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>These attacks, carried out by both organized terrorist groups and individual actors, often aim to exploit high-density public gatherings, critical infrastructure, and key transportation hubs, causing mass casualties and widespread disruption.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1AFB2232F25C41EC90F9429895832DE5"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Emerging automotive technologies, such as autonomous vehicles, Advanced Driver Assistance System (ADAS) capabilities, and ride-sharing platforms, create new vulnerabilities that could be leveraged by malicious actors to conduct sophisticated vehicle-based attacks.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7E0CD7D58A8F4772AE3B95DC9C19425E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Department of Homeland Security, through agencies like the Transportation Security Administration and the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency, plays a vital role in detecting, assessing, and mitigating the risks associated with vehicle-based threats.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD3A2CE44BC1A4FB1B69C64623D56B578"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Strengthened coordination between Federal, State, local, Tribal, territorial, and private sector stakeholders is essential to enhance prevention, preparedness, and response efforts, ensuring the safety of communities across the nation.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H58ADBA7B65804457964C6C62AC84AF70"><enum>3.</enum><header>Report on emerging threats and countermeasures related to vehicular terrorism</header><subsection id="H372DEF6B834B4561A82972DF6EAE56F9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report</header><paragraph id="H74C12BE009444C3080E069BF307C9A10" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security, in coordination with the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration and the Director of the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the Department of Homeland Security’s efforts to prevent, deter, and respond to vehicular terrorism.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7EC0E83FBFA3473F82025910D53A27B6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The report under paragraph (1) shall include the following:</text><subparagraph id="HBC47D55E608F482D98FC44A1ABADDFC9" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An assessment of the current and emerging threats posed by vehicular terrorism, as well as the following:</text><clause id="HD70E2335855647DE910C6B33B76EAED3" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An analysis of the methods, tactics, and motivations used by perpetrators of vehicular terrorism.</text></clause><clause id="HB8837B99794A485BB3A5A91EA74B2392" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>An evaluation of domestic and international trends in vehicular terrorism.</text></clause><clause id="H7F1245CE85EB4204994E72FB8B87BCBE" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An identification of potential future threats related to the misuse of connected or autonomous vehicles, Advanced Driver Assistance System (ADAS) -equipped vehicles, ride-sharing services, and advancements in automotive technologies, including cybersecurity threats to underlying software technologies (including artificial intelligence-enabled technologies) powering autonomous vehicles.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8CD182A926F24E4483DC61B19BA4B594" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A review of higher-risk locations and events that may be vulnerable to vehicular terrorism, including the following:</text><clause id="HFF59864CC95D4890A7C0ED08052589F4" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Critical infrastructure sites such as the following:</text><subclause id="H044E36A7A584472787F84D25779302FF" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Airports.</text></subclause><subclause id="HAC485E8F64894C048A56E85CA3D5B981" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>Seaports.</text></subclause><subclause id="H6BE7FD1B5D4F411793B71F5669CB4A3A" commented="no"><enum>(III)</enum><text>Federal, State, local, Tribal, and territorial government facilities.</text></subclause><subclause id="HAF245B57729F43DCBA1624BF2EB6C4DC" commented="no"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>Power plants.</text></subclause><subclause id="H7A5923C2539249AC942EB503179A2F9B" commented="no"><enum>(V)</enum><text>Substations.</text></subclause><subclause id="H2C5A2466B3B843609ADC63497DC49124" commented="no"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>Oil refineries.</text></subclause><subclause id="H0DDE2A46988148DFA7495DAC488F80EE" commented="no"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>Public transportation hubs.</text></subclause><subclause id="HC4DFB07E0B05448986FA6430BC488D0E"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Healthcare facilities.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HD8A979A415824AE3B51DF5F59A978172" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Soft-targets and crowded spaces, including mass gatherings and widely attended events such as parades, concerts, sporting events, political rallies, holiday markets, places of worship, public demonstrations, and ceremonial events.</text></clause><clause id="HCB825E5D7BDD4FB99D7239D11040AECF" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>High-density urban areas with limited physical security measures such as pedestrianized city centers, commercial districts, residential neighborhoods, public parks, recreational areas, educational institutions, and tourist destinations.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3AFE839D6DD646A4807E0C26436E7D4A" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A comprehensive summary of actions taken by the Department of Homeland Security, the Transportation Security Administration, and the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency to research measures that prevent, deter, and respond to vehicular terrorism, including the following:</text><clause id="H58125EE559FC4934839922BB7B2BFFA0" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The identification and coordination with State, local, Tribal, and territorial governments and industry partners for the strategic placement of physical barriers, bollards, and other protective infrastructure at higher-risk locations.</text></clause><clause id="H152D64227F484C849C6995892AC70C6A" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The research, testing, and deployment of geofencing, surveillance systems, cybersecurity measures, and other technologies designed to monitor, restrict, and manage vehicle access to such higher-risk locations.</text></clause><clause id="HD6B560F944264759BF9267C1287CA996" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The creation of real-time response strategies and operational plans to neutralize vehicular terrorism, including ongoing research into best practices for threat detection, incident management, and threat containment.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFD82DEA73532491D94C5F13EBDA5D2DB" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An evaluation of the Department’s engagement with private and public sector stakeholders to address risks of vehicular terrorism, including the following:</text><clause id="H103534FE564549EF873F078B976CC13E" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Collaboration with vehicle rental companies, ride-sharing platforms, vendors of connected, autonomous, and ADAS technologies, freight operators, and automotive manufacturers.</text></clause><clause id="H7F4D95662AB1450EB1BBB248E1C72A9F" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Development of industry-specific best practices to prevent the misuse of vehicles.</text></clause><clause id="HC5F2365CF5FD4EDEB385D8BF290B34A4" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Protocols for sharing threat intelligence and security guidance with private sector partners.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD2D7C15977F04035807D8A971CDF6C71" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>A description of the Department’s coordination efforts with Federal, State, local, Tribal, and territorial law enforcement agencies to prevent vehicular terrorism, including the following:</text><clause id="H92AE928F35E34A7A985EEC14340FD73F" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Mechanisms for sharing threat intelligence and situational awareness.</text></clause><clause id="HC888D38EA3934E9CA8167279999A9734" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Guidance provided to such law enforcement agencies regarding implementing countermeasures, such as traffic control measures and rapid vehicle containment protocols.</text></clause><clause id="H489833CE2B4D4C46B986443EE1B4B036" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Joint exercises and training programs to enhance interagency preparedness and response.</text></clause><clause id="H1F52850F4E034E8E9ACABBCDB1DF16C3" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Efforts to equip law enforcement, first responders, and private sector partners with the knowledge and skills to recognize and respond to vehicular terrorism, including the development of specialized curricula addressing emerging threats, such as connected or autonomous vehicles and other advanced technologies.</text></clause><clause id="H8D1A4E102D2C4F99919691DED69EBF01" commented="no"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Outreach efforts to ensure that smaller jurisdictions have access to necessary training resources and public safety awareness tools.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H252F0AC28A7C46A79B2F509F010FE4CC" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Recommendations for the research, development, and deployment of technologies to detect, deter, and mitigate vehicular terrorism, including the following:</text><clause id="HFB7FFD29197F48158B6947A779EABD94" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Vehicle immobilization systems and remote disablement technologies.</text></clause><clause id="HEA8E8E5D388B4E6186D922EE0C7CCC39" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Predictive analytics and threat detection software that incorporate artificial intelligence and machine learning algorithms to identify and flag in real time anomalous or suspicious vehicle behavior, as well as associated technologies to disable or divert a vehicle before it becomes a threat.</text></clause><clause id="HE7AD25D6F11A49F5B12F37D0C92A270C" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Innovations in cybersecurity to prevent the hacking or misuse of connected, autonomous, or ADAS-equipped vehicles.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC0DAFBD10E38485B98DF39FB6EE2EF0C" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of the Department’s engagement with privacy, civil rights, and civil liberties stakeholders to ensure all countermeasures and technologies, including artificial-intelligence and machine learning algorithms, deployed to prevent vehicular terrorism are implemented in a manner that respects individual rights and freedoms.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCABACCBD37ED49CFBABE759C233F7112" commented="no"><enum>(H)</enum><text>A review of the Department’s public awareness initiatives focused on the following:</text><clause id="H50041557C4B44C1696759694B92BED7A" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Educating the public on recognizing suspicious vehicle-related behavior and reporting potential threats.</text></clause><clause id="H784C1F466FF04AB7B57F8E51132DF77E" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Building trust and fostering collaboration between communities and law enforcement agencies.</text></clause><clause id="H4D77CDD56E984D5082D255BBBA3C9325" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Enhancing resilience by encouraging community-based security measures.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC5DB90244599463392420BA1682C6A00"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Such other elements as the Secretary of Homeland Security considers appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H37B4FB4EF9E044079DDEE199BA6FFA54"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report under paragraph (1) shall be submitted in classified form, but may include an unclassified executive summary.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6982267FED7F495AAB34589FD9371719"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Publication</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The unclassified executive summary of the report required under paragraph (1) shall be published on a publicly accessible website of the Department of Homeland Security.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3FC4BF588FA1495FBE726E71FCB8ACDC" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Briefing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the submission of the report under subsection (a), the Secretary of Homeland Security shall provide to the appropriate congressional committees a briefing on the findings, conclusions, and recommendations of such report.</text></subsection><subsection id="H9778A165AB4C4A77ADAA5C7B74CDF7EA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HEB5BF60EBE884BDA9A895C858C8A8B27"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="H0AA2395B43FE4B498264622779635E51"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H71DFA57551934F889978EA66F6C2C9DC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA96F1F1A2F4D4354AB26F6838D8E6106"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Vehicular terrorism</header><text>The term <quote>vehicular terrorism</quote> means an action that utilizes automotive transportation to commit terrorism (as such term is defined in section 2(18) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/101">6 U.S.C. 101(18)</external-xref>)).</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date>August 8, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

