<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDBF64E574617423ABF48629B6A693113" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 325 IH: Commemorating the 100th anniversary of the city of Hialeah, Florida.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress>
<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 325</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20250410">April 10, 2025</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000600">Mr. Diaz-Balart</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">Commemorating the 100th anniversary of the city of Hialeah, Florida.</official-title>
</form>
<preamble>
<whereas><text>Whereas the city of Hialeah was incorporated in 1925 with a population of 1,500 and now has over 236,000 residents;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the city’s name comes from the Seminole phrase <quote>Haiyakpo Hili</quote>, meaning <quote>high prairie</quote>;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas Hialeah was founded by Glenn Curtiss, an aviation pioneer, and James Bright, a cattleman;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, in 1925, the Hialeah Park Racetrack, nicknamed <quote>The Grand Dame</quote>, opened and hosted notable figures, including Winston Churchill;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas, in 1937, Amelia Earhart announced her intent to fly around the world at the former location of the Miami Municipal Airport, and after supervising extensive repairs to her airplane, she took off from Hialeah on June 1;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, in 1943, Hialeah became a booming manufacturing center for the war effort, producing crucial items from uniforms to airplane parts;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas, in 1961, Rene Sedanos opened a small bodega in East Hialeah called <quote>Sedanos</quote>, which later expanded to serve communities across the State of Florida and has 34 store locations today;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, in 1972, the Cao family opened the original Vicky Bakery in East Hialeah, becoming a staple in the community;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas, in 1973, the band KC and the Sunshine Band was formed in a small studio in East Hialeah, led by Hialeah native, Harry Wayne Casey, and became 1 of the most successful pop and disco bands of the 70s and 80s with 5 top number 1 hits and selling over 100,000,000 records worldwide;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, in 1974, Bernard Cap was founded in Hialeah and remains a leading manufacturer of quality uniform headwear, apparel, and accessories for over 50 years, supplying United States and foreign military forces, service academies, airlines, police, security, and other organizations;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas, in 1984, Gus Machado took over an old car dealership on 49th Street in Hialeah, and later became the largest Hispanic-owned Ford dealership in the State of Florida;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the city of Hialeah is home to hard-working families striving each day for their American dream;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas the Hialeah community is a unique blend of nationalities and cultures;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Hialeah has historically been home to thousands of Cuban exiles, who were forced into exile by the brutal dictatorship on the island;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas, in 1993, the Honorable Lincoln Diaz-Balart was sworn in as a Member of the 103rd Congress and became the first Cuban American to represent Hialeah in the United States House of Representatives;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Honorable Lincoln Diaz-Balart represented Hialeah until he retired from the United States House of Representatives in 2011, and was later succeeded by his brother, the Honorable Mario Diaz-Balart, who proudly represents Hialeah today;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas, today, the city holds the rank of Florida’s 5th largest city and the 6th largest municipality;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas 95 percent of the population identifies as Hispanic/Latino, one of the highest percentages of Hispanic residents in the country;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas approximately 84.1 percent of Hialeah’s residents are of Cuban descent, the highest proportion in the United States;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the city is known for its industrial strength, contributing to Florida’s overall economic vitality;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas the city is one of the largest employers in Miami-Dade County; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the city of Hialeah contributes to Florida’s economy, culture, and history through its diverse and vibrant community: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble>
<resolution-body style="traditional" id="H931203B52E934B04929B34744E95C487">
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H4E653C390F5143D7BCC4DC388107643A"><enum/><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="HEFB8AE6BB4E54D239683A0F69A1139CD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>congratulates the city of Hialeah on the occasion of its 100th anniversary;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6BBFFC8F28C249A18A72C60DEBD90529"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes and appreciates the significant economic and cultural impact of the city of Hialeah on the South Florida region and the United States as a whole; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0B92DF18185B4E79A6DFF545C49EA962"><enum>(3)</enum><text>commends and honors the people of Hialeah for their unique and significant contributions to the prosperity, culture, and history of the United States.</text></paragraph></section>
</resolution-body>
</resolution> 


