<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6259D03D0BCB43CBBF95BBCDA91A3A66" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3983 IH: Veterans Claims Quality Improvement Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3983</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250612">June 12, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000603">Mr. Luttrell</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which
        was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans'
          Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to improve the quality of the adjudication of claims for benefits under the laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6804AD566B6747958ADFE99A2712892F" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H4A75DF6D431D4B859369015AFAF93FF3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Veterans Claims Quality Improvement Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H5D1F0FE98C6C4A67A504422FCB1AE0BF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Notice of avoidable deferrals of claims for benefits under laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs; study and report on certain opinions of Department of Veterans Affairs Office of General Counsel</header> 
<subsection id="HBAD9CBD83AC04AC0829F2F973A5FCBEA" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Notice of avoidable deferrals</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall develop policies, procedures, and technological capabilities to ensure that each employee of the Veterans Benefits Administration that commits an avoidable deferral with respect to a claim for benefits under the laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs in the National Work Queue is notified of any avoidable deferrals that such employee commits with respect to the same claim.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HED1FF77DCF8F49859577FF84503929EE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Study and report on certain OGC opinions</header> <paragraph id="HE0BDE5F968B64AB3A112265510D64AEC" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Study</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, in consultation with the Office of the General Counsel of the Department of Veterans Affairs and the Chairman of the Board of Veterans’ Appeals, shall complete a study to identify—</text>
<subparagraph id="H40033E31683B41348268816F2F9DC6B5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>issues about which an opinion from the Office of the General Counsel of the Department would foster consistency in the decisions of the Secretary with respect to claims for benefits under the laws administered by the Secretary; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H06EC2C0EAA4E424B963C9D61F37B5BAE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>issues raised in appeals of such decisions to the United States Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims before the date of the enactment of this Act about which the Office of the General Counsel has had inconsistent opinions in matters involving substantially similar questions of law or fact.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE808D07EE976479BBA6EA8793A95E777"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a report that includes—</text> <subparagraph id="H74A776A2CE5240C0A66BA0ED72625A8D"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>the findings of the study required by paragraph (1);</text>
                    </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB01B4B416F254EDDBD85D626070A3BF6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a statement of which issues identified pursuant to such study about which the Office of the General Counsel of the Department intends to publish an opinion; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD483CAE1DC354BE4B765B9F4A2C96C2B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a timeline for the publication of any such opinion.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H116B823954DA4400BF4BE04DABCF2928"><enum>3.</enum><header>Improvements to system for adjudication of claims for benefits under laws administered by Secretary of Veterans Affairs</header> 
<subsection id="HC3F5F8D5252C4A2BB855DEE06DD666E2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Program for quality assurance in decisions of Board of Veterans’ Appeals; performance reviews</header> 
<paragraph id="HECE0751BEB224B5EA34E9DA963EB3E9A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 7101 of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H39C596F0D1554819AA641D2EBC474F04" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="HE63503AE5AB24DBD867A8AEA31A0ADCE"><enum>(f)</enum> <paragraph id="HFA651B96CE644EA5855D7DE15E6D0AD2" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Chairman shall carry out a program to ensure quality in the decisions of the Board. Under such program, the Chairman shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H780ACBAE0E464F9E8FAE75274A1B26EC" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>develop policies and procedures for—</text> <clause id="H62EF119516174D09BC6B6293CA7460BC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>measuring quality in such decisions;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H71A5EAB82D8A45BDA41824BFEAF92246"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>maintaining data and identifying trends with respect to—</text> <subclause id="HE93C410159E345388A1D9B4AD6F30759"><enum>(I)</enum><text>errors in such decisions;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HA04CA6DDE34E463BAB40D4B752E75BC8" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>errors in decisions remanded or returned to the Board by the Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H84EED02BEB8545CCA09383DDF43EE9C1" commented="no"><enum>(III)</enum><text>specific members of the Board that issued decisions that were subsequently vacated by the Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims; and</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="HAFE2B62B8DF847DEA8D37FCA0A5B7710" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>ensuring any such decision of the Board to remand a claim for a benefit under a law administered by the Secretary is necessary under any applicable law or regulation;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB8EE200B4F8A4B74B6E7A3F80C78F15E" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to a claim for such a benefit that is remanded to the Board by the Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims—</text> 
<clause id="HFF5D444D8DEB4456B8313F8C639F4469"><enum>(i)</enum><text>inform any employee of the Board responsible for drafting the decision of the Board with respect to such claim that such decision was remanded;</text></clause> <clause id="H317976064CD34303A7516C186B01DF9A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provide any such employee with a copy of the relevant order of the Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims (including a copy of any accompanying joint motion for remand); and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H6D0A53563B1F41A48610CB28787EB391"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>provide incentives to such employees to review such relevant orders and joint motions for remand; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7C17AA2B7EEB43759DE4C222FDD4CD9C" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>ensure, to the maximum extent practicable, that any error identified by the Board under such program is corrected before the date on which the Board issues the final decision associated with such error.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3CFB7A3CC78A490CA267CEAE092E73B1" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In developing policies and procedures to measure quality in decisions of the Board pursuant to clause (i) of subparagraph (A) of paragraph (1), the Chairman shall consider the data and trends maintained and identified pursuant to clause (ii) of such subparagraph.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H78153DC0A5FB43979A3F144DAA26A875" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Chairman may use technology, including artificial intelligence, to maintain such data and identify such trends.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1F21BB4B37AC4509A8E32B44778F68CC" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Senate an annual report on the program required by this subsection that includes, with respect to the period covered by the report, an identification of—</text> <subparagraph id="HB15EC521887A4E5DB1A7E70672EDFA70"><enum>(A)</enum><text>elements, if any of the process of the Board for reviewing an appeal under this chapter that lead to errors in decisions of the Board; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFB573DD38CD9401BB2645F4628E58142"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the most common reasons that a claim for a benefit under a law administered by the Secretary was remanded to such Board by the Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE5D56EF32EAA443B9FD856259010DFE5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Deadline</header><text>The Secretary shall submit the first report required by paragraph (2) of such section (as added by paragraph (1)) by not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF95492CF68F146F79D36383075CCE6C2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Training program for certain employees of Board of Veterans’ Appeals; performance reviews</header> 
<paragraph id="H13094B41ABB54846867559A395C85AE3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Training program</header> 
<subparagraph id="HDCF88A8DFA6348F3BE846414A9CEDD9E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Chapter 71 of such title (as amended by subsection (a)) is further amended by inserting after section 7101A the following new section:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="HA08A616183304DB0A9669F3268C6A876" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <section id="HB864BA28DCAB4999A53B0B31536406FD"><enum>7101B.</enum><header>Training program for Members of Board on timely and correct adjudication of appeals</header> <subsection id="H4B7DF8FE5B184FF4A9614E674237C004"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in conjunction with the Chairman of the Board of Veterans’ Appeals, shall develop and carry out a program to provide Members of the Board training on timely and correct adjudication of appeals under this chapter.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0DE67CE621BC425D844405F333FE3F55"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Required considerations</header><text>In carrying out the program required by subsection (a), the Secretary shall consider the following:</text> <paragraph id="H34304330BC51462AAF2211038043B418"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Feedback, if any, from members of the Board and covered employees with respect to such program.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H501013EEA5EF40ADB0CF233151F88546"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Data on errors in decisions of the Board maintained pursuant to the program for quality assurance required by subsection (f) of section 7101 of this title.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC2BD0A2218B84C8EA006784019379F9A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Any decision of the Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims to remand a claim for benefits under the laws administered by the Secretary to the Board for further action, including a joint motion to remand such claim.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HBF3289E622E844A498D193D4E564EB0F" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Assessments of effectiveness</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in conjunction with the Chairman of the Board of Veterans’ Appeals, shall develop a method to assess, on an annual basis, the effectiveness of the training program under this section. In developing such method, the Secretary shall consider best practices for assessing the effectiveness of training programs, including the Kirkpatrick evaluation model.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H23B5848B1E53405181E8890748BD1F26"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text>The Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Senate an annual report on the program required by subsection (a) that includes, with respect to the period covered by the report—</text> 
<paragraph id="H5D64FE623E90418AAA983FC10718721F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a statement of the topics of the training provided pursuant to this section, disaggregated by—</text> <subparagraph id="HF608DF36A6304B6F8D61D93E8192EDB7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>mandatory training; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7A91D4B46F9044D8A30A2F3B5734D789"><enum>(B)</enum><text>non-mandatory training; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFBBABB961B08442D81260E12455CD47B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the results of the assessment of the effectiveness of such program required under subsection (b).</text></paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H9759EE73452A49B099A68163F7E85941"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Covered employee defined</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>covered employee</quote> means an employee of the Board who is—</text> <paragraph id="HF8E991C190AA43819880CE238B50DCCA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not a member of the Board; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H224F8F92E7C6477AB58F576CF76E5C63"><enum>(2)</enum><text>responsible for drafting decisions of the Board.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H685A54F515454DE5B55F2C57627A0A68"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of such chapter is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 7101A the following new item:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="HD17C503407C64D7B9AABD5C07B575D8C" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry level="item">7101B. Training program for Members of Board on timely and correct adjudication of appeals.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H61020DA3D2E149B79796BED7A79840D2" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Performance reviews of Members of the Board</header><text>Section 7101A of such title (as amended by paragraph (1)) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H8A0114C0E8CB46EE872E456C2D430C59" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B) of subsection (c)(1) by striking <quote>not less often than once every three years</quote> and inserting <quote>not less often than annually</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HED7F4DDC9E9745F9B6D341536AF9E064" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="HDDBD8D6A4B4648DC80643FB6A6BF5D8C" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="H9A4A1CA83F2C4B298C61BAE39334F71A" commented="no"><enum>(h)</enum> <paragraph id="HE7577DD9EDA0470FB49F00939EC5878F" display-inline="yes-display-inline" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>With respect to any performance review of a covered employee, the Secretary may not consider the timeliness or quality of work of any Member of the Board.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6C293E8C74F2422FB8F7C2959BB1EC2A" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In this subsection, the term <quote>covered employee</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 7101B of this title.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H62ED7347310743748BFC28047E16382C" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Decisions of Board to remand</header> <paragraph id="H00ADF29399B2405D8679EB7E644BD33B" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Information relating to decisions to remand</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 7104 of such title is amended in subsection (d)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H38E439061B1C43D0B958942F630217AC" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (1) through (3) as paragraphs (2) through (4), respsectively; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDAD56651D1C043A1B7526976B633E468" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting before paragraph (2) (as so redesignated), the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H67560049C5424859B17D4B2EC9A2B97A"> 
<paragraph id="H1A1180BD11FF48118942B57C06A7EA6E" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to a claim that the Board remands for further action, a statement of the specific reasons such claim was remanded, including any failure on the part of the Secretary to comply with—</text> <subparagraph id="H8F795683A11942489537B854DFC5FAAC" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary’s duty to assist under section 5103A of this title; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1B63A5AA9F564F2DB0FBE3CB128933E4" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary’s duty to notify under section 5103 of this title;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA9882364692943A6BC0D5D8CC7161FD3" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notice of remanded decision for certain employees</header><text>Such section is further amended in—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H8A41E2E30CF642838178FAC1CD514026"><enum>(A)</enum><text>subsection (e)—</text> <clause id="HBF0A68EAE7B9456183663D59FEF5E590"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (1) through (3) as subparagraphs (A) through (C), respectively;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H51D26E527AFC49BFB88A82031827C2B6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>After</quote> and inserting <quote>(1) After</quote>; and</text></clause> <clause id="HDFAAA5723442462DAE6EE258C06F92EA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="H50F5C806AF9E4F11923FE2FF737E02F0" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="H27CBADAECDEC428BAF624C6884469043" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If, pursuant to a decision on an appeal, the Board remands a claim for a benefit under a law administered by the Secretary for further action, the Secretary shall, to the maximum extent practicable, issue a copy of such decision to each employee of the Veterans Benefits Administration who committed the error resulting in the decision of the Board to remand, when applicable.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCD67DD975F4F49308EC56A09774C4C29"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (f), by striking <quote>under subsection (e)</quote> and inserting <quote> under paragraph (1) of subsection (e)</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H51E05F5A2D364E7DA7EB319C4FB9961A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Annual reports for Board of Veterans’ Appeals</header> 
<paragraph id="H535490ACC92F42F0B512D18FD8DC7070"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/71">Chapter 71</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/7114">section 7114</external-xref> the following new section:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="HF09070DEF79B47B79DA103B4CFF31596" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <section id="HEC147DF5BD3646FBA8782FBDD0039DAF"><enum>7115.</enum><header>Annual report on Board of Veterans’ Appeals</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Chairman of the Board shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Senate an annual report that includes, for each decision of the Board to remand a claim for a benefit under a law administered by the Secretary to the Secretary for further adjudication during the period covered by the report, a statement of the reasons for such decision of the Board, disaggregated by decisions on—</text> 
<paragraph id="H010C9F50282E49FE905945A11E01EB24"><enum>(1)</enum><text>claims with a rating decision dated on or after February 19, 2019; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H790B722B296D40239C96024CCB8ED126"><enum>(2)</enum><text>claims with a rating decision dated before such date.</text></paragraph></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H85A72B6620554812B887FED411E76D69"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Deadlines</header><text>The Secretary shall submit the first reports required by subsections (a) and (b) of section 7115 of such title (as added by paragraph (1)) by not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC18A8DD8F8D4470AB30E90DE65877E61"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of such chapter is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 7114 the following new item:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="H42BDEE7B5F8B41259C6153D31B132D04" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry level="section">7115. Annual report on Board of Veterans’ Appeals</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1838196F9C6C4EA69DC7D843B80B7910"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Plan for improvements to quality in decisions of Board</header> 
<paragraph id="H36F37CBCEC0741A0B882368920BE4825"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than six months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, in consultation with the Chairman of the Board of Veterans’ Appeals and the head of the Office of Administrative Review of the Veterans Benefits Administration, shall develop a plan to—</text> <subparagraph id="HCB26C361D03F40F88A6F686710281C00"><enum>(A)</enum><text>improve the quality of decisions of the Board to remand, pursuant to section 7104 of title 38, United States Code, claims for a benefit under a law administered by the Secretary to the Secretary for further action; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7C5ADA61752D43D483BB3583B886A6B2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>mitigate the number of such decisions that are unnecessary under any applicable law or regulation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H64B210AFE9954540A3DBF20CC87A9A8F" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>The Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Senate a report on such plan by not later than six months after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

