<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Reported-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-GOE25146-HS8-DS-5YL"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S28 RS: Informing Consumers about Smart Devices Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><calendar>Calendar No. 47</calendar><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 28</legis-num><associated-doc role="report">Report No. 119–13]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250107">January 7, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S355">Mr. Cruz</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S275">Ms. Cantwell</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S431">Mr. Curtis</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00" added-display-style="italic" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><action stage="Reported-in-Senate"><action-date date="20250428">April 28, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Reported by <sponsor name-id="S355">Mr. Cruz</sponsor>, without amendment</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the disclosure of a camera or recording capability in certain internet-connected devices.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H912ACD7959564F5EB8DD9ED60460120D"><section section-type="section-one" id="HEBC6A30FBC3E41499951D1089E0C942A"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Informing Consumers about Smart Devices Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HF2AD8FF5F04D4B41A2BF12B4E124A3FF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Required disclosure of a camera or recording capability in certain internet-connected devices</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Each manufacturer of a covered device shall disclose, clearly and conspicuously and prior to purchase, whether the covered device manufactured by the manufacturer contains a camera or microphone as a component of the covered device. </text></section><section id="HA9A22BC9E6EA46F190EDC54E38C5296F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Enforcement by the Federal Trade Commission</header><subsection id="H60FE593ED41A48DABD94CFAFF02F1246"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Unfair or deceptive acts or practices</header><text>A violation of section 2 shall be treated as a violation of a rule defining an unfair or deceptive act or practice prescribed under section 18(a)(1)(B) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/57a">15 U.S.C. 57a(a)(1)(B)</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection id="H6AD2C1EDAD5743DCB229F9B5D4F7D22D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Actions by the Commission</header><paragraph id="HB61F2425B41A44E8AF084066E10915BE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Federal Trade Commission (in this Act referred to as the <quote>Commission</quote>) shall enforce this Act in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though all applicable terms and provisions of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>) were incorporated into and made a part of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC1CC9E7AF74D4242AA21C7EAFC611F4B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Penalties and privileges</header><text>Any person who violates this Act or a regulation promulgated under this Act shall be subject to the penalties and entitled to the privileges and immunities provided in the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id12ce2de410c7473d827ce713228e5602"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Savings clause</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to limit the authority of the Commission under any other provision of law. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H84A3B62B1C7A47D3A9A2BFA53A4E8770"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Commission guidance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Commission, through outreach to relevant private entities, shall issue guidance to assist manufacturers in complying with the requirements of this Act, including guidance about best practices for making the disclosure required by section 2 as clear and conspicuous and age appropriate as practicable and about best practices for the use of a pictorial (as defined in section 2(a) of the Consumer Review Fairness Act of 2016 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/45b">15 U.S.C. 45b(a)</external-xref>)) visual representation of the information to be disclosed.</text></subsection><subsection id="H51837F310EF347FF9601AE5DA48C2E7C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Tailored guidance</header><text>A manufacturer of a covered device may petition the Commission for tailored guidance as to how to meet the requirements of section 2 consistent with existing rules of practice or any successor rules. </text></subsection><subsection id="H10D200CEAA804B6682D9087CAA33AEA2"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Limitation on Commission Guidance</header><text>No guidance issued by the Commission with respect to this Act shall confer any rights on any person, State, or locality, nor shall operate to bind the Commission or any person to the approach recommended in such guidance. In any enforcement action brought pursuant to this Act, the Commission shall allege a specific violation of a provision of this Act. The Commission may not base an enforcement action on, or execute a consent order based on, practices that are alleged to be inconsistent with any such guidelines, unless the practices allegedly violate section 2.</text></subsection></section><section id="H78BF421ABE4E4CD7ADA58BB77680D889"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definition of covered device</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">As used in this Act, the term <term>covered device</term>—</text><paragraph id="HCC674D74579E428E9C0801C9E69F87EB"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means a consumer product, as defined by section 3(a) of the Consumer Product Safety Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/2052">15 U.S.C. 2052(a)</external-xref>) that is capable of connecting to the internet, a component of which is a camera or microphone; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2EE00B647AD0429E8BEF830B471FF9A9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>does not include—</text><subparagraph id="H0B465DC91F074DCEA40E511B0431A2B2"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a telephone (including a mobile phone), a laptop, tablet, or any device that a consumer would reasonably expect to have a microphone or camera;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9C877470EE8844B08D453D77B43DB86B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any device that is specifically marketed as a camera, telecommunications device, or microphone; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4D374B89F67E4D2E8C11E432065E31DD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any device or apparatus described in sections 255, 716, and 718, and subsections (aa) and (bb) of section 303 of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/255">47 U.S.C. 255</external-xref>; 617; 619; and 303(aa) and (bb)), and any regulations promulgated thereunder.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H5030E4E4685C41E997FA947538D4FC18"><enum>5.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act shall apply to all covered devices manufactured after the date that is 180 days after the date on which guidance is issued by the Commission under section 3(c), and shall not apply to covered devices manufactured or sold before such date, or otherwise introduced into interstate commerce before such date.</text></section></legis-body><endorsement><action-date date="20250428">April 28, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Reported without amendment</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

