<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H39442BB9FF22449CA0C16969E5867290" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3421 IH: Gunnison Outdoor Resources Protection Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3421</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250515">May 15, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001100">Mr. Hurd of Colorado</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To designate certain special management areas, wildlife conservation areas, protection areas, recreation areas, wilderness areas, and a scientific research and education area in the State of Colorado, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8420EC535AC240BEA5B682E837576E79" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H8A10B8D9893542358A4D73A35EBD5354"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Gunnison Outdoor Resources Protection Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HFDC8E842E0ED438C8CB37E842CF0E5D7"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="HED5F810EBFA845A6A422DA33B68F7955"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Collaboratively developed</header><text>The term <term>collaboratively developed</term>, with respect to a project, means the project is developed and implemented through a collaborative process that—</text> <subparagraph id="H4E907ADD106C4B66848854E29BCB5154"><enum>(A)</enum><text>includes multiple interested persons representing diverse interests; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H75E53D88EA0F4E55B1F05FDF66BDA7F1"><enum>(B)</enum> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H6EECC6B2B69E4B2680546FC0B1EF733A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is transparent and nonexclusive; or</text></clause> <clause id="H1D53A5FB02334C7898BB99BCA8DD9F24" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>meets the requirements for a resource advisory committee under—</text> 
<subclause id="HDE06810DEB0A4D5F8105F31C70DF76EC"><enum>(I)</enum><text>for projects carried out on National Forest System land, subsections (c) through (f) of section 205 of the Secure Rural Schools and Community Self-Determination Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/7125">16 U.S.C. 7125</external-xref>); or</text></subclause> <subclause id="HA223958D5477464FAB088A9D9784CA97"><enum>(II)</enum><text>for projects carried out on Bureau of Land Management land, subpart 1784 of part 1700 of title 43, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD05E0B9CB0DD47928EB41E5B16D4537F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>County</header><text>The term <term>County</term> means Gunnison County, Colorado.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H58CA6AE28C6B435A9802316DC28FBF9D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered area</header><text>The term <term>covered area</term> means each of the Special Management Areas, Wildlife Conservation Areas, Protection Areas, and Recreation Management Areas and the Scientific Research and Education Area.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HADF1BF6135BF4E96A09536C16161CAB4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Decommission</header><text>The term <term>decommission</term>, with respect to a road, means—</text> <subparagraph id="H3ADD5D6C07FB4B7DA8FE0DB24FB048FB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>reestablishing native vegetation on the road;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2289CE59464B4DB3AD88F58FD6D83892"><enum>(B)</enum><text>restoring any natural drainage, watershed function, or other ecological processes that were disrupted or adversely impacted by the road by removing or hydrologically disconnecting the road prism and reestablishing stable slope contours;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA955F06BA1BD47118F14F875D7A96E3F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>effectively blocking the road to vehicular traffic, where feasible; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7A5AD68EE459428EBAF128A8DBCDB98D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>developing and implementing an effective monitoring and response plan for invasive species and vehicular traffic incursions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H60C6E8A02A184D19AD1733032D3AA9EA"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Ecological integrity</header><text>The term <term>ecological integrity</term> has the meaning given the term in section 219.19 of title 36, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1F7FF3ED1E034BE89BA8C2D281DD8743"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Off-highway vehicle</header><text>The term <term>off-highway vehicle</term>—</text> <subparagraph id="HB0F0FDB8F4E34D52A4143634B22F2D05"><enum>(A)</enum><text>with respect to National Forest System land, has the meaning given the term in section 212.1 of title 36, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H06977A5F3147425097934D7CF15A22AF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to land managed by the Bureau of Land Management, has the meaning given the term <term>off-road vehicle</term> in section 8340.0–5 of title 43, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H14B3101ECD7241BFA3A7433593EE5911"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Over-snow vehicle</header><text>The term <term>over-snow vehicle</term> has the meaning given the term in section 212.1 of title 36, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4E25231EE23349F98E5E4712F12DA171"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Protection Area</header><text>The term <term>Protection Area</term> means a protection area designated by section 5(a).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H643500F1E56C4675BEA3EF32F91CAA10"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Recreation Management Area</header><text>The term <term>Recreation Management Area</term> means a recreation management area designated by section 6(a).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6052D9B8F24B4FDA9C8782D85EF943DF"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Restore</header><text>The term <term>restore</term> has the meaning given the term in section 219.19 of title 36, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE01892E8771242159E8DFBDBE3841E9B"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Scientific Research and Education Area</header><text>The term <term>Scientific Research and Education Area</term> means the Rocky Mountain Scientific Research and Education Area designated by section 7(a).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5EDE9F86BF684D9599C6ADD35037D46B"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HD30C7761C9254557943A6DCC122A5183"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary of Agriculture (acting through the Chief of the Forest Service), with respect to National Forest System land; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H308FE0AB20E84A64A0C40388619311C8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary of the Interior with respect to land managed by the Director of the Bureau of Land Management.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H77076C5C781546ED8866B2EEDFA1F29F"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Special Management Area</header><text>The term <term>Special Management Area</term> means a special management area designated by section 3(a).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF1CB040873674865944D17F8875AACE6"><enum>(14)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means the State of Colorado.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0336D59F422946F3BE010A793CD3BC77"><enum>(15)</enum><header>Wilderness area</header><text>The term <term>wilderness area</term> means any area designated as wilderness by the amendments to section 2(a) of the Colorado Wilderness Act of 1993 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1132">16 U.S.C. 1132</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/103/77">Public Law 103–77</external-xref>) made by section 8(a).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6B0E045870024C40B009624C3651581A"><enum>(16)</enum><header>Wildland-urban interface</header><text>The term <term>wildland-urban interface</term> means land within a covered area that is within <fraction>1/4</fraction> mile of the interface and intermix areas mapped as the wildland-urban interface in the document entitled <quote>The 2010 Wildland-Urban Interface of the Conterminous United States</quote> and published by the Department of Agriculture in 2015.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE9EEF36F4B60426BA3DFD3E7C3021E80"><enum>(17)</enum><header>Wildlife Conservation Area</header><text>The term <term>Wildlife Conservation Area</term> means a wildlife conservation area designated by section 4(a).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H36FBA1596C6641ADB923F6B96240DDDA"><enum>(18)</enum><header>Winter travel management plan</header><text>The term <term>winter travel management plan</term> means a decision designating roads, trails, or areas for over-snow vehicle use in accordance with—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H83CF790AFFA345639CB095660C0F4D2A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case of Forest Service land within a covered area, subpart C of part 212 of title 36, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H0319032C28A24C84B36FCE3FFC528295"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of Bureau of Land Management land within a covered area, subpart 8342 of title 43, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> <section id="H402633CC638C44C3AED3780D882D0950"><enum>3.</enum><header>Designation of special management areas</header> <subsection id="H044AB270942A4008B0A714F9577FB3A4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation</header> <paragraph id="HD7EBA575E0F94E2C99BDF7442FA492A3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>American Flag Special Management Area</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, certain Federal land in the County managed by the Forest Service comprising approximately 36,171 acres, as generally depicted as <quote>American Flag SMA</quote> on the map entitled <quote>Sheet 4: Brush Creek, Cement Creek, and Spring Creek</quote> and dated August 27, 2024, is designated as the <quote>American Flag Special Management Area</quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H20AD011FA24E49C2B8DE85C34C91668B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Beckwiths Special Management Area</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, certain Federal land in the County managed by the Forest Service comprising approximately 24,031 acres, as generally depicted as <quote>Beckwiths SMA</quote> on the map entitled <quote>Sheet 3: Kebler and Schofield Pass</quote> and dated August 27, 2024, is designated as the <quote>Beckwiths Special Management Area</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H88C880FCFC094479918322D572ECD234"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Clear Fork Special Management Area</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, certain Federal land in the County managed by the Forest Service comprising approximately 37,998 acres, as generally depicted as <quote>Clear Fork SMA</quote> on the map entitled <quote>Sheet 2: McClure Pass</quote> and dated August 27, 2024, is designated as the <quote>Clear Fork Special Management Area</quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF14B53CF4C8C495194E13436B37D50A1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>McIntosh Mountain Special Management Area</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, certain Federal land in the County managed by the Bureau of Land Management and the Forest Service comprising approximately 22,497 acres, as generally depicted as <quote>McIntosh Mountain SMA</quote> on the map entitled <quote>Sheet 8: Gunnison Valley and Ohio Pass</quote> and dated August 27, 2024, is designated as the <quote>McIntosh Mountain Special Management Area</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA703F5DC1A9A4D91AD52C97966217DBC"><enum>(5)</enum><header>North Poverty Gulch Special Management Area</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, certain Federal land in the County managed by the Forest Service comprising approximately 5,476 acres, as generally depicted as <quote>North Poverty Gulch SMA</quote> on the map entitled <quote>Sheet 3: Kebler and Schofield Pass</quote> and dated August 27, 2024, is designated as the <quote>North Poverty Gulch Special Management Area</quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H02813FA752394BF3AE233DB3EF317827"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Pilot Knob Special Management Area</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, certain Federal land in the County managed by the Forest Service comprising approximately 16,973 acres, as generally depicted as <quote>Pilot Knob SMA</quote> on the map entitled <quote>Sheet 2: McClure Pass</quote> and dated August 27, 2024, is designated as the <quote>Pilot Knob Special Management Area</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4B3AA0B3BA444248BB4C1D562D6972A5"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Signal Peak Special Management Area</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, certain Federal land in the County managed by the Bureau of Land Management and the Forest Service comprising approximately 28,345 acres, as generally depicted as <quote>Signal Peak SMA</quote> on the map entitled <quote>Sheet 9: Cabin Creek</quote> and dated August 27, 2024, is designated as the <quote>Signal Peak Special Management Area</quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA9FA97AF164F463EB77841915875755D"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Union Park Special Management Area</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, certain Federal land in the County managed by the Forest Service comprising approximately 22,483 acres, as generally depicted as <quote>Union Park SMA</quote> on the map entitled <quote>Sheet 5: Union Park</quote> and dated August 27, 2024, is designated as the <quote>Union Park Special Management Area</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2FB8B50F474F489F8B202DE62888E3AB"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Whetstone Headwaters Special Management Area</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, certain Federal land in the County managed by the Forest Service and the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 20,676 acres, as generally depicted as <quote>Whetstone Headwaters SMA</quote> on the map entitled <quote>Sheet 3: Kebler and Schofield Pass</quote> and dated August 27, 2024, is designated as the <quote>Whetstone Headwaters Special Management Area</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HBEFC7F0680D640C7ABB5D25689A816DB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of the Special Management Areas is to conserve, protect, and enhance for the benefit of present and future generations the natural, scenic, scientific, cultural, watershed, recreation, and wildlife resources of the Special Management Areas.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H1C41937CA5C84EFBA25F5BB0164160F0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Management</header> <paragraph id="H0E2D9D1E043B4F70830CAFE1F006FEE1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall manage the Special Management Areas in a manner that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H70C1861D335E413FBC04F44D73372191"><enum>(A)</enum><text>conserves, protects, and enhances the resources of the Special Management Areas; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEE9A3F4CC41442FEA3638E2AC031CFBD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is in accordance with—</text> 
<clause id="HAA65B1E7BE3D44F2BB3AE56269BAAD3D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>this Act; and</text></clause> <clause id="H12C62109E60A4238BED9761B01B0E056"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>other applicable laws.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H113980A939154D159ED2EE921277CE0B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Uses</header> 
<subparagraph id="H1DE60B5145414EE6B163A212605AE3E2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall only allow uses of the Special Management Areas that the Secretary determines would further the purpose described in subsection (b).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA1173EA404F647DA8495AEECF589B124"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Vehicle and bicycle use</header> <clause id="H6D96431C8F4C40E197DB0376481403F5"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The use of off-highway vehicles and bicycles in the Special Management Areas shall be permitted only on roads, trails, and areas designated for use by those vehicles on the date of enactment of this Act, except—</text> 
<subclause id="HEED2C12C4FC1448C8A85A3F800258C68"><enum>(I)</enum><text>as needed for administrative purposes;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H77E7DD2087E84CE4B00343F2C87A9E8D"><enum>(II)</enum><text>to respond to an emergency; or</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H14CFFF4254AB48218B9F9D82FB886ED1"><enum>(III)</enum><text>as authorized under clauses (ii) and (iii).</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H15878F3368CB46D1A5F6722018DB22E9"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Winter travel management</header><text>For any portion of a Special Management Area for which the Secretary has not adopted a winter travel management plan as of the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary—</text> 
<subclause id="H8117A680DB97458B83746CAC3F9AD0A5"><enum>(I)</enum><text>shall, not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, adopt a winter travel management plan with respect to the applicable portion of the Special Management Area; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HE6031D8B579D4789A58E5F58A656083F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>may, during any period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act and ending on the date of adoption of a winter travel management plan for the applicable portion under subclause (I), permit the use of over-snow vehicles in the applicable portion of the Special Management Area in accordance with the applicable land management plan or other applicable management direction.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="HA5663D394A8747B4820F7489DB0B7085"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Potential trails</header><text>The Secretary may permit—</text> <subclause id="H671B13016C0345449A1F66470A76F699"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the use of bicycles on the potential trails described in paragraph (3) if the trails are designated by the Secretary for the use; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H9A9BD61E51C54D78B732D1239E21F105"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the use of off-highway vehicles on the potential trails described in subparagraphs (A), (C), and (F) of paragraph (3) if the trails are designated by the Secretary for the use.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8286BE520D9D4BD29DBCB28D9CAB27F7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Nothing in this section affects the potential development, in accordance with applicable law, of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB150B9D26E8F4550B3EFB97FB0D62DE2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a proposed trail of less than 50 inches in width, commonly known as the <quote>Big Grassy Trail</quote>, within the American Flag Special Management Area designated by subsection (a)(1);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD6B13A025DC143F58200ED9F3537AC02"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the proposed trails, commonly known as the <quote>Crested Butte to Paonia Trail</quote> and the <quote>Crested Butte to Carbondale Trail</quote>, within the Beckwiths Special Management Area designated by subsection (a)(2);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBCF56772CD394E99968D09C41BC45EF4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the proposed trails, commonly known as the <quote>Antelope Ridge Trail and Connector</quote>, the <quote>East West Antelope Trail</quote>, the <quote>West Antelope Trail</quote>, and the <quote>Mill Creek Connector</quote>, within the McIntosh Mountain Special Management Area designated by subsection (a)(4);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1DAA493FB3D14A0F814F1DA1A32CA555"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the proposed trail, commonly known as the <quote>Gunnison to Crested Butte Trail</quote>, and the trails generally depicted in figure 7 of the document entitled <quote>Candidate Conservation Agreement: For the Gunnison sage-grouse, Centrocercus minimus—Gunnison Basin Population</quote> and dated 2012 within the Signal Peak Special Management Area designated by subsection (a)(7);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2503074292A844578A606674896A02E5"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the proposed trails, commonly known as the <quote>Gunnison to Crested Butte Trail</quote> and the <quote>Baxter Gulch to Splain’s Gulch Trail</quote>, in the Whetstone Headwaters Special Management Area designated by subsection (a)(9); or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF90AA0003E44432FB7644DF68D796E7D"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the proposed trail, commonly known as the <quote>Splain’s Gulch to Carbon Creek Trail</quote>, in the Whetstone Headwaters Special Management Area designated by subsection (a)(9).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H6D99EED6051B4266B681C4B77BC718BF"><enum>4.</enum><header>Designation of wildlife conservation areas</header> 
<subsection id="H8D92E512D0D14CA2928C8F4F8584F8AB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation</header> 
<paragraph id="H04DBF5708D354315B4AD54D90872F73E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Cabin Creek Wildlife Conservation Area</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, certain Federal land in the County managed by the Bureau of Land Management and the Forest Service comprising approximately 29,518 acres, as generally depicted as <quote>Cabin Creek WCA</quote> on the map entitled <quote>Sheet 9: Cabin Creek</quote> and dated August 27, 2024, is designated as the <quote>Cabin Creek Wildlife Conservation Area</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1E504D48EAF04389AF3A86483FB0DD8F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Flat Top Wildlife Conservation Area</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, certain Federal land in the County managed by the Forest Service comprising approximately 28,844 acres, as generally depicted as <quote>Flat Top WCA</quote> on the map entitled <quote>Sheet 8: Gunnison Valley and Ohio Pass</quote> and dated August 27, 2024, is designated as the <quote>Flat Top Wildlife Conservation Area</quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAA006B6E3E9E4201B42E8AC5DD01D3FE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Lake Gulch and Cebolla Creek Wildlife Conservation Area</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, certain Federal land in the County managed by the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 50,535 acres, as generally depicted as <quote>Lake Gulch and Cebolla Creek WCA</quote> on the map entitled <quote>Sheet 11: Lake Fork</quote> and dated August 27, 2024, is designated as the <quote>Lake Gulch and Cebolla Creek Wildlife Conservation Area</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9CEC21C1472F4CF595497707D172AF31"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Matchless Wildlife Conservation Area</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, certain Federal land in the County managed by the Forest Service and the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 12,975 acres, as generally depicted as <quote>Matchless WCA</quote> on the map entitled <quote>Sheet 4: Brush Creek, Cement Creek, and Spring Creek</quote> and dated August 27, 2024, is designated as the <quote>Matchless Wildlife Conservation Area</quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H63F6D6E51A3349D4954B0424EB65380C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Munsey Creek Wildlife Conservation Area</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, certain Federal land in the County managed by the Forest Service and the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 3,281 acres, as generally depicted as <quote>Munsey Creek WCA</quote> on the map entitled <quote>Sheet 3: Kebler and Schofield Pass</quote> and dated August 27, 2024, is designated as the <quote>Munsey Creek Wildlife Conservation Area</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD056A6C59D6D43E48885B46BE952EBA6"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Pinnacles Wildlife Conservation Area</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, certain Federal land in the County managed by the Forest Service and the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 27,935 acres, as generally depicted as <quote>Pinnacles WCA</quote> on the map entitled <quote>Sheet 8: Gunnison Valley and Ohio Pass</quote> and dated August 27, 2024, is designated as the <quote>Pinnacles Wildlife Conservation Area</quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF8032A45B0434714B4F48833761EC0FE"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Powderhorn Wildlife Conservation Area</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, certain Federal land in the County managed by the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 27,668 acres, as generally depicted as <quote>Powderhorn WCA</quote> on the map entitled <quote>Sheet 11: Lake Fork</quote> and dated August 27, 2024, is designated as the <quote>Powderhorn Wildlife Conservation Area</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF57B15C28BAA408CA161A82616D405A7"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Sawtooth Wildlife Conservation Area</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, certain Federal land in the County and in Saguache County, Colorado, managed by the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 43,109 acres, as generally depicted as <quote>Sawtooth WCA</quote> on the map entitled <quote>Sheet 11: Lake Fork</quote> and dated August 27, 2024, is designated as the <quote>Sawtooth Wildlife Conservation Area</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE313B7567B694EC083F1571C8AF1F186"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of the Wildlife Conservation Areas are—</text> <paragraph id="H6AEDC1C51B2D42ADAC8F8A61A36F6F1A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to conserve, protect, enhance, and restore for the benefit and enjoyment of present and future generations the wildlife and wildlife habitat of the Wildlife Conservation Areas; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1B1D0BD013684C88A42300DE76FAE237"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to conserve, protect, and enhance for the benefit and enjoyment of present and future generations the natural, scenic, scientific, cultural, watershed, and recreation resources of the Wildlife Conservation Areas.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H707D5B6BFD4041C3A1DCB4D8D1528F43"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Management</header> <paragraph id="H2107760B91DE4BD7B4AA1383047D17DE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall manage the Wildlife Conservation Areas in a manner that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H5F0D07418C224BAF88C93F04E81427B2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>furthers the purposes of the Wildlife Conservation Areas; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1692A914C6334CBFB2C07B223B1A74D3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is in accordance with—</text> 
<clause id="HDB265E7E0F8943529C049150C4025EC7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>this Act; and</text></clause> <clause id="H7ABD5D2E8967480BA0A35805959F4657"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>other applicable laws.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBC99197EB33B4E4FA62F226E6A0869B3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Uses</header> 
<subparagraph id="H6258A58652F94515AA3AA746277F7FEE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall only allow uses of the Wildlife Conservation Areas that the Secretary determines would further the purposes described in subsection (b).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H91C256B76A9F4911B6F90062727EE37E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Vehicle and bicycle use</header> <clause id="H9FDD1FD6B93C4AE597843D60D4EDAD9C"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The use of off-highway vehicles and bicycles in the Wildlife Conservation Areas shall be permitted only on roads, trails, and areas designated for the uses on the date of enactment of this Act.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H55D316B985354F91AD0AD1172993C399"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>Notwithstanding clause (i)—</text> <subclause id="H859D68BB331946B58CD21CD7AFAC0608"><enum>(I)</enum><text>off-highway vehicles and bicycles may be permitted—</text> 
<item id="HDEC67EAE941F4B8E99924B1C6FB7CEA9"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>as needed for administrative purposes; or</text></item> <item id="HD4A15AE8FB96415CA8D091EEA5EE5695"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>to respond to an emergency;</text></item></subclause> 
<subclause id="HA93BD023535B43A3A8F353D9B5460167"><enum>(II)</enum><text>for any portion of a Wildlife Conservation Area for which the Secretary has not adopted a winter travel management plan as of the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary—</text> <item id="HE825792FF52843BE922E92EADD191F71"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>shall, not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, adopt a winter travel management plan for the applicable portion of the Wildlife Conservation Area; and</text></item> 
<item id="H7EABDBA5E18643D28B6C3DB170C847F9"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>may, during the period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act and ending on the date of adoption of a winter travel management plan for the applicable portion under item (aa), permit the use of over-snow vehicles in the applicable portion of the Wildlife Conservation Area in accordance with the applicable land management plan or other applicable management direction;</text></item></subclause> <subclause id="H2FDC2825AFBB435F8BF2ACC4FEF4F400"><enum>(III)</enum><text>except as authorized under subclause (I), the use of off-highway vehicles and bicycles shall be prohibited in the Matchless Wildlife Conservation Area designated by subsection (a)(4); and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H854E5C2F678E49569A6193CEF2CBD8C1"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the Secretary may permit the use of bicycles on the potential trails described in paragraph (3) if the trails are designated by the Secretary for the use.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC68C613E885345DCB021AA1DBCC147AA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Nothing in this section affects the potential development, in accordance with applicable law, of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HA40007960BB44EE4843F6E57A95BFDD4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the proposed trail, commonly known as the <quote>Gunnison to Crested Butte Trail</quote>, in the Flat Top Wildlife Conservation Area designated by subsection (a)(2);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0FEE514C50D241F6B40750E24E62DCC2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the proposed trail, commonly known as the <quote>Crested Butte to Carbondale Trail</quote>, in the Munsey Creek Wildlife Conservation Area designated by subsection (a)(5); or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H47861E2A72E74EC5B1B452AF2CC05516"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the proposed trails, commonly known as the <quote>Tenderfoot Mountain to Bambi’s Trail</quote> and the <quote>Big Loop Trail</quote>, in the Sawtooth Wildlife Conservation Area designated by subsection (a)(8).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HC97B1F12BB7F4ED4AC0789AC03E8DD99"><enum>5.</enum><header>Designation of protection areas</header> <subsection id="H4A2E99AD0CEB41ECBB10C723585A72EE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation</header> <paragraph id="H289EAE1F0F1E4818A1086AA4C8174C4F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Castle Protection Area</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, certain Federal land in the County managed by the Forest Service comprising approximately 6,390 acres, as generally depicted as <quote>Castle Protection Area</quote> on the map entitled <quote>Sheet 8: Gunnison Valley and Ohio Pass</quote> and dated August 27, 2024, is designated as the <quote>Castle Protection Area</quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7D876E25206C4E26BEBA772A55D079F5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Deer Creek Protection Area</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, certain Federal land in the County managed by the Forest Service comprising approximately 3,136 acres, as generally depicted as <quote>Deer Creek Protection Area</quote> on the map entitled <quote>Sheet 3: Kebler and Schofield Pass</quote> and dated August 27, 2024, is designated as the <quote>Deer Creek Protection Area</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA977A99DF4A24A45B5795697464ECE5A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Granite Basin Protection Area</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, certain Federal land in the County managed by the Forest Service and the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 9,666 acres, as generally depicted as <quote>Granite Basin Protection Area</quote> on the map entitled <quote>Sheet 4: Brush Creek, Cement Creek, and Spring Creek</quote> and dated August 27, 2024, is designated as the <quote>Granite Basin Protection Area</quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD1C09E550F604FE78249536A10142440"><enum>(4)</enum><header>South Poverty Gulch Protection Area</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, certain Federal land in the County managed by the Forest Service and the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 1,350 acres, as generally depicted as <quote>South Poverty Gulch Protection Area</quote> on the map entitled <quote>Sheet 3: Kebler and Schofield Pass</quote> and dated August 27, 2024, is designated as the <quote>South Poverty Gulch Protection Area</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H0E926C0C45BC4C0C8F04D3CEFFCCA6A9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of the Protection Areas are—</text> 
<paragraph id="HB83FFFF5A08C4E4F86381EF78EA6E0F8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to protect the natural and undeveloped character of the Protection Areas; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H35C464D5BD514F59B792E4CCBA4D34A5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to conserve and protect for the benefit and enjoyment of present and future generations the natural, scenic, scientific, cultural, watershed, recreation, and wildlife resources of the Protection Areas.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1398DEF48E1B42EBB8EBF1AE2335531E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Management</header> 
<paragraph id="H8B5F0444EDDF4E7FA9B990B1428ECDA2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall manage the Protection Areas in a manner that—</text> <subparagraph id="H7C575AB2AC494C5DADEEF570E40DC466"><enum>(A)</enum><text>furthers the purposes of the Protection Areas described in subsection (b); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAF3ED3CF33224B87B11FE2667CF103DD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is in accordance with—</text> <clause id="H8274E7A3621E42C9BC482E4677F41631"><enum>(i)</enum><text>this Act; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HB809C2C47A2D4901B85F404B3BCDEC58"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>other applicable laws.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2BAD923C49B1493C9639AC088C6EA9C7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Uses</header> <subparagraph id="H66DE612CB2B8401584A566AB1378E608"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall only allow uses of the Protection Areas that the Secretary determines would further the purposes described in subsection (b).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9F65EEACF6CD47B983019EC46BC11DD9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Vehicle use</header> 
<clause id="H1A5AB567FE534A668D9EBFBF44AEC862"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in clause (ii), as needed for administrative purposes, or to respond to an emergency, the use of off-highway vehicles in the Protection Areas is prohibited.</text></clause> <clause id="H1E541A374E8A4D94AD6168BAA7EFB80B"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Over-snow vehicles</header><text>The Secretary may permit the use of over-snow vehicles in the Deer Creek Protection Area designated by subsection (a)(2) on roads, trails, and areas designated for the use on the date of enactment of this Act.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDBAC5B690D15456B9C2CC45146960EDE"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Bicycles</header><text>The Secretary may permit the use of bicycles in the Protection Areas only—</text> <clause id="HF95B09B4E6704A258D690D8C6051C035"><enum>(i)</enum><text>on roads and trails designated for the use on the date of enactment of this Act;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H84DE6F759BB345DEAADCF8B129B97E73"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>as needed for administrative purposes;</text></clause> <clause id="H95906AB1BD9F45259F8F8A956328CB0A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to respond to an emergency; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H306F1FF5648E4C37A017DE0E8D6B41A5"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>if designated by the Secretary for the use on the potential trails described in paragraph (3).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0BBF36E4404B4E669E88F0AD620F7F2C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Nothing in this section affects the potential development, in accordance with applicable law, of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H9D2E0DFEEDB1418F820B3B4D72F85124"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the proposed trail, commonly known as the <quote>Deer Creek to Brush Creek Connector Trail</quote>, within the Deer Creek Protection Area designated by subsection (a)(2);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H669A0887135A485EA8DBF8AC62F20637"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the proposed trail, commonly known as the <quote>Eccher Exit Trail</quote>, within the Granite Basin Protection Area designated by subsection (a)(3); or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HED84996B59C74261906BE3D7E3C73657"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the proposed trail, commonly known as the <quote>Lower Loop Trail Extension</quote>, in the South Poverty Gulch Protection Area designated by subsection (a)(4).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H468C3C89B05642F384D4DC11F392742B"><enum>6.</enum><header>Designation of recreation management areas</header> <subsection id="H4AF48305F2434A8CADBF85EC2B68D42A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation</header> <paragraph id="H76A4E1C34DFF40BF85EECB7F47E11245"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Double Top Recreation Management Area</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, certain Federal land in the County managed by the Forest Service comprising approximately 14,734 acres, as generally depicted as <quote>Double Top RMA</quote> on the map entitled <quote>Sheet 4: Brush Creek, Cement Creek, and Spring Creek</quote> and dated August 27, 2024, is designated as the <quote>Double Top Recreation Management Area</quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9C3BDC7E931A47AD850176097727017B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Horse Ranch Park Recreation Management Area</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, certain Federal land in the County managed by the Forest Service comprising approximately 3,513 acres, as generally depicted as <quote>Horse Ranch Park RMA</quote> on the map entitled <quote>Sheet 3: Kebler and Schofield Pass</quote> and dated August 27, 2024, is designated as the <quote>Horse Ranch Park Recreation Management Area</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF17C0F9F1D44420C9D6ACE44050AD80B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of the Recreation Management Areas are—</text> 
<paragraph id="HD3F60966893843D3AFCB24A6DED68CA7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to provide for, and improve the management of, recreation resources in the Recreation Management Areas for the benefit and enjoyment of present and future generation; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8BDFDEB3D6A94D04BD9541D7F8770575"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to conserve, protect, and enhance for the benefit and enjoyment of present and future generations the natural, scenic, scientific, cultural, watershed, and wildlife resources of the Recreation Management Areas.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE0848F5456284B8DBAFE4F75E028C265"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Management</header> 
<paragraph id="HF836E5D2B15F4296B41C9A9B5C4EC784"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall manage the Recreation Management Areas in a manner that—</text> <subparagraph id="HFE9F26F8F73C401CBD56E8539008EE27"><enum>(A)</enum><text>furthers the purposes of the Recreation Management Areas described in subsection (b); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8885CDD9581542E4AC67A8D9D326F8BB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is in accordance with—</text> <clause id="H200B7ECDCD9941A8BFB57A711C163B28"><enum>(i)</enum><text>this Act; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H2BFADD78BD8340DB8C811FF4CBE91C36"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>other applicable laws.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5DFCB8AC42654271A22AAF22BBA5D020"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Uses</header> <subparagraph id="H154FB83E1C684239842A77D8B8D3114F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall only allow uses of the Recreation Management Areas that the Secretary determines would further the purposes described in subsection (b).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H60193B74C44E4C6CB14DDBF09C9CF690"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Vehicle and bicycle use</header> 
<clause id="HCCC6B18F05B740A2B113E76FA0668992"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Double top</header> 
<subclause id="H343322CE146344CBA9342EB6EDA0636C"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subclause (II), the use of off-highway vehicles and bicycles in the Double Top Recreation Management Area designated by subsection (a)(1) shall be permitted only on roads and trails designated for the use on the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subclause> <subclause id="HCC6E2B08B0E94D71BED464227727F2F0"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Exceptions</header> <item id="H2521865C2D5F48D1B46E840A695E2C50"><enum>(aa)</enum><header>Over-snow vehicles</header><text>Except as provided in item (bb), the use of over-snow vehicles shall not be permitted in the Double Top Recreation Management Area designated by subsection (a)(1).</text></item> 
<item id="H0A02ECCAC86443F5A30BE8A2815B5169"><enum>(bb)</enum><header>Administrative use</header><text>Nothing in this section limits the use of off-highway vehicles in the Double Top Recreation Management Area designated by subsection (a)(1) as necessary for administrative purposes or to respond to an emergency (including as appropriate for administrative support and emergency response during the Grand Traverse skiing event, as permitted by the Grand Mesa, Uncompahgre, and Gunnison National Forests).</text></item></subclause></clause> <clause id="H6C8F77BF56FE497BB88B955B5248644C"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Horse ranch park</header> <subclause id="H65B996CAB8FB42DE956809727FD9A128"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Vehicle use</header> <item id="HC59A6BB372AE45BFA6B921A939F3877D"><enum>(aa)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in item (bb), the use of off-highway vehicles in the Horse Ranch Park Recreation Management Area designated by subsection (a)(2) is prohibited.</text></item> 
<item id="HF8C0E593AAF24B9CB8843E3FA1AA951B"><enum>(bb)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>The Secretary may permit the use of over-snow vehicles in the Horse Ranch Park Recreation Management Area designated by subsection (a)(2)—</text> <subitem id="H35610C4B0A814E9886BB0BF13FB05927"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>only on roads, trails, and areas designated for the use on the date of enactment of this Act; or</text></subitem> 
<subitem id="HB7BB9A5100224277BEC7245072E2E4D2"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>as needed for administrative purposes or to respond to an emergency.</text></subitem></item></subclause> <subclause id="H54FC373668EC4A52A0BB8DD3D1B5D788"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Bicycles</header><text>The Secretary may permit the use of bicycles in the Horse Ranch Park Recreation Management Area designated by subsection (a)(2) only—</text> 
<item id="H5B62199D60FB4EBE9B074B0D0BEBB383"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>on roads, trails, and areas designated for the use on the date of enactment of this Act;</text></item> <item id="HF7485101960748DDB8D62B15DC107FA6"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>as needed for administrative purposes;</text></item> 
<item id="H8928C3103C03433380BA409F4D9BD96B"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>to respond to an emergency; or</text></item> <item id="HA77A565F36304F66BE7C50E45EFA572C"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>if designated by the Secretary for the use on the potential trails described in subclause (III).</text></item></subclause> 
<subclause id="HA839DD4848DF485B9648D2F0281013DB"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Nothing in this section affects the potential development, in accordance with applicable law, of the proposed trail commonly known as the <quote>Crested Butte to Paonia Trail</quote>, the proposed trail commonly known as the <quote>Crested Butte to Carbondale Trail</quote>, or the proposed trail commonly known as the <quote>Dark Canyon Loop Trail</quote>, in the Horse Ranch Park Recreation Management Area designated by subsection (a)(2).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HB120F85E3D964CAD92899B6AC246D7B2"><enum>7.</enum><header>Designation of the Rocky Mountain Scientific Research and Education Area</header> <subsection id="HDFAE42718CF1447D8A44D220220B2CDC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, certain Federal land managed by the Forest Service comprising approximately 12,250 acres, as generally depicted as <quote>Rocky Mountain Scientific Research and Education Area</quote> on the map entitled <quote>Sheet 3: Kebler and Schofield Pass</quote> and dated August 27, 2024, is designated as the <quote>Rocky Mountain Scientific Research and Education Area</quote>.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE9BCAEE06E5C414989FD1D3D18A74763"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of the Scientific Research and Education Area are—</text> <paragraph id="HE25CC64729B246F3B264812415BFED8F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to encourage and preserve conditions necessary for ecological, evolutionary, geological, biogeochemical, climatological, biological, meteorological, and other natural science research and education;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCA114DC6DC23468CA8351243F5DD1F59"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to provide opportunities for the use of continually emerging techniques and methodologies in the conduct of the research and education described in paragraph (1); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC0A2BEF0F2F34FAEB63A0836E4489B20"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to conserve, protect, and enhance for the benefit and enjoyment of present and future generations the natural, scenic, scientific, cultural, watershed, recreation, and wildlife resources of the Scientific Research and Education Area.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5DA810D2A9404DE79CE14E92525EFDC6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Management</header> 
<paragraph id="H9ABCBFF88F494AFFBF429DD101BE1C15"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall manage the Scientific Research and Education Area in a manner that—</text> <subparagraph id="H193905ED1A354F098C12A1BA85BD1C93"><enum>(A)</enum><text>furthers the purposes of the Scientific Research and Education Area described in subsection (b); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H33190C9A755C406BB2221E7D9AFB6A9D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is in accordance with—</text> <clause id="H08C9B49E7F2545518CAD91F09EEDAC2E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>this Act; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HC460784D1F4D44098686CFB3F9720CAE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>other applicable laws.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEC6C62BBA3464DE6B6A7E6A4A9A54F59"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Uses</header> <subparagraph id="H35A4F6993E6745299247BE85AEE7FCF1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall only allow uses of the Scientific Research and Education Area that the Secretary determines would further the purposes described in subsection (b).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2473766BD8954934AAFB99C22DAD9873"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Vehicle use</header><text>Except as needed for administrative purposes or to respond to an emergency, the use of off-highway vehicles in the Scientific Research and Education Area shall be permitted only on roads designated for the use on the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFCE92E46474D44508D6F23CB1124F2AA"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Bicycles</header><text>The use of bicycles in the Scientific Research and Education Area shall be permitted only—</text> 
<clause id="HAE5C8A7330F84892AF245AA675B64F3B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>on roads and trails designated for the use by the Secretary on the date of enactment of this Act; or</text></clause> <clause id="HEF0635F929A64257A2D173FBE8F5D6CD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>on trails designated for the use by the Secretary after the date of enactment of this Act if the Secretary determines that the use is consistent with the purposes described in paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (b).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4EFC846E4718407C8444C622ECC89CEA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effect</header><text>Nothing in this section limits the authority of the Rocky Mountain Biological Laboratory to conduct scientific research or education activities inside or outside the boundaries of the Scientific Research and Education Area.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H6CE4659D91D242689E4A8FFB5432D79E"><enum>8.</enum><header>Designation of wilderness</header> <subsection id="H4CE788FE81934D23BDB6A258EBCF4EB7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation</header><text>Section 2(a) of the Colorado Wilderness Act of 1993 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1132">16 U.S.C. 1132</external-xref> note; 107 Stat. 756; 114 Stat. 1955; 116 Stat. 1055; 128 Stat. 3823) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H7DD680644AFA4B6CB0F36DB1EF2C107F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (6), by striking <quote>1993,</quote> and inserting <quote>1993, and approximately 2,096 acres, as generally depicted as <quote>Crystal Creek Wilderness Addition</quote> and <quote>Lottis Creek Wilderness Addition</quote> on the map entitled <quote>Sheet 4: Brush Creek, Cement Creek, and Spring Creek</quote> and dated August 27, 2024,</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEE0311F2CAA4488F92BD00E086A71D62"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (9)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H3883EDCC73824601B1F544B2E773D102"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Gunnison</quote> and inserting <quote>Gunnison and White River</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF95FEC2D5B3F4531BA968478977C4B72"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>1993,</quote> and inserting <quote>1993, and approximately 11,780 acres, as generally depicted as <quote>Poverty Gulch Wilderness Addition</quote>, <quote>Treasure Wilderness Addition</quote>, and <quote>Erickson Springs Wilderness Addition</quote> on the map entitled <quote>Sheet 3: Kebler and Schofield Pass</quote> and dated August, 27, 2024,</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8B2EF6894C4643F195A699F52B46347B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0BDF9F82FB4B40E6AF9235B323244177"> <paragraph id="H867D57D41C4F49449DB9A6FA410B758A"><enum>(23)</enum><header>Matchless Wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land in the Grand Mesa, Uncompahgre, and Gunnison National Forests comprising approximately 8,656 acres, as generally depicted as <quote>Matchless Wilderness</quote> on the map entitled <quote>Sheet 4: Brush Creek, Cement Creek, and Spring Creek</quote> and dated August, 27, 2024, which shall be known as the <quote>Matchless Wilderness</quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC33080CF305F42909EC1582B983699B7"><enum>(24)</enum><header>East Cement Wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land in the Grand Mesa, Uncompahgre, and Gunnison National Forests comprising approximately 7,684 acres, as generally depicted as <quote>East Cement Wilderness</quote> on the map entitled <quote>Sheet 4: Brush Creek, Cement Creek, and Spring Creek</quote> and dated August 27, 2024, which shall be known as the <quote>East Cement Wilderness</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE5A34546937E49418D7466F436E33E66"><enum>(25)</enum><header>Star Peak Wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land in the Grand Mesa, Uncompahgre, Gunnison, and the White River National Forests comprising approximately 7,210 acres, as generally depicted as <quote>Star Peak Wilderness</quote> on the map entitled <quote>Sheet 4: Brush Creek, Cement Creek, and Spring Creek</quote> and dated August 27, 2024, which shall be known as the <quote>Star Peak Wilderness</quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1440B01484DC43A589BB60B494739613"><enum>(26)</enum><header>Maroon Bells-Snowmass Wilderness addition</header><text>Certain Federal land in the Grand Mesa, Uncompahgre, and Gunnison National Forests comprising approximately 3,321 acres, as generally depicted as <quote>Deer Creek Wilderness Addition</quote> and <quote>Ashcroft Wilderness Addition</quote> on the map entitled <quote>Sheet 4: Brush Creek, Cement Creek, and Spring Creek</quote> and dated August 27, 2024, which shall be incorporated in, and managed as part of, the Maroon Bells-Snowmass Wilderness.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEBB63AD483C943F49022B68A20626EDD"><enum>(27)</enum><header>West Elk Wilderness addition</header><text>Certain Federal land in the Gunnison Field Office administered by the Bureau of Land Management, in the Grand Mesa, Uncompahgre, and Gunnison National Forests and in the Curecanti National Recreation Area, comprising approximately 58,603 acres, as generally depicted as <quote>Lamborn Wilderness Addition</quote>, <quote>Castle Wilderness Addition</quote>, <quote>Beaver Wilderness Addition</quote>, <quote>Steuben Creek Wilderness Addition</quote>, <quote>East Elk Creek Wilderness Addition</quote>, <quote>Dillon Mesa Wilderness Addition</quote>, <quote>Soap Creek Wilderness Addition</quote>, and <quote>Curecanti Wilderness Addition</quote> on the map entitled <quote>Sheet 7: West Elk Additions</quote> and dated August 27, 2024, which shall be incorporated in, and managed as part of, the West Elk Wilderness.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2F8498C2455E45EFA676571AC1557870"><enum>(28)</enum><header>Uncompahgre Wilderness additions</header><text>Certain Federal land in the Grand Mesa, Uncompahgre, and Gunnison National Forests comprising approximately 13,948 acres, as generally depicted as <quote>Uncompahgre Wilderness Additions</quote> on the map entitled <quote>Sheet 10: Uncompahgre Additions</quote> and dated August 27, 2024, which shall be incorporated in, and managed as part of, the Uncompahgre Wilderness.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H971967D4905C4F959371D50767E9F270"><enum>(29)</enum><header>Powderhorn Wilderness addition</header><text>Certain Federal land in the Gunnison Field Office administered by the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 9,604 acres, as generally depicted as <quote>Powderhorn Wilderness Addition</quote> on the map entitled <quote>Sheet 11: Lake Fork</quote> and dated August 27, 2024, which shall be incorporated in, and managed as part of, the Powderhorn Wilderness.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" id="H5E8EF2903BFC433581B05CC02A56C6C0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicable law</header><text>Any reference in the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.</external-xref>) or the Colorado Wilderness Act of 1993 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1132">16 U.S.C. 1132</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/103/77">Public Law 103–77</external-xref>) to the effective date of that Act shall be considered to be a reference to the date of enactment of this Act for purposes of administering the wilderness areas.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HDC6B001B8F7B441FA2846BD2875FD940"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Fire, insects, and diseases</header><text>In accordance with section 4(d)(1) of the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1133">16 U.S.C. 1133(d)(1)</external-xref>), the Secretary may carry out any measure within the wilderness areas that the Secretary determines to be necessary to control fire, insects, and diseases, subject to any terms and conditions that the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8BB02C7468124E93A1380D42DB3E85D1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>West Elk Wilderness boundary modification</header> 
<paragraph id="H8CD714DA7CF848CDAE8BF66F7D1336D8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The boundary of the West Elk Wilderness in the County is modified to exclude the approximately 15 acres generally depicted as <quote>West Elk Wilderness Boundary Pullback</quote> on the map entitled <quote>Sheet 3: Kebler and Schofield Pass</quote> and dated August 27, 2024.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H818224CBE8DA430B8CB97B95C03C9EEE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Withdrawal</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, the Federal land excluded from the boundary of the West Elk Wilderness under paragraph (1) is withdrawn from—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H30294F81AA7E488AB51EDBDAB10E884A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAB114149A7AA444DA13BA172383F396B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5B6C79762C78436B80939060D612C90D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>operation of the mineral leasing, mineral materials, and geothermal leasing laws.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H75F7FD8E702C422086C450FCDEEFA84A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Release</header><text>Congress finds that, for the purposes of subsection (c) of section 603 of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1782">43 U.S.C. 1782</external-xref>), the land within the Powderhorn Wilderness Study Area not designated as wilderness by this section (or an amendment made by this section)—</text> 
<paragraph id="H506327D34A554954AC673A1B54665312"><enum>(1)</enum><text>has been adequately studied for wilderness designation; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H69D161818C6F470B97295115EF69ED4E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is no longer subject to that subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H9B4B47F8269E4147A9ABCD51CD220772"><enum>9.</enum><header>North Fork Valley Watershed</header> 
<subsection id="H40A7C0A1A6514E47B36B63E2C914A660"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Withdrawal</header> 
<paragraph id="H1E3E314DD52940A8A5965211C1B22C50"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, the Federal land in Delta County, Colorado, as generally depicted as <quote>Oil and Gas Withdrawal</quote> on the map entitled <quote>Sheet 6: North Fork Valley</quote> and dated August 27, 2024, is withdrawn from operation of the mineral leasing laws with respect to oil and gas.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H84109D234DCA49DDAD5591711E002FD4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effect</header><text>Nothing in paragraph (1) prevents the Secretary of the Interior from authorizing the use or destruction of methane gas that would leak or be vented into the atmosphere from—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H5D13E5FC26564474981102FA1C9E069D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an active or inactive coal mine subject to a Federal coal lease; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7553718AC63E4EFE9C2AEF07482C1B5D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an abandoned underground coal mine or the site of a former coal mine—</text> 
<clause id="H7764EF7BC425433BAE811D18917D7191"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that is not subject to a Federal coal lease; and</text></clause> <clause id="H11453390A4A047DD99386F20A9388B91"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>with respect to which the Federal interest in land includes mineral rights to the methane gas.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HDAC07AC329FF4A20B779F835CD87A6CF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>No surface occupancy restriction</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, the Federal land in Delta County, Colorado, as generally depicted as <quote>Oil and Gas No Surface Occupancy</quote> on the map entitled <quote>Sheet 1: Electric Mountain</quote> and dated August 27, 2024, shall be subject to a no surface occupancy restriction with respect to oil and gas exploration, development, production, and distribution.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HE0EA6610966542788472ABB4543A4005"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Gunnison River motorized boats and boat ramp use</header> <paragraph id="HAF17B32FF0044CEA88B9382E3478C504"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding the limitation on transfer in the Gunnison Gorge National Conservation Area Approved Resource Management Plan dated November 2004, the Secretary of the Interior, in accordance with the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.</external-xref>) and subject to paragraph (2) and such terms and conditions as the Secretary of the Interior may require, may transfer the special recreation use permit for the use of motorized boats within the Gunnison Gorge Wilderness Area, if the use was established before the date of designation of the Gunnison Gorge Wilderness Area.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H52C719869CAE4601A0F698C2EF550975"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Boat ramp</header><text>The Secretary of the Interior may only transfer the special recreation use permit described in paragraph (1) under that paragraph if the Secretary of the Interior determines that—</text> <subparagraph id="HC747BC18E816475DB991564DA795CDF6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the right of the public to the permanent and reasonable use of the boat ramp for the Gunnison River at the Gunnison Forks Day Use Area in Delta County, Colorado, has been acquired by a Federal agency or a State or local government; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBA8CC4E1527541CD85AC318AE5600BA9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any fees to be charged by the Federal agency or the State or local government for public use of the boat ramp described in subparagraph (A) would be reasonable.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HF4F8C93EA497455D978A743449446EB3"><enum>10.</enum><header>Land to be held in trust for the Ute Mountain Ute Tribe</header> <subsection id="HEE03E659FF52473D8CD1B244E983F755"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Trust</header> <paragraph id="HCC83BB3141EF42A68C94535AD8CCB7D7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act and subject to valid existing rights, on request by the Ute Mountain Ute Tribe (referred to in this section as the <quote>Tribe</quote>), the Secretary of the Interior shall take into trust for the benefit of the Tribe the approximately 19,080 acres of land in the County, owned in fee by the Tribe, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Ute Mountain Ute Tribe; Pinecrest Ranch—Fee to Trust Legislation</quote> and dated September 20, 2024.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H74236C27019D4317AD0DDAF8FDA8E751"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>The land taken into trust by paragraph (1) shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H015803C2760145DFAF82171E47B8A117"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be part of the reservation of the Tribe; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE9A972729D1044FBA224E466E47BB700"><enum>(B)</enum><text>be administered in accordance with the laws and regulations generally applicable to property held in trust by the United States for the benefit of an Indian Tribe.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDF5B5A2D66F848ECBA955ABA1FE38CDD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Restriction on use for gaming activities</header><text>The land taken into trust by paragraph (1) shall not be eligible for, or considered to have been taken into trust for, any gaming activity under any Federal law, including the Indian Gaming Regulatory Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/2701">25 U.S.C. 2701 et seq.</external-xref>) and regulations promulgated by the Secretary of the Interior or the National Indian Gaming Commission under that Act.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HABA4B95118104EB1BED8BADE9C96782E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Survey</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, if any land is taken into trust under subsection (a), the Secretary of the Interior shall complete a survey to establish the boundaries of the land taken into trust under that subsection.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HEA01C1071712464CB65911B67F8A3BDD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effect</header><text>Nothing in this section shall affect the rights, title, interests, or jurisdiction of the County in County Road 25 or its right-of-way.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H0CD7DC3E4BE04D249C06C17291717E5D"><enum>11.</enum><header>General provisions</header> 
<subsection id="H47F0CC086DF747E0B48FA25DFD37D4BA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Maps and legal descriptions</header> 
<paragraph id="HF326656DD6F44EE893DFC432BD69669A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>As soon as practicable after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall file a map and a legal description of the covered areas and wilderness areas with—</text> <subparagraph id="HDB48BFD15CAF4435A8660BF993CA1925"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6AF61ED8BA604196BDB1E50FC2E49A98"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H118E1325ABC746D9A2B828410F29835F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Force of law</header><text>Each map and legal description filed under paragraph (1) shall have the same force and effect as if included in this Act, except that the Secretary may correct any typographical errors in the maps and legal descriptions.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE24893A129704C3E9D23EEE4836187A7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>Each map and legal description filed under paragraph (1) shall be on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of the Bureau of Land Management or the Forest Service, as applicable.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H598600CBD68942F0862B8A0035C41710"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Acquisition of land</header> <paragraph id="HDE329D00572446B18368FFB70A64B3B4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may acquire any land or interest in land within a covered area or wilderness area only through exchange, donation, or purchase from a willing seller.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H670581D2803A4BB88D48A80D8111CB18"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Management</header><text>Any land or interest in land acquired under paragraph (1) shall be incorporated in, and administered as a part of, the covered area or wilderness area in which the land or interest in land is located.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HCF294060B2884240AF663181BCF717CD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Withdrawal</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, the covered areas and wilderness areas are withdrawn from—</text> 
<paragraph id="H6DE5B5F22833488EB47A936F7A6B6687"><enum>(1)</enum><text>all forms of entry, appropriation, and disposal under the public land laws;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEC967819B7584BEDAD170C2303489A44"><enum>(2)</enum><text>location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE717787E9C4D4420BBEB7D6671D400C2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>operation of the mineral leasing, mining materials, and geothermal leasing laws.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H1F897917AAF64725B98450FD6C69951A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Fish and wildlife</header><text>Nothing in this Act affects the jurisdiction or responsibility of the State with respect to fish and wildlife in the State.</text></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" id="HA9A14A2EF7BD4F89B6BB6D69AEDC8CE5"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Grazing</header><text>The laws (including regulations) and policies followed by the Secretary in issuing and administering grazing permits or leases on land under the jurisdiction of the Secretary shall continue to apply within a covered area.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H5B94D4FF59A440209080EAAC0C8B3374"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Wildfire, insect, and disease management</header><text>In accordance with this Act, the Secretary may—</text> 
<paragraph id="HE461516727544B72BA66D193255DEA5C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>carry out any measures that the Secretary determines to be necessary to manage wildland fire, and treat hazardous fuels, insects, and diseases, in the covered areas; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H72D5FB16DE3D490F90CB5C712C81A17C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>coordinate the measures with the appropriate State or local agency, as the Secretary determines to be necessary.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF781CEDD40C541F7B00A1F82D5871291"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Vegetation management</header> 
<paragraph id="H6F7B20EF5193487099A64969A648ABA1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>No project shall be carried out in a covered area for the purpose of harvesting commercial timber.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA0C7CA90FCDD4E389D25B6BF66579B86"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Ecological restoration</header><text>Any vegetation management project carried out in a covered area outside of the wildland-urban interface that includes the harvest or sale of merchantable materials shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H0B94EF2A6A3C4CBEA2161F3E7F4F0762"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be collaboratively developed;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8892E3AE04D84856A8743EED596AB268"><enum>(B)</enum><text>limit the sale of merchantable materials to small diameter trees or biomass; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H48858C322558453DA41314ADC25C0515"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in accordance with the best available science—</text> <clause id="H6461BC49B2C34D2699CDFD037616EC7E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>restore ecological integrity;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H640BE100C13C443B907ADF888393CE64"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>maximize the retention of old growth and large trees, as appropriate for the forest type; and</text></clause> <clause id="H768DA1F0BADF45A99E5298FBAD95C000"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>focus on prescribed fire as the primary means to achieve modified wildland fire behavior, as measured by the projected reduction of uncharacteristically severe wildfire effects for the forest type.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE89794A7AA5848609F956AF2E0C96104"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Roads and trails</header> 
<paragraph id="H8BFC08B8148B4E6CB03499D650D267F0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), no road shall be constructed in a covered area.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBACD4D427EB74F9EAACA7FCDBFA12BBD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Nothing in paragraph (1) prevents the Secretary from—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE4100166172A4BECB5376B9723CB4FBE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>constructing a temporary road in a Protection Area, Recreation Management Area, or Special Management Area as the Secretary determines to be necessary as a minimum requirement for carrying out a vegetation management project in accordance with this Act;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H56A2808FBDDE49F4913859536C7E3978"><enum>(B)</enum><text>responding to an emergency; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7F6AF0AFBE4544228A3BB6DB4373131A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>authorizing the transportation of scientific research equipment within the Scientific Research and Education Area.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5914C6644A5C4CB88DBD794DBF1A1788"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Decommissioning of temporary roads</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date on which an applicable vegetation management project is completed, the Secretary shall decommission any temporary road constructed under paragraph (2)(A) for the applicable vegetation management project.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H988C70D1285046108C29E9AE5C0BD43D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Rerouting</header><text>Nothing in this Act prevents the Secretary from rerouting a trail within a covered area to protect public safety or natural resources from degradation, as determined to be appropriate by the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H712F76A916214F4F81D13EAF5FA88909"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Water rights</header><text>Nothing in this Act affects the use or allocation of any absolute or conditional water right that is—</text> 
<paragraph id="H6E4A8DCAC5D14BDB9C428977D4FCB8B5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>decreed under the laws of the State; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFB53A7ED67274B86871177468D147F67"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in existence on the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2590E2899ED848FBA5093492ECE4F7CB"><enum>(j)</enum><header>No buffer zones</header> 
<paragraph id="H56153185C63F405C8C21AC3E6E5828A3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Nothing in this Act establishes a protective perimeter or buffer zone around a covered area or wilderness area.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H12CD20C6034343CAAF2D808923813673"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Outside activities</header><text>The fact that a non-wilderness activity or use on land outside of a covered area or wilderness area can be seen or heard from an area within a covered area or wilderness area shall not preclude the conduct of the activity or use outside the boundary of the covered area or wilderness area.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFDACBFBE71A34E1DA9968F1428CF521D"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Seasonal closures</header><text>As appropriate and in accordance with applicable law, the Secretary shall develop and implement seasonal closures for off-highway vehicles and bicycles to protect wildlife and wildlife habitat in—</text> <paragraph id="H5245CD2D17614C039FD5579CC610D5C4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the McIntosh Mountain Special Management Area designated by section 3(a)(4);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD8389CE544984EB086F4B4E9F34FB875"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Signal Peak Special Management Area designated by section 3(a)(7);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7A4B408CF895405FAFBCF432CB8320CC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Cabin Creek Wildlife Conservation Area designated by section 4(a)(1);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAE26069FDEEA473996917DD520FEE800"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the Flat Top Wildlife Conservation Area designated by section 4(a)(2);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9F0B92BCF0A44452AE07C1C21770D861"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the Lake Gulch and Cebolla Creek Wildlife Conservation Area designated by section 4(a)(3); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDE4397FC8C3C4D3FA16AE2CFAD96C6E3"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the Pinnacles Wildlife Conservation Area designated by section 4(a)(6).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE63DE92D242140FBBC96A1B8E67BE803"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Restoration activities</header> <paragraph id="HB1CE0E8A92DC433F9DB94CB532EC730D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>As appropriate and in accordance with applicable law, the Secretary shall conduct wet meadow and riparian restoration projects to improve climate resiliency and wildlife habitat in—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HFBBCE8C49C254D0EB4E487834C6C7B96"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the McIntosh Mountain Special Management Area designated by section 3(a)(4);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA021368578C045F3AFECD805A6A16BBF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Signal Peak Special Management Area designated by section 3(a)(7);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H00119B4B534B43B3BE4BDBF190B14872"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Flat Top Wildlife Conservation Area designated by section 4(a)(2);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7A06CAB508004374BA7371E293C1D00F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Lake Gulch and Cebolla Creek Wildlife Conservation Area designated by section 4(a)(3);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H071635E63F3544DC9421D60B762A535D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the Pinnacles Wildlife Conservation Area designated by section 4(a)(6); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAF999135C36F4BEAA98D8D8FA86BDD6E"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the Sawtooth Wildlife Conservation Area designated by section 4(a)(8).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA6BFBE11BBC64BCA83B73CBBDF9D4429"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Collaboration</header><text>In carrying out the projects described in paragraph (1), the Secretary shall seek to collaborate with—</text> <subparagraph id="HCA67C9308D81424DA5F869142C17B12B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Colorado Division of Parks and Wildlife;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCDD3063401AB402D9797DBE3564CE7A5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Upper Gunnison River Water Conservancy District;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HED7971B50C0C4A62A4862D2EB13544C3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the County;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H752345B52FA9448FB7BCFD9595F15389"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in the case of a project located in the Sawtooth Wildlife Conservation Area designated by section 4(a)(8), Saguache County, Colorado;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HABA279FDD67F429ABAB586179A00E23A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the United States Fish and Wildlife Service; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H686BA3282D3C414F9D8E9D43554925E2"><enum>(F)</enum><text>other interested entities and individuals.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H417E26E9186840BCB27F9FBE88C2FCC3"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Tribal rights and uses</header> <paragraph id="HA1C6424C0324436FA3782C6AAA50D1FE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Treaty rights</header><text>Nothing in this Act affects the treaty rights of any Indian Tribe.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC5E20E5A67B1440D8BB6C33AAE2E56CC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Traditional Tribal uses</header><text>Subject to any terms and conditions that the Secretary determines to be necessary and in accordance with applicable law, the Secretary shall allow for the continued use of a covered area or wilderness area by members of Indian Tribes—</text> <subparagraph id="H40207345660A46AF99DCD566AB96CD77"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for traditional ceremonies; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4F9C0FDE0E814AD3B0C6BC3885DB4BD2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>as a source of traditional plants and other materials.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

