<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5BBAE43D6A764251995CD5947E177483" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2096 IH: Protecting Our Nation’s Capital Emergency Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2096</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250314">March 14, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000597">Mr. Garbarino</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S001212">Mr. Stauber</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To restore the right to negotiate matters pertaining to the discipline of law enforcement officers of the District of Columbia through collective bargaining, to restore the statute of limitations for bringing disciplinary cases against members or civilian employees of the Metropolitan Police Department of the District of Columbia, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H34A4FE702DC642188878BEFDB8035A46" style="OLC"><section id="H2E6334110FC84E2FB6BB08DBD9963631" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting Our Nation’s Capital Emergency Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HA3624D6E1CA04FD6932CF3DBE40AE45A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings; purpose</header><subsection id="H98DAF2CAA032449D9D426999681B5C68"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H86BBB1956DB64DD6AF5D14FB6DA655C2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As of September 25, 2023, Washington, DC had recorded 24,996 crimes committed within the city limits, up 30 percent or almost 5,400 crimes from the same date in 2022.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H516AE8ABF71E4DC5AC85E47E0E305C8C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As of September 25, 2023, 197 homicides had been committed in Washington, DC, up 29 percent from the same date in 2022 and nearly twice the total number of homicides in 2012.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H886092EC07D04CBAB7BCBF8704DD3B4A"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As of September 25, 2023, violent crime incidents in Washington, DC are up over 37 percent from the same time in 2022, including 120 reports of sexual abuse (up 1 percent) and 2,545 reports of robberies (up 65 percent).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFE8B63A28CE8416B8CCA4CC9845C8934"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As of September 25, 2023, there have been 5,262 reports of motor vehicle thefts in Washington, DC, up 107 percent from the same date in 2022.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H61A8C5DC07084865B84888CD52F1A979"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Metropolitan Police Department of the District of Columbia has lost over 1,200 members since 2020. The total number of members is down 478 since 2020 and the staffing levels at the Department are the lowest they have been in over 50 years.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H77B5F6CD354A46B8ACDD767F2D2CC7C5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the purpose of this Act to combat the rise in violent crime in our Nation’s Capital by eliminating policies which place law enforcement personnel of the District of Columbia at risk and discourage them from serving, ensuring that such personnel will be treated equitably and fairly and the recruitment and retention of such personnel shall be increased.</text></subsection></section><section id="HDEF779407AD2497DA17C4A11BF7FD634"><enum>3.</enum><header>Restoration of equitable and fair treatment of law enforcement personnel of District of Columbia</header><subsection id="HD7307EAC8DF0488BA0902E1D6BC7703B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Restoration of right To negotiate matters pertaining to discipline of District of Columbia law enforcement officers through collective bargaining</header><text>Section 1708 of the District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978 (sec. 1–617.08, D.C. Official Code), as amended by section 116(b) of the Comprehensive Policing and Justice Reform Amendment Act of 2022 (D.C. Law 24–345), is amended by striking subsection (c).</text></subsection><subsection id="HD6349454DB004D71892A0EC20669E53E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Restoration of statute of limitations for claims against members or civilian employees of Metropolitan Police Department</header><text>Subtitle M of title I of the Comprehensive Policing and Justice Reform Amendment Act of 2022 (D.C. Law 24–345) is repealed, and any provision of law amended or repealed by such subtitle is restored or revived as if such subtitle had not been enacted into law.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

