<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7A54F1F67F2443ACB0ED31BB8974BAC5" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5309 IH: Congressional Tribute to Constance Baker Motley Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5309</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250911">September 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000216">Ms. DeLauro</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="A000055">Mr. Aderholt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000380">Mr. Amo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000369">Mr. Amodei of Nevada</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001318">Ms. Balint</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000490">Mr. Bishop</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001296">Mr. Boyle of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001313">Ms. Brown</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001112">Mr. Carbajal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001127">Mrs. Cherfilus-McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000537">Mr. Clyburn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001069">Mr. Courtney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001130">Ms. Crockett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000230">Mr. Davis of North Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000631">Ms. Dean of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000071">Mr. Ellzey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000299">Ms. Escobar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000459">Mr. Fleischmann</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000468">Mrs. Fletcher</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000476">Mr. Frost</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000597">Mr. Garbarino</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000586">Mr. García of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000592">Mr. Golden of Maine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000585">Mr. Gomez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001081">Mrs. Hayes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001047">Mr. Himes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001066">Mr. Horsford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="I000058">Mr. Ivey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000295">Mr. Joyce of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000602">Ms. Lee of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Lieu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001208">Mrs. McBath</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001227">Ms. McClellan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001226">Mr. Menendez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001206">Mr. Morelle</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001214">Mr. Mrvan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000015">Mr. Neal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000191">Mr. Neguse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000188">Mr. Norcross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000474">Mrs. Torres of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000172">Ms. Ocasio-Cortez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000034">Mr. Pallone</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000197">Ms. Pelosi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000610">Ms. Plaskett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000617">Mrs. Ramirez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000305">Ms. Ross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000609">Mr. Rutherford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000579">Mr. Ryan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001190">Mr. Schneider</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001221">Ms. Scholten</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001157">Mr. David Scott of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001207">Ms. Sherrill</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001148">Mr. Simpson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001159">Ms. Strickland</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000486">Mr. Torres of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000482">Mrs. Trahan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000788">Ms. Williams of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="V000129">Mr. Valadao</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To posthumously award a congressional gold medal to Constance Baker Motley, in recognition of her enduring contributions and service to the United States.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H67BC0BE39C4842E28769BD713F968657" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H666251AF16F0456DBF8EA0D1EDF48815"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Congressional Tribute to Constance Baker Motley Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H230462C270D34AE3AF34E8D77C753E23"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
<paragraph id="HCB0DE9E1FA714DFF8AC5E2E61CABA625"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Constance Baker Motley was born in 1921, in New Haven, Connecticut, the daughter of immigrants from the Caribbean island of Nevis.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC0A32197E168433AA2BDD0F187A4F57D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In 1943, Constance Baker Motley graduated from New York University with a Bachelor of Arts degree in economics.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H94A5A09FBD8A46539E56A95E1A84FCDF"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon receiving a law degree from Columbia University in 1946, Constance Baker Motley became a staff attorney at the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People Legal Defense and Educational Fund, Inc. (in this Act referred to as the <quote>LDF</quote>), and fought tirelessly for 2 decades alongside Thurgood Marshall and other leading civil rights lawyers to dismantle segregation throughout the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6C26584BBA5845A0BA1B607E66B59D17"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Constance Baker Motley was the only female attorney on the LDF legal team that won the landmark desegregation case, Brown v. Board of Education, 347 U.S. 483 (1954).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0C5167D0A35E44459C1614773E9EF487"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Constance Baker Motley argued 10 major civil rights cases before the Supreme Court, winning all but one, including the case brought on behalf of James Meredith challenging the refusal of the University of Mississippi to admit him.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H50783EC167F140C2ACA99A11ADECA19A"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Constance Baker Motley’s only loss before the United States Supreme Court was in Swain v. Alabama, 380 U.S. 202 (1965), a case in which the Supreme Court refused to proscribe race-based peremptory challenges in cases involving African-American defendants, and which was later reversed in Batson v. Kentucky, 476 U.S. 79 (1986), on grounds that were largely asserted by Constance Baker Motley in the Swain case.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9933D443F49B44239FC985F669CB37B0"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In 1964, Constance Baker Motley became the first African-American woman elected to the New York State Senate.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9E024309C8E64AF6B49D575E429CB8AA"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In 1965, Constance Baker Motley became the first African-American woman, and the first woman, to serve as president of the Borough of Manhattan.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0561515E30654C2C95D040316D557F54"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Constance Baker Motley, in her capacity as an elected public official in New York, continued to fight for civil rights, dedicating herself to the revitalization of the inner city and improvement of urban public schools and housing.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5B74F5D7F32A4B09A78A58A163616457"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In 1966, Constance Baker Motley was appointed by President Lyndon B. Johnson as a judge on the United States District Court for the Southern District of New York.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H24C5663803844764AF3F9052181D965F"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The appointment of Constance Baker Motley made her the first African-American woman, and only the fifth woman, appointed and confirmed for a Federal judgeship.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H38C70AE542114830934BD0F4548A8D09"><enum>(12)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In 1982, Constance Baker Motley was elevated to Chief Judge of the United States District Court for the Southern District of New York, the largest Federal trial court in the United States.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H433D7EEF73FA4A39AE9496DD83D4E6C9"><enum>(13)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Constance Baker Motley assumed senior status in 1986, and continued serving on the United States District Court for the Southern District of New York with distinction for nearly 2 decades.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1AFDB1A7853A427EB200687C6A6065CD"><enum>(14)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Constance Baker Motley passed away on September 28, 2005, and is survived by her son, Joel W. Motley III, 3 grandchildren, and nieces and nephews in Connecticut and in other States.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9AA171EA627043A99E3AB7055A36809C"><enum>(15)</enum><text>September 14, 2021, was the 100th anniversary of the birth of Constance Baker Motley.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HABE9D7E245274D91BB91CB7D1A37E9D3"><enum>3.</enum><header>Congressional gold medal</header> <subsection id="H04F6AD91C93F4C2AA3D5D9B794FF45AD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Presentation authorized</header><text>The President pro tempore of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives are authorized to make appropriate arrangements for the posthumous award, on behalf of Congress, of a gold medal of appropriate design in commemoration of Constance Baker Motley, in recognition of her enduring contributions and service to the United States.</text></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0EA3B5C7BC7B4EF18C3F8CB326FD51E3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Design and striking</header>
<paragraph id="HAA07E717C48F403CB28D851C75819613"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For the purpose of the award referred to in subsection (a), the Secretary of the Treasury (in this Act referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall strike a gold medal with suitable emblems, devices, and inscriptions, to be determined by the Secretary.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB1F8EEF308D54DD98EB78FD28111C6F4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Image</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The emblems, devices, and inscriptions determined by the Secretary shall include an image of Constance Baker Motley and an inscription of the name of Constance Baker Motley.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HA86B25C191264693A3131BA71DF4E2FF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Presentation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to the award described under subsection (a), the award shall be presented to Constance Baker Motley’s son, Joel Motley III, and her niece, Constance Royster.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HB5E60C6CBCD646B98A566060D05903F1" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Disposition of medal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Following the award of the gold medal under subsection (a), the gold medal shall be given to Joel Motley III.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="H947BF0E340C64868B64B5A4C0AA823B6"><enum>4.</enum><header>Duplicate medals</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary may strike and sell duplicates in bronze of the gold medal struck under section 3, at a price sufficient to cover the cost thereof, including labor, materials, dies, use of machinery, and overhead expenses.</text></section> <section id="H21C9B5B63058429D9CC31E2DB5978C08"><enum>5.</enum><header>National medals</header> <subsection id="HEE266AEC9F074CB4A6CFCA3953759954"><enum>(a)</enum><header>National medal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">All medals struck under this Act are national medals for purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/51">chapter 51</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code.</text></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HECD21804E98D438E9DB7964A27D42026"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Numismatic items</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of sections 5134 and 5136 of title 31, United States Code, all medals struck under this Act shall be considered to be numismatic items.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H5FD5834583494FA08F2E85C7688F709C" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>6.</enum><header>Authority to use fund amounts; proceeds of sale</header> <subsection id="H22B6413ECF5B40F099C027D8C50D24CC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority To use fund amounts</header><text>There is authorized to be charged against the United States Mint Public Enterprise Fund such amounts as may be necessary to pay for the costs of the medals struck under this Act.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H39AEF98F8EE143FAB2BFF420B626EA83"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Proceeds of sale</header><text>Amounts received from the sale of duplicate bronze medals authorized under section 4 shall be deposited into the United States Mint Public Enterprise Fund.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

