<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4BDF893AC92E482286B6CC2358B45784" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4923 IH: Stop Foreign Propaganda Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4923</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20250808">August 8, 2025</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000594">Mr. Tony Gonzales of Texas</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To impose sanctions on persons who knowingly provide content or media services to sanctioned foreign propaganda outlets, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H5742B9218182423D9EE7D060F15F07B3" style="OLC">
<section id="H785A2ADF640B428BAB05A92711E4EAFF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop Foreign Propaganda Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HE76D770D47084E4D878F12CAD45A70B3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Codification of Executive Order 13846</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Executive Order 13846 of August 6, 2018 (83 Fed. Reg. 38939), entitled <quote>Reimposing Certain Sanctions With Respect to Iran</quote>, shall have the force and effect of law.</text></section> 
<section id="H9613F77D4B1747649E5EF3A5560B1115"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sanctions with respect to provision of media services to sanctioned foreign media entities</header> 
<subsection id="H410B69699A9E47528864B216D8D47D8D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall impose the sanctions described in subsection (c) with respect to any person who knowingly provides material support or media services, and receives compensation, barter, or any other form of consideration therefor, to a covered foreign media entity.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H483AC09A1DD34D969CFE0E782F54667B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>This section applies to any United States person or foreign person subject to the jurisdiction of the United States.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFA850ACDF3CB4DC389B785A71A5BC04C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Sanctions described</header><text>The sanctions described in this subsection are the following:</text> <paragraph id="H2762D55959B34C6DBF351915C35FC8D9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The blocking and prohibition of all transactions in property and interests in property of the person pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701 et 18 seq.).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4014A8F172064F8BBDD4527566C2F1CA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The prohibition on United States persons from entering into procurement contracts or transactions with the person.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF93B2861EE114CC2A1FCD9480A0F50F3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The prohibition of financing assistance from the Export-Import Bank of the United States to the person.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HABED16A1AD5D4082899C9152B296E2E1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>In the case of a person that is an alien, the denial of a visa or exclusion from the United States in accordance with section of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(a)(3)(C)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H8A4C1CDA4EB9450DAD8A3697D264D759"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>The President may waive the application of sanctions under this section with respect to a person if the President—</text> 
<paragraph id="H15B768FB1E074AD08A0055FC152726B4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>determines that such a waiver is in the national interest of the United States; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB86F7B5A99514E9EA7E4ED0974C11A5A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submits to the appropriate congressional committees a written explanation of the reasons for the waiver.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HDDD7EC075CD54CE1863E9494A57CD7CD"><enum>4.</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of State, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that includes—</text> <paragraph id="H7282045B10B94A80B4378F7CFF43707A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a list of all persons, including United States persons and foreign persons subject to the jurisdiction of the United States, that have knowingly provided material support or media services to any covered foreign media entity and a description of the nature, value, duration, and scope of such transactions, including any payments, barter arrangements, or third-party facilitation mechanisms;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD37BF054E1AD4732814F21622A0E7B69"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any enforcement actions, designations, penalties, or license denials initiated pursuant to this Act or other applicable sanctions authorities during the reporting period; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H59CF4A999E594D1F985452F4FEC768F2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an assessment of to the extent the Government of Iran, including the Islamic Republic of Iran Broadcasting and its affiliates, has directly or indirectly financed or contracted with any foreign news organization, media outlet, production company, or content distributor—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H37FF3A4B92F74FD2BB36F0866BE6B667"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to disseminate regime-aligned narratives, disinformation, or coercive propaganda targeting U.S. or allied audiences; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB492AE8FF7874361815E967A3C599584"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to circumvent existing U.S. sanctions or export control measures through third-party intermediaries or subsidiaries.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H726A974D72984642B1BA62F996C2635A"><enum>5.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act—</text> <paragraph id="HDA56040BB9604C5FB73F2E6A8259F0A8"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>the term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means—</text>
                <subparagraph id="HF73CB3D4C0764CE78D86C4A0093B747E">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Financial Services, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives; and</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H55662E6DB6DF48CDB83E45B16D025340">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on Finance, and the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate;</text>
                </subparagraph>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H47DCDB98752A4F27ADCCD6E57255DE9D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <quote>foreign media entity</quote> means any media organization that—</text> <subparagraph id="HB5293CC1A97E4F5E8D96A50A168A2A53"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is owned, controlled, funded, or operated, in whole or in part, by a foreign government or an entity designated pursuant to United States sanctions law;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H83399C9B6DE544A6B09D9BCFB082A15E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is designated by the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Director of National Intelligence, as an instrument of foreign state propaganda or foreign malign influence operations; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H75ECC3A9B7FB48A398844466B8B520B2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>acts on behalf of, or in coordination with, a sanctioned foreign person to disseminate disinformation, suppress dissent, or engage in state-sponsored information operations;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4A29F5165BDD4813A9505268895F8D40"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <quote>knowingly</quote> means that a person has actual knowledge of the conduct, the circumstance, or the result, or should have known of the conduct, the circumstance, or the result;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2917F662C2524B1BB5E8620C734B2CEB"> <enum>(4)</enum> <text>the term <quote>material support or media services</quote> includes the provision of content, editorial services, journalistic contributions, photographs, video footage, syndicated materials, production infrastructure, backend technology, distribution platforms, or any service or resource that directly enables the broadcast, publication, or dissemination of information; and</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H67C9084C01FA440D869747771F89F5F9"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the term <quote>United States person</quote> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HACC7109602D647C5AEA78E6790E5C7C2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a United States citizen or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H304787AE231B427296B13C423BB83649"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an entity organized under the laws of the United States or any jurisdiction within the United States, including any foreign branch of such entity; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1489CCB2B7A04A0D84860D8FF4AD754E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any person physically present in the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body>
</bill>


