<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-RIL25541-L3K-KP-2J2"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 251 ATS: Supporting the designation of May 4 through May 10, 2025, as “Children's Mental Health Awareness Week”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 251</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250522">May 22, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S438">Mr. Husted</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S418">Mr. Fetterman</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Supporting the designation of May 4 through May 10, 2025, as <quote>Children's Mental Health Awareness Week</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas millions of youth in the United States struggle with mental health challenges, many of which suffer undiagnosed and untreated;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas adults who struggle with mental health often show symptoms in their youth that go unaddressed and can continue later in life; </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas childhood and adolescence can be challenging times in life, leaving our youth especially vulnerable to anxiety, depression, bullying, and self-harm;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas stigma surrounding mental health often prevents youth from seeking the help and support they need, which can exacerbate the effects of mental health conditions;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, mental health conditions are chronic conditions, and untreated mental health conditions can harm the development and well-being of children, impacting their academic, social, and home environments;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas youth suicide continues to be a significant public health crisis, affecting families, individuals, and communities, and there is a need for extensive suicide awareness and prevention programs; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas May 4 through May 10, 2025, is an opportunity to strengthen public awareness of youth mental health conditions and advocate for meaningful action to improve mental health care for children in the United States: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id83aaed4e96ee43919299ac5756e5d78d"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the designation of May 4 through May 10, 2025, as <quote>Children's Mental Health Awareness Week</quote> to raise awareness of the mental health conditions facing our children and the importance of early detection, treatment, intervention, and prevention strategies;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id477583385d99446b9af45cefd0efc701"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the relationship between children’s mental health and plenty of outdoor recreation, a healthy diet, regular socialization with peers, and adequate sleep;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id86c048199122422e9b6f4c197cd79891"><enum>(3)</enum><text>urges youth mental health be categorized as a national priority and calls for the continued promotion of mental health in schools and communities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id76adff0c31cc4ebd97bd6fccfd230e3f"><enum>(4)</enum><text>applauds the collaboration of local, State, and Federal organizations in promoting awareness of youth mental health and providing support for those in need;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9c2c2accc37f49b5a0ba4e00f5a6885c"><enum>(5)</enum><text>advocates for individuals, families, and communities to participate in activities during <quote>Children's Mental Health Awareness Week</quote> to promote mental health initiatives, reduce stigma, and facilitate access to essential services and resources; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4b0a5d43b9cb4104ba3ebeb4026ac852"><enum>(6)</enum><text>reaffirms the importance of mental health as a necessary aspect of overall well-being and urges continued efforts to facilitate access to mental health care for the children of the United States. </text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

