<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB0D02752689144EE8D7FBBE5B25A91D4" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3538 IH: Wildlife Confiscations Network Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3538</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250521">May 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000597">Mr. Garbarino</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of the Interior to establish a Wildlife Confiscations Network, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8BAB2EB08A34446B9744375AF3C91031" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H06EB5DDEB3FB4CFDAC800FE62F08A8E2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Wildlife Confiscations Network Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H86BF9BA8FF9C47BA9FDF4417B4413F76"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HDA480CB911034A8796FAEC856231C774"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Wildlife trafficking is a continued and growing threat to our national security, hinders sustainable economic development, and undermines our laws.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD9B476CBF82B4C9488EED59F1EA5671F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The connections between trafficking in illegal wildlife and natural resources with the financing of groups involved in transnational organized crime pose additional threats to the United States.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE2E61A4FC8B847C2805DCED45E2127FF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>President Donald J. Trump’s Executive Order No. 13773 demonstrated continued support for Enforcing Federal Law with Respect to Transnational Criminal Organizations and Preventing International Trafficking.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H562AD72D31464D1DA4F85D3226E16E06"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Lacey Act Amendments of 1981 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/3371">16 U.S.C. 3371 et seq.</external-xref>) prohibits the importation, exportation, transportation, sale, receipt, acquisition, or purchase of any fish or wildlife or plant taken, possessed, transported, or sold in violation of any law, treaty, or regulation of the United States or any Indian tribal law, or foreign law.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC0AD9B23332E461EA69FDC504C3A87CE"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Congress remains strongly committed to combating wildlife trafficking and transnational organized crime.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9EF0B6F692644688B23BEC690A345383"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The United States border is secured by Federal agents and inspectors responsible for identification, seizure, confiscation and holding of illegal imports, including a diverse array of live wild animals, notably at U.S. ports of entry or exit with an increased burden seen in Los Angeles, Miami, and across the Southern border.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H291B771310E4422286E59FB149E3EBA1"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Customs and wildlife enforcement officers at ports of entry have limited holding capacity, care experience, and transportation options for interdicted live wildlife.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9D6061077ECE420BBA363D127501DEA7"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Numerous species of wildlife require extensive quarantine protocols to protect domestic livestock and wildlife, beyond the capacity of our ports and borders, that can be administered by facilities within the Wildlife Confiscations Network.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H68F916CF4811428DAA53ACD75B62521C"><enum>(9)</enum><text>When illegally imported live wild animals and plants are seized at U.S. ports of entry, it is critical for law enforcement to obtain forensic documentation, maintain evidentiary integrity, and ensure the health, wellbeing, and proper care of all seized wildlife and plants in government custody.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H502EBF6443104FF78528A85A46C04584"><enum>(10)</enum><text>From 2015 to 2019, the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service had 834 cases involving live wildlife interdiction, which included 48,793 individual live animals, an average of nearly 30 per day, requiring placement and care.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H30E30BE3594D4EBEB99B74D672379308"><enum>(11)</enum><text>In 2023, the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service and Association of Zoos and Aquariums formed a cooperative agreement to implement a pilot network in southern California to lessen the logistical burden by serving as a point of contact to coordinate placement and care of seized live animals while maintaining legal chain of custody.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5575A45E1F4548128C3AE877C9AC4D6C"><enum>(12)</enum><text>The Wildlife Confiscations Network provides a cooperative and coordinated response for the care and wellbeing of wildlife confiscated from illegal trade at United States border crossings and points of entry in Southern California from the point of seizure to placement or repatriation and, in just 2 years, has successfully placed over 4,100 individual animals into care.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H37373DEE84324BC1BE1C45F7DF0655DF"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Confiscation of trafficked plants and animals is critical to preventing their re-entry into illegal trade, empowering law enforcement to document and maintain evidence of and effectively combat illegal wildlife trafficking.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1223AEB83F9C4DE48DCAD15713CFBDC4"><enum>(14)</enum><text>The Wildlife Confiscations Network clearly aligns with OMB Circular A–76 by supporting wildlife law enforcement, an inherently governmental function, and removing the placement and care of confiscated live wildlife from government responsibility. It must be extended and expanded nationwide to allow law enforcement officers across the country to focus on their mission and mandate in combating wildlife crime.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H49269DA6214C484291AD643CF968D253"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H46C00BB6ADAB4F6398AC9472B6F60BAE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>CITES species</header><text>The term <term>CITES species</term> means an animal species that is listed in one of the Appendices of the Convention on International Trade in Endangered Species of Wild Fauna and Flora.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4ECA967F348D4813B9FB4FEBAC7F0C82"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Committee</header><text>The term <term>Committee</term> means the committee established under section 4(b)(3).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8E3491E3765541B09AC026E6241FADB6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Confiscated animal</header><text>The term <term>confiscated animal</term> means an individual of a CITES species or a threatened or endangered species that is—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H55E0C015487C4CC2B152659108A7F13F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>seized at or en route to or from a port or border of the United States; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAC892BF59EAC4A749DA146C7B42543C9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>placed at a qualified animal care facility for provision of general care and welfare to such individual.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE3E9584E74234BDE992133111F556F81"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Network</header><text>The term <term>Network</term> means the Wildlife Confiscations Network established under section 4(a).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H54E89D7E4592403CBACBC3A04E7BA365"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Qualified animal care facility</header><text>The term <term>qualified animal care facility</term> means a zoological facility, aquarium facility, wildlife sanctuary, animal rescue organization, animal rehabilitation organization, nongovernmental organization, university that has been reviewed by the Committee and—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H34C03603699E4217AF35280188611F8A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that, as of the date of the enactment of this Act, provides care to an individual of a CITES species or a threatened or endangered species; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA05FAEF6BADA44F2838CEBC932C9FB32"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has expertise in the care of wildlife and has received and provided care for a confiscated animal within the 5 years preceding the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCE3C46177B044763914F6CC628B697C2"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H27258483DFD0405B9EECAC604CBACC58"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Threatened or endangered species</header><text>The term <term>threatened or endangered species</term> means an animal species that is listed under the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1531">16 U.S.C. 1531 et seq.</external-xref>)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H16AB422BE2F4477DBEBA6E734C174563"><enum>(A)</enum><text>as a threatened species; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6F592933C7E94B95B73C319C4E8B5792"><enum>(B)</enum><text>as an endangered species.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H9911319EA38D4962923E74F8BC85DD5D"><enum>4.</enum><header>Wildlife confiscations network</header> 
<subsection id="HD403D5D582934F0FB49D468EF63FEE3B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a voluntary, cooperative program, in partnership with a professional accrediting zoological association with existing capacity and expertise in wildlife confiscations, to assist Federal wildlife law enforcement agencies with the placement and care of confiscated animals, to be known as the <quote>Wildlife Confiscations Network</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HF20B2D6F920348D187595C41DB1BE113"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Functions</header><text>The Network shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H71C838071A564D8291BA3659FF6EDB45"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establish a cooperative and coordinated response protocol for the care and welfare of confiscated animals;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H63505313DB54431EB0C43E1E7F6652BD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>create and maintain a database of qualified animal care facilities to provide immediate triage needs and long-term housing and care for confiscated animals;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H82DB107F790F451AAF329BA9C71E75CE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>establish a committee within the Network to review and approve or reject applications for inclusion in the Network submitted under subsection (c) by entities listed in paragraph (1) of that subsection; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1B57E1A6431541D4ABC49E6B34F12D2A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>act as the single point of contact for Federal wildlife law enforcement agencies to assist in the placement and care of confiscated animals in qualified zoological facilities.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4B3A37127A554A2998ECC5E006337A20"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Membership</header> 
<paragraph id="H4DE6B05AE2F24E299FF07009632B98D9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each of the following entities may submit to the Committee an application to join the Network:</text> <subparagraph id="HD40A7AF87D6B4B50856A139799FC1CB6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Wildlife sanctuaries.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2853032234B344CAB8AFD4F8E0EEE179"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Aquarium facilities.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H777D01449FA34D629C5B6C55C9E719D1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Zoological facilities.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7B6FCFCE2C7041E1B5E8C449946620EC"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Animal rescue organizations.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9C4F9B6489EC43CF99BAB560C77EA365"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Animal rehabilitation organizations.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCC0843C068A842E9ACA63B3D60B97482"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Universities.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H13D9BD30B08C4E609643D01B3E93CF29"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Nongovernmental organizations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE367F94721AF4D928581F732C81E8F09"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents of application</header><text>An application submitted under paragraph (1) by an entity listed in that paragraph shall contain information sufficient for the Committee to determine whether such entity—</text> <subparagraph id="HFCF0829E54A9483490AC9688031C2B07" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has, as determined by the Committee, the necessary credentials, including all necessary local, State, and Federal permits and licenses; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5FC2EF5A970A48CFA376FE404472C945"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is an effective, responsible, and appropriate entity capable of assisting Federal wildlife law enforcement agencies in the placement and care of confiscated animals.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB3984308DF13431193C0267F2BF75A83"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Determination</header><text>The Committee shall review each application submitted under paragraph (1) and approve or reject each such application.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H60B95B83B5D840D095C493E2A48E0A44"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Committee</header> 
<paragraph id="H5B61FE69020B4A6AA689E385BC9CEEEC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>The Committee shall include representatives from each of the following entities, provided they are members of the Network:</text> <subparagraph id="H36F5AE7642254231BBA593380DDA09C4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The United States Fish and Wildlife Service.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA1BF42474AC84CCB8B91EAD974478C17"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The professional accrediting zoological association partner administering the Network as established under section 4(a).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF320809BF8994A96A2499C14AA69B207"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Zoological facility.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB0BA7ECF2DC74B2A87AD93DA5D080BDC"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Aquarium facility.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBFF80520321847BC8B9FF3A34A4E548F"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Wildlife sanctuary.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H68B626BE25524DCDA79BD0853F0E27AE"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Nongovernmental organization.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6A57F4C8E28E4ED4A6FE1841D8744AB1"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Wildlife rehabilitation facility, wildlife rescue organization, or other animal holding facility.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4549B9903FB14E1C91BD2BAA3DA4E227"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Initial members</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with community stakeholders, including public and private entities that are actively involved in the care, rescue, and rehabilitation of any threatened or endangered species, and with advisement from the partnered professional accrediting zoological association, shall appoint each initial member to the Committee in accordance with paragraph (1).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H70C90A7D83E34FE6A29C701E66FAF0DA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Subsequent members</header><text>Except for the appointment of the initial members of the Committee under paragraph (2), each member of the Committee shall be elected by a majority vote of the members of the Committee through a call for service and application process implemented by the Committee.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H44CB74B6E0E9413588240456EA8EE57D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Term of membership</header> 
<subparagraph id="HE694C3FEE3B1427FA1D2CB21EF327B7C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Initial members</header><text>Of the initial members appointed to the Committee by the Secretary—</text> <clause id="H737A377629204202904B6AEF80DE441D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>2 members shall be appointed for a term of 1 year;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA93E8764641641F0990FD2E05F27B7A5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>2 members shall be appointed for a term of 2 years; and</text></clause> <clause id="HFDA8B385DEFA4FED8482B4E16B0691EF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>3 members shall be appointed for a term of 3 years.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC7EF4DA9C47C4C6D8D0EC0794A7080AD"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Subsequent members</header><text>Each member of the Committee elected under paragraph (3) shall serve on the Committee for a term of 3 years.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HFE7492A8EFDB45CC8BAF6BB157F1BC25"><enum>5.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">To carry out this section, $5,000,000 is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary for each of the fiscal years 2026 through 2030.</text></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

