<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ALL25096-6YM-G6-6DR"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S352 IS: Disaster Assistance Fairness Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 352</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250130">January 30, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S417">Mr. Budd</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S384">Mr. Tillis</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to provide assistance for common interest communities, condominiums, and housing cooperatives damaged by a major disaster, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HA0B7DCEE95AD4355BC5DD60800EBB44A"><section section-type="section-one" id="H7AC1980853A64102AC6550E69EB3749E"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Disaster Assistance Fairness Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H34FAE3B0C18D4FA28E7F8C536700DF53"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 102 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5122">42 U.S.C. 5122</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HE56B2090F6DC423099400E41746C8853"><paragraph id="HE2DCCFB8A42040E1B0006A766D4D5553"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Residential common interest community</header><text>The term <quote>residential common interest community</quote> means a nonprofit mandatory membership organization comprising of owners of real estate described in a declaration or created pursuant to a covenant or other applicable law with respect to which a person, by virtue of the person’s ownership of a unit of the real estate, is obligated to pay for a share of—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2448549121a34590a39768460b649faf"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">real estate taxes;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf71e76fb008e44a5bc6de7b3af4346ce"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">insurance premiums; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8edf3183876344ab94a608dcc9a597f6"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">maintenance or improvement of, or services or other expenses relating to, common elements, other units, or any other real estate other than the unit described in the declaration.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC30F2B2A2C7A4D898B7F359D2746AF57"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Condominium</header><text>The term <quote>condominium</quote> means a multi-unit housing project—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf85c015a307f4c9e9ff56b06f903a25c"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in which each dwelling unit is separately owned;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8628df18061f4ad5b31f9aa352bf52be"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the remaining portions of the real estate of which are designated for common ownership solely by the owners of the dwelling units, each owner having an undivided interest in the common elements; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide6640325505f48d593d9e7553d7740e9"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">which is represented by a condominium association consisting exclusively of the owners of each dwelling unit, which is, or will be responsible for the operation, administration, and management of the project.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAEBAA60325454A259529D49AC95BDC70"><enum>(15)</enum><header>Housing cooperative</header><text>The term <quote>housing cooperative</quote> means a multi-unit housing entity in which each dwelling unit is subject to separate use and possession by 1 or more cooperative members whose interest in such unit, and in any undivided assets of the cooperative association that are appurtenant to such unit, is evidenced by a membership or share interest in a cooperative association and a lease or other document of title or possession granted by such cooperative as the owner of all cooperative property.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="HD371E2F749F64A6492715663F783DAD1"><enum>3.</enum><header>Removal of debris resulting from a major disaster in residential common interest communities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 407 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5173">42 U.S.C. 5173</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H096AE846C0984A4BA8E198460A4CC994"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating subsections (d) and (e) as subsections (e) and (f), respectively; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBB032F090DDD421A82DAA71BC8D3778F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (c) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H2ECDB641D297439FAADE0134B725DE0F"><subsection id="H614B7ECDE36147249EA9623776E86E58"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rules relating to residential common interest communities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall issue rules which provide that removal of debris or wreckage from real estate owned by a residential common interest community resulting from a major disaster is in the public interest when a State or local government determines in writing that such debris or wreckage constitutes a threat to life, public health or safety, or the economic recovery of the residential common interest community.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="H82727F9E783348F1B46C2F58253C0916"><enum>4.</enum><header>Condominiums and housing cooperatives damaged by a major disaster</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 408(c)(2)(A) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5174">42 U.S.C. 5174(c)(2)(A)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H768F7E8FE82A491885DF081618E0D3CC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in clause (i) by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF83970DF5E484258A3094D9F9E42413D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating clause (ii) as clause (iii); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5F58AD63E88042BF98E390C1F8560C9A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after clause (i) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H857F1632494146C2BF074CEC0D68FBDC"><clause id="H1EACC781458B429FAEE4EE2A9C67BA16"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the repair of essential common elements of a condominium or housing cooperative (such as a roof, exterior wall, heating and cooling equipment, elevator, stairwell, utility access, plumbing, and electricity) if an individual’s or household’s pro rata share of essential common element repair costs are satisfactorily documented; and</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="HD04410F0F6D7466A818D78C810ED4F3B"><enum>5.</enum><header>Applicability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The amendments made by this Act shall apply with respect to a major disaster declared by the President under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5121">42 U.S.C. 5121 et seq.</external-xref>) on or after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

