<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H40D272CBA4CB4E8CBC8384A3AAFDF1BD" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-joint" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HJ 32 IH: Expressing support for designation of the week of February 3, 2025, through February 7, 2025, as “National School Counseling Week”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IA</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. J. RES. 32</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250131">January 31, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001156">Ms. Sánchez</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S000510">Mr. Smith of Washington</cosponsor>) submitted the following joint resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>JOINT RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for designation of the week of February 3, 2025, through February 7, 2025, as <quote>National School Counseling Week</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the American School Counselor Association has designated the week of February 3, 2025, through February 7, 2025, as <quote>National School Counseling Week</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas school counselors have long advocated that the education system of the United States must provide equitable opportunities for all students;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas school counselors have long emphasized the importance of personal and social development in contributing to academic achievement;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas school counselors help develop well-rounded students by guiding them through their academic, social-emotional, and career development;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas school counselors play a vital role in ensuring that students are college and career ready and aware of financial aid and college opportunities;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas school counselors may encourage students to pursue challenging academic courses to prepare them for college majors and careers in the science, technology, engineering, and mathematics fields;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas school counselors provide support for students whose family members have been deployed to conflicts overseas;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas school counselors help students cope with serious and common challenges of growing up, including peer pressure, bullying, mental health issues, school violence, disciplinary problems, and problems in the home;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas school counselors are also instrumental in helping students, teachers, and parents cope with trauma and community and national tragedies;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas school counselors are among the few professionals in a school building that are trained in both education and social and emotional development;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, despite the important contributions of school counselors to student success, counseling positions are not always protected when local budgets are cut, especially in tough economic times;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the average student-to-counselor ratio in the Nation’s public schools, 376-to-1, far exceeds the 250-to-1 ratio recommended by the American School Counselor Association, the National Association for College Admission Counseling, and other organizations;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the celebration of <quote>National School Counseling Week</quote> would increase awareness of the important and necessary role school counselors play in the lives of students in the United States; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the week of February 3, 2025, through February 7, 2025, would be an appropriate week to designate as <quote>National School Counseling Week</quote>: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H2CC6B48C71944B139FDCB787B56DB7A4"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HCEE9AE32C52D472C85F8281D7A5F1F4E"><enum/><text>That Congress—</text><paragraph id="H40D7E6AB804A4965875D0C590FA92660"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">honors and recognizes the contributions of school counselors to the success of students in the Nation’s elementary and secondary schools; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1CB8551CDD1D4DD3B2876B4E345C750F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>encourages the people of the United States to observe <quote>National School Counseling Week</quote> with appropriate ceremonies and activities that promote awareness of the crucial role school counselors play in preparing students for fulfilling lives as contributing members of society. </text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

