<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H73567E850FC44189B95731068F46C62A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2577 IH: Preparing Leaders to Assess Needs for School Safety Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2577</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250401">April 1, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000609">Mr. Rutherford</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="N000191">Mr. Neguse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000594">Mr. Tony Gonzales of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001110">Mr. Correa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001081">Mrs. Hayes</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to establish Regional School Safety Development Centers to provide consultation for schools to develop or improve a school safety plan based on evidence-based best practices, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H217E150DF7E249398076173E6DAA840D" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HA0065D9011CA44908478F705A14DAB3D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Preparing Leaders to Assess Needs for School Safety Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>PLAN for School Safety Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H85E38FEC563244BAABB9846AAE38A5B2"><enum>2.</enum><header>School safety development center program</header> <subsection id="HA1926821157E45A09BE24F01692F34CF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subtitle A of title XXII of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/651">6 U.S.C. 651 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H9C5F4567E76642F88CE3AABD406E5C64" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="H9B0955F403F74F159DF68F6D585A82D4"><enum>2220F.</enum><header>School Safety Development Center Program</header> 
<subsection id="HAF006E54BE0D423881F052153EFBDB3F" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall make awards, including grants or cooperative agreements, to eligible entities to establish, improve, or maintain statewide or intrastate Regional School Safety Development Centers (<quote>School Safety Development Centers</quote>) for the purposes of providing customized consulting services to schools to develop, improve, or implement the school’s individualized school safety plan.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HF92C8FC330364DEF9B834D2CFC677017"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Awards</header> <paragraph id="HD49D9543675B4A2A9B726EE7693DFC80"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Application</header><text>To seek an award under this section, an eligible entity shall submit an application to the Director at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Director may require. At minimum, any such application shall include evidence of the applicant’s expertise in comprehensive school safety and school climate, including evidence-based violence prevention for students and educators, suicide prevention, student mental health, and school security.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H592D387ECC014D88B921AC8F7707B9C9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Preference</header><text>In making awards under this section, the Director shall, as appropriate, give preference to eligible entities that have existing relationships with local schools, particularly those in rural, Tribal, or low-resourced communities, as applicable by the proposed geographical area, or minority-serving institutions described in sections 371(a) and 326(e)(1) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1067q">20 U.S.C. 1067q(a)</external-xref> and 1063b(e)(1)).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE28D26BFB0F34DBB9E5D8582E6BF12A2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity shall use an award received under this section to establish, improve, or maintain a School Safety Development Center, which shall include each of the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HEB952C5A522A44B4B583C3731C2160ED"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Developing communications materials for and disseminating to schools, educators, parents, legal guardians, and youth, and increasing State-wide or intrastate regional public awareness of evidence-based research and best practices for school safety and student mental health.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H726669EEB8704979B28DB67987082EAB"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Conducting individualized consultations with schools to research and analyze a school’s existing school safety and student mental health policies, or developing or improving, in coordination with a school, a customized school safety and student mental health plan to fit the individualized, age- and developmentally-appropriate needs of such school community based on evidence-based best practices.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1957CBA6E76049FA9FA76CF63D1CE224"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Assisting schools in the implementation of their customized school safety and mental health plan, including the following:</text> <clause id="H1EA143E809A04A88B920E8116182F6D9"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Identification of Federal or State government funding for implementation of the plan, in whole or in part.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H4C3F614C5E4640B9A4DD774B6B8DD31D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Provide training, resources, or technical assistance to assist schools in applying for such Federal or State government funding.</text></clause> <clause id="HA2A2FD507F244B4F9040B3E1261013DC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Providing training, resources, and technical assistance to educate school staff and families regarding the policies and procedures of the plan.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAF241EE6480643C595B49B9333661AE9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Matching requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal share of the cost of activities for which a grant or cooperative agreement is made to an eligible entity under this section may not exceed 95 percent of the total cost of such activities.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HB4A14552AF0B4B72ADE577365DBBE23F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Award administration</header> <paragraph id="HA653642EDAA24D72B0144F8D38908B37"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Training and technical assistance</header><text>The Director, in consultation with the Secretary of Education and the Youth Advisory Council (established pursuant to paragraph (2)(C)), shall provide eligible entities receiving awards under this section, training and technical assistance on the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H9F1835132EF14C88947B126249E5B33D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Best practices for individualized consulting with schools based on their unique needs for implementation in accordance with subsection (b)(3).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H854047B8D9B44D40AC84A67DB6861BEA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Evidence-based practices and recommendations established under section 2220D that are presented in a clear and concise manner for schools and the public.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H109D4A3D54CD4350A94FAD7F65995F75"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Subject matter experts</header> 
<subparagraph id="H5A067E791F19429FA8598ACECDDA5B24"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Personnel</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall hire additional personnel and contractors with expertise in school mental health and school administration to provide additional subject matter expertise in implementing evidence-based programming within schools to carry out paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9589639B6B8048FA87989C81B4F9758D" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Detailee</header> <clause id="H350DD7EE88654DE7923AF64CEF7B57D2" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Education shall detail, on a reimbursable basis, to the Agency an employee of the Department of Education to assist in the provision of the training and technical assistance described in paragraph (1).</text></clause> 
<clause id="H0C81546BC83F4569805BD4574EC7BFAD" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Reimbursement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall reimburse the Secretary of Education for any costs associated with the detailee under clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1A21AB9AE1CE47149243F322784F6B13"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Youth Advisory Council</header> <clause id="H9FD5606F4BD14F389E4C7E677551E1CC"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this section, the Director shall establish and convene a Youth Advisory Council for the purpose of providing joint advice on the implementation of this section.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H10B7BA559FEC4D8489CD06A402E49705"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Participation</header><text>The Youth Advisory Council shall include participation from the following:</text> <subclause id="H9E8789F911114C1FB455BD01D2ECC1D1"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Parents, academic experts, mental health professionals, and members of civil society with respect to the prevention of violence in schools.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HCBD25ACB6A0D4983A4E1AFC228AAB030"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Youth representation, including youth who have experienced school violence.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF04372B9F39843A89479CCFA8E532421"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text>Not later than two years after the date of the enactment of this section and annually thereafter, the Director shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security, the Committee on the Judiciary, the Committee on Education and Workforce, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs, the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions, and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate a report on actions taken by the Director to implement this section, including information relating to the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HAE51F704D8F041C4911CE43031A432B9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The name, location, and number of eligible entities in each State receiving awards under this section.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H15970729890246DB90DF95D0AFBBA679" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A comparative analysis of actions recommended in school safety plans by such eligible entities through the School Safety Development Centers assisted through such awards.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0F893B20D4B9424CB45C936D598E2361"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of the effectiveness of such School Safety Development Centers in assisting schools to develop and implement school safety plans, as a means to avert violence, including self-harm, if applicable, and policy recommendations for improved effectiveness.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HBF5B1C726ECC44EC99DB77C6BDB45A34"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header> <paragraph id="H4549A8B5213D4C47890D954A797A0BDD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Waiver of requirements</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to establish, satisfy, or waive any requirement under any of the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H641275FA90844FDAA6C8DDEBE85FEA25"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Title II of the Americans With Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12131">42 U.S.C. 12131 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H481B3A88EE284B9698457FF9FC3A901D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/701">29 U.S.C. 701 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H04EA40C614534B6982090E3FEBF39F7F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d">42 U.S.C. 2000d et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H20C2E84EAA3C4EEEAC8736B0A1B71C11"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Title IX of the Education Amendments of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1681">20 U.S.C. 1681 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE10CFA7BA8E04025900DF0FC078660D8"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The Age Discrimination Act of 1975 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6101">42 U.S.C. 6101 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB37D93F50C1A401DA0652BA9A8E65AE0"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1232g">20 U.S.C. 1232g</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H38D9CDFD70D9426D9A6610487FA7A49F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>No effect on other laws</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section may be construed to preclude or contradict any other provision of law authorizing training in the use of firearms.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HAE47A13A31AE43709BD8ECACA3135517"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header> <paragraph id="HA4C9D416E10641DB870147B63301A401" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To carry out this section, there are authorized to be appropriated $25,000,000 annually from fiscal years 2026 through 2030.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCF90B059376A4D6D95E46C8EECBD1DFC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Restriction on use of funds</header><text>Amounts made available to carry out this section may not be used to—</text> <subparagraph id="H0AA86AD8DD5E4561A55C3228607D0BC8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>consult or train any school or person in the use of firearms; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H42CA04913F70476C866E1EC2CA0F69C6" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">hire school personnel or school-based contractors for the schools the School Safety Development Centers are advising under subsection (b)(3).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE52F08A8AB34475B978876419D25306B"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H1366CECF029D4F5EBA557A0E1DB290C2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible entities</header><text>The term <quote>eligible entities</quote> means any of the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HA50AAE731ED949C58570D0EE82780DF4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A State.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1C413916DD6C49FBA090C34CDF5217D8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A State educational agency (as such term is defined in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBB28048B432441D0A377B2DFC7F52710"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A Tribal educational agency (as such term is defined in section 6132 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7452">20 U.S.C. 7452</external-xref>)).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA6006C8207CA4198A4EE6550F0D30DA9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>An institution of higher education eligible for assistance under title III of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1051">20 U.S.C. 1051 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5256C5BF53BA454D8593F306C5AECD12"><enum>(E)</enum><text>A Tribal College or University (as such term is defined in section 313 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1059c">20 U.S.C. 1059c</external-xref>)).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB54F2C558C19423395D9F5836B99FFA3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Evidence-based</header><text>The term <quote>evidence-based</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBB4E7A01E54C48568690ECF9BAFF4981"><enum>(3)</enum><header>School</header><text>The term <quote>school</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 2704 of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10554">34 U.S.C. 10554</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H724EB7F10D7A4C458C39B17CCB93F319"><enum>(4)</enum><header>School safety plan</header><text>The term <quote>school safety plan</quote> means a set of common actions schools can take to address the foundational elements of school safety, including designated staff, school climate and mental health, reporting systems, threat assessment, emergency planning, educator training, student prevention training, exercises and drills, site assessments, and recovery plans.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H1578120AB6C1457B8C985B1439439551"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents in section 1(b) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 2220E the following new item:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H8A9C8193B1FD4CD8A3661E0EABA03A71" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 2220F. School Safety Development Center program.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

