<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF5EB8200578948A1822C86CA4B27411D" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 111 IH: Expressing support for blockchain technology and digital assets.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 111</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250205">February 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000301">Mr. Johnson of South Dakota</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001213">Mr. Steil</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000230">Mr. Davis of North Carolina</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000486">Mr. Torres of New York</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for blockchain technology and digital assets.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas entrepreneurs and innovators are building and deploying this next generation of the internet;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas digital asset networks represent a new way for people to join together and cooperate with one another to undertake certain activities;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas digital assets have the potential to be the foundational building blocks of these networks, aligning the economic incentive for individuals to cooperate with one another to achieve a common purpose;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the digital asset ecosystem has the potential to grow our economy and improve everyday lives of Americans by facilitating collaboration through the use of technology to manage activities, allocate resources, and facilitate decision making;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas blockchain networks and the digital assets they empower provide creator control, enhance transparency, reduce transaction costs, and increase efficiency;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas blockchain technology facilitates new types of network participation which businesses in the United States may utilize in innovative ways;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas digital asset companies are establishing operations outside of the United States, in countries that embrace the potential of blockchain technology and digital assets and provide safeguards for consumers through clear legal frameworks; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas digital assets, despite the purported anonymity, provide law enforcement with an exceptional tracing tool to identify illicit activity and bring criminals to justice: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H2252E37475274D68A02A1CE2E12F678C"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HCED442CE18D649199FD7B9D45F88F713"><enum/><text>That it is the sense of the House of Representatives that—</text><paragraph id="HA3F740D4459B430085FFA335CA062E8B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the United States should seek to prioritize understanding the potential opportunities of the next generation of the internet;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HACBEBFF754F6403A98EB7316B2B27467"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the United States should seek to foster advances in technology to improve our financial system and create more fair and equitable access to financial services for everyday Americans;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC0A1F0049E1D4050AC650C62E11F7E69"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the United States must support the development of digital assets and the underlying technology in the United States or risk the shifting of the development of such assets and technology outside of the United States, to less regulated countries;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9EC7A7E30F4A4F4DB99DF7B8F4AC3DB4"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the United States should strive to be a global leader in the development and adoption of digital assets and blockchain technology;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H56F3B4193CCC401FB89CEC1122D7BB79"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress should enact a functional framework tailored to the specific risks of different digital asset-related activities and unique benefits of distributed ledger technology, distributed networks, and decentralized systems; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H555D26B49D0E4172B05DF66326E4DE7E"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consumers and market participants will benefit from a framework for digital assets consistent with longstanding investor protections in securities and commodities markets, yet tailored to the unique benefits and risks of the digital asset ecosystem.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

