<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9AD3916F50294FDE9CB2D1178D28686E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 759 IH: Federal Firefighters Families First Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 759</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250128">January 28, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000598">Mr. Garcia of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001117">Mr. Casten</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000530">Mr. Deluzio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000874">Mr. Hoyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001214">Mr. Mrvan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001156">Ms. Sánchez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001205">Ms. Scanlon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000188">Mr. Norcross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001112">Mr. Carbajal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001090">Mr. Harder of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000476">Mr. Frost</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000606">Mr. Raskin</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 5, United States Code, to provide for pay equality and the more accurate computation of retirement benefits for certain firefighters employed by the Federal Government, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H86C5F681208B435C986876B607CD08E5" style="OLC"><section id="HDF94046350FF439F8A93768C9D1753B1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; purposes</header><subsection id="H995C2E5C150B4DDE81827D915C2E26F8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Federal Firefighters Families First Act</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HCAF2D780C52941B6A4EEE3C5DB44603C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of this Act are—</text><paragraph id="H46FA17EB676845279D6AD067FA202A4D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to improve pay equality between Federal firefighters, other Federal employees, and municipal and other public sector firefighters;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H405BCB8752914ED1853184F3C4379BA1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to enhance recruitment and retention of firefighters in order to maintain the highest quality of Federal fire service;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2E5D9F9FC2C34526994DDF52A7F78F5D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to include the pay of all regularly reoccurring scheduled hours during the firefighter workweek when computing such retirement benefits of firefighters; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEF47D3564C1946BF98674D1C0ED2BCD7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to establish the regular workweek for Federal firefighters.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H856FF7C99FC8460993023EA562799D77" commented="no"><enum>2.</enum><header>Computation of pay</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Sections 5545b(b)(1)(A) and 5545b(c)(1)(B) of title 5, United States Code, are amended by striking <quote>2756</quote> and inserting <quote>2087</quote>.</text></section><section id="HA7CB94754D944BE6A9E59041DC68BF88"><enum>3.</enum><header>Computation of annuity based on certain firefighter service</header><subsection id="HC682D75A1DF84F0DADD258D4D4578FC5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 5545b of title 5, United States Code, as amended by section 2, is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HDE3FABA0F0164B22B696CA854470D1A9" style="OLC"><subsection id="H60C492D2A0464E498AE3AA105FE994EF"><enum>(e)</enum><text>For purposes of any determination of <term>average pay</term> under section 8331(4) or 8401(3), in the case of a firefighter who is subject to subsection (b), the rate of basic pay in effect for such firefighter for a year of creditable service (or, in the case of an annuity under subsection (d) or (e)(1) of section 8341 or under chapter 84 based on less than 3 years of creditable service, for any other period of creditable service) shall, in addition to the amount determined under subsection (b) for such year (or other period), include an amount equal to one-half the firefighter’s basic hourly rate (as computed under subsection (b)(1)(A)) for such year (or other period) times the number of overtime hours included as part of such firefighter’s regular tour of duty during such year (or other period).</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HD5810D79EA244B6BAC32484A4F85F46B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text>Sections 8331(4) and 8401(3) of title 5, United States Code, are amended by striking the semicolon at the end and inserting <quote>, subject to section 5545b(e);</quote>.</text></subsection></section><section id="H7F488CAE813C4BD1A02C252AA95C1608" commented="no"><enum>4.</enum><header>Establishment of a maximum hours of Federal firefighters’ regular workweek</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 5545b of title 5, United States Code, as amended by section 3, is further amended by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H0A375D25C87C4350A5B1ED3B82494D80" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H759CCE474CFD4BC38E6030C1135EBB83" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of enactment of the Federal Firefighters Families First Act, the Office of Personnel Management shall prescribe regulations establishing the maximum number of regularly reoccurring hours which comprise a workweek for a firefighter covered by this section. The maximum number of such hours shall not exceed an average of 60 hours per week.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H5BC5F624511241ED9B69E3803933E651"><enum>5.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The amendments made by this Act shall apply with respect to any annuity entitlement to which is based on a separation from service occurring after the end of the 60-day period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

