<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H03098CD2D0964601A45C6D7D7417FE58" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 255 IH: To name the Department of Veterans Affairs community-based outpatient clinic in Lubbock, Texas, as the “General Bernie Mittemeyer VA Clinic”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 255</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250109">January 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="A000375">Mr. Arrington</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To name the Department of Veterans Affairs community-based outpatient clinic in Lubbock, Texas, as the <quote>General Bernie Mittemeyer VA Clinic</quote>.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC69536451F0049A7BF11DE12E7D18280" style="OLC"><section id="HF2F9E132BEB843789B909979A82A4240" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Name of Department of Veterans Affairs community-based outpatient clinic, Lubbock, Texas</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"> The Department of Veterans Affairs community-based outpatient clinic in Lubbock, Texas, shall after the date of the enactment of this Act be known and designated as the <quote>General Bernie Mittemeyer VA Clinic</quote>. Any reference to such clinic in any law, regulation, map, document, record, or other paper of the United States shall be considered to be a reference to the General Bernie Mittemeyer VA Clinic.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

