<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" slc-id="S1-NEW25465-J74-5L-DNG"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 256 IS: Designating May 2025 as “American Stroke Month”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code>III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 256</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250522">May 22, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S409">Mr. Luján</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Designating May 2025 as <quote>American Stroke
 Month</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas quick identification and treatment for stroke results in a higher chance of survival and reduces recovery time for individuals experiencing a stroke;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas treatment depends on the type of stroke someone is having, which must be diagnosed by a health care professional;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, when dealing with a time-sensitive medical emergency like a stroke, the right care, at the right time, at the right facility, is of the utmost importance;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas a system of care allows for scientifically proven measures to be applied to every patient, every time;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, every 40 seconds, someone in the United States has a stroke;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas stroke is a leading cause of serious long-term disability and the fifth-leading cause of death in the United States, causing more than 160,000 deaths each year;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas nearly <fraction>1/2</fraction> of adults in the United States have high blood pressure, which is a leading cause and controllable risk factor for stroke;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the <quote>F.A.S.T.</quote> warning signs and symptoms of stroke include face drooping, arm weakness, speech difficulty, and time to call 911;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, during American Stroke Month in May, and year-round, the <quote>Together to End Stroke</quote> initiative of the American Stroke Association strives to teach people everywhere that stroke is largely preventable, treatable, and beatable; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas more research and education is needed to help prevent and treat stroke: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="S1"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph commented="no" id="idc2df25b83fde49f4aabb4955c5c56feb"><enum>(1)</enum><text>designates May 2025 as <quote>American Stroke Month</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf0ee80a2535745c78e4ebb8720087d6c"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes and reaffirms the commitment of the Federal Government and people of the United States to fighting stroke—</text><subparagraph id="id317c487448ff4ef0aee0bac686b1cef6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by promoting awareness about the causes, risks, and prevention of stroke;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0df14269f4a640eb97258b626cab16de"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by supporting research on stroke; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd47ef7e0e3b04550a86ceeb1e7f17844"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by improving access to affordable, quality care to reduce long-term disability and mortality;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id44e3c7cbd33945e5999a87f421fddddd"><enum>(3)</enum><text>commends the efforts of States, territories, and possessions of the United States, localities, nonprofit organizations, businesses and other entities, and the people of the United States who support American Stroke Month; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9ce4acdb1dbe44cfa5f83b06b6e69efc"><enum>(4)</enum><text>encourages all individuals in the United States to familiarize themselves with the risk factors associated with stroke, recognize the warning signs and symptoms, and on first sign of a stroke, dial 911 immediately in order to begin to reduce the devastating effects of stroke on the population of the United States.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution>

