<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCE42591064064EDCB79C3E6A7E8A6DA1" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 558 IH: Remembering the lives lost and honoring the survivors 3 years after the Independence Day Parade shooting that occurred on July 4, 2022, in Highland Park, Illinois.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 558</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250627">June 27, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001190">Mr. Schneider</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001315">Ms. Budzinski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001117">Mr. Casten</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000454">Mr. Foster</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000586">Mr. García of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000617">Mrs. Ramirez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001225">Mr. Sorensen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="U000040">Ms. Underwood</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="J000309">Mr. Jackson of Illinois</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Remembering the lives lost and honoring the survivors 3 years after the Independence Day Parade shooting that occurred on July 4, 2022, in Highland Park, Illinois.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, in Highland Park, Illinois, on July 4, 2022, thousands of joyous spectators lined the Independence Day Parade route expectantly waiting for their children and grandchildren, their friends, neighbors, and coworkers to walk by in procession;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, at 10:14 a.m. that day, just moments after the Highland Park Independence Day Parade began, the sense of community elation was shattered by a single individual who acquired a gun, climbed a ladder to a rooftop, and fired 80 bullets into the joyous crowd below;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the 7 people who were murdered that day were—</text><paragraph id="HD0F57698CF174B2FBD19BC5DB50CA45B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Katie Goldstein, age 64, of Highland Park, Illinois, a beloved wife and mother, who was known for her kind, caring personality, and for bringing neighbors delicious baked goods during the holidays;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H166C1FB680DD419A8D10B149F5499AB6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Irina McCarthy, age 35, of Highland Park, Illinois, a wife and mother of 2-year-old Aiden, who met her husband Kevin through their mutual work in the pharmaceutical industry;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFCBE17DB537F405680FB8FFD47430B9D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Kevin McCarthy, age 37, of Highland Park, Illinois, a husband and father of 2-year-old Aiden, who died protecting his son from gunfire;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0BECF21C990C406E90EE38E8D64855E5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Stephen Strauss, age 88, of Highland Park, Illinois, a brother, husband, father, and grandfather, who was a joke-teller and avid reader and greatly enjoyed the Art Institute of Chicago and the Chicago Symphony Orchestra;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H859D6B1438484752B72767F88B6C5CDB"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Jacquelyn Sundheim, age 63, of Highland Park, Illinois, a kind and caring wife and mother, who was a lifelong member of North Shore Congregation Israel in Glencoe, where she also taught preschool and served as the events coordinator;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC58274545C94488795BDAC6945D5B69E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Nicolas Toledo-Zaragoza, age 78, of Morelos, Mexico, who was attending the parade with his children, grandchildren, and great-grandchildren; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF05C0ED1EFE34F4BA0CF20A8E6B1925B"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Eduardo Uvaldo, age 69, of Waukegan, Illinois, who was a devoted husband, father, and grandfather;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas more than 40 people were wounded by bullets and shrapnel, many grievously injured;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 2-year-old Aiden McCarthy lost both parents who sacrificed their lives while saving his;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 8-year-old Cooper Roberts suffered a severed spinal cord, impairing his ability to walk, and his mother Keely and twin brother Luke were also injured;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas all who attended the parade and who live in Highland Park will be forever changed by this tragedy;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Highland Park Police Department and the Highland Park Fire Department led dozens of agencies in responding to the shooting with bravery and professionalism, including—</text><paragraph id="H56759DDC943C43569CD624BD6B335738"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Illinois State Police, the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives, the Federal Bureau of Investigation, the United States Secret Service, the United States Marshals Service, the Naval Criminal Investigative Service, the Lake County Major Crimes Task Force, the Lake County Sheriff’s Office, the Cook County Sheriff’s Office, the Northwest Central Dispatch System, the Regional Emergency Dispatch Center (RED Center), the Glenview Public Safety Dispatch Center, the Highland Park Community Emergency Response Team (CERT);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA521D62C32D04654ABADAC3599D6F590"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the police departments of Addison, Antioch, Arlington Heights, Bannockburn, Barrington, Barrington Hills, Bartlett, Berwyn, Buffalo Grove, Carpentersville, Cary, Crystal Lake, Deerfield, Des Plaines, Elk Grove Village, Elmhurst, Evanston, Fox Lake, Franklin Park, Glencoe Public Safety, Glenview, Grayslake, Gurnee, Hanover Park, Harwood Heights, Hoffman Estates, Inverness, Kenilworth, Kildeer, Lake Bluff, Lake Forest, Lake Villa, Lake Zurich, Libertyville, Lincolnshire, Lincolnwood, McHenry, Morton Grove, Mount Prospect, Mundelein, Niles, Norridge, North Chicago, North Riverside, Northbrook, Northfield, Palatine, Prospect Heights, Riverwoods, Rolling Meadows, Rosemont, Round Lake, Round Lake Beach, Round Lake Park, Schiller Park, Skokie, Streamwood, Vernon Hills, Wauconda, Waukegan, Western Springs, Wheeling, Wilmette, Winnetka, Winthrop Harbor, and Zion; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H71BBB4B56F5C40748E1812BBF8C42984"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the fire departments of Addison Fire Protection District, Buffalo Grove, Deerfield-Bannockburn Fire Protection District, Des Plaines, Evanston, Glencoe Public Safety, Glenview, Hanover Park, Lake Bluff, Lake Forest, Libertyville, Lincolnshire-Riverwoods Fire Protection District, Morton Grove, Niles, Northbrook, Northfield, Park Ridge, Prospect Heights, Skokie, Streamwood, Waukegan, Wilmette, and Winnetka;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the emergency responders and the doctors, nurses, and other health care providers at Highland Park Hospital, Glenbrook Hospital, Evanston Hospital, Northwestern Medicine Lake Forest Hospital, Advocate Lutheran General Hospital, and University of Chicago Medicine Comer Children’s Hospital provided professional and dedicated care to the victims;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in the 3 years since, dozens of volunteer counselors traveled to North Shore School District 112 and Township High School District 113 to assist the community in the process of healing and met with several thousand community members in need of counseling;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas a significant step towards justice has been served with the person responsible for this horrific crime sentenced to life in prison with no possibility for parole;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the people of Highland Park and across the United States still mourn the 7 lives tragically cut short and continue to pray for all the people, their family and friends irreparably changed by this tragedy;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the people of Highland Park and of the United States mourn for all whose lives were stolen, and pray for all who have been irreversibly affected by gun violence in our country—whether by mass shootings, violence in our streets, domestic violence, suicide, or accidental shooting;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Highland Park is strong, and fortunate to be supported by its neighbors and friends both near and far who have stood united with the community and will remain so as they mark this 3-year anniversary; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in June 2022, Congress passed, and the President signed into law, the Bipartisan Safer Communities Act: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HD8BC72A655294C20A546CC6A493D65DD"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H55CA2328A4A848588BF26773D6F1B815"><enum/><text>That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="H1536A6BE235D4A9797F419215C33CE90"><enum>(1)</enum><text>remembers the horrific Independence Day Parade mass shooting that occurred in Highland Park, Illinois, on July 4, 2022;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBDB2D51C3F834A15B1A1EFA5826D4D14"><enum>(2)</enum><text>joins with Highland Park as they will gather to mark the 3rd anniversary of the tragic day;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7199DE570E1C4BC2A6473D7400964912"><enum>(3)</enum><text>honors the memory and the lives of the 7 innocent people who were murdered—Katie Goldstein, Irina McCarthy, Keven McCarthy, Steven Strauss, Jacquelyn Sundheim, Nicolas Toledo-Zaragoza, and Eduardo Uvaldo;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H67EB6C03E8C7412BB2D9D278EBEDE0A6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>stands with all those who were wounded or otherwise affected in the shooting, and continues to pray for their recovery;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3910A44DE8D84400969399A68D291515"><enum>(5)</enum><text>is united with the residents of Highland Park and Lake County, Illinois, as well as the families, friends, and loved ones as they continue to march toward recovery;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9ACA56F6D6494E82A60CD772FC13D29D"><enum>(6)</enum><text>reiterates its hope that all those injured by the attack, both physically and emotionally, continue to recover, and vows to support all those impacted by the violence;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC935265C84B44E42A79C3A0AC3BEC1A3"><enum>(7)</enum><text>commends the courageous actions of the individuals who placed themselves in harm’s way to protect others during this heinous attack;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H50E8A50B0F3E41E9A1878893F8125A34"><enum>(8)</enum><text>remains grateful for the bravery of community members, leaders, law enforcement, first responders, health professionals, and all others who responded to the attack;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H51D68EE15D6742449846974871B50A83"><enum>(9)</enum><text>expresses admiration for the resolve and courage that the City of Highland Park, its elected leaders, and the community as a whole have demonstrated in the 3 years since the attack and pledges its continued support for the community; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H55278F2AC1FD40C58735BF169B67FE2F"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">strives to continue to work to reduce gun violence in the United States.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

