<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H32496CFF96704BAEB64B271053129201" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4192 IH: the Military PFAS Transparency Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4192</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250626">June 26, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001237">Ms. McDonald Rivet</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="B001301">Mr. Bergman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000399">Mrs. Kiggans of Virginia</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 10, United States Code, to direct the Secretary of Defense to submit to Congress an annual report on the funding and status of interim remedial actions of the Department of Defense relating to perfluoroalkyl and polyfluoroalkyl substances, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC4A2C48D2B154481A0D0749A593387B4" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H3BFE9FADDBF6457D960F4863B25EBDDB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as <quote><short-title>the Military PFAS Transparency Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H36B79870B7564CE69B5B1A8345BD1892"><enum>2.</enum><header>Annual report on funding and status of interim remedial actions of Department of Defense relating to PFAS</header> 
<subsection id="HA74EB890D391444591A88C3D99FC8BA9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/160">Chapter 160</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="H5A4E095CD149449794F5D0D4586EE3BE" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <section id="H8DD08E5389584F04952E4D57BE0BCD33"><enum>2717.</enum><header>Annual report on perfluoroalkyl and polyfluoroalkyl substances</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE06681ECBAAD442AB21549CF4F9D43F1"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this section, and annually thereafter, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives a report on the funding and status of interim remedial actions of the Department of Defense relating to perfluoroalkyl and polyfluoroalkyl substances (in this section referred to as <quote>PFAS</quote>).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1B4203F3420145468B28E800BD9C8B03"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>Each report required by subsection (a) shall include information regarding the following:</text> <paragraph id="H12C26139E0A94B458A3BA7F8B83F41DB"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The total funding budgeted and obligated, for the current fiscal year and for any prior fiscal year, per site at each installation, for interim remedial actions of the Department of Defense relating to PFAS.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB2725F0888A4407FAADD846D7CA9CB04"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of each report after the initial report, the total funding budgeted, obligated and expensed, per site at each installation, on such actions since the previous report.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBFC727673B8245BFADB05565F79836BE"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The general and operating status of interim remedial actions related to PFAS per site at each installation, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H25A4B4EECC954575B567AF2F1CCB5668"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a list of all announced or selected interim remedial actions, and for each such action, the function and role of the action with respect to addressing PFAS at the installation;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0EA05C5BAFBB425FBF778754C80E0D8C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for each action listed, a phase-specific status update including whether—</text> 
<clause id="H17D472A69F7542BF94AC711C365CD196"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the design is pending, in progress, or completed;</text></clause> <clause id="H200DCD776FCF44F3964B9466E33A4367"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>contracting is pending, in solicitation, awarded, or delayed;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HE48D3F08869D47209933B6C0FB7E247D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>construction or execution has begun, is in progress, completed, or delayed;</text></clause> <clause id="H0B778A055BD6485DB8BAAE99F280BD2B"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the action is currently operating, its duration, and any performance metrics available;</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC943F4F185A84DEBBB3B071BB97CA56D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>identification of actions that are one-time in nature (such as soil removal and disposal), and the status of each action;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC02FB22749074DFB9251C16399EC5F43"><enum>(D)</enum><text>timelines for completion of each phase, including original projected timelines and any updates;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H49062948F9D6422C99AA855F037EBD73"><enum>(E)</enum><text>for any phase delayed by more than 12 months beyond the original projection, a site-specific explanation for the delay; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB516C1B983614229AEF4E941543E489F"><enum>(F)</enum><text>identification of any administrative, regulatory, funding, or other barriers contributing to delays or budgetary effects, along with the plan of the Secretary to address each such barrier.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> </section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8B8E0B0A8D6845578F985993D682CB55"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Required remediation acceleration strategy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees a perfluoroalkyl and polyfluoroalkyl substances remediation acceleration strategy, which shall include—</text> <paragraph id="HF2F1AD0946604AF681FCFCDC04A4B0EB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>criteria for prioritizing military installations based on risk to human health, environmental impact, and proximity to affected communities;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA79741EAC7114993AB1A45373CCABDD9"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">timelines for completing each phase of the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9601">42 U.S.C. 9601 et seq.</external-xref>) cleanup process;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5C25321A9476435C9E5A2807C6F8A000"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a plan for deploying additional resources, technologies, or personnel to reduce delays, including an identification of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H638D9E49878F44FC8C9566E33369F518"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of laboratories that are accredited by the Department of Defense Environmental Laboratory Accreditation Program to test for PFAS; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDAB1FAD6D085444BBE33C8C92C070F79"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of laboratories that are in the process of being so accredited; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H065999ED85B54F96B856C1F700DD7CE8"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">benchmarks for evaluating performance of each military department or defense agency on perfluoroalkyl and polyfluoroalkyl substances response efforts.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H35A8B1DFBC0C4A839512BA61B07D9F8B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Public transparency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall make publicly available an accessible online dashboard that includes the actions of the Department of Defense relating to perfluoroalkyl and polyfluoroalkyl substances. The dashboard shall be updated semiannually and shall include a summary of—</text> 
<paragraph id="H3384964FBEB14C7AAD10D7D5D1FB8EFB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>site-by-site funding levels and expenditures at each installation;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD2DC44AB635A4543AD84ECB35FC053DB"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the status of remediation and investigation efforts;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5ACC0B0859C84D62A4B0E80EF7D43151"><enum>(3)</enum><text>projected and actual completion timelines; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H442FB490B20849E0B536E397DAEEAA6F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>points of contact for community engagement.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

