<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-BUR25153-67D-N9-97L">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1861 IS: Servicemember Healthcare Freedom Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>II</distribution-code>
        <congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session>1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. 1861</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action>
            <action-date date="20250522">May 22, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</sponsor> introduced the following
                bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title>To amend title 10, United States Code, to allow members of the Selected
            Reserve and National Guard holding employment within the Federal Government the choice
            between military and civilian healthcare plans, and for other purposes.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause">
        <section section-type="section-one" id="S1">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Servicemember Healthcare Freedom Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf1b22ac79d7547809e176c58d9cebcfb">
            <enum>2.</enum>
            <header>Findings</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> <paragraph id="id0b78db571ca64c009028ea673b9182f7"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>Thousands of members of reserve components and the National Guard, in addition to their military service, work for the United States Government in a civilian capacity.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="idbab2c0a32dc04c68aec272d19b019691">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>Nearly all members of the Selected Reserve and the National Guard, and their families, are entitled to purchase a TRICARE Reserve Select (TRS) healthcare plan as a service-related benefit.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="idf4c6caef1fda401bbef396c426533d69">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>As of the day before the date of the enactment of this Act, eligibility for Federal Employee Health Benefits (FEHB) prohibits members of the Selected Reserve and National Guard from enrolling in TRS plans.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="idb56a3c18de1446eda241a48e610afc2f">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>Removal of such prohibition for members of the Selected Reserve and the National Guard will provide continuity of care throughout mobilization cycles.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="id63b3ae5952864601817cc9045038fa1a">
                <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text>Providing members of the Armed Forces with the ability to purchase comprehensive, low-cost health insurance increases the readiness and lethality of the Armed Forces as a whole.</text>
            </paragraph>
        </section>
        <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb3498a4289224d608cd76b4ec43d3457">
            <enum>3.</enum>
            <header>Modification of expiration date to allow members of the Selected Reserve and
                National Guard, eligible for Federal Employee Health Benefits, to enroll into
                TRICARE Reserve Select as of January 1, 2026</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1076d(a)(2) of title 10, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>January 1, 2030’’ and inserting “January 1, 2026</quote>.</text>
        </section>
    </legis-body>
</bill>

