<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5DE82D827E7A45E499EE2094D9623B76" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 381 IH: LNG Public Interest Determination Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 381</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250114">January 14, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001117">Mr. Casten</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001066">Ms. Castor of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000593">Mr. Levin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001223">Mr. Magaziner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001225">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Natural Gas Act to require that impacts to climate stability, consumer energy costs, and environmental justice be considered in a determination of whether proposed exportation of natural gas is in the public interest, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6B5545FD8E80487D8BCB3036F8250A0A" style="OLC"><section id="H82BA2A5A20F64E2288A39F7B565354CC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>LNG Public Interest Determination Act of 2025</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="HE099FF9AB4D84CDC9D28C8BA870F2297"><enum>2.</enum><header>Exportation of natural gas</header><subsection id="H6E2E460F403E443E89333B4EAD94269E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Exportation of natural gas</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3 of the Natural Gas Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/717b">15 U.S.C. 717b</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H2B3476C334D44002ADA27CCA876466F5" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="HF215445CC4F4425F9A1E811561606B60"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Exportation of natural gas</header><paragraph id="HE62078F2019B4DD9966F41F64EA256D3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Order required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No person shall export any natural gas from the United States to a foreign country without first having secured an order of the Secretary of Energy authorizing it to do so. The Secretary of Energy may issue such order upon application only if, after opportunity for hearing, the Secretary of Energy finds that the proposed exportation will be consistent with the public interest. The Secretary of Energy may by its order grant such application, in whole or in part, with such modification and upon such terms and conditions as the Secretary of Energy may find necessary or appropriate, and may from time to time, after opportunity for hearing, and for good cause shown, issue such supplemental order for such exportation as it may find necessary or appropriate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD6A3EAB7B0F7496FAA96321B880E9858"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Deadline</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Energy shall find whether proposed exportation of natural gas will be consistent with the public interest under paragraph (1) by not later than the date that is 1 year after the later of—</text><subparagraph id="HF1BBE796382A4A4C897CFAC43707AB05"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the date on which the Secretary of Energy receives the final environmental impact statement for such proposed exportation from the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDB6E2FF1D7AF4E59B5241C975AF5F3B1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the date on which the Secretary completes each assessment required by paragraph (4). </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H51A73A1D729E438D80ADEDF932F3C23B" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public interest finding</header><text>The Secretary of Energy may find that proposed exportation of natural gas for which an application is submitted under paragraph (1) will be consistent with the public interest under such paragraph only if the Secretary of Energy determines, based on the applicable assessment under paragraph (4), that the proposed exportation of natural gas will not be likely to—</text><subparagraph id="H26909A7F67F04928A5E366672905DA0A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">significantly contribute to climate change, including by slowing the global energy transition needed to achieve deep reductions of global greenhouse gas emissions within the next decade and net-zero global greenhouse gas emissions not later than 2050;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0CE4693E9003485EB8AD36020BEDEC1B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>materially increase energy prices or energy price volatility for any segment of United States consumers; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8CBAAFAA1EA94AE996D17ACF828F6261"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">create a disproportionate cumulative burden of adverse human or environmental impacts on rural, low-income, minority, and other vulnerable communities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA6BE05A291574DC28F3CA3EEE4AE68CB"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Assessments</header><subparagraph id="HDD62A294B53847CD84395B5E3AD6D985" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Climate change assessment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A determination under paragraph (3)(A) shall be based on an assessment of the expected impact of the proposed exportation of natural gas on climate change. Such assessment shall be based on the latest scientific information and use the 20-year global warming potential of methane, and shall include—</text><clause id="HAE98A8C56D0D4DB0B58F4760F15E88D7" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">quantified estimates of the greenhouse gas emissions associated with the full lifecycle of the natural gas proposed for exportation, including emissions associated with the extraction, transportation, liquefaction, storage, regasification, and consumption of such natural gas;</text></clause><clause id="H6A21CF17015E4C6DAFBE687E226B08F9" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a comparison of the estimated greenhouse gas emissions in clause (i) to a baseline that is consistent with United States international commitments to achieve deep reductions of global greenhouse gas emissions within the next decade and deep decarbonization pathways toward net-zero global greenhouse gas emissions not later than 2050;</text></clause><clause id="HD95BA795B19545ADA3DE1A7154979E89" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an assessment of the potential effects of the proposed exportation of natural gas on clean energy alternatives, including—</text><subclause id="HC1643AB811D948B2AE7861B59B641518" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any decrease in global investment in and deployment of renewable energy, electrification, and energy efficiency and conservation technologies; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HB3F3687CB79C4E1C9B116D92527C1395" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any decrease in United States exports of clean energy technologies;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HA03877E4AD784EB39483029F0A335C7F" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">quantified estimates of the social cost of the estimated greenhouse gas emissions in clause (i); and</text></clause><clause id="H7BCA346D70844FCDBF6076E758D89AB2"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an identification of the extent to which climate change is accelerating the loss of economic value in the United States due to rising sea levels, more intense storms, eroding coasts, increased risk and severity of wild fires, and other impacts associated with climate change.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H43000AD3212B4E40B4A9044056B34AEB" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Economic assessment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A determination under paragraph (3)(B) shall be based on an assessment of the expected economic impact of the proposed exportation of natural gas, including an assessment of the impact of the proposed exportation on all United States consumers, with specific estimates regarding each of the following consumer subgroups:</text><clause id="HD2A1E4A06E65474297F934134E6C7BC1" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Low-income consumers.</text></clause><clause id="H8836ED7E24A7450C9CB0EA53E9B858D3" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Working families.</text></clause><clause id="H275D2ACDCA674C049E10E08FEFBBE958" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Small businesses.</text></clause><clause id="H8BC87CBA06604EF7B581686B5557057B" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Manufacturers.</text></clause><clause id="H24B476C52CF84A909D7D2653F1521647" commented="no"><enum>(v)</enum><text>State and local governments.</text></clause><clause id="HE57F4867A00A4FCEA32ACE7FD2611417" commented="no"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Producers and users of fertilizer.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2E5C1C010167448EB8E6699AB9CD1818" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Environmental justice assessment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A determination under paragraph (3)(C) shall be based on an assessment of the expected impact of the proposed exportation of natural gas on environmental justice (which shall be consistent with Executive Order 14096 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</external-xref> note; relating to revitalizing our Nation's commitment to environmental justice for all), as published April 21, 2023), including assessments of impacts on—</text><clause id="H70600C5F601645E6B6EBB10B66590F60" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the preexisting cumulative environmental burdens and social and health risks posed to rural, low-income, minority, and other vulnerable communities;</text></clause><clause id="H30141A3B66754E4BBC0E42FFD0398BA4" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">local fisheries and the economic livelihood of the people employed by local fisheries; </text></clause><clause id="HE4E8397EDCE0431ABADF68F703A605E2" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">racial and socioeconomic disparities in impacted communities; and</text></clause><clause id="HC00D3BADC84B463FAD5498204C202ABF" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">compliance with civil rights laws.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H27B0F2334A2B44D99E61879DB82D249C" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Public participation</header><text>The Secretary of Energy shall—</text><subparagraph id="H38DCA1686C1F46109A6D60A59780DD4F" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide to the public an opportunity to meaningfully participate, including by providing comments, in—</text><clause id="HB181332A64F944BDB92381AD7533BA69" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the finding of the Secretary of Energy on whether proposed exportation will be consistent with the public interest under paragraph (1); and</text></clause><clause id="H46F31002E64643059BEB958A297533A8" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any study by the Department of Energy intended to inform such finding; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF1EDE230E90148A39D6F8990FBB31A31" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensure that opportunities to meaningfully participate under subparagraph (A) address barriers that affect members of communities with environmental justice concerns, including those related to disability, language access, and lack of resources.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA4580AB8989C4A238D0C6E1F6951B0A4"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Major Federal action</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Issuing an order authorizing the exportation of natural gas under this subsection shall be considered a major Federal action under section 102(2)(C) of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4332">42 U.S.C. 4332(2)(C)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HE5EDFA34B93F4268A3607180E690DF54"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3 of the Natural Gas Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/717b">15 U.S.C. 717b</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H84093BDCC395404A889E8BC37CF6C0AB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text><subparagraph id="H6539EFD0F4774D8EB260065E0E15E5A5"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>export any natural gas from the United States to a foreign country or</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H47D6D67A025740E5A3C52C969402D331"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>to the United States</quote> after <quote>from a foreign country</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6A167C7DB89142BAB723CB6FD8DEE65E" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking <quote>exportation or</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H716FE29ADEE34A71B71E659DD41D30F0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text><subparagraph id="H9B237E12C2F641AAB31D8C44DC86C702"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>, or the exportation of natural gas to a nation with which there is in effect a free trade agreement requiring national treatment for trade in natural gas,</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAFE2981EC65F435E98F15C783B53C19E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>or exportation</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H306AEACD390B4340BDF637551789B288"><enum>3.</enum><header>Process coordination; hearings; rules of procedure</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 15(b)(1) of the Natural Gas Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/717n">15 U.S.C. 717n(b)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>Commission</quote> and inserting <quote>Federal Energy Regulatory Commission</quote>. </text></section><section id="HFBD2E8FDE45C49C68F513EF7150EF814" commented="no"><enum>4.</enum><header>Termination of categorical exclusion for approval or disapproval of the exportation of natural gas</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The categorical exclusion under B5.7 of appendix B to subpart D of part 1021 of title 10, Code of Federal Regulations, (relating to export of natural gas and associated transportation by marine vessel) shall have no force or effect.</text></section><section id="H92F3C04CA78E473E9877B1BF0DB1DF7E" commented="no"><enum>5.</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Energy shall issue a rule to carry out this Act and the amendments made by this Act.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

