<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-KAT25456-P6H-YJ-3FR"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S161 RS: She Develops Regulations In Vehicle Equality and Safety Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><calendar>Calendar No. 141</calendar><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 161</legis-num><associated-doc role="report">[Report No. 119–56]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250121">January 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S357">Mrs. Fischer</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S229">Mrs. Murray</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S252">Ms. Collins</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S422">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S372">Mrs. Capito</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S353">Mr. Schatz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S416">Mrs. Britt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S408">Mr. Hickenlooper</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S402">Ms. Rosen</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S375">Mr. Daines</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00" added-display-style="italic" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><action stage="Reported-in-Senate"><action-date date="20250131">July 31, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Reported by <sponsor name-id="S355">Mr. Cruz</sponsor>, with an amendment</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Secretary of Transportation to issue rules relating to the testing procedures used under the New Car Assessment Program of the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="idD918994FE52245E0858EB14BF0FF04AC" changed="deleted" reported-display-style="strikethrough" committee-id="SSCM00"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>She Develops Regulations In Vehicle Equality and Safety Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>She DRIVES Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id42729aca29624a00aa26f4879971f586" changed="deleted" reported-display-style="strikethrough" committee-id="SSCM00"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1265bee985a84fb5b3463698926f057f"><enum/><text>In this Act:</text><paragraph id="ide5cb9ae74d5b4713aa5e1398f9f73075"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Crashworthiness</header><text>The term <term>crashworthiness</term> has the meaning given the term in section 32301 of title 49, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf0701a6971ea4d39ba3df572d674e6cb"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Transportation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0383bf665ab1413da2898062f9cfdd0c"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Testing device</header><text>The term <term>testing device</term> means a testing device used for compliance testing of motor vehicles and motor vehicle equipment with respect to Federal motor vehicle safety standards that is described in part 572 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations). </text></paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida1e873cfff204e50b056523ef78d6fa8" changed="deleted" reported-display-style="strikethrough" committee-id="SSCM00"><enum>3.</enum><header>Federal Motor Vehicle Safety Standards updates</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2ef8a402e54f497283e9f21df72846b2"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Front impacts</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide66dbeb8e3be478cb17dabc629c5684a"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 15 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall revise parts 571 and 572 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations), to include the following:</text><subparagraph id="ide70fdf2441f24190b24ae4de44d2a33f"><enum>(A)</enum><text>50th percentile adult male Test Device for Human Occupant Restraint (THOR) frontal impact testing device.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id493c936144d04d559d033f9039f7547d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>5th percentile adult female Test Device for Human Occupant Restraint (THOR) front impact testing device.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id21150ec0635f43d682f011e6c56dd171"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Front impact final rules</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id610b23cd1d774427bd4705d45e0633e3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2217c900501f4b43945e655b7321d9e8"><enum>(i)</enum><header>THOR-50M</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall issue a final rule to require the use of the testing device described in paragraph (1)(A) into parts 571 and 572 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbfbc3acec7fd48928d116859ec903168"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>THOR-05F</header><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id55d7000b928442f696588a05442e8f00"><enum>(I)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Proposed rulemaking</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall issue a notice of proposed rulemaking to require the use of the testing device described in paragraph (1)(B) into parts 571 and 572 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1a362f88f0fe447097e7039db5c2667b"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Final rule</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall issue a final rule to require the use of the testing device described in paragraph (1)(B) into parts 571 and 572 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id41e0eb28d9354e16aa99bbdf3801e088"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>In issuing the final rules under clauses (i) and (ii)(II) of subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall—</text><clause id="idebd911dc353e45bf90bcc2a8edea996b"><enum>(i)</enum><text>establish or update the injury criteria, including the head, neck, chest, abdomen, pelvis, upper leg, and lower leg injury criteria, for the testing devices described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (1) based on real world injuries and the greatest potential to increase safety; and</text></clause><clause id="id9951c18dbcb6468ea1e36fef47c9b6a6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>establish crashworthiness frontal impact tests with those testing devices for adult female occupants in all designated front seating positions tested, as of the date of enactment of this Act, for adult male occupants.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0e742f25bf134fe7948de30eb39604f2"><enum>(C)</enum><header>New car assessment program update</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4baf1c5e0bb04b9daf51bf7b1eb8abd1"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall promulgate a final decision notice to update the testing procedures used to test the crashworthiness of passenger motor vehicles under the New Car Assessment Program of the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration to require the use of the testing devices described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (1).</text></clause><clause id="idbf7f35d0c4f947a5b9bc9abbd6336ad1"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Timing</header><subclause id="id2543d388a9ea446d820378bf41897a77"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The final decision notice required under clause (i) shall be promulgated concurrently with the issuance of the final rule required under subparagraph (A)(i) if the Secretary determines that promulgating the final decision notice concurrently with the final rule required under that subparagraph does not delay issuance of that final rule.</text></subclause><subclause id="id79ef64464eda468db071dcd383083af7"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Delay</header><text>If the Secretary determines under subclause (I) that promulgating the final decision notice concurrently with the final rule required under subparagraph (A)(i) would delay the issuance of that final rule, the Secretary shall issue that final rule before promulgating the final decision notice required under this subparagraph.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id96a91de2ea3749319fa27a59ab013fce"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Side impacts</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfd6d8cff23ce41fcbbbd8d3c347c8f25"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall revise parts 571 and 572 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations), to include the following:</text><subparagraph id="id0d2050dd224e4857aa495a9e7a65d63c"><enum>(A)</enum><text>50th percentile adult male Worldwide Harmonized Side Impact Dummy side impact testing device.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd4d052208c964beb88c99a492bae933d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>5th percentile adult female Worldwide Harmonized Side Impact Dummy side impact testing device.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5126a2a0c018431da5d5582964bb55f6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Side impact final rule</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id60a5bd8fa8d44add8b798a88376ddadf"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb3916d02e8374e40a15c2043f29f2630"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Proposed rulemaking</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall issue a notice of proposed rulemaking to require the use of the testing devices described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (1) into parts 571 and 572 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).</text></clause><clause id="idccee6d27e8b34d8aaf18fa2084f8d037"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Final rule</header><text>Not later than 30 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall issue a final rule to require the use of the testing devices described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (1) into parts 571 and 572 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id95ceb103c3b94f93a7acc5d2417a2399"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>In issuing the final rule under subparagraph (A)(ii), the Secretary shall—</text><clause id="id0826efd28bb0481da2682f022190aef1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>establish or update the injury criteria, including the head, neck, chest, abdomen, pelvis, and upper leg criteria, for the testing devices described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (1) based on real world injuries and the greatest potential to increase safety; and</text></clause><clause id="idf8eede385b6440bb9d09c8c25fb4079d"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>establish front seat crashworthiness side impact tests with those testing devices for adult female occupants in all designated front seating positions tested, as of the date of enactment of this Act, for adult male occupants.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7036707b500e4effb6c156b5165f544a"><enum>(C)</enum><header>New car assessment program update</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id96b3d08d2ad74984828d45736683b26a"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall promulgate a final decision notice to update the testing procedures used to test the crashworthiness of passenger motor vehicles under the New Car Assessment Program of the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration to require the use of the testing devices described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (1).</text></clause><clause id="id198158b2d80544b08e6e9d3266b7e19e"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Timing</header><subclause id="id248ee8d5f81d4161a4dfd3113a65ef11"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The final decision notice required under clause (i) shall be promulgated concurrently with the issuance of the final rule required under subparagraph (A)(ii) if the Secretary determines that promulgating the final decision notice concurrently with the final rule required under that subparagraph does not delay issuance of that final rule.</text></subclause><subclause id="idc6bb2b9dba194bfbb7308cb8a336cbd8"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Delay</header><text>If the Secretary determines under subclause (I) that promulgating the final decision notice concurrently with the final rule required under subparagraph (A)(ii) would delay the issuance of that final rule, the Secretary shall issue that final rule before promulgating the final decision notice required under this subparagraph.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb36da29e06934fbb996479f973b10158" changed="deleted" reported-display-style="strikethrough" committee-id="SSCM00"><enum>4.</enum><header>Testing devices roadmap</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf4ec42752b4d4d1f81b928f2a713d515"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Initial report</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf0e608ede9e44a13ada7a52835e7bd2c"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives a report that—</text><subparagraph id="id9b3dac2871414193927d779ac1cbe3c3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identifies timelines for the Secretary to incorporate testing devices, other than the testing devices described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of section 3(a)(1) and subparagraphs (A) and (B) of section 3(b)(1), that the Secretary is researching, as of the date of enactment of this Act, into the regulations contained in parts 571 and 572 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idde31533d88bf4ef5b5dd14de897d8517"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identifies testing devices used for similar crashworthiness standards in other countries that are more advanced than the testing devices required or being researched by the Secretary; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7655ec69c88647d283c615a0fa282a7e"><enum>(C)</enum><text>subject to paragraph (2), describes a process for the Secretary to update the testing devices required in the United States under regulations in effect on the date of enactment of this Act, including whether the Secretary can adopt more advanced testing devices already used for compliance in other countries, such as testing devices in use or being considered as part of the European New Car Assessment Programme.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id03234be1d28e4f94ae463950eff5c24c"><enum>(2)</enum><header>No update needed</header><text>If the Secretary determines that testing devices used in the United States as of the date of enactment of this Act do not need to be updated, the Secretary shall include in the report required under paragraph (1) a description for why the Secretary believes those testing devices do not need to be updated, including by providing a description for each testing device described in part 572 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations), that the Secretary determines does not need to be updated.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8f8c133832a1400cb7b58cd7e096449e"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Follow-Up report</header><text>Not later than 5 years after the date on which the Secretary submits the report required under subsection (a), the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives a report that—</text><paragraph id="idd5a2fbc5d7a34519b0cfb9a0f78ae7bf"><enum>(1)</enum><text>describes whether the Secretary has met the timelines described in subsection (a)(1)(A); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6f2cadb7451948ccbdfb4b1e46c1c087"><enum>(2)</enum><text>identifies any new testing devices used in other countries that are more advanced than the testing devices required or being research by the Secretary as of the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body><legis-body display-enacting-clause="no-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="id269e89d6-2a45-4da1-b99d-725ac484332d" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="SSCM00"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>She Develops Regulations In Vehicle Equality and Safety Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>She DRIVES Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id247365cc-de1f-4b1f-9702-689a5d9e80ba" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="SSCM00"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcc8beb3b-bf56-4e89-92c9-9962a52b5f5c"><enum/><text>In this Act:</text><paragraph id="id27637948-2595-4365-81f2-cc7e367338f8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Crashworthiness</header><text>The term <term>crashworthiness</term> has the meaning given the term in section 32301 of title 49, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id044cdf36-4d89-4006-9455-92262995de49"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Transportation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idEF8B291855B045B9A3D289BF6C0FFB6B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Testing device</header><text>The term <term>testing device</term> means a testing device used for compliance testing of motor vehicles and motor vehicle equipment with respect to Federal motor vehicle safety standards that is described in part 572 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations). </text></paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id29ec4c56-9154-463b-bcd3-9d4bc71bac1c" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="SSCM00"><enum>3.</enum><header>Federal Motor Vehicle Safety Standards updates</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf7457f6d-7dea-4e6b-84ce-51a34bb40ff3"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Front impacts</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7823c28f-8501-4a2a-b45f-405abd0c21cd"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 15 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall revise parts 571 and 572 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations), to include the following:</text><subparagraph id="id24082d57-3218-4190-9419-ffc90ea03a5d"><enum>(A)</enum><text>50th percentile adult male Test Device for Human Occupant Restraint (THOR) frontal impact testing device.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id00508f95-eb7d-4881-b2cc-60e8b9376004"><enum>(B)</enum><text>5th percentile adult female Test Device for Human Occupant Restraint (THOR) frontal impact testing device.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id42923066-7ef7-4b83-a4f0-c5462e2f430f"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Front impact final rules</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8e732c05-12bb-4888-bac7-15d915f1c9bf"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id009eb491-a2c8-4561-b91b-f4d19623aa04"><enum>(i)</enum><header>THOR-50M</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall issue a final rule to require the use of the testing device described in paragraph (1)(A) into parts 571 and 572 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ideb469e53-a24e-42b1-a978-43a89f2d8bc3"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>THOR-05F</header><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6de0d176-f6a6-4317-94eb-64c76faf7efe"><enum>(I)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Proposed rulemaking</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall issue a notice of proposed rulemaking to require the use of the testing device described in paragraph (1)(B) into parts 571 and 572 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf3383558-47b3-4d68-9f0a-47253eba3dbb"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Final rule</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall issue a final rule to require the use of the testing device described in paragraph (1)(B) into parts 571 and 572 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id519ce46d-fe61-439e-918c-3fb4f9e4e4ca"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>In issuing the final rules under clauses (i) and (ii)(II) of subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall—</text><clause id="idfc252770-015f-4df7-8b64-6138d16e9688"><enum>(i)</enum><text>establish or update the injury criteria, including the head, neck, chest, abdomen, pelvis, upper leg, and lower leg injury criteria, for the testing devices described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (1) based on real world injuries and the greatest potential to increase safety; and</text></clause><clause id="ida7ec53c5-c8d9-41da-848a-c6c0da1c21e4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>establish crashworthiness frontal impact tests with those testing devices for adult female occupants in all designated front seating positions tested, as of the date of enactment of this Act, for adult male occupants.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id99b6145f-d27c-4186-8ad9-796b038a9c72"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Side impacts</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1ccb773d-7562-48cb-873d-8fc5c4478670"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall revise parts 571 and 572 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations), to include the following:</text><subparagraph id="id18e09282-d629-46a4-87b1-806c844a4888"><enum>(A)</enum><text>50th percentile adult male Worldwide Harmonized Side Impact Dummy side impact testing device.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id32c13437-e9d5-4d57-93be-2a3d2611431d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>5th percentile adult female Worldwide Harmonized Side Impact Dummy side impact testing device.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id82796ae9-df76-4b60-a779-fa727ad5d754"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Side impact final rule</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf5047696-d58d-4028-94e6-43ea046ee634"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5a771d18-b0fa-47d1-9a23-1c9cba359345"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Proposed rulemaking</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall issue a notice of proposed rulemaking to require the use of the testing devices described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (1) into parts 571 and 572 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).</text></clause><clause id="id7e7d708a-f167-41b3-bfcc-1d7dc61e2b2f"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Final rule</header><text>Not later than 30 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall issue a final rule to require the use of the testing devices described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (1) into parts 571 and 572 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id51ec7719-26c0-472b-8330-3c248833d344"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>In issuing the final rule under subparagraph (A)(ii), the Secretary shall—</text><clause id="id2a1c52a2-e80f-46e2-bb75-a2fa72160fc1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>establish or update the injury criteria, including the head, neck, chest, abdomen, pelvis, and upper leg criteria, for the testing devices described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (1) based on real world injuries and the greatest potential to increase safety; and</text></clause><clause id="idd557ddfe-fbc0-4ac6-9454-6bd3bc0049f7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>establish front seat crashworthiness side impact tests with those testing devices for adult female occupants in all designated front seating positions tested, as of the date of enactment of this Act, for adult male occupants.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id1d9ff14dce014327b55043b08102f98d" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="SSCM00"><enum>4.</enum><header>New car assessment program update</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3515894b15ac4f3e8bfaeae9ccc8f3bb"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Front impacts</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idac756869-344c-46a5-b032-b641e416983b"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall promulgate a final decision notice to update the testing procedures used to test the crashworthiness of passenger motor vehicles under the New Car Assessment Program of the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration to require the use of the testing devices described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of section 3(a)(1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf4a7cbf9-2e7e-4924-8299-8284d3e4a4e7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Timing</header><subparagraph id="id98a6554e-11a6-46de-8330-79e2c32b3e0c"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The final decision notice required under paragraph (1) shall be promulgated concurrently with the issuance of the final rule required under section 3(a)(2)(A)(i) if the Secretary determines that promulgating the final decision notice concurrently with the final rule required under that section does not delay issuance of that final rule.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddf52eaef-02f7-46b6-a3ab-be81bde955f2" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Delay</header><text>If the Secretary determines under subparagraph (A) that promulgating the final decision notice concurrently with the final rule required under section 3(a)(2)(A)(i) would delay the issuance of that final rule, the Secretary shall issue that final rule before promulgating the final decision notice required under this subsection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id85d90f9a31e6432c9c06911f7eb7aee4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Side impacts</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id89fc10841f4b40cebf4bb28814d050b3"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>The Secretary shall promulgate a final decision notice to update the testing procedures used to test the crashworthiness of passenger motor vehicles under the New Car Assessment Program of the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration to require the use of the testing devices described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of section 3(b)(1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7AFDCB292195403DBFD02109AD58EAC5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Timing</header><subparagraph id="idA71F314FFD384ADB885C993504E23484"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The final decision notice required under paragraph (1) shall be promulgated concurrently with the issuance of the final rule required under section 3(b)(2)(A)(ii) if the Secretary determines that promulgating the final decision notice concurrently with the final rule required under that section does not delay issuance of that final rule.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB461CC2E9D854427AA8A8BB09AF89313" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Delay</header><text>If the Secretary determines under subparagraph (A) that promulgating the final decision notice concurrently with the final rule required under section 3(b)(2)(A)(ii) would delay the issuance of that final rule, the Secretary shall issue that final rule before promulgating the final decision notice required under this subsection. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id30528328-7f3c-4031-b954-3c07abcbb6e1" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="SSCM00"><enum>5.</enum><header>Testing devices roadmap</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7ae2d142-5609-49ca-b229-27d8528c4099"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Initial report</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id294b2305-af6b-4a5f-b1ff-1c2fca950143"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives a report that—</text><subparagraph id="id0c280208-b762-4adc-afc2-880c1d39a6c0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identifies timelines for the Secretary to incorporate testing devices, other than the testing devices described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of section 3(a)(1) and subparagraphs (A) and (B) of section 3(b)(1), that the Secretary is researching, as of the date of enactment of this Act, into the regulations contained in parts 571 and 572 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7de04488-b10d-45a3-ac83-056f3039fb7a"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identifies testing devices used for similar crashworthiness standards in other countries that are more advanced than the testing devices required or being researched by the Secretary; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0ac5eca9-57f4-4059-a594-06de491dabad"><enum>(C)</enum><text>subject to paragraph (2), describes a process for the Secretary to update the testing devices required in the United States under regulations in effect on the date of enactment of this Act, including whether the Secretary can adopt more advanced testing devices already used for compliance in other countries, such as testing devices in use or being considered as part of the European New Car Assessment Programme.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idf94723e4-ac95-4fb3-a782-2848bd5d68dd"><enum>(2)</enum><header>No update needed</header><text>If the Secretary determines that testing devices used in the United States as of the date of enactment of this Act do not need to be updated, the Secretary shall include in the report required under paragraph (1) a description for why the Secretary believes those testing devices do not need to be updated, including by providing a description for each testing device described in part 572 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations), that the Secretary determines does not need to be updated.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6a88789e-7396-4631-9fb0-6c8d6ed2877f"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Follow-up report</header><text>Not later than 5 years after the date on which the Secretary submits the report required under subsection (a), the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives a report that—</text><paragraph id="id85d2c91e-1e63-4d98-b499-7a3792e32628"><enum>(1)</enum><text>describes whether the Secretary has met the timelines described in subsection (a)(1)(A); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id928b9734-d7d1-4309-87f8-afa4d968d9a2" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><text>identifies any new testing devices used in other countries that are more advanced than the testing devices required or being research by the Secretary as of the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6ccf51efc0d34aea8485810239171c0a" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="SSCM00"><enum>6.</enum><header>Savings provision</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9609db6bd5fd4766bfb625b98eedb723"><enum/><text>Nothing in this Act restricts the ability of the Secretary to update a testing device through proceedings separate from, or subsequent to—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2605f611279843a6bccc86778f0e6fd3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the final rules required under clauses (i) and (ii)(II) of section 3(a)(2)(A) and section 3(b)(2)(A)(ii); and </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id03d83e08c5f24fbdb141b63473cd89eb"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the final decision notices required under subsections (a)(1) and (b)(1) of section 4.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body><endorsement><action-date date="20250131">July 31, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

