<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MDM25I81-2LC-6R-LGH" star-print="first-star-print" key="G">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2844 IS: Charlie Kirk Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
<congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>S. 2844</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
<action>
<action-date date="20250917" legis-day="20250916">September 17 (legislative day, September 16), 2025</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S411">Mr. Marshall</sponsor> (for <cosponsor name-id="S346">Mr. Lee</cosponsor>) (by request) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title>To clarify United States policy with respect to limitations on the domestic dissemination of program material about the United States that was prepared or disseminated by the United States Agency for Global Media or its component networks.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H84E8DE5B645C4EB7A55D45DFDDEB30B4">
<section id="id398bbdbee66a4dfaa0fc27f4712a0e26" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Charlie Kirk Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="id092079ffabef4d9bac03f20389225543"><enum>2.</enum><header>Dissemination abroad of information about the United States</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id642aa5fa807e42fea6a45d106ef7936d"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">United States Information and Educational Exchange Act of 1948</header><text>Section 501 of the United States Information and Educational Exchange Act of 1948 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/1461">22 U.S.C. 1461</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ideb5676a24c1d4cfd9cab0dda63ddef68">
<section id="id0fc18bb4e5964a438e3b13189fdd16b1"><enum>501.</enum><header>General authorization</header>
<subsection id="ideb6123ad81524ea58349442f14956368"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Dissemination of information abroad</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Chief Executive Officer of the United States Agency for Global Media (referred to in this section as the <quote>USAGM CEO</quote>), working through its component networks, is authorized to provide for the preparation, and dissemination abroad, of information about the United States, its people, and its policies, through press, publications, radio, motion pictures, the internet, and other information media, and through information centers, instructors abroad, and other direct or indirect means of communication. Except as provided in subsection (b), any such information (other than <quote>Problems of Communism</quote> and the <quote>English Teaching Forum</quote>, which may be sold by the Government Publishing Office) may not be disseminated within the United States, its territories, or possessions. However, such information may be made available in the English language at the Department of State, at all reasonable times following its release as information abroad, for examination only by representatives of United States press associations, newspapers, magazines, radio systems, and stations, and by research students and scholars, and on request, shall be made available for examination by Members of Congress.</text></subsection> <subsection id="id56123f34a8554885a0095869b1d16585"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Dissemination of information within the United States</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id20144897a860463a9f5666faa7b83eb9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The USAGM CEO shall make available to the Archivist of the United States (referred to in this subsection as the <quote>Archivist</quote>), for domestic distribution, motion pictures, films, video, audio, and other materials prepared for dissemination abroad beginning 12 years after the date on which—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7e2b3b0ef2794e2ea4cce0fed99a869a"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such material was initially disseminated abroad; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id080583e8df224b02ac29e1ed1dc4dadb"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the material was prepared, if such material was never disseminated abroad.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide3a75fbdadf843d89d72417e2b33f1e4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reimbursement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The USAGM CEO shall be reimbursed for any expenses resulting from the implementation of paragraph (1). Such reimbursement shall be credited to the applicable appropriation of the United States Agency for Global Media.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf40ff1ab3198423ea22f84a77e2d5e46"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Responsibilities of the archivist</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Archivist—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idece3b1a217d94a738607edaf1dfed6f9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall be the official custodian of the material described in paragraph (1);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0790fbda5327478cb61406b8b9bea004"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall promulgate regulations to ensure that persons seeking the release of such material—</text>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id478275c641db4aad97a51161396441c9"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have secured necessary United States rights and licenses; and</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id230d2c2ca18e44979ceb63b8905f77cd"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>have paid a fee, in accordance with section 2116(c) of title 44, United States Code, which is sufficient to cover the costs incurred by the Archivist to provide such material to such persons; and</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcfe88fdf6527407fb29d49706ee82ea6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>all fees collected pursuant to subparagraph (B)(ii) are paid into, administered, and expended as part of the National Archives Trust Fund.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="idfa2cd50547d4414d96f310d1f58a4a68"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to require the USAGM CEO to make material disseminated abroad available in any format other than in the format disseminated abroad.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection>
<subsection id="ida1355e2010934c268fdb497ccafe17e1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Foreign Relations Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 1986 and 1987</header>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4e224b776fd947f7a18b74fcfe7291b0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 208 of the Foreign Relations Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 1986 and 1987 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/1461-1a">22 U.S.C. 1461–1a</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4dea76dd9372468db926c7d8f107175c"> <section id="id02b09d6d954c453492cf229bd4b0b93a"><enum>208.</enum><header>Ban on domestic activities of the United States Agency for Global Media</header> <subsection id="idc3cb5660ce254084bbef61ac93eca6ac"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subsections (b) and (c) and in section 501 of the United States Information and Educational Exchange Act of 1948 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/1461">22 U.S.C. 1461</external-xref>)—</text>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5f84a661421b4025ae7ee753491f3040"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">amounts appropriated to the United States Agency for Global Media or its component networks (referred to collectively in this section as <quote>USAGM</quote>) may not be used to influence public opinion in the United States; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb77316da9a1148eeb2bb37c5cc3ce6e6"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">no program material prepared by USAGM may be distributed within the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide52a961093704734a5e412fa38259c48"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exemption</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The limitation under subsection (a) shall not apply to programs carried out pursuant to the Mutual Educational and Cultural Exchange Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2451">22 U.S.C. 2451 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0d740650be164cb581a923579ca4c829"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Savings provision</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section may be construed to prohibit any employee of the United States Agency for Global Media from responding to inquiries from members of the public about USAGM operations, policies, or programs.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddfc6de24c810433d95b70b68752891f2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents for the Foreign Relations Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 1986 and 1987 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/1461-1a">22 U.S.C. 1461–1a</external-xref>) is amended by striking the item relating to section 208 and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="id9cb0141a-be08-4730-b391-4a4f0681ffe4"> <toc> <toc-entry level="section" idref="id02b09d6d954c453492cf229bd4b0b93a">Sec. 208. Ban on domestic activities of the United States Agency for Global Media.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

