<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H73D96F79E30C49C58124232741ECDEF0" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1087 IH: United States Colored Troops Congressional Gold Medal Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1087</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250206">February 6, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="A000380">Mr. Amo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001081">Mrs. Hayes</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">House Administration</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To posthumously award a Congressional Gold Medal, collectively, to the African Americans who served with Union forces during the Civil War, in recognition of their bravery and outstanding service.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD16924C58CD74F76A2802673C7EE398C" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="H9A55D44DAB364D5391B1F57A379D76EB"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>United States Colored Troops Congressional Gold Medal Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HBEAE8B8EBD1E42459B4F03A69C1A6D7C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H1EA03A110AED4E4B956F6AFDC97B3B70"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Since the colonial era, African Americans have served the United States in times of war.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDAEF86BD8CBB4B2F8D047E82264DD9E9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>During the Civil War, approximately 200,000 African-American men served in the Union Army and 19,000 African-American men served in the Union Navy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2CF958CE4604471A853374F67F3EF056"><enum>(3)</enum><text>During the Civil War, African-American women were not allowed to formally enlist as soldiers or sailors, though they served as nurses, cooks, spies, and scouts for the Union Army and the Union Navy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H661AC26A0AE24389973A33D5B93944C3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>While African-American men served in the Navy since its establishment, there was resistance to enlisting them to take up arms for the Union Army at the start of the Civil War.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H28F2A627C4DF47C0ADC6FDA983CAFACC"><enum>(5)</enum><text>As the Civil War dragged on, President Lincoln broke from the previous policy of his administration and determined that liberating enslaved persons <quote>was a military necessity absolutely essential for the salvation of the Union</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H679AAD627579437DB6B8291507DEF782"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The Act entitled <quote>An Act to suppress insurrection, to punish treason and rebellion, to seize and confiscate the property of rebels, and for other purposes</quote>, approved July 17, 1862 (commonly known as the <quote>Second Confiscation Act</quote>) (12 Stat. 589; chapter 195), and the Act of July 17, 1862 (commonly known as the <quote>Military Act of 1862</quote>) (12 Stat. 597; chapter 201), were the first official authorizations to employ African Americans in the Union Army.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD807849E05C14835AAACF3BC5FF4E1ED"><enum>(7)</enum><text>It was not until January 1, 1863, the effective date of the Emancipation Proclamation issued by President Lincoln, that the Union Army was ordered to receive African-American men.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB9F6CD7CEED14DF1B08E4F41FCD6EE6F"><enum>(8)</enum><text>On May 22, 1863, the United States War Department issued General Order Number 143, which established the Bureau of Colored Troops for the recruitment and organization of regiments of the Union Army composed of African-American men, called the United States Colored Troops (referred to in this section as <quote>USCT</quote>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA7CA31DC016845BA8CE3AC3C19DA7456"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Leaders such as Frederick Douglass encouraged African Americans to enlist to advance the cause of citizenship. <quote>Once let the black man get upon his person the brass letters, <quote>U.S.</quote>, let him get an eagle on his button, and a musket on his shoulder and bullets in his pocket, there is no power on [E]arth that can deny that he has earned the right to citizenship.</quote>, wrote Douglass.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H79BD0134A9364B1AA7EB16E0FB8EBC2D"><enum>(10)</enum><text>African-American sailors constituted a significant segment of the Union Navy, making up 20 percent of the total enlisted force of the Navy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H41E54ACA77C0426DB2B5EBB33A18673E"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Although there were rank restrictions on African Americans in the Navy before the Civil War, this policy changed after the establishment of the USCT, when the Union Navy started to compete with the Union Army for enlistment of African Americans.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3AF08D25C36E4DA883BB4E9251C645F6"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Yet, in practice, most African Americans could not advance beyond lowest ranks of <quote>boy</quote> and <quote>landsman.</quote></text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB7CB717985884763BF3594D2FF1B2726"><enum>(13)</enum><text>African-American soldiers and sailors served with distinction, honor, and bravery amid racial discrimination and adverse circumstances, including the risk of enslavement and torture if captured.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8E1F4C8075A543B3AD8F12C30BBCCD72"><enum>(14)</enum><text>Eighteen members of the USCT and 8 African-American sailors were awarded the Medal of Honor, the highest honor in the United States for bravery in combat.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H818A5B5B004246F58A380C3E8BE759AD"><enum>(15)</enum><text>For generations after the Civil War, the contributions of African Americans in the Civil War were excluded from historical memory.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HADF164ED7E8242DB9B64D5F1595356DD"><enum>(16)</enum><text>Public Law No. 102–412 (106 Stat. 2104) authorized the establishment of a memorial on Federal land in the District of Columbia to honor African Americans who served with Union forces during the Civil War. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC784026160304920BDF0BF61269C2282"><enum>(17)</enum><text>This memorial, featuring a bronze statue of USCT soldiers, an African-American sailor and family, is surrounded by the Wall of Honor, which lists the names of the members of the USCT.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1DE707A9D434471BB66ABAFF10FC9916"><enum>(18)</enum><text>The African American Civil War Museum is located in the District of Columbia.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H55981962945140D79B656E4D77AB7296"><enum>(19)</enum><text>Patriots and heroes who rose in service to a Nation that would not fully recognize them, the African Americans who served the Union during the Civil War deserve our recognition for their contributions to the grant of emancipation and citizenship for nearly 4,000,000 enslaved people and the preservation of the Union. </text></paragraph></section><section id="H665C8499AFA148CC80177D13E684044B"><enum>3.</enum><header>Congressional Gold Medal</header><subsection id="H06BD007FCF614AE4BC741F2A0114C3A6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Presentation authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President pro tempore of the Senate shall make appropriate arrangements for the posthumous presentation, on behalf of Congress, of a gold medal of appropriate design to the African Americans who served with Union forces during the Civil War, collectively, in recognition of their bravery and outstanding service during the Civil War.</text></subsection><subsection id="H9C363A66B46C4533910DAE251F897508"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Design and striking</header><text>For the purposes of the award referred to in subsection (a), the Secretary of the Treasury (hereafter in this Act referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall strike a gold medal with suitable emblems, devices, and inscriptions, to be determined by the Secretary.</text></subsection><subsection id="H660C843781524978B5DD06EF7CCF28F1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Smithsonian Institution</header><paragraph id="HAAC6F1A339C642379721B823B6C37966"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Following the award of the gold medal under subsection (a), the gold medal shall be given to the Smithsonian Institution, where the medal shall be available for display as appropriate and available for research.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC74D14B77F6E49498767C9ABD267850E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sense of the Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that the Smithsonian Institution should make the gold medal received under paragraph (1) available for display elsewhere, particularly at appropriate locations associated with the United States Colored Troops.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H6AFDFCBCC2F24114B5DB3A9F2D87E7A7"><enum>4.</enum><header>Duplicate medals</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary may strike and sell duplicates in bronze of the gold medal struck pursuant to section 3 at a price sufficient to cover the cost thereof, including labor, materials, dies, use of machinery, and overhead expenses.</text></section><section id="H8D4A77CE4BC84B44A13D97B99F52F248"><enum>5.</enum><header>Status of medals</header><subsection id="H0A2C6CD585544AD2AEEA8A05EC1EB249"><enum>(a)</enum><header>National medals</header><text>The medals struck pursuant to this Act are national medals for purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/51">chapter 51</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1CCC645878994C6A9BE635E3028EB15B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Numismatic items</header><text>For purposes of section 5134 of title 31, United States Code, all medals struck under this Act shall be considered to be numismatic items.</text></subsection></section><section id="H36489A49169540088C2595E48245C63B"><enum>6.</enum><header>Authority to use fund amounts; proceeds of sale</header><subsection id="H9A723DBE7F0B4EA2A954D1536D19F9A8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority To use fund amounts</header><text>There is authorized to be charged against the United States Mint Public Enterprise Fund such amounts as may be necessary to pay for the cost of the medals struck under this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1815F39E205B463FA31F1969712ECDC2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Proceeds of sale</header><text>Amounts received from the sale of duplicate bronze medals under section 4 shall be deposited in the United States Mint Public Enterprise Fund. </text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

