<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H87CD6EE1E0A3419AB633120844A1CAB6" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1388 IH: Fair-Value Accounting and Budget Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1388</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250214">February 14, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000190">Mr. Norman</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000576">Mr. Grothman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001224">Mr. Self</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBU00">Committee on the Budget</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Rules</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974 to provide for fair-value credit estimates, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H839A41619E3B41719062BB755D4C35A4" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H3970422CCD2D486BB729DE41FC5CCD1D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Fair-Value Accounting and Budget Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section> <section id="HCDF4A5FF796348249A2E0EF677C77348"><enum>2.</enum><header>Fair-value credit estimates</header> <subsection id="HC4F00BF4CF224C83AD9ACE7193AC2478"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Fair-Value estimates</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Part A of title IV of the Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974 is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="appropriations" id="H67C5065A7D07477EAC40E15834CB7636" display-inline="no-display-inline">
<section id="H5CFDD887E38640F4B325AA4FB294017E"><enum>407.</enum><header>Fair-value credit estimates</header>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H6A331B1A3CFA4FE78427143F9A8938AF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Fair-Value estimates</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any estimate prepared by the Director of the Congressional Budget Office for a measure that establishes or modifies any program providing loans or loan guarantees shall provide a fair-value estimate of such loan or loan guarantee program.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H0E68D1B29FAD4950B4A241E76D8765CC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Baseline estimates</header><text>The Congressional Budget Office shall include estimates of loan and loan guarantee programs, on a fair-value and credit reform basis, as practicable, in the Office’s publication entitled <quote>The Budget and Economic Outlook</quote> (or any successor report).</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H86D90CD026014179903C98F2464D21C4" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text>If the Director of the Congressional Budget Office provides an estimate pursuant to subsection (a), the chair of the Committee on the Budget of the House of Representatives or the Senate shall use such estimate to determine compliance with this Act and other budget enforcement requirements.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H5715C7B3FA704668819A51455C583A4B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In 2026 and each year thereafter, not later than 90 days after the date the President submits to Congress a budget under section 1105(a) of title 31, United States Code, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall submit a report, to the Committees on the Budget of the House of Representatives and the Senate, on fair-value estimates of the cost of Federal credit programs.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HEF6F682B0BE7402181FA940987C75D2C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definition of fair-Value</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out this section, the Director of the Congressional Budget Office and the Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall use the definition of <quote>fair-value</quote> as set forth in the publication of the Government Accounting Standards Board, issued in February 2015, entitled <quote>Fair Value Measurement and Application</quote>.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HBFFD9570DF9E419BA683606B0D9A6848"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents for the Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974 Act set forth in section 1(b) of such Act is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 406 the following new item: </text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HD6C623E7EC7B4E0EB83C23E0727D89AC" display-inline="no-display-inline">
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 407. Fair-value credit estimates.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

