<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H997BC5FD285F4DDE99CBEBA18C00B66E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2524 IH: Replacing Exploitative Partisan Estimates with Alternatives by Liquidating Congressional Budget Office Requirements</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2524</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250331">March 31, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000478">Ms. Tenney</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="C001129">Mr. Collins</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Committee on Rules</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HBU00">the Budget</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974 to provide that Congress may request estimates of legislation from reputable accounting firms for purposes of budget enforcement, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H630A1A882DD54864AFB610347B473B7F" style="OLC"><section id="H46DE7BFC755B48D181602F6E18D84E90" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Replacing Exploitative Partisan Estimates with Alternatives by Liquidating Congressional Budget Office Requirements</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>REPEAL CBO Requirements Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H8975C2F47C3F43EEA58F6211AE47AF62"><enum>2.</enum><header>Budget estimates by reputable accounting firms</header><subsection id="HDB44674890DF44A98D187B7D72315B56"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 402 of the Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1985 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/653">2 U.S.C. 653</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H6E9EEB49012E472782D8D6F482F95321"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>The Director</quote> and inserting <quote>(a) <header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">In general</header-in-text>.—The Director</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD577BA9ACC5C4C74BFD78C21D283D12E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H2A580FC6F00143C485DDEBB2D951CD96" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="HDC83BA53C47E4D6AA7F6D19833215497"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Estimate by accounting firms</header><subparagraph id="H7B83F65444D843A890271EC90FD00F68"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the chair of any committee of the House of Representatives or the Senate (except the Committee on Appropriations of each House) may, instead of an estimate under subsection (a), obtain an estimate for any bill or resolution of a public character reported by such committee from a private reputable accounting firm.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H87AA4623C5AC490CA42605A877C525AF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Application</header><clause id="HE36C2D53BEE14BB685C973FD6C7E18F8"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any estimate obtained under subparagraph (A) shall be used in lieu of an estimate prepared by the Congressional Budget Office under subsection (a) for budget enforcement with respect to the applicable bill or joint resolution, including for purposes of this Act, the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985, the Statutory Pay-As-You-Go Act of 2010, any concurrent resolution on the budget, the Rules of the House of Representatives, and the Standing Rules of the Senate (including for purposes of reconciliation).</text></clause><clause id="H7DAF0DD118F742949373CFE667E3C40D"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>CBO estimate not required</header><text>If an estimate is obtained under subparagraph (A), then the Office shall not prepare an estimate for the applicable measure under subsection (a). </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB2EED74701414BA8937620F581F69D09"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Definition of private reputable accounting firm</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, the term <quote>private reputable accounting firm</quote> means any of the ten public accounting firms registered with the Public Company Accounting Oversight Board with the largest net revenue during the previous year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H04C6E68FEDD24F86AC2C9DF3AC227B61"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 312(a) of such Act is amended by adding at the end the following: <quote>The estimates by a private reputable accounting firm under section 402(b) may be used by either such Committee for purposes of carrying out this subsection.</quote>. </text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

