<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6D269698BEAC443CABA858972DF2D608" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2403 IH: Telling Everyone the Location of data Leaving the U.S. Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2403</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250327">March 27, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="A000372">Mr. Allen</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require that any person that maintains an internet website or that sells or distributes a mobile application that stores and maintains information collected from such website or application in the People&#8217;s Republic of China to disclose that such information is stored and maintained in the People&#8217;s Republic of China and whether the Chinese Communist Party or a Chinese State-owned entity has access to such information.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HAB101EB7AB5440BA9D578AAC693D5A0D" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H16BD1868763649D3983B5A1C4DEB4FCF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Telling Everyone the Location of data Leaving the U.S. Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>TELL Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H6EE8E8044D6245ABB1FFCA33E7B722BE"><enum>2.</enum><header>Country disclosure requirements</header> <subsection id="H41DC3B03FA9A4FF29870A383CB2DAE58"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Disclosure requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any person that maintains an internet website or that sells or distributes a mobile application that stores and maintains information collected from such website or application in the People’s Republic of China shall disclose to any individual who downloads or otherwise uses such website or application, in a clear and conspicuous manner, the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H313DD31423AF47EA8622679425E82068"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That such information is stored and maintained in the People’s Republic of China.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFFF25C99A25846BFB3B50D26FFB27BB1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether the Chinese Communist Party or a Chinese State-owned entity has access to such information.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7F9B45D30C7B4B158E26824845349199"><enum>(b)</enum><header>False information</header><text>It shall be unlawful for a person required to disclose information under subsection (a) to knowingly disclose false information under such subsection.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H3465E18DD2CD4E13BAC4B99CC596553B"><enum>3.</enum><header>Enforcement</header> <subsection id="H58706D0584824438AC9D56DFF1006F1A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Unfair or deceptive acts or practices</header><text>A violation of this Act shall be treated as a violation of a rule defining an unfair or deceptive act or practice prescribed under section 18(a)(1)(B) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/57a">15 U.S.C. 57a(a)(1)(B)</external-xref>).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HEB57FCC33E1444D3B0382D90D5A63B25"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Powers of Federal Trade Commission</header> 
<paragraph id="HF7B6DEE4447C4504A064B1D7151C0C96"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Federal Trade Commission shall enforce this Act in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though all applicable terms and provisions of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>) were incorporated into and made a part of this Act.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H76EA2163F1054C6C99189AB976EE1135"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Privileges and immunities</header><text>Any person that violates this Act shall be subject to the penalties, and entitled to the privileges and immunities, provided in the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

