<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" slc-id="S1-ROM25044-80G-WP-RTS"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 41 ATS: Authorizing the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate to conduct quarterly blood donation drives during the 119th Congress.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 41</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250127">January 27, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S174">Mr. McConnell</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Authorizing the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate to conduct quarterly blood donation drives during the 119th Congress.</official-title></form><resolution-body><section section-type="section-one" id="id413e372584784d79a74a81c872e39b1b"><enum>1.</enum><header>Quarterly Senate blood donation drives</header><subsection id="id80a85ebff23c438ba3a2baa386e82e13"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization</header><paragraph id="id7c2ace8f210646f687c5122f934e8c76"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>During the 119th Congress, the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate (referred to in this resolution as the <term>Sergeant at Arms</term>) is authorized to conduct a blood donation drive once every quarter of a calendar year, in accordance with paragraphs (2) and (3).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id089cf553ee814271bbf4d41ab115785a"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Date selection</header><text>The Sergeant at Arms shall, in consultation with the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate, select the date for each drive conducted under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idba517f4fad104abe88d11ffdfc26a488"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Selection of locations and partnering blood donation organizations</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7e97a51856894c3aa0e85ab35ef05e93"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Sergeant at Arms shall identify and, with the approval of the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate, select a location and a partnering blood donation organization for each drive conducted under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id65ac0684bc554df4ad63ed08e2d0872d"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Member requests</header><text>In identifying appropriate partnering blood donation organizations under subparagraph (A), the Sergeant at Arms may consider a request from a Senator for a specific blood donation organization. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id6ed2f04ff04641669f2ddf57b9f31ec8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>Physical preparations for the conduct of, and the implementation of, each drive authorized under subsection (a)(1) shall be carried out in accordance with such conditions as the Sergeant at Arms, in consultation with the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate, may prescribe. </text></subsection></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

