<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HEFC807BC82C041E7A48B28E072E941E6" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5399 IH: Equitable Arts Education Enhancement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5399</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250916">September 16, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000400">Ms. Kamlager-Dove</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000110">Mr. Fields</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Education to carry out a grant program to support arts education at minority-serving institutions of higher education.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H45DCC13E435B445681E487CF05E678F9" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H71626DAFC1FF4D9CB052B9AFC0EE1AEA" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Equitable Arts Education Enhancement Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section>
<section id="HD0386BD46BFD4DAAA419FB8211D4119C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> <paragraph id="H2CF1908E3E8B4E22892141D67664DAD7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>According to a 2021 study by Americans for the Arts, the arts are an invaluable aspect of American society, as they strengthen the economy, improve healthcare, spark creativity and innovation, and unify communities, with 73 percent of participants agreeing that the arts help them to better understand other cultures.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5616186F680F4E779C67B18D047013CF" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The American Alliance of Museums found that <quote>93 percent of museum directors are white, as are 92.6 percent of board chairs and 89.3 percent of board members</quote>, reflecting a clear lack of diversity in the leadership of museums.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4C9223720A2D4A4EA566316285283B4A"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Minority-serving institutions, or <quote>MSIs</quote>, are uniquely positioned to produce a diverse generation of art professionals and help bring much needed attention to works by BIPOC (Black, Indigenous, People of Color) artists. MSIs have historically served as long-standing conservators and crucial supporters of artist from diverse backgrounds. At a time when diversity, equity, and inclusion are being targeted, the teaching, supporting, and displaying of essential Minority artists who may otherwise have remained unrecognized must be prioritized.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF3698C2B82004E178C33EC59D21E710F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Arts programs and arts departments are expensive and have often fallen victim to funding shortfalls. In 2018, the College Art Association reported that at least 18 institutions of higher education planned to severely curtail or eliminate their arts departments.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAECFF91767484EB3860D8409CC7D91E0"><enum>(5)</enum><text>An increased investment in MSI arts, arts education, and culture programs can further help Black, Indigenous, students of color access an affordable arts education and ensure the continued preparation, conservation, display, and study of works by Minority artists.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="HFF3C8B501413402A81DA658C8DF7C32D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Grants to minority-serving institutions</header>
<subsection id="H5A5DDDAD94644C52BF12EFD7E9B77400"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Education (referred to in this section as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall carry out a program under which the Secretary makes grants to minority-serving institutions, on a competitive basis, to support arts education at such institutions.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H8443CD6C336B4F05A5C694EEF9A682B9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, a minority-serving institution shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HB8C04B81A04B4B9AAC7E1F8EB7A943F4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Uses of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A minority-serving institution that receives a grant under this section shall use such grant to support increased racial minority access to arts education at the institution, which may include—</text> <paragraph id="HF2AED86B5BB94529909B782FB3B914B4"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">providing financial and other assistance to students in arts, arts education, and cultural programs;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HCCF919CBEB804952AEA3EB3B8C667943"><enum>(2)</enum><text>establishing outreach programs and development offices for arts, arts education, and cultural departments;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9EA5386C06D84C07A31DEDB343C7B8D6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>providing comprehensive wraparound services for arts, arts education, and cultural students, including faculty and peer mentorship, work-based learning opportunities, guidance counseling, and career advising;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1A6F42243112431F832F61D3E3D973F9"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">presenting and exhibiting art and performances produced by minority-serving institutions, and maintaining, monitoring, and protecting minority art collections in exhibition and in storage;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD033AAF4950D453595077462321AC105"><enum>(5)</enum><text>providing well-paid apprenticeship, internship, and fellowship opportunities to students in arts, arts education, and cultural programs through partnerships with nonprofit arts, arts education, and cultural institutes;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HBB22DAB1BB2A4B24BBD17585DB355FBB"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">offering stipends to students in arts education preparation programs to enable such students to participate in clinical experiences;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H099B35C3A1404BCA8C9A9CCFAF6D8DF1"><enum>(7)</enum><text>developing mentoring programs for future arts educators;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC6DFCCC2506F44FDA7A84B474269EAA0"><enum>(8)</enum><text>providing training and stipends for mentor teachers; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0D0A9BDBF925455F8E5C2761A47DCA44"><enum>(9)</enum><text>paying for future arts educators and mentor teachers to participate in professional learning opportunities offered by nonprofit arts education organizations.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H0450B683418445F6BD79B4D65DB305F7"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In determining the appropriate uses of funds under subsection (c), a minority-serving institution shall give special consideration to uses of funds that directly benefit minority students.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HB23253783BA74F238AA768F0DA830BBD"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this section.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="HFF027F0A78A64626B3CDB559395F272E"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="HF6C5EA2C4EB544CA8E2D20BEB1CEFDB8"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>arts</term> means art forms used for self-expression and interpretation, including dance, music, theater, literary, visual, graphic, media arts, plastic, and decorative arts.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF9E5648804324282B267DD5D53B8D11E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>minority</term> means an individual from an underrepresented racial minority.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB916B3155F874334830634EBCB22D577"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>minority-serving institution</term> means an institution specified in section 371(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1067q">20 U.S.C. 1067q(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

