<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H8B797861254F44CDBE1DB225E4DFA7C3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 890 IH: Stopping Pharma’s Ripoffs and Drug Savings For All Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 890</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250131">January 31, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000579">Mr. Ryan</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 35, United States Code, to prevent double patenting, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H21934E3D911F4D8DA6B500A9935A8042" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H5438A902D3A04177BC8D18E57D57B9A8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stopping Pharma’s Ripoffs and Drug Savings For All Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section> <section id="HE432E3EE15F049C9950231473A137384"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prevention of double patenting</header> <subsection id="H65D19C77B0CE476C993037517CA25A4F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 253 of title 35, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block id="H9BFBCDAF0DD549609C37A36DA01F065E" style="OLC">
<subsection id="HD97636FD21794F63B36408890C03757F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Disclaimers of drug patent term</header>
<paragraph id="HA737A7A4B622492F9374D82CA4B13B14"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in paragraph (2), in a proceeding challenging the validity of patents under section 505(c) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/355">21 U.S.C. 355(c)</external-xref>) with respect to a drug, under section 351(l) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/262">42 U.S.C. 262(l)</external-xref>) with respect to a biological product, or a Federal district court proceeding involving patents that are the subject of an action under section 271(e)(2), the patentee shall be presumed to have disclaimed the patent term for each of the listed patents after the date on which the term of the first patent expires, subject to the exceptions provided for in subsection (2).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAC0D3177646A44CEB62C941C74CEB7AF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Demonstration of distinct inventions</header><text>If a patentee demonstrates by a preponderance of the evidence that certain patents described in paragraph (1) cover patentably distinct inventions from the invention claimed in the first such patent to expire, no part of the term of any such patent shall be presumed to have been disclaimed, and all patent term extensions granted by the United States Patent and Trademark Office shall be respected, unless and to the extent the patentee expressly disclaims, in writing, the patent term for each such patent.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection>
<subsection id="H109BBA9BF5B2499CA9479573846FEEFA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>USPTO review</header>
<paragraph id="H331702A678324FD9BF204280C022124A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection—</text> <subparagraph id="HAB540FEEE92C42BCAADCED960813D587"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the term <term>Office</term> means the United States Patent and Trademark Office; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H5A2D8BD84125455889C11269B95B0914"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the term <term>Director</term> means the Under Secretary of Commerce for Intellectual Property and Director of the Office.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9E75332D56EC40B399C434620684EB8F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Review</header><text>The Director shall conduct a comprehensive review of the patent examination procedures of the Office to determine whether the Office—</text>
<subparagraph id="H4BC979E0611B44E6B1176F439E6E1317"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is using best examination practices, guidance, and procedures to avoid the issuance of patents relating to the same drug, or biological product, that are not patentably distinct from one another, and not subject to an appropriate disclaimer of patent term; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H63DDA329CB8D4F26B933758D1C1A1C84"><enum>(B)</enum><text>should develop and implement new practices, guidance, or procedures to—</text>
<clause id="H612A4858D3BC4537B15ECC8E3FCAD20D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>improve examination of patent applications relating to the same drug or biological product; and</text></clause> <clause id="HF60E5A1250D442FFB10B60E34621B600"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>reduce the improper issuance of patents that improperly extend the term of exclusivity afforded a new drug or biological product.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9FFD9099933548C6B5383178AEC311E6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director shall submit to the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives a report that contains—</text> <subparagraph id="H5D693986EB4D4E5B93D282A3317AB780"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the findings from the review conducted under paragraph (2); and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H360065E0F0BA4B0FBF85539139B7270F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any recommendations of the Director with respect to the review conducted under paragraph (2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

