<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-BIN25190-DV5-09-CY7"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 337 IS: Recognizing the 250th anniversary of the postal service of the United States.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 337</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250724">July 24, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S380">Mr. Peters</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S383">Mr. Sullivan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S288">Ms. Murkowski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S388">Ms. Hassan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S384">Mr. Tillis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S436">Ms. Slotkin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S266">Mr. Crapo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S252">Ms. Collins</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing the 250th anniversary of the postal service of the United States.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, on July 26, 1775, the Second Continental Congress founded the first national postal service to facilitate secure communication between the Continental Army, Congress, and citizens during the American Revolution;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the importance of a postal service is recognized in the Constitution, which gave Congress the power to establish post offices and post roads;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the postal service has grown from 75 post offices in the original 13 colonies to more than 30,000 locations in every corner of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the postal service holds a unique place in the history of the United States and in the hearts of the people;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the postal service embodies the spirit of innovation, determination, longevity, and resilience of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the postal service has facilitated commerce and united the United States;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas the United States Postal Service was established as an independent establishment of the Federal Government in 1971;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas the United States Postal Service provides all people in all parts of the United States with universal and open access to its delivery network; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States Postal Service remains a vital part of the critical infrastructure of the United States through the delivery of mail and package services 6 days each week to 168,600,000 delivery points: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id6cf2d3e4daae472dafb39d6216db85f0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognizes the historic significance of the 250th anniversary of the founding of the postal service;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id546446bb91654093a64ebe556e813a3f"><enum>(2)</enum><text>honors the men and women who served and continue to serve as employees of the postal service;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0ae409f941514438bdac8bda832657f2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>celebrates 250 years of service by the postal service to the people of the United States and looks forward to another 250 years of service; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id884467e70b0a4fc6a3582df04d58b0f5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>invites the people of the United States to join in the celebration of the 250th anniversary of the postal service by writing a letter, buying stamps, or recognizing a postal employee.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

