<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H67FF00B249F64E2D97A0CB775545206F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4197 IH: LGBTQ+ Panic Defense Prohibition Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4197</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250626">June 26, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000614">Mr. Pappas</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001130">Ms. Crockett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001117">Mr. Casten</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001223">Mrs. Sykes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001159">Ms. Strickland</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001227">Ms. McClellan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000402">Mr. Kennedy of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000629">Ms. Davids of Kansas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000788">Ms. Williams of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000530">Mr. Deluzio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001220">Mr. McGarvey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001225">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000034">Mr. Pallone</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001081">Mrs. Hayes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000476">Mr. Frost</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000477">Mrs. Foushee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001112">Mr. Carbajal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001110">Mr. Correa</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 18, United States Code, to prohibit defenses based on sexual orientation or gender identity or expression.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H274E9B0B378648EFB33B069A1867447F" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HB6B031EED48747678F4B431338C7E0A3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>LGBTQ+ Panic Defense Prohibition Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HFC487A4ACF7E4954BE514721D65A72BF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text>
<paragraph id="H1E40EE95D2B249F4A05328C1514DD83D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the American Bar Association has urged the Federal Government to take legislative action to curtail the availability and effectiveness of the legal defenses that seek to partially or completely excuse crimes such as murder and assault on the grounds that the sexual orientation or gender identity of the victim is provocation enough for the violent reaction of the defendant;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA255C6DA9BD3410FA69A36C6D1F4123F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">panic defenses based on sexual orientation or gender identity or expression, which continue to be raised in criminal proceedings in Federal courts across the United States, are surprisingly long-lived historical artifacts, remnants of a time when widespread public antipathy was the norm for lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, and queer (referred to in this Act as <quote>LGBTQ</quote>) individuals;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H843729BD6DAD4B678CDF569957118538"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">panic defenses based on sexual orientation or gender identity or expression characterize sexual orientation and gender identity or expression as objectively reasonable excuses for loss of self-control, and thereby illegitimately mitigate the responsibility of a perpetrator for harm done to LGBTQ individuals;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H637A226118224CE7821104362716C496"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">panic defenses based on sexual orientation or gender identity or expression appeal to irrational fears and hatred of LGBTQ individuals, thereby undermining the legitimacy of Federal criminal prosecutions and resulting in unjustifiable acquittals or sentencing reductions;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H72FFF9A58803424284EC2DEF6B67E1A6"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the use of panic defenses based on sexual orientation or gender identity or expression is entirely incompatible with the express intent of Federal law to provide increased protection to victims of bias-motivated crimes, including crimes committed against LGBTQ individuals;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD93A2E75C73C4309B9E5E5E8F2E8AD3B"><enum>(6)</enum><text>continued use of these anachronistic defenses reinforces and institutionalizes prejudice at the expense of norms of self-control, tolerance, and compassion, which the law should encourage, and marks an egregious lapse in the march of the United States toward a more just criminal justice system; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H29681DF2A94F478093C96B08C1C33424"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to end the antiquated notion that LGBTQ lives are worth less than others and to reflect modern understanding of LGBTQ individuals as equal citizens under law, panic defenses based on sexual orientation or gender identity or expression must end.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H3AFA6DBF270E4A84B8A8C65D3381F9D7"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibition on panic defenses based on sexual orientation or gender identity or expression</header> <subsection id="H13AF2977C680436A880E32E31C166D77"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/1">Chapter 1</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6F0117E1035C4548986F194A572616E7" style="USC">
<section id="HFA2CE896EFAF49699FD303340B6B45FE"><enum>28.</enum><header>Prohibition on panic defenses based on sexual orientation or gender identity or expression</header>
<subsection id="H32BA993AC85C4516BF0FABC4EB7764B9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>No nonviolent sexual advance or perception or belief, even if inaccurate, of the gender, gender identity or expression, or sexual orientation of an individual may be used to excuse or justify the conduct of an individual or mitigate the severity of an offense.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H13F88B5497934F46B1A73CAD6B1E1FDC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Past trauma</header><text>Notwithstanding the prohibition in subsection (a), a court may admit evidence, in accordance with the Federal Rules of Evidence, of prior trauma to the defendant for the purpose of excusing or justifying the conduct of the defendant or mitigating the severity of an offense.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection>
<subsection id="H6CA32A62AA1B45679125F02A00F4284F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="HD3538CC64A6E47598AF2FF9E62D041A9" style="USC"> <toc> <toc-entry idref="HFA2CE896EFAF49699FD303340B6B45FE" level="section">28. Prohibition on panic defenses based on sexual orientation or gender identity or expression.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H55278FE45F4C47AB8B41E782BB39B14F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>The Attorney General shall submit to Congress an annual report that details prosecutions in Federal court involving capital and noncapital crimes committed against LGBTQ individuals that were motivated by the victim’s gender, gender identity or expression, or sexual orientation.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

