<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA6130D5E741642E2851644793F7CB8BA" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 892 IH: Mortgage Rate Reduction Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 892</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250131">January 31, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000579">Mr. Ryan</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Veterans' Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the heads of certain agencies to disclose information about loans insured and guaranteed by such agencies, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H4F8173EB8CDB4EC2AEE3E22735745039" style="OLC"><section id="H98631FBA25AD41258EDEE764ABECB241" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Mortgage Rate Reduction Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="HBF5DD527A03F4F4F9D18F12083C65F9C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of the Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of the Congress that—</text><paragraph id="H7CF0F7E53C224187A73B19CC8CEF0069"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Assistant Secretary for the Office of Housing and Federal Housing Commissioner should, acting through the Federal Housing Administration, insure second mortgages under section 203 of the National Housing Act for properties for which the Federal Housing Administration has insured a first mortgage, to facilitate the assumption of such first mortgage by a subsequent purchaser of such property;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEDCBBF74DE914D66B4132219D49925CB"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary of Agriculture should guarantee loans for eligible housing under section 502(h) of the Housing Act of 1949 that are second mortgages if the Secretary of Agriculture insures the loan that is the first mortgage against such eligible housing, to facilitate the assumption of such first mortgage by a subsequent purchaser of such eligible housing; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H69F4F1BABE6C44E7BA8E856B275A925E" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary of Veterans Affairs should insure and guarantee real estate housing loans secured by second liens under subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/37">chapter 37</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, if the Secretary of Veterans Affairs insures the first lien against such real estate, to facilitate the assumption of the first mortgage against such real estate by a subsequent purchaser of such real estate.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HE9002BBBAB4A464D9832FAB4A6C8DD13"><enum>3.</enum><header>Insurance for secondary mortgages</header><subsection id="H284D133DC1CF474AB78921235FF37ECF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Federal Housing Administration</header><paragraph id="H6D26130391714B33B1F933D478EA8C44"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 201(a) of the National Housing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1707">12 U.S.C. 1707(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="H531700EC7921442A87FE7FDD8C7A97A7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>a first mortgage</quote> each place it occurs and inserting <quote>a first mortgage or second mortgage</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB7453FBE8B9E49FB9543B0046BA43FC4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>secured thereby.</quote> and inserting the following: <quote>secured thereby; and the term <quote>second mortgage</quote> means, with respect to real estate against which there is a first mortgage that has been insured under section 203, such classes of second liens as are commonly given to secure advances on, or the unpaid purchase price of, real estate, under the laws of the State in which the real estate is located, together with the credit instrument, if any, secured thereby</quote>. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H129BD96BDAE241F0BCF7FC116A28CFED"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text>Section 203 of the National Housing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1709">12 U.S.C. 1709</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>first mortgage</quote> each place it occurs and inserting <quote>first mortgage or second mortgage</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4E02426601CE464DB5A93217DB07A539" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Department of Veterans Affairs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3703(d)(3) of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="H31662D6BB3DE4E9EB84A4FB70BC48718" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>first lien</quote> and inserting <quote>first lien or second lien</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H933A81B2FA19493C8B7E89C53C1A881F" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HAD635C44149F4729A1949DC22F4A1248" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="H1EBD91BACB7A4FC490B761CBAFD914CB" commented="no" indent="up2"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A real estate housing loan may only be secured by second lien if the Secretary insures or guarantees the first lien on such real estate.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HBFD07277FB154FEB8BFDBCF39A173A8F"><enum>4.</enum><header>Disclosure of information about loans guaranteed and insured</header><subsection id="H814274138DD54ACC92EFF1FD70DC4A2C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Loans insured by the Federal Housing Administration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Assistant Secretary for the Office of Housing and the Federal Housing Commissioner shall, not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this section, publish on a public website a list of all properties for which the Federal Housing Administration has insured a mortgage under section 203 of the National Housing Act that includes the following information for each property insured:</text><paragraph id="H188F921BE31C41ABB8401F259CE64F14"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The address of the property against which there is a mortgage insured by the Federal Housing Administration. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCCDE4C80AAFE4313B7D89548C58010B9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The date of the origination of the mortgage that is insured by the Federal Housing Administration. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H92A0C91624DE4F3CA1D1737C0BFABDAE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Loans insured by the Department of Agriculture</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Agriculture shall, not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this section, publish on a public website a list of all properties for which the Department of Agriculture has guaranteed loan under section 502(h) of the Housing Act of 1949 that includes the following information for each loan insured:</text><paragraph id="HE0689314C918488FB4700CE920919E57"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The address of the property against which there is a loan guaranteed by the Department of Agriculture.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC9227A8ED7F94486A0931F0D85902570"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The date of the origination of the loan that is guaranteed by the Department of Agriculture.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H45E443D02C0247A183603D409966BD6B" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Loans insured by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall, not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this section, publish on a public website a list of all properties for which the Department of Veterans Affairs has insured or guaranteed a housing loan under subchapter I of chapter 37 of part III of title 38, United States Code, that includes the following information for each housing loan insured or guaranteed:</text><paragraph id="H951E162813F14573B422A13BA6619AEB" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The address of the property against which there is a housing loan insured or guaranteed by the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H18B7B74B251F4DCA845D1C5884DF55D9" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The date of the origination of the housing loan that is insured or guaranteed by the Department of Veterans Affairs. </text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

