<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-KEN25454-RY1-YX-XK7">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2483 IS: To provide that members of the Advisory Committee on Immunization Practices may not be terminated except for cause and to require the immediate reinstatement of the members of such advisory committee.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>II</distribution-code>
        <congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session>1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. 2483</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action>
            <action-date date="20250728">July 28, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S430">Ms. Blunt Rochester</sponsor> (for herself,
                    <cosponsor name-id="S409">Mr. Luján</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S415">Mr.
                    Warnock</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S359">Mr. Heinrich</cosponsor>,
                    <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S428">Ms. Alsobrooks</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice
                and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health,
                    Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title>To provide that members of the Advisory Committee on Immunization Practices
            may not be terminated except for cause and to require the immediate reinstatement of the
            members of such advisory committee.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body>
        <section id="id51d36be52ae64f9caa351f896c49d37c" section-type="section-one">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Membership of the Advisory Committee on Immunization Practices</header>
            <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idda018ea84f1345a1a496488cf030c9be">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Requirements for termination of members
                    of ACIP</header>
                <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb3666f9106d744888b6775148b2b272d">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                    <header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header>
 <text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services (referred to in this section as the <term>Secretary</term>) may only terminate a member of the Advisory Committee on Immunization Practices (referred to in this section as the <term>Advisory Committee</term>) for cause and after notice and opportunity for hearing.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="idba7f1194a44648f385cc087d9e30e22b">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Justification for termination</header>
 <text>If the Secretary terminates a member of the Advisory Committee for cause as described in paragraph (1), not later than 1 day after the date of such termination, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives, and make publicly available, a written justification for such termination.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc3412135520948709a446c87e2bef974">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
                    <header>Effect on Federal employees</header>
 <text>With respect to a member of the Advisory Committee who is also an employee of the Federal Government, a termination for cause as described in paragraph (1) shall apply only with respect to the membership of the individual as such a member and may not be construed to modify or otherwise impact any protection available to the individual in the capacity of the individual as such an employee.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id0dd40322c01a4a2a96f5b03f7cded00f">
                    <enum>(4)</enum>
                    <header>Definition of for cause</header>
 <text>In this subsection, the term <term>for cause</term>, with respect to a termination of a member of the Advisory Committee, means a termination based on inefficiency, neglect of duty, or malfeasance in office.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6fe0d100a80140469a41ab0df55e6834">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Reinstatement of certain ACIP members</header>
 <text>The Secretary shall immediately revert to the membership of the Advisory Committee as in effect on June 8, 2025, and such members of such Committee shall serve the remainder of the terms that applied to such members as of June 9, 2025.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="idc846c2a2d4eb41348819e0b5f4eca9f2">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Requirements for appointment of members of ACIP</header>
 <text>In the case of any vacancy in the membership of the Advisory Committee that occurs after the date on which the individuals are reinstated to the Advisory Committee under subsection (b), the Secretary shall appoint a member to fill such vacancy from among individuals recommended by the Comptroller General of the United States.</text>
            </subsection>
        </section>
    </legis-body>
</bill>

