<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H45AEEBC7BFD54FA4A999DA70CD6F8754" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1710 IH: PLO and PA Terror Payments Accountability Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1710</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250227">February 27, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001217">Mr. Moskowitz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000478">Ms. Tenney</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To impose sanctions with respect to the system of compensation of the Palestine Liberation Organization and the Palestinian Authority that supports acts of terrorism.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H123DDE4AB804429494BB01848EFB849C" style="OLC"><section id="H78E9194CF87D44D9A60DB7C9DFC63D2E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>PLO and PA Terror Payments Accountability Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H0697281572CF49AAABBB608483EAFEFB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings; statement of policy</header><subsection id="H086A525F73064EEF8BAB3C18CD84996E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress makes the following findings:</text><paragraph id="H4599EA25496143179AA49DFCD7A66B70"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Palestine Liberation Organization and the Palestinian Authority provide hundreds of millions of dollars per year in payments, salaries, and benefits to terrorists and the families of terrorists as part of a system compensation that incentivizes, encourages, rewards, and supports acts of terrorism.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H172FC1CA0DA94AF7AC6D0E4DF829DC18"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Palestine Liberation Organization and the Palestinian Authority policies, laws, and regulations that direct, authorize, enact, facilitate, and implement a system of compensation in support of acts of terrorism require payments, salaries, and benefits to terrorists including those who are members and part of organizations designated as foreign terrorist organizations by the Secretary of State under section 219 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1189">8 U.S.C. 1189</external-xref>), including Hamas and Islamic Jihad, that receive direct support including financial and military assistance from Iran, the leading state sponsor of terrorism in the world.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFBD42B92A1C74910807C7CA8F91A9BD9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In 2018, Congress passed the Taylor Force Act (title X of division S of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/141">Public Law 115–141</external-xref>; 132 Stat. 1143) into law that calls on the Palestine Liberation Organization and the Palestinian Authority to end their system of compensation that incentivizes, encourages, rewards, and supports acts of terrorism and restricts United States assistance <quote>that directly benefits the Palestinian Authority</quote> unless the Secretary of State certifies to Congress that the Palestine Liberation Organization and the Palestinian Authority have met specific conditions including terminating that system of compensation and revoking the policies, laws, and regulations that authorize and implement the system of compensation. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC679D67D349F497B9B589F8E7C86A3BF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Despite the enactment of the Taylor Force Act, the Palestine Liberation Organization and the Palestinian Authority have continued their system of compensation that incentivizes, encourages, rewards, and supports acts of terrorism.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2D51B25321A24E9EBDFF57147041CEC6"><enum>(5)</enum><text>On October 7, 2023, Hamas, Islamic Jihad, and other Gaza-based terrorist organizations attacked Israel on Shabbat and during the Jewish holiday of Simchat Torah, committing the deadliest attack on the Jewish people since the Holocaust.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD35CA96CBD1E4127ABE012E8FA93E800"><enum>(6)</enum><text>On October 7, 2023, Hamas fired thousands of rockets into Israel, deliberately targeting Israeli civilians, and thousands of terrorists invaded Israeli communities—massacring, raping, torturing, decapitating, burning alive, seriously injuring, and kidnapping Israelis and Americans, including men, women, children, babies, and grandparents, and including Holocaust survivors, with children being murdered in front of their parents and parents being murdered in front of their children.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB4E06E06D3894A85A1669699029919FA"><enum>(7)</enum><text>On October 7, 2023, Hamas murdered more than 1,200 who were mostly civilians, and kidnapped more than 240, including Israeli and American men, women, children, babies, and grandparents, and took them to Gaza as hostages.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAA54B4EB6DD34645BDB2B29EC4C318FA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text>It shall be the policy of the United States to hold the Palestine Liberation Organization and the Palestinian Authority accountable including through the imposition of sanctions for providing payments, salaries, and benefits to terrorists and the families of terrorists as part of a system compensation that incentivizes, encourages, rewards, and supports acts of terrorism.</text></subsection></section><section id="H9BD8F69C98734C81AA239023EFEFE427"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H788814DE49194E598B4794F40410DB3D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Act of terrorism</header><text>The term <term>act of terrorism</term>—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBAF9729470DA4A6196D4654710CE2AC1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means an act of international terrorism (as defined in section 2331 of title 18, United States Code); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA8036DC1D9654EC7A7A48FD87D4B1D2A"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes the meanings given the terms <quote>terrorist activity</quote> and <quote>engage in terrorist activity</quote> by section 212(a)(3)(B) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(a)(3)(B)</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE96F9F1206BA4D2090E916FD4D89CAAF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H37732FA10828453AAAAB124C5395C1E0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAE9237ED04C5479DA9D120F43EE0E201"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4F6928EB6E7B4CDB8D9DCCAED0DEE495"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Foreign person</header><text>The term <term>foreign person</term> means any person or entity that is not a United States person.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE7C0EC67B6EB4C5198E505F1F2A791DA"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Knowingly</header><text>The term <term>knowingly</term>, with respect to conduct, a circumstance, or a result, means that a person had actual knowledge, or should have known, of the conduct, the circumstance, or the result. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H46F28041319F4F6B9723D6318FF47B77"><enum>(5)</enum><header>System of compensation</header><text>The term <term>system of compensation</term>, with respect to the Palestinian Authority and the Palestinian Liberation Organization, means the payments described in subparagraph (B) of section 1004(a)(1) of the Taylor Force Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2378c-1">22 U.S.C. 2378c–1</external-xref>) and the system of compensation described in subparagraph (C) of that section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA1D488EEB4FE4E749CBFA928496E025F"><enum>(6)</enum><header>United states person</header><text>The term <term>United States person</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="HE3B9BB636777416D950E3A93D54CD1AF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a United States citizen or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence to the United States; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEACAA8199CA34FA4BA39973117477B1A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an entity organized under the laws of the United States or any jurisdiction within the United States, including a foreign branch of such an entity; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE76DB1582B224D8DB1906B357FFACE50"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"> a person in the United States. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H8B6EEC8B14B34DF9BCBADB6151120FBB"><enum>4.</enum><header>Imposition of sanctions on certain foreign persons supporting terrorism</header><subsection id="H648DC5A5B43B42CA9F2F7649E0A805F3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and an ongoing basis thereafter, the President shall impose the sanctions described in subsection (b) on—</text><paragraph id="H2D3A2F6490BA46488B41C7699EC6945A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any foreign person that—</text><subparagraph id="H573D0B2A32D841F1869E24925A6686AF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has served in a position as a representative, minister, official, or employee of the Palestine Liberation Organization, the Palestinian Authority, or any other foreign person that has directed, authorized, been responsible for, materially assisted with, enacted, implemented, or otherwise facilitated the Palestine Liberation Organization and the Palestinian Authority system of compensation supporting acts of terrorism; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5D9231E099CD4CAB8334EB427D41F721"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has provided payments, salaries, and benefits to terrorists and the families of terrorists as part of the Palestine Liberation Organization and the Palestinian Authority system of compensation supporting acts of terrorism;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H134AC289CC614EE4AB4874473D4D0335"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any entity that directly or indirectly has operated, ordered, controlled, directed, or otherwise facilitated the Palestine Liberation Organization and the Palestinian Authority system of compensation supporting acts of terrorism including the Commission of Prisoners and Released Prisoners, the Institute for the Care of the Families of the Martyrs and the Wounded, the Palestine National Fund, National Association of the Families of the Martyrs of Palestine, or any successor, agency, instrumentality, organization, or affiliated entities thereof; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H91941BD75FC94515B1A80223046C3952"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any foreign person that has knowingly provided significant financial, technological, or material support and resources support to, or knowingly engaged in a significant transaction with a foreign person described in subparagraph (1) or (2).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H21E6FC7854E04906A39B3211EAB9CE57"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sanctions described</header><text>The sanctions that shall be imposed with respect to a foreign person described in subsection (a) are the following:</text><paragraph id="HAD509273E0BB4C829AE1ED2C9340EE21"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Blocking of property</header><text>The President shall exercise all of the powers granted to the President under the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>) to the extent necessary to block and prohibit all transactions in property and interests in property of the foreign person if such property and interests in property are in the United States, come within the United States, or are or come within the possession or control of a United States person.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H705B9F50C1A8485BBD9E447BC72F00C5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Ineligibility for visas, admission, or parole</header><subparagraph id="H63955A7A217A4B978365509FBB570F04"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Visas, admission, or parole</header><text>An alien described in subsection (a) is—</text><clause id="H62EB392CECEB486AB832220B78C46704"><enum>(i)</enum><text>inadmissible to the United States;</text></clause><clause id="H02CABA92B8DB48BBA6EF97605EE8A16F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>ineligible to receive a visa or other documentation to enter the United States; and</text></clause><clause id="H6D321BB41E894C00A2FC4018E7FF9322"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>otherwise ineligible to be admitted or paroled into the United States or to receive any other benefit under the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3A6FA2A84F9143FB8DAA3785E4DCFA9D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Current visas revoked</header><clause id="H4F23F5A1A2354F40AD4945546AFB2391"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An alien described in subsection (a) is subject to revocation of any visa or other entry documentation regardless of when the visa or other entry documentation is or was issued.</text></clause><clause id="H0746EA18A9624D928159ADF7B56C5E18"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Immediate effect</header><text>A revocation under clause (i) shall—</text><subclause id="H82A05A2DBFB24E8696B1AAF0E475D18C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>take effect immediately; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HC60234B857D9478B94BA5A37C3107E41"><enum>(II)</enum><text>automatically cancel any other valid visa or entry documentation that is in the alien’s possession.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HD9EA97C2D05A4F2FAE83280F6A013C99"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text>The penalties provided for in subsections (b) and (c) of section 206 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1705">50 U.S.C. 1705</external-xref>) shall apply to a person that violates, attempts to violate, conspires to violate, or causes a violation of this section or any regulations promulgated to carry out this section to the same extent that such penalties apply to a person that commits an unlawful act described in section 206(a) of that Act. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H41A58C51AD7248ADA888DE8C9AA32B16"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Congressional requests</header><text>Not later than 30 days after receiving a request from the chairman or ranking member of one of the appropriate congressional committees with respect to whether a person meets the criteria of a person described in subsection (a), the President shall—</text><paragraph id="HD2D062CE7048449D933171AA29B124B3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>determine if the person meets such criteria; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1E615DA89960496FAAC45561CAEFFF67"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submit a classified or unclassified report to the chairman or ranking member, that submitted the request with respect to that determination that includes a statement of whether or not the President imposed or intends to impose sanctions with respect to the person.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8E02B93A44E54937B7809BC3A541ABB1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Implementation; regulations</header><paragraph id="HA7E786E7D70143DAB465FDBC2350A3D9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President may exercise all authorities provided under sections 203 and 205 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1702 and 1704) for purposes of carrying out this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4978FC4ABE764C39B67FCB2DF96818C9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall issue such regulations or other guidance as may be necessary for the implementation of this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3B2ED5124C084FB6A79E257D63755242"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H55BF247014C34E0C9CF99B9520956BA2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Material support or resources</header><text>The term <term>material support or resources</term> has the meaning given that term in section 2339A(b) of title 18, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H37D44620DDFC4801886C020CBE9CA9A4"><enum>5.</enum><header>Imposition of sanctions with respect to financial institutions that facilitate transactions supporting terrorism</header><subsection id="HEE9DCB8E6A964D29A3B225FF249F9F9D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and on an ongoing basis thereafter, the President shall impose the sanctions described in subsection (c) with respect to each foreign financial institution that engages in the activities described in subsection (b).</text></subsection><subsection id="H7FB57D0E6C884FABBEFB5754369FD941"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Activities described</header><text>A foreign financial institution engages in an activity described in this subsection if the institution—</text><paragraph id="H8C654757EDF946AD93701A5171A71634"><enum>(1)</enum><text>processes, participates in, facilitates, or provides a transaction that are payments, salaries, or benefits, or any other conduct described in section 4(a); or </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3407D60E7D364573967DB3C51EFC7BFC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>knowingly conducted or facilitated any significant financial transaction with any foreign person subject to sanctions under section 4(a).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCA0CE980387E4264B312D63CE8EAC827"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Sanctions described</header><text>The President shall prohibit the opening, and prohibit or impose strict conditions on the maintaining, in the United States of a correspondent account or a payable-through account by a foreign financial institution described in subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="HF84C94DC0D4944F3AB247220A0B7660E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HD165CE29FAF04BD595FBD8FCC6614A12"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Correspondent account; payable-through account</header><text>The terms <quote>correspondent account</quote> and <quote>payable-through account</quote> have the meanings given those terms in section 5318A of title 31, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H393C1AB0275B411AA7101B27F32C23BC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Foreign financial institution</header><text>The term <term>foreign financial institution</term> has the meaning of that term as determined by the Secretary of the Treasury pursuant to section 104(i) of the Comprehensive Iran Sanctions, Accountability, and Divestment Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/8513">22 U.S.C. 8513(i)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H1ACB8386AA2A4671B656B16E6285091B"><enum>6.</enum><header>Termination</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The provisions of this Act shall have no force or effect only if the Secretary of State certifies in writing to the appropriate congressional committees that the Palestine Liberation Organization and the Palestinian Authority system of compensation providing payments, salaries, and benefits to terrorists and the families of terrorists that incentivizes, encourages, rewards, and supports acts of terrorism as described in this Act, has ceased to be in effect and is no longer taking place. </text></section></legis-body></bill> 

