<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4D02A9A2068A4AA6B1E0C782B56BD1B2" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 621 IH: Recognizing August 5, National Night Out, the national coming together of Americans all over the Nation to unite and promote public safety.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 621</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250729">July 29, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000474">Mrs. Torres of California</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing August 5, National Night Out, the national coming together of Americans all over the Nation to unite and promote public safety.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, on the first Tuesday of August, the Nation will observe National Night Out, a day to cultivate a better relationship between residents of a community and their local law enforcement, and to promote public safety;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the participation in National Night Out by over 38,000,000 neighbors in over 17,000 communities across the United States for over 40 years is inspiring;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the relationship between local law enforcement and the residents which they are sworn to protect is important in creating a true sense of community;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas general awareness of public safety has improved, because of the continued efforts of communities to meet their law enforcement officers and participate in National Night Out activities; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas National Night Out not only includes Americans on the mainland, but includes those in United States territories and military bases to ensure all are included in the effort of community building and public safety awareness: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HE8165496FD8C4273B8200700DFCDC6BE"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H89C7921CD5C1405194D8B14500BE00BD"><enum/><text>That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="HB97EBADB9F614BA8B0FF8800F37FA90E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>encourages law enforcement departments to use National Night Out to improve relationships with the communities they serve;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA91372D545C1405C8BA966C5529CE666"><enum>(2)</enum><text>encourages public safety departments to inform communities—</text><subparagraph id="H226BD875A5044CAAA674D3FB2CC16760"><enum>(A)</enum><text>how to most effectively contact their 911 responders and emergency service providers; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H03F7B598C3BA49E08A6BDE876FE9E2AC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>how they carry out their duties; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H957FB3E275134309872C2F0ED7660453"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recognizes the impact that has been made for over 40 years in communities all over the United States of America by National Night Out in creating a more united country by fostering relationships between residents, neighbors, and local law enforcement, and promoting public safety awareness.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

