<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H42D3F8F16BB64870B7F0D13D45493196" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 582 IH: Establishing an advisory working group to make recommendations with respect to relief portraits in the Hall of the House of Representatives.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 582</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250715">July 15, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Establishing an advisory working group to make recommendations with respect to relief portraits in the Hall of the House of Representatives.</official-title></form><resolution-body style="OLC" id="HBB223EAB3551406185E5454E988EC82C"> 
<section id="HD3D83BEBDC94479295DEE25A76F1A051" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Establishment of advisory working group</header> 
<subsection id="H4130D120DE3F4EF380C166E6AE8264E5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment; composition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established an advisory working group to carry out this section that shall consist of the following members:</text> <paragraph id="H00B9A26088884EF4B8843E083932FD88"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Clerk of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD7C90516A872485CA813CBA350999E52"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Curator of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA0ED42FDEE1741DFAA8C0F365919ED24"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Curator for the Architect of the Capitol.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H472DB4665A1B483EA8A96A53CB3BF877"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Chair and ranking minority member of the Committee on House Administration.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAA6515EBB79043AEAF3EC44CCC5BF08E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Chair and ranking minority member of the Subcommittee on the Legislative Branch of the Committee on Appropriations.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA37594F6569B46A0A5D1D35DE5D7ACD1"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The Co-Chairs of the Congressional Bipartisan Women’s Caucus.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H9AB5D9DDA9FD463A9266D13F4C68DCDD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text>The advisory working group shall submit to the Speaker of the House of Representatives, the Minority Leader, and the Committee on House Administration a written report that includes recommendations with respect to the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H45CB5764EC5C49A1B3B86E03A098E1DF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Two women whose portraits would be suitable for inclusion among the relief portraits of lawgivers placed above the doors to the public gallery of the Hall of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9C024D987A6C4F3DAE1447AAD19D4C8D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The planning, funding, and commissioning of the relief portraits of the women described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCAB85E3985364808BC1F069D99D978F4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The installation of the relief portraits described in paragraph (2) in the Hall of the House of Representatives, including whether the relief portraits should replace any existing relief portrait.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF4C5A8FD81A54C4AA787710D4FB5D7DB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A timeline for such installation that would minimize the disruptive effect of the installation on the business conducted in the Hall of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H530B4A0BD1F74278916E5EE4978A6B64"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>The advisory working group shall designate two members among the individuals described in paragraphs (4) through (6), with the approval of the Speaker and the Minority Leader, to take such actions as are necessary for the advisory working group to carry out this section.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HFA21A6A8C3FA447991406238AB1D154A" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Consultation with experts</header><text>In carrying out this section, the advisory working group shall consult with the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H8A3C39BCD1BF4C869ECB67A566B59D8E" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Leading and reputable scholars with respect to the history of law, women’s history, and related disciplines of study and research.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF001E5A186354BFCAD6B48BA73DC7F75" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Staff of the Library of Congress.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HADFB76AF85724AEF87FECC4DDABCD85D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Deadline for submission</header><text>The advisory working group shall submit the report described in subsection (b) not later than the earliest of the following:</text> <paragraph id="HF47437F75A8E4F4EABA6E9455BCB36F1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>One year after the date of the adoption of this Resolution.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEEC0508E244C475EBAF6A6E8A717F8E5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The end of the One Hundred Nineteenth Congress.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

