<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H416B576C3A8C4246B0EFAE543DE8689D" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 338 IH: Expressing support for the designation of April 17, 2025, as “Cambodian Genocide Remembrance Day” to remember the horrific slaughter of almost 2,000,000 Cambodian people at the hand of the Khmer Rouge regime.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 338</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250417">April 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000482">Mrs. Trahan</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="G000598">Mr. Garcia of California</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of April 17, 2025, as <quote>Cambodian Genocide Remembrance Day</quote> to remember the horrific slaughter of almost 2,000,000 Cambodian people at the hand of the Khmer Rouge regime.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, April 17th, 1975, marked the fall of Phnom Penh to the Khmer Rouge, thereby marking the beginning of the Cambodian Genocide;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, beginning on April 17, 1975, and for the next 4 years, almost 2,000,000 Cambodian people were starved, tortured, and murdered under the direct orders of the Khmer Rouge regime and their leader Pol Pot;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas nearly one fourth of the population of Cambodia at the time were killed during the genocide;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, April 17th, 2025, marks the 50th anniversary of the beginning of the Cambodian Genocide;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas by designating April 17th as a day of remembrance, the utmost respect and reverence can be given to the lives that were lost;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas recognizing this day serves to honor those who survived the genocide with the utmost admiration;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Cambodian communities have found new beginnings across the United States, acting as a symbol of resiliency and strength;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, in 2019, the cities of Lowell, Los Angeles, and Long Beach proclaimed April 17th to be Cambodian Genocide Remembrance Day; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, in 2023, the State of Massachusetts proclaimed April 17th to be Cambodian Genocide Remembrance Day: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="OLC" id="HD7C9F00083F24FF99263C8C0EA1C7540"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HFD460E98A1CD49DDA3BF507091D3AC5C"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> 
<paragraph id="HFB7667A8B8ED41FD8326BB61B90A752B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the principles and values of <quote>Cambodian Genocide Remembrance Day</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5F1512F764B24091A2F01AB59C411C5E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>acknowledges the long and continued struggle of the Cambodian people to foster a free and just democratic process;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB06CD7296C98403BBB36E7F31001C229"><enum>(3)</enum><text>further acknowledges the work of the Cambodian diaspora community throughout the United States to gain recognition of the Cambodian Genocide by the Federal Government;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4B9ABF6624D34CA89D764015CED86590"><enum>(4)</enum><text>encourages all to reflect on the history of the Cambodian Genocide and the legacy that it has left, both within Cambodia and abroad; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD15B77FE0FDA46F587A10CB02883C53C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>requests that the President issue a proclamation calling upon the people of the United States to observe such a day with appropriate ceremonies and activities.</text></paragraph> </section> </resolution-body></resolution>

