<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-CAN25215-7T7-JJ-7NK"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1071 IS: To require the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to disinter the remains of Fernando V. Cota from Fort Sam Houston National Cemetery, Texas, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1071</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250314">March 14, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S287">Mr. Cornyn</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S355">Mr. Cruz</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSVA00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to disinter the remains of Fernando V. Cota from Fort Sam Houston National Cemetery, Texas, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="idaf48ded3a2024953a655270be04d7473" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Disinterment of remains of Fernando V. Cota from Fort Sam Houston National Cemetery, Texas</header><subsection id="idf2af3a1379784bff8829bf3e78c8e5df"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Disinterment</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall disinter the remains of Fernando V. Cota from Fort Sam Houston National Cemetery, Texas.</text></subsection><subsection id="idc87261af6ed7439ca77e75e44f7663f3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Notification</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs may not carry out subsection (a) until after notifying the next of kin of Fernando V. Cota.</text></subsection><subsection id="id031cb5de3bd242fea7bcbd8d2b2d7914"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Disposition</header><text>After carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall—</text><paragraph id="id6aa37423a6e54d72b27841bdb217f418"><enum>(1)</enum><text>relinquish the remains to the next of kin described in subsection (b); or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb1ad9806f7a349cfa7f011a82241841b"><enum>(2)</enum><text>if no such next of kin responds to the notification under subsection (b), arrange for disposition of the remains as the Secretary determines appropriate. </text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

