<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB122FE1C05BE4091B76F263AA4F570C7" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1877 IH: Protecting Americans’ Social Security Data Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1877</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250305">March 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000557">Mr. Larson of Connecticut</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="N000015">Mr. Neal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000490">Mr. Bishop</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000530">Mr. Deluzio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000305">Ms. Jacobs</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000309">Mr. Jackson of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001315">Ms. Budzinski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001066">Mr. Horsford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001296">Mr. Boyle of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001190">Mr. Schneider</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="I000058">Mr. Ivey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001127">Mrs. Cherfilus-McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001229">Mrs. McIver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001081">Mrs. Hayes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000216">Ms. DeLauro</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000301">Ms. Elfreth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001201">Mr. Suozzi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001211">Mr. Stanton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001156">Ms. Sánchez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000148">Mr. Auchincloss</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001225">Mr. Sorensen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000601">Mr. Landsman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000380">Mr. Amo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="U000040">Ms. Underwood</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000622">Mr. Riley of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001206">Mr. Morelle</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001313">Ms. Brown</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001220">Mr. McGarvey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000620">Ms. Pettersen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000687">Mr. Mfume</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000610">Ms. Plaskett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000621">Ms. Randall</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000631">Ms. Dean of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XI of the Social Security Act to establish that political appointees and special governments may not access beneficiary data systems, to establish civil penalties for certain violations relating to disclosure or access of beneficiary information, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA6406D330BD9476BACA4403974E9F486" style="OLC"><section id="HE2586A1C2E9D431DBC6C514DD51B02AA" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting Americans’ Social Security Data Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H58806A97B262471D84C169C429C16D65"><enum>2.</enum><header>Access by political appointees and special government employees</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1106 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1306">42 U.S.C. 1306</external-xref>) is amended by adding after subsection (g) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H8610B6B9F4594DCC85629991B32741AB" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="HB974141C583041A79179A574043536B8"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Access by political appointees and special government employees</header><paragraph id="H2059A40894544A49B724AAFCB843068D" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other subsection of this section, an individual who is a political appointee (as that term is defined in section 4(a) of the Edward ‘Ted’ Kaufman and Michael Leavitt Presidential Transitions Improvements Act of 2015 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/3101">5 U.S.C. 3101</external-xref> note)) or a special government employee (as that term is defined in section 202(a) of title 18, United States Code) may not access a beneficiary data system.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDE816A99C4D74085B12026079FC2F745"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Beneficiary data system defined</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>beneficiary data system</quote> means a system that is maintained by the Social Security Administration for the purposes of administering this Act that—</text><subparagraph id="H1DB6B579A465488599762440F047E77A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">issues or records social security account numbers;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2D89882CCA9741EE8777162FBE755231"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is used to determine eligibility for benefits under this Act;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9753243308B04CA896073596A408388C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to pay benefits under this Act; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H29281D653F1E4F85A91929814E2B07C8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>otherwise contains personally identifiable information about individuals receiving or applying for a benefit under this Act, including—</text><clause id="H227EB20CE5DB4E64A614893CE8AD5B3D"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Master Files of Social Security Number Holders and SSN Applications (Numident);</text></clause><clause id="HE2DF013D256B428D931719DA70E82A5A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Master Beneficiary Record;</text></clause><clause id="HC41798D18A854A77BD31EF8FE008E4A9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Supplemental Security Income Record and Special Veterans Benefits;</text></clause><clause id="H9531546B6C7B4DA6B6EDD9604646E9CF"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the National Disability Determination Services File; </text></clause><clause id="H6BFFE55C77DA480FBA519EBA6318BB48"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Earnings Recording and Self-Employment Income System; and</text></clause><clause id="H211CD624A12041E0AD81CF851C498EB4"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>any other system accessible through the Enterprise Data Warehouse.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H4D7E516699984CC5877F31309E6D5EB4"><enum>3.</enum><header>Civil damages for unauthorized access or disclosure of certain information</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1106 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1301">42 U.S.C. 1301</external-xref>) is further amended by adding after subsection (h), as added by section 2, the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H02BAB7377EFF4085A858C11B185B3008" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H585602FFEEE848B79566290C6DF1F450"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Civil penalties</header><paragraph id="H930E90767AD740519406DF85B22257F8" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><subparagraph id="H340F548DE27E40208C8788B89C3FC22F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Disclosure or access by employee of United States</header><text>If any officer or employee of the United States negligently discloses or accesses any information that pertains to an individual in violation of any provision of subsection (a) or (h), such individual may bring a civil action for damages against the United States in a district court of the United States.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2AC023F508234EB5A2935B21672189A7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Disclosure or access by a person who is not an employee of United States</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If any person who is not an officer or employee of the United States negligently discloses or accesses any information that pertains to an individual in violation of any provision of subsection (a) or (h), such individual may bring a civil action for damages against such person in a district court of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H376174598D8A4CE88917272780BA6DAC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No liability shall arise under this section with respect to any disclosure or access—</text><subparagraph id="H1AE62CE6B2A8413BAB7E6D74FD924D55"><enum>(A)</enum><text>which results from a good faith, but erroneous, interpretation of subsection (a) or (h); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H75B1D8C00B1D4604BAE959A5EAEC3686"><enum>(B)</enum><text>which is requested by the individual.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3C4E4006380F48BCBFFC51DEC8CB49A0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Damages</header><text>In any action brought under paragraph (1), upon a finding of liability on the part of the defendant, the defendant shall be liable to the plaintiff in an amount equal to the sum of—</text><subparagraph id="H3C667DE35EE9424DAB980812C8D68C8C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the greater of—</text><clause id="HA05ABFCAE12044EEADBCED05CD45FB4A"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$5,000 for each act of unauthorized access or disclosure with respect to which such defendant is found liable; or</text></clause><clause id="HB742732184A34A0A8BA72380ED67110E" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the sum of—</text><subclause id="HFD15E0E1330E4E9D9A24E0403EAE9D56" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the actual damages sustained by the plaintiff as a result of such unauthorized access or disclosure, plus</text></subclause><subclause id="H68F4F418BA4146658A5A313BDCF9F41B" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a willful access or disclosure or an access or disclosure which is the result of gross negligence, punitive damages, plus</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H33242EBC6C6A4BB9B4793981ACD55A4B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the costs of the action, plus</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6EEECAB9D0814775955CCE273F467B0B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>reasonable attorneys fees, except that if the defendant is the United States, reasonable attorneys fees may be awarded only if the plaintiff is the prevailing party.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8F8E6C6A9CF246719FB63CF14F934F8D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Period for bringing action</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, an action to enforce any liability created under this section may be brought, without regard to the amount in controversy, at any time within 2 years after the date of discovery by the plaintiff of the unauthorized disclosure or access.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H810612D96973436BB5E17BA463AFA8DF"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Notification of unlawful disclosure or access</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If any person is criminally charged by indictment or information with disclosing or accessing any information that pertains to an individual in violation of subsection (a) or (h), the Commissioner of Social Security shall notify such individual as soon as practicable of such disclosure or access. The Commissioner shall also notify such individual if a Federal or State agency (upon notice to the Commissioner by such Federal or State agency) proposes an administrative determination as to disciplinary or adverse action against an employee arising from the employee’s unauthorized disclosure or access of the individual’s information. The notice described in this subsection shall include the date of the unauthorized disclosure or access and the rights of the individual under such administrative determination.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H07836A1173424C32B3CD8ADC77D3DA9B"><enum>4.</enum><header>Investigations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1106 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1301">42 U.S.C. 1301</external-xref>) is further amended by adding after subsection (i), as added by section 3, the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H72FD8DB177644934BE8CCB6B86D07F63" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H76AB82BCA8AC4B5283EC7048968B7D0C"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Investigation and report</header><paragraph id="H2B7FCC9AE4E34514A4E7F96FB9965980"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Investigation</header><text>The Inspector General of the Social Security Administration shall investigate each disclosure in violation of subsection (a) and each access of a beneficiary data system in violation of subsection (h).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0FCABCDE63C94F319B61176BBB094B33"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Treatment of disclosure or access</header><text>For the purposes of this subsection, the Inspector General may, if the Inspector General determines appropriate, treat a series of violations of subsection (a) or (h) as a single violation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H637B68F6E78648A2B173205F997619FB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the Inspector General becomes aware of a violation of subsection (a) or (h), the Inspector General shall submit to Congress a report on such violation, which shall include—</text><subparagraph id="HD7354AC1438140148684205C8CECCE6E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a detailed description of the violation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H137E912914444178A4FB9A3FBA006405"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a risk assessment of any threat to the privacy of any individual whose information was disclosed or accessed, national security, cybersecurity, or the integrity of the applicable beneficiary data system as a result of the violation; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAE884CB3C112479AB204AB49724BA974"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a detailed description of any stopped payment during the unauthorized use or access.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H772893DDD50346CEB6AF935C560A47E9"><enum>5.</enum><header>Privacy regulations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding this Act and the amendments made by this Act, part 401 of title 20 of the Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on January 19, 2025, shall have the force and effect of law.</text></section><section id="HB3ED759655064DC7A1422F3D72EE1D31"><enum>6.</enum><header>GAO study and interim reports</header><subsection id="HAC1A21D732F445F4BBE2AA9E2A2B8BCF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller of the United States shall submit to the Committee on Finance of the Senate and the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives a report including the following information:</text><paragraph id="H54702C0FB6BA442D8FB23AE68C92BB55"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The results of a study on the effects of the changes made to section 1106 of the Social Security Act by this Act, and by any subsequent Acts.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H161DA0C8E3C947C09FD50C83B5A6B868"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A summary of any investigations conducted under section 1106(i).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1236DDCCEE4D41B8A34BFE288FA7C897"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Any convictions under section 1106(a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA38DE38A597D42F594A6E0A3633783E2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Any civil actions brought under section 1106(j), including the results of such civil action.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC50DCCA178A94C18A546F8FE268D1C29"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Interim reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 month after the date of enactment of this Act, and monthly thereafter until such time as the report required under subsection (a) is submitted, the Comptroller of the United States shall submit to the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate an interim report on the information required under subsection (a), including the status of the study described in paragraph (1) of such subsection.</text></subsection></section><section id="HB91604BF2F4A410085EE2FE1BA195F5A"><enum>7.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The amendments made by sections 2, 3, and 4 of this Act shall apply to violations of section 1106 of the Social Security Act occurring on or after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

