<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD8C869A6FD5C4522878167890B324C30" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1352 IH: To designate the General George C. Marshall House, in the Commonwealth of Virginia, as an affiliated area of the National Park System, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1352</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250213">February 13, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001230">Mr. Subramanyam</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To designate the General George C. Marshall House, in the Commonwealth of Virginia, as an affiliated area of the National Park System, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HDABC8300D3BA412ABD9FCE5D2974994D" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H5A54B78F05554D7C85C1304D7D2E350C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Establishment of the General George C. Marshall House as an affiliated area</header>
<subsection id="HCFC800454A294C4C889CFC9DEA2DF5CC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The General George C. Marshall House, in the Commonwealth of Virginia, is established as an affiliated area of the National Park System.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H3FC2A2A6F954466D962FBD37A13BF7A8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Description of affiliated area</header><text>The affiliated area shall consist of the area generally depicted as the <quote>General George C. Marshall House Property, Leesburg, Virginia</quote> on the map titled <quote>General George C. Marshall House, Proposed Affiliated Area</quote>, numbered 999/189,974, and dated September 2023.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H20400D17CAE54F1A902FBFC9CB4B615C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>The affiliated area shall be managed in a manner consistent with—</text> <paragraph id="H3179376C95C549AF8492C99328FEEB09"><enum>(1)</enum><text>this Act; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H11AD64B4117C411F8548BD1D7DFED8E7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any law generally applicable to units of the National Park System.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H56782E70BFDA4CDFA47B9F98B207E462"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Management entity</header><text>The George C. Marshall International Center shall be the management entity for the affiliated area.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H65E21A6EB8164884811C721F2170A3C2"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Agreements</header><text>The Secretary of the Interior (referred to in this section as the <quote>Secretary</quote>)—</text> <paragraph id="H5C1F473C7B994BFD8051B51CFB1C2618"><enum>(1)</enum><text>may provide technical assistance and enter into cooperative agreements with the management entity for the purpose of providing financial assistance for the marketing, marking, interpretation, and preservation of the affiliated area; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB5EB5FBAC8A8475C922EEB396BA093E2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall enter into an agreement with the management entity that delineates the roles and responsibilities for the management of the area consistent with the policies and standards that apply to units of the National Park System.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE4572E3237C04658A1D9EBE3A4D3501D"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Limited role of the secretary</header><text>Nothing in this Act authorizes the Secretary to acquire property at the affiliated area or to assume managerial or financial responsibility for the operation, maintenance, or management of the affiliated area.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H8DAAAE5207EB44F89A5C1979EC2795F0"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Private property protection</header><text>Nothing in this Act affects the land use rights of private property owners adjacent to the General George C. Marshall House.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H43BAE1750B5E41CE958E83251C50FE49"><enum>(h)</enum><header>No buffer zones</header> <paragraph id="H66817A304008444889EC49D4ABC42496"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to create buffer zones outside of the General George C. Marshall House.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H33D508A8C24C47B89C97E608B2995338"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Activity or use outside the general george c. marshall house</header><text>The fact that an activity or use can be seen, heard, or detected from within the George C. Marshall House shall not preclude, limit, control, regulate, or determine the conduct or management of activities or uses outside of the George C. Marshall House.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

