<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA0550C80AAC048B498D79C7FFFE9F2DC" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2640 IH: Brian Tally VA Employment Transparency Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2640</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20250403">April 3, 2025</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000603">Mr. Luttrell</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to ensure that certain health care contractors of the Department of Veterans Affairs are subject to Federal tort claims laws, to improve the accountability of physicians of the Department, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="HFA5036712B6340348058ECAAA52C0C87" style="OLC">
<section id="HFD85488FC7BB4902B5AC0B52F7172654" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Brian Tally VA Employment Transparency Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H9B6505A222AF44AF98FF1255A8C8FF6C" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Accountability of health care providers at facilities of the Department of Veterans Affairs</header> <subsection id="H80D14B73D3B1455C90E2076117C7F400"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Treatment of contractors under Federal tort claims laws</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 7316 of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9BA08D1C53D04FC886FDBC9168C61593" style="USC">
<subsection id="HA204CC6BFD864500B9571767EEE624E7"><enum>(g)</enum>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HB3F581CCCA5F4B558BF2623EE5B7E583"><enum>(1)</enum>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HC6AB8EC1327F4C4E87EAE31A4ADF9BE7"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section shall not apply with respect to civil actions or other proceedings brought by an individual, or the estate of an individual, for damages for personal injury, including death, allegedly arising from the malpractice or negligence of a non-Department provider in the course of providing hospital care, medical services, or nursing home care at a facility of the Department, if the Secretary provides to the individual, or the estate of the individual, by not later than 45 days after the Secretary receives notice of the civil action or other proceeding, the information referred to in subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFEC79FAD2401420CA3AF95FE51745D6C" indent="up2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The information referred to in this subparagraph is the following:</text>
<clause id="HD51E3B1B83224AF392182027DA3F659F"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of the extent of the involvement of the non-Department provider in the hospital care, medical services, or nursing home care furnished to the individual.</text></clause> <clause id="H11C14D86B9CE4265B878AAB7BBCE9679"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The nature of such care or services furnished to the individual by the non-Department provider.</text></clause>
<clause id="HA632ECDC60D84348963CB1F9A8C7D73F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The full name of the non-Department provider.</text></clause> <clause commented="no" id="H066414DA548B4CCE993F2766CAFF3BD8"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The fact that the notification is made pursuant to this paragraph.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HFF065976AA654D3EB6768F19B027A5FD" indent="up2"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A civil action or other proceeding arising from an incident of alleged malpractice or negligence of a non-Department provider may not be brought in both a State court and in a Federal court.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE7F10DD5901A497AB2A2E68B213B6614" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H1AB0CB983A7F48FF82FC443E2689149F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>If five or more separate covered cases brought during a five-year period include allegations of malpractice or negligence on the part of any individual non-Department provider, the Secretary—</text>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE7E6BE4AE8E349C5AE70FB17BC7CB70F" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall revoke the provider’s authorization to provide hospital care, medical services, or nursing home care at a facility of the Department; and</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA85F9580B1244B56A68750832F137086" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may not enter into any contract or agreement that authorizes the provider to provide such care or services at a facility of the Department.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H2674238489B84FD68840EB69E5409A78" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Secretary shall establish a process by which a non-Department provider may appeal an action under subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA99C6F4EFEB6470F9EBA22873D7A25FE" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In this subsection:</text>
<subparagraph id="HEAF689FD07034185ADB70145F643CA4E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The term <term>covered case</term> means any of the following:</text> <clause id="HCE7247CBE7034293A408B593DE5184D8"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A civil action or proceeding pursuant to this section that resulted in a judgment against the United States, or such an action or proceeding that the United States compromises or settles.</text></clause>
<clause display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H33F5ADA7B6A945B9897B40A42ABBC7DB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A civil action or proceeding pursuant to State law for personal injury, including death, allegedly arising from malpractice or negligence that resulted in a judgment against a non-Department provider, or such an action or proceeding that the non-Department provider compromises or settles.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6EFB5E784EAC417CA614FD0618001ED6"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>non-Department provider</term>—</text>
<clause id="HEE13D60548414217B35B495EEC5AAF80"><enum>(i)</enum><text>means a health care provider who is not an employee of the Federal Government but who is authorized by the Secretary to provide health care or treatment at a facility of the Department pursuant to a contract or other agreement; and</text></clause> <clause id="H49BF900FB1474CAEB350736A6AA375A0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>does not include a provider through which the Secretary furnishes care or services under section 1703 of this title.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection>
<subsection id="H8A9722263126481E8502C61EA21E4692"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Notifications and outreach regarding Federal tort claims</header><text>Such section, as amended by subsection (a), is further amended by adding at the end the following new subsections:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDA48D3D09A9C41D0A8C610DBDF3A892C" style="USC"> <subsection id="HCC5CB6CE99A242E5B0139693090E4AEE"><enum>(h)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days following the date on which a judgment is entered against the United States in a civil action or proceeding pursuant to this section that includes a conclusion that a non-Department employee committed negligence or malpractice, the Secretary shall notify the following entities with respect to such judgment:</text>
<paragraph id="HAF928BD8B1594369931FB11C5F3F6DDC"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The appropriate licensing entity of each State in which such non-Department employee is licensed as a health care professional.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H288B1F00F6174F5C926C68BEDB89DDFE"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The National Practitioner Data Bank established pursuant to the Health Care Quality Improvement Act of 1986 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/11101">42 U.S.C. 11101 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HE481E060E6AA423BBA465030C14EE1E5"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall publish in a clear and conspicuous manner on the internet website of the Department an explanation of the rights of an individual under this section, including—</text> <paragraph id="H4BD29384F0E44FD29289CC11F9930229"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an explanation of the procedure to file an administrative claim pursuant to section 515 of this title or section 2675 of title 28;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7ACFEFD9C90748368924205878830106"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the circumstances under which an individual may file a civil action or proceeding pursuant to this section; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H73C3EF6F380E4179A78F015706D7DF8E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>time limits that can bar recovery under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection>
<subsection id="HE7D5355957744E4EBA186109FA739351"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Accountability of physicians of the Department</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 7461 of such title is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H3E495C2B66B24916BB1FD296838D12EC"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (a)—</text>
<subparagraph id="HE817DC6C3A094D9099E76864E3E3CBFA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>(1)</quote> before <quote>Whenever</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5029CA80F7384FB9BAFAF39D26BF6983"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
<quoted-block style="USC" id="H2C9A758BAA934720953654888B31A4B0" display-inline="no-display-inline">
<paragraph id="H713E2F0A6E984EA49E98C61FB6EF8F41" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Under Secretary shall bring charges under paragraph (1) based on professional conduct or competence against a section 7401(1) employee who is accused of committing negligence or malpractice in three or more separate civil actions or proceedings pursuant to section 7316 of this title within a five-year period if such actions or proceedings—</text> <subparagraph id="H3EC75759B2D4406FA229829C7812DB50"><enum>(A)</enum><text>resulted in a judgment against the United States; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H1615FB386A024FBDAF87569D0E7971E1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>were compromised or settled by the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8CD0212A96724890A42E3ED849BE6840"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (c)(3), by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text>
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H48168D2220054DB09F4A85A4F04AC0A6" style="USC">
<subparagraph id="H51567AC678C645F3AF227EC6E14C2954"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The provision of care subject to a civil action or proceeding pursuant to section 7316 of this title that—</text> <clause id="HA9D75619EEAB46C9A424C2EE32BB2947"><enum>(i)</enum><text>resulted in a judgment against the United States; or</text></clause>
<clause id="H36B37C49624B43CF8C5966474431E8B4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is compromised or settled by the United States.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="HDDA5BBDF728F4AB98A04A762D4F48086"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall take effect with respect to actions or omissions covered under section 7316 of title 38, United States Code, occurring on or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section>
</legis-body>
</bill> 


