<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-BUR25314-6M0-7J-L3G"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1180 IS: Abolish TSA Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1180</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250327">March 27, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S346">Mr. Lee</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S412">Mr. Tuberville</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To abolish the Transportation Security Administration, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Abolish TSA Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4ec1bdd37d934ea1b0a93f0c02780acd"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida2de5aa8b8c340a1a013aa4ffca4e71e"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Administration</header><text>The term <term>Administration</term> means the Transportation Security Administration.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfa461cf3602543eda8c36ab4d2dee080"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idadbca353980b4d9a936adf5436bd5dba"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8e71e1381abe413399fbe4cf311e06ed"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id48e412f3f3384b3ba40f21f118ac690b" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Homeland Security and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5ea98bff91144e1ea21f6c9af8ad4930"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Homeland Security. </text></paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id529bd248a470452f92bff3711e9bc83d"><enum>3.</enum><header>Policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It shall be the policy of the Secretary—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd54a0276bc9945ad8902d37343a434b0"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to expeditiously eliminate or transfer all authorities, enforcement functions, and programs of the Administration; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id79de8d5059be4d858d73ab1243c0cf5e"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to privatize all commercial airport security to increase cost-efficiency and security.</text></paragraph></section><section id="id6b9dfe10cc024f668a823aff21ec3de1"><enum>4.</enum><header>Termination of the Transportation Security Administration</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">On the date that is 3 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administration shall be abolished, and any program for which the Administrator has administrative responsibility as provided by law or by delegation of authority pursuant to law is repealed. </text></section><section id="id8625baa60680472dbb84b02dd12b64c8"><enum>5.</enum><header>Reorganization plan</header><subsection id="idfa20af5eb0844c5eba82af79e5468499"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall, in consultation with the Secretary of Transportation, submit to Congress a reorganization plan for the Administration.</text></subsection><subsection id="id87274e6e84a54e82b0134f81a27e47ed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The plan required by subsection (a) shall include the following:</text><paragraph id="id3e51e74964d94ec1bf6efa837ce3884d"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A plan for the establishment of the Office of Aviation Security Oversight within the Federal Aviation Administration, which shall—</text><subparagraph id="id2e9a3695d501498e930c6fd5c838f9f4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be headed by a Director; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2f4c3101b140466890d4841b3cb59183"><enum>(B)</enum><text>be responsible for the oversight and regulation of all aviation security activities described in section 44920 of title 49, United States Code, except that no employee of the Office shall conduct airport screening services.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id08ab00b991d045b7be50f539799faf5e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A plan for the rapid transfer of all aviation security activities and equipment to qualified private screening companies described in section 44920 of title 49, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddb49145e32764ea386b1a1cae904cbe3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A description of any necessary changes, as the Secretary determines, to the program described in section 44920 of title 49, United States Code;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3ea59f6cab294a8582f03f84241b1f40"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Subject to paragraph (2), a plan for proportional reductions of operations and personnel until the transfer is complete and no operations of personnel of the Administration remain.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide0500315665f4696a6025f73b2922649"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A plan to transfer to the Department of Transportation any functions, personnel, assets, and liabilities of the Administration with respect to surface transportation, including activities relating to mass transit, freight rail, highway motor carriers, and pipelines.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idad6d933fcd124101a2b2a7488dea730a"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exclusions</header><text>The plan may not include—</text><paragraph id="id11cbb4d28d06465e877e88c09a718ce4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any agency requirement or regulation compelling private contractors conducting airport security screening services to conduct warrantless searches and seizures; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id64f62e2f12e84ff292861cb4705d4579"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an extension of the deadline in section 4. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id2aee0b6021d74152ab84441950b615a8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Periodic reports</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc976b95fa7ff46fe87190a136b2f772a"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and every 30 days thereafter, the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Transportation, shall submit a report to the Comptroller General of the United States and the appropriate congressional committees on the progress of compliance with this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id784c6f61c9bc481993cbc14eb669c9c7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>GAO Report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, and every 180 days thereafter, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report detailing the compliance of the Secretary with this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id088aebdc269f4dffa8b9867a6eee8025"><enum>6.</enum><header>Congressional review of reorganization plan</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4896fbc4d66f4a5ebb216a33f241c7f1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Joint resolution of approval defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>joint resolution of approval</term> means only a joint resolution of either House of Congress—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id55cf2b9dd6ea4e349647051b2b518c23"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the title of which is as follows: <quote>A joint resolution approving the Secretary of Homeland Security’s reorganization plan for the Transportation Security Administration.</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd81168d52cea4408aaaf6f4c722547a9"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the matter after the resolving clause of which is the following: <quote>Congress approves the reorganization plan submitted by the Secretary of Homeland Security to Congress in accordance with section 5 of the <short-title>Abolish TSA Act of 2025</short-title> on ___ relating to___</quote>, with the first blank space being filled with the appropriate date and the second blank space being filled with a detailed description of the proposed reorganization plan required by section 5, including any amendments made by Congress.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id1ed792b32f1347e48efc5032bfc006fa"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Introduction and reference of resolution</header><text>Not later than the first session day following the date on a which a reorganization plan is transmitted to the House of Representatives and the Senate under section 5, a joint resolution of approval shall be introduced by a member of the House or Senate.</text></subsection><subsection id="idc42709ecb7c24eedb4f56eeabea425c5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consideration in the House of Representatives</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2692612ae3d84dd9921bb0ba367eac86"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Committee referral</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A joint resolution of approval shall be referred to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb8a3d4bac9fe426f9867945f6a4633b5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Floor consideration in House of Representatives</header><text>If the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives has not reported the joint resolution within 75 continuous session days after the date of referral, that committee shall be discharged from further consideration of the joint resolution. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ida34c2f7fe85f455792c69f1943809341"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Consideration in the Senate</header><paragraph id="id8eb8e31f2ce942cfba29da9d3d9cac3e"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Committee referral</header><text>A joint resolution of approval introduced in the Senate shall be referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8a72aca1e1884b208406f2cae4837870"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reporting and discharge</header><text>If the committee to which a joint resolution of approval was referred has not reported the joint resolution within 75 continuous session days after the date of referral of the joint resolution, that committee shall be discharged from further consideration of the joint resolution and the joint resolution shall be placed on the appropriate calendar.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5270447942304f8cb90898794795005e"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Proceeding to consideration</header><text>Notwithstanding Rule XXII of the Standing Rules of the Senate, it is in order at any time after the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation reports a joint resolution of approval to the Senate or has been discharged from consideration of such a joint resolution (even though a previous motion to the same effect has been disagreed to) to move to proceed to the consideration of the joint resolution, and all points of order against the joint resolution (and against consideration of the joint resolution) are waived. The motion to proceed is not debatable. The motion is not subject to a motion to postpone. A motion to reconsider the vote by which the motion is agreed to or disagreed to shall not be in order.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide4047c0c7bf54ea5ab92e955534cb8f2"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Rulings of the chair on procedure</header><text>Appeals from the decisions of the Chair relating to the application of the rules of the Senate, as the case may be, to the procedure relating to a joint resolution of approval shall be decided without debate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5832835bb6c548fd9879fee0fb9ac386"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Consideration of veto messages</header><text>Debate in the Senate of any veto message with respect to a joint resolution of approval, including all debatable motions and appeals in connection with the joint resolution, shall be limited to 10 hours, to be equally divided between, and controlled by, the majority leader and the minority leader or their designees.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id967556b2570243e08078434c56d24d1f"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Rules relating to Senate and House of Representatives</header><paragraph id="id88a7d7ae173a4b89860fef74a6a339d5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Treatment of Senate joint resolution in House</header><text>In the House of Representatives, the following procedures shall apply to a joint resolution of approval received from the Senate (unless the House has already passed a joint resolution relating to the same proposed action):</text><subparagraph id="idb9b27d6a76b149308b2cf1cdb118cb24"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The joint resolution shall be referred to the appropriate committee.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idcf4403a2ac224f5883036093e71c35d4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>If a committee to which a joint resolution has been referred has not reported the joint resolution within 5 legislative days after the date of referral, that committee shall be discharged from further consideration of the joint resolution.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6f0e605758804e8f8c125f1d7546657f"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Beginning on the third legislative day after each committee to which a joint resolution has been referred reports the joint resolution to the House or has been discharged from further consideration thereof, it shall be in order to move to proceed to consider the joint resolution in the House. All points of order against the motion are waived. Such a motion shall not be in order after the House has disposed of a motion to proceed on the joint resolution. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the motion to its adoption without intervening motion. The motion shall not be debatable. A motion to reconsider the vote by which the motion is disposed of shall not be in order.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id09e64659c75644b98491c2d6a5e2a3ab"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The joint resolution shall be considered as read. All points of order against the joint resolution and against its consideration are waived. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the joint resolution to final passage without intervening motion except 2 hours of debate equally divided and controlled by the sponsor of the joint resolution (or a designee) and an opponent. A motion to reconsider the vote on passage of the joint resolution shall not be in order.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="iddd9c124d78c74eb5975dc7e42c06265a"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Treatment of House joint resolution in Senate</header><subparagraph id="idd8f60cd5d9df4ff1a2b45411006bb0c6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Receipt before passage</header><text>If, before the passage by the Senate of a joint resolution of approval, the Senate receives an identical joint resolution from the House of Representatives, the following procedures shall apply:</text><clause id="id035d7a6989324283bde16a87509ccc1c"><enum>(i)</enum><text>That joint resolution shall not be referred to a committee.</text></clause><clause id="id1111b6130caf45db8c7ef8c9a7304280"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>With respect to that joint resolution—</text><subclause id="id589c5bb26b614c50a1f7497194780ad6"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the procedure in the Senate shall be the same as if no joint resolution had been received from the House of Representatives; but</text></subclause><subclause id="id648a6a51e871462e9219fd4e3f8b2abc"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the vote on passage shall be on the joint resolution from the House of Representatives.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1c4acd887de94b1289ea2ed0025c22c5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Receipt after passage</header><text>If, following passage of a joint resolution of approval in the Senate, the Senate receives an identical joint resolution from the House of Representatives, that joint resolution shall be placed on the appropriate Senate calendar.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8c50a9d7e6e94d13aca22c9fee772ae9"><enum>(C)</enum><header>No companion measure</header><text>If a joint resolution of approval is received from the House, and no companion joint resolution has been introduced in the Senate, the Senate procedures under this subsection shall apply to the House joint resolution.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idaaafde17ea32447ebf862e5d836a92f1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Application to revenue measures</header><text>The provisions of this paragraph shall not apply in the House of Representatives to a joint resolution of approval that is a revenue measure.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id33b8263ef92e4c209a1c7b8855613a38"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Rules of House of Representatives and Senate</header><text>This section is enacted by Congress—</text><paragraph id="ide7d4aa37433e4b07be763b7ec215fe1d"><enum>(1)</enum><text>as an exercise of the rulemaking power of the Senate and the House of Representatives, respectively, and as such is deemed a part of the rules of each House, respectively, and supersedes other rules only to the extent that it is inconsistent with such rules; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7474a57791fb442eb9527bdf9be6cfe4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>with full recognition of the constitutional right of either House to change the rules (so far as relating to the procedure of that House) at any time, in the same manner, and to the same extent as in the case of any other rule of that House. </text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

