<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" slc-id="S1-NEW25673-MCT-2Y-3DY"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 271 IS: Commemorating June 11, 2025, as “World Franchise Day”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code>III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 271</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250611">June 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S419">Mr. Mullin</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Commemorating June 11, 2025, as <quote>World Franchise
 Day</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the World Franchise Council, which consists of over 40 national franchise associations from around the world, recently established June 11 every year as World Franchise Day;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas franchising has served as a core business model in the United States for decades and has empowered aspiring entrepreneurs of all backgrounds to launch and operate independent businesses under the brand and operational guidance of an established company;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, through the business format of franchising, hundreds of thousands of entrepreneurs have achieved the American Dream of business ownership;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas franchising has contributed to robust job creation and provided foundational skills development to millions of workers in every community in which a franchise exists;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas franchising has its roots in 1731 with Benjamin Franklin, who is credited with founding the first commercial franchise system in the Americas due to his efforts expanding his printing business by agreeing to partnerships with his workers to run their own printing shops;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas franchising further took hold in the mid-19th century as Isaac Singer, who revolutionized the sewing machine industry, developed a franchise system to distribute and repair his machines, setting the stage for a model that would soon spread to other industries;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, as of 2025, franchising is a proven business growth strategy used in over 200 industries, including childhood education centers, action parks, spas, hardware stores, health care laboratories, home remodeling and repair services, salons, campgrounds, hotels, fitness clubs, auto shops, pet stores, tax preparation offices, restaurants, and more;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas franchising offers a unique entrepreneurial opportunity to minorities, veterans, and all aspiring entrepreneurs, with nearly a 26-percent minority ownership rate, and 14-percent veteran ownership rate;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas franchising in the United States consists of 830,876 franchise establishments that support nearly 8,800,000 direct jobs, $896,900,000,000 in economic output for the economy, and contributes almost 3 percent of the gross domestic product; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas franchising is set to continue to serve as a vital business growth model for opportunity, entrepreneurism, job creation, and career skills development in communities throughout the United States and the world: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="S1"><text>That the Senate commemorates June 11, 2025, as <quote>World Franchise Day</quote>.</text></section></resolution-body></resolution>


