<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD9C3B9918EF04FB0918716322F038314" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3577 IH: Eliminate Non-approved Devices and Contraband Electronics Limiting Links to Society Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3577</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250523">May 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001257">Mr. Bilirakis</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001306">Mr. Balderson</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to provide for additional prohibitions and enhanced penalties for providing or possessing wireless communications devices in detention facilities, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD87B84AB78704F83A07C37BC0EA84EB4" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HE6157DCF01E2475E90D96D250705C9A2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Eliminate Non-approved Devices and Contraband Electronics Limiting Links to Society Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>END CELLS Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H0737DFE28D1B43AF9F1F8A9E73FA7BFD"><enum>2.</enum><header>Amendment to Communications Act of 1934</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title V of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/501">47 U.S.C. 501 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H0565C35563464227A8DF6A94B2478DC0" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="H2E4405097A974F249A1B07B1D747B860"><enum>512.</enum><header>Providing or possessing wireless communications devices in detention facilities</header> 
<subsection id="H4EBE2356E03442C396952039F59DB8EB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibited acts</header><text>It shall be unlawful for any person—</text> <paragraph id="H6AF243F58B364D79B11AE2DF41CD8F38"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in violation of any Federal or State statute or rule, or order issued under such statute or rule, to provide or attempt to provide to a person held in a detention facility a wireless communications device;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCC78AF352DBC4853AA501F591D818D7F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to willfully and knowingly facilitate the introduction, in violation of any Federal or State statute or rule, or order issued under such statute or rule, of a wireless communications device into a detention facility; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H61EA12F28CCB4D3EA293D4545D5A832F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>being a person held in a detention facility, to possess or obtain, or attempt to obtain, a wireless communications device in violation of a Federal or State statute or rule, or order issued under such statute or rule.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB1AB036601DF420FA389D5F6F785F602"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Penalties</header> 
<paragraph id="H9342AD7199E246B9A374BEC507CA186B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Civil forfeiture</header> 
<subparagraph id="HE1DC9025569A42699E8CC1BB470CD4D9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Amount</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding paragraph (2) of section 503(b), the amount of any forfeiture penalty determined or imposed under such section for a violation of subsection (a) shall not exceed $50,000 for each violation or each day of a continuing violation, except that the amount assessed for any continuing violation shall not exceed a total of $1,000,000 for any single act or failure to act.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H63F532B4F29E4B50890A9E2AB548996E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>No citation required</header><text>Paragraph (5) of section 503(b) shall not apply in the case of a violation of subsection (a).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE7562F05A1424D5A9599C543A6C1C0C0"><enum>(C)</enum><header>2-year statute of limitations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding paragraph (6) of section 503(b), no forfeiture penalty for violation of subsection (a) shall be determined or imposed against any person if the violation charged occurred more than 2 years prior to the date of issuance of the notice required by paragraph (3) of section 503(b) or the notice of apparent liability required by paragraph (4) of section 503(b) (as the case may be).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFC93C45C9A7B4CD2BE58E21A70882062"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Criminal fine</header><text>Any person who willfully and knowingly violates subsection (a) shall upon conviction thereof be fined not more than $50,000 for each violation, in lieu of the fine provided by section 501 for such a violation. Nothing in this section shall be construed to supersede the provisions of section 501 relating to imprisonment or the imposition of a penalty of both fine and imprisonment.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H520BEA340A214BE691265BE93455B362"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effect on other laws</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to—</text> <paragraph id="HF00463688F6F4DE09CFD8FB1577F9C5C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>prohibit any lawfully authorized investigative, protective, or intelligence activity of a law enforcement agency of the United States, a State, or a political subdivision of a State, or of an intelligence agency of the United States; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBE009B0CC567490F9AF526BB8212554A" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>prevent the chief legal officer, or any other officer, of a State from exercising the powers conferred on such officer by the laws of such State to enforce State law, including punishing those found guilty of violating State law.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H52EE6667387C4FB784766FCBCF60142F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H57DF5570955346078F6927410B6D6F70"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Detention facility</header><text>The term <quote>detention facility</quote> means a correctional, detention, or penal facility located within the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H81B09EFB233D4C37A89436371D8EF030" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Wireless communications device</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>wireless communications device</quote> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE01BC0CD21B44951AAF7A7C5ED102837" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a device that enables the user to send or receive a radio communication, regardless of whether a license from the Commission is required for the use or operation of such device; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2CE2AE36A7F24808BCC1D0DAF80A20F9" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a component that provides identification or authentication to enable a device described in subparagraph (A) to connect to a communications network.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
<section id="H9B58B2CB88824464A3CB71BF1AB9E5D6" commented="no"><enum>3.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The amendment made by this Act shall apply with respect to conduct that occurs after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></section> </legis-body></bill>

