<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H970C9AB74A544B24A938B9BA14094918" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3948 IH: Offshore Pipeline Safety Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3948</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250612">June 12, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Bureau of Safety and Environmental Enforcement to further develop, finalize, and implement updated regulations for offshore oil and gas pipelines to address long-standing limitations regarding its ability to ensure active pipeline integrity and address safety and environmental risks associated with decommissioning, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H67B3C95F650743FDA36D63041DDD0254" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H20A0862B6E4D4411BDF026296112129C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Offshore Pipeline Safety Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HFBC98354541B4BF789DE927DA15A3BB7"><enum>2.</enum><header>Finalization of regulations related to offshore pipelines</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the Bureau of Safety and Environmental Enforcement, shall issue final regulations relating to Oil and Gas and Sulphur Operations in the Outer Continental Shelf—Pipelines and Pipeline Rights-of-Way (72 Fed. Reg. 56,442 (Oct. 3, 2007)). Such regulations shall require owners of oil and gas pipelines subject to such regulations—</text>
<paragraph id="H07250DD89E4E4B61BA61AA4BA44FAE16" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to provide for internal and external inspections of pipelines by a third-party no less frequently than every two years, unless the Director of the Bureau determines that any such inspection is not required; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB3DF6160B1B64F9B85E518C2E0A98848"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to equip such pipelines with a leak detection system or device that provides continuous volumetric comparison between the pipeline’s product input and output and includes alarms and adequate sensitivity to detect variations between input and discharge volumes to enable any leaks from the pipeline to be detected as quickly as possible.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="HA642E78A27C7498E9A45080243CC2EF9"><enum>3.</enum><header>Addressing environmental risks of decommissioning pipelines</header>
<subsection id="H6C3A1CA49A214501B5B73382A8B1CBE3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study on environmental risks of decommissioning pipelines versus removing pipelines</header>
<paragraph id="H9B08EC86ED774218A8D335C9282EF551"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Directors of the Bureau of Safety and Environmental Enforcement and the Bureau of Ocean Energy Management shall jointly conduct a study to evaluate the environmental benefits and risks associated with decommissioning oil and gas pipelines in place on the sea floor compared to removing such pipelines. Such study shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="HB747B26E43A444248AA213B3C30B866E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an evaluation of pipelines that have been decommissioned in place, identifying decommissioned pipelines at high-risk of causing safety and environmental harm, causing obstructions, or otherwise unduly interfering with present or future uses of the outer continental shelf; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H25337B597FD940878BC08D1826A8706B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>recommendations on the best uses of the revenues generated by the annual pipelines fees as authorized by subsection (d).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2521D11ED1694514981BEA15292C2E79"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Directors shall transmit a report to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate, detailing the findings and determinations of the study, including any recommendations for legislation.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H2B1CF3ECE96D4A52ABA12B816D2379DC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Required considerations in reviewing decommissioning applications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In determining whether to permit an owner to decommission an oil or gas pipeline, the Bureau of Safety and Environmental Enforcement, shall fully consider whether the offshore oil and gas pipeline constitutes a hazard to navigation and commercial and recreational fishing operations, unduly interferes with other uses of the outer continental shelf, or has adverse environmental effects.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HB65DC8C3319547FA8929617E2A294081"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Ongoing monitoring of decommissioned pipelines</header><text>The Bureau of Safety and Environmental Enforcement shall continually monitor the condition and location of all oil and gas pipelines that have been decommissioned and remain in place, and shall maintain all relevant records of such monitoring.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H1B0B7DD741164FD7A662273C2C3A6BF3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Annual pipeline owners fee</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 after the date of enactment of this Act, the Bureau of Safety and Environmental Enforcement shall issue regulations to assess an annual fee on owners of offshore oil and gas pipelines for the purpose of providing the Bureau with funds to decommission or remove such pipelines in the event an owner files for bankruptcy. Such fee shall be no less than—</text> <paragraph id="H3B8BF4694A9A46A7B83D37A7E88EF432"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$10,000 per mile for such pipelines in water with a depth of 500 feet or greater; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H296A46E70A004BC5A800B5D3D1F33F5B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$1,000 per mile for pipelines in water depth of under 500 feet.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H42D0CA0ACDC64312A32F1BCD26FBF4FD"><enum>4.</enum><header>Requirement relating to exposed segments of offshore pipelines</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If the Bureau of Safety and Environmental Enforcement identifies any exposed segment of any active or decommissioned pipeline, the Bureau shall either remove the pipeline from the ocean or ensure it is properly decommissioned and does not pose a threat. If a segment of any active pipeline is exposed or shifts, the Bureau shall re-secure such segment to the sea floor.</text></section>
<section id="HA501C1DBE26447DD9CE9243993A2A9CA"><enum>5.</enum><header>Completion of study relating to environment risks of chemical products used in oil and gas operations</header>
<subsection id="HB56E5C738BCC4A7781DD011E5F765B1F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Completion of study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Bureau of Safety and Environmental Enforcement shall complete a study addressing the risks to the environment of chemical products used in oil and gas operations including umbilical lines. In conducting the study, the Bureau shall seek input from chemical suppliers and the oil and gas industry.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H107C270E42EE4332B17424E64B302559"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than two years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Bureau shall transmit a report of the findings and determinations in such study to Congress, including any recommendations for legislation.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="HA6EED5D5054E44E6AD0A8B8A0120E88A" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>6.</enum><header>Effective Date</header>
<subsection id="HF06E45B955D647DA96C85C1EBB29CE61"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No provision of this Act shall take effect without considering whether such action will result in a reduction of reef fish habitat.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

