<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-OLL25056-WCN-66-XP5"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S307 IS: Prison Staff Safety Enhancement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 307</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250129">January 29, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S414">Mr. Ossoff</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To address sexual harassment and sexual assault of Bureau of Prisons staff in prisons, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Prison Staff Safety Enhancement Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idb6845a12ba0341788a4c9d4ba1ceaa0a"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="id6eb6dde88daa4458ad049572106839f1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In 2023, the Office of the Inspector General of the Department of Justice released a report titled <quote>Evaluation of the Federal Bureau of Prisons’ Efforts to Address Sexual Harassment and Sexual Assault Committed by Inmates Toward Staff</quote> (in this section referred to as the <term>Inspector General report</term>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6e5f0bf14c664e3893f0c698c3237e62"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Inspector General report examined all sanctioned inmate sexual incidents in the Bureau of Prisons (in this section referred to as the <term>Bureau</term>) between fiscal years 2015 and 2021, and found that inmate-on-staff sexual harassment and sexual assault is widespread.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8a4ddd957e2743ab9b8dd6b89760dc3e"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Inspector General report further found that the Bureau does not collect adequate data on inmate-on-staff sexual harassment and sexual assault and that, because of the Bureau's inadequate data, the Bureau has not been able to identify the full scope of inmate-on-staff sexual harassment and sexual assault.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb2a2c0d5c0334eb39260d8ee28d59367"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Inspector General report further found that the Bureau does not have systems to evaluate the effectiveness of the Bureau's strategies to mitigate inmate-on-staff sexual harassment and sexual assault.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id920e503a2a514681b92450826b69ab5e"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Inspector General report made recommendations to the Bureau to address the failures in the Bureau's data collection and mitigation efforts, but the Bureau has not implemented these recommendations.</text></paragraph></section><section id="idfb8003b948c34ec08ca1fb27ecb7429c"><enum>3.</enum><header>Addressing sexual harassment and sexual assault of Bureau of Prisons staff</header><subsection id="id80f7687451884225b35e1833b0c839bf"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="id80fbbfeca7374984b6f77d9b9eec9203"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Bureau</header><text>The term <term>Bureau</term> means the Bureau of Prisons.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5f6a59d761d2478593d9afa482b07ebe"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Correctional officer</header><text>The term <term>correctional officer</term> has the meaning given the term in section 4051 of title 18, United States Code. </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8c47855dd5d04e8681b48657649bfdf5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Inspector General</header><text>The term <term>Inspector General</term> means the Inspector General of the Department of Justice.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8336678ba5c14a5fb5a058558a5a71f9"><enum>(4)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Incarcerated individual</header><text>The term <term>incarcerated individual</term> has the meaning given the term <term>prisoner</term> in section 4051 of title 18, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0b9e59b480c944208090a756918c971e"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Sexual assault</header><text>The term <term>sexual assault</term> means an act described in subsection (b), (c), or (d) of section 920 of title 10, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3bced11b9bf94e4b90d00ae528829371"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Sexual harassment</header><text>The term <term>sexual harassment</term> means unwelcome sexual advances, requests for sexual favors, or other verbal or physical conduct of a sexual nature that explicitly or implicitly affect an individual’s employment, unreasonably interfere with an individual’s work performance, or create an intimidating, hostile, or offensive work environment.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id70c8755ec905414b9638c3e065a87e81"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Implementation of recommendations by Bureau</header><paragraph id="idd3d74c1d10794d189eb9617d568e957b"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Bureau shall fully implement each recommendation in the report released by the Inspector General in 2023 titled <quote>Evaluation of the Federal Bureau of Prisons’ Efforts to Address Sexual Harassment and Sexual Assault Committed by Inmates Toward Staff</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id97df5b8542264ed78fdb405c11cb59f0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>If the Bureau has not fully implemented each recommendation referenced in paragraph (1) by the deadline under that paragraph, the Bureau shall submit a report to Congress by that deadline that includes an explanation of the failure to fully implement each recommendation and a detailed timeline for full implementation.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id9bc7bd4b2b57414cb8080c9fc2e0f269"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Data analysis by Inspector General</header><paragraph id="idb80659b6514c46f0a61d1fe42fce9ef2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date as of which the Bureau has fully implemented each recommendation referenced in subsection (b)(1)—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbd35eaf1db4d49939ed2fae473312bb2"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Inspector General shall request from the Bureau, and the Bureau shall provide, updated data on the number and prevalence of sexual harassment and sexual assault incidents perpetrated by incarcerated individuals against a correctional officer or other employee of the Bureau during fiscal years 2022 through 2025;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id125d999cdcde47f5bceefb14ec785275"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Inspector General shall conduct an analysis of the data described in subparagraph (A); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3e6054d1482341c8990b5b9039f1910b"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Inspector General shall provide Congress and the Attorney General with the analysis conducted under subparagraph (B) and any additional recommendations, including analysis of whether the Bureau has taken sufficient steps to identify the prevalence and scope of sexual harassment and sexual assault incidents perpetrated by incarcerated individuals against a correctional officer or other employee of the Bureau and to mitigate such incidents.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idc878592256414b08b38a50265e2f9127"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Analysis of punishments</header><text>The analysis required under paragraph (1)(C) shall include an analysis of punishments for sexual harassment and sexual assault as of the date of enactment of this Act in facilities controlled by the Bureau of Prisons, including data on the use of such punishments during the 5-year period preceding the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id81066a09fe1c4502be122aaa0ba2b373"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rulemaking by Attorney General</header><text>Not later than 1 year after receiving the analysis under subsection (c), the Attorney General shall promulgate a rule adopting national standards for prevention, reduction, and punishment of sexual harassment and sexual assault perpetrated by an incarcerated individual against a correctional officer or other employee of the Bureau.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

