<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H191645AC1BE94F75BE0BEA4ED107F3FC" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 268 IH: Of inquiry requesting the President and directing the Secretary of Defense to transmit information to the House of Representatives relating to certain military activities against the Houthis and information referring or relating to certain laws and certain policies, guidance, instructions, standards, practices, and procedures of the Department of Defense applicable to the control, communication, transmission, or delivery of classified or sensitive information.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 268</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250327">March 27, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000510">Mr. Smith of Washington</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Of inquiry requesting the President and directing the Secretary of Defense to transmit information to the House of Representatives relating to certain military activities against the Houthis and information referring or relating to certain laws and certain policies, guidance, instructions, standards, practices, and procedures of the Department of Defense applicable to the control, communication, transmission, or delivery of classified or sensitive information.</official-title></form><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HB5E1592AFFE348F8B75EB697F546CF3C"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H427FB172546949A3915F3A33C831F3CC"><enum/><text>That the President is requested, and the Secretary of Defense is directed, to transmit to the House of Representatives, not later than 14 days after the date of the adoption of this resolution, any information, including, but not limited to, copies of any document, record, telephone record, recording, memo, transcript, map, chart, table, graph, log, calendar, notation, minute, message, correspondence, email, text, chat, electronic communication, or any other form of communication, or any portion of any communication in the possession of the President or the Department of Defense that refers to, or relates to, the military activities against the Houthis that occurred on or about March 15, 2025, or that refers to, or relates to, any policy, guidance, instruction, standard, practice, or procedure of the Department of Defense, or any law, that has been applicable to the control, communication, transmission, or delivery of classified or other sensitive information at any time since January 20, 2025.</text></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

