<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H18641E7F6BC74CEE8269454630287C54" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2457 IH: Technology Grants to Strengthen Domestic Mining Education Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2457</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250327">March 27, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="O000086">Mr. Owens</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001228">Ms. Maloy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000620">Ms. Pettersen</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001213">Mr. Moore of Utah</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Energy to provide technology grants to strengthen domestic mining education, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE785FCB384F647D4A7D24514FA33BCC0" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H9E6B1C4D95204D9DA1532D11945C8BCB" section-type="section-one" commented="no"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Technology Grants to Strengthen Domestic Mining Education Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Mining Schools Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HC828BDE8E8C0499A8828718CE0996F73"><enum>2.</enum><header>Technology grants to strengthen domestic mining education</header> <subsection id="HE24C0D4A61354EE99E159009817230D4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H6C0D060E6A59415DB9F7FF93FED47B12" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Board</header><text>The term <term>Board</term> means the Mining Professional Development Advisory Board established by subsection (d)(1).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H948555B903054D5389DAC235C8B3F26A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given the term in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE68079F567AC4412BFC9BBC96FF7A7C1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Mining industry</header><text>The term <term>mining industry</term> means the mining industry of the United States, consisting of the search for, and extraction, beneficiation, refining, smelting, processing, reprocessing, and recycling of, naturally occurring metal and nonmetal minerals from the earth. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1E54466E9DD24ECE8B2816011DD6D1FB" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Mining profession</header><text>The term <term>mining profession</term> means the body of jobs directly relevant to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H33B57AC273B94700BAE5C9F89BFECEA8" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the exploration, planning, execution, and remediation of metal and nonmetal mining sites; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFAB209FCE927497FB15E6F4E480FC4E9" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the extraction, including the separation, refining, alloying, smelting, concentration, processing, reprocessing, and recycling of mineral ores.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H12EF47B29242406B9C1C991EE0A01D2C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Mining school</header><text>The term <term>mining school</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H5B01CB71DA7A466A8F8314196D778464"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a mining, metallurgical, geological, or mineral engineering program accredited by the Accreditation Board for Engineering and Technology, Inc., that is located at an institution of higher education, including a Tribal College or University; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H29A16F7DCCDE4F5F91ABEF0E68EB87DA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a geology or engineering program or department that is located at a 4-year public institution of higher education located in a State the gross domestic product of which in 2021 was not less than $2,000,000,000 in the combined categories of “Mining (except oil and gas)” and “Support activities for mining”, according to the Bureau of Economic Analysis.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFE2F0FE572194978B2EE78000CA0923A"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Energy.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF8BFD3AF537E40B8BB371DA19030DEF1"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Tribal College or University</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Tribal College or University</term> has the meaning given the term in section 316(b) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1059c">20 U.S.C. 1059c(b)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H70A6EB63F69F42738C73DF4150B1B0BE" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Domestic mining education strengthening program</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of the Interior (acting through the Director of the United States Geological Survey), shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H08CE0994F0D64B9AB2F1516095E38EBA" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish a grant program to strengthen domestic mining education; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB662E35A53884D5C81348909CEBF13A9" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">under the program established under paragraph (1), award competitive grants to mining schools for the purpose of recruiting and educating the next generation of mining engineers and other qualified professionals to meet the future energy and mineral needs of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HEC170416EDE341219C3CA75928AC5056"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Grants</header> 
<paragraph id="HA30F3124CBF049A4BEE4EA7F033C29C5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In carrying out the grant program established under subsection (b)(1), the Secretary shall award not more than 10 grants each year to mining schools.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H41B350BD2B2245FF9F8723AFD664944E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Selection requirements</header> <subparagraph id="HB3CAE458467B42CCAD522FC2ABB7B8B8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To the maximum extent practicable, the Secretary shall select recipients for grants under paragraph (1) to ensure geographic diversity among grant recipients to ensure that region-specific specialties are developed for region-specific geology.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC2511B0F78F140F59F5A55B6E03AA789"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Timeline</header><text>The Secretary shall award the grants under paragraph (1) by not later than the later of—</text> <clause id="H73E40C9BCEF9451D9E63C81E7D169B57" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the date that is 180 days after the start of the applicable fiscal year; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H96D595AA6CBC4948924C82EE8D71E6AB" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the date that is 180 days after the date on which the Act making full-year appropriations for the Department of Energy for the applicable fiscal year is enacted.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7831E5B89E554BCA871D1DF7683B0D20"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Recommendations of the Board</header> <subparagraph id="H2AE7C3EC6BAD4FD1BB795C29DE316A7F" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In selecting recipients for grants under paragraph (1) and determining the amount of each grant, the Secretary, to the maximum extent practicable, shall take into consideration the recommendations of the Board under subparagraphs (A) and (B) of subsection (d)(3).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0C70FDF80BB94842A2A245F0BE045800" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Selection statement</header><text>In selecting recipients for grants under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall—</text> <clause id="HED24C365FAE541B6BE69024B0528483B" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in response to a recommendation from the Board, submit to the Board a statement that describes—</text> 
<subclause id="H58053BD8567D403389461C584A2100D1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether the Secretary accepts or rejects, in whole or in part, the recommendation of the Board; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HC219372CF8E446468317585C3D3327BF" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the justification and rationale for any rejection, in whole or in part, of the recommendation of the Board; and</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="HBA9081E594FB4FC284D881E3BB1EBFD6" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>not later than 15 days after awarding a grant for which the Board submitted a recommendation, publish the statement submitted under clause (i) on the Department of Energy website.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1BE4E50CA22E44E393F62FC6D4FC6493"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>A mining school receiving a grant under paragraph (1) shall use the grant funds—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H04BCEEC7BB094C269580CF401434D5D8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to recruit students to the mining school; and </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5BDDF1E2804446F9B815126D67CFB31B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to enhance and support programs related to, as applicable— </text> 
<clause id="HB58B53610B2C461B97AF42767E18D811"><enum>(i)</enum><text>mining, mineral extraction efficiency, and related processing technology;</text></clause> <clause id="H89E2EAA8F03F4FC2A189FFF4457104D0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>emphasizing critical mineral and rare earth element exploration, extraction, and refining;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H54C0BF5086BC42559D0198F1BDB29E82"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>reclamation technology and practices for active mining operations;</text></clause> <clause id="H7AAC711DFDBB4FB5B67605F9E7990D6B"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the development of reprocessing systems and technologies that facilitate reclamation that fosters the recovery of resources at abandoned mine sites;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HB4DD19B61F7A478A8A0BABA09D07787F"><enum>(v)</enum><text>mineral extraction, refining, processing, reprocessing, and recycling methods that reduce environmental and human impacts;</text></clause> <clause id="H884D728A13904056A53D7CF2EE7FDAEC"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>technologies to extract, refine, separate, melt, produce, or recycle minerals, including rare earth elements;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HDA3D03B22B9246F4A895E3560A4EBF12"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>reducing dependence on foreign energy and mineral supplies through increased domestic critical mineral production and recycling;</text></clause> <clause id="H92507260084E4C34BC986275ED0BD3E8"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>enhancing the competitiveness of United States energy and mineral technology exports;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HBA743366339A4622AF64122A005B000A"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>the extraction or processing of coinciding mineralization, including rare earth elements, within coal or other ores, coal or mineral processing byproduct, overburden, or residue from coal, minerals, or other ores;</text></clause> <clause id="H885DA435A51E4D1992916A51ADC9894C"><enum>(x)</enum><text>enhancing technologies and practices relating to mitigation of acid mine drainage, reforestation, and revegetation in the reclamation of land and water resources adversely affected by mining;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H3406D843624E4FDDB358CA8BBB8CE0DE"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>enhancing exploration and characterization of new or novel deposits, including rare earth elements and critical minerals within phosphate rocks, uranium-bearing deposits, and other nontraditional sources;</text></clause> <clause id="HBEF3F59290F942A89F4D0514AF01FF25"><enum>(xii)</enum><text>meeting challenges of extreme mining conditions, such as deeper deposits or cold region mining;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H644B64D417144E329274C585493C9641"><enum>(xiii)</enum><text>mineral economics, including analysis of supply chains, future mineral needs, and unconventional mining resources; and</text></clause> <clause id="HEA40C26795224E73B13865680A474951"><enum>(xiv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">mining practices that reduce environmental impact, including mining practices that reduce water usage, mitigate surface disturbance, and promote overall resource efficiency.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF9F5B689A6114B1FAF3E8458328FB84E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Mining Professional Development Advisory Board</header> 
<paragraph id="HF3DF375F44534362A62C7C8E763EB188"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is established an advisory board, to be known as the <quote>Mining Professional Development Advisory Board</quote>. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE5DCAFD046534B8B99F0A9D7C36C6546"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Composition</header><text>The Board shall be composed of 6 members, to be appointed by the Secretary not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, of whom—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H2F974560B6EC4084A90B43BF92DB9BB2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>3 shall be individuals who are actively working in the mining profession and for the mining industry; and </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H02016DF8141A44DFBA9C3042256CF600"><enum>(B)</enum><text>3 shall have experience in academia implementing and operating professional skills training and education programs in the mining sector.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0624BAF1D1E047D290FAC16FE72B9D3E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Board shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HAA16E68F48FA4E528E8E705E494C0D78"><enum>(A)</enum><text>evaluate grant applications received under subsection (c) and make recommendations to the Secretary for selection of grant recipients under that subsection;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA9601FD1DBA84494BFFD9DCC25C8DA78"><enum>(B)</enum><text>propose the amount of the grant for each applicant recommended to be selected under subparagraph (A); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4C3034EAC6264140B9ADEB7F5F11BC1F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>perform oversight to ensure that grant funds awarded under subsection (c) are used for the purposes described in paragraph (4) of that subsection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5F48FB29B7D740CEBE42F4E84BC0BA1D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Term</header><text>A member of the Board shall serve for a term of 4 years.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H06FAE225CEDF47788513D27CA1B11DB2"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Vacancies</header><text>A vacancy on the Board—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE3B57A7183DB4E31841926DBFB049D1F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall not affect the powers of the Board; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0DD5D234E7F04E5D9CB51CF1F9A154D3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment was made by not later than 180 days after the date on which the vacancy occurs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HB9ECD786107C45BE97662D66426EFBA1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>3.</enum><header>Repeal of the Mining and Mineral Resources Research Institute Act of 1984</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"> <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/98/409">Public Law 98–409</external-xref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1221">30 U.S.C. 1221 et seq.</external-xref>) is repealed.</text></section> <section id="HD48741CA9B7A415E8E2B984305B6CF94"><enum>4.</enum><header>No additional funds authorized</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No additional funds are authorized to carry out the requirements of this Act, and the activities authorized by this Act are subject to the availability of appropriations made in advance for such purposes.</text></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

