<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MIR25641-2D1-F7-XLN"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 S2048 IS: PRC Military and Human Rights Capital Markets Sanctions Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2048</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250612">June 12, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S423">Mr. Ricketts</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To prohibit the purchase of certain securities from covered entities, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HC93EB599BC1F480DB23A17F2E3269350"><section section-type="section-one" id="HD78194803ABF4F4CACDED7E963388A82"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>PRC Military and Human Rights Capital Markets Sanctions Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section section-type="subsequent-section" id="HC79A96BA979E499E938317E3E5913D36"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on purchase of certain securities from covered entities</header><subsection commented="no" id="H0CA5A06C77DF4356980E47D9F78F0310"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0459fd9e60724c8a8178f60294f7c295"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Covered entity</header><subparagraph commented="no" id="H3049E2EBF0044957932CFC3F61EDD8B9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In this section, the term <term>covered entity</term> means the following:</text><clause id="idc69c2369ee274b1d8f56efd2a0f39db3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Any entity that is on the list of Specially Designated Nationals and Blocked Persons maintained by the Office of Foreign Assets Control of the Department of the Treasury, or any entity under common ownership or control with such entity.</text></clause><clause id="id11f71c0822504f73a6a1526c6bbf2d42"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Any entity on the Non-SDN Chinese Military-Industrial Complex Companies List (commonly known as the <quote>NS–CMIC List</quote>) maintained by the Office of Foreign Assets Control of the Department of the Treasury pursuant to Executive Order 13959 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note; relating to addressing the threat from securities investments that finance communist Chinese military companies), or any entity under common ownership or control with such entity.</text></clause><clause id="idc4d6972490c64cc9b3ecbe405530eb46"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Any Chinese military company included on the list maintained by the Department of Defense under section 1260H(b) of the William M. (Mac) Thornberry National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/283">Public Law 116–283</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/113">10 U.S.C. 113</external-xref> note) as of the date of the enactment of this Act, or any entity under common ownership or control with such company.</text></clause><clause id="id6fc10b1849e1492e8dc1034b338af75e"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Any Chinese entity with respect to which sanctions have been imposed under the under the Global Magnitsky Human Rights Accountability Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/10101">22 U.S.C. 10101 et seq.</external-xref>), or any entity under common ownership or control with such entity.</text></clause><clause id="id754a08f6c6dc41a2b47b3a50ce5c6be6"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Any Chinese entity that produces goods that have been the subject of a withhold release order issued pursuant to section 307 of the Tariff Act of 1930 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1307">19 U.S.C. 1307</external-xref>) during the 2-year period ending on the date of the enactment of this Act, or any entity under common ownership or control of such entity.</text></clause><clause id="id18eb27f528f0431bb4d4f8d2864b8a5d"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Any Chinese entity included on the Entity List maintained by the Bureau of Industry and Security of the Department of Commerce and set forth in Supplement No. 4 to part 744 of title 15, Code of Federal Regulations, or any entity under common ownership or control with such entity.</text></clause><clause id="id327d7d223edb41319c36b4138cf65cf1"> <enum>(vii)</enum> <text>Any Chinese entity on a list maintained under clause (i), (ii), (iv), or (v) of section 2(d)(2)(B) of the Act entitled <quote>An Act to ensure that goods made with forced labor in the Xinjiang Autonomous Region of the People’s Republic of China do not enter the United States market, and for other purposes</quote>, approved December 23, 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/78">Public Law 117–78</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/6901">22 U.S.C. 6901</external-xref> note) (commonly referred to as the <quote>Uyghur Forced Labor Prevention Act</quote>), or any entity under common ownership or control with such entity.</text>
 </clause><clause id="iddbe3f008785e4afa9ae7e4b85f047f94"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>Any Chinese entity on the Military End-User List maintained by the Bureau of Industry and Security and set forth in Supplement No. 7 to part 744 of title 15, Code of Federal Regulations, or any entity under common ownership or control with such entity.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9dec398572294f1c9e687865793b31fb"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Control</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A), the term <term>control</term> has the meaning given the term in section 230.405 of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ida7952858aa144527895b5e3105b2982f"><enum>(2)</enum><header>United states person</header><text>The term <term>United States person</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="id1db7a3e056cf4410ab71d71d7abb04e0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a United States citizen or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence to the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id27d86af4634a4024965941917079d16c"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an entity organized under the laws of the United States or any jurisdiction within the United States, including a foreign branch of such an entity; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id85e15ba8869b4de1a25e6bfd5220bb38"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any person in the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1E5AD595EFD7466686FBE0F919C7E9B5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the President shall—</text><paragraph id="H44CCC7EA4B1E442882974E1B93D2BD88"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">compile and maintain a single list of covered entities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H774767D081FB415E956BF06C4B26607C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">where possible, include in the list described in paragraph (1) a unique identification number for each covered entity, such as a Committee on Uniform Securities Identification Procedures number or a Stock Exchange Daily Official List number;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDE58E1D09D7043F682A1E55F155E1C80"><enum>(3)</enum><text>make the list described in paragraph (1) available to the public; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7F13D1D1AB9D4FA38D5820313D6F225D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>publicly identify and prohibit the purchase, sale, or holding by a United States person of a—</text><subparagraph id="H116C12BCA0E747F6B1DB85AFFA7844B8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>publicly traded security issued by a covered entity;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H906E2D6B620044098C544DC994A1D2C6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>publicly traded security that is derivative of a publicly traded security issued by a covered entity; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H91B5B7BCFA504CD680000DEB18B08501"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">security that provides investment exposure to a publicly traded security issued by a covered entity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDE7F5E852D6C4C20B529DE278C0DF3D6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Divestment required</header><paragraph id="H6F05DCF1101A4A458CCFCD3AB32EC22A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding subsection (b), a United States person shall divest of all securities described in subsection (b)—</text><subparagraph id="H2C73FB76528A4F71BA20D271982DE7AA"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to a security identified by the President under subsection (b) before the end of the 90-day period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act, not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE17AEE7C61F74EC7A5A4373BBAEFB364"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to a security identified by the President under subsection (b) after the end of the 90-day period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act, not later than 180 days after the date of such identification.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA9B4D97544B642239964738348A83A7B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Facilitating divestment transactions</header><text>Subsection (b) shall not apply to a United States person to the extent the person is facilitating the divestment of securities described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H537AFAA609F9409CBA18497F10C5F25D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Penalties</header><paragraph id="H80A410B0E35D46E1A791051600A19080"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A United States person that violates, attempts to violate, conspires to violate, or causes a violation of this Act shall be subject to the following penalties:</text><subparagraph id="HB8D3A30410174F0198F7ABD517924DE3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A civil penalty in an amount not to exceed the greater of—</text><clause id="H715F71BFBE254A688762B507D6F0BA94"><enum>(i)</enum><text>$250,000; or</text></clause><clause id="H8761D5834E80475495F3511554FAF385"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an amount that is twice the amount of the transaction that is the basis of the violation with respect to which the penalty is imposed.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8832D428D26F4FEDBB6ACE2197802D1A"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to a United States person that willfully violates, willfully attempts to violate, willfully conspires to violate, or aids or abets in the commission of a violation of this Act shall be subject to a criminal penalty—</text><clause id="H93DF1605A9C14C36ACE192154A113D80"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">of a fine of not more than $1,000,000; or</text></clause><clause id="H2A4D2F464DBF45C59AD63D0822F79DBA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if such United States person is an individual, a fine of not more than $1,000,000, a term of imprisonment of not more than 20 years, or both.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H18DEA078665C4FC48EB1EA1C24CD78F3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Amount of a transaction defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of paragraph (1)(A)(ii), the term <quote>amount of a transaction</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="H31A679C598AB4303BD69B76DCDFFE5D9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>with respect to a purchase that violates this Act, the purchase price;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5693FB3DD0FE455B9267276B281E50A5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to a sale that violates this Act, the sale price; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6733CACABA3E41F2A7F83C9BBF547781"><enum>(C)</enum><text>with respect to the holding of a security that violates this Act, the fair market value of the security at the time of the violation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

