<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3EB6770FD0384EE6A9B6A0077E86C538" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3143 IH: State Planning for Reliability and Affordability Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3143</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250501">May 1, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000300">Mr. Evans of Colorado</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="L000600">Mr. Langworthy</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 to add a standard related to State consideration of reliable generation, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6ECF020DA7094AE89F460FC2F93434AB" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H8137BE6542314C51885DF3FA6EDC6988" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>State Planning for Reliability and Affordability Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="H81794E6EEDA14519895565208E1A006D"><enum>2.</enum><header>State consideration of reliable generation</header> <subsection id="HE7122C00BDF14958B0742F7753E3BB63"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 111(d) of the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/2621">16 U.S.C. 2621(d)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H5EB60AEB705B48F5AA8A89B13BBC0A17"> 
<paragraph id="H4B95697BA6FF41EE86746D78CD1BC46B"><enum>(22)</enum><header>Ensuring electric reliability with reliable generation facilities</header> 
<subparagraph id="H0CD2F01BB948429AB908497D2EC8FD8C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each electric utility that employs integrated resource planning shall establish, as part of such integrated resource planning, measures, sufficient to ensure the reliable availability of electric energy over a 10-year period, to maintain—</text> <clause id="HDD5C4373F509494CBE5469FA83BD6693"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the operation of reliable generation facilities; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="HF71842DDAE664D4A850CDA0C6D6788FD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the procurement of electric energy from reliable generation facilities.</text> </clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBB02E98B0D4C4F20BF63071725033975" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <enum>(B)</enum> <header>Reliable generation facility defined</header> <text>In this paragraph, the term <term>reliable generation facility</term> means an electric generation facility that ensures the reliable availability of electric energy by—</text>
                            <clause id="HD86568B2F0F940BAA13CDECEDC6616F2">
                                <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">having operational characteristics to enable the generation of electric energy on a continuous basis for a period of not fewer than 30 days;</text>
                            </clause>
                            <clause id="H855CF1A6678940799F9D397A34475CF5">
                                <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>having—</text> <subclause id="H4F610AE02574422CB2C4665EFF8EC252"> <enum>(I)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">adequate fuel, or a continuously available energy source, on-site to enable the generation of electric energy on a continuous basis for a period of not fewer than 30 days; or</text>
                                </subclause>
                                <subclause id="H129AB93C44054FA791343E75881B5995">
                                    <enum>(II)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">contractual obligations that ensure adequate fuel supply to achieve the generation of electric energy on a continuous basis for a period of not fewer than 30 days;</text>
                                </subclause>
                            </clause>
                            <clause id="H3B287C64227C4E95AC7AB6B2A266CD89">
                                <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">having operational characteristics to enable the generation of electric energy during emergency and severe weather conditions; and</text>
                            </clause>
                            <clause id="H29B8D833D78E4E128654D2D1EF271E2E">
                                <enum>(iv)</enum>
 <text>providing essential services related to the reliable availability of electric energy, including frequency support and voltage support.</text>
                            </clause>
                        </subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6C7F42B4448A4799B5A09AB28426B0D6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header> 
<paragraph id="H0AE64E13E8C644EF99BCED25654BD6E9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Obligations to consider and determine</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 112 of the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/2622">16 U.S.C. 2622</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="HE7249C5880FF456B9A866C0E241FB112"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (b), by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H028FE950B06F44A6B68314FC73AEBEA2"> 
<paragraph id="HB3551C9850134B6687474FA32211AD33"><enum>(9)</enum> 
<subparagraph id="H2E2F018215E64893BCCA6960812EB937" commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this paragraph, each State regulatory authority (with respect to each electric utility for which the State has ratemaking authority) and each nonregulated utility shall commence consideration under section 111, or set a hearing date for consideration, with respect to the standard established by paragraph (22) of section 111(d).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC070625AB47243879CAD968150555FB2" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this paragraph, each State regulatory authority (with respect to each electric utility for which the State has ratemaking authority), and each nonregulated electric utility shall complete the consideration and make the determination under section 111 with respect to the standard established by paragraph (22) of section 111(d).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDF92CF4B24DF4F66AF73E2E48180B216" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text> <clause id="H3A76021CED7D43CF8CD33FCECCF1A870" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>subsection (b)(2)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (b)</quote>; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA3083A5DF831460DB489B6BDA4199A80" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>In the case of the standard established by paragraph (22) of section 111(d), the reference contained in this subsection to the date of enactment of this Act shall be deemed to be a reference to the date of enactment of that paragraph (22).</quote> after <quote>paragraph (21).</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H47F0AE63C3E94B00AD2419877809CB5D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0000E54C3D9F47E8A5EBD1E711AE658F"> 
<subsection id="H1E575C4E4C5446AB9F64D3EF1BEEC942"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Other prior State actions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsections (b) and (c) shall not apply to the standard established by paragraph (22) of section 111(d) in the case of any electric utility in a State if, before the date of enactment of this subsection—</text> <paragraph id="HCBF125D079694AC7B8A0CCD570E8072A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the State has implemented for the electric utility the standard (or a comparable standard);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3E0936D0147240C1BE993B4B1FF294F4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the State regulatory authority for the State or the relevant nonregulated electric utility has conducted a proceeding to consider implementation of the standard (or a comparable standard) for the electric utility; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF50F657CE00A4A1AB36C4CE78A28C934"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the State legislature has voted on the implementation of the standard (or a comparable standard) for the electric utility during the 3-year period ending on that date of enactment. </text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H00A341910C7F4D9E98C372C14916BCD0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prior and pending proceedings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 124 of the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/2634">16 U.S.C. 2634</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>In the case of the standard established by paragraph (22) of section 111(d), the reference contained in this section to the date of enactment of this Act shall be deemed to be a reference to the date of enactment of that paragraph (22).</quote> after <quote>paragraph (21).</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

