<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Reported-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" dms-id="H11163c62-e350-4162-8969-f5fde25d3399" public-private="public" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 282 RH: Providing for consideration of the joint resolution (S.J. Res. 18) disapproving the rule submitted by the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection relating to “Overdraft Lending: Very Large Financial Institutions''; providing for consideration of the joint resolution (S.J. Res. 28) disapproving the rule submitted by the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection relating to ''Defining Larger Participants of a Market for General-Use Digital Consumer Payment Applications''; providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 1526) to amend title 28, United States Code, to limit the authority of district courts to provide injunctive relief, and for other purposes; providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 22) to amend the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 to require proof of United States citizenship to register an individual to vote in elections for Federal office, and for other purposes; and for other purposes.”</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">House Calendar No. 14</calendar><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 282</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 119–49]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250401">April 1, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000568">Mr. Griffith</sponsor>, from the <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Committee on Rules</committee-name>, reported the following resolution; which was referred to the House Calendar and ordered to be printed</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Providing for consideration of the joint resolution (S.J. Res. 18) disapproving the rule submitted by the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection relating to <quote>Overdraft Lending: Very Large Financial Institutions''; providing for consideration of the joint resolution (S.J. Res. 28) disapproving the rule submitted by the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection relating to ''Defining Larger Participants of a Market for General-Use Digital Consumer Payment Applications''; providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 1526) to amend title 28, United States Code, to limit the authority of district courts to provide injunctive relief, and for other purposes; providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 22) to amend the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 to require proof of United States citizenship to register an individual to vote in elections for Federal office, and for other purposes; and for other purposes.</quote></official-title></form><resolution-body style="traditional" id="Haf37bdb1-ba33-4c65-a982-5ad0982f03f8"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H7c9e9cab-fd31-408e-9b16-7cef388934aa"><enum/><text>That upon adoption of this resolution it shall be in order to consider in the House the joint resolution (S.J. Res. 18) disapproving the rule submitted by the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection relating to ‘‘Overdraft Lending: Very Large Financial Institutions’’. All points of order against consideration of the joint resolution are waived. The joint resolution shall be considered as read. All points of order against provisions in the joint resolution are waived. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the joint resolution and on any amendment thereto to final passage without intervening motion except: (1) one hour of debate equally divided and controlled by the chair and ranking minority member of the Committee on Financial Services or their respective designees; and (2) one motion to commit.</text></section><section id="H1FD09CD2D75C425ABFFA90E2EEDECE04"><enum>2.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon adoption of this resolution it shall be in order to consider in the House the joint resolution (S.J. Res. 28) disapproving the rule submitted by the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection relating to ‘‘Defining Larger Participants of a Market for General-Use Digital Consumer Payment Applications’’. All points of order against consideration of the joint resolution are waived. The joint resolution shall be considered as read. All points of order against provisions in the joint resolution are waived. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the joint resolution and on any amendment thereto to final passage without intervening motion except: (1) one hour of debate equally divided and controlled by the chair and ranking minority member of the Committee on Financial Services or their respective designees; and (2) one motion to commit. </text></section><section id="HC63B95B0D60B47A1B6DA82A79BF8FD27"><enum>3.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon adoption of this resolution it shall be in order to consider in the House the bill (H.R. 1526) to amend title 28, United States Code, to limit the authority of district courts to provide injunctive relief, and for other purposes. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived. The amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on the Judiciary now printed in the bill shall be considered as adopted. The bill, as amended, shall be considered as read. All points of order against provisions in the bill, as amended, are waived. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the bill, as amended, and on any further amendment thereto, to final passage without intervening motion except: (1) one hour of debate equally divided and controlled by the chair and ranking minority member of the Committee on the Judiciary or their respective designees; and (2) one motion to recommit.</text></section><section id="H2C9BC33DD06A4FB8B571F94384BDD606"><enum>4.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon adoption of this resolution it shall be in order to consider in the House the bill (H.R. 22) to amend the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 to require proof of United States citizenship to register an individual to vote in elections for Federal office, and for other purposes. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived. The bill shall be considered as read. All points of order against provisions in the bill are waived. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the bill and on any amendment thereto to final passage without intervening motion except: (1) one hour of debate equally divided and controlled by the chair and ranking minority member of the Committee on House Administration or their respective designees; and (2) one motion to recommit.</text></section><section id="HC507EB0EDB194B5F92D5E0B1A1FA99E2"><enum>5.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">(a) House Resolution 23 and House Resolution 164 are laid on the table.</text><subsection id="H0FDA1414E4E9477B8816697B0986C7F5"><enum>(b)(1)</enum><text>A motion to discharge a committee from consideration of a bill or resolution that, by relating in substance to or dealing with the same subject matter, is substantially the same as House Resolution 23 shall not be in order. </text></subsection><subsection id="HC524175E731A48989640A49A10754EB1"><enum>(b)(2)</enum><text>A motion to discharge the Committee on Rules from consideration of a resolution providing a special order of business for the consideration of a bill or resolution that, by relating in substance to or dealing with the same subject matter, is substantially the same as House Resolution 23 shall not be in order.</text></subsection><subsection id="H010E6442B7B5492EA292D7357F717A3D"><enum>(c)</enum><text>A motion to discharge on the Calendar of Motions to Discharge Committees that is rendered out of order pursuant to subsection (b) shall be stricken from that calendar. </text></subsection></section></resolution-body><endorsement><action-date date="20250401">April 1, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Referred to the House Calendar and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></resolution> 

