<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H69C171CE083D48F39676D5AB1055A5EF" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 308 IH: Low Income Housing for Defense Communities Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 308</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250109">January 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001213">Mr. Moore of Utah</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S001159">Ms. Strickland</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide tax incentives for rental housing for members of the Armed Forces.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H10488BA96D894762AF106333C7D81E0A" style="OLC"><section id="H621B7E50A212407BA7A26903F32FD75D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; sense of Congress</header><subsection id="H550A238BA29F402180DA57D8411EF2CA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Low Income Housing for Defense Communities Act</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HFAC92B03289F481CBD6E9B4AABFC0C80"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that in addition to expanding and strengthening the affordable housing credit for active duty military members through the provisions in the Low Income Housing for Defense Communities Act, further steps should be taken to drive investment into affordable housing projects in the United States and boost overall housing supply for workers and families in the United States, such as the Affordable Housing Credit Improvement Act of 2023. </text></subsection></section><section id="H2371B0C70D6246A4861F0F30D5237DD4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Tax incentives for rental housing for members of the Armed Forces</header><subsection id="H66F0121B62FD40918E5069B0C90E9B76"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Military basic housing allowance not taken into account in applying certain income restrictions on residential rental projects</header><paragraph id="H372992BF510849F789BE0B24D74AFC89"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Low-income housing tax credit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/42">Section 42(i)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H689254B11EE84CB7B68CB0A834A77351" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="HCB10E85994A54720A5F6380EE5307312"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Income determined without regard to military basic housing allowance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Payments under section 403 of title 37, United States Code, as a basic pay allowance for housing shall not be taken into account in determining income for purposes of this section.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="HF6F7DCBE7C0C48D8A61D7270B4E0AAEB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Tax-exempt bonds for qualified residential rental projects</header><subparagraph id="H1FC718F2C9DE477C807F48DE83515AA5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 142(d)(2)(B) of such Code, as amended by subparagraph (B), is amended by inserting after clause (i) the following new clause:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H4763DEDE453844B8B0A76A5662B6D28C" display-inline="no-display-inline"><clause id="H92970228D6B04BF6AC427847FB81BF42"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Income determined without regard to military basis housing allowance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Payments under section 403 of title 37, United States Code, as a basic pay allowance for housing shall not be taken into account in determining income for purposes of clause (i). </text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H751323EC83FB4F3380C4AED782903074"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Repeal of deadwood</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 142(d)(2)(B) of such Code is amended by striking clauses (ii), (iii), and (iv).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H795B4516023C41DE8934AA46BD98AB1D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this subsection shall apply to determinations made after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9F70A762A5DD4687800095F80CBF673B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Increase in low-Income housing credit for buildings near certain large military installation</header><paragraph id="H2BB8DE2039B84C58B16C1CF3D9B236F8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/42">Section 42(d)(5)(B)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new clause:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H0A77D4C9FCC74927A2E2BCB5860607F2" display-inline="no-display-inline"><clause id="HDBECE7429A904169A34B212BE69B6E5D"><enum>(vi)</enum><header>Buildings near certain large military installation</header><subclause id="HF29EC7AF58FA4BF1842289F1ED9953BE"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any building which is located within 15 miles of a large military installation shall be treated as located in a difficult development area which is designated for purposes of this subparagraph.</text></subclause><subclause id="H4F0A3C1886D441F8858A01BD65160382"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Large military installation</header><text>For purposes of this clause, the term <quote>large military installation</quote> means any military installation with a total plant replacement value (as determined by the Secretary of the Defense) in excess of $2,833,000,000.</text></subclause></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H6735314BD11843BB8961DFA306DBE89B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by this subsection shall apply to buildings placed in service after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE9CD43DE4CE04DADBACA3397DE7ACB34"><enum>(3)</enum><header>No requirement that buildings be occupied solely by members of the Armed Forces</header><text>Nothing in the amendment made by this subsection shall be applied or interpreted to require that buildings described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/42">section 42(d)(5)(B)(vi)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (as added by this section) be occupied solely by members of the Armed Forces.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

