<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCAC6918FC55A4A6DB4BFCB24F743FC9F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1696 IH: Puerto Rico Low-Income Housing Support Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1696</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250227">February 27, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001103">Mr. Hern&#225;ndez</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="T000486">Mr. Torres of New York</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the definition of extremely low-income families under the United States Housing Act of 1937.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6B7DC5134F7945D2B5C656A25852776B" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H1CC11AF23CFB440C864AE588F1F0FFF6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Puerto Rico Low-Income Housing Support Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H915E3F4DBB1441BC98A9E90E227C7DCF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definition of extremely low-income families</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Clause (i) of section 3(b)(2)(C) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437a">42 U.S.C. 1437a(b)(2)(C)(i)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H5CA764ACCFEB4D80BB695E1055BAEF92"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Puerto Rico or any other</quote> and inserting <quote>any</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H687A927E5F8F463CB6A33776BF35A7C0"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting before the closing parentheses the following: <quote>other than Puerto Rico and in the case of public housing agencies and projects located in Puerto Rico, the same poverty guidelines as used for the contiguous 48 States and the District of Columbia shall apply</quote>.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H0E464BCE354A4A3F855DA71F36B1F9B0"><enum>3.</enum><header>Report on low income housing access in Puerto Rico</header> 
<subsection id="H71A45386F4C845D9942F6E1022D913D8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Comptroller General shall, not later than 180 day after the date of the enactment of this section, submit a report to the Congress about efforts made by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, in collaboration with the Government of Puerto Rico, to connect low-income families residing in Puerto Rico with—</text> <paragraph id="H9DD53D7C74644712B929CF521A3962A1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>housing assistance available in Puerto Rico; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H460D1898E123409497A39CE63C491B4E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">affordable dwelling units, including dwelling units that are part of a housing project assisted under the United States Housing Act of 1937. </text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H44E3A482DBAA41AD9869BE8FE5586046"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report required under subsection (a) shall include—</text> 
<paragraph id="HFBFA329647954B6AB037DF1743745AFE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an assessment of how the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) and the Puerto Rico Public Housing Administration (PRPHA) identify and address housing needs for extremely low-income families that reside in Puerto Rico;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H104E1704A8E142CBB684AB097ED6D34D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an assessment how the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development uses Federal disaster recovery funds to rebuild and expand low-income housing after natural disasters in Puerto Rico, including hurricanes and earthquakes; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB4C5DFEABFE94023B540780B632CFF44"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recommendations to improve the effectiveness of Federal and local housing programs that serve extremely low-income families that reside in Puerto Rico.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

