<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6B69252BF2EF4588AD2A2897F55C4639" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2969 IH: Finding Opportunities for Resource Exploration Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2969</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250417">April 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000804">Mr. Wittman</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001066">Ms. Castor of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001194">Mr. Moolenaar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001085">Ms. Houlahan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000593">Mr. Gimenez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001215">Ms. Stevens</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000486">Mr. Torres of New York</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To allow the Secretary of the Interior to enter into memoranda of understanding for the purpose of scientific and technical cooperation in the mapping of critical minerals and rare earth elements, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H7CCE8F57F30F4E788BB0E1AB6A92E7D9" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HAB81C8FE631D4831B652F1E2D17ACC22" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Finding Opportunities for Resource Exploration Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Finding ORE Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC89CCE80F33D4689910143244C4600A7"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3BB28D3FE47148959BD084DBAA8508A0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Allied foreign country</header><text>The term <term>allied foreign country</term> means a country with which the United States has entered into a mutual defense treaty or other mutual defense agreement.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF419DF79A008470282D31AF0A20770E7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Critical mineral</header><text>The term <term>critical mineral</term> has the meaning given the term in section 7002(a) of the Energy Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1606">30 U.S.C. 1606(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA17D24CC59EB4FE2A0359B2F8EA06B65"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text>The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given the term in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD93A10C1BBA041DEB89E8EA68C1B44AA"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Partner foreign country</header><text>The term <term>partner foreign country</term> means a country that is a source of a critical mineral or rare earth element.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7487ADE80A35444EAEE822FEE24BAB2D"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Rare earth element</header><text>The term <term>rare earth element</term> means cerium, dysprosium, erbium, europium, gadolinium, holmium, lanthanum, lutetium, neodymium, praseodymium, promethium, samarium, scandium, terbium, thulium, ytterbium, or yttrium.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H60060D75B81841449987F332C0350AC2"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the United States Geological Survey.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H37245656B0404179A3830CB34AD08B76"><enum>3.</enum><header>Memorandum of understanding with respect to the mapping of critical minerals and rare earth elements</header> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA6E619BB6AA74646BED0DBFED4DE6C48"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Memorandum of understanding</header><text>The Secretary may enter into a memorandum of understanding with 1 or more heads of agencies of partner foreign countries with respect to scientific and technical cooperation in the mapping of critical minerals and rare earth elements.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFFBF81870BA248039A566B694294D84C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Objectives</header><text>In negotiating a memorandum of understanding under subsection (a), the Secretary shall seek to increase the security and resilience of international supply chains for critical minerals and rare earth elements by—</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H42D49DC7FE7642948A3595907EBF273F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>committing to assisting the partner foreign country through cooperative activities described in subsection (c) that help the partner foreign country map reserves of critical minerals and rare earth elements;</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H48C3CC96A88A4DBDA7411CB96D15E69B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>ensuring that private companies headquartered in the United States or an allied foreign country are offered the right of first refusal in the further development of critical minerals and rare earth elements in the partner foreign country;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBB6E60595C18488FB4E612942D7EDA32"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">facilitating private-sector investment in the exploration and development of critical minerals and rare earth elements, including by leveraging preferential financing from entities such as the United States International Development Finance Corporation and the Export-Import Bank of the United States that prioritizes projects committed to processing minerals in the United States or an allied foreign country; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7968C9D7925747CF923254F063C54979"><enum>(4)</enum><text>ensuring that mapping data created through the cooperative activities described in subsection (c) is protected against unauthorized access by, or disclosure to, governmental or private entities based in countries that are not—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5C32310C42C74426B0C59CFEE117F6B3"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a party to the memorandum of understanding; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6B15890622E74134B7726E776ACF9D03"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an allied foreign country.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H096947F9189747A4AFDCD8440533766B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Cooperative activities</header><text>The cooperative activities referred to in subsection (b) include—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEFDD15A49F484A5290A4CA15DDC22F2E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>acquisition, compilation, analysis, and interpretation of geologic, geophysical, geochemical, and spectroscopic remote sensing data;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8A85935A45954F20AF831EFD59E60986"><enum>(2)</enum><text>prospectivity mapping and mineral resource assessment;</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8AA98C2BB0114F499CB1EE7B8450E7E0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>analysis of geoscience data, including developing derivative map products that can help more effectively evaluate the mineral resources of the partner foreign country;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB898B125642740F4979094A03C07DE55"><enum>(4)</enum><text>scientific collaboration to enhance the understanding and management of the natural resources of the partner foreign country to contribute to the sustainable development of the mineral resources sector of that partner foreign country;</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H73B9ED997372422197FE6A444AD2D38E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>training and capacity building in each area described in paragraphs (1) through (4);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2F42EAC5FC74433D838200E55F7CBB64"><enum>(6)</enum><text>facilitation of education and specialized training in geoscience and mineral resource management at institutions of higher education;</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD0840975F7584F8DA0F2C8B8A345F901"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">training in environmental and workplace standards for relevant officials of the government and private companies of the partner foreign country; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6DAEFAD81E634396A4C9F7A78766B1F9"><enum>(8)</enum><text>cooperation among entities of the partner foreign country that are a party to the memorandum of understanding and entities in the United States, including Federal departments and agencies, institutions of higher education, research centers, and private companies.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H5A119FF661B7445C9D29E3443C95866F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Notification to Congress</header><text>The Secretary shall notify Congress not later than 30 days before the Secretary intends to enter into a memorandum of understanding under subsection (a).</text></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H43A47921720642B08A8A1AA3CDB79CAE"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Collaboration with Secretary of State</header><text>The Secretary shall collaborate with the Secretary of State in—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCACD5EAE86E644929989837A63B75D75"><enum>(1)</enum><text>prioritizing and selecting partner foreign countries with which to enter into a memorandum of understanding under subsection (a);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE733937B6DBF4408A0BE46CF5B6ECDEA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>negotiating a memorandum of understanding under subsection (a); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8E845E3B22944F5DAD930A6E1C887379"><enum>(3)</enum><text>implementing a memorandum of understanding entered into under subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC331BB074727446B838374E699FDAC4E"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Consultation with private sector</header><text>The Secretary shall consult with relevant private sector actors, as the Secretary determines to be appropriate, in—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC3E3E3AD93AB48AE9DF48995EEA81436"><enum>(1)</enum><text>prioritizing and selecting partner foreign countries with which to enter into a memorandum of understanding under subsection (a); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB68FA342F2A9442B9417F47D007AA83E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>assessing how a memorandum of understanding can best facilitate private sector interest in pursuing the further development of critical minerals and rare earth elements in accordance with the objectives described in subsection (b).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

