<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9D6D8608BB8B44068CFF2CE921B61647" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1904 IH: Improving Coordination of Agriculture Research and Data Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1904</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250306">March 6, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S001218">Ms. Stansbury</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the National Agricultural Research, Extension, and Teaching Policy Act of 1977 to establish the Climate Scientific Research Advisory Committee and the Rural Climate Alliance Network, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H3FE677EE578D4D97B76ECBFAC7BE8EDA" style="OLC"><section id="H53636A2D4ED547EEA4013585CD6247C8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Improving Coordination of Agriculture Research and Data Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H9719DE585B034B50879879CB22BC36F7"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purposes of this Act are—</text><paragraph id="HCEFC096331A241BE9D35A1D33FC64A21"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to strategically align agriculture climate research and data systems;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3C140794419E4892BB0253719F878ADB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to strengthen technical assistance and technology transfer; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H440F1B934551443DB253CD0CA9FDF37A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to establish a national agriculture climate research agenda to mitigate and adapt to climate change.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HBEE5B4048BE24BB9B6C97BC4538B21D1"><enum>3.</enum><header>Agriculture climate research coordination and data</header><subsection id="H097346C54771444DBB734F4C706917E6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Agriculture Climate Scientific Research Advisory Committee</header><text>Subtitle B of the National Agricultural Research, Extension, and Teaching Policy Act of 1977 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/3121">7 U.S.C. 3121 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H118ABC6FE3084CD5B00C64CACC33BF02" style="OLC"><section id="HB9790B0B3C644ABEAEE6B7677F76EF32"><enum>1413C.</enum><header>Agriculture Climate Scientific Research Advisory Committee</header><subsection id="H4025E90D99904F0B995577B3FF3EF01C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Secretary shall establish within the Office of the Chief Scientist an advisory committee, to be known as the <quote>Agriculture Climate Scientific Research Advisory Committee</quote> (referred to in this section as the <quote>Committee</quote>).</text></subsection><subsection id="HCE3954D49ABE4656ACBBE10D6E964380"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Committee shall—</text><paragraph id="H0E91538187E34A84BEBBFF8D135BA225"><enum>(1)</enum><text>review, and make recommendations and provide consultation to the Secretary regarding, the long-term and short-term national policies and priorities of the Department of Agriculture for—</text><subparagraph id="HFF80107ACEFC4B8CB1ECBFABA414D384"><enum>(A)</enum><text>data collection for climate-specific agricultural research, extension, education, and economics; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAEA12602F0304A52A80AABD5765D91DC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>agricultural climate research priority areas and scientific agendas for measuring, monitoring, reporting, and verification of climate and environmental outcomes that include—</text><clause id="H0615F07E9F814BE58134AC12AF80397D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>carbon removal, carbon sequestration, and greenhouse gas emission related to agriculture;</text></clause><clause id="H781F890D641F4841B4337A8DD0E3BAB0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>soil health;</text></clause><clause id="HDF357C5CDC364788A60A35639CF75B30"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>livestock methane production;</text></clause><clause id="HFF5B6B02720A4AD3AB3FB9640047C7A3"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>wetland management; and</text></clause><clause id="H9588D9891308481380E7B64FFCA4E184"><enum>(v)</enum><text>climate smart agriculture practices;</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF990D4717AD94CD394505EFB77C3AAE9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>identify gaps in current agriculture climate research and develop a biennial national research agenda and annual scientific recommendations to address areas of critical need for publicly funded agriculture climate research;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC2F71A84FD4D4F858926AACF98485AE8"><enum>(3)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HBC3793F873064C35A5546DB5FED737CB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>every 5 years, evaluate the results and effectiveness of climate-specific agricultural research, extension, education, and economics with respect to the policies and priorities described in paragraph (1); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9BCAD04C4D494483AB9ED0958DF7821E" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>make recommendations to the Secretary based on such evaluation;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAACD5378F00D48FBAD469408DC520B9C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>review and make programmatic and priority research recommendations to the Under Secretary for Research, Education, and Economics on the climate-specific agricultural research, extension, education, and economics described in paragraph (3)(A);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD2CD554F5FCE49BB89A6BAC523C85492"><enum>(5)</enum><text>review and make recommendations on the mechanisms of the Department of Agriculture for technology assessment, which shall be conducted by qualified professionals, for the purposes of—</text><subparagraph id="HEEE8994FC07749E6851D776BEA8C7407"><enum>(A)</enum><text>performance measurement and evaluation of the implementation by the Secretary of the strategic plan of the Department of Agriculture required under section 306 of title 5, United States Code;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEEBA5897ED1B4A17925F89A4F17B284F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>implementation of climate-specific national research policies and priorities that are consistent with the purposes described in section 1402; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFB0523944C734BAABD97DC80580D8FC7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the development of mechanisms for the assessment of emerging public and private climate-specific agricultural research and technology transfer initiatives;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE77CBA80A773422BA0DEBFA38D26BCF3"><enum>(6)</enum><text>every 5 years, establish and update standardized data collection, management, and dissemination protocols for—</text><subparagraph id="H1E318D0250824FA1A2116190315B2F38"><enum>(A)</enum><text>agriculture climate research programs of the Department of Agriculture; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H13EC6E4705F1409CAB99962E459119AF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>initiatives of the Rural Climate Alliance Network established under section 1419(c);</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5C5A7B99F9AC4017868A70B55D9FFF79"><enum>(7)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HD8242137A5384841952E800C55023F48"><enum>(A)</enum><text>consult with industry groups, producer networks, advocacy organizations, scientific societies, and higher education associations on climate-specific agricultural research, extension, education, and economics; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBED47987E01241ABBB8F687F4DDB03DA" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>make recommendations to the Secretary based on such consultation;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC9158A94AA9D4897BFB7AA5500D5124F"><enum>(8)</enum><text>consult with, and receive communications from, other Federal departments and agencies on climate plans and priorities relating to agriculture and forestry for the purpose of advising the Secretary of opportunities for collaboration, coordination, and avoiding duplication;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7A29C1D7F890430AB7D97181A5FE3F0C"><enum>(9)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HD50F96CCBFE94B199A067677E5CE6DB4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>review climate research technology transfer and new scientific practices for climate mitigation and adaptation; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H720283DF0C7A483AB442215CD21A8C9D" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>make recommendations to the Rural Climate Alliance Network established under section 1419(c) based on such review; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA825F875D8674A4C91A9E6AF93ADA265"><enum>(10)</enum><text>review and suggest annual budget recommendations to support a climate research agenda for the Secretary to propose in each annual budget of the Department of Agriculture.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAE0948A2052442BB97886FA2D8E00415"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Membership</header><paragraph id="H6E4F060986884B94A506052433EF6E84"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Number and appointment</header><subparagraph id="H67B117525BF345AA9DA3CD77F918A5C1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Committee shall be composed of 18 members as follows:</text><clause id="H52B9EFF162C84904BE32D5E48585A296"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The Secretary.</text></clause><clause id="H6364AA0477394280B2DB7FA2F0861171"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The Chief Scientist.</text></clause><clause id="H46B7D4BF57EF4EEDB619DB907ED43B24"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The Director of the Global Climate Change Program established under section 2402 of the Food, Agriculture, Conservation, and Trade Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/6701">7 U.S.C. 6701</external-xref>).</text></clause><clause id="H78E78ADE3AE14FCD839164E77680D606"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The Under Secretary for Natural Resources and Environment.</text></clause><clause id="H18AFB649D5D9485CBDC2CE0101B01E96"><enum>(v)</enum><text>The Under Secretary for Farm Production and Conservation.</text></clause><clause id="H97108B3F14F04CB2B1856E8EF72C59CA"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>The Under Secretary for Marketing and Regulatory Programs.</text></clause><clause id="H5D065C1B36F646CD943B508053461B3C"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>The Executive Director of the Foundation for Food and Agriculture Research.</text></clause><clause id="H3EEC18A6570A4FAC92D0E1E95E4C1A15"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>The Administrator of the Agricultural Research Service.</text></clause><clause id="H6768633153584F8B820C7E7B059C592E"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>The Director of the National Institute of Food and Agriculture.</text></clause><clause id="HE577AC98B5C64BED9EC53543340EE8D0"><enum>(x)</enum><text>The Administrator of the Economic Research Service.</text></clause><clause id="H052EFF53D597499DBEF4F9A752300280"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>The Administrator of the National Agricultural Statistics Service.</text></clause><clause id="HAE5562472BE5451A8F8CB2D8B813B5A0"><enum>(xii)</enum><text>The Director of the Office of Energy and Environmental Policy.</text></clause><clause id="H8EF12695533A42C8B2BD0FE0EAA6B51D"><enum>(xiii)</enum><text>The Deputy Chief for Research and Development of the Forest Service.</text></clause><clause id="HC6683D2A81234BA2A02472BB2BB5960E"><enum>(xiv)</enum><text>1 member of the National Academy of Sciences, to be appointed by the Secretary.</text></clause><clause id="H42F652C6BF704D8C864F6C4919DF8030"><enum>(xv)</enum><text>4 members to be appointed by the Secretary from nominations submitted by the nominating entities described in subparagraph (B).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF46CBB0FAF514F9385E28CCF88BEA927"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Nominating entities described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The nominating entities described in this subparagraph are organizations, associations, societies, cooperative extensions, State agricultural experiment stations, technical assistance provider organizations, councils, federations, producer groups, agriculture manufacturing entities, restaurants, the food service industry, the agriculture technology industry, environmental organizations, forestry organizations, nonprofit organizations, and companies or other entities as determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB8639910378F41818DD7D53CCF39B0E9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Terms</header><subparagraph id="HA500420856934A92BBDD41FA7776B9FF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), members of the Committee appointed under clause (xiv) or (xv) of paragraph (1)(A) shall be appointed for a term of not more than 6 years.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5803FB8FBEFB41B3B074292379025C3C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Terms of initial appointees</header><text>The initial members of the Committee appointed under clause (xiv) or (xv) of paragraph (1)(A) shall be appointed for the following terms:</text><clause id="HF1E6DE5AD3834D34B9D3D4B672BB13EA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>2 shall be appointed for a term of 2 years, which may be extended by the Secretary for an additional 6 years.</text></clause><clause id="H1CDC4214966C432FB4AA5510F016354B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>2 shall be appointed for a term of 4 years, which may be extended by the Secretary for an additional 6 years.</text></clause><clause id="H8020514AC87C44B393F94DFB03577E63"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>1 shall be appointed for a term of 6 years.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5E2047A7B98A4A4AB4AFAA7652E3EE61"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), members of the Committee appointed under clause (xiv) or (xv) of paragraph (1)(A) may not serve consecutive terms on the Committee.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD0DDB13E7A344115B5CB90482E5FEDAC"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Vacancies</header><text>Any vacancy on the Committee—</text><clause id="HE3DAF51B436D4769A3D2A9DE9B671F85"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall not affect the duties of the Committee under this section; and</text></clause><clause id="HE5E4DF1126A344C6B9D748E012660BB2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H83BA22C3C6E5434195F02389E8F2425C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Chairperson, vice chairperson, and executive subcommittee</header><subparagraph id="H3054D786A8B94DD78E5C89E563DA771D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Election</header><text>At the first meeting of the Committee each calendar year, the Committee shall elect from among the members of the Committee—</text><clause id="HB41BD42CCA7149769674FAB0BAFA9E7E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a chairperson;</text></clause><clause id="H5A7ECDABD0B6449FA7EFED5321EADC2E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a vice chairperson; and</text></clause><clause id="H0DF519E0A81B4FCFA231962CCEB02927"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>7 members to serve on the executive subcommittee established under subparagraph (B).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB938B67BD5234E948D2C3BC7FA7A2C3E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Executive subcommittee</header><text>The Committee shall establish an executive subcommittee charged with the responsibility of working with the Secretary and officers and employees of the Department of Agriculture to summarize and disseminate the recommendations of the Committee.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3168D9E282C14756BB5F84EAEADB5EDE" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Consultation and recommendations</header><paragraph id="H3B9E3D2DF3F64ACAB3ED61F268919288" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Duties of Committee</header><text>In fulfilling the duties of the Committee under this section, the Committee shall consult with appropriate agencies of the Department of Agriculture.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7D8CFF07FD5C48DDAB11EAAEBC5E96E5" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duties of Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After receiving recommendations from the Committee pursuant to any provision in this section, the Secretary shall provide a written response to the Committee regarding the manner and extent to which the Secretary will implement such recommendations.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0AEFD0C267A6474CAA47AD48BF4DDCB0"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Compensation and personnel</header><paragraph id="HD4F743E66A264A3A9BCEAEE57E6F278D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appointment of executive director and staff</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To assist the Committee in the performance of the duties of the Committee, the Secretary may appoint, without regard to the civil service laws, and after consultation with the chairperson of the Committee—</text><subparagraph id="HA740A082E17A498C8EA980D662AA21DA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a full-time executive director, who shall—</text><clause id="H743BCAA4BB4A4D769E89E03B40545993"><enum>(i)</enum><text>perform such duties as the chairperson of the Committee may direct; and</text></clause><clause id="H017C8CC23B4F4CDC9946F91446E07D9C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>receive compensation at a rate not to exceed the rate payable for GS–15 of the General Schedule established by section 5332 of title 5, United States Code; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBC10905B54D44BEFB4A298D42D493383"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a professional staff of not more than 3 full-time employees qualified in climate-specific agricultural research, extension, education, and economics, of which 1 shall serve as the executive secretary of the Committee.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H083A14E4D751439CAE26491C9A23426C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additional assistance and personnel</header><text>The Secretary shall detail, on a reimbursable basis, personnel of the Department of Agriculture to the Committee as necessary to assist the Commission in carrying out its duties under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD5C0CBD0BB30467F9ACE248AD945771E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Compensation of members</header><subparagraph id="H1F5E835DC5114ACA8CAE6ACCE5EF7D9B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), members of the Committee shall serve without pay for each day during which such members are engaged in the actual performance of duties vested in the Committee.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC6EE6DF5B791479FA453C7B84208EFC1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Prohibition of compensation of Federal employees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Members of the Committee who are full-time officers or employees of the United States may not receive additional pay, allowances, or benefits by reason of their service on the Committee.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA485A21B16F34F0C9D8653E1EB5DB99A"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Travel expenses</header><text>A member of the Committee shall be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, at rates authorized for employees of agencies under subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/57">chapter 57</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, while away from the home or regular place of business of the member in the performance of services for the Committee.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4C9448DFFAA04239A3B2691EC1936570"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Federal Advisory Committee Act charter</header><text>The Committee shall be deemed to have filed a charter for the purpose of section 1008(c) of title 5, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Federal Advisory Committee Act</quote>).</text></subsection><subsection id="HAA106E868B7A4EEABFD4843C969EC575" commented="no"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>Section 1013(a)(2) of title 5, United States Code, (relating to the termination of advisory committees) shall not apply to the Committee.</text></subsection><subsection id="H7041DFE4CC6245A5B01DD41EF70CE794"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Committee expenses not counted toward general limitations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The expenses of the Committee shall not be counted toward any general limitation on the expenses of advisory committees, panels, commissions, and task forces of the Department of Agriculture contained in any Act making appropriations for the Department of Agriculture, whether enacted before, on, or after the date of enactment of this section, unless the appropriation Act specifically refers to this subsection and specifically includes the Committee within the general limitation.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HD11550C277F44633B2C9D9976344BC5B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rural climate alliance network</header><text>Subtitle C of title XIV of the National Agricultural Research, Extension, and Teaching Policy Act of 1977 is amended by inserting after section 1418 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/3153">7 U.S.C. 3153</external-xref>) the following:</text><quoted-block id="H7D6AC01C824A41D68C3D0D0114B9E997" style="OLC"><section id="HB4973780605B4BCA933197734898CEDB"><enum>1419.</enum><header>Rural Climate Alliance Network</header><subsection id="H4237D35CB0A648369999B3325C626CF2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition of agricultural producer</header><text>In this section, the term <term>agricultural producer</term> means an individual who is engaged in farming, ranching, forestry, aquaculture, or another occupation relating to agriculture.</text></subsection><subsection id="H57E7730683FB463FACD88333B0C4E2E6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of this section are—</text><paragraph id="H208EC8043762402A95A44937457DEB53"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to provide science-based climate adaptation and mitigation assistance and training programs to rural communities and agricultural producers;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H40EEE73ED82742499C40CD842CD4807A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to coordinate the transfer of new technology and research relating to climate change that will impact behavioral and management changes to agricultural systems, including to—</text><subparagraph id="H7DE87B977E6A475A8C726D1DCB66CBEE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>individuals who work in the field of climate science, including agricultural producers; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE7C50B39075048149998885CE06909AD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>individuals, organizations, and other entities with an established history of working with agricultural producers;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H25DFD70BF0694A8EB08D9874AF552130"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to improve agriculture research collaboration, data collection, and partnerships and the sharing of information about new scientific advancements in climate research, as well as inform future research efforts; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H76267C8C53BB48DC9213672B04DED4E1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to facilitate the exchange of regional agriculture climate data and research through a network of partners.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF2B8EB1CD6524141B241E7A4A151B1D9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rural Climate Alliance Network</header><paragraph id="HB3267CB8A7164D4A91BBA63E2129C19F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall establish and administer through the Climate Hubs a network, to be known as the <quote>Rural Climate Alliance Network</quote> (referred to in this subsection as the <quote>Network</quote>)—</text><subparagraph id="HDB340A213F7B41C5A981971009318210"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that serves as a coordination hub for the provision of agriculture climate research, climate data, extension, and technical assistance for agricultural producers, the food and agricultural industry, nonprofit organizations relating to food and agriculture, and researchers relating to food and agriculture to address the effects of climate change; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCF202832C1614C52B57C6E22128704AB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to improve—</text><clause id="HDDDCDDD2119C4CA98B5DD8B17971182A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>responses to climate disasters through data collection and information sharing;</text></clause><clause id="HEB756F102BE342F8BB7ED33D2C696DF6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>communication of climate risks;</text></clause><clause id="HB377F579177A497682693668E9AD4E43"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>accessible education and technical transfer of climate-related, regionally relevant agricultural data and research to agricultural producers in all regionally appropriate languages;</text></clause><clause id="H161CEED231C544B9842045E9D855C7BE"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>tools and networks that deliver information to prevent damage from extreme weather events, pest and disease outbreaks, and other related climate change impacts;</text></clause><clause id="H821DA8B3E36E455BB56D55FDD4EC6FC6"><enum>(v)</enum><text>communication between agricultural producers and the agricultural research community to ensure that agricultural research considers the perspectives of agricultural producers, such as changes in yield and fluctuating costs of inputs;</text></clause><clause id="H5321E3EFD6484650A401BAF706A3BE4C"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>coordination between other Federal agencies, as the Secretary determines appropriate; and</text></clause><clause id="H2DE7066B11044B1B9A5EA019EBDA4861"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>coordination between entities in the private sector, such as participants in the agricultural and food supply chains that work with agricultural producers, relating to climate data, adaptation, mitigation, and response.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H060732029F2B42BCB7FE62D4A95A44FA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Composition</header><text>The Network shall include—</text><subparagraph id="H2DA2820C8DBF4B7C876C506A8540E39C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>entities, and employees of entities, that conduct research, exchange data, provide monitoring and verification services, or provide technical assistance relating to food and agriculture, including—</text><clause id="H08132A22D6AD46C395FF072E6C154261"><enum>(i)</enum><text>colleges and universities;</text></clause><clause id="HCFDFE93143174660AEA7D23AED86964C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>State cooperative institutions;</text></clause><clause id="H23541306C6D94B11BD31094C67A0D434"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>State extension services;</text></clause><clause id="HD0DEC500A2BE4EC790B80993AA0FE395"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>State departments of agriculture;</text></clause><clause id="H3521AE83DE944D4AA43AF6DB9AA07CBD"><enum>(v)</enum><text>State agricultural experiment stations;</text></clause><clause id="HC994AF762DEE446A9C5B47ABB3B276CF"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Indian Tribes (as defined in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>));</text></clause><clause id="HD40FC4503B3F4DCD99686A05B3C1660F"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>qualified nonprofit organizations, as determined by the Secretary;</text></clause><clause id="HD4BC63F1F6C44335A7B919007A444E6C"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>qualified private businesses, as determined by the Secretary;</text></clause><clause id="H32B9E27030514C76864BDAF1DC01B32D"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>agricultural producers, producer groups, or producer organizations, including agricultural trade associations and research and promotion boards (commonly known as <quote>checkoffs</quote>);</text></clause><clause id="H0CFDC8E96E0E4560B429FD0E7CD644F3"><enum>(x)</enum><text>agencies and offices within the Department of Agriculture; and</text></clause><clause id="H8AEADAB669774A039661D25AE108E223"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>any other technical assistance provider, research entity, or data analytics entity that the Secretary determines to be qualified to participate in the Network;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB7CACECFAA3D4899BF1C0F798085FC2E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>climate resilience-related research networks within the Department of Agriculture, including—</text><clause id="H5DA8C049310240EF970A262DD7FE1541"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Long-Term Agroecosystem Research Network;</text></clause><clause id="H86C87E6D8582414E9A943E9C7AB9F751"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Extension Disaster Education Network;</text></clause><clause id="HBFC418F4CB4F4743BA2C479E38FAE92A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the Eastern Forest Environmental Threat Assessment Center;</text></clause><clause id="HB9888E72FA96406FAB529A7F9E864BC3"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the Western Wildland Environmental Threat Assessment Center;</text></clause><clause id="H8CD385147E17477090198805680B656F"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the Sustainable Agriculture Research and Education program;</text></clause><clause id="H181D923811094F0AAE411094E6F8F04E"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the National Soil Dynamics Laboratory;</text></clause><clause id="H404874D02B23471BA7A78729BDA96583"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>the National Cooperative Soil Survey;</text></clause><clause id="H60D5E7EF0ED84FFBA8DC8112B41799DD"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>the Economic Research Service;</text></clause><clause id="HFFBA6FA53F394626B194A23A29DCF30D"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>regional and rural development centers; and</text></clause><clause id="HB90CADD82B68420BA1A602DEAA0FE3BE"><enum>(x)</enum><text>other existing climate-related research networks within the Department of Agriculture that the Secretary determines to be appropriate to participate in the Network; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE237A1CDF83244A994DAE9F9D7AE164B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>other government-affiliated entities and climate resilience-related research networks outside of the Department of Agriculture, including—</text><clause id="H3D336E93BC6B41F29A94D816F02764B0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Foundation for Food and Agriculture Research;</text></clause><clause id="H887EB79C8CC3482EA31EFBD7015D937D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the U.S. Global Change Research Program;</text></clause><clause id="HEC3BF5873A794B2BADA9E92B070C1EB4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>State and public weather station networks;</text></clause><clause id="H837320A38C2843E9BD4F2E1B140F15BC"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the National Weather Service and other weather data systems within the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration;</text></clause><clause id="H0F3DE69128CE45AAA2D74E3575EE93FE"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the harvest program of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration; and</text></clause><clause id="H9E1B1170F397461A883738CD02936200"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>other existing local, State, or Federal climate-related research networks, as determined by the Secretary.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H784242873854433AAA2119C2E63806B5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Activities of the network</header><paragraph id="HC4AAA9FAEAAD4D0293C6B73192425B7D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An individual or entity within the Network may—</text><subparagraph id="H0F3277A038CA4D51A6892F0AD57B950D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>through the means described in paragraph (2)—</text><clause id="HBC68AD75865948859232BEB0EDADB80B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>initiate, expand, or sustain agricultural research programs that build capacity to mitigate, respond to, and recover from climate change disasters, including—</text><subclause id="H516B4DECC6DD4C179553846188941347"><enum>(I)</enum><text>programs of the Agricultural Research Service;</text></subclause><subclause id="HE5D36248BF1C4B5992432799E882291A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the Agriculture and Food Research Initiative;</text></subclause><subclause id="H534C0610C78843EBAFAA1D11F6ED23B6"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the Sustainable Agriculture Research and Education program;</text></subclause><subclause id="H8922C815E51A405C909423AF2ACF333F"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the Agriculture Advanced Research and Development Authority; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HFCAA67FC01CE4C90A284CE8E3F689CC8"><enum>(V)</enum><text>programs of the Foundation for Food and Agriculture Research;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HABBDCC4D9CB14C36A4CE879FCFCEEA36"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>inform and advise about agricultural climate variability, change, vulnerability, risk, adaptation, and mitigation;</text></clause><clause id="HBD554E31ED9E4451BF8DD0717F8D7A3B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>respond to climate impacts on ecosystems, economics, and diversity;</text></clause><clause id="HF28F535FEBA84FA188EA4B879479F515"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>collect and store agricultural climate data to share with other individuals and entities within the Network and Federal research partners;</text></clause><clause id="HB82A5617E00B42BBA7B092DD32C58493"><enum>(v)</enum><text>assist agricultural producers in implementing new management approaches to adapt to, reduce the risk of, and provide societal solutions to mitigate climate change;</text></clause><clause id="H27048D8542524478A1F5909926E9A02E"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>transfer technology, research outcomes, and information; and</text></clause><clause id="H293538E3F5A041AAA3E7F2F3897B7B82"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>improve climate change awareness, education, and planning assistance, as necessary; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7992EF83926E49F08C5A70AD165C31EC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>enter into cooperative agreements or contracts, on a multiyear basis, with community-based, direct-service organizations to initiate, expand, or sustain—</text><clause id="H7260E75FA7A94DABB825A25E1674C215"><enum>(i)</enum><text>activities carried out under subparagraph (A) and paragraph (2); or</text></clause><clause id="H3123963F99594FFD96BA1256C3C65ED8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>programs described in subsection (b)(1).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H430C4C8190574F38A6B5BD882BE73060"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Means described</header><text>An eligible entity may carry out the activities described in paragraph (1)(A) through—</text><subparagraph id="H9D0E0AE81C7D41A8992503FED9A78A45"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the development of phone technology, online applications, websites, handbooks, manuals, publications, warning systems, and other communication networks in all regionally appropriate languages;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H74A2FCEC87914DF6B664F5C7C7FF311F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>training, including training programs and workshops, for disseminating information to—</text><clause id="H27A7C8F851B0481689C674B8FD2282D4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>crop insurance agents;</text></clause><clause id="H5A43C7C088DF40288989C62B1043A7FF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>loan and credit officers;</text></clause><clause id="H98673D47D6B2474984BA3451618EB0FA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>agricultural suppliers;</text></clause><clause id="H30BD353270B24269AEC0B1536DBBCF6E"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>agricultural producers;</text></clause><clause id="H63BB21D453EA4C0389F5EF24C69AEF1D"><enum>(v)</enum><text>State cooperative agents;</text></clause><clause id="H8F7CCABCC9024D75B5CB491507106B6D"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>third-party providers (as defined in section 1242(a) of the Food Security Act of 1985 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/3842">16 U.S.C. 3842(a)</external-xref>));</text></clause><clause id="H6F90784C63CC4E1681E50BB55891DC46"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>Certified Crop Advisers and Certified Professional Soil Scientists certified by the American Society of Agronomy;</text></clause><clause id="H916FB1FC49814EC5B39F0645B942F705"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>Federal officers and employees, including officers and employees of the Natural Resources Conservation Service, the Farm Service Agency, the Agricultural Research Service, and the Forest Service;</text></clause><clause id="H1BE6B58ECA07439DBE6DBACCA2D7BA9C"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>non-Federal technical assistance providers;</text></clause><clause id="H1B026C60AF29411EA95EB880ACF6A5A4"><enum>(x)</enum><text>climate change experts who work with agricultural producers; and</text></clause><clause id="HDC6FEAAB1F88471CA6F6EFCF679DA871"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>other individuals and entities that may—</text><subclause id="HDD3C8E1385BE4E29BA65EA02DC0BF26D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>assist agricultural producers who are vulnerable to climate impacts; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H52A3C4DBAA564BDE969EFDF741FAA235"><enum>(II)</enum><text>provide societal solutions to mitigate the climate impacts of agriculture;</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5A6E96BF780F4A78BBD67274C1D38580"><enum>(C)</enum><text>curriculum development for managing climate risks, mitigating climate change, and understanding climate risks and economic implications; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9F5FDDFF0682469D89CC95F9E26402C8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>such other means as the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB1C95CD9FA664CA58619DB32FEC69264"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><paragraph id="H9F7D7F66CA5A4332AF3E041799D29E8E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Improving Coordination of Agriculture Research and Data Act</short-title>, the Secretary shall submit to Congress and any relevant Federal department or agency, and make publicly available, a report describing—</text><subparagraph id="H79900D6AF676406DA42397CBD07761B9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the current needs of climate mitigation and resilience research and data systems in the food and agriculture sector;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2565C0457F464EAAAF932E3C669D22D4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>progress made toward developing and adopting climate solutions across the food and agriculture system;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8B91E328735242F98713F622EA2D1591"><enum>(C)</enum><text>technical assistance needs of rural communities and agricultural producers;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFF12DA16F3F840AEA22FF1D629E9C460"><enum>(D)</enum><text>actions and recommendations of the Agriculture Climate Scientific Research Committee (established under section 1413C); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H402E541E3F9A466DAD51BDD91D777C2C"><enum>(E)</enum><text>recommended Federal budget activities and funding levels for research, data systems, and technical assistance priorities relating to climate mitigation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H42370FCAAEED4627892D8BF7005D0A75"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report under paragraph (1) shall include—</text><subparagraph id="HBC215168F68645B99FBE86E484DA1A4F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an inventory and assessment of efforts to support the climate change adaptation, mitigation, risk management, and resilience tools for agricultural producers by—</text><clause id="HE01E39623354470BB4CF1904266EAB08"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Federal Government;</text></clause><clause id="H4C5244CAC69C4CDD92A24D4FD263419F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>States and territories of the United States;</text></clause><clause id="H721D2623A6664329910F17C6FF68E7FE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Indian Tribes (as defined in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>));</text></clause><clause id="HF484B413FA2B456C9A8BB9E229BD078C"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>units of local government;</text></clause><clause id="HF64CC2C0D96149DF869F1EC02FF51BA4"><enum>(v)</enum><text>communities comprising agricultural producers;</text></clause><clause id="H5ACA78FD8B7B43E09C3F7981D66BA515"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>qualified nonprofit organizations, as determined by the Secretary;</text></clause><clause id="HEAAA43EFDED745BB8F1E0CDCD216549D"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>agriculture and food businesses;</text></clause><clause id="H1DF790B2AF4D41BBAEAB5B0539CA4110"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>State extension services;</text></clause><clause id="H7E7FB10E45394BB6B91BA06746F00070"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>land-grant colleges and universities; and</text></clause><clause id="H943E93F3F45F48D0B25E122BEE95DE6E"><enum>(x)</enum><text>other appropriate entities, as determined by the Secretary;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H00AD05634FC74366B4245025EB108662"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a baseline report on soil carbon sequestration on measurable soil carbon stocks and sequestration;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8039295BB6DA4354BD5562F8B81F9415"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a description of the challenges faced by agricultural producers that may impact the climate change resilience of those agricultural producers;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H17F1B2FF05AF4C45BF7BB1F8C671C18B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a long-term strategy for responding to the challenges described under subparagraph (C) and recommendations based on best practices for further action to be carried out by appropriate Federal departments or agencies—</text><clause id="H112FA75A7A664D8094F9B7DB92BC94CF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to improve the response by the Federal Government to those challenges; and</text></clause><clause id="H8DBE82B3C0034071B0405D9A8A89D666"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to seek to improve climate change resilience among rural communities and agricultural producers; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2A668DC154EC4A83871C42C80F1448D5"><enum>(E)</enum><text>an evaluation of the impact that climate change challenges faced by rural communities, Indian Tribes, and agricultural producers have on—</text><clause id="H0B740F86A7AF4CC6A5E67DC63CC05E5C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the agricultural workforce;</text></clause><clause id="HD77BD5DE82C940C0B756EC568230F117"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>agricultural production;</text></clause><clause id="H1A88F70CF51743B7B8764BC31E2FD5C0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>rural families and communities, including relating to food security; and</text></clause><clause id="HCBBBDA55612E40AEA483E76C847F6E7D"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>succession planning.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

