<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HAFDCF86264D7471A9FA3EA0440B7DE99" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4960 IH: Beneficiary Enrollment Notification and Eligibility Simplification 2.0 Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4960</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250812">August 12, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000599">Mr. Ruiz</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001257">Mr. Bilirakis</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001190">Mr. Schneider</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to establish a system to notify individuals approaching Medicare eligibility.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HEBAFD36590384F3AA90241BC3FF4DF43" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H0F3A224586944F8A9855CD470E68CCE8"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Beneficiary Enrollment Notification and Eligibility Simplification 2.0 Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>BENES 2.0 Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HF235E1141DD44305A45F447C2FC02018"><enum>2.</enum><header>Beneficiary enrollment notification and eligibility simplification</header> <subsection id="H021E544137F04A879CE51B9DBAF5FC96"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Eligibility and enrollment notices</header> <paragraph id="H1A1A3A84B3E04A5EB0F2E82182B6E503"><enum>(1)</enum><header>As part of social security account statement for individuals attaining ages 60 to 65</header> <subparagraph id="H0AC3DE520516429DAD222075302ABFB6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1143(a) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1320b-13">42 U.S.C. 1320b–13(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2185272C3DB1498594FA43E7875D9CE2">
<paragraph id="H2ED38E199BBD48959A38CA989C09404B" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Medicare eligibility information</header>
<subparagraph id="H21C41E16E2C34914829A30AB0EFEB035"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of statements provided on or after the date that is 2 years after the date of the enactment of this paragraph to individuals who are attaining ages 60, 61, 62, 63, 64 and 65, the statement shall also include a notice containing the information described in subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE6CB31212B374AF1BA20DDD0A73DD754"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Contents of notice</header><text>The notice required under subparagraph (A) shall include a clear, simple explanation of—</text>
<clause id="HD2DF00A1690043F8A2840C10AAD15777"><enum>(i)</enum><text>eligibility for benefits under the Medicare program under title XVIII, and in particular benefits under part B of such title;</text></clause> <clause id="H4F2F04297A034909842AB0063CD9CDF2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the reasons a late enrollment penalty for failure to timely enroll could be assessed and how such late enrollment penalty is calculated, in particular for benefits under such part B;</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" id="H618A6A3EFAC04DC68CC449175C833AA7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the availability of relief from such late enrollment penalty and retroactive enrollment under section 1837(h) (including as such section is applied under sections 1818(c) and 1818A(c)(3)), with examples of circumstances under which such relief may be granted and examples of circumstances under which such relief would not be granted;</text></clause> <clause id="H900B9DFFC2214CB4B078782BD2D858E0"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>coordination of benefits (including primary and secondary coverage scenarios) pursuant to section 1862(b), in particular for benefits under such part B;</text></clause>
<clause id="H154BA64D7AE94AE793BF2715103F5E2A"><enum>(v)</enum><text>enrollment, eligibility, and coordination of benefits under title XVIII with respect to populations, for whom there are special considerations, such as residents of Puerto Rico and veterans; and</text></clause> <clause id="HDB73973AB44949B0A3E5D1262D065CF5"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>online resources and toll-free telephone numbers of the Social Security Administration and the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (including 1–800–MEDICARE and the national toll-free number of the Social Security Administration) that provide information on eligibility for benefits under the Medicare program under title XVIII.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA889AD2453494C7F92A783269AB4EB86"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Development of notice</header>
<clause id="H065036B77ED44751BB80A885FD8A2884"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, in coordination with the Commissioner of Social Security, and taking into consideration information collected pursuant to clause (ii), shall, not later than 12 months after the last day of the period for the request of information described in clause (ii), develop the notice to be provided pursuant to subparagraph (A).</text></clause> <clause id="H02EEA7B81E3E4042A05977AF405DEABD"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Request for information</header><text>Not later than 6 months after the date of the enactment of this paragraph, the Secretary shall request written information, including recommendations, from stakeholders (including the groups described in subparagraph (D)) on the information to be included in the notice.</text></clause>
<clause id="HC252246CBEC94BDEA8733CFD76F793BE"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Notice improvement</header><text>Beginning 4 years after the date of the enactment of this paragraph, and not less than once every 2 years thereafter, the Secretary, in coordination with the Commissioner of Social Security, shall—</text> <subclause id="HD48BE31B741C40A999DC66607F0962D7"><enum>(I)</enum><text>review the content of the notice to be provided under subparagraph (A);</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H4E5A7F84073041AAB1180E05507FB486"><enum>(II)</enum><text>request written information, including recommendations, on such notice through a request for information process as described in clause (ii); and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H9375342B706245068E4A1534A2D823E8"><enum>(III)</enum><text>update and revise such notice as the Secretary deems appropriate.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HCB114D703A054ECE84E0A157E0241B7F"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Groups</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (C)(ii), the groups described in this subparagraph include the following:</text> <clause id="H190093330B184EA083B9ABE9BB907266"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Individuals who are 60 years of age or older.</text></clause>
<clause id="H5CCE15CF51CE4810AC19C7FF29633CEA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Veterans.</text></clause> <clause id="H08E244752B5242EB8FDA41536038B3E3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Individuals with disabilities.</text></clause>
<clause id="HA678FC65CF7D4A2C9812D3345F3636FB"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Individuals with end stage renal disease.</text></clause> <clause id="HF1E9B9D11B2D418F88242C5803A0073B"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Low-income individuals and families.</text></clause>
<clause id="H55D6A01BB5294DAEAEC5742452AF9483"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Employers (including human resources professionals).</text></clause> <clause id="H9A8AAD91FD8F433DA1004ECDABD20FB4"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>States (including representatives of State-run Health Insurance Exchanges, Medicaid offices, and Departments of Insurance).</text></clause>
<clause id="H1D38C5478F9D49BCA8832E586C2F56B2"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>State Health Insurance Assistance Programs.</text></clause> <clause id="H474F043EAA244E3089D96932D0C08123"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>Health insurers.</text></clause>
<clause id="HD07DB63B56454537B5D391EA38367F35"><enum>(x)</enum><text>Health insurance agents and brokers.</text></clause> <clause id="H6CF6A0C571924CC6844A9B2F4CD44194"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>Such other groups as specified by the Secretary.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H1B7E14A67957408CAD5F96E8AD027514"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Posting of notice on websites</header><text>The Commissioner of Social Security and the Secretary shall post the notice required under subparagraph (A) on the public internet website of the Social Security Administration and on Medicare.gov (or a successor website), respectively.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2C134FA0BB9C4B95B86B28786D06BD19"><enum>(F)</enum><header>No effect on obligation to mail statements</header><text>Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed to relieve the Commissioner of Social Security from any requirement under subsection (c), including the requirement to mail a statement on an annual basis to each eligible individual who is not receiving benefits under title II and for whom a mailing address can be determined through such methods as the Commissioner determines to be appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H89E0715367424CD79B8261545ECC168D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Timing of statements</header><text>Section 1143(c)(2) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1320b-13">42 U.S.C. 1320b–13(c)(2)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new sentence: <quote>With respect to statements provided to individuals who are attaining age 65, as described in subsection (a)(4), such statements shall be mailed not earlier than 6 months and not later than 3 months before the individual attains such age.</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6137C705E12C49268E5EDE2E6F3F0979"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Social security beneficiaries</header><text>Title XI of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1301">42 U.S.C. 1301 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 1144 the following new section:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H598ED031FBBC4FEA8A2FCB40D923D953">
<section id="H9FEAA428B2B4487BB17A02ED708CFBC4"><enum>1144A.</enum><header>Medicare enrollment notification and eligibility notices for Social Security beneficiaries prior to medicare eligibility</header>
<subsection id="H21EE1B8A864943A5AC57A8E0BB1AF087"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Notices</header>
<paragraph id="H3F5A5B3A7E83462298E2E27E1C7A8BD1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commissioner of Social Security shall distribute the notice to be provided pursuant to section 1143(a)(4), as may be modified under paragraph (2), to individuals entitled to monthly insurance benefits under title II in accordance with subsection (b).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBCA0E27D00B64E57A8CBEB9467721057"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authority to modify notice</header><text>The Secretary, in coordination with the Commissioner of Social Security, may modify the notice to be distributed under paragraph (1) as necessary to take into account the individuals described in such paragraph.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5BAC29D76C9F4DBFBA5C0CFDFEF73862"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Posting of notice on websites</header><text>The Commissioner of Social Security and the Secretary shall post the notice required to be distributed under paragraph (1) on the public internet website of the Social Security Administration and on Medicare.gov (or a successor website), respectively.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="H4BC4A76FB5D64F1783E36D942B92FD3B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Timing</header><text>Beginning not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this section, a notice required under subsection (a)(1) shall be mailed to an individual described in such subsection—</text>
<paragraph commented="no" id="H88B672118F084766887CDE9C4428298A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the third month before the date on which such individual’s initial enrollment period begins as provided under section 1837; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H9A893402009E43229B6C699CFA08B09F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the case of an individual with respect to whom section 226(b) applies (except for an individual who will attain age 65 during the 24 month period described in such section), in the month before such date on which such individual’s initial enrollment period so begins.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

