<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H8960740B123D46E4B56079EFE05F928D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5548 IH: Fraud Accountability and Recovery Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5548</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250923">September 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000475">Mr. Finstad</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to prohibit the President from providing assistance to the government of any country that has failed to extradite an individual that has been convicted of committing fraud against the United States or that has failed to take all appropriate measures with respect to assisting the recoupment of those funds.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC2AB737B8C0648C696C74B34FF39AD40" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H10F2FABF336743558FE71F3F38C2615B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Fraud Accountability and Recovery Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H0D727199FAF542908F835CBDA25AF4E3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on assistance</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 620 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2370">22 U.S.C. 2370</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block style="traditional" id="H51B565FB34FB45B68261AD622EC5A27A" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="HE8E27D972A0840D483019BF8C1FC65DD"><enum>(z)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No assistance shall be furnished under this Act to the government of any country the President determines—</text> 
<paragraph id="HC92A146EED274DB19FD97C0ECC58C473"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has failed to extradite an individual convicted of committing fraud against the United States or benefitting from the proceeds of defrauding the United States; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDF702BF91CBB46949CC6867870959824"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has failed to take all appropriate legal, administrative, or enforcement measures to assist in the recoupment of Federal funds fraudulently stolen from the United States by identifying, freezing, seizing, and repatriating the funds so fraudulently obtained.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
<section id="H87035EEE971F4EE8A58DD0BAC4C727C2"><enum>3.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> <paragraph id="HDFBAFA0EF1CE4809B724EA68E584868D"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">According to the Government Accountability Office, the Federal Government lost between $233,000,000,000 and $521,000,000,000 annually to fraud from fiscal years 2018 through 2022.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H38DB084B28DE44759C6C3150B8D258B8">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>The range reflects the varying risk environments for fraud—ninety percent of the estimated fraud losses fell in this range.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5047532305BF498BB45B7EC612B38CE1">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In Minnesota, the nonprofit organization Feeding Our Future and associated individuals carried out the largest COVID–19 pandemic fraud scheme in the United States, stealing over $250,000,000 intended to feed hungry children.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9EA09C0F46D542F1A4D022E39A6469BC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Department of Justice has charged 75 defendants in the fraud scheme, and Federal prosecutors have secured multiple convictions against participants in this scheme, which involved the submission of false reimbursement claims, the creation of fictitious meal sites, and the laundering of Federal funds through shell entities and fraudulent invoices.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5CAEFE4BC6474C749DD8B761664210EA"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Charges and convictions in the Feeding Our Future scheme include—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H491295CD5600422EA6346EA052FC7D8E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>wire fraud;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF2AA47A4DE2C4BF08C7EBF85833ED749"><enum>(B)</enum><text>conspiracy to commit wire fraud;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1BC2965705D245A6AC40266E9A88EE26"><enum>(C)</enum><text>theft of government funds;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD5245E5155C940B58AC388341CB72074"><enum>(D)</enum><text>conspiracy to defraud the United States;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5A05657BAE254D3C9EA6866771CDD418"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Federal program bribery;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H011213CC568744A989F49888CBF59E4A"><enum>(F)</enum><text>money laundering; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6B57C54BF4AF425D8987A646C85860AD"><enum>(G)</enum><text>engaging in monetary transactions with criminally derived property.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4E0419DBB4C7467F93E9F94B9E32A8A1"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Some of the proceeds of this fraud were used to purchase luxury real estate and vehicles, and at least one defendant transferred funds and property abroad, including to Kenya, beyond the reach of United States authorities.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H1377DD0D6149413B9B1B3EC06074EED6"><enum>4.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress as follows:</text> <paragraph id="H90956492A27D494C8E99B7047E044656"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States lacks adequate tools to ensure the recovery of stolen taxpayer funds and property transferred overseas, leaving American taxpayers without recourse when foreign jurisdictions fail to cooperate.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE7E6E6ACC8AD4C2297242139DCC9F99F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Strengthening program integrity, recouping stolen funds, and preventing individuals convicted of defrauding Federal programs from seeking international harbor are essential to safeguarding taxpayer dollars and ensuring programs assist those that Congress intended.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H22767992EF314376A4574C79D916FA0D"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Providing additional deterrence by ensuring potential fraudsters lack a safe harbor abroad is critical to preventing future fraud schemes.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HD60D091ACD84407FAAA762B36BFA81B1"><enum>5.</enum><header>Waiver</header> 
<subsection id="H7C399FABB0C94E02B8BBA4DF09F95EC6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may waive the limitation under section 620(z) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961, as added by section 2, if the President certifies to Congress that prohibiting such assistance is contrary to the national security of the United States.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HEAB657BEDE3442B8A63182099AAD074E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prior notification</header><text>Not later than 15 days before the entry into effect of a waiver under subsection (a), the President shall submit to the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate a notification of intent to issue such a waiver, along with a justification.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H05FC92CE839C46BB96E7918DF6B9C9E4"><enum>6.</enum><header>Report on noncompliant countries</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Secretary of State shall submit to the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate a report that—</text> <paragraph id="HB31C8C74DE3549988503615EA3D44359"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">lists each country the President determines has failed to take all appropriate legal, administrative, or enforcement measures as described in section 620(z)(2) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (as added by section 2); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4AC4446B2B0C48678DD0388DC8A1995E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">describes the total amount of fraudulently obtained funds and court-ordered remedies, such as recoveries, restitution, or fines, along with seizures and forfeitures from the United States attributable to the failure to take all such measures by each such country.</text></paragraph> </section> </legis-body></bill>

