<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H09DDCBA7944146B199127A2CFB9D7CFA" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3345 IH: Sovereign States Education Restoration Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3345</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250513">May 13, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001077">Mr. Higgins of Louisiana</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001212">Mr. Moore of Alabama</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To abolish the Department of Education, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H1B9D84067E014769B3B5555283F5A9B9" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HCDFBB550884045BA87B81A209C7F616D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Sovereign States Education Restoration Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H510032D85627428295592633A59947FF" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Abolishment of Department of Education</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Effective on the date that is 270 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Department of Education is abolished, and, with the exception of the programs transferred under section 3, any program for which the Secretary of Education or the Department of Education has administrative responsibility as provided by law or by delegation of authority pursuant to law is repealed, including each program under the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H246F968C4E4C4D7DB66C5704926A3725"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Department of Education Organization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/3401">20 U.S.C. 3401 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H36437260D9A243CC8EAF7FB79560E142" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The General Education Provisions Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1221">20 U.S.C. 1221 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H1ECD32B2452C4338B5D1668DED2DCC27"><enum>3.</enum><header>Transfer of certain department of education programs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act—</text> <paragraph id="H41DF2B4E8FBA40F9AFA4A820EACD376D" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>all functions, programs, and authorities of the Secretary of Education under the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1460">20 U.S.C. 1460 et seq.</external-xref>) shall be transferred to the Department of Health and Human Services;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC8C7E45DB14A49E4AB09F7CB711D6412" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>each authority and program of the Office of Indian Education of the Department of Education shall be transferred to the Department of the Interior;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3915B4B5AB4E400AA1D548AAD5AEF188" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>each Impact Aid program under title VIII of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7701">20 U.S.C. 7701 et seq.</external-xref>) shall be transferred to the Department of Health and Human Services;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H018BBD1C1D974DBAB34D7FB846945E27" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the Federal Pell Grant program under title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070a">20 U.S.C. 1070a</external-xref>) shall be transferred to the Department of the Treasury;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC49A07A0810C4FFB9C897FFEBEA5CFD2"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the Federal Family Education Loan Program under part B of such title IV shall be transferred to the Department of the Treasury;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE0AFD85ED23945C9AB6DA947414B9FA5"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the William D. Ford Federal Direct Loan Program under part D of such title IV shall be transferred to the Department of the Treasury;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7B541F534F274D88B89888F4DC9B9D4E"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the Federal Perkins Loans Program under part E of such title IV shall be transferred to the Department of the Treasury;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB53787BF86494323A546DFEFA1A157D1"><enum>(8)</enum><text>the activities described in part F, G, or H of title IV that are carried out by the Department of Education shall be transferred so as to be carried out by the Department of Treasury;</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDCE7F652981F4BB58832F578FDBA81E6"><enum>(9)</enum><text>the Health Education Assistance Loan program under title VII of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/292">42 U.S.C. 292 et seq.</external-xref>) shall be transferred to the Department of Treasury; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H672A843A55AB49E9B6B445A6B6435EC2"><enum>(10)</enum><text>the programs under the Education Sciences Reform Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/9501">20 U.S.C. 9501 et seq.</external-xref>) and the Educational Technical Assistance Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/9601">20 U.S.C. 9601 et seq.</external-xref>) shall be transferred to the Department of the Treasury.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H5C9D68B629044A6C85FDB943CF210A69"><enum>4.</enum><header>Block grants to States</header> <subsection id="HE18B3641A30E48BD816A7A497868ADC0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Elementary and secondary education State block grant program</header> <paragraph id="H702BA8EC161F4E778817F460473CF745"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury shall carry out a program under which the Secretary makes allocations to States to support elementary and secondary education, including career and technical education.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC2D4ABC27F264BF8873BBA8B4F5CAB06" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Allocations to States</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The allocations made by the Secretary of Treasury to each State under this subsection for a fiscal year shall be in an amount that bears the same relationship to the amount appropriated to carry out this subsection for the fiscal year as the number of students in kindergarten through grade 12 who were enrolled in public, private, and home schools in the State for the previous fiscal year bears to the number of such students in all States for the previous fiscal year.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8B545753DA0240B3B614C4D941DCBAC8" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>A State that receives an allocation under this subsection shall use such funding for any purpose relating to early childhood, elementary, or secondary education.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H4D56D132CCC64F4497727CF3301C5FEE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Postsecondary education State block grant program</header> 
<paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H0806177B86304F1AA3A83603E22E7663"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In General</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury shall carry out a program under which the Secretary makes allocations to States to support postsecondary education.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDAF4EBD235D34D57BCA867D3E0160F2F" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Allocations to States</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The allocations made by the Secretary of Treasury to each State under this subsection for a fiscal year shall be in an amount that bears the same relationship to the amount appropriated to carry out this subsection for the fiscal year as the number of students who were enrolled in postsecondary educational institutions in the State for the previous fiscal year bears to the number of such students in all States for the previous fiscal year.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="HB7B64DE0879A476891DCD1EDA07AFC7E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Block grant conditions</header><text>As a condition of receiving a block grant under this subsection, a State shall provide the Secretary of Treasury with an assurance that the State will carry out each of the following:</text> <paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H2AD0A0518C054451B433E7C9A3CE8D18"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Submitting student data to the Secretary of Treasury, annually, as requested by the Secretary of Treasury and as necessary for executing the program under this section.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H3D67AB5AC0DD4465840011F8743B2C90"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Completing of annual audits that conform to generally accepted accounting principles, auditing procedures, and safeguarding of funds that conform to <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/75">chapter 75</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Single Audit Act of 1984</quote>) and submitting the results of such audits to the Secretary of Treasury.</text></paragraph> <paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H01C94206B3034181A864FF1F56B15FD3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Complying with all applicable Federal civil rights laws, including those described in section 5.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H9BEFC66C0094482AAD4D4140A6E0A99C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Misused or misappropriated funds</header><text>If the Secretary of Treasury finds that any funds under this section have been misused or misappropriated by the State, the Secretary of the Treasury—</text> <paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H60A703EBA92E4522B9CA61A26245AF89"><enum>(1)</enum><text>may require repayment of the misused funds and withhold Federal funds under this section for the next fiscal year; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H1E4BA1469A8B4E38AA802758B46FC756"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may reach a voluntary resolution agreement with that State.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H589DD6B7AB324283917C55B120FA3EE4"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H136A7C7FDAFA4FBD9F4FF2C0CF7A2C1C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>State</term> means each of the 50 States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, and each of the outlying areas; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8DBC2C10A6CF4CC090EC32B8603A8AEB"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>outlying area</term> means American Samoa, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, Guam, and the United States Virgin Islands, the Republic of the Marshall Islands, the Federated States of Micronesia, and the Republic of Palau.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="HEF630051464D46C78600F3B4777DEBD5"><enum>5.</enum><header>Civil Rights Laws</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Civil Rights Division of the Department of Justice shall be responsible for receiving complaints and otherwise enforcing and carrying out Federal civil rights laws that are applicable to the grant programs under section 4 and the programs described in paragraphs (4) through (7) of section 3, including—</text> <paragraph id="H4C09B9EC61734B9C9F25B1756720D67C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>section 504 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/794">29 U.S.C. 794</external-xref>);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC70D13F3BBBB45A4AAC9B0C8425491A3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>title IX of the Education Amendments of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1681">20 U.S.C. 1681 et seq.</external-xref>); or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H97FD37EDCEF04C82B747E514AB883EB7" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><text>title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d">42 U.S.C. 2000d et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H8F466DF90F104C7E969C3E7B1FB7F8C3"><enum>6.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out sections 3, 4, and 5, an amount equal to the total amount appropriated to the Department of Education for fiscal year 2019, of which—</text> <paragraph id="H9BF251672A6242679FE0D5003F534501"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not more than 50 percent shall be used to award block grants to States under section 4; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H65F920E2C84F4A0EBC59DAB8EFD395DD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not more than 20 percent shall be used for the administration and oversight required by Federal agencies under this Act.</text></paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

