<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="HB26FCB76F8D34B11BF26D1DC8E69888A" resolution-type="house-resolution">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 574 IH: A resolution expressing support for the designation of a “Faith and Defiance Day,” honoring the victims of the July 13th, 2024 shooting, condemning political violence, and acknowledging the positive impact President Donald J. Trump has had on America.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress>
<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 574</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20250710">July 10, 2025</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000619">Mr. Rulli</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">A resolution expressing support for the designation of a <quote>Faith and Defiance Day,</quote> honoring the victims of the July 13th, 2024 shooting, condemning political violence, and acknowledging the positive impact President Donald J. Trump has had on America.</official-title>
</form>
<preamble>
<whereas><text>Whereas America is a nation rooted in faith and founded in defiance of an unjust authority;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas President Trump, after being struck by a would-be assassin’s bullet on July 13th, 2024, stood in an act of faith and defiance, pumping his fist and rallying Americans to “fight, fight, fight!”; </text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas Corey D. Comperatore, a devoted husband and father, was tragically killed while shielding loved ones from the hail of gunfire during the July 13th attack;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas James Copenhaver and David Dutch were grievously injured in the July 13th attack; </text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas numerous supporters in attendance, including an emergency room physician, heroically provided comfort and medical aid to the victims of the July 13th attack;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the brave efforts of the Secret Service, local law enforcement agencies, first responders, and medical professionals prevented further harm during the attack;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas President Trump rightly stated God alone prevented the unthinkable from happening;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the motto of the United States, “In God We Trust,” reflects the enduring faith that steeled President Trump for a return to Butler, Pennsylvania, even after an additional assassination attempt occurred just five miles from his home on September 15th, 2024; </text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas Donald J. Trump was elected as the 47th President of the United States in the 2024 election, winning with an Electoral College margin of 312–226, while also securing the national popular vote and winning every swing State; and</text></whereas> <whereas> <text>Whereas President Trump has continued his “fight, fight, fight” for what is best for the United States of America, resilient in his faith and defiant in the face of wickedness; Now, therefore, be it </text>
        </whereas></preamble>
<resolution-body style="traditional" id="H49FC76BB254C483D97C8CD59F8FD4F91">
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HE76B73BFFF8A4FF4B2154C4853B4A1C1"><enum/><text>That the House of Representatives:</text> <paragraph id="H57B3CE6D8D9A4A6EB28852F7E373E599"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Supports the designation of a “Faith and Defiance Day”.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H50470B81E5CD4130ADB38D888595B7FA"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Honors the life and heroism of Corey D. Comperatore.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H73CD331CEDD841E29EA8446EB12AD980"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Recognizes James Copenhaver and David Dutch for their strength and courage in recovery.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H183DCB66E9BB4E0E9CE90599126A778A"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Condemns all acts of political violence, regardless of target or motive.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCCDA7BB05073401ABE47652A335E614C"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Acknowledges the positive impact our 45th and 47th President Donald J. Trump’s leadership has had on national policy and public sentiment.</text></paragraph></section>
</resolution-body>
</resolution> 


