<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-WAL25045-KFC-YF-J8V"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>107 S438 IS: Providing Individuals Various Opportunities for Technical Training to Build a Skills-Based Cyber Workforce Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 438</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250205">February 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S381">Mr. Rounds</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S380">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to provide for education and training programs and resources of the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency of the Department of Homeland Security, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H1C6C886A710C4E7C974CCB511478254B"><section section-type="section-one" id="HD81799692F1845269EB27C426CE26252"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Providing Individuals Various Opportunities for Technical Training to Build a Skills-Based Cyber Workforce Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Cyber PIVOTT Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HFCE9B8882ADC49B6AFA472F6E323701F"><enum>2.</enum><header>CISA education and training programs and resources</header><subsection id="H5693CC2AB44A47149E2532894B454634"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subtitle D of title XIII of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/107/296">Public Law 107–296</external-xref>; 116 Stat. 2298 et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following new section: </text><quoted-block id="H72D159CE78314760AD1A068BE03FA778"><section section-type="subsequent-section" id="H7E9DFCE618494CCB8508604E4F2A4F7C"><enum>1334.</enum><header>CISA education and training programs and resources</header><subsection id="HDF55FDD9AB494650BA3FDD93AC3071AD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id159131b179414be2a4593b4b2f683c5f"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Armed Forces</header><text>The term <quote>Armed Forces</quote> has the meaning given the term <quote>armed forces</quote> in section 101 of title 10, United States Code. <italic></italic></text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida46a0759970440f683e1441a6d59ff1f"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Community college</header><text>The term <quote>community college</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 5002 of the William M. (Mac) Thornberry National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9401">15 U.S.C. 9401</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idA6C86080B15F47339D68E16DE707845A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Cyber-relevant</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>cyber-relevant</term> means an area of national security that would impact the cyber resiliency of the United States, including relating to operational technology, critical infrastructure, artificial intelligence, quantum computing, security awareness, or computer science. </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2277f6ea38d44e00ad14dfb06dc27d30"><enum>(4)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Director</header><text>The term <quote>Director</quote> means the Director of the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0910c5b86ed941a3b5d18cbbefaecb88"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Executive agency</header><text>The term <quote>Executive agency</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 105 of title 5, United States Code. </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide482295badd146a0948f41e894e6bb0b"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text>The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given the term in section 101(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8395da2bd3334487a5c8386d38ccb383"><enum>(7)</enum><header>NICE Cybersecurity Workforce Framework</header><text>The term <quote>NICE Cybersecurity Workforce Framework</quote> means the National Initiative for Cybersecurity Education (NICE) Cybersecurity Workforce Framework (NIST Special Publication 800–181, revision 1, published November 16, 2020).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id09463fa7dba04dc6b675f4a2d9ebb4ec"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Participating institution</header><text>The term <quote>participating institution</quote> means a community college, technical school, or other institution of higher education offering 2-year programs with which the Director has entered into a partnership or other arrangement as described in subsection (b)(1)(A).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida7acfba6688c4fe08187f3652001919d"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Program</quote> means the <quote>Providing Individuals Various Opportunities for Technical Training to Build a Skills-Based Cyber Workforce Program</quote> or the <quote>PIVOTT Program</quote> established under subsection (b)(1). </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idB807DCD040F84DB283EA75CE14EBD3C0"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Skills-based exercise</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>skills-based exercise</term> means a condensed program lasting not less than 1 day that focuses on practice and application, rather than research and study. </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id693db089d4d3410bb3bb355cba9cdce2"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Technical school</header><text>The term <quote>technical school</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 411.167 of title 20, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0b9fbe5eb8414f8bb90148424828c1ab"><enum>(12)</enum><header>University-level educator</header><text>The term <term>university-level educator</term> means an educator that teaches at the level of an institution of higher education.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id65befadb0d5b4b9e9f75ae31295982e4"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Expanding education and training programs and resources to community colleges, technical schools, and other institutions of higher education offering 2-Year programs</header><paragraph id="HC3D4F1E8185047FCBAF6C5C16F8ED339"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment of PIVOTT Program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this subsection, the Director shall establish a program—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0cd58bffeeec4504b29828d57ffc0f70"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">under which the Director shall seek to enter into partnerships or other arrangements with community colleges, technical schools, and other institutions of higher education offering 2-year programs to establish educational and training programs and facilitate internship and post-graduation Federal job opportunities at participating institutions; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id63fee459f6584b2a82ece3ab47351b30"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that shall be known as the <quote>Providing Individuals Various Opportunities for Technical Training to Build a Skills-Based Cyber Workforce Program</quote> or the <quote>PIVOTT Program</quote>. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id77d69cb399da46eca4130e4d74ca99bf"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Student qualifications</header><subparagraph commented="no" id="H4567E733CE4C479A8E533FE28492EA21"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>The following categories of students shall be eligible to participate in the Program:</text><clause commented="no" id="HB0CFC7C0350A4D389FA0548E902539A3"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Students who are enrolled in but who have not yet started a 2-year cyber or cyber-relevant associate’s degree program or comparable technical certification, as determined by the Director, at a participating institution. </text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H1CE871B6DBFF404D9825DE668D4DAD48"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Students who are currently enrolled in their first semester of a 2-year cyber or cyber-relevant associate’s degree program or comparable technical certification, as determined by the Director, at a participating institution.</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H65FB16369EAC4DDBB75760561AB1D70F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Students identified by the Director who are eligible and qualified to enroll in a 2-year degree cyber or cyber-relevant associate’s degree program or comparable technical certification at a participating institution, such as individuals who are pursuing a career change, have a high school diploma or equivalent, or would be considered entry-level employees.</text></clause><clause id="H9E1804B1B1DF4D31B3AFB4171FD96C75"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Students enrolled in technical certifications at participating institutions that are less than 2 years in duration but— </text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id618d909ab4104b6b86305e13ec83c1cc"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">align with Tasks, Knowledge, and Skills, as described in the NICE Cybersecurity Workforce Framework; and </text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida991afcba04c4185bd9601439f00b1ca"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prepare students to serve in Federal, State, local, Tribal, or territorial government cyber or cyber-relevant roles.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H8C7CE3A9434D474F97E9DBA28B0FBC07"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Scholarships</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, acting through the Director, shall provide students participating in the Program with full tuition scholarships, including academic fees, lab fees, travel, lodging, per diem, stipends, internship costs, costs associated with virtual participation, certification testing fees, and any other expenses the Director determines necessary to complete any requirement under the Program, including for participation in 1 in-person skills-based exercise in accordance with paragraph (4)(B), including travel, lodging, meals, in-person or in-laboratory post-course assessments fees, and other necessary expenses as determined by the Director.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBD7178A9CD2F4C2E961AC0C0D46307B8"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Service obligation</header><clause id="H99F47FD426F84734A117E26428379FA1"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each student who participates in and completes the Program shall fulfill a 2-year service obligation in a cyber or cyber-relevant role, as described in the NICE Cybersecurity Workforce Framework or the Department of Defense Cyber Workforce Framework, to advance the cyber mission of an Executive agency or a State, local, Tribal, or territorial government.</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="HB739E1227EC3486C97A1AAB6C4BE961B"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The service obligation specified in clause (i) shall not apply to any student who—</text><subclause commented="no" id="H90DBB2928DB049A59A0869D52762533D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>has completed a term of service in the Armed Forces that is equal to the service obligation specified in clause (i);</text></subclause><subclause id="H37F3E362F2B1430BA5697CFDCC8B5BC8"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is currently serving in the Armed Forces; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H00ABC75639BE48BD822C73DCBEF220AE"><enum>(III)</enum><text>pursues service in the Armed Forces in a cyber or cyber-relevant role during or immediately after the date on which the student completes the Program.</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" id="H47EE4DF15E51413F8BB0BEBA9395A31D"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Delayed service</header><text>Any student who, immediately after the date on which the student completes the Program, enrolls in a 4-year degree program may complete the service obligation specified in clause (i) after receiving such 4-year degree.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HB5D7D9FC226A420A99197004CC294BDF"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Program completion timeline</header><clause id="H06152AD19A00448F8AC808B5DE7E0AE7"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each student who participates in the Program shall complete participation in the Program not later than 4 years after the date on which the student begins the Program, or pursuant to rules of the relevant participating institution if such rules are in effect at the time the student begins such participation.</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H20BE7B0955224AB792A492B85E28609B"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Process for updated completion timeline</header><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3c3fa8e2fbec474dafde3e59d2b2b30c"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Application for waiver</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any student who experiences extreme hardship during participation in the Program may submit to the Director an application to waive the application of the timeline specified in clause (i). </text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5592784843814d2c96849f486d41d53a"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Determination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director, in consultation with the appropriate participating institution, shall determine on a case-by-case basis whether a student who submits an application for a waiver under subclause (I) may be granted additional time to complete the Program.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7E5B5D3DE80D465783305E90DBE444F7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Institutional requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A community college, technical school, or other institution of higher education is eligible to participate in the Program if the community college, technical school, or institution of higher education is—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H13634A45E237428391C7786DC2D4B585"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a participant in the National Centers of Academic Excellence in Cybersecurity program; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H86E95050347F448A93D74B8A523A6E3A"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">determined eligible by the Director, taking into consideration— </text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id22ce852982694b48991d69f34b032540"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether the virtual or in-person course offerings of the community college, technical school, or institution of higher education align with career pathways, as described in the NICE Cybersecurity Workforce Framework; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2590ba2db80f47879fb17b2feb1f5a43"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the presence of a cybersecurity clinic on campus.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEB227A8EF68140CB82B74D51F20F6ACC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Program components</header><subparagraph commented="no" id="H8458310A65564751BF992260F3B1C37A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In accordance with subparagraph (C), students participating in the Program shall complete a minimum of 4 eligible skills-based exercises described in subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7CD064888F4642F1A52F1D0B44CAAEDE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Eligible skills-based exercises</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Eligible skills-based exercises described in this subparagraph may include the following:</text><clause id="HD2C2DFEAE413492F8D3E46D7EA2E2FA7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Laboratory work.</text></clause><clause id="H93833187E45F4306A7902281593D08DD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Competitions such as hackathons, challenges, and capture the flag.</text></clause><clause id="H4FB95E3E884C4C5D9309D0824C4A2D75"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Virtual programming.</text></clause><clause id="HAE0732F69A0E4E00929B6A26F00AB6B0"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Table-top exercises.</text></clause><clause id="HBADA6FA42FDF42E1A04161A0E5482C0F"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Industry training workshops.</text></clause><clause id="H5997D165966D4174A447F1FF7689F5B1"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Exercises in a box.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD705430FDF7E416DBB128268A74C327A"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Provision</header><clause commented="no" id="H21F1F847EA384AAE95123AAD88B7F54A"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall coordinate with participating institutions to provide not fewer than 1 skills-based exercise required under subparagraph (A) each semester.</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H5DBA20EAEC7141FDAEE445E16F713D2D"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Student requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Students participating in the Program shall complete not fewer than 1 of the 4 skills-based exercises required under subparagraph (A) in person.</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H28C8977097714F7EBB1B015A088F4807"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Administration of exercises</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director, in coordination with participating institutions, shall offer not fewer than 1 in-person skills-based exercise to Program participants every 2 years.</text></clause><clause id="H5F8B885D53774428B88CC507CF45EF11"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall coordinate and may jointly offer the skills-based exercises required under subparagraph (A) with the following:</text><subclause id="H6EF79850E4714AA89C7EC15B8AD9A45F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Other Federal agencies, such as the Department of Defense, the Federal Bureau of Investigation, the National Security Agency, and the Office of the National Cyber Director, as appropriate.</text></subclause><subclause id="H0CCD94697DE743C2AC48787F474AD3AD"><enum>(II)</enum><text>Non-Federal entities with cyber or cyber-relevant expertise, including cybersecurity clinics.</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" id="H8F2D9ABF158F49ABB8CB7675A1EEB137"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>A student participating in the Program who is unable to complete a skills-based exercise required under subparagraph (A) may submit to the participating institution a proposal for a comparable skills-based exercise, as determined by the Director.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCBC23B6D50D942089BEC6DF355C0FA23"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Internships</header><clause commented="no" id="H4AB9C3873DD847AD8D95EFE37D033CB6"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director and participating institutions shall, as a core requirement of the Program, coordinate with appropriate entities to place students participating in the Program in an approved cyber or cyber-relevant internship, as determined by the Director, with any of the following:</text><subclause id="HEE451822EE824E6B8F9B428E1046EF74"><enum>(I)</enum><text>A State, local, Tribal, or territorial government entity.</text></subclause><subclause id="H489743CF771F4D61B04AB93D223AFA2A"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A critical infrastructure owner or operator that is located in a rural community or is considered to be a high-risk sector, as determined by the Director.</text></subclause><subclause id="H44F2B1E3164E4C9483CDBDE544749F16"><enum>(III)</enum><text>A Federal department or agency, including with the Regional Security Advisors program of the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency.</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" id="H53C46F767C704903959CA6A7A820E466"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Prioritization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A student who has communicated in writing to the Director or the appropriate participating institution during the internship placement process that the student intends to serve in a Federal Government position beyond the obligations of the student under paragraph (2)(C) shall be prioritized for Federal cyber internship opportunities that require a security clearance.</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="HCE6891C34A874F3BA438FFBFABC86117"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Current Federal employees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall coordinate with the heads of appropriate Federal agencies to establish an approved cyber or cyber-relevant internship program for students participating in the Program who are Federal employees.</text></clause><clause id="HA6395DB75939418887AA4A77CBE374BF"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Security clearances</header><text>The Director shall take such actions as may be necessary to begin, not later than 1 year before an appropriate student under this subparagraph completes participation in the Program, the process to provide the student with an appropriate security clearance.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H341CF2D3F9984DEDBA9B51C8C8C5F170"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Outreach initiatives</header><subparagraph commented="no" id="H1EC6CC8776FE47A18303BC25EEEF84EA"><enum>(A)</enum><header>CISA</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1c93e7c6a1034e9f80e86ebfbaacd33f"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Responsibilities of Director</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall—</text><subclause commented="no" id="H11844C35755A47C59590DDF7D9094B27"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conduct regional outreach initiatives, including at institutions designated as National Centers of Academic Excellence in Cybersecurity, and provide informational materials about the Program—</text><item id="H108E1A667915460A9312160EF6E6C053"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>at each regional office of the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency; and</text></item><item id="HEF79550B12104FA5A9C5B33EED272AFB"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to industry partners to promote the Program; and</text></item></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H2CD6C576BBF5458789A177928A488AEB"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">seek to engage with industry stakeholders to produce an annual report—</text><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2f192b4c5e2f46139491744b1032a0b1"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">on industry-relevant skills intended to inform the skills-based exercises offered under the Program; and</text></item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id739ef74d87104e94bb5245c0dadd833a"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>that—</text><subitem commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf1d74d1275f24262a8dc8b8641f116f2"><enum>(AA)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may include input from an advisory committee, established by the Director and composed of university-level educators; and</text></subitem><subitem commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id97509757443846188c3e40354a868697"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>shall be submitted to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section, and each year thereafter. </text></subitem></item></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc262559c7b304e09a16a25d5c7920ea0"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>FACA exemption</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/10">Chapter 10</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, shall not apply to the advisory committee established by the Director under clause (i)(II)(bb)(AA). </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H43FD9287B3CF439D97B7CE42A2F3FF72"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Recruitment fair</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id50f9ece586e4497fb2d69e7539ee2815"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each fiscal year, the Director, in coordination with the National Cyber Director, shall host a voluntary Federal Government recruitment fair that includes Federal Government agency representatives who seek to recruit for vacant cybersecurity positions. </text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id63895dd3b4d94ed38ba0e10bc29f5cd4"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Information regarding recruitment fair</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall post information regarding the recruitment fair required under clause (i) on a dedicated website of the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency. </text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id85c580a049d9490994fd62986cd9cc87"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Hosting of recruitment fair</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each recruitment fair required under clause (i)—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id63876894bb8844a1b894dcb3013f28d0"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may be hosted online or in-person; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id28311f5c718149afa5d93d617654adc0"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall be hosted at not fewer than 5 participating institutions.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2897B6349D984936B52C5A412A21DB41"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Program completion benefits</header><subparagraph commented="no" id="H56E1CB9F87B946838C933D525892D699"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Database</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director, leveraging existing educational content repositories, shall maintain an online database that shall—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id282e6b94b4354b15a10fc83bb051557d"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide cyber training and education resources, mapped to job roles set forth in the NICE Cybersecurity Workforce Framework, and information relating to Federal job opportunities in cyber or cyber-relevant fields; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idedc62d933bab4e718e83d37218b32458"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be made available for access by, as appropriate, students who have successfully completed the Program.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H331031AE3E064CB4A50C91B571B9193C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Certification program</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6b1128286f1a47c1a71a0376b23528f6"><enum>(i)</enum><header>List of certification programs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall establish and update annually a list of existing cyber certification programs developed or offered by entities in the private sector, academia, nonprofits, or other institutions, as determined by the Director. </text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id12466e505f964f50b94c74abd4d14886"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, acting through the Director, may fund, through vouchers requested by a student participating in the program, not more than 3 certifications and associated certification examinations per student from the list established under clause (i), provided that any such student shall have completed the Program and requested the voucher not later than 10 years after the date on which the student completed the Program.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H1743BC2EB68C474C9A4E705224E6BA52"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Additional scholarship opportunities for students who complete the program</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc80b212a16ce458d988219526e8b648a"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director may select, pursuant to an application process designed by Director, not more than 10 students per year who have completed the Program and have been employed by the Federal Government for not less than 7 years to be eligible for scholarships to be applied to cyber or cyber-relevant degree programs offered at institutions designated as National Centers of Academic Excellence in Cybersecurity. </text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide59e457c19964485ac476db136fb13e0"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Amounts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Scholarship amounts under this subparagraph shall be determined by the Director, subject to the availability of appropriations for such purpose.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H570AFC396E5F48FA95652FE7575E0425"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Terms of Program scholarship</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5a8be1d9f61049f2a3c712c6f77d6b16"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), a scholarship recipient under this section shall be liable to the United States for repayment of a scholarship awarded to the recipient as provided under subsection (e) if the recipient—</text><clause id="H5970E9F30CC04AC48B235A92B5617030"><enum>(i)</enum><text>fails to maintain an acceptable level of academic standing at the participating institution, as determined by the Director;</text></clause><clause id="H979BE7FE816A488CBD2B03EED3DDDD4C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is dismissed from the participating institution for disciplinary reasons;</text></clause><clause id="H5ACD4E2E1D594C3BAD2A0D32BC2FD275"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>withdraws from the eligible degree program before completing the Program;</text></clause><clause id="H4AD0DF88FD0546B3ADD57C6FC5971CA0"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>declares that the recipient does not intend to fulfill the post-award employment obligation under this section; or</text></clause><clause id="H30061F83241B4A95A12E401A628DF657"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">fails to maintain or fulfill the post-graduation government service or post-award obligations or requirements of such recipient.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H075FA199E6E8459A907A7BB22D0402D3"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director may, on a case-by-case basis, exempt from liability for repayment a scholarship awarded to a student who is participating or has participated in the Program if the relevant student—</text><clause id="H29732FA51A6947579D32ADE785193626"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">enlists or commissions in the Armed Forces prior to completion of the Program; or</text></clause><clause id="H2BE99578053C43DFB58201C951775F67"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has a documented history of demonstrated effort to secure a position with a Federal, State, local, Tribal, or territorial government within 2 years after the date on which the student completes the Program but who is not offered such a position.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HB33F650A2DAF4EF987F3A096A1415F85"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Monitoring compliance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As a condition of participation in the Program, a participating institution shall enter into an agreement with the Director to monitor the compliance of recipients of scholarships awarded under this section with respect to the post-award employment obligations of such recipients.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H9BBFA5D36E94491AA3CA44DC88DCC0DF"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Amount of repayment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a circumstance described in subsection (b)(7)(A) occurs before the completion of 1 year of a post-scholarship employment obligation under this section, the total amount of scholarship awards received by an individual under this section shall—</text><paragraph commented="no" id="HE0E31648BAD644ED80766A3550526CDA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be repaid to the Department immediately; or</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H6131FC469DD947E58B878CFFF15E172D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>be treated as a loan to be repaid in accordance with subsection (e).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC6783FAC913E4FAD8ACD3F6007EDE96F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Repayments</header><text>A loan referred to subsection (d)(2) shall—</text><paragraph commented="no" id="H7E688366A109404D812986AC54FE646F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>be treated as a Federal Direct Unsubsidized Stafford Loan under part D of title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087a">20 U.S.C. 1087a et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9C3966F5C78846AA8ECEAD5C723C7967"><enum>(2)</enum><text>be subject to repayment, together with interest thereon accruing from the date of the scholarship award, in accordance with terms and conditions specified by the Secretary (in consultation with the Secretary of Education) in regulations promulgated to carry out this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBDFC4F31E63E4CB2A83E221F028DEC07"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Collection of repayment</header><paragraph commented="no" id="HF91E4B8DDFE4484D844103D57B80216F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a scholarship recipient is required to repay a scholarship under this section—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H8DB555DA80F9480C968244522D68BF55"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary shall determine the repayment amounts and notify such recipient of the amount owed; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H33DC1E3CCF604634BAA59E143DF8CE0E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary, or a participating institution acting on behalf of the Secretary, shall collect such amount within a period of time as determined by the Secretary, or such amount shall be treated as a loan in accordance with subsection (e).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H4E8DCBA66589433B98DD66CC0410AE05"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Returned to the Department</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in paragraph (3), any repayment under this subsection shall be returned to the Department. </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H4EA75AC3AB3D476E8519057E5EF7D1A4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Retention of percentage</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id081f564ef2a74c17b086615a598906b6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A participating institution may retain a percentage of any repayment the participating institution collects under this subsection to defray administrative costs associated with the collection of such repayment. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id89029d08224645d99a005b4724074366"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Percentage applicable</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish a single, fixed percentage that participating institutions may retain from repayments collected under subparagraph (A) that shall be applicable to all participating institutions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H5FBCCD5C2C274CEE89F73045A702AF0C"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may provide for the partial or total waiver or suspension of any repayment obligation by a scholarship recipient under this section if compliance by the scholarship recipient with the repayment obligation is impossible or would involve extreme hardship to the scholarship recipient.</text></subsection><subsection id="H4F3D38C19A634143B21D41BA027479C6"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Timeline for implementation</header><paragraph commented="no" id="H8D20544CFC5B46F8A2FAABDC2866E15E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director and participating institutions shall seek to enroll in the Program, subject to the availability of appropriations, not fewer than 250 students for the first full academic year of the Program that begins 1 year after the date of the enactment of this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H3BA041665FF0417E9494E436344D44DD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Growth of program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning with the second full academic year of the Program, the Director and participating institutions shall seek to enroll in the Program each full academic year, subject to the availability of appropriations, not fewer than double the number of students enrolled in the immediately preceding full academic year until the number of such students reaches 1,000 each full academic year.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HC91355EBA7C6444F9E4E89B273415A07"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Plan for 10,000 students</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8ecc0624b1f946b380ef4c3df500b158"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Development of plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Director and participating institutions shall develop a plan, subject to capacity and administrative capabilities, to enroll by not later than 10 years after the date of the establishment of the Program not fewer than 10,000 students in the Program each academic year. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id60e2abc0d7f841329d44f5146585d522"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Briefing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall brief the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives regarding such plan.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HDC3D12EEDA9F4BA5945FBFCABE2C7B71"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Report on enrollment goals</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Director and participating institutions fail in any academic year to meet the minimum quota specified in paragraph (1) or (2), as the case may be, of subsection (h), the Director shall brief the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives not later than 30 days after the conclusion of that academic year.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HFA7CAB3075404619B6772721748A0E27"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents in section 1(b) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/107/296">Public Law 107–296</external-xref>; 116 Stat. 2135) is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 1333 the following new item: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE299AD83C128409E9834268422197A9E"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 1334. CISA education and training programs and resources.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HF233223AA4664A19850D15F46BDFDAF2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Review of CISA education, training programs and resources</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director of the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives a review of the education and training programs of the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency, which shall evaluate the cost, reach, and current demand of those programs, including relating to any resource gaps in any of those programs.</text></subsection><subsection id="H243B0D03146E4381BC0D571C35DCCA0E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Promoting Cybercorps Scholarship for Service as a gold standard program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Homeland Security and the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives a report on current support provided by the Department of Homeland Security to the CyberCorps Scholarship for Service Program, including opportunities to provide additional funding to the CyberCorps Scholarship for Service Program under existing training and education programs of the Department of Homeland Security.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

