<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-RIL25154-7R4-WN-91V"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 84 ATS: Congratulating the Philadelphia Eagles on their victory in Super Bowl LIX in the successful 105th season of the National Football League.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 84</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250219">February 19, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S418">Mr. Fetterman</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S433">Mr. McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S426">Mr. Kim</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S430">Ms. Blunt Rochester</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Congratulating the Philadelphia Eagles on their victory in Super Bowl LIX in the successful 105th season of the National Football League.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, on Sunday, February 9, 2025, the Philadelphia Eagles defeated the Kansas City Chiefs by a score of 40 to 22 to win Super Bowl LIX in New Orleans, Louisiana;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Eagles made their fifth Super Bowl appearance and won their second Super Bowl;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Eagles took the lead with under 7 minutes remaining in the first quarter via a 1-yard rush by Eagles quarterback Jalen Hurts utilizing the <quote>Tush Push</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Eagles never relinquished their lead for the duration of the game;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the combined efforts of the Eagles offensive line, the tallest and heaviest starting offensive line in NFL history, paved the way for 135 total rushing yards in the game;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Eagles quarterback Jalen Hurts completed 17 of 22 pass attempts for 221 yards and 2 touchdowns, rushed 11 times for 72 yards and 1 touchdown, and was named Super Bowl LIX’s Most Valuable Player;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Eagles kicker Jake Elliott went 4-for-4 in field goal attempts and 4-for-4 in point-after-touchdown attempts, including a 50-yard field goal;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Eagles running back Saquon Barkley of Coplay, Pennsylvania, rushed 25 times for 57 yards, adding to his overall rushing total of 2,504 yards for the 2024–2025 NFL season and postseason, the most rushing yards in a single season of any running back in NFL history;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas wide receiver Devonta Smith led the Eagles with 4 receptions for 69 yards and 1 touchdown;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas defensive end Josh Sweat led the Eagles defensive line with 2.5 sacks of Patrick Mahomes and 2 tackles for loss;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Eagles cornerback Cooper DeJean intercepted a pass from Patrick Mahomes and returned the pass for a touchdown in the first quarter, the first interception return for a touchdown by a rookie player in Super Bowl history;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas linebacker Zack Baun led the Eagles defense with 7 tackles and intercepted another pass from Patrick Mahomes with less than 2 minutes in the first half;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Eagles defense held the Chiefs offense to 0 points in the first half;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the entire roster of the Eagles contributed to the Super Bowl victory;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the victory of the Philadelphia Eagles in Super Bowl LIX instills a sense of pride for Eagles fans across the country; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas people all over the world are saying, <quote>Go Birds!</quote>: Now, therefore, be it </text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="idaac55f2f63b84e55b2da22550d21a3c1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>congratulates the Philadelphia Eagles and their entire staff and fans everywhere of the Philadelphia Eagles for their victory in Super Bowl LIX; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id61e19a0d634544f794c73a931ac327ea"><enum>(2)</enum><text>respectfully directs the Secretary of the Senate to transmit an enrolled copy of this resolution to—</text><subparagraph id="id2708ae113a664825ae9ade1c17678e73"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the chairman and chief executive officer of the Philadelphia Eagles, Jeffrey Lurie;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8b56658463b646458e0d4ecace66b615"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the executive vice president and general manager of the Philadelphia Eagles, Howie Roseman, and the head coach of the Philadelphia Eagles, Nick Sirianni; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idedfdd0fa5e854970b715b0086e54d83b"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the senior advisor to the general manager and chief security officer for the Philadelphia Eagles, Dom DiSandro.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

