<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H312DE162C6784AEEBF7235618FC62975" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4471 IH: No More Narcos Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4471</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250716">July 16, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000136">Mr. Vasquez</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="C001133">Mr. Ciscomani</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish and implement an informational campaign and national strategy to prevent minors from working with cartels and transnational criminal organizations.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF1CBC97C7D5E492E9E9918D6C1FB6309" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HAE9344BD71AE4F6C894E78DDCACC8A3A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No More Narcos Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HC3CF789E950C4F66BAEF1D473E5F93DB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Informational campaign and national strategy</header> <subsection id="HEAC095CA68654C6E94CBFA3C98E24DE0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General, acting through the Administrator of the Drug Enforcement Administration and in consultation with the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Secretary of Education, the Director of National Drug Control Policy, and such other Federal, State, local, or tribal agency as may be appropriate, shall establish and implement an informational campaign to educate covered students on the dangers and risks of working with cartels or other transnational criminal organizations.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H570CEF367C0E45A888EFA8A6B47389EE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>National strategy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security shall establish and implement a national strategy to combat cartels and other transnational criminal organizations targeting and recruiting minors in the United States to engage in unlawful smuggling or trafficking activities.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HB205AC37B2D94BE59EA1851387903826"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="HF5382D8DA9AF4BF78466DFFC4562619E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered student</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered student</term> means students in middle grades and high school in United States communities 100 miles or less from the United States-Mexico border.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9F55CF5EAA8F4DF4B22ACEFD968E6211"><enum>(2)</enum><header>High school</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>high school</term> has the meaning given that term in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE83F903BD7AF4C69847F8853889151D2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Middle grades</header><text>The term <term>middle grades</term> has the meaning given that term in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H888D8B94BF7D4B7EB0825FAEA4062AFE"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Minor</header><text>The term <term>minor</term> means an individual who has not attained 18 years of age.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4B8DCFA4DFB545189AC061752C1E6DF6"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Transnational criminal organizations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>transnational criminal organization</term> means self-perpetuating associations of individuals who—</text> <subparagraph id="H57FCC4ACCF0A4BEFAB4F76109276A592"><enum>(A)</enum><text>operate transnationally for the purpose of obtaining power, influence, monetary or commercial gains, wholly or in part by illegal means, while protecting their illegal activities through—</text> 
<clause id="H90C25D7038874BEB87FD903EC5949392"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a pattern of corruption or violence; or</text></clause> <clause id="H392747ED903349C98637474157E266D4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a transnational organizational structure and the exploitation of transnational commerce or communication mechanisms. Transnational criminal organizations; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6A435E22FF9747E8B07DFA628EDD5B3F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>engage in a broad range of criminal activities, including drug and weapons trafficking, migrant smuggling, human trafficking, cybercrime, intellectual property theft, money laundering, wildlife and timber trafficking, illegal fishing, and illegal mining.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H83D4F000A26540C8B65596D00ACA4D6C"><enum>3.</enum><header>DOJ Assets Forfeiture Fund</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 524(c)(1) of title 28, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H4C87F7A54BFB40E483A9E4B4D3F65ECC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (I), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE8AF64C5857B4B718FC8F4B8310FF7BB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (J)(ii), by striking the period and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4B2985025D7B46E8A6F88F5385EAB293"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (J) the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H5B6D51AC20794F75AF3418F881CBAE50" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subparagraph id="H206D931E38C54A58805427E08364B840"><enum>(K)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">payments for—</text> 
<clause id="HC47E8ADCDB1E429392D025EF7716AC1E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the informational campaign to educate students on the dangers and risks of working with cartels or other transnational criminal organizations under the No More Narcos Act; and</text></clause> <clause id="H179E3F2362DA4C90B6EF5FD7E8364AF9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the national strategy to combat cartels and other transnational criminal organizations targeting and recruiting minors in the United States to engage in unlawful smuggling or trafficking activities under such Act.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

