<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-NEW25429-X6N-66-9Y8"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 175 ATS: Recognizing April 14, 2025, as “World Quantum Day”, and commemorating and supporting the goals of World Quantum Day.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 175</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250410">April 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S391">Mr. Young</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S388">Ms. Hassan</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S275">Ms. Cantwell</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing April 14, 2025, as <quote>World Quantum Day</quote>, and commemorating and supporting the goals of World Quantum Day.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas quantum physics describes nature at the scale of atoms and subatomic particles;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas <quote>World Quantum Day</quote> is celebrated by scientists in more than 70 countries to promote public understanding of quantum science and technology around the world;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States has recognized quantum information science, engineering, and technology as a key technology area for economic competition;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas quantum information science, engineering, and technology can solve problems that current technologies and computing methods cannot;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas quantum physics helps us to understand and develop technologies critical to everyday life, such as GPS, semiconductors, and lasers;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas quantum information science, engineering, and technology may be able to make transformative breakthroughs in fields as varied as logistics, material sciences, and life sciences;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas quantum information science is a multidisciplinary field, bridging science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (referred to in this preamble as <quote>STEM</quote>);</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas STEM is a critical part of education for children, and aptitude in STEM is essential for a knowledge-based society and for economic competition;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States needs to reinforce STEM education for all students in order to better prepare children for future careers in emerging technologies, including quantum, to succeed in a 21st-century economy;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas STEM can be a fun and interesting part of education for children, and learning about quantum principles of superposition and entanglement can be an engaging way to teach children and attract children to study STEM;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas 2025 marks 100 years since the inception of quantum mechanics, and the United Nations has proclaimed 2025 as the <quote>International Year of Quantum Science and Technology</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Planck constant is a fundamental constant governing quantum physics, which is used to define universal measurements such as the kilogram; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the rounded first significant digits of the Planck constant are 4.14, and thus April 14 of each year is internationally recognized as <quote>World Quantum Day</quote>: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id311d3a7c8f5c4456a74643b04a484b5d"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognizes April 14, 2025, as <quote>World Quantum Day</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8fb5041b5e6846e28fa5f93b855a89c8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>supports the goals of World Quantum Day to recognize and celebrate the role that quantum physics plays in our daily lives; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0d8c455eb24a4449bb7cc9d026d22b8d"><enum>(3)</enum><text>encourages schools and educators to observe World Quantum Day with appropriate activities that teach students about quantum physics and engage students in the study of science, technology, engineering, and mathematics. </text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

