<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H43F5ADD825304F269E288B268570718A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4925 IH: Original Securities and Exchange Atonement Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4925</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250808">August 8, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Green of Texas</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Securities Act of 1933 to require covered issuers to carry out a racial equity audit every 2 years, to require atonement for the descendants of enslaved persons, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H93513CF5F0F04A2CA8E1604EE1FA4AEE" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H53E66F384DDB49ACAC694EDDBC9B0509" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Original Securities and Exchange Atonement Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section>
<section id="HF80D5296EE41477EBD9530575E657F15"><enum>2.</enum><header>Racial equity audit</header>
<subsection id="H5AA5985363284E1DBA292C6EFFBD0439"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Securities Act of 1933 is amended by inserting after section 4A (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/77d-1">15 U.S.C. 77d–1</external-xref>) the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H80B51CA8B1FB4349B9EC49DD29B894BA" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <section id="H5B9E3603FD2846D0BE74AD356E0CE01D"><enum>4B.</enum><header>Racial equity audit</header> <subsection id="HFBA950BF03E04F56988027C856317DB9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than the end of the 6-month period beginning on the date of enactment of this section, and every 2 years thereafter, each covered issuer shall—</text>
<paragraph id="HE7A97EBD196E4DA48E29FAA22A577FC4"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conduct an independent audit to assess within each line of business—</text> <subparagraph id="HF5DA394C2E6E4AFE8D48EA49427A9481"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the issuer’s policies and practices on civil rights, equity, diversity, and inclusion;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H60C339CFFC7B4191B2B3661FD7F16527"><enum>(B)</enum><text>how such policies and practices affect the issuer’s business; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6DB747504BCA4468B4B82774EECC72D7"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether the issuer, any predecessor institution of the issuer, or any affiliate of the issuer had direct or indirect ties to or profited from the institution of slavery;</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD317C5E4230346FA914EE895A630FA98"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">issue a report to the Commission containing—</text> <subparagraph id="H013338DDA51C4AE98C51C88BE5F9D502"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case of—</text>
<clause id="HF8D7315F3A554E8D98AA912E15DB7E7E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the initial report or any subsequent report for which the covered issuer determines material changes have occurred since the previous report, all findings and determinations made in carrying out the assessments required under paragraph (1); or</text></clause> <clause id="H35BE0375D3FC48E1B9E933DE544E51C2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a subsequent report for which the covered issuer determines no material changes have occurred since the previous report, an attestation that no material changes were found under the assessments required under paragraph (1);</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H8E735E4E6BF342F1B80FDAEE804B4EBC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to the extent the issuer identifies ties to or profits from the institution of slavery, a disclosure of the steps the issuer has taken to reconcile such ties or profits; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HECA69F1A350A47BD932D092F17CDC3AB"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to the extent the issuer identifies ties to or profits from the institution of slavery and has not taken steps to reconcile such ties or profits, a disclosure of the steps to reconcile such ties or profits the issuer plans to take, which may include—</text>
<clause id="HC17BDA75393043828E91EC04CBC2C5B3"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">startup capital and funded savings programs in low to moderate income communities for low to moderate income individuals residing in such communities;</text></clause> <clause id="HBA69C570F9264D38A0E893CDE6F4054C"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>grants or contributions to historically Black colleges and universities; and</text>
                  </clause>
<clause id="H05FC1B35E21C464AA7AA137767BCE267"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">grants or contributions to historically black organizations exempt from taxation as described in paragraph (3) or (4) <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and exempt from taxation under section 501(a) of such Code; and</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA43517A7784E465194F2FCC407758EAF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>make the report described under paragraph (2) available to the public, including on a website of the issuer and a website of the Commission.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H4E70B461B4B64BE8A61E7EFB22E102AA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Failure To issue report</header>
<paragraph id="H142D925F6F2F4DCB963782798793FDB3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Enforcement by Commission</header>
<subparagraph id="HC678BB2BD75D4DDEAA3F595FC3ACAF76"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Covered issuer fines</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any covered issuer that fails to issue a report required under subsection (a)(2), or that reports false, misleading, or inaccurate information in such a report, shall be fined by the Commission in an amount of $20,000 per day until the report is issued, or until the report is corrected to not be false, misleading, or inaccurate, as applicable.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5C97924A231A462A90108A59DC9FC8EC"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Employee fines</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any employee or officer of a covered issuer who intentionally fails to issue a report required under subsection (a)(2) or that reports false, misleading, or inaccurate information in such report, shall be fined by the Commission in an amount of $2,000 per day until the report is issued, or until the report is corrected to not be false, misleading, or inaccurate, as applicable.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H59A2AC7AC0164B16BB195B652CCD6A80"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Transfer of amounts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall transfer—</text> <clause id="HE9245B68F5A0459B90CB7BC0B2EEC5CB"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">50 percent of the fines collected pursuant to subparagraphs (A) and (B) to the Secretary of the Treasury, and the Secretary of the Treasury shall, without further appropriation, use such funds to carry out the duties of the Office of Minority Low to Moderate Income Programs; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H17AF514349464ADCA5069DB49B48E82B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">50 percent of the fines collected pursuant to subparagraphs (A) and (B) to the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, and the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development shall, without further appropriation, use such funds to carry out—</text> <subclause id="H4169F83C501749C2B62DABFB493FB430"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a program to provide housing counseling and homebuyer assistance, including downpayments, closing costs, and interest rate buydowns, to first-time, first-generation minority low to moderate income homebuyers;</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H285D59026DD2458FAF1492DCAB013ACD"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">eviction and foreclosure assistance to minority low to moderate income renters and homebuyers;</text></subclause> <subclause id="HFADBE919DD004184AEDE17792D5E4BAC"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">affordable housing production under the Housing Trust Fund established under section 1338 of the Federal Housing Enterprises Financial Safety and Soundness act of 1992 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/4568">12 U.S.C. 4568</external-xref>), including permanent supportive housing for people experiencing homelessness;</text></subclause>
<subclause id="HC6C8B0DB5EB341D5AFF59113492C682C"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">rental assistance to eligible low income households under the Housing Choice Voucher Program under section 8(o) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437f">42 U.S.C. 1437f(o)</external-xref>); and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H582C07E9AC874A3FAFDC7FFCD433F217"><enum>(V)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">formula grants to participating jurisdictions to conduct Equity Plans under the rule of the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development implementing the requirement under the Fair Housing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3601">42 U.S.C. 3601</external-xref>) to affirmatively further fair housing.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1C2DDBE8D61F4FE5B5B5F1D1CA8A5E2C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Private right of action</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person that holds the securities of a covered issuer and suffers harm as a result of the failure of such covered issuer to issue a report required under subsection (a)(2), may bring an action against the covered issuer in the appropriate district court of the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCAB2AC95BB18471D8526733429B01751"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Whistleblower awards</header> <subparagraph id="H8C7FE0787A354674A757842AEE005F82"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall pay an award or awards to 1 or more individuals who voluntarily provided original information to the Commission that led to the successful enforcement of the fines required under subparagraph (A) or (B) of paragraph (1) in the case of the failure of a covered issuer to issue a report required under subsection (a)(2) or that reports false, misleading, or inaccurate information in such a report.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H06A27B7C5B5C4CA2A6E631111E1F08C9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Amount</header><text>The amount of an award under subparagraph (A) shall—</text> <clause id="HA887C7D9AE424B598F7F9ECC4C0FC5C1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>be established by the Commission by rule in an amount that the Commission determines is sufficient to create incentive for individuals to voluntarily provide original information and deter noncompliance with subsection (a); and</text></clause>
<clause id="H1B46CCC8B94648729B54B02C2CA704D7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>not be less than $20,000.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFBEA37C3E3464818BA925045C74046D5"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Original information defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this paragraph, the term <quote>original information</quote> means information that—</text>
<clause id="H146F73D1422642C3A15DE0A6D5DECA34"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is derived from the independent knowledge or analysis of an individual who voluntarily provides the information to the Commission;</text></clause> <clause id="H3DE45B816225436D847B0526E381717E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is not known to the Commission from any other source, unless the whistleblower is the original source of the information; and</text></clause>
<clause id="HFD1DE176CFFB45278E0D54E0572B26C4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>is not exclusively derived from an allegation made in a judicial or administrative hearing, in a governmental report, hearing, audit, or investigation, or from the news media, unless the whistleblower is a source of the information.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H9B95866D360F40DF92E95AF2B1730DAE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text>
<paragraph id="H2A5A99C1314D49CB831CA85F21AFF3C0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Area median income</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to an individual, the term <quote>area median income</quote> means the median income for the area in which the individual lives, as determined by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development for purposes of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437">42 U.S.C. 1437 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7B6A5FE7BF4141C89F1AACBCF6725FF5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered issuer</header><text>The term <quote>covered issuer</quote> means an issuer that—</text>
<subparagraph id="H957A66474F534317A358C69CAE171737"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">makes use of the mails or any means or instrumentality of interstate commerce; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6AA92E6CADE54714B62FEA1995975B99"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has—</text>
<clause id="H72EFCFDC47E345468EA09B75E639982B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>more than 100 employees; or</text></clause> <clause id="H0A29DA1AF2A044F3A1B4C03076EF5F09"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a capitalization of greater than or equal to $300,000,000.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H3409EA40424144FE904EE1DAA0A9094A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Low to moderate income</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to an individual, the term <quote>low to moderate income</quote> means the individual has earnings of less than 80 percent of the area median income.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCF400CFC35DC4DCEAE18E006092832C1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Minority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>minority</quote> means racial and ethnic populations that are underrepresented in the general population relative to the number of persons in the total population.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7EC3A4FB259445C3A97154A7424A49EF"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Reconcile</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>reconcile</quote> means to account for and balance in an equitable manner.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H38200952C26445B5855CC1C09C6CF47B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Office of Minority Low to Moderate Income Programs</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/3">Chapter 3</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code, is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="H06C0E7B6D63441C98DB3CD053EBB8367"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subchapter I, by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="HF5190279407F4774884E51797F73C64A" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <section id="H7174BAD67C8B4A63826AB004C1136ECA"><enum>317.</enum><header>Office of Minority Low to Moderate Income Programs</header> <subsection id="HE04FB85EF37A4E8191A7503F1C1013DF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established, within the Department of the Treasury, an Office of Minority Low to Moderate Income Programs.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H16D2C1F49E934F3D97D241CB5C7F960D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Office of Minority Low to Moderate Income Programs shall provide grants for—</text> <paragraph id="HF97568E05C5E4DBB94FFAF46DD92D94E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>startup capital and funded savings programs in low to moderate income minority communities for low to moderate income minority individuals residing in such communities; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2CF6C38F8F144D9A9C70BD0BD159149B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such other programs determined appropriate by the Secretary in furtherance of atonement for descendants of enslaved persons.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H1002C1E9235646D2BF8B5EB81A99DA5C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Funding</header> <paragraph id="HFDAB0FC3D8A347A7B25AA56674085F54"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of the Treasury $3,000,000,000 to carry out this section.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE2EC3370B7C948E5BD9EC48B0330CEF6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administrative costs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury may use 2 percent of amounts appropriated to carry out this section for administrative expenses related to carrying out the duties of the Office of Minority Low to Moderate Income Programs.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE1E3CAEF570E410CB8E23D62BC059ED6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text>
<paragraph id="H4DA1C7C1C8734887B7DA31C00C4D155C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Area median income</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to a community, the term <quote>area median income</quote> means the median income for the area in which the community is located, as determined by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development for purposes of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437">42 U.S.C. 1437 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H703BE9ECF167453397C2B04E2353773E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Low to moderate income community</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>low to moderate income community</quote> means a census tract in which 51 percent or more of the households located in the census tract earn less than 80 percent of the area median income.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H824B61A6DC5E457394993B6FC86C81E6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the table of contents for such chapter, by inserting after the item relating to section 316 the following:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="H3EA09F84B2354F00B4BBD4A56104B41C" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">317. Office of Minority Low to Moderate Income Programs.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

