<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6EB39040B07F4CB3AD94C38151A63EF3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4447 IH: Transit Bus Affordability Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4447</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250716">July 16, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000476">Mr. Frost</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="T000463">Mr. Turner of Ohio</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Comptroller General of the United States to conduct a review of the efficient use of funds in procuring new buses for transit service, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC8B34CAAD03B4E218E71EA8BA5B29745" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H99317D5DAEB74D71BB11F47E05524C0E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Transit Bus Affordability Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HA7BD65DF9FE745079F01E3017B297B87" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Report on options for procuring buses for transit service</header> <subsection id="H70464C7A4AC844DBB3339B50E88ED368"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a review of the factors responsible for the high and rising costs of transit bus manufacturing and procurement in the United States in order to recommend ways to mitigate those costs and promote the efficient use of Federal, State, and local funds in procuring new buses for transit service.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8064C7E2B3B549F1A4550084560C20B6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>In conducting the review under subsection (a), the Comptroller General shall analyze the following:</text> <paragraph id="H972E167C66144A10916EA83677B985A1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The primary cost drivers in the design and procurement process for transit buses in the United States.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD79F717A0E1748EB8024D7EB610A848B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A comparison of—</text> <subparagraph id="H0FD2DCD127E4495F9EF126952552B42E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the costs to design, manufacture, and procure transit buses in the United States with the costs to design, manufacture, and procure such buses in other countries; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC39CC7AD3B00495E8C74D7F112602C96"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the most recent 10-year period for which data is available, the increase in price of transit buses with increases in the prices of medium-duty vehicles, school buses, and other commercial vehicles.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H31B54B477F7A47AABFC2C85F1F7A6683"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The effects of bus manufacturing and supplier challenges on bus procurements funded by the Federal Transit Administration, such as buses procured pursuant to the low or no emission grant program and the buses and bus facilities competitive grant program under section 5339 of title 49, United States Code.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8D828461588849F4B75E8D47BCF45796"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The steps taken by the Administrator of the Federal Transit Administration, States, transit agencies, manufacturers, and industry stakeholders to reduce bus costs and accelerate delivery timeframes, including a description of—</text> <subparagraph id="HD2AC686CE90F4CE1B8F08ED9AC6D84DD"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">what is known about how likely such steps are to affect the costs and manufacturing timeframes for new transit bus orders;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H29BE65C1C7934AF7B73D5B70ECD17F14"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the effect of the use of State contracts and joint procurement on vehicle costs; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H59E4A742E7D641ED9562A616757CD387"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any additional authorities identified by stakeholders that the Administrator or transit agencies may need to help minimize bus costs and delivery delays.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HBDB2D13D235C4AE4BA7690B7BF679F46"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General shall submit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a report on the review conducted under this section.</text> </subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

