<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0EAFAD140748406ABF5554CEB672E310" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4795 IH: Protect Economic and Academic Freedom Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4795</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250729">July 29, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000450">Ms. Foxx</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to prohibit an institution that participates in a nonexpressive commercial boycott of Israel from being eligible for certain funds under that Act, to require an institution that participates in certain programs under that Act to certify that students are not unreasonably obstructed from participating in academic programs in Israel, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF7C2AD3559FA4338BE220E7F14D5D3ED" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HF644C8D5885F488894FE562C55E62FE0" section-type="section-one" commented="no"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protect Economic and Academic Freedom Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H5F09C54663154A30AED5C00421B3E3D4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Ineligibility of institutions of higher education participating in certain nonexpressive commercial boycotts</header> <subsection id="H54BEE6E600FD4D0FBD533C44EF308603"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Ineligibility</header><text>Part B of title I of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1011">20 U.S.C. 1011 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEAC10B5C89C645588B4253A68D0A2396" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H22B13DB3D53B4B0E911A96549044A613"><enum>124.</enum><header>Ineligibility of institutions participating in certain nonexpressive commercial boycotts</header> 
<subsection id="HCE02F49F47104D0BB1C4E68886EDEA8E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than July 31 of each year, an institution of higher education that participates in any program under title IV shall certify to the Secretary that the institution will not engage in a nonexpressive commercial boycott of a major strategic partner of the United States for the period beginning on the date of such certification and ending on July 31 of the following year.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H216A33580F7A4F379C1391FB57FB7EC2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Public availability of list; notification</header><text>Not later than 7 business days after July 31 of each year, the Secretary shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H028637728EAC4EB5A6E6071B9B636373" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identify and make publicly available on a website of the Department a list of all institutions of higher education described in <internal-xref idref="HCE02F49F47104D0BB1C4E68886EDEA8E" legis-path="124.(a)">subsection (a)</internal-xref> that did not submit a certification under such subsection for such year; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H358FB2A87D8646069928A181490DC20D" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">notify each institution of higher education identified pursuant to <internal-xref idref="H028637728EAC4EB5A6E6071B9B636373" legis-path="124.(b)(1)">paragraph (1)</internal-xref> of such identification and inclusion on such list.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H91365629350E4FF6810F6F80CBAA4485"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HF1E83E6E524F4DA89641829EAF1F6DA7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Major strategic partner</header><text>The term <term>major strategic partner</term> with respect to the United States means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H66FEFC6D95B74D8382F188A5FC437685"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a country described in section 4 of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/296">Public Law 113–296</external-xref>; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC1E3E621D89948B6905208867F45E3DE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an entity licensed or regulated by, or organized under the laws of, such a country.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H59528417E1644774B0A7805A583C36EE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Nonexpressive commercial boycott of a major strategic partner</header><text>The term <term>nonexpressive commercial boycott of a major strategic partner</term>—</text> <subparagraph id="H6CE632A4B077455883332016766E23D8" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means a commercial action (including engaging in refusals to deal and terminating business activities) that—</text> 
<clause id="HBB89AD8903644BAFAE10DB7684B1C882"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is intended to limit commercial relations with a major strategic partner; and</text></clause> <clause id="H36D6E6640A354287AAB6DDBDF803244D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is not based on a valid business reason; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAE15A7F761B8491E8E9E6D0D2A64408F" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not include actions described in regulations issued to provide for the exceptions described in section 1773(a)(2) of the Anti-Boycott Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4842">50 U.S.C. 4842(a)(2)</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HB359A804215D435AAA88BC108727447B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Program participation agreement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 487(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1094">20 U.S.C. 1094(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HF13004669D8E4828BDE1750326E8B818" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="H297813717DC64D11B18D821DEB9A1522"><enum>(30)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The institution will comply with the requirements of section 124.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> <section id="HC929274B3EC649A485655CE366D856E9"><enum>3.</enum><header>Eligibility for title VI funds</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title VI of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1121">20 U.S.C. 1121 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new sections:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H513F69940C554B5EB3EF5536D3677BAE" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="H8316AB3B439041119F52B671AC994972"><enum>639.</enum><header>Institutional certifications</header> 
<subsection id="H93C583E0D890434B8C7587E4ACE360EB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Annual requirement for institutional eligibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than July 31 of each calendar year beginning on or after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Protect Economic and Academic Freedom Act of 2025</short-title>, an institution of higher education participating or applying to participate in any program under this title shall submit to the Secretary the certification required under <internal-xref idref="HEBFD00DA5B5849D3A704F66078A10738" legis-path="639.(b)">subsection (b)</internal-xref>. An institution that does not submit such certification by July 31 of a calendar year shall be ineligible to receive any funds under this title in the first fiscal year that begins after such July 31, including any funds under this title that would otherwise have been available to the institution in such fiscal year for a grant awarded during a previous fiscal year.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HEBFD00DA5B5849D3A704F66078A10738"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Certification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An institution shall certify to the Secretary that, for the period beginning on the date of such certification and ending on July 31 of the following year, the institution will—</text> 
<paragraph id="H0FDD5C77215C4CCD8EE084085FA243E1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">permit students and faculty of the certifying institution to participate in academic programs, including conferences, teaching exchanges, cultural exchanges, study abroad programs, joint research, and other collaborative educational activities, in a major strategic partner (as defined in section 124) of the United States in the same manner, and under the same terms and conditions, as students and faculty of the institution are permitted to participate in academic programs in other foreign countries; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB6BF741B0BF24B068921474094A06F2F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">permit students and faculty of postsecondary educational institutions in such a major strategic partner to participate in academic programs offered by the certifying institution, including conferences, teaching exchanges, cultural exchanges, study abroad programs, joint research, and other collaborative educational activities, in the same manner, and under the same terms and conditions, as students and faculty of other foreign postsecondary educational institutions that are not in such a major strategic partner.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HAA1B9621FA8946898433D8D2D461E737"><enum>639A.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that limitations on cooperative efforts by institutions of higher education, consortia of such institutions, or partnerships between nonprofit educational organizations and institutions of higher education with a major strategic partner (as defined in section 124) of the United States do not serve the security, stability, and economic vitality of the United States.</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> </legis-body></bill>

