<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H97C7641B0AB54CCCAADF0251C658E784" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2647 IH: Safe Workplaces Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2647</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250403">April 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000191">Mr. Neguse</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Labor to issue nonmandatory guidance on reducing the threat of violence in the workplace, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H99A2352F6A6549D78CFA973EC8A2FDC9" style="OLC"><section id="H8F53C67516EC49758E2F77831DD3D8E9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Safe Workplaces Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="HFB36C65C45594850B9F5093E54BE8366"><enum>2.</enum><header>OSHA guidance on reducing the threat of violence in the workplace</header><subsection id="H11885EE2D1444BF5B752626D6C5C4991"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health shall conduct a study on reducing the threat of violence in the workplace. </text></subsection><subsection id="H8000BC7E61A342C68D96DC774285C9E3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 15 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director shall submit to the Secretary of Labor, the Committee on Education and Labor of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate a report on the results of the study conducted under subsection (a), which shall include recommendations that the Secretary of Labor shall consider when issuing the guidance described in subsection (c).</text></subsection><subsection id="H861FB8B539B0462783D2FCB6B4F21E80"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Guidance</header><paragraph id="HA46CF5DE5073484589B8D8D8F89C98B3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 4 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Labor, acting through the Occupational Safety and Health Administration, shall issue nonmandatory guidance on activities and work practice controls that can be implemented by workplaces to reduce workplace violence. Such guidance shall be differentiated to the extent necessary to account for the unique characteristics of, and the potential for threats of violence at, of each variety of workplace, including grocery stores, retail stores, movie theatres, hospitals, office buildings, restaurants and bars, religious facilities, manufacturing facilities, mail distribution centers, community centers, child care centers, and schools.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9B7B1C05A2F344C99E37C582CBE5ACDE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consideration</header><text>In issuing the guidance required under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall—</text><subparagraph id="HC54E57564897446995EDB5B144254B36"><enum>(A)</enum><text>consider the recommendations included in the report required under subsection (b); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE440F313894E4B76AFC0CB900CD66782"><enum>(B)</enum><text>take into account engineering controls, dangerous weapons, and environmental risk factors that may impact a workplace.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBCA9CDF7E4B14CAA9AA45D40F93E5745"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H504C19041499478597C8FD00B124DFF3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Dangerous weapon</header><text>The term <term>dangerous weapon</term> means an instrument capable of inflicting death or serious bodily injury, without regard to whether such instrument was designed for that purpose.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF6C271F4A776483B9495A15FEE815988"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Engineering controls</header><subparagraph id="HBAD8EF7F16F54591841C7D973FA29EC3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>engineering controls</term> means an aspect of the built space or a device that removes a hazard from the workplace or creates a barrier between an employee and the hazard.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC5001E3BADAD4754980066F1D9075292"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text>For purposes of reducing workplace violence hazards, the term <term>engineering controls</term> includes electronic access controls to employee occupied areas, weapon detectors (installed or handheld), enclosed work­stations with shatter-resistant glass, deep service counters, locks on doors, removing access to or securing items that could be used as weapons, furniture affixed to the floor, opaque glass, closed-circuit television monitoring and video recording, sight-aids, and personal alarm devices.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5BC1A45E28354938B212B0E063F6F936"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Environmental risk factors</header><subparagraph id="HC0CD4E1CD2B94CAC866539A079AA40EB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>environmental risk factors</term> means factors in the facility or area in which a service is performed that may contribute to the likelihood or severity of a workplace violence incident.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1D10AB398CEC444A898C21E4E7B1F57A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Clarification</header><text>Environmental risk factors may be associated with the specific task being performed or the work area, such as working in an isolated area, poor illumination or blocked visibility, and lack of physical barriers between individuals and persons at risk of committing workplace violence.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H50E00EA1FCBC4546A2778F9C3C63DBFE"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Threat of Violence</header><text>The term <term>threat of violence</term> means a statement or conduct that—</text><subparagraph id="HDB756B81564B49A4B49CCF4131B4BCBF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>causes an individual to fear for such individual’s safety because there is a reasonable possibility the individual might be physically injured; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBD42D394BE68414299B1182E6C9C378D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>serves no legitimate purpose.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA6D25856516942E5800240EB6B99AEDA"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Work practice controls</header><subparagraph id="HA94D3C5FA9734A93BD7B2A3339CB0DA3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>work practice controls</term> means procedures and rules that are used to effectively reduce workplace violence hazards.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H26EDB4710E54427C90812F826F6A431F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text>The term <term>work practice controls</term> includes—</text><clause id="HB60907C098E545D5B40A5C71DB3B3DDE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>assigning and placing sufficient numbers of staff to reduce workplace violence directed at employees by customers, clients, patients, students, inmates, or any individual for whom the workplace provides services or for whom the employee performs services;</text></clause><clause id="H9B20A73CF7A94DA7BE6B88331F7C7104"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a provision of dedicated and available safety personnel such as security guards;</text></clause><clause id="H9ADB1FEA84DD41CBB9E1D26CB27626C7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>employee training on workplace violence prevention methods and techniques to de-escalate and minimize violent behavior; and</text></clause><clause id="H2220610C72C741DC8EEE0DC165C0A7DC"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>employee training on procedures for response in the event of a workplace violence incident and for post-incident response.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAE45F5F725884A1FB9E40714C58BEDFB"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Workplace violence</header><subparagraph id="H47D42C33E3AD41068A86DA4A020BBF1D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>workplace violence</term> means any act of violence or threat of violence, without regard to intent, that occurs at a workplace or while an employee performs a service.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC9F42FFA66F040CCA222E1D1786A80E6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusions</header><text>The term <term>workplace violence</term> does not include lawful acts of self-defense or lawful acts of defense of others.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H54D99D6EBDDF469F9AEB17124A394E96"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text>The term <term>workplace violence</term> includes—</text><clause id="H068C3924DBE845E99CCC02E430D4944C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the threat or use of physical force against a employee that results in or has a high likelihood of resulting in injury, psychological trauma, or stress, without regard to whether the employee sustains an injury, psychological trauma, or stress; and</text></clause><clause id="H666FFC813932401BB01DD0B2760D8F06"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an incident involving the threat or use of a firearm or a dangerous weapon, including the use of common objects as weapons, without regard to whether the employee sustains an injury, psychological trauma, or stress.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

