<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-BUR25158-M4D-0Y-R0C"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 72 IS: Affirming that Hamas cannot retain any political or military control in the Gaza Strip .</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 72</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250211">February 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S293">Mr. Graham</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S374">Mr. Cotton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S402">Ms. Rosen</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S416">Mrs. Britt</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Affirming that Hamas cannot retain any political or military control in the Gaza Strip .</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas Hamas was established in 1987, with the Hamas Covenant stating <quote>Israel will exist and will continue to exist until [it is] obliterate[d]</quote> clearly signifying the intent of Hamas to destroy the State of Israel, eradicate the Jewish population, and undermine peace and prosperity in the Middle East;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on October 8, 1997, the Secretary of State designated Hamas a foreign terrorist organization in accordance with section 219 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1189">8 U.S.C. 1189</external-xref>) for their repeated support for acts of terrorism;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, since 2007, Hamas has served as the de facto governing body in the Gaza Strip;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on October 7, 2023, Hamas—</text><paragraph id="idfa06b3e81ef34b24b0c159e066f93c2d"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">launched an unprovoked attack against the State of Israel;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0d7884377a734183a221482c5ea6dbca"><enum>(2)</enum><text>brutally murdered more than 1,200 innocent men, women, and children;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2281221be9154a98bdac333ae90ca599"><enum>(3)</enum><text>took more than 250 individuals hostage; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id047383a5ce40454f9d8de27b394a4df6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>injured thousands more individuals in the deadliest attack on the Jewish people since the Holocaust;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States Government has concluded that—</text><paragraph id="id0b3e3f8e6a0548188d9ed96770af5174" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text><quote>Hamas has received funding, weapons, and training from the Islamic Republic of Iran</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida90e3ed116a444ccbb9620ad32e84bb5" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text><quote>Iran provides up to $100,000,000 annually in combined support to Palestinian terrorist groups, including Hamas</quote>; and</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Hamas has threatened to attack the State of Israel again and stated <quote>We must teach Israel a lesson, and we will do this again and again. The Al-Aqsa Deluge [the name Hamas gave its October 7 onslaught] is just the first time, and there will be a second, a third, a fourth</quote>: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id359ca06f094746898f8d46b400bb7b4c"><enum>(1)</enum><text>affirms that Hamas cannot be allowed to retain any political or military control in the Gaza Strip;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6f6fcb41de264862bbd593d43cea189e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>calls upon the President to use all economic and diplomatic tools possible to halt all sources of funding for Hamas from the Islamic Republic of Iran and all other sources of revenue; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id76dd9858be234104a4d52685c98d63dd"><enum>(3)</enum><text>supports the State of Israel as it continues to defend its sovereignty against attacks from Hamas, the Islamic Republic of Iran, and all other Iranian proxies. </text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

