<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MIR25512-HJC-H4-4S3">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1621 IS: Restoring Fair Housing Protections Eliminated by Trump Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
<congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>S. 1621</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
<action>
<action-date date="20250506">May 6, 2025</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S366">Ms. Warren</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title>To restore the fair housing mission of the Department of Housing and Urban Development, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H3E6F4D442B7045C082A761009E645B01">
<section section-type="section-one" id="HEDD25870781A4628BADE470F60510D7B"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Restoring Fair Housing Protections Eliminated by Trump Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H14591B44F23245F6957C4039479FA861"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds the following:</text>
<paragraph id="HDA8F411B0859420DA3CE04966A501E76"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The current Administration has taken several steps that seriously undermine fair housing protections for people in the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2A7B958E1D6B46B2B3D43073842FCF06"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On February 10, 2025, the Secretary announced that he would halt all current and future enforcement of the Equal Access Rule of the Department that protects persons who are experiencing homelessness from discrimination on the basis of sexual orientation and gender identity while residing in shelters and while receiving homeless services.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5E79296041754E738B643C3477954EB8"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On February 11, 2025, the Secretary stated in an interview regarding the halting of Equal Access Rule enforcement that, <quote>We want to uphold, first, what the bible says—that there’s male and female</quote> and also stated that Department and the Office of Management and Budget <quote>are going after AFFH</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H24321C080B4C4DE1B48191FD96B8C81A"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On February 12, 2025, the Secretary submitted an interim final rule about affirmatively furthering fair housing to the Office of Management and Budget for review.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB9101F94E4754780A739566EA1FD5D0F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>On February 12, 2025, the Secretary submitted a proposed Equal Access Rule to the Office of Management and Budget for review.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAD78FBB1C9514821A7020373F9C393A2"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On February 14, 2025, Bloomberg Law reported that the Trump Administration plans to eliminate 50 percent of the staff at the Department.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H67969022DF834DD6B854E07FE7967DA3"><enum>(7)</enum><text>On February 26, 2025, ProPublica reported that the United States DOGE Service (commonly referred to as the <quote>Department of Government Efficiency</quote> or <quote>DOGE</quote>) was given access to confidential fair housing discrimination complaints.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5A7AFAEA6463432AA8C8A9010B19FB64"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On February 26, 2025, the Secretary announced the rescission of the rule to affirmatively further fair housing and announced the Department will now rely on localities to self-certify that they comply with the law, even if the locality has not shown to the Department that it has affirmatively furthered fair housing, through an interim final rule issued on March 3, 2025, entitled <quote>Affirmatively Furthering Fair Housing Revisions</quote>.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7EDAEF86DBF5423E8FF50A5DEBF6750A"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On February 25, 2025, the Secretary, at the direction of the United States DOGE Service (commonly referred to as the <quote>Department of Government Efficiency</quote> or <quote>DOGE</quote>), canceled 78 Fair Housing Initiatives Program grants that private nonprofit fair housing organizations use to investigate and root out illegal housing discrimination.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBA7951C2BDE04911A4465792417581F8"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On March 13, 2025, Fair Housing Initiatives Program grantees filed a class action lawsuit in a United States District Court.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H83064D032C58428CB51B1603363F34F1"><enum>(11)</enum><text>On March 25, 2025, the United States District Court in the District of Massachusetts granted a temporary restraining order directing the Secretary to reinstate the 78 Fair Housing Initiatives Program grants.</text></paragraph></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id355e497e114d416a9edc48826ec3e95c"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id09a4c035b8fe4611a920165038e39f69"><enum/><text>In this Act:</text>
<paragraph commented="no" id="H2A8A053A68304E50B35F6EA5E07CE0BE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Artificial intelligence</header><text>The term <term>artificial intelligence</term> has the meaning given the term in section 238(g) of the John S. McCain National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2019 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/2358">10 U.S.C. 2358</external-xref> note).</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfb134bacce3a430a837ede9084e891bd"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Covered housing</header><text>The term <term>covered housing</term>—</text>
<subparagraph id="HD984505F142C43D1855CBC83D7249783"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to a complaint alleging a violation of the Fair Housing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3601">42 U.S.C. 3601 et seq.</external-xref>), means—</text> <clause id="H111B2C53E5EF4DF192ED2F02655468C0"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">housing assisted under the program for supportive housing for the elderly under section 202 of the Housing Act of 1959 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1701q">12 U.S.C. 1701q</external-xref>), including the direct loans program under such section 202 as in effect before the date of enactment of the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/12701">12 U.S.C. 12701 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></clause>
<clause id="HB452BE1086A44327AC5097E028E2BB1C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>housing assisted under the program for supportive housing for persons with disabilities under section 811 of the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/8013">42 U.S.C. 8013</external-xref>);</text></clause> <clause id="HB5979A4C03B24476B7F71C9CA060518A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>housing assisted under the program for housing opportunities for people with AIDS/HIV under subtitle D of title VIII of the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12901">42 U.S.C. 12901 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></clause>
<clause id="H967D553D0D194E7D923092DA119D3CE8"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>housing assisted under any of the programs under subtitles B through D of title IV of the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/11371">42 U.S.C. 11371 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></clause> <clause id="H36A49EC3599D4CC78EC2B646C2059A1D"><enum>(v)</enum><text>housing assisted under the HOME Investment Partnerships program under subtitle A of title II of the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12741">42 U.S.C. 12741 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></clause>
<clause id="H8F510133E4BF4D98A92CB477B32024E8"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>housing assisted under the rent supplement program under section 101 of the Housing and Urban Development Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1701s">12 U.S.C. 1701s</external-xref>);</text></clause> <clause id="H524D375C07CA46EE9EAA167DF83F3578"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>housing financed by a loan or mortgage that is insured under section 203 of the National Housing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1709">12 U.S.C. 1709</external-xref>);</text></clause>
<clause id="H31EA2432D5A84081AFCFA66F827DCE13"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>housing financed by a loan or mortgage that is—</text> <subclause id="H7A2FAC57D0F640A681EFAD38D0D3A7B3"><enum>(I)</enum><text>secured by a first or subordinate lien on a residential real property, including any such secured loan, the proceeds of which are used to prepay or pay off an existing loan secured by the same property; and</text></subclause>
<subclause id="HDE45DD26E51A4B2FA13FEC35DFA07E8C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>purchased or securitized by the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation or the Federal National Mortgage Association;</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H94B97D5A633D410D9E045E13E28B1EF8"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>housing insured, assisted, or held by the Secretary or a State or State agency under the multifamily rental assistance program under section 236 of the National Housing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1715z-1">12 U.S.C. 1715z–1</external-xref>);</text></clause>
<clause id="HF442669FEDF343ECBA556E954BC9169E"><enum>(x)</enum><text>public housing assisted under title I of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437">42 U.S.C. 1437 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></clause> <clause id="H0BF4F95D17AF4D06A9D430D6E943D4D4"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>a dwelling unit assisted under the Housing Choice Voucher program for rental assistance under section 8(o) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437f">42 U.S.C. 1437f(o)</external-xref>);</text></clause>
<clause id="HCC7CF88050004BA1927F9E9795B63379"><enum>(xii)</enum><text>housing assisted with project-based rental assistance provided under section 8 of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437f">42 U.S.C. 1437f</external-xref>);</text></clause> <clause id="H40C177BD0B0D47518475CF174146267B"><enum>(xiii)</enum><text>housing assisted with funds from the Housing Trust Fund as established under section 1338 of the Federal Housing Enterprises Financial Safety and Soundness Act of 1992 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/4568">12 U.S.C. 4568</external-xref>);</text></clause>
<clause id="H486C1A32C0694282864855627955D6E6"><enum>(xiv)</enum><text>housing assisted under any of the rural housing assistance programs under section 514, 515, 516, 533, 538, or 542 of the Housing Act of 1949 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1484">42 U.S.C. 1484</external-xref>, 1485, 1486, 1490m, 1490p–2, 1490r);</text></clause> <clause commented="no" id="H30DC988C39AE4320AD70E13E97AD5205"><enum>(xv)</enum><text>any housing project for which equity is provided through any low-income housing tax credit pursuant to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/42">section 42</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986;</text></clause>
<clause id="H602B54D9AA8C4F86890A10338B0DD488"><enum>(xvi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">housing assisted under the Comprehensive Service Programs for Homeless Veterans program under subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/20">chapter 20</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code;</text></clause> <clause commented="no" id="H78309728D44A430782D6A56412020524"><enum>(xvii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">housing and facilities assisted under the grant program for homeless veterans with special needs under section 2061 of title 38, United States Code;</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" id="HA14EE3C95E3E43018203C817EAEDEDB1"><enum>(xviii)</enum><text>permanent housing for which assistance is provided under the program for financial assistance for supportive services for very low-income veteran families in permanent housing under section 2044 of title 38, United States Code;</text></clause> <clause id="H1678435977F74F8F97523EA582CCF68C"><enum>(xix)</enum><text>any other housing assisted by any housing program administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs;</text></clause>
<clause id="H5C84724EF81B4AE8B46AE2A315216A5A"><enum>(xx)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">housing assisted by the Community Development Financial Institutions Fund established under the Community Development Banking and Financial Institutions Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/4701">12 U.S.C. 4701 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></clause> <clause id="H6490A218BFCF4FEDA950BA12943A33BD"><enum>(xxi)</enum><text>housing assisted under the Neighborhood Reinvestment Corporation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/8101">42 U.S.C. 8101 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></clause>
<clause id="H4A632851ED074182AA8CFE868EA975D0"><enum>(xxii)</enum><text>housing assisted under title I of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5301">42 U.S.C. 5301 et seq.</external-xref>), including housing assisted with amounts provided during a disaster as described in such Act;</text></clause> <clause id="H5404DBC74B2A4A88B0A0F14074FF80AA"><enum>(xxiii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">transitional or short-term housing assisted under the grant program under section 40299 of the Violence Against Women Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/12351">34 U.S.C. 12351</external-xref>);</text></clause>
<clause id="HE5F5002FC1034A70ABBD609D6E3D21BD"><enum>(xxiv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">housing assisted under such other Federal housing programs as identified for the purposes of section 7 of this Act; and</text></clause> <clause id="HF555ECC2ACEC4A3CB85BD8F3A2FA65BD"><enum>(xxv)</enum><text>Federally subsidized dwelling units that provide affordable housing to low-income persons by means of restricted rents or rental assistance, as identified for the purposes of section 7 of this Act; and</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H310D76BD998A4FCFAFBF331AA7500C59" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to a complaint alleging a violation of the Violence Against Women Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/12291">34 U.S.C. 12291 et seq.</external-xref>), means a covered housing program, as defined in section 41411 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/12491">34 U.S.C. 12491</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida29fec9e461a4cf3853ed05e31191533"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Department</header><text>The term <term>Department</term> means the Department of Housing and Urban Development.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcbc7a9a145a247c6912aa96efcf979f4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HB4EA26B8E6784FBFBAF9DCB1F7210483"><enum>4.</enum><header>Mission of the Department of Housing and Urban Development</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2 of the Department of Housing and Urban Development Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3531">42 U.S.C. 3531</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="H0B9D5B224FE244848108F85FB4117EDF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the section heading, by inserting <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="traditional">; mission of department</header-in-text></quote> after <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="traditional">purpose</header-in-text></quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H599AE16999634411B4101406935D174E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>(a) <header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Purpose</header-in-text>.—</quote> after <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="traditional-inline">Sec</header-in-text>. 2.</quote>; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD627193512D74058A1562322DA33CC44"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1ED57F02AA9B47B1B298D96E0B8DB3B7"> <subsection id="HD0A948A7E4864EFB9BF40AAC95D5D0AD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Mission of Department</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The mission of the Department of Housing and Urban Development shall be to create strong, sustainable, inclusive communities and quality affordable homes for all. The Department of Housing and Urban Development shall work to strengthen the housing market to bolster the economy and protect consumers, meet the need for quality affordable rental homes, utilize housing as a platform for improving quality of life, build inclusive and sustainable communities free from discrimination, and transform the way the Department does business.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section>
<section commented="no" id="HD5CB7049DF544132919DCBF59514023C"><enum>5.</enum><header>Implementation of affirmatively furthering fair housing regulation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall carry out the following:</text> <paragraph id="HFDEAE277A8504ACA94D75953602563B7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Repeal the interim final rule issued on March 3, 2025, entitled <quote>Affirmatively Furthering Fair Housing Revisions</quote>.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HBCACB5AEB0AB4E6899FA1C7498E5B957"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Issue a rule that defines <quote>affirmatively furthering fair housing</quote> in the following manner:</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0a918f2e9db649279354e590e2379b91"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><quote>Affirmatively furthering fair housing</quote> means—</text>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0d72e8cec9e048d38eb1ff85be978a01"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">taking meaningful actions, in addition to combating discrimination, that overcome patterns of segregation and foster inclusive communities free from barriers that restrict access to opportunity based on protected characteristics; and</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd17d9e52326e4ae599260c6d91fbf450"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in particular, taking meaningful actions that, taken together, address significant disparities in housing needs and in access to opportunity, replacing segregated living patterns with truly integrated and balanced living patterns, transforming racially or ethnically concentrated areas of poverty into areas of opportunity, and fostering and maintaining compliance with civil rights and fair housing laws.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd45be1d6f24c4689b393f9dac011dbd7"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The duty to affirmatively further fair housing extends to all of a program participant’s activities and programs relating to housing and urban development.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> <section id="H3990F815F8DA448E905D0C36375791ED"><enum>6.</enum><header>Review of online complaints of violations of Fair Housing Act</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report that includes—</text>
<paragraph id="H6D08647F8C854DE39CD3431D00EECEB6"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a review of the complaints filed with the Secretary under section 810 of the Fair Housing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3610">42 U.S.C. 3610</external-xref>) during the 5-year period preceding the date of enactment of this Act that alleged a discriminatory housing practice involving a digital platform or artificial intelligence, including any artificial intelligence used for—</text> <subparagraph id="H8E0C88F5CC27405B87CDCDD8CFCC56BE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>advertisement delivery and targeting;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD5F59243EA5A4BF99EDA060AACB6AFA9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>tenant screening;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0B75BD70E54E4227A2A67AD0DCB2B756"><enum>(C)</enum><text>automated mortgage underwriting;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H4891F621171E4025B9BC47DFE6CE8FB1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>dynamic pricing of real estate; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H026B61976E2C4F62A44409D685D16E97"><enum>(E)</enum><text>real estate listings; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD9C6EAAD2E0948E087886D45ED192FF3"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an analysis of trends and risks related to—</text> <subparagraph id="HE8F1AC9637104A44AE139A60EBDAEEC9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>discrimination that occurs in connection with the use of digital platforms to rent or purchase housing;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HBED71D35A6E44683ACB0F10B3070744F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the sufficiency of the Fair Housing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3601">42 U.S.C. 3601 et seq.</external-xref>) to remedy discrimination during the rental or purchase of housing through digital platforms; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2EFC5C0882B2402CA2380B4284F9D6E5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>steps the Secretary plans to take to address that discrimination.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section>
<section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3E5D7A50D5B2472CB2BCB809318A78B1"><enum>7.</enum><header>Publicly available database for fair housing complaints</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary shall develop, and update on a quarterly basis, a database that is publicly available on a website of the Department that includes, subject to applicable confidentiality constraints, the following:</text> <paragraph id="H4B5E79CA94EE447CA016EFA64F1CE71A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The total number of complaints alleging violations of the Fair Housing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3601">42 U.S.C. 3601 et seq.</external-xref>) that were received by the Secretary, disaggregated with respect to both number and percentage, by each protected class established under such Act.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" id="HFEF62AE6295D40219A25242DB06B8DB4"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number and percentage of the total number of complaints that allege violations of the Violence Against Women Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/12291">34 U.S.C. 12291 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H42CA3FD2E8354637B500044B8D651FEB"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number and percentage of the total number of complaints referred to in paragraphs (1) and (2) that—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H72B500CFF882454884D9AAA27EA9B9AA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>were made by persons experiencing homelessness;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H89696E22F8BE402AB5265C223622A832"><enum>(B)</enum><text>were made by tenants; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HF9B22C8D44534FF1842A76316986CFB4"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">were made by persons who have applied for covered housing, disaggregated by each specific type of covered housing for which such person applied.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEA222A1025394684B0929ECBA415F261"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For each State, the number and percentage of the total number of complaints referred to in paragraphs (1) and (2) that were made by residents of such State.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H81F3946A1B6D4D12A08601E5003E98E4"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number and percentage of the total number complaints referred to in paragraphs (1) and (2) that alleged that the complainant was retaliated against after reporting the alleged violation and, of such number, the number and percentage that alleged that the complainant was evicted for any retaliatory reason.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBE90270E3B1244FDB537A7AD9674BDA4"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The status of the complaints referred to in paragraphs (1) and (2), including a detailed description of the resolutions and remedies provided and, for complaints that were administratively closed, of the reasons for such closures.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8AD9BC901F1142DCBA0FE7A10C2D8C63"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number and percentage of the total number of complaints referred to in paragraph (1) that were received by—</text> <subparagraph id="HEF9F3CD280194ABA89E00663F017327C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>State agencies assisted under the Fair Housing Assistance Program authorized under section 810 of the Fair Housing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3610">42 U.S.C. 3610</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H458AE020DE0D4E8F8F2C8CC6A9DCFF0B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>local agencies assisted under the Fair Housing Initiatives Program authorized under section 817 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3616">42 U.S.C. 3616</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H262B1EEC31A14F5C92891F5279715471"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number and percentage of the total number of complaints referred to in paragraph (1) that ended in a reasonable cause charge by the Secretary or were referred to the Attorney General by the Secretary.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0385C3B139BA4CAC880E70D5103B14B3"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number and percentage of the total number of complaints referred to in paragraph (1) received by the Attorney General that were not referred to the Attorney General by the Secretary.</text></paragraph></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

