<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA144BEAD1BD4474C96264E7185024E19" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 473 IH: Stopping Home Office Work’s Unproductive Problems Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 473</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20250116">January 16, 2025</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001108">Mr. Comer</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="H001077">Mr. Higgins of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000480">Mr. Timmons</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001302">Mr. Biggs of Arizona</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001115">Mr. Cloud</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000450">Ms. Foxx</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000600">Mr. Langworthy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001132">Mr. Crane</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000609">Mr. Palmer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001239">Mr. McGuire</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000576">Mr. Grothman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000246">Mr. Fallon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001316">Mr. Burlison</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000250">Mr. Sessions</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000311">Mr. Jack</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001309">Mr. Burchett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000825">Ms. Boebert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000605">Mr. Perry</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000596">Ms. Greene of Georgia</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To restore in-person work at Federal agencies to not less than pre-pandemic levels, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="HC67DD0581DA84DE4B3779A6EF561ED89" style="OLC">
<section id="H823531E19A7648C8B43D34C794F34F0D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stopping Home Office Work’s Unproductive Problems Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SHOW UP Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HF9C669B897304D31A299291AF1406A64" commented="no"><enum>2.</enum><header>Reinstatement of pre-pandemic telework policies, practices, and levels for Executive agencies</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, each agency shall adopt and apply telework policies, practices, and levels at the agency that are equivalent to, or otherwise permit no additional levels of telework than, those which were in effect on December 31, 2019, and may not expand any such policy, practice, or level until the date that an agency plan is submitted to Congress with a certification by the Director of the Office of Personnel Management under section 3.</text></section>
<section id="H6715C027DD8D4E9E865FB4110334B39F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Study, plan, and certification regarding Executive agency telework policies, practices, and levels for Executive agencies</header>
<subsection id="HDD975D7C8F6E4DEF808261149A3EE668"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the head of each agency, in consultation with the Director, shall submit to Congress—</text> <paragraph id="H2CF42A07D1EC482886EFA07C709BF619"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a study on the impacts on the agency and its mission of expanding telework by its employees during the SARS–CoV–2 pandemic that commenced in 2019 and maintaining such expanded telework thereafter, including an analysis of—</text>
<subparagraph id="HFC8258E890A345F699186DB849E2C263"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any adverse impacts of that expansion on the agency’s performance of its mission, including the performance of customer service by the agency;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H356C0D2279A943AE9E2BE9B939720364"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any costs to the agency during that expansion attributable to—</text>
<clause id="H6A1FE33B7C3648968EDF66E884167AEB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>owning, leasing, or maintaining underutilized real property; or</text></clause> <clause id="H481CD85C03E149ADBEE353E1ED376E38"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>paying higher rates of locality pay to teleworking employees as a result of incorrectly classifying such employees as teleworkers rather than remote workers;</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H39BAFA0A25AE410E88D0A317BC8BBE50"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any degree to which the agency failed during that expansion to provide teleworking employees with secure network capacity, communications tools, necessary and secure access to appropriate agency data assets and Federal records, and equipment sufficient to enable each such employee to be fully productive;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAC09E64F03DC49D69624660BE8484C3D"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any degree to which that expansion facilitated dispersal of the agency workforce around the Nation; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H7BD603704A354058AF995ED69DF97C71"><enum>(E)</enum><text>any other impacts of that expansion that the agency or the Director considers appropriate;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA249714336C94CD8AC99AB55BAEBB2BA"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any agency plan to expand telework policies, practices, or levels beyond those in place as a result of section 2; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4EA79BD6E6CB4C4DA31765CD359943BC" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a certification by the Director that such plan will—</text> <subparagraph id="H859C87CDCA764D84ACDD65544154C1D9" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>have a substantial positive effect on—</text>
<clause id="H01CDBF742C2745C2900A4327B65AF978"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the performance of the agency’s mission, including the performance of customer service;</text></clause> <clause id="H4989B7BD8A694FC1B6179C1F74A0F2B7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>increasing the level of dispersal of agency personnel throughout the Nation; and</text></clause>
<clause id="HBB07430F43574AEE8051AA05A27150A6" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the reversal of any adverse impact set forth pursuant to paragraph (1)(D);</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H38F9A3316929484A8E32526449CEF38B" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>substantially lower the agency’s costs of owning, leasing, or maintaining real property;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H423D98895F2447F6BFB9EFDD2CCF016C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>substantially lower the agency’s costs attributable to paying locality pay to agency personnel working from locations outside the pay locality of their position’s official worksite; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCE8AE6A81F314A1F8A98B33B2C7BAC26"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure that teleworking employees will be provided with secure network capacity, communications tools, necessary and secure access to appropriate agency data assets and Federal records, and equipment sufficient to enable each such employee to be fully productive, without substantially increasing the agency’s overall costs for secure network capacity, communications tools, and equipment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H0603FF038F5F41BF8CADB866C985B877"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitation</header>
<paragraph id="H626405BF42694E7CBAB9CF3BCF81E6FB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An agency may not implement the plan submitted under subsection (a)(2) unless a certification by the Director was issued under subsection (a)(3).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCA3BA8D375A241849D817D69D8C80421" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Subsequent plans</header><text>In the event an initial agency plan submitted under subsection (a)(2) fails to receive such certification, the agency may submit to the Director subsequent plans until such certification is received, and submit such plan and certification to Congress.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H798C4F59CD0149F6B27D208CA4EC96EA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this Act—</text> <paragraph id="HC7CBEDD89A7F4FB6AEA114D382967156"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>agency</term> has the meaning given the term <term>Executive agency</term> in section 105 of title 5, United States Code, except that such term does not include the Government Accountability Office;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H61F61F40EE5342C1990B9CE5170DAF11"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>Director</term> means the Director of the Office of Personnel Management;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5F6D17AF16234B668332A6AC8F566419"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>locality pay</term> means locality pay provided for under section 5304 or 5304a of such title; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1887545DBA4C42659B44F7094B48503E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the terms <term>telework</term> and <term>teleworking</term> have the meaning given those terms in section 6501 of such title, and include remote work.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

