<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9DE0D8F403FC49B9AD92609BEEE93525" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4604 IH: Protecting America’s Treasures by Raising Inflow from Overseas Tourists (PATRIOT) Parks Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4604</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250722">July 22, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001235">Mr. Moore of West Virginia</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="Z000018">Mr. Zinke</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Federal Lands Recreation Enhancement Act to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to collect a surcharge from international visitors to units of the National Park System, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD4823D9185A24155A25E200B535CE119" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H0898931A3C5C4834A4128C16B06836A6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting America’s Treasures by Raising Inflow from Overseas Tourists (PATRIOT) Parks Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HCBF0C03636174A38A1A85C13E527EF2B" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Surcharge for international visitors to units of the National Park System</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA49EDCBD0743405795B2C8720E08625B"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Entrance fee surcharge</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 803(e) of the Federal Lands Recreation Enhancement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/6802">16 U.S.C. 6802(e)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7EF55AE0297B48DAB4C70882051C7C72"> 
<paragraph id="HDFD8A379F9C740848BC2A06B57ED6D22"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Entrance fee surcharge for international visitors</header> 
<subparagraph id="HBBA29921736940F3BF7BAA67209CEB40"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Definition of international visitor</header><text>In this paragraph, the term <term>international visitor</term> means a nonimmigrant individual admitted into the United States under—</text> <clause id="HACB23C54D11341E981263A6AD1BCDE3F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>section 101(a)(15)(B) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(15)(B)</external-xref>); or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H4BBFAD9B1A0C45CFB73E62703A076AD3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>section 217 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1187">8 U.S.C. 1187</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HADB3362A912A4CE887CF5D6D0B041373"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Entrance fee surcharge</header> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H682F1F8F15094714BFD34402766255AF"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subparagraph (C), for any unit of the National Park System for which an entrance fee is charged, the Secretary may, at the election of the Secretary, or shall, on request of the superintendent of the applicable unit of the National Park System, authorize the superintendent of the applicable unit of the National Park System to establish for any international visitors charged the entrance fee a surcharge in an amount established by the superintendent of the applicable unit of the National Park System, by regulation, to be collected by the Secretary in accordance with this paragraph.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HB5857070822B4AC48A5BDFDA9B0D7CDA"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Determination of surcharge amount</header><text>In establishing the amount of a surcharge under clause (i), the superintendent of the applicable unit of the National Park System shall ensure that the amount maximizes revenue for the applicable unit of the National Park System while retaining international visitation at the applicable unit of the National Park System.</text></clause> <clause id="H0594E57A80B84056AF18A225FA4DCC35"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Per-vehicle fee</header><text>In a case in which an entrance fee to a unit of the National Park System subject to a surcharge under clause (i) is a per-vehicle charge, the Secretary shall establish, by regulation, a process for the superintendent of the applicable unit of the National Park System to proportionately levy and collect the surcharge from international visitors under that clause.</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD639EE4956624EEEAEF20A5FF448282D"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Methods of collection</header><text>A surcharge established under clause (i) shall be collected—</text> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCDA1B23EEBAE4F8BBC1AEE337DC11079"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by the Secretary, using the standard methods by which entrance fees may be collected for a unit of the National Park System under this section; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1DA648F6EF95429A95F5B757653AF0FC"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the Secretary enters into an agreement with a third-party travel vendor to provide for the collection of the surcharge, by the applicable third-party travel vendor, in accordance with the agreement.</text></subclause></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8CAB78F03D7F4C40858964C12982FB46"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Suspension or modification; increase</header> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB3A15B51D9C74FE19FF0AAF9C34DD751"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Suspension or modification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At the election of the Secretary or on request of the superintendent of a unit of the National Park System at which a surcharge is established under clause (i), the Secretary may suspend the collection of, or otherwise modify, the surcharge for the applicable unit of the National Park System, including providing for tiered pricing of the surcharge based on visitation levels at the unit of the National Park System, as determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text></subclause> 
<subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF9F19FB63A2D4ABB92356FAC9239451B"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Increase</header><text>The Secretary may establish a minimum percentage increase that shall apply to a surcharge established by a superintendent under clause (i) within an applicable timeframe established by the Secretary.</text></subclause></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB2AFBB415BBA4B1D83EE8524BB4791BB"><enum>(vi)</enum><header>Visa fees; administration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A surcharge established under clause (i)—</text> 
<subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H736101A73E014E47873B05BF2EA739D6"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall be in addition to, and separate from, any statutory immigrant visa fee charged to an international visitor; and</text></subclause> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H56236B82D0074E7EA5F1B90E3BF51DC3"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall not be subject to administration by the Secretary of State or the Secretary of Homeland Security.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF1E17DA83DD34998BCADC4B4273056C1"><enum>(vii)</enum><header>Disposition of proceeds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, all proceeds from a surcharge on international visitors collected under this paragraph shall be retained by the applicable unit of the National Park System at which the surcharge was collected, to be distributed by the Secretary for maintenance, visitor services, staffing, and related needs at the unit of the National Park System, as determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H548D966B6B2241A4AB87F51B1C9320D1"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>The following exceptions to the surcharge authorized under subparagraph (B) apply:</text> 
<clause id="HA38B43F0571E488D8E33C2F8FD66E08B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>No surcharge may be applied to the entrance fee to Washington Monument in the District of Columbia.</text></clause> <clause id="HFE7F5E10C23341A1A0D8FC9297D40194"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>If a unit of the National Park System has been designated as an International Peace Park by an Act of Congress and is subject to a Memorandum of Understanding with the government of a foreign country relating to management or stewardship of the unit, no surcharge may be applied to the entrance fee of a national of that foreign country for entry onto that unit from an entry point within the United States.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H810C635731CF45FA8ABB82468C8773DC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Recreation passes</header><text>Section 805(a) of the Federal Lands Recreation Enhancement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/6804">16 U.S.C. 6804(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB9A3B99F12D445228119E530F5F3F44E"> <paragraph id="H4BDEDF0E22054B7E87A10AA6B5815B5D"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Surcharge for certain international visitors</header> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD49B554EFC63461CACCB57735832C149"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish, by regulation, a surcharge to be collected from the sale of any National Parks and Federal Recreational Lands Pass to an international visitor (as defined in section 803(e)(3)(A)), the amount of which may be increased by the Secretary in a percentage and in a timeframe determined to be reasonable by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H96CDC6A04FE14866939E0F3E93E8DA03"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Disposition of proceeds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any amounts collected as a surcharge under subparagraph (A) shall be deposited in the National Parks and Public Land Legacy Restoration Fund established by section 200402(a) of title 54, United States Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

