<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H8A4E8C00A322432B97CFDA882688C163" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3023 IH: Preventing Hospital Overbilling of Medicare Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3023</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250424">April 24, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000929">Mrs. Spartz</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act and title XXVII of the Public Health Service Act to address incorrect billing by off-campus hospital locations, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H4760965DC4494B369C7314AEDDC29E19" style="OLC"><section id="H76160690D7F54F9D9936680B6C573571" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Preventing Hospital Overbilling of Medicare Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H47DE0D64343E4A4B8DD20F939EC43B52" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Addressing incorrect billing by off-campus hospital locations</header><subsection id="HD6372E6305C24B0B84F12AFE42552DD1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Promoting Medicare site-Neutral payments</header><paragraph id="H74E14FFEF2A44CBC859D3618C1D9FF46"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Removing certain exceptions to the definition of an off-campus outpatient department of a provider</header><subparagraph id="H349C9B91E5D14BA0821385F7BC11E4AE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1833(t)(21)(B) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395l">42 U.S.C. 1395l(t)(21)(B)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H9E8E0B82BD2B4E85B06F55CE246426DC" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="H3C3A1B6977C547BF8043E663BB1796F7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Off-campus outpatient department of a provider</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of paragraph (1)(B)(v) and this paragraph, the term <quote>off-campus outpatient department of a provider</quote> means a department of a provider (as defined in section 413.65(a)(2) of title 42 of the Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect as of the date of the enactment of the Bipartisan Budget Act of 2015) that is not located—</text><clause id="H6AB06F4F3D68482BB5BB164F735B37FD"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">on the campus (as defined in such section 413.65(a)(2)) of such provider; or</text></clause><clause id="H60836F4C09F144208FAF0EC495C63915"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">within the distance (described in such definition of campus) from a remote location of a hospital facility (as defined in such section 413.65(a)(2)).</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFE2B43AEAE4D4D01A8F4A7E83D4343E5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by subparagraph (A) shall apply with respect to items and services furnished on or after January 1, 2026.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA8EA598ED13645CAA6813FFE48971AB9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Removing site-neutral exception for off-campus emergency departments</header><text>Section 1833(t)(21)(A) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395l">42 U.S.C. 1395l(t)(21)(A)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>before January 1, 2026</quote> after <quote>furnished</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7A29F9E755BC495DA66FBEE8152AEAB7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Clarifying Secretarial authority to promote site-neutral payments</header><text>Section 1833(t)(2)(F) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395l">42 U.S.C. 1395l(t)(2)(F)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new sentence: <quote>Such method may include actions determined appropriate by the Secretary to promote site-neutral payment policies to reduce expenditures attributable to items and services furnished under this part, such as actions to prevent hospitals from billing for items and services furnished at an off-campus outpatient department of a provider as if such items and services were furnished at such hospital.</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE47FCBB53E8D4829A2AB1250F9848B96"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Ensuring separate NPIs for off-Campus outpatient departments of a provider</header><paragraph id="H24687ADF79C540678EFC2926D49116E0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1173(b) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1320d-2">42 U.S.C. 1320d–2(b)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H13D318A336E0421693B1D73247D335D9" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H605D17AC74254F66A25C223A37ADA53E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Ensuring separate NPIs for off-campus outpatient departments of a provider</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The standards specified under paragraph (1) shall ensure that, not later than January 1, 2026, each off-campus outpatient department of a provider (as defined in section 1833(t)(21)(B)) is assigned a separate unique health identifier from such provider. </text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H37EDF3A54D7449778AE6950459C1E09B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Treatment of certain departments as subparts of a hospital</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than January 1, 2026, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall revise sections 162.408 and 162.410 of title 45, Code of Federal Regulations, to ensure that each off-campus outpatient department of a provider (as defined in section 1833(t)(21)(B) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395l">42 U.S.C. 1395l(t)(21)(B)</external-xref>)) is treated as a subpart (as described in such sections) of such provider and assigned a unique health identifier pursuant to section 1173(b)(3) of such Act (as added by paragraph (1)). </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H26B759BA370345AC82CA88C1BEC982F4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Off-Campus departments of a provider billing requirements</header><paragraph id="HF776411AFC694C4A91C07B00DE1BEC2A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Medicare</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1866(a)(1) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395cc">42 U.S.C. 1395cc(a)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="H307F092AC380469FB8603F537D30F6D5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (X), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H20767B5CCBDE442C8BE4E7C5FBA0E5A4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (Y)(ii)(V), by striking the period and inserting <quote>, and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4C4C9BC4FB214EE2B38DC495106ED3DF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (Y) the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H0949B592AAC447FE871013AAA09033DD" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="HB4964DD4A7054ED9A8526079D767C796" indent="up1"><enum>(Z)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a hospital with an off-campus outpatient department of a provider (as defined in section 1833(t)(21)(B)), with respect to items and services furnished at such department of a provider on or after January 1, 2026, to bill under this title (including under part C of this title) for such items and services using the unique health identifier established for such department of a provider pursuant to section 1173(b)(3) on a HIPAA X12 837P transaction or CMS 1500 form (or a successor transaction or form).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H410EBC6215374184BF91E1BEE31B69C4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Other providers</header><text>Part E of title XXVII of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg-131">42 U.S.C. 300gg–131 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H2690FE29013C4D9FA940E12BE0E57608" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="H2AC763B276CF40B2882EBA8C568BBFEF"><enum>2799B–10.</enum><header>Billing requirements for off-campus departments of a provider</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">A health care provider may not, with respect to items and services furnished to an individual at an off-campus outpatient department of a provider (as defined in section 1833(t)(21)(B) of the Social Security Act), submit a claim for such items and services to a group health plan or health insurance issuer, and may not hold such individual liable for such items and services, unless such items and services are billed—</text><paragraph id="H257DF75FBDCA47FF9C021A92DBB5EFF9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>using the separate unique health identifier established for such department pursuant to section 1173(b)(3) of such Act; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF592F7B268804D78868437BE1083022D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">on a HIPAA X12 837P transaction or CMS 1500 form (or a successor transaction or form).</text></paragraph></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H7DF63FCE95574E34B211A65819F4AB68"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by paragraph (1) shall apply with respect to claims submitted for items and services furnished on or after January 1, 2026.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H68CBE0424BFE4C9C922C004B675F92AF"><enum>(d)</enum><header>NAIC model Act or regulation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall request that, not later than 6 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the National Association of Insurance Commissioners establish a model Act or regulation designed to address the issue of hospitals inappropriately billing for items and services furnished at off-campus outpatient departments of a provider (as defined in section 1833(t)(21)(B) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1935l">42 U.S.C. 1935l(t)(21)(B)</external-xref>)) by allowing health insurance issuers and group health plans (as such terms are defined in section 2791 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg-91">42 U.S.C. 300gg–91</external-xref>)) to reject such claims unless such department of a provider bills in accordance with the provisions of section 2799B–10 of such Act. The Secretary shall request that such model Act or regulation include requirements similar to those found in Colorado House Bill 18–1282.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

