<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-HEY25075-887-5P-1DG"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S219 IS: Veterans Health Care Freedom Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 219</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250123">January 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S412">Mr. Tuberville</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S398">Mr. Cramer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S318">Mr. Wicker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S381">Mr. Rounds</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S355">Mr. Cruz</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S435">Mr. Sheehy</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSVA00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to carry out a pilot program to improve the ability of veterans to access medical care in medical facilities of the Department of Veterans Affairs and in the community by providing veterans the ability to choose health care providers.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HC9B6C7E14050449C922B51DB025D84C9"><section section-type="section-one" id="HD99D1E1C07A445D3B6FD0C3DA7F63395"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Veterans Health Care Freedom Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section section-type="subsequent-section" id="H7F07A8F7DAE64865B20663E700D54293"><enum>2.</enum><header>Pilot program on ability of veterans to choose health care providers</header><subsection id="H5383683AF71D4298BFBE73B90931793B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Pilot program</header><paragraph id="H44AC0C2BD9E44665ADFE37889A1B6215"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs, acting through the Center for Innovation for Care and Payment of the Department of Veterans Affairs, shall carry out a pilot program to improve the ability of eligible veterans to access hospital care, medical services, and extended care services through the covered care system by providing eligible veterans the ability to choose health care providers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H963BB9A940FD4D9597ED80F16C2A2983"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Locations</header><text>The Secretary shall select a minimum of four Veterans Integrated Service Networks in which to carry out the pilot program.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBE6B20A2F38B483189DE3C7C650B064E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Removal of certain requirements To access care</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the pilot program, the Secretary shall furnish hospital care, medical services, and extended care services to eligible veterans through the covered care system as follows:</text><paragraph id="HD5E85A8BF23B4C929D0BF155E66A01D3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>At medical facilities of the Department of Veterans Affairs, regardless of whether the facility is in the same Veterans Integrated Service Network as the Network in which the veteran resides.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7FA6CF7BABE94142A55A623F0B086807"><enum>(2)</enum><text>At non-Department facilities pursuant to, as appropriate—</text><subparagraph id="H2FFE7E9D986444E6A6DA31F766F0CA65"><enum>(A)</enum><text>section 1703 of title 38, United States Code, without regard to the requirements specified in subsection (d) of such section; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4B0C933ADDB64678A494AFA9448AC69E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>section 1703A of such title, without regard to whether the care or service is not feasibly available to the eligible veteran from a facility of the Department or through a contract or sharing agreement entered into pursuant to a provision of law other than such section as required under subparagraphs (A) and (C) of subsection (a)(1) of such section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0B1BC1912514413C98769E101F243DDF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Election of veteran</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In accordance with subsections (d) and (e), an eligible veteran participating in the pilot program may elect to receive hospital care, medical services, and extended care services at any provider in the covered care system.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5AE95C194CD14656B0D1F4DE30517C2D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Coordination of care</header><paragraph id="H64D179847CF445408776A0388778DDB6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Selection</header><text>Each eligible veteran participating in the pilot program shall select a primary care provider in the covered care system. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id93F0BA145C2B4768A13DEA0A94ED7551"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>The primary care provider of an eligible veteran selected under paragraph (1) shall—</text><subparagraph id="H540AFA231D6045688F7EFBB6577FA4ED"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">coordinate with the Secretary and other health care providers with respect to the hospital care, medical services, and extended care services furnished to the veteran under the pilot program; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5EA77AC86025447EA00890ECD27AF509"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">refer the veteran to specialty care providers in the covered care system, as clinically necessary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC6CADC64867F433C87328E7BAE4EEA56"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Systems</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish systems as the Secretary determines appropriate to ensure that a primary care provider can effectively coordinate the hospital care, medical services, and extended care services furnished to a veteran under the pilot program.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFC76F99519B340E3A0E52FFE5A100652"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Specialty care</header><paragraph id="HB36F7F21350C449DB3F4F1B850FB3728"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Access</header><text>Subject to subsection (d)(2)(B), an eligible veteran participating in the pilot program may select any specialty care provider in the covered care system from which to receive specialty care.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7290F610F10B4A16B148A88A707E8097"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Designation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may designate a specialty care provider as a primary care provider of an eligible veteran participating in the pilot program if the Secretary determines that such designation is in the health interests of the veteran (such as an endocrinologist with respect to a veteran diagnosed with diabetes, a neurologist with respect to a veteran diagnosed with Parkinson’s disease, or an obstetrician-gynecologist with respect to a female veteran).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2782B571F5ED417C866EE55A29024FA3"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Mental health care</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible veteran participating in the pilot program may select a mental health care provider in the covered care system from which to receive mental health care.</text></subsection><subsection id="H887AAD62AE3C40888E8189E6C7604922"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Information</header><text>In carrying out the pilot program, the Secretary shall furnish to eligible veterans the information on eligibility, cost sharing, treatments, and providers required for veterans to make informed decisions with respect to—</text><paragraph id="H392C58DE57F04EDCA61AED6A7852008B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>selecting primary care providers and specialty care providers; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H188813F572384D9DAA98DF4D479E4159"><enum>(2)</enum><text>treatments available to the veteran.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H55F9541D764B4284B45C4A61163E782B"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Duration</header><paragraph id="HF63A6329B94847AC84D821D78D50098D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Phase in</header><text>The Secretary shall carry out the pilot program during the three-year period beginning on the date that is one year after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H32892FBF844D46CE99A020752915B0D4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Permanent requirement</header><subparagraph id="H55EDBE1446FD4E8CA61DDBBA3EFE81CF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Veterans Community Care Program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1703(d) of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text><clause id="H62838109F23F45EBA2CA30AA54A2CAA1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>The Secretary shall</quote> and inserting <quote>Except as provided by paragraph (4), the Secretary shall</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="H99858CC38FDB4A7A94C5AA3A5731E335"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H42AE3A36AC7B43E6A5EDB8D2FC04BCF6"><paragraph id="HF999F2D1CA1E4B029E652B2CAD7A661A" indent="up1"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning on the date that is four years after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Veterans Health Care Freedom Act</short-title>—</text><subparagraph id="HF2741FA889F14595B84598DA88371094"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the requirements under paragraphs (1), (2), (3), and (4) shall not apply with respect to furnishing hospital care, medical services, and extended care services to a covered veteran under this section; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF6935E86B4BA470ABA798389AF7C9C60"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary shall furnish hospital care, medical services, and extended care services to a covered veteran under this section with the same conditions on the ability of the veteran to choose health care providers as specified in the pilot program described in section 2 of such Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2484F31CA06648008EF093AA64E5532A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Veterans Care Agreements</header><text>Section 1703A(a)(1) of such title is amended—</text><clause id="H97932E6AD919402D90615FF87D1425E2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>For purposes</quote> and inserting <quote>Except as provided by subparagraph (E), for purposes</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="HD98FA154875B4C23B076709C095D3A1E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H08BC261D436B40D0BEA177572AB66CAD"><subparagraph id="H173AAA2A2B3D4D14B803E62136CFCF6F" indent="up2"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning on the date that is four years after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Veterans Health Care Freedom Act</short-title>—</text><clause id="HBC9CDE1264CA4B98BB3033DDD2E38185"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the requirement under subparagraph (A) and (C) that care or services may only be furnished under this section to covered individuals when such care or services are not feasibly available to the covered individual from a facility of the Department or through a contract or sharing agreement entered into pursuant to a provision of law other than this section shall not apply with respect to furnishing hospital care, medical services, and extended care services to a covered individual under this section; and</text></clause><clause id="H522A8A44FB244F8CBEBE15DF842401F4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary shall furnish hospital care, medical services, and extended care services to a covered individual under this section with the same conditions on the ability of the individual to choose health care providers as specified in the pilot program described in section 2 of such Act.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7C9C0ACB5F5043AEB43D98DB5A647219"><enum>(C)</enum><header>V<enum-in-header>ISN</enum-in-header>s</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning on the date that is four years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall furnish hospital care, medical services, and extended care services to veterans under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/17">chapter 17</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, at medical facilities of the Department of Veterans Affairs, regardless of whether the facility is in the same Veterans Integrated Service Network as the Network in which the veteran resides.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H11CE060F7CD548479A65AEDC5B776A7B"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Reports</header><paragraph id="H05C2AA974C264DE08D931D1B2E3523D1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Implementation</header><subparagraph id="idDE39184D334C4F0689B26BCDE92C866E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On a quarterly basis during the two-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on the implementation of the pilot program.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idEC620EABE9D84D6BA4F79514C5B87186"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Final design</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">One of the reports required under subparagraph (A) shall contain a description of the final design of the pilot program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H79AD039D6B8A470BBCFF36EF192BE7FB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Annual</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On an annual basis during the period beginning on the date that is one year after the date of the submission of the final report under paragraph (1) and ending on the date of the conclusion of the pilot program, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on the results of the pilot program.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H64B59AC79DD34FC1BFD3BE316FF91F85"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives, may prescribe regulations to carry out this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H6375A4D803284EDCB6F852A7AB854F77"><enum>(k)</enum><header>No additional appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No additional funds are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section and the amendments made by this section, and this section and the amendments made by this section shall be carried out using amounts otherwise made available to the Veterans Health Administration.</text></subsection><subsection id="H89DD8DD58BF3460C9100BD7AF53D360F"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H01757D3DCD9C455EB6DAA933F79AA4CC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered care system</header><text>The term <term>covered care system</term> means each—</text><subparagraph id="H2076C33B76BF4325A2F979BC32F5AA8E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>medical facility of the Department;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB87A093E6D8A42718A8A2721949167B9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>health care provider specified in subsection 1703(c) of title 38, United States Code; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6858D43BE20E4313B92165C2D60A032C"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">eligible entity or provider that has entered into a Veterans Care Agreement under section 1703A of such title.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H51DD0690D0804523B10494E9A534B944"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible veteran</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible veteran</term> means a veteran who is enrolled in the patient enrollment system of the Department of Veterans Affairs under section 1705 of title 38, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCA2E512CD789494092860FF2F698AA87"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Hospital care; medical services; non-Department facilities</header><text>The terms <term>hospital care</term>, <term>medical services</term>, and <term>non-Department facilities</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 1701 of title 38, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

