<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MDM25C24-S51-2P-WCW"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>107 S2645 IS: DHS Suicide Prevention and Resiliency for Law Enforcement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2645</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250801">August 1, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S380">Mr. Peters</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S399">Mr. Hawley</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To establish the Law Enforcement Mental Health and Wellness Program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="idf03d56cc-0c7b-49c0-a300-cc62e908586b" changed="not-changed"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>DHS Suicide Prevention and Resiliency for Law Enforcement Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" id="idb7e9b15a-91a1-424a-97c6-588a1c73dd74" changed="not-changed"><enum>2.</enum><header>Department of Homeland Security suicide prevention and resiliency for law enforcement</header><subsection commented="no" id="id64296675-97bb-482c-81a7-22496d8a74c3" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title VII of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/341">6 U.S.C. 341 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 710 the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida59f0b0e-fa00-4e4e-aa3b-7b532348ab6c" changed="not-changed"><section commented="no" id="id3e4f021a-0feb-4e2a-ad93-987d6dfeacdf" changed="not-changed"><enum>710A.</enum><header>Suicide prevention and resiliency for law enforcement</header><subsection commented="no" id="ida112b986-b3fd-4daa-9549-b8ffb7a31726" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><paragraph commented="no" id="ide08892b1-a291-4e55-a44f-878289c658f8" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Department of homeland security component</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Department of Homeland Security component</term> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="id3a17bd5f-9d0c-4ca9-9167-32e5075fdaea" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">U.S. Customs and Border Protection;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id5184bb95-5a05-4082-8681-116b6d898310" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="idfcbf4aa1-28ab-4204-a93b-a58677443cc9" changed="not-changed"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Office of the Inspector General of the Department of Homeland Security;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id31d980a9-b640-4781-936e-b2bdd6dab9f0" changed="not-changed"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the United States Coast Guard;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id9e5ea29f-8262-4d2e-8c15-d662495be3e7" changed="not-changed"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the United States Secret Service;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id739b683a-ed85-4a53-9d5b-5d1e156b6911" changed="not-changed"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Transportation Security Administration; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id35724e08-7ae2-44ff-8dc9-07b5b307fdf5" changed="not-changed"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other Department of Homeland Security component or office with law enforcement officers or agents.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idc188eab3-d14c-49c5-9bb2-caa07466c2a4" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Program</term> means the Law Enforcement Mental Health and Wellness Program established pursuant to subsection (b).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id10ccf0f2-7bdf-4490-b6ca-0dab7cb2e3f7" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Law Enforcement Mental Health and Wellness Program</header><paragraph id="id264daa01-9993-4693-857a-c062fa397c52" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><subparagraph id="id71fc26e8-504e-4aa8-9562-6949df57bf23" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall establish, within the office overseen by the Chief Medical Officer, the Law Enforcement Mental Health and Wellness Program.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida4b15953-5d0b-4a49-a0f8-13f1aa7c5e9c" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of the Program shall be to provide a comprehensive approach to address the mental health and wellness of Department of Homeland Security law enforcement agents and officers.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd3abe1fd-b510-41c0-a0a2-7fabb5136a94" changed="not-changed"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>The Secretary, working through the Program, shall—</text><clause id="id73349ea6-815c-4a1f-b026-90d862788581" changed="not-changed"><enum>(i)</enum><text>establish and maintain policies and standard operating procedures, consistent with best evidence-based practices, that detail the authority, roles, and responsibilities of the Program;</text></clause><clause id="id801e83ee-3007-40bb-a987-cc7b6ff217c4" changed="not-changed"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>conduct data collection and research on mental health, suicides, and, to the extent possible, attempted suicides, of law enforcement personnel within the Department of Homeland Security, in accordance with section 552a of title 5, United States Code (commonly known as the Privacy Act of 1974), section 501 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/791">29 U.S.C. 791</external-xref>), the Department of Homeland Security’s directives and policies, section 1128E of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1320a-7e">42 U.S.C. 1320a–7e</external-xref>), and section 2(a) of the Law Enforcement Suicide Data Collection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/143">Public Law 116–143</external-xref>);</text></clause><clause id="id377b052a-d967-4eeb-89b0-3a471690444b" changed="not-changed"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>track current trends and leading practices from other governmental and nongovernmental organizations for law enforcement mental health and wellness;</text></clause><clause id="id5a7b335d-baeb-4522-a97a-bf28ae5c60c3" changed="not-changed"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>evaluate current mental health and resiliency programs within Department of Homeland Security components;</text></clause><clause id="id8afb5826-9da3-492e-9c3d-f12cdd18e146" changed="not-changed"><enum>(v)</enum><text>promote education and training related to mental health, resilience, suicide prevention, stigma, and mental health resources to raise mental health awareness and to support the needs of supervisors, clinicians, care-givers, peer support members, chaplains, and those who have been exposed to trauma;</text></clause><clause id="id302fa9f974e84835811d11ea25f15bc5" changed="not-changed"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>establish partnerships with faith-based organizations, community-based organizations, counseling programs, or other social service programs that provide mental health and suicide prevention support services;</text></clause><clause id="idf5a2a15b-4975-4843-8521-4922756da821" changed="not-changed"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>establish the Peer-to-Peer Support Program Advisory Council, which shall—</text><subclause id="ida035ff23-c3cd-4816-a2a3-fd94236cdfa7" changed="not-changed"><enum>(I)</enum><text>include at least 1 licensed clinician and at least 1 official with requisite and relevant training and experience in peer support for law enforcement personnel from each Department of Homeland Security component;</text></subclause><subclause id="id0609d87c-0f67-4caf-9952-60ccd62c291c" changed="not-changed"><enum>(II)</enum><text>evaluate component peer support programs;</text></subclause><subclause id="idd9bafd22-3f19-4035-b521-43349c311723" changed="not-changed"><enum>(III)</enum><text>identify and address any potential deficiencies, limitations, and gaps;</text></subclause><subclause id="id90910041-661e-4b2e-8440-aafa42530d8f" changed="not-changed"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>provide for sharing of leading practices or best practices, including internationally recognized peer support standards of care protocols;</text></subclause><subclause id="id98d8e85a-0d9c-45dd-bf1d-b37c084a31c0" changed="not-changed"><enum>(V)</enum><text>create a peer support network that enables the sharing of trained peer support personnel, chaplains, and other peer-to-peer personnel across Department of Homeland Security components, and may also include outside agency organizations, such as faith-based organizations, community-based organizations, counseling programs, and other social service programs; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id17e3e94c-bae4-4462-8d6b-78ab7b99061f" changed="not-changed"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>sustain peer support programs through ongoing funding of annual and refresher training and resources for peer support programing in the workplace—</text><item id="idf988afc1-cc77-4959-ac57-6f44068c5ab3" changed="not-changed"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>to ensure minimum standards for peer support services; and</text></item><item id="id68d0c47a-dcaa-46ab-906c-d92244927774" changed="not-changed"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>to provide appropriate care for peer support personnel across Department of Homeland Security components;</text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="idb0b8bdf0-9757-4702-a00a-23e7ed01325d" changed="not-changed"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>assist Department of Homeland Security components in developing a program to provide suicide prevention and resiliency support and training for—</text><subclause id="id8193cc77-5d91-478b-a5ec-6d9a479c41e4" changed="not-changed"><enum>(I)</enum><text>families of law enforcement agents and officers; and</text></subclause><subclause id="idd60c7063-1b9d-4d20-a2e3-127c45389770" changed="not-changed"><enum>(II)</enum><text>surviving families of officers and agents who have died by suicide;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="ide5536a79-3f50-4138-9ce4-c588c0a4dcc9" changed="not-changed"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>work with law enforcement mental health and wellness program officials of Department of Homeland Security components (which shall include peer support-trained personnel, agency mental health professionals, chaplains, and, for components with employees having an exclusive representative, the exclusive representative with respect to such program) to implement new policies, procedures, and programs that may be necessary based on findings from data collection, research, and evaluation efforts; and</text></clause><clause id="id3dbad6a8-022c-405c-8179-6d68441b3040" changed="not-changed"><enum>(x)</enum><text>conduct regular outreach and messaging, across Department of Homeland Security components, of available training opportunities and resources.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id87dbbb82-8bb6-4eea-9201-10fafddbfb57" changed="not-changed"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Confidentiality; limitation</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9a4d236c-f1f8-4f41-8542-98d63f74ea2a" changed="not-changed"><enum>(i)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Confidentiality</header><text>Actions described in subparagraph (C) may not—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idebac57fe3ca8437ab62d0d2d7d613aaf" changed="not-changed"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include the publication of any personally identifiable information; or</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id88ae9b9fdd1244b9889ae09cea1d7325" changed="not-changed"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">compel any employee to provide any information for the purposes of this subsection.</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id42ce41ae-7864-441e-adad-777c67725d7a" changed="not-changed"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Personally identifiable information collected pursuant to subparagraph (C) may not be used for any purpose other than the implementation of this section unless otherwise permitted under applicable law. Any personally identifiable information that is collected, maintained, or used pursuant to this section is subject to applicable public nondisclosure requirements, including sections 552 and 552a of title 5, United States Code.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd0b09389-0f58-429a-905a-fcfcc5ee2758" changed="not-changed"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Personnel</header><clause id="id2273b457-ee70-4012-b6b2-a75f7bd108cd" changed="not-changed"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Management</header><text>The Workplace Health and Wellness Coordinator of the Department, under the direction of the Chief Medical Officer of the Department, shall be responsible for the ongoing management of the Program.</text></clause><clause id="ida864ecd0-e0bf-4913-b014-8eabfe48fcd3" changed="not-changed"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Minimum core personnel requirements</header><text>Subject to appropriations, the Secretary shall ensure that the Program is staffed with the number of employees that the Chief Medical Officer determines to be necessary to carry out the duties described in subparagraph (C), including representatives from each Department of Homeland Security component and the Office of the Chief Privacy Officer.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id6d9e73c2-0810-47a6-8d48-900638ce15a3" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Directive</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>DHS Suicide Prevention and Resiliency for Law Enforcement Act</short-title>, the Chief Medical Officer of the Department shall—</text><subparagraph id="idec98aee3-e0a0-400c-a99b-3e4d30a67b91" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>issue a directive or policy that outlines the roles and responsibilities of the Program; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id97fefeb7-990c-4bcc-b08d-498d8fedc099" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>distribute such directive or policy among all Department personnel.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idef1367aa-bbb9-4ba0-b2b5-9b497eef857f" changed="not-changed"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Chief Medical Officer of the Department shall require the Program to regularly coordinate with the Department of Homeland Security components by assigning at least 1 official from each such component to the Program for the purpose of coordinating with field points of contact who are responsible for carrying out duties within Department mental health and wellness programs.</text></subsection><subsection id="id78545277-447f-418b-a9a6-08aaf0516eb6" changed="not-changed"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Department of Homeland Security components</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall require the head of each Department of Homeland Security component to prioritize and improve mental health and wellness programs, which may include other Department of Homeland Security component personnel, that—</text><paragraph id="idca520b95-4a43-4548-9459-5daab45ee31e" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide adequate resources for law enforcement mental health, well-being, resilience, and suicide prevention programs and research;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7df420f5-4075-4558-9a94-42ecc66425ac" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">promote a culture that reduces the stigma of seeking mental health assistance through regular messaging, training, and raising mental health awareness;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id46696847-aee7-418d-b8bf-148e30fe9991" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">offer several avenues of seeking mental health or counseling assistance, both within the Department of Homeland Security component and through private sources, which may include faith-based organizations, community-based organizations, counseling programs, and other social service programs, that provide for anonymity and include access to external mental health clinicians;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id990d98d1-6385-4206-8be9-609bffc1e004" changed="not-changed"><enum>(4)</enum><text>review and revise relevant policies of Department of Homeland Security components that inadvertently deter personnel from seeking mental health assistance;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb50e95e0-18e8-4d96-bb7e-f0a1bf220753" changed="not-changed"><enum>(5)</enum><text>ensure that such programs include safeguards against adverse action by such component with respect to any employee solely because such employee self identifies a need for psychological health counseling or assistance or receives such counseling or assistance;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id639006c8cdfa4c8c9e277d89a182fb15" changed="not-changed"><enum>(6)</enum><text>ensure that such programs include safeguards regarding automatic referrals for employment-related examinations or inquiries that are based solely on an employee who self identifies a need for psychological health counseling or assistance or receives such counseling or assistance, except that such safeguards shall not prevent a component referral to evaluate an employee’s ability to meet established medical or psychological standards by such component or to evaluate an employee's national security eligibility;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2971b0ae-fc51-4424-ba8f-4b78ae929768" changed="not-changed"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">implement policies that require in-person or live and interactive virtual suicide awareness and law enforcement resiliency training for law enforcement officers and agents;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0eff8320-f60d-45b9-a6a7-be4f24d7d207" changed="not-changed"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">make such training available, as appropriate, to other personnel—</text><subparagraph id="id5e1d8db2-93db-476e-8326-e8271337c9a8" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">upon the commencement of their employment with the Department of Homeland Security;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id13f65f18-43f8-4c6e-b0e8-abddd3895eb9" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">on an annual basis during such employment;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida0e241e6-5dac-4366-be2c-bb2ac649ab3d" changed="not-changed"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">during such employees’ transition into a supervisory role; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id43bd6ab9-8837-410b-9ee7-23e2672554af" changed="not-changed"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if feasible, shortly before the officer, agent, or other Department of Homeland Security component personnel terminates his or her employment with the Department, if such individual elects to participate; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idec26ccd7-25fe-438a-a5cb-f9a7b1f05e3c" changed="not-changed"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include prevention and awareness training opportunities and support services for families of officers, agents, and other Department of Homeland Security component personnel.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0ff8cf71-a909-4607-8245-d1d0a1c71516" changed="not-changed"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Data collection and evaluation</header><paragraph id="id00a5cc0e-e93c-4cee-95b5-634cfb14ab76" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Assessment of effectiveness of law enforcement health and wellness programs</header><text>The Workplace Health and Wellness Coordinator of the Department, under the direction of the Chief Medical Officer of the Department—</text><subparagraph id="id640d3762-427d-4081-bf72-08ed1204b09e" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall develop criteria to assess the effectiveness of law enforcement health and wellness programs carried out by the Department;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5d074b30-cbfe-4916-99eb-739c9ad4cc40" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall conduct annual confidential surveys of law enforcement agents and officers within Department of Homeland Security components to assist in evaluating the effectiveness of law enforcement health and wellness programs in accordance with the criteria developed pursuant to subparagraph (A);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbbbf047f-4634-4d1b-9f1f-0fad924fb984" changed="not-changed"><enum>(C)</enum><text>shall ensure that the surveys conducted pursuant to subparagraph (B)—</text><clause id="id49d67212-816a-4430-8718-7df39c1b214e" changed="not-changed"><enum>(i)</enum><text>incorporate leading practices in questionnaire and survey design and development; and</text></clause><clause id="idbd322aa2-c84b-4e42-8a82-c11665b509c2" changed="not-changed"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>establish a baseline and subsequently measure change over time; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id43d53a97-637b-4a98-b61a-2a2b16302e07" changed="not-changed"><enum>(D)</enum><text>may utilize contractor support in carrying out the duties described in subparagraphs (A) through (C).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idbce8cf25-0a72-49f0-9a5f-c256e341e163" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Recommendations</header><text>The Chief Medical Officer of the Department shall provide recommendations to Department of Homeland Security components based on the evaluation of programs and the results of the surveys conducted pursuant to paragraph (1)(B).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc5fd4fa6-cdf9-45be-984e-8f1f34665251" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Incident reports</header><text>Each Department of Homeland Security component shall report, to the Workplace Health and Wellness Coordinator, incidents of suicide involving law enforcement officers and agents and any data consistent with data collected under section 2(a) of the Law Enforcement Suicide Data Collection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/143">Public Law 116–143</external-xref>). The Workplace Health and Wellness Coordinator shall forward such information to the Law Enforcement Officers Suicide Data Collection Program established pursuant to such section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idac357aeb-b9af-472d-9bed-9fa57fd4dc00" changed="not-changed"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Confidentiality; limitation</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9113bdc7-f183-460a-99ce-ecdd03c7071c" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Confidentiality</header><text>Activities described in paragraph (1) and reporting described under paragraph (3) may not include the publication of any personally identifiable information.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id39d3ab82-1133-471c-aeec-af8453ea2914" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Personally identifiable information collected pursuant to paragraph (1) may not be used for any purpose other than the implementation of this section unless otherwise permitted under applicable law. Any personally identifiable information that is collected, maintained, or used pursuant to this section is subject to applicable public nondisclosure requirements, including sections 552 and 552a of title 5, United States Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idb84b8fd4-86c9-436b-830b-af63f2f0e29f" changed="not-changed"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Briefing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>DHS Suicide Prevention and Resiliency for Law Enforcement Act</short-title>, and annually thereafter through fiscal year 2027, the Chief Medical Officer of the Department shall provide a briefing to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate</committee-name> and the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives</committee-name> regarding the implementation of the requirements described in this section.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0098cb2d846243d792219c7bb31ec1f5" changed="not-changed"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Voluntary participation; clarification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Participation in any program, survey, or data collection conducted under this section is voluntary.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idea9530cfffe84cb89c27513235358842" changed="not-changed"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any provision of this section, the Secretary may provide services under the Program to any employee of the Department.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="iddac95292-dbdc-44fb-ae50-4c029bc6c8ac" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents in section 1(b) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/107/296">Public Law 107–296</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 710 the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="ida533b9b6-c940-4d9d-851d-7a9fa45d8c72" changed="not-changed"><toc changed="not-changed"><toc-entry level="section" changed="not-changed">Sec. 710A. Suicide prevention and resiliency for law enforcement.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

