<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-CAN25227-Y54-YT-L0F"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 SRES 141 ATS: Recognizing the 204th anniversary of the independence of Greece and celebrating democracy in Greece and the United States.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 141</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250326">March 26, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S317">Mr. Barrasso</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S423">Mr. Ricketts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S270">Mr. Schumer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S410">Ms. Lummis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S437">Mr. Justice</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S316">Mr. Whitehouse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S345">Mr. Johnson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S259">Mr. Reed</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S330">Mr. Bennet</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S384">Mr. Tillis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S404">Mr. Scott of Florida</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing the 204th anniversary of the independence of Greece and celebrating democracy in Greece and the United States.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the people of ancient Greece developed the concept of democracy, in which the supreme power to govern was vested in the people;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the founding fathers of the United States, many of whom read Greek political philosophy in the original Greek language, drew heavily on the political experience and philosophy of ancient Greece in forming the representative democracy of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Petros Mavromichalis, the former Commander-in-Chief of Greece and a founder of the modern Greek state, said to the citizens of the United States in 1821, <quote>It is in your land that liberty has fixed her abode and … imitating you, we shall imitate our ancestors and be thought worthy of them if we succeed in resembling you.</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in an October 21, 1823, letter to Greek scholar Adamantios Koraes discussing the ongoing Greek struggle for independence, Thomas Jefferson wrote that <quote>[n]o people sympathise more feelingly than ours with the sufferings of your countrymen, none offer more sincere and ardent prayers to heaven for their success</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on January 19, 1824, in a speech in support of his resolution to send an American envoy to Greece amid its struggle for independence, then-Congressman Daniel Webster recognized <quote>the struggle of an interesting and gallant people … contending against fearful odds, for being, and for the common privilege of human nature</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas individual American Philhellenes, including future abolitionists Dr. Samuel Gridley Howe and Jonathan Peckham Miller, and George Jarvis, traveled to Greece to fight alongside and provide aid to the Greek people in their struggle for independence;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the people of the United States generously sent humanitarian assistance to the people of Greece during their struggle for independence, often through philhellene committees;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Greece heroically resisted Axis forces at a crucial moment in World War II, forcing Adolf Hitler to change his timeline and delaying the attack on the Soviet Union;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Winston Churchill said that <quote>if there had not been the virtue and courage of the Greeks, we do not know which the outcome of World War II would have been</quote> and <quote>no longer will we say that Greeks fight like heroes, but that heroes fight like Greeks</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas hundreds of thousands of Greeks were killed during World War II;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Greece consistently allied with the United States in major international conflicts throughout its history as a modern state and has been a member of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization since 1952;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States has demonstrated its support for the trilateral partnership of Greece, Israel, and Cyprus by enacting into law the Eastern Mediterranean Security and Energy Partnership Act of 2019 (title II of division J of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/94">Public Law 116–94</external-xref>) and through joint engagement with Greece, Israel, and Cyprus in the <quote>3+1</quote> format;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas this support was bolstered in the United States-Greece Defense and Interparliamentary Partnership Act of 2021 (subtitle B of title XIII of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/81">Public Law 117–81</external-xref>), establishing a 3+1 Interparliamentary Group to discuss the expansion of cooperation in areas of common concern;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States maintains close bilateral cooperation with Greece on security, energy, and other shared priorities, including the commitment to security cooperation that led to the conclusion of a Mutual Defense Cooperation Agreement, which was updated in 2019 and 2021, in order to enhance defense ties between the two countries and promote stability in the broader region;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the ongoing United States-Greece Strategic Dialogue reflects Greece’s importance to the United States as a geostrategic partner, especially in the Eastern Mediterranean and Balkans, and as an important NATO ally;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on November 13, 2023, the United States and Greece signed a memorandum of understanding to advance energy security and cooperation in the Western Balkans;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas regular high-level engagement between the Governments of the United States and Greece continued through 2024 and into 2025, during which both governments reaffirmed the strategic importance of the United States-Greece relationship and pledged to continue and increase cooperation based on shared values and interests; </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in the framework of the fifth United States-Greece Strategic Dialogue, on February 9, 2024, Greece became the 35th country to sign onto the Artemis Accords, affirming its commitment to a peaceful, sustainable, and transparent cooperation in space;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Government and people of Greece actively participate in peacekeeping and peace-building operations conducted by international organizations, including the United Nations, the North Atlantic Treaty Organization, the European Union, and the Organization for Security and Co-operation in Europe;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Greece has shown a strong commitment to meeting NATO defense spending obligations, recognizing the need for a more robust European pillar within NATO; </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Greece remains an integral part of the European Union and a current non-permanent member of the United Nations Security Council;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Greek-American community has greatly contributed to American society and has helped forge the strong ties between the United States and Greece;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Governments and people of Greece and the United States are at the forefront of efforts to advance freedom, democracy, peace, stability, and human rights;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas those efforts and similar ideals have forged a close bond between the peoples of Greece and the United States; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas it is proper and desirable for the United States to celebrate March 25, 2025, Greek Independence Day, with the people of Greece and to reaffirm the democratic principles from which those two great countries were founded: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id3d6f2c9764ab4e308dd6ecea61c0a15b"><enum>(1)</enum><text>extends sincere congratulations and best wishes to the people of Greece as they celebrate the 204th anniversary of the independence of Greece;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddb1efa9fa8224da39709e2e31c9b9a9a"><enum>(2)</enum><text>expresses support for the principles of democratic governance to which the people of Greece are committed;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id98321be11e9a4563b03f74b95f208563"><enum>(3)</enum><text>commends the Greek-American community for its contributions to the United States and its role as a bridge between the two countries;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf0574ef839124eee8cf9ee3aa701b64e"><enum>(4)</enum><text>notes the important role that Greece has played in the wider European region and in the community of nations since gaining its independence 204 years ago; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7af8d4cc01e74c779e81c02400c172be"><enum>(5)</enum><text>appreciates the ever-stronger bilateral relationship, based on shared values and interests, including the important energy and security partnership that exists between the United States and Greece, and the important role that Greece plays in bolstering European energy security; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb5f35809b793466cac7aba431ce8f5a8"><enum>(6)</enum><text>appreciates Greece as a valued NATO ally and its critical role in ensuring regional stability.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

