<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H04245CD6AC5042308F0F7899CC14FD08" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4734 IH: Hands Off Our Social Security Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4734</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250723">July 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001218">Ms. Stansbury</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="N000191">Mr. Neguse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000557">Mr. Larson of Connecticut</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="J000310">Ms. Johnson of Texas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To protect Social Security benefits and ensure the continued effective operation of the Social Security Administration.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H740249F6FAC4431882EF09D5B1ECD53A" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H55005FFC88B64A4EB20BD2ECB5CDD768" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Hands Off Our Social Security Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="H7F962C3F599D4C3699DC9E5C8A405E7F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purpose of this Act is to ensure the continued effective operation of the Social Security Administration and to protect Social Security services for all Americans by prohibiting tampering with benefits, unauthorized data mining, privatization efforts, workforce reductions, office closures, and communication changes that hinder access to Social Security benefits.</text></section> 
<section id="H3376687D93424A1A898E0404DC8BF0D8"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibition on tampering with social security benefits</header> 
<subsection id="H08F08DD220DF42129819098120039AB1">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
 <text>No Federal officer, special government employee, or contractor shall alter, withhold, or delay Social Security benefits in any manner that is not authorized by law.</text>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="H2712087514174DC98B8F8DB81D3324AA"><enum>(b)</enum><text>Any action to modify Social Security benefits shall require an Act of Congress.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HA3E6146F71284554B433DB43135ECD2A"><enum>4.</enum><header>Prohibition on unauthorized data mining and privacy violations</header> <subsection id="H1AE0E71115E84AF19DB2B41DEE04D632"> <enum>(a)</enum> <text>No Federal officer, special government employee, or contractor shall collect, share, or use Social Security data or personally identifiable information of beneficiaries or applicants for any purpose other than administering Social Security programs consistent with existing privacy laws.</text>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="H6096902CF8444C7A9CD6FC160301D286"><enum>(b)</enum><text>Any data mining or use of Social Security or personal data for commercial, political, or unauthorized purposes is prohibited.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HC0E03284E5EF40AD8C4437A8CD315AFC"><enum>(c)</enum><text>Violations of this section shall be subject to investigation and penalties under applicable Federal privacy and data protection laws.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H4BD0FC2786CC4F22A40D83CCE78DCDC9"><enum>5.</enum><header>Prohibition on privatization of Social Security benefits and services</header> 
<subsection id="HA7F386A3DFF144EF99D0FCF42D4CFE10"><enum>(a)</enum><text>No action shall be taken to privatize, outsource, or otherwise transfer Social Security benefits administration or services to private entities without express approval by an Act of Congress.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HDF855060181447D78EA9A34F0D511A61"><enum>(b)</enum><text>The Social Security Administration shall remain a Federal agency responsible for the administration and delivery of Social Security benefits.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HAE0B48218BE747FAB62ADB6EB8C3BC85"><enum>6.</enum><header>Prohibition on unauthorized workforce reductions at the SSA</header> 
<subsection id="H3744BC3D1ED0499895D8E5E95ABAA41A"><enum>(a)</enum><text>No officer or special government employee of the Federal Government shall implement or authorize any reduction in the workforce of the Social Security Administration without approval from an Act of Congress.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HEE18D523FC974CB7AE0B5CADE7488851"><enum>(b)</enum><text>Any reduction in SSA staffing levels shall require a detailed report to Congress, including the anticipated impact on service delivery and plans to maintain adequate service levels.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H2A448050B21F45C9BE84C48C510E8B24"><enum>7.</enum><header>Prohibition on closure of SSA offices without Congressional consent</header> 
<subsection id="H2F910EB5854C4A13A6B3E976C3233E36"><enum>(a)</enum><text>The closure or consolidation of any Social Security Administration office or field office shall be prohibited unless expressly authorized by an Act of Congress.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H3ACB8D3C0B8C4F9AAD303F6618440A50"><enum>(b)</enum><text>The SSA shall maintain a minimum number of fully operational field offices in each state proportional to the population served.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H715463EDB837421480D8E167ED4E8621"><enum>8.</enum><header>Maintenance of multi-channel communication systems</header> 
<subsection id="H42EFF068A5F04FF8A486919E3E1BBFB5">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
 <text>The Social Security Administration shall maintain its existing telephone and in-person communication services and ensure its effectiveness as essential channels for beneficiary assistance.</text>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="HCE413F83C29E485EA6929896E26A8257"><enum>(b)</enum><text>Any changes to communication methods, including use of social media platforms such as Twitter, shall be supplementary and not replace existing official communication channels.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H917591E459F047E69A53B04E1941941C"><enum>(c)</enum><text>No communication services essential to SSA beneficiaries shall be terminated or diminished without prior approval by an Act of Congress.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HB95044D4C0DD4AA192A759C927B2CACA"><enum>9.</enum><header>Enforcement and oversight</header> 
<subsection id="H0DFBC11B3EC042399B8491F5979E36C1"><enum>(a)</enum><text>The Government Accountability Office (GAO) shall conduct annual audits of SSA workforce levels, office operations, and communication services to ensure compliance with this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HB7189B1ECF7249F6B6668B431B87FACE"><enum>(b)</enum><text>The Comptroller General shall report findings to Congress, including any noncompliance and recommendations for corrective action.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H387E86DD13434C5CA3795ABF68ED59C6"><enum>10.</enum><header>Severability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any provision of this Act, or the application thereof, to any person or circumstances, is held invalid, the remainder of the Act, and the application of such provisions to other persons or circumstances, shall not be affected thereby.</text></section> </legis-body></bill>

