<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB84EDCB3F0844E41BCB62BD49A0B0526" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4712 IH: Parity for Tribal Law Enforcement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4712</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250723">July 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000189">Mr. Newhouse</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000600">Ms. Perez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001053">Mr. Cole</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000629">Ms. Davids of Kansas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001194">Mr. Moolenaar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001159">Ms. Strickland</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Z000018">Mr. Zinke</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000136">Mr. Vasquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001119">Ms. Craig</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001322">Mr. Baumgartner</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Natural Resources</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Indian Law Enforcement Reform Act to provide for advancements in public safety services to Indian communities, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC45C533C144E420AA1FD16630D9151AB" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="HC3F37234CA7146E6AA2C809FD29C2DEF"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Parity for Tribal Law Enforcement Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HCD317389562C490985BECC6983D7CE3A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Tribal law enforcement officers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Indian Law Enforcement Reform Act is amended by inserting after section 4 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/2803">25 U.S.C. 2803</external-xref>) the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H6D92A14FABC24512AAB4C5C8FFDC66FE">
<section id="H07C36EE4C525471AB67704CD4920FEB3"><enum>4A.</enum><header>Tribal law enforcement officers</header>
<subsection id="H1C54B23F740744EB8CFC9BD0086FF4F0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of Federal law, law enforcement officers of an Indian tribe that have contracted or compacted any or all Federal law enforcement functions through a contract or compact entered into pursuant to the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5301">25 U.S.C. 5301 et seq.</external-xref>) (referred to in this section as <term>Tribal officers</term>) shall have the authority to enforce Federal law within the area under the jurisdiction of the Indian tribe if—</text> <paragraph id="H8365F98687734E239C95034BAF466D02"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the applicable Tribal officers have—</text>
<subparagraph id="HBFC9B860E2C44FF09C58C768C4241B84"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">completed training that is comparable to that of an employee of the Office of Justice Services of the Bureau who is providing the same services in Indian country, as determined by the Deputy Bureau Director of the Office of Justice Services of the Bureau (or a designee);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE8265783C4B145B48EC4369141BB9AC3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>passed an adjudicated background investigation equivalent to that of an employee of the Office of Justice Services of the Bureau who is providing the same services in Indian country; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H9AEA3488039947498634DFA59F757D5D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>received a certification from the Office of Justice Services of the Bureau, as described in subsection (c); and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFE3E0C511A754985BB0703E3B97614DA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Indian tribe has adopted policies and procedures that meet or exceed those of the Office of Justice Services of the Bureau for the same program, service, function, or activity.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HDB105A30072B4A4FA1A0E454288DFB8E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Deemed To be Federal law enforcement officers</header><text>Subject to the guidance issued by the Secretary pursuant to subsection (c)(1)(B) and notwithstanding any other provision of law, while acting under the authority granted by the Secretary through a contract or compact entered into pursuant to the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5301">25 U.S.C. 5301 et seq.</external-xref>), a Tribal officer shall be deemed to be—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8BEF8D29FC344BF39C60A37EE267CB20"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a Federal law enforcement officer for the purposes of—</text>
<subparagraph id="HE737D64B050B4506AFE428CFC9AB0440"><enum>(A)</enum><text>sections 111 and 1114 of title 18, United States Code;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H82D00B07A466410ABF6457272869EA7A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>chapters 83 and 84 of title 5, United States Code; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA6712B66E2E54AA7AB1D74CA16FD1F9F"><enum>(C)</enum><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/171">chapter 171</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Federal Tort Claims Act</quote>); and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H547B6E17D3584438A9A60DA0E550EAED"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an eligible officer under subchapter III of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/81">chapter 81</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H95D88E938543452484D76AAD1B8ABC5C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Certification</header>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H40C3C9284CD8439DAEFD14BD1B9876A9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Parity for Tribal Law Enforcement Act</short-title>, the Secretary shall—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H49606F8D5DAC4A6B8008F4F21259EAF7"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">notwithstanding section 5, develop procedures for the credentialing of Tribal officers under this section to provide confirmation that Tribal officers meet minimum certification standards and training requirements for Indian country peace officers, as prescribed by the Secretary; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8876665FF42E44BEBE47AF9CBFEC44FA"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">notwithstanding any other provision of law, issue guidance, in consultation with Indian tribes, to otherwise implement this section, ensuring that, in implementing subsection (b)(1)(B), the guidance—</text> <clause id="H051B526C182E4DD78B9C29864D0CD8B8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>provides for the voluntary participation by Tribal officers, on a position-by-position basis;</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6F1217EE1AF64913938FAEC2FF14170E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>allows Tribal officers to purchase service credit for prior years of service consistent with the guidance issued by the Secretary under this subparagraph;</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF3CDA034DA5E4CF5808724886083CECA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>allows for the participation of Tribal officers, the salaries of which are funded in whole or in part by grants from the Office of Community Oriented Policing Services of the Department of Justice or any other agency in the Department of Justice; and</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1F7126A9A54344EF88C01C030C9D5A98"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>recognizes that Tribal officers may participate if the Indian tribes of those Tribal officers have a mandatory retirement age that exceeds the applicable Federal mandatory retirement age for Federal law enforcement officers.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9178D7B33DD9480CB739F65D94743EA4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>IPA Bridge Program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Tribal officers who choose to attend a State or other equivalent training program approved by the Deputy Bureau Director of the Office of Justice Services of the Bureau (or a designee) rather than attend the Indian Police Academy shall be required to attend the Bridge Program of the Indian Police Academy, or an equivalent program, prior to receiving a certification under this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section>
<section id="HF41A258130714280A57B556347308469"><enum>3.</enum><header>Oversight, coordination, and accountability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Attorney General, acting through the Deputy Attorney General, shall coordinate and provide oversight for all Department of Justice activities, responsibilities, functions, and programs to ensure a coordinated approach for public safety in Indian communities, accountability, and compliance with Federal law, including—</text> <paragraph id="H7EBBDE08440D4134B02494E25A8F7898"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the timely submission of reports to Congress;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HAEE063EA89C54AF7915665E030FA714B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>robust training, as required under Federal law and as needed or requested by Indian Tribes or Federal and State officials relating to—</text> <subparagraph id="H3C1278C95F5040E3B75C898C7AD888E4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>public safety in Indian communities; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H1A7B50332BC541098F741085817495F0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>training outcomes demonstrating a better understanding of public safety approaches in Indian communities;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3B85F2C795F04621BA25FBDC5136AA8C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the updating of, and improvements to, United States Attorney operational plans;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB948C51FAFD0405CAEBC431761A94FD3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>comprehensive evaluation and analysis of data, including approaches to collecting better data, relating to public safety in Indian communities; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H224B68D31FB3479E8FA20839B8529377"><enum>(5)</enum><text>other duties or responsibilities as needed to improve public safety in Indian communities.</text></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

