<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H257DC929160E4EEA899105A79842100B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5226 IH: Deceptive Downsizing Prohibition Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5226</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250909">September 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001110">Mr. Correa</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="F000110">Mr. Fields</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000309">Mr. Jackson of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Federal Trade Commission to promulgate regulations that prohibit the practice of deceptive downsizing, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB90E22B2AF7345F1AC9DCB7278281014" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H8184F1F1B9E14F8EBB2418A52D30CF0D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Deceptive Downsizing Prohibition Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H0058B9EBBAD4416C9AA754487ECA0FB3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H87F09C44AECE4FA4BCF516C2DDA80EDE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Manufacturers of consumer products, including food, are reducing the size of such products while continuing to use packaging designed for the same or similar product of a larger size.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB31A9F2F94E547DDB0ACB3DE710E4FD4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The practice of deceptive downsizing substantially harms consumers and reduces the purchasing power of consumers.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H79AA115CB65347DFAF777E2CE87EF9F9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Consumers frequently do not appreciate or recognize that the size of a consumer product has changed until after the purchase, if ever.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H19EB4B9AB6B545C0A3F59327334A860F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The trend toward producing consumer products of reduced size without reducing the price has driven inflation, causing substantial injury to consumers that is not reasonably avoidable.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6DA01094DE21416182CEA3062A728AD3"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Federal Government plays an essential role in protecting consumers from unfair or deceptive acts or practices, including ensuring manufacturers of consumer products do not deceive customers.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H03558D6D3CCB4B8AA97CAC70698F2C21"><enum>(6)</enum><text>This Act shall protect consumers by prohibiting manufacturers of consumer products from selling such products, regardless of price or cost, of reduced size in packaging previously used for the same or similar product of a larger size.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF88F8F8223884C179A2399A774E25110"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Consumers need clear, conspicuous, and easily understandable notice of a change in the size of a consumer product and simply including the reduced size on the packaging without context or highlighting does not provide sufficient notice to consumers to avoid a violation of this Act.</text></paragraph> </section> <section id="HEA8C553041CC40AABA40D9C28AFB2151"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="H464280FF17F6458CA15678B76E08FB4E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Federal Trade Commission.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBD8A97111E07444BAAFAE7ED8A11A764"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consumer product</header><text>The term <term>consumer product</term> has the same meaning given the term in section 101 of the Magnuson-Moss Warranty—Federal Trade Commission Improvement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/2301">15 U.S.C. 2301</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE3F908DEEDD942E4A08B858793E617F6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Deceptive downsizing</header><text>The term <term>deceptive downsizing</term> means the practice of a manufacturer of a consumer product selling such a product of reduced size using the same or substantially similar packaging that was used for any prior version of the same or substantially similar product that was of larger size.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H17272741F54B4FABAE1267D39BF90733"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Larger size</header><text>The term <term>larger size</term> means a consumer product of greater volume, size, mass, weight, or quantity relative to the consumer product that is the subject of the alleged deceptive downsizing.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H358D31624681424186C35A7BEEACA65F"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Reduced size</header><text>The term <term>reduced size</term> means a reduction in volume, size, mass, weight, or quantity of a consumer product relative to any prior version of the same or substantially similar consumer product.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HDDD97649237F44E7A811F9BC61BFE327"><enum>4.</enum><header>Prohibition on deceptive downsizing</header> <subsection id="H9F76482A60CF4A81AEA8FFA7C66A05A6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A manufacturer of a consumer product may not engage in deceptive downsizing with respect to such consumer product.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9948D3960B7A4D1BAE61DBB7A19ABB76"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Safe harbor</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A manufacturer of a consumer product shall not be liable for deceptive downsizing with respect to such consumer product in violation of subsection (a) if the manufacturer sells the consumer product in a reduced size using the same or substantially similar packaging as for the larger size of the consumer product and—</text> <paragraph id="H6589C61601344789995EE8E0F7B2BD4B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the manufacturer provides notice on the principal display panel of such packaging that the consumer product is of reduced size; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBFA94C7CD3A64647B9210B4064DDD783"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such notice—</text> <subparagraph id="HCDA8990B8E6F4B87A80800C93DF35795"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is conspicuous, clear, and easy for consumers to read and understand; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H69A2BA0483F34BB582AB83B21CB050F3"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">states the larger size of the consumer product and the reduced size of the consumer product.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HE2DB5A5EAD4643DA91A2051DF0225E25"><enum>5.</enum><header>Regulations relating to prohibition on deceptive downsizing</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Commission may promulgate, under section 553 of title 5, United States Code, any regulations the Commission determines necessary to carry out the provisions of this Act.</text></section> 
<section id="H51D86BB62B934A1294651DD26A11F90D"><enum>6.</enum><header>Enforcement by Federal Trade Commission</header> 
<subsection id="H64225871CF8349A9AAEF036FFFFBF8DD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Unfair or deceptive acts or practices</header><text>A violation of this Act shall be treated as a violation of section 18(a)(1)(B) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/57a">15 U.S.C. 57a(a)(1)(B)</external-xref>) regarding unfair or deceptive acts or practices.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H646BF9941C544344A8FF8322ADB87ACC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Powers of Commission</header><text>The Commission shall enforce this Act in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though all applicable terms and provisions of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>) were incorporated into and made a part of this Act, and any person who violates this Act shall be subject to the penalties and entitled to the privileges and immunities provided in the Federal Trade Commission Act.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0F3F4A8C3EA84DAB9595DDB050601EDA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this Act may be construed to limit the authority of the Commission under any other provision of law.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

