<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-HLA25026-KMG-MF-XPP"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 21 IS: Designating October 10, 2025, as “American Girls in Sports Day”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 21</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250113">January 13, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S395">Mrs. Hyde-Smith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S378">Mr. Lankford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S411">Mr. Marshall</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S345">Mr. Johnson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S323">Mr. Risch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S384">Mr. Tillis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S153">Mr. Grassley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S344">Mr. Hoeven</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S374">Mr. Cotton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S376">Ms. Ernst</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S317">Mr. Barrasso</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S420">Mr. Schmitt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S416">Mrs. Britt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S287">Mr. Cornyn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S410">Ms. Lummis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S318">Mr. Wicker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S412">Mr. Tuberville</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S375">Mr. Daines</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S293">Mr. Graham</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S355">Mr. Cruz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S346">Mr. Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S398">Mr. Cramer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S266">Mr. Crapo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S266">Mr. Sheehy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S383">Mr. Sullivan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S373">Mr. Cassidy</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S407">Mr. Hagerty</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Designating October 10, 2025, as <quote>American Girls in Sports Day</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas athletic participation has an important, positive impact on young girls, improving their physical health, self-confidence, and discipline;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas women have been responsible for some of the greatest athletic feats in the sports history of the United States, from the Olympic games to professional competition;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas female athletes have served as inspirations for generations of women and girls;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the enactment of Title IX of the Education Amendments of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1681">20 U.S.C. 1681 et seq.</external-xref>) (referred to in this preamble as <quote>Title IX</quote>) marked a pivotal moment in the Federal support of girls in sports;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas there are fundamental biological differences between men and women that put women at a competitive disadvantage in sports and jeopardize their safety during competition;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in recent years, there has been an increase in the number of biological men allowed to compete in women’s sports;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, since 2003, biological men have displaced women and girls from over 950 championship titles, medals, scholarships, and records they should have rightfully won, including at least 28 women's sports titles in volleyball, swimming, mountain biking, track and field, weightlifting, and cycling;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the National Association of Intercollegiate Athletics (NAIA) has instituted new policies to protect biological girls in sports and ensure that only student athletes whose biological sex is female will be allowed to compete in NAIA-sponsored women’s sports teams; </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas it is imperative that women’s and girl’s opportunities to compete athletically are protected; and</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas October 10th, as represented by the Roman numerals <quote>XX</quote>, signifies the female XX chromosomes: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="iddf17d157f79f4ed8b2e0780de7d076ad"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognizes October 10, 2025, as <quote>American Girls in Sports Day</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1695273ba55e4c088cf4a5cfed093a68"><enum>(2)</enum><text>celebrates the impact of women on the sports culture and history of the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id62364876f2a848229c125a06469f94c8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recognizes the importance of Title IX in protecting biological women in sports; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3ea7f13de847462681c01c6399c526a5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>calls on sports-governing bodies in the United States and abroad to protect biological women and girls in sports.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

