<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H657E451301794A2295F8E86891D57981" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 275 IH: Special Interest Alien Reporting Act of 2024</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 275</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250109">January 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000596">Ms. Greene of Georgia</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="G000590">Mr. Green of Tennessee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001077">Mr. Higgins of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001132">Mr. Crane</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000591">Mr. Guest</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001317">Mr. Brecheen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Homeland Security to publish on a monthly basis the number of special interest aliens encountered attempting to unlawfully enter the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H5D1DC722813F47EF8ECE0F40864C1BE7" style="OLC"><section id="HD10118C28A0B44788EB7E41C9A1D1513" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"> This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Special Interest Alien Reporting Act of 2024</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HD4642EE830B043B2B888CFF6FB7AF7B5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Publication by the Department of Homeland Security of the number of special interest aliens encountered attempting to unlawfully enter the United States</header><subsection id="H10D78CA5D4A64350B68859AC7C50CB47"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than the seventh day of each month, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall publish on a publicly available webpage of the Department of Homeland Security and submit to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a report on the total number, and an identification of the nationalities or countries of last habitual residence, of special interest aliens encountered by the Department attempting to unlawfully enter the United States during the immediately preceding month. Each such report shall also include the following:</text><paragraph id="H3CF3745057984A42BD2235403B4F80A2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Such number disaggregated by geographic regions of such encounters.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5147CD5F87A84B38AFE6F3C6143B9004"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Specifications relating to whether such encounters were made at land, air, or sea ports of entry, between ports of entry, or in the interior of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAE66CD0269A54284B917F3374FA75E10"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Identification of any such nationalities or countries of last habitual residence that are covered nations.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H76EDF91239764B55BBA363D7F2D0F46F" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph id="HF5315CEB731147078AE23F03B283514B" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Alien</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>alien</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 101 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2F63717A221D4EF6B3E1D6C735DE5787" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered nation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>covered nation</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 4872(d)(2) of title 10, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBDF491F797AE4E538E5FFB9F4F747C9C" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Special interest alien</header><text>The term <quote>special interest alien</quote> means an alien who, based on an analysis of travel patterns, potentially poses a national security risk to the United States or its interests.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

