<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-BAG25B27-J53-LJ-48D"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2061 IS: Molly R. Loomis Research for Descendants of Toxic Exposed Veterans Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2061</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250612">June 12, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor
          name-id="S229">Mrs. Murray</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read
        twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSVA00">Committee on Veterans'
 Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Interagency Working Group on Toxic Exposure to conduct research on the diagnosis and treatment of health conditions of descendants of individuals exposed to toxic substances while serving as members of the Armed Forces, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="id2a66bcc9cb774146ab8d0cba543ba8d1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Molly R. Loomis Research for Descendants of Toxic Exposed Veterans Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id439312b9a1d04774b821fddc91092493" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Research on diagnosis and treatment of health conditions of descendants of individuals exposed to toxic substances while serving in Armed Forces</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1def2edae69143c694b5628be47dc158"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (b) of section 501 of the Sergeant First Class Heath Robinson Honoring our Promise to Address Comprehensive Toxics Act of 2022 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/168">Public Law 117–168</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6EC629B3891A4279AB3EB19232BD8AE8"><paragraph id="id77d68616662949e49420ce4ac3af38dd"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Establish Federal interagency task forces to conduct collaborative research activities.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="id09612f731d5a488895f5486975c7eb3f"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text>Subsection (c) of such section is amended by striking paragraphs (2) and (3) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idE163064C6CCA4F7DBA3DBF1E43D98CDC"><paragraph id="id69f995c4a21348b49eedb8f2b4117c51"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Molly R. Loomis Research for Descendants of Toxic Exposed Veterans Act of 2025</short-title>—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id784dfcaf4a5944d08bc11c3a21a3a63e"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a report containing a description of the collaborative research activities identified by the Working Group under subsection (b);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7aca5e875c9b4cdfa2ee49b24339109d"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the findings of the members of the Working Group with respect to the collaborative research activities described in subparagraph (A); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd92da0581bbc4dfc91636854e6e3c6af"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such recommendations as the Working Group may have for legislative or administrative action to improve collaborative research activities among the members of the Working Group.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id91b24eddedd24894b27f572b6abda7c0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Not less frequently than annually during the five-year period covered by the strategic plan developed under subsection (b)—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5201bf074f73468ba503e72e700e7de9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a summary of the collaborative research activities carried out by the members of the Working Group and the findings of the members with respect to such research activities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfdff9ee6b7924bbf888017ecc6551d54"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a progress report on implementation of the strategic plan developed by the Working Group under subsection (b); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id99a81c0254a145f0a522a0e8a10b1048"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such recommendations as the Working Group may have for legislative or administrative action to improve collaborative research activities among members of the Working Group.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5084bd3178fd45cf9b708c3ccdfa39cd"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Research requirements</header><text>Such section is amended—</text><paragraph id="id43ba3d2ba2c74ba4b8cd3a34c63cb157"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (c) through (e) as subsections (d) through (f), respectively;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idae27acccd24943c4af74da2867c1e70b"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (e), as redesignated by paragraph (1), by striking <quote>under subsection (c)</quote> and inserting <quote>under subsection (d)</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id504750c6e91c4e58b4a60a31b16b66c3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (b) the following new subsection (c):</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idC4BABCC2F5F34EC9B339B0CFC11069D6"><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1641d1e444b7449ab6598f0928075fc7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Requirements relating to certain research on impacts to descendants</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Molly R. Loomis Research for Descendants of Toxic Exposed Veterans Act of 2025</short-title>, the Working Group and the Agency for Toxic Substances and Disease Registry shall—</text><paragraph id="idff603c5fcfb84fae9cee57a61427640b"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establish an interagency task force to conduct research on the diagnosis and treatment of health conditions of descendants of toxic-exposed veteran (as defined in section 101 of title 38, United States Code); and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idefa5d4a165f14c0c99aa444bb3ba7c66"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">maintain a publicly available website with information on the activities and findings of the Agency under paragraph (1), including a review of all relevant data to determine the strength of evidence for a positive association between a health condition researched and a toxic exposure risk activity (as defined in section 1710(e)(4) of title 38, United States Code) based on the categories set forth under section 1173(c)(2) of title 38, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

