<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" slc-id="S1-NEW25576-H57-SC-18J"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 294 ATS: Designating the week of May 18 through May 24, 2025, as “National Public Works Week”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 294</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250618">June 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S372">Mrs. Capito</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S316">Mr. Whitehouse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S428">Ms. Alsobrooks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S398">Mr. Cramer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S318">Mr. Wicker</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S430">Ms. Blunt Rochester</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Designating the week of May 18 through May 24, 2025, as “National Public Works Week”.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas public works professionals work around the clock to ensure the vital infrastructure, facilities, and services of communities to deliver dependable, sustainable, and resilient human needs that include the health, safety, and well-being of the people of the United States, while advancing the quality of life for all;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas public works infrastructure, facilities, and services could not be provided without the dedicated efforts of public works professionals who represent Federal, State, and local governments, and private sector organizations throughout the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas public works professionals design, build, operate, and maintain the transportation systems, water infrastructure, sewage and refuse disposal systems, public buildings, sanitation and waste management systems, and other structures and facilities that are vital to the people and communities of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas many public works professionals are first responders and are the first to arrive and last to leave a natural disaster area or incident scene; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas understanding the role that public infrastructure plays in protecting the environment, improving public health and safety, contributing to economic vitality, and enhancing the quality of life of every community of the United States is in the interest of the people of the United States: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="S1"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="idca180b206b5642a48f68dc0271f84cb4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>designates the week of May 18 through May 24, 2025, as <quote>National Public Works Week</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf4406c52948b4f928e4a80f7c2c755ec"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes and celebrates the important contributions that public works professionals make every day to improve—</text><subparagraph id="id62d49b5611164d0c97bb1d1af21e1be2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the public infrastructure of the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id70ad6a37d3fc4f4a9187a22ac87024aa"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the health, safety, and well-being of our communities that public works professionals serve; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id42448b4ba526498fba1fb5e03f5400f2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>urges individuals and communities throughout the United States to join with representatives of the Federal Government in activities and ceremonies that are designed—</text><subparagraph id="idb5df83b95dd8432cb3bfd4357f9f5017"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to pay tribute to the public works professionals of the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5c593b128cfa45aca75e2a07f505dfbb"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to recognize the substantial contributions that public works professionals make to the United States. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

