<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-SIL25079-8D0-C3-F9D"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S256 IS: Pardon Transparency and Accountability Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 256</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250125">January 25, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the President to publish a statement of reasons for pardons, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Pardon Transparency and Accountability Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id6f90aea2b7654a8ba56a2f40608d7488"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="id0b71ae3871264181b19ddc22fe873f9c"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Executive clemency</header><text>The term <term>executive clemency</term>—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id030cbd5035a0441eb3afb0402c01752b"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means any exercise by the President of the power to grant reprieves or pardons under clause 1 of section 2 of article II of the Constitution of the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6f233c3b24b347a481a357571d990e68"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes any pardon, commutation, reprieve, or remission of a fine.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id7c05aa82c9d54fcb8d33119e6a882268"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Victim</header><text>The term <term>victim</term> has the meaning given the term in section 503(e) of the Victims’ Rights and Restitution Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/20141">34 U.S.C. 20141(e)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section><section id="id6cef5742251f413b95d9753ee7bdfc0b"><enum>3.</enum><header>Statement of reasons for pardons</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">On the date on which any grant of executive clemency is made, the President shall publish in the Federal Register and on the official website of the President a written explanation of the reasons for granting such executive clemency.</text></section><section id="id780100a9db1e448c9f37ff3c9fac7824"><enum>4.</enum><header>Duties of the Pardon Attorney</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1eacf69a16c140a992fe7a98cf375d0e"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Justice Impact Statement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Pardon Attorney shall, as soon as the Pardon Attorney becomes aware of any potential grant of executive clemency being considered by the President, begin preparing a Justice Impact Statement, which shall be made available to the President and Congress as soon as practicable but not later than 30 days after the date on which the Pardon Attorney becomes so aware, and which shall include—</text><paragraph id="id156c161f17a14d0dadb5d7d5d6e01e89"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a description of the efforts of the Pardon Attorney—</text><subparagraph id="id183348c12b9449eeb76834f22e11d7fc"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to contact victims as required under subsection (c)(1); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida63e1ff8a53043c48ce2528ec2e63073"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to make each determination required under paragraphs (2) and (3) of subsection (c); and </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idabbb47c7df684231967542def6585ad7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any written statement submitted by a victim under subsection (c)(1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd077326d5b914dab8de3a69e203f16a9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Notification</header><text>Any employee of the Department of Justice or Executive Office of the President who learns that the President is considering a grant of executive clemency shall immediately inform the Pardon Attorney of such consideration.</text></subsection><subsection id="id7e6e95fa79f044d6921c63385822b40a"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Determinations required</header><text>In the preparation of any Justice Impact Statement under subsection (a), the Pardon Attorney shall make all reasonable efforts to—</text><paragraph id="id3ee01918c4df44c1869475eb6dd5831b"><enum>(1)</enum><text>inform the victims of any crime committed by the person receiving a grant of executive clemency that they may submit written statements for inclusion in the Justice Impact Statement prepared by the Pardon Attorney;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida58e6786ebf2406eae964febb2e54465"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">determine the opinions of the victims described in paragraph (1) regarding the potential grant of executive clemency; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id79f8cc99a32842669aa6358e36ed9655"><enum>(3)</enum><text>determine the opinions of the Attorney General, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and other Federal, State, local, and Tribal law enforcement officials, as appropriate, as to the potential impact of the grant of executive clemency on the success of any ongoing investigation or prosecution.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id48530792cf0149a38f90f12a31351a69"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Justice Impact Statement completion</header><text>The Justice Impact Statement required under subsection (a) shall be completed and submitted even if submitted after executive clemency is granted.</text></subsection></section><section id="idab7e53985b134d63aad15f820bffaa2e"><enum>5.</enum><header>Pardon lobbying disclosure</header><subsection id="id032cd32529a2429fb7ccacb0807bc742"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>Section 3 of the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1602">2 U.S.C. 1602</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7a6dda7528c5497581a8f46098c54370"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (8)—</text><subparagraph id="iddce1a9555e134831bc2fe1a73dbbab36"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)—</text><clause id="id2079ce2b50a94909bded65106b77899c"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in clause (iii), by striking <quote>or</quote> after the semicolon;</text></clause><clause id="idfafa938233554acdbf1b1bdf2c80d1b0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in clause (iv), by striking the period and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="id2d0ef47c1e7241c7ad8b5fdfc8573556"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idAE14C795E0FB42B39D310CFAEC711E21"><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1cb38419f5dd44f79c1ed5514c52a582"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the issuance of a grant of executive clemency, as defined in section 2 of the <short-title>Pardon Transparency and Accountability Act of 2025</short-title>, in the form of a pardon, commutation of sentence, reprieve, or remission of fine.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida64bbabda0764cc9ae93f241271a4863"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)(xii), by striking <quote>made to</quote> and inserting <quote>except as provided in subparagraph (A)(v), made to</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddb2068116b734a0e8694eeb77b949a14"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (10), by inserting after the word <quote>period</quote> the following: <quote>, or any individual who is employed or retained by a client for financial or other compensation for services that include not fewer than 1 lobbying contact relating to a potential grant of executive clemency, as defined in section 2 of the <short-title>Pardon Transparency and Accountability Act of 2025</short-title>, regardless of the percent of the services provided by the individual to that client that consist of lobbying activities.</quote></text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id241922db28624db39cfa113354a18ea7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Registration of lobbyists</header><text>Section 4 of the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1603">2 U.S.C. 1603</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB3C22B1A5DB94757A3DADAC1C19E81CC"><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2b49452ebddd4c7a91898cbb9cd3d358"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Registration relating to grants of executive clemency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 days after the date on which a lobbyist first makes a lobbying contact pertaining to a potential grant of executive clemency, as defined in section 2 of the <short-title>Pardon Transparency and Accountability Act of 2025</short-title>, or is employed or retained to make a lobbying contact pertaining to a potential grant of executive clemency, as so defined in that Act, whichever is earlier, such lobbyist (or the organization employing such lobbyist) shall register with the Secretary of the Senate and the Clerk of the House of Representatives in accordance with the requirements of this section, regardless of the total income or expenses related to such lobbying activities.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="id4cd5bdf30ab5461f8682364f515011e9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reports by registered lobbyists</header><text>Section 5 of the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1604">2 U.S.C. 1604</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3AC89F1845D5445C89E19ECC49788E34"><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id80907f70cb654fc28a563330698b437b"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Lobbying contacts relating to executive clemency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 days after a lobbying contact pertaining to a potential grant of executive clemency, as defined in section 2 of the <short-title>Pardon Transparency and Accountability Act of 2025</short-title>, each registrant shall file a report with the Secretary of the Senate and the Clerk of the House of Representatives containing the information described in subsection (b) relating to the lobbying contact pertaining to the potential grant of executive clemency.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="id4d5fcd88fcdc40fa847dd1fe3b8ee75f"><enum>6.</enum><header>Studies and reports</header><subsection id="idbffe8ea93ca2412693cfb0eb8704ad99"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Studies</header><paragraph id="idfb63aa8934e74b6bb4d58f4e8bfbe9aa"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Beginning on the date that is 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, and every other year thereafter, the Pardon Attorney shall conduct a study on the extent of compliance or noncompliance with this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb19f6b2c87074a529b628744678f22f5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header><text>Not later than April 1 of each year following the completion of the study required under subsection, the Pardon Attorney shall submit to Congress a report containing the findings of the study and any recommendations to improve compliance with this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id105fad5de3744248b8904005b21790fe"><enum>7.</enum><header>Severability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any provision of this Act, an amendment made by this Act, or the application of such a provision or amendment to any particular person or circumstance is held invalid, the remaining provisions of this Act and the amendments made by this Act, and the application of such remaining provisions and amendments to any other person or circumstance, shall not be affected thereby. </text></section></legis-body></bill> 

