<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H487D62C9A9F940EAADF63B27F0E3BD34" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3357 IH: Enhancing Multi-Class Share Disclosures Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3357</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250513">May 13, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to require issuers with a multi-class stock structure to make certain disclosures in any proxy or consent solicitation material, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H1BD1873BF01749D78C94B989FAF7BB4E" style="OLC"><section id="H48A9B4E8BC4A4EB4AF45C8406CFDE93F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Enhancing Multi-Class Share Disclosures Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H295DE5A590C54F4DAAD4D2A6A0329810"><enum>2.</enum><header>Disclosure relating to multi-class share structures</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 14 of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78n">15 U.S.C. 78n</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDC546BDAA4884703B5518289901E822F" style="OLC"><subsection id="HF5B59A701A50495BA6D7E05BAD134E2F"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Disclosure relating to multi-Class share structures</header><paragraph id="H0E18F3ABFF3843DAA559E878A47D3133"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Disclosure</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall, by rule, require each issuer with a multi-class share structure to disclose the information described in paragraph (2) in any proxy or consent solicitation material for an annual meeting of the shareholders of the issuer, or any other filing as the Commission determines appropriate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H60063E8E31C94ADC916FAF990CFF61B7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Content</header><text>A disclosure made under paragraph (1) shall include, with respect to each person who is a director, director nominee, or named executive officer of the issuer, or who is the beneficial owner of securities with 5 percent or more of the total combined voting power of all classes of securities entitled to vote in the election of directors—</text><subparagraph id="H642714C5463343F3914BB3A0C2C2B5B9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of shares of all classes of securities entitled to vote in the election of directors beneficially owned by such person, expressed as a percentage of the total number of the outstanding securities of the issuer entitled to vote in the election of directors; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB2108E016FBE4A67AE941957E65A4020"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the amount of voting power held by such person, expressed as a percentage of the total combined voting power of all classes of the securities of the issuer entitled to vote in the election of directors.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF5607C59789F4F6B947EE3C3C0DAED72"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Multi-class share structure</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, the term <term>multi-class share structure</term> means a capitalization structure that contains 2 or more types of securities that have differing amounts of voting rights in the election of directors.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

