<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H78BCE067F28D4FE3AB68395077BACD1B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1115 IH: Weather Radar Coverage Improvement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1115</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250207">February 7, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001087">Mr. Crawford</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001224">Mr. Moran</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To develop the next generation of weather radar, authorize supplemental gap radar coverage, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H144C13B0443741FC92FFD73291DFF0FF" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H3A8A1E07969F4D108801EE193845C8ED" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Weather Radar Coverage Improvement Act</short-title></quote></text></section> <section id="HC85AE15C8C0E4FAE86D85F5CEDDF4F72"><enum>2.</enum><header>Next generation phased array radar</header> <subsection id="H7BEE15A9849E49C7B0447F5F7148FD08"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Under Secretary, in consultation with the Director of the National Weather Service, shall develop a plan to replace the Next Generation Weather Radar of the National Weather Service (<quote>NEXRAD</quote>) system in existence as of the date of the enactment of this section.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HC03A3314998347869287AA527340727A" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Procurement deadline</header><text>The Under Secretary shall take such actions as may be necessary to ensure the replacement described in subsection (a) is completed by not later than September 30, 2040.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H67347413127947E18B44F648757C8C73"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The plan developed pursuant to subsection (a) shall include the following:</text>
<paragraph id="HBFB53E3ADB3842B7B785A76F19A53F29"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Estimates of quantifiable improvements in coverage and accuracy to be made from replacement of the NEXRAD system referred to in such subsection.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H715098E5021C4D59B9FEDF58D9676938"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Development of a prototype digital phased array radar to test and determine the specifications and requirements for such replacement.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8D2F080694EE44DD815D2C84E6E94E7A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Establishment of a weather surveillance phased array radar testbed for the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H198AF2AD9868475BAC80F0DCBF29F839"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Evaluation of commercial radars with the potential to replace or supplement the NEXRAD system.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HDA7FBA883D0B48B4BA6725B59D6DE2D6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Providing technical assistance for the use of small, gap filling radars in regions where geographical topography prevents full utilization of larger systems.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC45B1E0BD94B44918D17C19E966D89D5"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Consultation and input solicited from meteorologists, emergency managers, and public safety officials regarding the specifications and requirements for replacement of the NEXRAD system referred in such subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H31FA7BDF6B2F44DC87879D0600AD394E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Radar-as-a-Service</header>
<paragraph id="HC455DA25CC3F424EA442C4DE1BDE8C51"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In order to supplement gaps in radar coverage in existence as of the date of the enactment of this section and ensure the continued performance of weather radar capabilities, the Director of the National Weather Service may utilize and contract with third party entities to fill such radar gaps using diverse weather radars and data assimilation technologies to better detect significant precipitation and severe weather over a greater area across the population.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7CAE010AADD14E8A9346AB6362546BCE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In carrying out the activities under paragraph (1), the Director of the National Weather Service shall prioritize utilizing and contracting with third party entities that have participated in the testbed established in accordance with subsection (c)(3).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9915CE74BF3E4C499A5661193FF57182"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Weather camera systems</header><text>In carrying out the activities under paragraph (1), the Director of the National Weather Service may consider weather camera systems and services as viable technologies to supplement gaps in radar coverage.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H12CD958EE0E94ECABEF9AD876FC54DE2"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Updates to Congress</header><text>The Under Secretary shall provide to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate periodic updates on the implementation of this section.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H2956E49C6383442186ED20D60AFABBEB"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <quote>Under Secretary</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 2 of the Weather Research and Forecasting Innovation Act of 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/8501">15 U.S.C. 8501</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

