<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6EBA8F8C5BA641FC82545F420D65AF95" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5382 IH: Health Career Advancement and Remuneration Exclusion for Training Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5382</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250916">September 16, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To improve training requirements for health profession opportunity grant programs and exclude assistance provided by those programs from income tax, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6EE6AA46B36E44598938607EDDDE41B7" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H0D828ECAFA0544798A908939067EED99" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Health Career Advancement and Remuneration Exclusion for Training Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Health CARE Training Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HCCDF3F60DB6D4B34A3DC74BB50A15897"><enum>2.</enum><header>Training requirement for health profession opportunity grant participants</header> <subsection id="H0C408726689F40E8B4BBAB5351644420"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 2008(a)(2) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1397g">42 U.S.C. 1397g(a)(2)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block id="HDFB71D5B73054078A7C0FEBF42FC71C8" style="OLC">
<subparagraph id="H7D09B9329CEF4D0A99340E069B605FA5"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Training</header><text>A demonstration project conducted by an eligible entity awarded a grant under this subsection shall provide to an eligible individual participating in the project who is being trained to qualify for a recognized post-secondary credential (including an industry-recognized credential, and a certificate awarded by a local workforce development board established under section 107 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act) which is awarded in recognition of attainment of measurable technical or occupational skills necessary to gain employment or advance within an occupation, a number of hours of such training that is not less than—</text> <clause id="H22BA4D09213A4503829AF08EAD3A04EE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the number of hours of training required for certification of that level of skill by the State in which the project is conducted; or</text></clause>
<clause id="H0C6282BCAB664A2D85CFB1189A52789A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if there is no such requirement, such number of hours of training as the Secretary finds is necessary to achieve that skill level.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HA2F29910D16345AFAA993C39B66EA080"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by subsection (a) shall take effect on October 1, 2025.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="H113755404F5E4479AA7E24F9E5DF5FF8"><enum>3.</enum><header>Exclusion of assistance provided under a health professions workforce demonstration project from Federal income tax</header>
<subsection id="H209083CBCD7C4FF6AA9ABBC63D6BC416"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 2008(a)(2)(A)(ii) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1397g">42 U.S.C. 1397g(a)(2)(A)(ii)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block id="H3C35996B9A1F48F59F0297B9CEDF03B4" style="OLC"> <clause id="H36C301593B234A3AA7F4694355A02BA2"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Income disregard</header><text>Amounts paid to an eligible individual as a cash stipend or as emergency assistance under a project for which a grant is made under this section shall not be considered income for any purpose under the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, and an entity making such a payment shall not be required to submit an information return under subtitle F of such Code with respect to the payment.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection>
<subsection id="HEC32C424FD434A14897B269805D98684"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by subsection (a) shall apply with respect to amounts paid on or after October 1, 2025.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

