<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-TAM25392-DKC-8L-NP5"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1258 IS: Stephen Hacala Poppy Seed Safety Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1258</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250402">April 2, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S374">Mr. Cotton</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S343">Mr. Boozman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To prohibit the sale of food that is, or contains, unsafe poppy seeds.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HAE82C8C4D28947349789967482EFA059"><section section-type="section-one" id="H7A1D25C1422F4239956ED03E7CA0604A"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stephen Hacala Poppy Seed Safety Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HA57F18B7B5954B699FF47CDD6F4857AD"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings; purpose</header><subsection id="HCA4E95E38CB04C5ABC41D54688AF9449"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds as follows:</text><paragraph id="HE22B14966E7F402982277F77915E40E9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Stephen Hacala was a 24-year-old from Fayetteville, Arkansas, who was dearly loved by family and friends when he died from morphine intoxication caused by consumption of contaminated poppy seeds.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA8C9C03C3E804F95BD6CD2ADC5042295"><enum>(2)</enum><text>At least 19 people in the United States have been confirmed to have died from morphine overdoses from contaminated poppy seeds.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA71B2FE3E1F04E2F9FE90768427950F8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Women in the United States have tested positive for opiates in hospitals at childbirth due to poppy seed consumption in food, leading to unwarranted scrutiny from child welfare officials.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF8E49EA9F2B440C1B6016D59BB991543"><enum>(4)</enum><text>In 2023, the Department of Defense issued a warning to all servicemembers to avoid poppy seed consumption due to opiate contamination and the risk of positive drug tests.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCFB342AD11F0420EA6779E4D53217879"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Studies of pharmaceutical opiates have found that a dose of just 20 to 50 morphine milligram equivalents per day increases the risk of overdose and death among patients prescribed morphine for pain treatment.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAB54A84B69F042EF83FB15272211A36B"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Poppy products purchased in the United States have been found to have up to 2,788 milligrams of morphine per kilogram of seeds after extraction.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H292961E4E2FA4904B67EED575B98404D"><enum>(7)</enum><text>While poppy seeds are excluded from the definition of <quote>opium poppy</quote> and <quote>poppy straw</quote> under the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/801">21 U.S.C. 801 et seq.</external-xref>), that definition does not exclude unwashed poppy seeds that have been contaminated with opium alkaloids from the latex of the plant. The opium alkaloids (inclusive of morphine, codeine, and thebaine), if present as contaminants on poppy seed material, are also not exempted from control under that Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0FDFC40E904E4320A2E8B3EEDAD9F74F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>It is the purpose of this Act to establish levels for contamination of poppy seeds by morphine, by codeine, and by other illicit compounds, above which poppy seeds shall be considered adulterated foods that are prohibited in interstate commerce.</text></subsection></section><section id="H47E7AEE42AB5494F8A7D80DFD633F0F0"><enum>3.</enum><header>Unsafe poppy seeds as adulterants in food</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall—</text><paragraph id="HD5873386E63641FC863C4A256BE1C75A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, issue a proposed rule establishing levels for contamination of poppy seeds by morphine, by codeine, and by any other compound which the Secretary may designate, above which poppy seeds shall be deemed adulterated under section 402 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/342">42 U.S.C. 342</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB86C930AAB9F4B7989C586E6A28D79CC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, finalize such rule.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HCEC4834D1EEB4E6498AF96448A204E7F"><enum>4.</enum><header>Poppy seeds as a controlled substance</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed as exempting poppy seeds that are contaminated by morphine, codeine, another alkaloid compound, or any other compound designated by the Secretary of Health and Human Services under section 3 from regulation under the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/801">21 U.S.C. 801 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

