<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H954F8CC1E52A458181EC17BF8D56AAD8" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1553 IH: Empowering and Enforcing Environmental Justice Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1553</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250225">February 25, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="M001229">Mrs. McIver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001130">Ms. Crockett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000402">Mr. Kennedy of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000197">Ms. DeGette</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish an Office of Environmental Justice within the Department of Justice, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H19A2A6D1CE034AAF9C8EB2F1AAE32D63" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="HB9280736EEC5451DA41151646B23FA7A"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Empowering and Enforcing Environmental Justice Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H0AEA5D09A2A64DFB8A906E6C1D287F07"><enum>2.</enum><header>Office of Environmental Justice</header><subsection id="HEC57C903A08E435BB188F0331B7200DC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/31">Chapter 31</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA956BEF81B414FE5A509CCDF62828C2D"><section id="H80EF56269A5E427E919921EDC5CE3220"><enum>530E.</enum><header>Environmental Justice</header><subsection id="HDDFEA61A17534EE789C3903EA8201762"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HA9CA690748124BFCB73048255EA0BFFE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Council</header><text>The term <quote>Council</quote> means the Senior Advisory Council established under subsection (c).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H196A57A64C0D4EBD8E3D5522CFC7F515"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Department</header><text>The term <quote>Department</quote> means the Department of Justice.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H47D7B7338BE848948D3BF1CE61C3D1A3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Environmental justice</header><text>The term <quote>environmental justice</quote> means the just treatment and meaningful involvement of all people, regardless of income, race, color, national origin, Tribal affiliation, or disability in agency decision-making and other Federal activities that affect human health and the environment so that individuals—</text><subparagraph id="HD2715DB0562D412DA711E818BAB21A61"><enum>(A)</enum><text>are fully protected from disproportionate and adverse human health and environmental effects (including risks) and hazards, including those related to climate change, the cumulative impacts of environmental and other burdens, and the legacy of racism or other structural or systemic barriers; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9CE78DE84FE04C0D8AE5852933855197"><enum>(B)</enum><text>have equitable access to a healthy, sustainable, and resilient environment in which to live, play, work, learn, grow, worship, and engage in cultural and subsistence practices.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0B36D906633C4BAAB37BA64D95BDEFE9" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Environmental justice matter</header><text>The term <quote>environmental justice matter</quote> includes any civil or criminal matter in which the conduct or action at issue may involve a disproportionate and adverse environmental or human health effect on— </text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H33F430D2793C461CA9B5803971B02775"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an identifiable low-income, Tribal, or Indigenous population or community in the United States; or </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5FC993A0B2E94007A990667E5DD05E74"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a community in the United States with environmental justice concerns.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFBA465A20B694F4FB602933A50FE764F"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Indigenous population or community</header><text>The term <quote>Indigenous population or community</quote> includes populations or communities of American Indians, Alaska Natives, and Native Hawaiians.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA1F27E5C43574DC7B8705A378623110A"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Low-income community</header><text>The term <quote>low-income community</quote> means any census block group in which 30 percent or more of the population are individuals with an annual household income equal to, or less than, the greater of—</text><subparagraph id="H4812F28D6E404BEE922F0CE57FF84F9C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an amount equal to 80 percent of the median income of the area in which the household is located, as reported by the Department of Housing and Urban Development; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H74D92315FAD949DBA7324F177FF681DD"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">200 percent of the Federal poverty line.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H918C06B8840341979E9D4A676B93488C"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Office</header><text>The term <quote>Office</quote> means the Office of Environmental Justice established under subsection (b)(1). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEAB512A22632456580082B14B5A396E5"><enum>(8)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <quote>State</quote> means any State of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0526EC31C7C84337812EA25034F59111"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Office of Environmental Justice</header><paragraph id="H08FBF73409FC4868BB3775D77E2F6ECA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established the Office of Environmental Justice within the Environment and Natural Resources Division of the Department. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6CC8924384A7485ABBD9DBBA3D7F4B3B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Personnel and funding</header><text>The Attorney General shall provide to the Office such personnel and funds as are necessary to establish the Office under paragraph (1) and to carry out the duties of the Office under paragraph (4). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H27E97817D12942968BADB01D043D3985"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Leadership</header><text>The Office shall be headed by a Director, who shall be appointed by the Attorney General.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5FCAC551E1794FEB94072BA117B54C9C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Director shall:</text><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H077868778EC44D0CB5EC867110FCD502"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Develop, and update every 5 years thereafter, the environmental justice strategy for the Department relating to Federal actions to address environmental justice.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8AA0735335F544C1B27EB72F4526664D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Coordinate environmental justice matters that arise at the Department and United States Attorneys' offices, including building outreach and engagement capacity and competency among the Department’s personnel. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H4644AE064EB04A458634D84ECF4C6FBB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Administer the grant program established under section 3 of the <short-title>Empowering and Enforcing Environmental Justice Act of 2025</short-title>. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H26D61D648C7445208F4979AF9687A590"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Promote and protect the right of the public to participate meaningfully in the decision-making process on environmental justice matters and design communications efforts with the goal of maximizing community understanding of how to participate in environmental justice matters, including how to file administrative complaints with Federal agencies.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H05081022BA094F8D9232FEDE201AB2E1"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Counsel and assist State, local, and Tribal governments on how to coordinate their actions with the Federal Government with respect to environmental justice matters and counsel and assist State, local, and Tribal governments and Indigenous populations or communities in providing equal environmental protection for all individuals. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9F07E64DC55B47DB94EF968F91A98873"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Provide support for State and local environmental enforcement training in communities with environmental justice concerns. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0EA09AFA47954D90928F91FB4318E2B6"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Work with the Community Relations Service to facilitate a working relationship between parties involved in environmental justice matters, including regulated industry, State, local, and Tribal decision-makers, nonprofits, low-income communities, and Indigenous populations or communities.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF12EFF5224EF45BCA2C438859010EF04"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Organize, at minimum, bimonthly calls or meetings with environmental justice organizations and communities with environmental justice concerns.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7BE09E8F811F4822A2D794F269E5FF82"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Manage the Council.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA3FA0179E1734497B6A4EE9080C0CBDC"><enum>(J)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Make recommendations to Federal agencies on community participation in the development of administrative settlement agreements relating to environmental justice matters. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7D9AC9B259A441F9B2DBD015F7FBF69B"><enum>(K)</enum><text>Develop—</text><clause id="H63DBE834BE464EDB8798CCB7E7F7E072"><enum>(i)</enum><text>instructional videos and other materials for Department personnel to provide an overview of the scope of environmental justice matters and procedures for identifying and reporting such matters; </text></clause><clause id="HA4223F2EDFB5483D9B594B8E079B78A2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>education programs for environmental attorneys about criminal, civil, and civil rights laws;</text></clause><clause id="HD2DC4FF2C3204138B2428B80983A494C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>education programs for civil, criminal, and civil rights attorneys about environmental laws for the purpose of identifying and effectively addressing environmental justice matters;</text></clause><clause id="H8DD69CAEA47E4C238E54041EBC2ED231"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>an email address that Department attorneys and other Department personnel may contact that enables Department attorneys and other Department personnel to seek information and guidance on environmental justice matters;</text></clause><clause id="H630D751EA9734E06BA18E3E7BE59CFB3"><enum>(v)</enum><text>joint education and training activities, where appropriate, with Federal agencies and State, local, and Tribal legal offices;</text></clause><clause id="H864E98705C5D47FAB7F9816BE29AD1D2"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a continuing legal education course on environmental justice matters, developed in coordination with the Office of Legal Education and the Environmental Protection Agency; and</text></clause><clause id="HDF24747CD3804640A69F61AD111691E4"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>training programs with respect to environmental justice for individuals participating in the Attorney General's Honors Program.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC09E54796DB04CE1A20D552B577F8C4E"><enum>(L)</enum><text>Coordinate with all relevant components within the Department to develop and maintain an appropriate system for tracking and assessing cases that raise environmental justice matters. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H703A9261FB5E4722A7B85D4BBA541216"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Senior Advisory Council</header><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9DDDA1C482484E00AC05A8726F5C6F18"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established a Senior Advisory Council to advise the Assistant Attorney General of the Environment and Natural Resources Division on matters of environmental justice and recommend policy and initiatives with respect to environmental justice matters.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF54ADBB1332A459F820744846A632DAE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Co-chair</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Co-chairs of the Council shall be the Assistant Attorney General of the Environment and Natural Resources Division and the Director of the Office.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H50BC50CA312F40DB8B5C3F1AE74CA832"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Members</header><text>The Council shall be composed of:</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="HBD392E91DE72471D9B50262F212ADB19"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Assistant Attorney General of the Environment and Natural Resources Division.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H7000B89E2B2544B4AFF2BBC06D183A87"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Director of the Office.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA1BFA3E9D31844D097CE7A5C67911517"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">One representative of the Office of the Deputy Attorney General.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3CC2F8E1F77B4FFBBF8377309CB5D905"><enum>(D)</enum><text>One representative of the Office of the Associate Attorney General.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB1397ECB04224F39913533358ED30CDD"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">One representative from the Environmental Enforcement Section of the Environmental and Natural Resources Division.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2C2D8DB1C5484AB5B5C205EAFA05E635"><enum>(F)</enum><text>One representative from the Environmental Defense Section of the Environment and Natural Resources Division. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3B1243B7EB334291BADF7BE0E5A3FEF6"><enum>(G)</enum><text>One representative of the Civil Rights Division.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD8B6EBE363E04FDFB81EE4638CE47665"><enum>(H)</enum><text>One representative of the Civil Division.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA2288A87AC504441A8FF9BE616A1D4B8"><enum>(I)</enum><text>One representative of the Federal Bureau of Investigation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7FFA9216C74F40C7B6A4CD20AAB3146E"><enum>(J)</enum><text>One representative of the Bureau of Prisons.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7202A05CAA6B4B038541FF080480FD08"><enum>(K)</enum><text>One representative of the Community Relations Service.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H61E42776C3CF4C32AFB14ED2110806E7"><enum>(L)</enum><text>One representative of the Office for Access to Justice.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7E42CD1B9F0E4F468AF777F040A60CD2"><enum>(M)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">One representative of the Office of Legal Policy.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4B2DB42EF8CA4EE3AAD75A38BF0D56C1"><enum>(N)</enum><text>One representative of the Office of Legislative Affairs.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0F347EC32F764E09B87948D74ED96F2C"><enum>(O)</enum><text>One representative of the Office of Tribal Justice.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H01D50674958E4CDB8A51BB6377568184"><enum>(P)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Two representatives from the Executive Office for United States Attorneys.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HAA320BB0D4D94C4ABB5AB768EA469044"><enum>(Q)</enum><text>The Section Chief of the Environmental Justice Section. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H713D696361744628ADB60DCB061DF143"><enum>(R)</enum><text>Not fewer than 2 representatives from United States Attorneys' offices. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2E588C7F9311497FA86E0AFD7907A2F0"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Reporting requirement</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H84D8E9927DE94105B1C38A1B8B6608ED"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Empowering and Enforcing Environmental Justice Act of 2025</short-title>, and annually thereafter, each member of the Council shall submit to the Director a report on the implementation of the progress of the component of which the member is a representative in implementing the environmental justice strategy of the Department and any proposed revisions to the environmental justice strategy of that component. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2BC820AAC5164346B8691FB25ED4662A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Other reports and briefings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to the reports required under subparagraph (A), the Director may also request a report or briefing from the head of any component not a member of the Council explaining how the component may facilitate the efforts of the Department in meeting the obligations of the Department under the environmental justice strategy.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB2A53B65E5FD4BBEAED4843A2265D73E"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Administration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall coordinate and support the work of the Council. The Director shall convene the Council not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Empowering and Enforcing Environmental Justice Act of 2025</short-title> and shall convene the Council not less than 4 times annually thereafter. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H535CB7ADA67D4C3088B6C5F5CBC966AD"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Guidance for Department</header><subparagraph id="H72B65DACB5F64DD68E3EB19BF8B05E0D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Empowering and Enforcing Environmental Justice Act of 2025</short-title>, the Council shall develop guidance with respect to environmental justice and provide such guidance to Department personnel, including provisions for identifying, tracking, and addressing environmental justice matters.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4950AF23FAB8423B988D045065964859"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Review and update</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 3 years after the development of the guidance under subparagraph (A), and every 3 years thereafter, the Department shall review and update such guidance.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H2274B74C9D4F4E989450379F26F4DF6A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/31">chapter 31</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H65B875F6612F4BC38AC93F767C0BF3F8"><toc><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">530E. Environmental justice.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="HE2FD265BB808497083C236501046788D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Environmental Justice Matters Enforcement Grants</header><subsection id="HF1CD7883ABF845B8A4742C4B71F61F71"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section: </text><paragraph id="HD1DE1CBFFD1345C5869F716B9D7FCF30"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Certain congressional committees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>certain congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="HC6EAB5132C8348E7BBEB7130E91C999C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committees on Environment and Public Works and the Judiciary of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA0AA2041F91D4DB6B80991448FB7EF9E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committees on Energy and Commerce and the Judiciary of the House of Representatives. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H953844A33B0743AFB6F994D2A0978607"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Environmental justice</header><text>The term <quote>environmental justice</quote> means the just treatment and meaningful involvement of all people, regardless of income, race, color, national origin, Tribal affiliation, or disability in agency decision-making and other Federal activities that affect human health and the environment so that individuals—</text><subparagraph id="HC359E64D0D55401E9FAAD73212AD0001"><enum>(A)</enum><text>are fully protected from disproportionate and adverse human health and environmental effects (including risks) and hazards, including those related to climate change, the cumulative impacts of environmental and other burdens, and the legacy of racism or other structural or systemic barriers; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE77247EA3F3B47B19654640555138DF4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>have equitable access to a healthy, sustainable, and resilient environment in which to live, play, work, learn, grow, worship, and engage in cultural and subsistence practices.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H226ED3CF1E024E84A919023390C02FC7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Environmental justice matter</header><text>The term <quote>environmental justice matter</quote> includes any civil or criminal matter where the conduct or action at issue may involve a disproportionate and adverse environmental or human health effect on an identifiable low-income, minority, Tribal, or Indigenous population or community in the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H508FC1330FC5484298F567AD60CD04EB"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Indigenous population or community</header><text>The term <quote>Indigenous population or community</quote> includes populations or communities of American Indians, Alaska Natives, and Native Hawaiians.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H4E91651A46064271A154E19DF100C122"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Low-income community</header><text>The term <quote>low-income community</quote> means any census block group in which 30 percent or more of the population are individuals with an annual household income equal to, or less than, the greater of—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H0BF8FEDA12674B189C95061C9F556F1E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an amount equal to 80 percent of the median income of the area in which the household is located, as reported by the Department of Housing and Urban Development; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HC23624A347B249C2BA09025EFF3254CA"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">200 percent of the Federal poverty line.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1681B0EA8323441CB5433643A8B40192"><enum>(6)</enum><header>State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>State</term> means any State of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC7BD77956EEE44358EF2253D69EB1CCF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General shall establish a grant program (in this section referred to as the <quote>Program</quote>) within the Office of Environmental Justice to improve the capacity of State, local, and Tribal governments to enforce environmental laws involving environmental justice matters.</text></subsection><subsection id="H0A913F107AE44178AD74DBCC7670F154"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Grant authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the Program, the Assistant Attorney General may award grants on a competitive basis to eligible recipients, except that no eligible recipient may be awarded more than 1 grant. </text></subsection><subsection id="H4235988D2B814387BA7E3F9B9A2317EA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Eligible recipients</header><text>The Assistant Attorney General may award a grant under the Program to a State, local, or Tribal government determined by the Assistant Attorney General to be capable of carrying out a project pursuant to subsection (e).</text></subsection><subsection id="H7BBEBB4ED199495F978CFC6134DC4899"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Grant funds</header><text>Grant funds awarded under the Program, shall only be used to—</text><paragraph id="HB35A8E55F4FE4A97A3225D4E911CFCD3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">train State, local, and Tribal agencies responsible for prosecuting and enforcing laws involving environmental justice matters;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA7C24878425C4C1A837DEA5446EE8A88"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">hire staff to assist in the investigation, prosecution, and enforcement of laws involving environmental justice matters; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFAC62C3D81614FCD870BCB86E94624E0"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish collaborative programs to provide technical and legal assistance, outreach, and engagement to help communities with environmental justice concerns participate in decisions impacting the environment, health, and safety of those communities with environmental justice concerns. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7C164776114947B384349E3D33B780BF"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Applications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible for a grant under the Program, an eligible recipient shall submit to the Assistant Attorney General an application in such form, at such time, and containing such information as the Assistant Attorney General determines to be appropriate.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA159DB2D43FB48BCA924D3D3DA7F3620"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Limitations on grant amounts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to the availability of appropriations under subsection (j), each grant made under this section shall be for an amount not less than $50,000 and not greater than $1,000,000.</text></subsection><subsection id="H4021871848FF4EE1930542AAA333E6BC"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Federal share</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal share of a project under the Program shall not exceed 80 percent, unless the Attorney General waives, wholly or in part, this requirement.</text></subsection><subsection id="H42F6C081864640A5BA733E77A9405154"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, and every 2 years thereafter, the Attorney General shall submit a report to certain congressional committees on the grant program established under this section, including a description of the grantees and activities for which grantees used grants awarded under this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H03ED8CAF65CD46EB985C96C829D6E99F"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $50,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2026 through 2035.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

