<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H633F627B7CDA42F7A55A238DFCF253BA" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 675 IH: Expressing support for the designation of September 2025 as “National Prostate Cancer Awareness Month”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 675</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250903">September 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001218">Mr. McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000628">Mr. Dunn of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Lieu</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001226">Mr. Menendez</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of September 2025 as <quote>National Prostate Cancer Awareness Month</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas more than 3,100,000 men have at some point been diagnosed with prostate cancer and are still alive in the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 1 in 8 men in the United States will be diagnosed with prostate cancer in their lifetimes and 1 in 44 men in the United States will die from prostate cancer;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Men’s Health Network advises that prostate cancer is the most commonly diagnosed nonskin cancer and the second-leading cause of cancer-related deaths among men in the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the American Cancer Society estimates that, in 2025, 313,780 men will be diagnosed with, and more than 35,770 men will die of, prostate cancer;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 40 percent of newly diagnosed prostate cancer cases occur in men under the age of 65;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the odds of developing prostate cancer rise rapidly after age 50;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas African-American men suffer from a prostate cancer incidence rate that is significantly higher than that of White men and have more than double the prostate cancer mortality rate than that of White men;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas having a father or brother with prostate cancer more than doubles the risk of a man developing prostate cancer, with a higher risk for men who have a brother with the disease and the highest risk for men with several affected relatives;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas screening by a digital rectal examination and a prostate-specific antigen blood test can detect the disease at the earlier, more treatable stages, which could increase the chances of survival for more than 5 years to nearly 100 percent;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas only 32 percent of men survive more than 5 years if diagnosed with prostate cancer after the cancer has metastasized;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas there are typically no noticeable symptoms of prostate cancer in the early stages, making appropriate screening critical;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Department of Veterans Affairs has established 21 Precision Oncology Centers of Excellence in order to deliver precision oncology services to veterans suffering from prostate cancer;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas ongoing research promises further improvements in prostate cancer prevention, early detection, and treatment; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas educating people in the United States, including health care providers, about prostate cancer and early detection strategies is crucial to saving the lives of men and preserving and protecting families: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H789A2D4D8CC6407296A86CF736465BCA"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HCB11D1F623884EFDA4117CEF7AE97FA5"><enum/><text>That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="H273D39CE8CAB42D3AF5BCBA120CC9E9E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>expresses support for the designation of <quote>National Prostate Cancer Awareness Month</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H86A0AD083C48438A95BABBE3A2168E00"><enum>(2)</enum><text>declares that steps should be taken—</text><subparagraph id="H4BA9CB06F7D64A30BE178DCED475AE6E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to raise awareness about the importance of screening methods for, and treatment of, prostate cancer;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8D521E324FE54E64BF5FA5557D66B4D7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to encourage research—</text><clause id="HC9E606DAC959474AAB0FF03A6A1EFBC5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to improve screening and treatment for prostate cancer;</text></clause><clause id="H820E5F331E7E4566AAF5120D8F6F0BC2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to discover the causes of prostate cancer; and</text></clause><clause id="H7E9413CA663A4ABAA7F8173A6021F9DC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to develop a cure for prostate cancer; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1423BB83C26B413AA73477D92AA5D429"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to continue to consider ways to improve access to, and the quality of, health care services for detecting and treating prostate cancer; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC1C45765D07340408364D2B9D0E5F351"><enum>(3)</enum><text>calls on the people of the United States, interest groups, and affected persons—</text><subparagraph id="H46CD07D71C5C4F8692F7E35E9DAEE3F9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to promote awareness of prostate cancer;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB4225B4DE15E48F1A6CAC5E87A787B92"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to take an active role in the fight to end the devastating effects of prostate cancer on individuals, families, and the economy; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H84D866806B824F24B67BF7AF9C5767D8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to observe National Prostate Cancer Awareness Month with appropriate ceremonies and activities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

