<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-KAT25738-CL2-PC-SD6"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2917 IS: Safety Funding Parity Adjustment Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2917</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250919" legis-day="20250916">September 19 (legislative day, September 16), 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S435">Mr. Sheehy</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To prescribe a process to allow the Secretary of Transportation to make funding adjustments with respect to highway safety funding, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Safety Funding Parity Adjustment Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id32d022acfa4441a1aa5872477da80e28"><enum>2.</enum><header>Highway safety funding adjustments</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5ae850805c434d1ea05058234f1ea38c"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaaa04152a3c8429896abfc69b4ebb817"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Transportation.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idec2fb95977334f9dad56302ee923bdfb"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Section 402 funding</header><text>The term <term>section 402 funding</term> means funding to carry out section 402 of title 23, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id42954195d4944adfbc3cd2d95f59f28b"><enum>(3)</enum><header>section 405 funding</header><text>The term <term>section 405 funding</term> means funding to carry out section 405 of title 23, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id180fe9d3b44d4f5c8c487bbe8c2f0848"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Initial Determination</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, before distributing or apportioning any funds for a fiscal year under section 402 or 405 of title 23, United States Code, the Secretary shall make a determination as to whether, prior to any funding adjustment under this section, and not counting any transfers of funds to carry out section 402 of that title from chapter 1 of that title, there is an increase in section 402 funding or section 405 funding over the prior fiscal year.</text></subsection><subsection id="id39deb6bc1c7d49bc87e1f7dceb613bb7"> <enum>(c)</enum> <header>Increases in section 402 funding and section 405 funding</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id897034faeb634d79bcf92565daf08b68"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary makes a determination under subsection (b) that there is an increase in section 402 funding and section 405 funding for the current fiscal year over the prior fiscal year, the Secretary shall determine whether the percentage increase in section 402 funding for the current fiscal year over the prior fiscal year is at least 4 times the percentage increase in section 405 funding for the current fiscal year over the prior fiscal year.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="idf43357bca2b949d6bf0a955f529c3f88">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>No adjustment</header>
 <text>If the Secretary makes a determination under paragraph (1) that the percentage increase in section 402 funding for the current fiscal year is at least 4 times the percentage increase in section 405 funding for the current fiscal year, the Secretary shall not make a funding adjustment under this section.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id119bd6e609464069b12e3d77bfc69777">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
                    <header>Adjustment required</header>
 <text>If the Secretary does not make a determination under paragraph (1) that the percentage increase in section 402 funding for the current fiscal year is at least 4 times the percentage increase in section 405 funding for the current fiscal year, the Secretary shall—</text>
                    <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcb19170bbf0f42ab8622a8707dfbb4bb">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reduce section 405 funding for the current fiscal year proportionately and in a total amount that, when added to section 402 funding for the current fiscal year, results in a rate of increase in section 402 funding for the current fiscal year over section 402 funding for the prior fiscal year that is 4 times the percentage increase in section 405 funding for the current fiscal year over section 405 funding for the prior fiscal year; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id649eccd4ad8c44aebd1353f731298942">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>add the total amount by which section 405 funding for the current fiscal year is reduced under subparagraph (A) to section 402 funding for the current fiscal year.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
 </subsection><subsection id="id888b5b4d9f134943a15267714252b42e"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Increase in section 402 funding but not in section 405 funding</header><text>If the Secretary makes a determination under subsection (b) that there is an increase in section 402 funding but not section 405 funding for the current fiscal year over the prior fiscal year, the Secretary shall not make a funding adjustment under this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="id1b4aae2d7d0f478394a91fe537894508"><enum>(e)</enum><header>No increase in section 402 funding and no increase in section 405 funding</header><text>If the Secretary makes a determination under subsection (b) that there is no increase in section 402 funding or section 405 funding for the current fiscal year over the prior fiscal year, the Secretary shall not make a funding adjustment under this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="id128349a3d59542378a3e8fe714764bdd"><enum>(f)</enum><header>No increase in section 402 funding and an increase in section 405 funding</header><text>If the Secretary makes a determination under subsection (b) that there is an increase in section 405 funding for the current fiscal year over the prior fiscal year and that section 402 funding for the current fiscal year is less than the section 402 funding for the prior fiscal year, the Secretary shall proportionately reduce section 405 funding and increase section 402 funding for the current fiscal year in accordance with the following:</text><paragraph id="id38ad80d9d4f14ab3808ea355aabe38b3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>If the increase in section 405 funding for the current fiscal year over the prior fiscal year is not sufficient to bring section 402 funding for the current fiscal year up to the level of section 402 funding for the prior fiscal year, or exactly equal to the amount needed to bring section 402 funding for the current fiscal year up to the level of section 402 funding for the prior fiscal year, then the full amount by which section 405 funding was increased for the current fiscal year over the prior fiscal year shall be transferred by the Secretary to section 402 funding.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddda7e70aad3c4c0aa90e22422eb84037"><enum>(2)</enum><text>If the increase in section 405 funding for the current fiscal year over the prior fiscal year is more than sufficient to bring section 402 funding for the current fiscal year up to the level of section 402 funding for the prior fiscal year, the section 405 funding for the current fiscal year shall be proportionately reduced by an amount that, when added to section 402 funding for the current fiscal year, results in a percentage increase in section 402 funding for the current fiscal year over section 402 funding for the prior fiscal year that is 4 times the percentage increase in section 405 funding for the current fiscal year over section 405 funding for the prior fiscal year.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3cfc30df00244dc1a3f80373359ddeff"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Distribution of funds</header><text>After making an applicable funding adjustment under this section, the Secretary shall proceed to the distribution of section 402 funding and section 405 funding for the current fiscal year.</text></subsection><subsection id="id0c87fcf027704f719eef666f5243e405"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This section shall take effect on October 1, 2026.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

