<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2766BB8758444C56BA0EEB913868EBC3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3050 IH: Countering Hate Against Israel by Federal Contractors Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3050</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250428">April 28, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000478">Ms. Tenney</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S001196">Ms. Stefanik</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001214">Mr. Steube</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001118">Mr. Cline</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit Federal agencies from contracting with companies engaged in a boycott of Israel, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H14F3DCB44CAF43C2838ECBD73DBB7064" style="OLC"><section id="HDB1A9AB068B54AE5B7D47787EBBA489B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Countering Hate Against Israel by Federal Contractors Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H5F5A9B6F1B84460EADEABC18C699E130"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on Federal agencies contracting with companies engaged in a boycott of Israel</header><subsection id="H60C69062BCCB40AAB45558088C415524"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The head of a Federal agency—</text><paragraph id="HF00A4C73B90944728D5E465B53D20040"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may not enter into a covered contract with a company after January 1, 2026 unless such company certifies to such head at the time the contract is entered into that the company is not engaging in a boycott of Israel; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA042E8D0F3204C52864AC8FA50D9E74D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall include in any covered contract with a company entered into after January 1, 2026, a prohibition on the company engaging in a boycott of Israel during the term of the contract. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA25775E5F1BA4D739D10115089D6FDE3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Notices and Remedy</header><paragraph id="H5D43EC022C8D4810BCB63EE13BB44302" display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Written notice of prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The head of a Federal agency shall include in each solicitation for a bid or proposal for a covered contract written notice of the prohibition described under subsection (a). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC08BA437AC9D40E8A2F9FA9336F06DC9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notice upon finding of boycott</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the head of an Federal agency determines through a public report or a notice from Congress that a company violated the prohibition described under subsection (a)(2) with respect to a covered contract with the Federal agency, the head of the Federal agency shall—</text><subparagraph id="H300D3E10839A4AE8841E36C436CD5241"><enum>(A)</enum><text>notify the company of such determination; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H181BE868F7434A1BA44C1EE6CC86B26D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>make a notice of such determination available on the website of the agency. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEA8459E7D0AB4687A8E1091C6EC31FC8" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Termination of contract</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On the date that is 30 days after a company receives a notice under paragraph (2)(A), the head of a Federal agency shall terminate a covered contract entered into by the head of the Federal agency with a company for a violation of the prohibition described under subsection (a)(2) by the company, unless the company ends the boycott of Israel to the satisfaction of the head of the Federal agency before such date.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7170999EA06344DAB8900563867A3FFA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Appeal process</header><text>The appeals process established under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/41/71">chapter 71</external-xref> of title 41, United States Code, shall apply with respect to a contract subject to the provisions of this Act. </text></subsection><subsection id="H1663292739214839B2756487F3BB3720"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to—</text><paragraph id="H695762E721B34E418D97572F2A4B0694" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">infringe upon any right protected under the First Amendment to the Constitution; or </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H52A14B32AE3B4CD388B575A5C9F6F3AE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>take a position on final status issues associated with the Palestinian-Israeli conflict. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCAA68F9E81244E928EB3CAFAD88CFC6C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H2CAD80375F0448C68DAF4CE131EF068A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Company</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>company</term> means any organization, association, corporation, partnership, joint venture, limited partnership, limited liability partnership, limited liability company, or other entity or business association, including all wholly owned subsidiaries, majority-owned subsidiaries, parent companies, or affiliates of those entities or business associations (but not including an individual or sole proprietorship or individuals) with more than 10 employees.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H95F0A53E225E4181A84F37E0C547D1B5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered contract</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered contract</term> means a contract in excess of $100,000.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEF092318EF754F50A4BCB77C197D4F70"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Engaging in a Boycott of Israel</header><text>The term <term>engaging in a boycott of Israel</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H40831B9B416D4AF5B5643041A34A579B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>engaging in an action (including a refusal to deal or an action to terminate a business activity) that is intended to limit commercial relations with Israel, a person doing business in or with Israel, or authorized by, licensed by, or an entity organized under the laws of the State of Israel to do business, when such actions are taken in—</text><clause id="H59EB508C18404F60A8D28188A43B51E2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>compliance with or adherence to calls for a boycott of Israel; or </text></clause><clause id="H24A60E49DA994AF68DD0C5F56B27379B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a manner that is—</text><subclause id="H5376D50C522744E8BF21A089A6DB1390"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in any way discriminates on the basis of nationality, national origin, or religion; or</text></subclause><subclause id="HE4D308F66559430F85A26CF6A331690F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>not based on a valid business reason; and</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC5BBB2F2A502488FB088F84DE14A78CE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes a statement of the company that the company—</text><clause id="H529502C5E65C47379F27DA05E5F60A4A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is participating in an action described under subparagraph (A); or</text></clause><clause id="H2F02664E3A794FAB918439F02ACA1433"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has taken such action at the request with, in compliance with, or in furtherance of calls for such action.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H06B0034C64824D57B06ACBEFFDDB9944"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Federal Government entity</header><text>The term <term>Federal Government entity</term> means an instrumentality of the Government of the United States, or any political subdivision thereof, including all boards, commissions, agencies, institutions, authorities, corporations, and bodies politic of the Federal Government, established by or in accordance with Federal law or regulations. </text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

