<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-SIL25845-1L6-FM-CKC">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2723 IS: Treatment Court, Rehabilitation, and Recovery Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>II</distribution-code>
        <congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session>1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. 2723</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action>
            <action-date date="20250904">September 4, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S318">Mr. Wicker</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was
                read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on
                    the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title>To amend the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to modify
            the provisions relating to treatment courts.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause">
        <section section-type="section-one" id="S1">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Treatment Court, Rehabilitation, and Recovery Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section id="idA139201A06404BA3BF52A8CBF6B17FC2">
            <enum>2.</enum>
            <header>Treatment courts</header>
            <subsection id="idFC2BD00828E44C819A02FA9A8D22245A">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
 <text>Title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10101">34 U.S.C. 10101 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by striking part EE (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10611">34 U.S.C. 10611 et seq.</external-xref>) and inserting the following:</text>
                <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3E53116FBF244FEBB988A507F3CA3339">
                    <part id="idCE6D7C1F83C84780BD35BA1703AD3E90" style="OLC">
                        <enum>EE</enum>
                        <header>Treatment court discretionary grant program</header>
                        <section id="idE7EF7A2B8085446C85D453F1532E46EB">
                            <enum>2951.</enum>
                            <header>Grant authority</header>
                            <subsection id="id01DB371FAE8349F79CBE8466CFAE4BE3">
                                <enum>(a)</enum>
                                <header>In general</header>
 <text>The Attorney General may make grants—</text> <paragraph id="ida85c39ae69c947719a8e6e0a90b6cf2a"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>to States, State courts, local courts, units of local government, and Indian tribal governments, acting directly or through agreements with other public or private entities; and</text>
                                </paragraph>
                                <paragraph id="idDB55E8D3348D4388AFD0949FED5CD28C">
                                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>to establish or enhance—</text> <subparagraph id="idcec7050fa0264b578955b787f708d161"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>juvenile drug treatment courts that serve teens charged with delinquency offenses caused or influenced by a moderate to severe substance use disorder or co-occurring mental health disorder;</text>
                                    </subparagraph>
                                    <subparagraph id="idbc55d8b6f67f407a919ecdd3a5f8c7f5">
                                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>family treatment courts that serve parents or guardians in dependency proceedings facing allegations of child abuse or neglect caused or influenced by a moderate to severe substance use disorder;</text>
                                    </subparagraph>
                                    <subparagraph id="id1d950922dd944cc5989fefc7be07a9a5">
                                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>Tribal healing to wellness courts that serve Native Americans by providing healing and communal practices to serve persons charged with drug-or alcohol-related violations of tribal laws;</text>
                                    </subparagraph>
                                    <subparagraph id="idebcc9f9f252b4fa08bca36b212f8be31">
                                        <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>impaired driving courts that serve adults charged with repeated instances of driving under the influence of drugs or alcohol;</text>
                                    </subparagraph>
                                    <subparagraph id="id3f6bc9510c3d4d568e9eb847d5531bd6">
                                        <enum>(E)</enum>
 <text>adult drug treatment courts that serve as an alternative to incarceration for adults with substance use disorders, including co-occurring substance use and mental health disorders; and</text>
                                    </subparagraph>
                                    <subparagraph id="id756cd1f016194929949003706b4cddd6">
                                        <enum>(F)</enum>
 <text>any other treatment courts that adhere to national best practice standards endorsed by the National Association of Drug Court Professionals.</text>
                                    </subparagraph>
                                </paragraph>
                            </subsection>
                            <subsection id="id87e1ce48ffca4934a579350fe241f915">
                                <enum>(b)</enum>
                                <header>Limitation</header>
 <text>Economic sanctions imposed in this section shall not be at a level that would interfere with the treatment and must conform to constitutional standards including, but not limited to, an opportunity to present evidence at a hearing regarding the participant’s financial status and ability to pay.</text>
                            </subsection>
                        </section>
                        <section id="idce128515f8364e2da18b18a67a23b108">
                            <enum>2952.</enum>
                            <header>Eligibility</header>
                            <subsection id="idb8fcbb7cf5064b9786659eff7bb3e477">
                                <enum>(a)</enum>
                                <header>Definition</header>
 <text>In this section, the term <term>participant</term> means an adult or juvenile in the court system who—</text>
                                <paragraph id="id2a0be8d4c0bb4df5aacf6562046649fb">
                                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>has been diagnosed by a substance use treatment professional as having a substance use disorder or co-occurring mental illness and substance abuse disorders;</text>
                                </paragraph>
                                <paragraph id="id88962b20f0a94134a05230b6d03e6af4">
                                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                                    <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id5aaa5833794c46ecbde542235fe22fba">
                                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>meets established eligibility criteria as approved by the adult, juvenile, or tribal treatment court team, that, at a minimum, includes the judge, prosecutor, defense bar, and treatment community; and</text>
                                    </subparagraph>
                                    <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc9fa768d46414fb39e466f451d796999" indent="up1">
                                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for family treatment courts, at a minimum, includes the judge, child welfare agency or prosecutor, defensive bar, and treatment community;</text>
                                    </subparagraph>
                                </paragraph>
                                <paragraph id="ida0b078196ed843f8ba83fd97fe814f11">
                                    <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>has been determined, by the treatment court team, not to pose a risk of violence to any person in the program, or the public, if selected to participate in the program; and</text>
                                </paragraph>
                                <paragraph id="idf4714bf280f64003b4913ebe756329ff">
                                    <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>has not been charged with or convicted of—</text> <subparagraph id="ided3b362d1eb74e19a93b6d1dc5e8cf5a"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>any sex offense (as defined in section 111 of the Sex Offender Registration and Notification Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/20911">34 U.S.C. 20911</external-xref>)) or any offense relating to the sexual exploitation of children; or</text>
                                    </subparagraph>
                                    <subparagraph id="id8715a8cd6eb248bbab7f8430f936f9c2">
                                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>murder or assault with intent to commit murder.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="idd69e91e8c1f7458e83d2a47ca5d3d05d"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Determination</header> <text>In determining whether a participant meets the eligibility criteria, the treatment court team shall take into account—</text>
                                <paragraph id="idc31229866a014ff791a851817813c87c">
                                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>whether the participation of the participant in the program would pose a substantial risk of violence to the community;</text>
                                </paragraph>
                                <paragraph id="ide4ee20b257e441da93c7168b5fe323ba">
                                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>the criminal history of the participant and the nature and severity of the offense for which the participant is charged;</text>
                                </paragraph>
                                <paragraph id="id828f0d28c4444cc78a15a15b42e0bf46">
                                    <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>the views of any relevant victims to the offense;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="idaee6dccfbd3646b6b460928e8e212835"> <enum>(4)</enum> <text>the extent to which the participant would benefit from participation in the program; and</text>
                                </paragraph>
                                <paragraph id="idb64eeefb3879400b81e8465d77c65648">
                                    <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text>the extent to which the community would realize cost savings because of the participation of the participant in the program.</text>
                                </paragraph>
                            </subsection>
                        </section>
                        <section id="idA384A865B01D4C07942B17367EE47060">
                            <enum>2953.</enum>
                            <header>Administration</header>
                            <subsection id="id56C2B05F4BCE4B84B6C34C8CBCD44006">
                                <enum>(a)</enum>
                                <header>Definitions</header>
 <text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="id8a7b32c8a9854a7384dcf021cabcd551"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>Medication for addiction treatment</header> <text>The term <term>medication for addiction treatment</term> means the use of medications approved by the Food and Drug Administration for the treatment of substance use disorder.</text>
                                </paragraph>
                                <paragraph id="id6dc5727afec340c6ac9809a384a141ea">
                                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                                    <header>State substance abuse authority</header>
 <text>The term <term>State substance abuse authority</term> means the State agency responsible for administering the Substance Abuse Prevention and Treatment Block Grant under subpart II of part B of title XIX of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300x-21">42 U.S.C. 300x–21 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
                                </paragraph>
                            </subsection>
                            <subsection id="idcdd068363f8c49ea87dde4d36faf2aa9">
                                <enum>(b)</enum>
                                <header>Consultation</header>
 <text>The Attorney General shall consult with the Secretary of Health and Human Services and any other appropriate officials in carrying out this part.</text>
                            </subsection>
                            <subsection id="idca19d3a4d2b84bb881135839775552fa">
                                <enum>(c)</enum>
                                <header>Use of components</header>
 <text>The Attorney General may utilize any component or components of the Department of Justice in carrying out this part.</text>
                            </subsection>
                            <subsection id="id474b1dc7953d47bbb9b862e587ef9793">
                                <enum>(d)</enum>
                                <header>Regulatory authority</header>
 <text>The Attorney General may issue regulations and guidelines necessary to carry out this part.</text>
                            </subsection>
                            <subsection id="id547ddb974c38490d8bccebb0fc82e637">
                                <enum>(e)</enum>
                                <header>Administrative costs</header>
                                <paragraph id="id72b40f0cfeff4e9badad6e5cf7b603df">
                                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>Not more than 10 percent of a grant made under this part may be used for costs incurred to administer such grant.</text>
                                </paragraph>
                            </subsection>
                            <subsection id="id45ca362de9d54eb995d3ecbe05cd87de">
                                <enum>(f)</enum>
                                <header>Applications</header>
 <text>In addition to any other requirements that may be specified by the Attorney General, an application for a grant under this part shall—</text>
                                <paragraph id="idcd321f75cdbe4253a4ce6f1960405713">
                                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>explain the long-term strategy and detailed implementation plan that outlines how the program will—</text>
                                    <subparagraph id="id5f426a4ea75048fdbc354c3b883e65f0">
                                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>serve treatment courts described in 2951(a)(2);</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id16203c7a416d4949a1fa9c58786eb9d6"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>achieve the implementation of national best practice standards described in section 2951(a)(2)(F); and</text>
                                    </subparagraph>
                                    <subparagraph id="idF0233C18B4AF421FA4597A81A53DF370">
                                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>obtain the necessary support to continue the proposed program following the conclusion of Federal support;</text>
                                    </subparagraph>
                                </paragraph>
                                <paragraph id="id972DE82968BA4E30A1A82D0DA5E53A13">
                                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>certify that—</text> <subparagraph id="id4caf9876df0143448ddfd0aa4173a62c"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>the program will not discriminate based upon race, gender, gender identity, religion, national origin, sexual orientation, economic status, or immigration status;</text>
                                    </subparagraph>
                                    <subparagraph id="idc445f92cbd174ba8b49b71d2744b9a1d">
                                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>the program will provide adequate protections for offenders’ right to competent counsel;</text>
                                    </subparagraph>
                                    <subparagraph id="idfd28ed914c1345f2b6d81a009b28949b">
                                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>evidence-based clinical assessment will determine the level of care, and that evidence-based substance use disorder treatment, including medication for addiction treatment, will be available if clinically appropriate;</text>
                                    </subparagraph>
                                    <subparagraph id="ide81c70ee71d741b39d029ba5d0e8a267">
                                        <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>substance use disorder treatment providers and services are licensed or accredited by the State substance abuse authority and that State standards of care will be utilized;</text>
                                    </subparagraph>
                                    <subparagraph id="idd05dfd0acb044c47b2184b28039b26a1">
                                        <enum>(E)</enum>
 <text>there has been appropriate consultation with all affected agencies and that there will be appropriate coordination with all affected agencies, including State or local prosecutors, the defense bar, law enforcement, probation, courts, State or local treatment agencies, and other community services;</text>
                                    </subparagraph>
                                    <subparagraph id="id3477a03ed48d4d6f945a6e069270b9a7">
                                        <enum>(F)</enum>
 <text>1 or more designated judges are responsible for the program;</text>
                                    </subparagraph>
                                    <subparagraph id="id154be1c528c44fd987126bd7ece79c14">
                                        <enum>(G)</enum>
 <text>there is an inability to fund the program adequately without Federal assistance;</text>
                                    </subparagraph>
                                    <subparagraph id="id1755d49c2e9b41a4abdd601a35766d4d">
                                        <enum>(H)</enum>
 <text>Federal support provided will be used to supplement, and not supplant, State, Indian tribal, and local sources of funding that would otherwise be available;</text>
                                    </subparagraph>
                                    <subparagraph id="ide2be700b980f42cab323024bcdf6b5b1">
                                        <enum>(I)</enum>
 <text>the payment, in whole or part, by the participant of treatment costs and restitution, to the extent practicable, shall be based on ability to pay and will not be at a level that would interfere with program participation; and</text>
                                    </subparagraph>
                                    <subparagraph id="id6428bbabfbb84065be5de891471d89b0">
                                        <enum>(J)</enum>
 <text>impaired driving court applicants are compliant with section 164(b) of title 23, United States Code; and</text>
                                    </subparagraph>
                                </paragraph>
                                <paragraph id="idddf0412ed5c14609800101c3291d1952">
                                    <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>describe—</text> <subparagraph id="idd8afab4a030a43339a1fb6e8f26dc86f"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>the admission criteria to ensure that—</text>
                                        <clause id="ida11a808a6d6742f6ab1f70ad0fb40e7a">
                                            <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>the criteria are broad enough to provide equal access for all individuals under the treatment court’s jurisdiction who are in high need of substance use disorder treatment based on evidence-based clinical assessments;</text>
                                        </clause>
                                        <clause id="idee190bdd788040dbbe1bc49b83c4760d">
                                            <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>the individual circumstances of each offender are considered as mitigating or aggravating factors; and</text>
                                        </clause>
                                        <clause id="idfcb374b33e594403bf2541608934886a">
                                            <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>an evidence-based clinical assessment is utilized to determine the level of care;</text>
                                        </clause>
                                    </subparagraph>
                                    <subparagraph id="id78a51a474b7d4df7b8c7938adf60ba9d">
                                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>the components of the program to include—</text> <clause id="id4692740a2c8049c4bfa1572b3fc1257d"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>a process to ensure equivalent access and retention in the program that includes collecting and examining access and retention data to ensure unfair disparities do not exist;</text>
                                        </clause>
                                        <clause id="idb81c541141314057b7452901507e60f7">
                                            <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>substance use disorder or mental health treatment for each participant based on individualized assessments and evidence-based treatment services;</text>
                                        </clause>
                                        <clause id="id65d2a5e05784451882f7a4e68871974c">
                                            <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>case management, relapse prevention, education, vocational training, job placement, housing placement, medical and dental care, parenting programs, child care, or other family support services for each participant who requires such services;</text>
                                        </clause>
                                        <clause id="idFC53274806014C76BA7C15128800066A">
                                            <enum>(iv)</enum>
 <text>diversion, probation, or other supervised release;</text> </clause> <clause id="idD74DB8CCD9884364BD5BE7A3A17FA77C"> <enum>(v)</enum> <text>evidence-based graduated responses;</text>
                                        </clause>
                                        <clause id="idC4744A860F184609A58B4245496201CD">
                                            <enum>(vi)</enum>
 <text>periodic and random testing for the use of controlled substances or other addictive substances; and</text>
                                        </clause>
                                        <clause id="id29BCD00F66E8418996A93A6E7252C9C6">
                                            <enum>(vii)</enum>
 <text>the methodology that will be used to evaluate the program’s process and outcomes; and</text>
                                        </clause>
                                    </subparagraph>
                                    <subparagraph id="id06E88A2DFDC74FE0B221100377F9AF60">
                                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>the related governmental or community initiatives that complement the program.</text>
                                    </subparagraph>
                                </paragraph>
                            </subsection>
                        </section>
                        <section id="id0f89c1b6999d446eb24ba5036a81343b">
                            <enum>2954.</enum>
                            <header>Applications</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">To request funds under this part, the chief executive or the chief justice of a State, or the chief executive or judge of a unit of local government or Indian tribal government, or the chief judge of a State court, or the judge of a local court or Indian tribal court shall submit an application to the Attorney General in such form and containing such information as the Attorney General may reasonably require.</text>
                        </section>
                        <section id="id1bbe9851f4b94d31b69fcf21f23b95e2">
                            <enum>2955.</enum>
                            <header>Federal share</header>
                            <subsection id="id7159b96aacc7442689e10e4c4fccfced">
                                <enum>(a)</enum>
                                <header>In general</header>
 <text>The Federal share of a grant made under this part may not exceed 75 percent of the total costs of the program described in the application submitted under section 2954 for the fiscal year for which the program receives assistance under this part, unless the Attorney General waives, wholly or in part, the requirement of a matching contribution under this section.</text>
                            </subsection>
                            <subsection id="id88c845182caa4c3799c2bf5e90dd2b4e">
                                <enum>(b)</enum>
                                <header>In-Kind contributions</header>
 <text>In-kind contributions may constitute a portion of the non-Federal share of a grant.</text>
                            </subsection>
                        </section>
                        <section id="id2c5202e04bfa4c479fda63619a72c8e0">
                            <enum>2956.</enum>
                            <header>Distribution and allocation of funding</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Attorney General shall ensure—</text>
                            <paragraph id="id1fae7d659a314f09b4b9dddf6cddc9d9">
                                <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>all grants awards have in place a process to ensure equivalent access and retention in the program that includes—</text>
                                <subparagraph id="id960946d49a5a45ffb0d351532292b90a">
                                    <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>collecting and examining access and retention data to ensure unfair disparities do not exist;</text>
                                </subparagraph>
                                <subparagraph id="id6d36d9808a46431d84e0ce1f497dafc7">
                                    <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>modifying the eligibility criteria, admissions protocols, and other program elements to address disparities, enhance recruitment, and improve retention;</text>
                                </subparagraph>
                                <subparagraph id="id619cd9b7740d4c729bb9cb1fca8a9984">
                                    <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>continually monitoring whether racial and ethnic minority and female participants have equal access to the programs, receive equivalent services in the programs, and successfully complete the programs at rates equivalent to non-minorities and males; and</text>
                                </subparagraph>
                                <subparagraph id="id8212f46cc8674dac91fd6494fc8e20d9">
                                    <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>admission criteria that serve individuals with a high need of substance use disorder treatment based on clinical assessments;</text>
                                </subparagraph>
                            </paragraph>
                            <paragraph id="idca8eae9405184769bc97ad8de423d461">
                                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>all grant awards—</text> <subparagraph id="id7a6c40e04ff14f219e4134e9e1d044e4"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>use evidence-based clinical assessment to determine the level of care for evidence-based substance use disorder treatment, including medication for addiction treatment, if clinically appropriate and available; and</text>
                                </subparagraph>
                                <subparagraph id="id5652b883e87a4942b964ece9d54e37f3">
                                    <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>use substance use disorder treatment providers and services are licensed or accredited by the State substance abuse authority and that standards of care of the State are used;</text>
                                </subparagraph>
                            </paragraph>
                            <paragraph id="idD56AF97BEBCC45109833592F7BD5D8C3">
                                <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>priority in funding is given to those applicants that have demonstrated adherence to the practice standards established or endorsed by the National Association of Drug Court Professionals;</text>
                            </paragraph>
                            <paragraph id="idD373234D1FE2417FBD6340246BE5D942">
                                <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>all States, State courts, local courts, units of local government, and Indian tribal governments are provided with an opportunity to apply and be considered for a grant under this part;</text>
                            </paragraph>
                            <paragraph id="id7bdbf6886d0d4cb3b39141f7f2c54f32">
                                <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text>to the extent practicable, equitable geographic distribution of grant awards is made; and</text>
                            </paragraph>
                            <paragraph id="idC1E01D835BCB43578D42729106E1F670">
                                <enum>(6)</enum>
 <text>training and technical assistance is available to States that applied and did not receive a grant award.</text>
                            </paragraph>
                        </section>
                        <section id="id7f9d458f2ba64a02947f9249639a3079">
                            <enum>2957.</enum>
                            <header>Report</header>
                            <subsection id="idd0caf5d2d3b54ab6b9ad587652986425">
                                <enum>(a)</enum>
                                <header>Grant report</header>
 <text>A State, Indian tribal government, or unit of local government that receives funds under this part during a fiscal year shall submit to the Attorney General a description and an evaluation report on a date specified by the Attorney General regarding the effectiveness of this part.</text>
                            </subsection>
                            <subsection id="id61c70c972bec4c68845792928bd11bdf">
                                <enum>(b)</enum>
                                <header>Evaluation</header>
 <text>The Department of Justice, Bureau of Justice Assistance shall conduct a national multi-site evaluation on the effectiveness of treatment courts to be submitted to Congress within three years of enactment of this bill. The evaluation shall focus on target population, evidence-based substance use and mental health treatment, including medication for addiction treatment, recidivism, and program outcomes.</text>
                            </subsection>
                        </section>
                        <section id="id1b4fe0bb29a040f4a92a804d2cb73969">
                            <enum>2958.</enum>
                            <header>Technical assistance, training, and evaluation</header>
                            <subsection id="id9eb87ed40f524e18b1119e09b92a5f1f">
                                <enum>(a)</enum>
                                <header>Technical assistance and training</header>
 <text>The Attorney General may provide technical assistance and training in furtherance of the purposes of this part. All training and technical assistance must adhere to the national best practice standards established by the National Association of Drug Court Professionals or those approved by the Department of Justice.</text>
                            </subsection>
                            <subsection id="id1e55ae891c0b40ab95efede6cfa01759">
                                <enum>(b)</enum>
                                <header>Evaluations</header>
 <text>In addition to any evaluation requirements that may be prescribed for grantees (including uniform data collection standards and reporting requirements), the Attorney General shall carry out or make arrangements for evaluations of programs that receive support under this part.</text>
                            </subsection>
                            <subsection id="id931cec65abb14336af10c62b10288708">
                                <enum>(c)</enum>
                                <header>Administration</header>
 <text>The technical assistance, training, and evaluations authorized by this section may be carried out directly by the Attorney General, in collaboration with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, or through grants, contracts, or other cooperative arrangements with other entities.</text>
                            </subsection>
                            <subsection id="idaf9871b6876b47ea8eda20f42a679b98">
                                <enum>(d)</enum>
                                <header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
 <text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $100,000,0000 for each year for fiscal years 2024 through 2028.</text>
                            </subsection>
                        </section>
                    </part>
                    <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
                </quoted-block>
            </subsection>
        </section>
    </legis-body>
</bill>

