<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD62FEB3B50E449D4B326825D28D6D1D3" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 763 IH: Expressing support for the designation of September 2025 as National Campus Sexual Assault Awareness Month.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 763</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250923">September 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of September 2025 as National Campus Sexual Assault Awareness Month.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas freshmen and sophomores in college are at a greater risk of being sexually assaulted than juniors or seniors;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas college students are at a higher risk of sexual assault during the first few months of school, with more than 50 percent of college sexual assaults occurring in either August, September, October, or November;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas many college students are survivors of <quote>incapacitated assault</quote>, in which they are sexually assaulted while drugged, drunk, passed out, or otherwise incapacitated;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas these survivors often know their attackers;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas less than 12 percent of rapes and attempted rapes of college students are reported to campus authorities or local law enforcement;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas college sexual assault survivors are likely to tell someone they know, most often a friend, about their experience;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas 20 percent of college sexual assault survivors fear reprisal by the perpetrator;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas many college sexual assault survivors fear poor treatment by campus or law enforcement authorities, or even lack knowledge of the reporting process;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas 10 percent of colleges still do not allow confidential reporting of sexual assaults to campus authorities;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas 22 percent of colleges provide no sexual assault response training for members of their faculty and staff;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas 41 percent of colleges have not conducted a single sexual assault investigation in the last 5 years;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas most colleges fail to provide access to a specially trained Sexual Assault Nurse Examiner;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas law enforcement officials at 30 percent of colleges receive no training on how to respond to reports of sexual violence;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas more than 70 percent of colleges do not have protocols regarding how the institution and local law enforcement should work together to respond to sexual violence;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas 33 percent of colleges fail to provide training to dispel <quote>rape myths</quote> to persons adjudicating sexual assault claims;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas 43 percent of the Nation’s largest colleges have students assisting in adjudicating sexual assault cases, which creates privacy and conflict-of-interest concerns;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas 22 percent of colleges allow athletic department oversight of sexual violence cases involving student athletes;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas many college sexual assault survivors experience confusion over how to report a sexual assault, are unsure of acceptable standards of sexual conduct and definitions of rape and sexual assault, and fear punishment for activities preceding some sexual assaults, such as underage drinking;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas 21 percent of the Nation’s largest private colleges report not independently investigating all claims of sexual assault that they conveyed to the Department of Education;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas only 10 to 25 percent of the perpetrators of college sexual assaults are permanently expelled;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas less than 7 percent of reported college rape cases result in criminal charges against the perpetrator;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas survivors of campus sexual assaults are more likely to have their lives disrupted, such as by changing a college major, changing campus housing, and dropping a class, than the average student;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas 7 States require colleges to adopt affirmative consent policies; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas September 2025, when many students begin or return to college, is an appropriate month to designate as National Campus Sexual Assault Awareness Month: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HA89E5EFD1A254786A860722BECF0DA5F"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H8D98A7DB2F9542E48FB289DF5D166255"><text>That the House of Representatives supports the designation of National Campus Sexual Assault Awareness Month.</text></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

