<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MAZ25300-93S-4W-X8H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1584 IS: Transparency and Honesty in Energy Regulations Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1584</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250501">May 1, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S378">Mr. Lankford</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To prohibit Federal agencies from considering, in taking any action, the social cost of carbon, the social cost of methane, the social cost of nitrous oxide, or the social cost of any other greenhouse gas, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Transparency and Honesty in Energy Regulations Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id6b8c9dfdc21c494db720c1ba7bcbfc17"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="idc2935a4645e54c43bfb42a7fda784dcd"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Federal agency</header><text>The term <term>Federal agency</term> has the meaning given the term <term>agency</term> in section 551 of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id372249d779bf43b9989bdf140b8ed451"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Social cost of carbon</header><text>The term <term>social cost of carbon</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="id9b9d146ff11b4ed68a218889b54c74b6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the estimate of the social cost of carbon described in—</text><clause id="ideafac3eed78a4b4785efa169aa6337a6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the document of the Interagency Working Group on Social Cost of Carbon, United States Government, entitled <quote>Technical Support Document: Social Cost of Carbon for Regulatory Impact Analysis Under Executive Order 12866</quote> and dated February 2010;</text></clause><clause id="id5744191a73b647fb9834fd6dde48610c"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the document of the Interagency Working Group on Social Cost of Greenhouse Gases, United States Government, entitled <quote>Technical Support Document: Social Cost of Carbon, Methane, and Nitrous Oxide Interim Estimates under Executive Order 13990</quote> and dated February 2021;</text></clause><clause id="id1f2cad5d114941719c5c353ff29a35d0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the document of the Interagency Working Group on Social Cost of Greenhouse Gases, United States Government, entitled <quote>Technical Support Document: Technical Update of the Social Cost of Carbon for Regulatory Impact Analysis Under Executive Order 12866</quote>, dated May 2013, revised in November 2013 and July 2015, and published and revised in August 2016;</text></clause><clause id="id878bc2f19f6740548c8a787c152e0cfd"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the document of the Environmental Protection Agency entitled <quote>Regulatory Impact Analysis for the New Source Performance Standards for Greenhouse Gas Emissions from New, Modified, and Reconstructed Fossil Fuel-Fired Electric Generating Units; Emission Guidelines for Greenhouse Gas Emissions from Existing Fossil Fuel-Fired Electric Generating Units; and Repeal of the Affordable Clean Energy Rule</quote> and dated April 2024;</text></clause><clause id="idc7afc9f5e7774ebab640a36b7774fa0f"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the document of the Environmental Protection Agency entitled <quote>Regulatory Impact Analysis for the Final Federal Good Neighbor Plan Addressing Regional Ozone Transport for the 2015 Ozone National Ambient Air Quality Standard</quote> and dated March 2023;</text></clause><clause id="id437beba92bb24f4cad1cd9aab9113f2d"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the document of the Environmental Protection Agency entitled <quote>Regulatory Impact Analysis for the Final National Emission Standards for Hazardous Air Pollutants: Coal- and Oil-Fired Electric Utility Steam Generating Units Review of the Residual Risk and Technology Review</quote> and dated April 2024;</text></clause><clause id="id5ed2c714edea444984a6aa81823877e8"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>the document of the Environmental Protection Agency entitled <quote>Benefit and Cost Analysis for Supplemental Effluent Limitations Guidelines and Standards for the Steam Electric Power Generating Point Source Category</quote> and dated April 18, 2024; or</text></clause><clause id="id121b9cc3ee5449309e6fb86816db88f2"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>any successor or substantially related document; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idade6330b38634ebebfd0973bfb72fb9b"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other estimate of the monetized damages associated with an incremental increase in carbon dioxide emissions in a given year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idf7cce25641404eb3a984bc8a8f6a73c0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Social cost of greenhouse gases</header><text>The term <term>social cost of greenhouse gases</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="idb6fe37df0ed447b9a3b82505d5b4233b"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the estimate of the social cost of any greenhouse gas that is described in—</text><clause id="ide411eb5841764f4893fe27bc88b1fc2b"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the document of the Interagency Working Group on Social Cost of Carbon, United States Government, entitled <quote>Technical Support Document: Social Cost of Carbon for Regulatory Impact Analysis Under Executive Order 12866</quote> and dated February 2010;</text></clause><clause id="id6d7fd7f55e8e43f299954c2208974a07"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the document of the Interagency Working Group on Social Cost of Greenhouse Gases, United States Government, entitled <quote>Technical Support Document: Technical Update of the Social Cost of Carbon for Regulatory Impact Analysis Under Executive Order 12866</quote>, dated May 2013, revised in November 2013 and July 2015, and published and revised in August 2016;</text></clause><clause id="id1693d10b31d640749093946e88a736bb"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the document of the Interagency Working Group on Social Cost of Greenhouse Gases, United States Government, entitled <quote>Addendum to Technical Support Document on Social Cost of Carbon for Regulatory Impact Analysis under Executive Order 12866: Application of the Methodology to Estimate the Social Cost of Methane and the Social Cost of Nitrous Oxide</quote> and dated August 2016;</text></clause><clause id="id51063e15cbac40de8323128ef4675d14"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the document of the Interagency Working Group on Social Cost of Greenhouse Gases, United States Government, entitled <quote>Technical Support Document: Social Cost of Carbon, Methane, and Nitrous Oxide Interim Estimates under Executive Order 13990</quote> and dated February 2021; or</text></clause><clause id="id7d496a36f3ab4788b3e01f1bb9c86013"><enum>(v)</enum><text>any successor or substantially related document; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd072f15e9d494c639f6b206000387920"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other estimate of the monetized damages associated with an incremental increase in greenhouse gas emissions in a given year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idcbc87ab4299d40479262b37562d8a7f0"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Social cost of methane</header><text>The term <term>social cost of methane</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="ida75e77eccab64bc1bc7ed6a25951fcf4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the estimate of the social cost of methane described in—</text><clause id="id4cd92760aa2a4c9ab5bc30fdbce219cc"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the document of the Interagency Working Group on Social Cost of Greenhouse Gases, United States Government, entitled <quote>Addendum to Technical Support Document on Social Cost of Carbon for Regulatory Impact Analysis under Executive Order 12866: Application of the Methodology to Estimate the Social Cost of Methane and the Social Cost of Nitrous Oxide</quote> and dated August 2016;</text></clause><clause id="id189165414bef409695ee986e60399c53"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the document of the Interagency Working Group on Social Cost of Greenhouse Gases, United States Government, entitled <quote>Technical Support Document: Social Cost of Carbon, Methane, and Nitrous Oxide Interim Estimates under Executive Order 13990</quote> and dated February 2021;</text></clause><clause id="id520a0e82ad5d47d79cd3101ab932f28b"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the document of the Environmental Protection Agency entitled <quote>Benefit and Cost Analysis for Supplemental Effluent Limitations Guidelines and Standards for the Steam Electric Power Generating Point Source Category</quote> and dated April 18, 2024; or</text></clause><clause id="ide21e98d70dc14d28b46a9eac118d31a6"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>any successor or substantially related document; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id619b317ab46a4fa994ce4baba4f3fb9d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other estimate of the monetized damages associated with an incremental increase in methane emissions in a given year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id4ef7b26881f5459e9c515e4f297de055"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Social cost of nitrous oxide</header><text>The term <term>social cost of nitrous oxide</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="id4f23c10d499046feb52fcfa056937de5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the estimate of the social cost of nitrous oxide described in—</text><clause id="id2d30dcd8733549f49b3649cd011844ea"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the document of the Interagency Working Group on Social Cost of Carbon, United States Government, entitled <quote>Addendum to Technical Support Document on Social Cost of Carbon for Regulatory Impact Analysis under Executive Order 12866: Application of the Methodology to Estimate the Social Cost of Methane and the Social Cost of Nitrous Oxide</quote> and dated August 2016;</text></clause><clause id="idae82234fe7ad435299e90c1637ec9344"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the document of the Interagency Working Group on Social Cost of Carbon, United States Government, entitled <quote>Technical Support Document: Social Cost of Carbon, Methane, and Nitrous Oxide Interim Estimates under Executive Order 13990</quote> and dated February 2021; or</text></clause><clause id="id3f0bcafe5cd2410bb5d6d41e078159ae"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any other successor or substantially related document; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id38fc268a34a9431f9c8eec01f3058e1b"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other estimate of the monetized damages associated with an incremental increase in nitrous oxide emissions in a given year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="id9e734b5614c94819867ec2fdd7a7f0b0"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibition on considering the social cost of greenhouse gases, including the social cost of carbon, the social cost of methane, and the social cost of nitrous oxide</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The head of a Federal agency may not consider the social cost of carbon, the social cost of methane, the social cost of nitrous oxide, or the social cost of greenhouse gases—</text><paragraph id="id3ef659824f274ea7b6fdf283182ca044"><enum>(1)</enum><text>as part of any cost-benefit or cost-effectiveness analysis required under—</text><subparagraph id="idb851a88dba5c476ba3d862b277ed4149"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any law;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4b293dbb862a406ba82d4992fad367fc"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Executive Order 12866 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/601">5 U.S.C. 601</external-xref> note; relating to regulatory planning and review); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id209575046fa44e8494c1250a902e0d41"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Executive Order 13563 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/601">5 U.S.C. 601</external-xref> note; relating to improving regulation and regulatory review);</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="iddc3565d7d3cf47f1923ad33647c6f435"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in any rulemaking;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id26c2b25d05dd4dbf9712c857d7f005f0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in the issuance of any guidance;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id72dc460753884b1f9dea0b4419b40124"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in taking any other agency action; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd1bc728216724ae0bfb1107bc66ee579"><enum>(5)</enum><text>as a justification for any rulemaking, guidance document, or agency action.</text></paragraph></section><section id="id408cfcc5fd124d3b8999ea2902fb6419"><enum>4.</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the head of each Federal agency shall submit to the Committees on Environment and Public Works and Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate and the Committees on Energy and Commerce and Natural Resources of the House of Representatives a report describing the number of proposed and final rulemakings, guidance documents, and agency actions that, since January 2009, have used the social cost of carbon, the social cost of greenhouse gases, the social cost of methane, or the social cost of nitrous oxide, including the use of the social cost of carbon, the social cost of greenhouse gases, the social cost of methane, or the social cost of nitrous oxide as part of any cost-benefit analysis required under Executive Order 12866 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/601">5 U.S.C. 601</external-xref> note; relating to regulatory planning and review) or other relevant authority. </text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="id525a50bb631b4a858a60e98fca7992ad"><enum>5.</enum><header>Prioritizing accuracy in environmental analyses</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7c5345825e2d40409f4f41a227173d3a"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Limitation on permitting and regulation</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5746a69c3a184fdd8469f84ee688f061"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out any permitting adjudication or regulatory process—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id26a48dc5e22c4378883c4386d3d1cf06"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the head of each Federal agency shall, in taking into account any environmental considerations, only use such environmental considerations as are explicitly required under an Act of Congress; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb3804716c275428ab74ed934493b7fd9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the use of any environmental consideration not described in subparagraph (A) is prohibited.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3fa4006543bb498a806e01c3d6de8d04"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of robust methodologies</header><text>In carrying out paragraph (1), the head of a Federal agency, in the determination of the head of that Federal agency—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id07e8dc624da24553b90f41639dfe447c"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall strictly use the most robust methodology of assessment available; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5deb6d688b6b4f6083d9ff90a711c108"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall not use any methodology that is arbitrary or ideologically motivated.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idee18178458b24d31a734c05e81122a2a"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Regulatory analysis</header><text>The head of each Federal agency shall—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf540992ecb8d4659b1c239ef88694bd6"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure that any estimates to assess the value of changes in greenhouse gas emissions resulting from the actions of that Federal agency, including with respect to the consideration of domestic versus international effects and evaluating appropriate discount rates, are, to the extent permitted by law, consistent with the guidance contained in Office of Management and Budget Circular A–4, dated September 17, 2003; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb4b461844ae445799d2579e1d1ee81cc"><enum>(2)</enum><text>as appropriate and consistent with applicable law, initiate a process to make such changes to any rule, regulation, policy, or action of the Federal agency as may be necessary to ensure consistency with Office of Management and Budget Circular A–4, dated September 17, 2003.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

