<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H49B797FBBA7943B090A9D113E9EDEA4B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1930 IH: Border Workforce Improvement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1930</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250306">March 6, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000310">Ms. Johnson of Texas</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="C001055">Mr. Case</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000593">Mr. Levin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001211">Mr. Stanton</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require an assessement of CBP and ICE staffing at the southern border, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H417F0848A4D642AE8306710D79078349" style="OLC"><section id="HA444711798DC4DF6A8511973C14B3078" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Border Workforce Improvement Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H488C3700EB01447381A2AA8FA537D9B5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Assessment on DHS staffing needs at the southern border</header><subsection id="H66E2928579F4432DA45431E674256917"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security, in coordination with the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection (CBP), the Director of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE), and the Director of United States Citizenship and Immigration Services (USCIS), shall conduct an assessment of staffing needs at the southern border of the United States.</text></subsection><subsection id="H63651571D74F41D9912D4331990002EC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The assessment under subsection (a) shall include the following:</text><paragraph id="HCFB1FE0C05C646BBB620CC5893C2EEAA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Reviews of existing staffing models and methodologies for deploying personnel of CBP, ICE, and USCIS at the southern border and across the country, and the effect of continuously relying on details and overtime to temporarily fill staffing gaps.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H829E252B4A1A43FDA575002E81E2F31F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Factors within and outside of the control of the Department of Homeland Security that are affecting workloads and exacerbating staffing challenges to identify solutions CBP, ICE, and USCIS can accomplish, as well as solutions that require congressional action.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA0D695B293C749DBA7919BFB309BFF76"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An identification of critical capability gaps in human resources, new technology integration, and streamlined risk management systems across CBP, ICE, and USCIS.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBD1A0D0AA8F24D14899F66EE03E79B51"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date on which the assessment under subsection (a) is complete, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that includes the following:</text><paragraph id="H087BD1D6FC8748AC945952E8CB212AE8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The findings of such assessment.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBEA2CCAC952C45029FCECE2DDA4ADC8C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A description of how the Secretary, the Commissioner of CBP, the Director of ICE, and the Director of USCIS should implement the recommendations contained in such assessment.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDFC978B0803444809672D7DE2E87A21F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means—</text><paragraph id="HC47E4D15ACAB4BF5B8E52270A2B76353"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee of Homeland Security and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H36CE567BD00247DAAF486C7082277681"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee of Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

