<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="H1FC4076123AE4579A249EF79EA2164E0" resolution-type="house-resolution"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 799 IH: Recognizing President Donald J. Trump’s Role as a Transformational Peacemaker Whose Achievements in International Diplomacy Merit the Nobel Peace Prize.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 799</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251010">October 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000133">Mr. Van Drew</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001086">Mrs. Harshbarger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000622">Mr. Patronis</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S000168">Ms. Salazar</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing President Donald J. Trump’s Role as a Transformational Peacemaker Whose Achievements in International Diplomacy Merit the Nobel Peace Prize.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas President Donald J. Trump has demonstrated steadfast and exceptional dedication to the advancement of peace, security, and global stability;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas President Trump has consistently pursued a foreign policy of “peace through strength,” achieving diplomatic breakthroughs that have eluded career diplomats for decades;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas President Trump has been widely recognized as a leader committed to resolving long-standing international conflicts and advancing the cause of peace, particularly in the Middle East;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas nearly two years ago, on October 7, 2023, Hamas terrorists launched a brutal and unprovoked assault on the State of Israel, murdering approximately 1,200 innocent civilians in their homes, neighborhoods, and at a music festival, and abducting 251 individuals who were taken as hostages into Gaza;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the House of Representatives reaffirms its commitment to remembering the atrocities committed on that day—the deadliest for the Jewish people since the Holocaust;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas President Trump’s leadership led to the brokering of a historic peace agreement that marked the end to hostilities in the war initiated by Hamas, securing the release of hostages, disarming Hamas, and removing the terrorist group from power in Gaza;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas this peace agreement creates a historic opportunity to foster a more stable, secure, and prosperous future for Israelis, Palestinians, and the broader Middle East;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas President Trump’s peace plan has been accepted by Israel, our allies, and partners across the Middle East and the world;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas this diplomatic achievement was the result of tremendous leadership by President Trump, whose approach prioritizes American interests and global peace;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas President Trump’s leadership has also contributed to the resolution of numerous other international conflicts, including:</text><paragraph id="H4983A0BE18E24E6DA484E9D000F10954"><enum>(1)</enum><text> Azerbaijan and Armenia.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFC52FF9018E043CB89490C7486F8393D"><enum>(2)</enum><text> Cambodia and Thailand.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H353A9055BF2548BB8369A3DE2440105A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Israel and Iran.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA4F1D0A168864C099DCB58E153A19E60"><enum>(4)</enum><text> Rwanda and the Democratic Republic of the Congo.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCEC202992C994FF89753692FB29A2B16"><enum>(5)</enum><text> India and Pakistan.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H24654727ADF049A3BA06B02786971840"><enum>(6)</enum><text> Egypt and Ethiopia.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H200ABEA35DE9424DA354A37C446E4917"><enum>(7)</enum><text> Serbia and Kosovo.</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas global leaders, security experts, and elected officials have publicly recognized President Trump’s unique and historic role in furthering peace, including the following notable remarks:</text><paragraph id="HA7B9678845DC4EF782A98E466D4DA900"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu: “Few leaders have achieved such tangible breakthroughs to peace in such a short time. In these times of great historic change, I can think of no one more deserving than President Trump of the Nobel Peace Prize.”</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFEC59B0C0BB84857A796294C798C019A"><enum>(2)</enum><text> NATO Secretary General Mark Rutte: “Without President Trump, this deadlock with Putin would not have been broken. He is the only one who could do this.”</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2419239571A649FD9E531863AEB89001"><enum>(3)</enum><text>General Jack Keane (ret.): “[This] is the undisputed global leader sitting down with the prominent leaders in Europe and President Zelensky to discuss a pathway forward for peace—and it is stunning.”</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9C999A9C0BBB4799B7A4BC0FE4A4D9EF"><enum>(4)</enum><text> Former U.S. Ambassadors, senior officials, military leaders, and public commentators have also consistently credited President Trump with forging meaningful diplomatic solutions and restoring American leadership in the world.</text></paragraph></whereas></preamble><resolution-body id="H341672FD93A4419CA43E11E53826DEA0" style="traditional"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H60B36B63616B4FAA8EE4D24B1604F238" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum/><text>That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="HE26F239945344AFD9433382B71015C65"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognizes President Donald J. Trump’s exceptional and unwavering dedication to the pursuit of global peace, security, and diplomacy; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF04910EA9A684A3C9FDCB71458BEF90E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>urges the Norwegian Nobel Committee to award President Donald J. Trump the Nobel Peace Prize, in recognition of his historic achievements in securing peace, ending violent conflicts, and promoting global stability.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

