<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HBEFD7F909F5142A7AD609EF6E7129ADE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2278 IH: Survivor Benefits Delivery Improvement Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2278</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250321">March 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to improve equitable access to certain benefits under the laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs and to improve certain outreach to individuals who served uniformed services and dependents of such individuals, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA1A360FE49E54F20904F1E777E631C9B" style="OLC"><section id="HC8EA9EAED948419680A8200890F14210" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Survivor Benefits Delivery Improvement Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HED6C48E7809C4EA98FA5643F3671B641"><enum>2.</enum><header>Equitable access to certain benefits of Department of Veterans Affairs for survivors of veterans</header><subsection id="HDE42F808C0B844E1AFE4A38179C33E23"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section may be cited as the <quote>Survivor Benefits Data Collection Act of 2025</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H31C1A7555EA645C5B26C106C2FFAD070"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Collection of demographic data</header><paragraph id="HE6DB72EFCBA141A89442161D824D450A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Collection</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/53">Chapter 53</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new section (and conforming the table of sections at the beginning of such chapter accordingly):</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H7EBFBFD6BBDD4B53A3ED530160CCDB57" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="H7683B74844B745118BCF826CC130D22D"><enum>5322.</enum><header>Demographic data of certain beneficiaries</header><subsection id="H13C26F96404A4159A3C48EDCCE8DCEF6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Collection</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in consultation with the entities described in subsection (b), shall—</text><paragraph id="H46A48295A6BC4C8682C636639EBA4218"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop a method to collect the demographic data of—</text><subparagraph id="H3DA850E12DE440259BFDABC1E45BC227"><enum>(A)</enum><text>each covered survivor receiving disability and indemnity compensation under chapter 13 of this title, pension under chapter 15 of this title, or increased pension (or additional compensation or allowances) under this title based on the need of regular aid and attendance or by reason of being permanently housebound; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H99F82486D400494AB3BDC2CCE898ED77"><enum>(B)</enum><text>each person who receives burial benefits under chapter 23 of this title; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBD358A97169E4B9491F477A260C9D48C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">collect demographic data pursuant to the method developed under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAA7F862628DB426A90C43FD58DD739F9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Entities for consultation</header><text>The entities described in this subsection are the following:</text><paragraph id="H1A3EE42D46BF4AB8BC02DB6A189BDCF2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Advisory Committee on Minority Veterans established under section 544 of this title.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8A5CFB78DA564E1BBF708A3D2FF07337"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Advisory Committee on Women Veterans established under section 542 of this title.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC540C65D7DAE45A9A460641EC044E80B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Veterans’ Family, Caregiver, and Survivor Advisory Committee of the Department of Veterans Affairs, or successor advisory committee.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2ED72171E26C411F984B573C286584B1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Veterans service organizations.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF77C73445A3F49248FA6978FD7491F76"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Designation of underserved demographics</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="H23D81042F14E4B799A67813C4F270C56"><enum>(1)</enum><text>designate as an underserved demographic any demographic the Secretary determines, taking into account the demographic data collected under subsection (a), is underserved with respect to the benefits specified in such subsection; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE389E1E2EF2B4200A4F52F017CB53C9B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>review such designations on at least a biennial basis and update as appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H16C1E01241BE41D793C669CF9E9864A9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Inclusion in annual reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For each annual benefits report of the Veterans Benefits Administration, the Secretary shall include as part of the report information concerning the demographic data collected under subsection (a) during the fiscal year covered by the report.</text></subsection><subsection id="H6CEF125310E04A8985B1BB5A5F126A44"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effect on application</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed as requiring any person to submit demographic data or as authorizing the Secretary to consider whether a person submits demographic data in evaluating any claim for benefits under the laws administered by the Secretary.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC90C6048E1614943A083EB7C258086EB"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H80A9F0B57D534503ACC761A4D66A5D34" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>covered survivor</term> means a surviving spouse, child, or parent of a veteran. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H93E7A7975212462CBBE354F87416B103"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>demographic data</term> includes, with respect to an individual, the following:</text><subparagraph id="H572A894A609A4195A04523E8B6565877"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Race.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H44E3CF1816734286A66A56E3BEB6B9BB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Ethnicity.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H62A6ED164FC740DA88431B8F01D32646"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Tribal affiliation, if any. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H12BC675D450B4B79BEE841E32DCC6B6A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>LGBTQIA+ status.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9A8CB929F07E4634B771A76EFAB48726"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Geographic location.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDD6760D20E5344E9BDCA0A5C17FFFB15"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <term>veterans service organization</term> means any organization recognized by the Secretary under section 5902 of this title.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H4ADC65EAA0DF4227B069D691A4BE5338"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Deadlines; applicability</header><subparagraph id="HADC73DF3542D425FA257B681C35E5791"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Deadline for collection</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall develop the data collection method under subsection (a) of section 5322 of title 38, United States Code (as added by paragraph (1)), and commence the collection of data pursuant to such method, by not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H912B6106BC8742349100E9A836C17234"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Deadline for initial designations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall make the initial designation of any underserved demographics under subsection (c) of such section 5322 by not later than one year after the date on which the Secretary commences the collection of data under subsection (a) of such section.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H462E9D7F7BA34C16B5B90E6DDD6E9110"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Applicability regarding annual reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The requirement under subsection (d) of such section 5322 shall apply with respect to annual benefits reports of the Veterans Benefits Administration submitted on or after the date that is one year after the date on which the Secretary commences the collection of data under subsection (a) of such section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H73A9C25AE4AD4A7893CE7B255E78DAE7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Outreach and education</header><paragraph id="HBD1B9E842887458BAE65B90CFB7FCF43"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Strategy for underserved demographics</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of initial designation, the Secretary shall develop and submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and House of Representatives an outreach and education strategy for raising awareness regarding the benefits specified in section 5322(a) of title 38, United States Code (as added by subsection (b)), among covered survivors who belong to an underserved demographic. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC5928DAD112E4F5B80E882EC50FB5807"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligibility of veterans for certain burial benefits</header><subparagraph id="H63AC02A70DF840C1B04846115DDC66F8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Outreach plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of initial designation, the Under Secretary for Memorial Affairs shall develop and submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Senate an outreach strategy for raising awareness regarding eligibility for burial in a national cemetery under section 2303 of title 38, United States Code, among veterans and beneficiaries who belong to an underserved demographic.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0E3CB4CE0E634497A7F358C053DB1A62"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Education activities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Under Secretary shall carry out education activities pursuant to the plan developed under subparagraph (A) to ensure that the veterans and beneficiaries specified in such paragraph are made aware of any eligibility specified in such subparagraph.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFE7C6616F0C04FF28CB0CD7E83E43B26"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of initial designation, and annually thereafter for five years, the Under Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Senate a report on the efforts taken by the Under Secretary pursuant to this paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFE2CDC2F5645469F8E1F4EEE8D21DD97"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection:</text><subparagraph id="H62ED35BBE8564FD5952665570BA6C1B6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The term <term>covered survivor</term> has the meanings given that term in section 5322(e) of title 38, United States Code (as added by subsection (b)).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB417CFADD2114270AA9A30054D5DF825"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>date of initial designation</term> means the date on which the Secretary makes the initial designation of any underserved demographics.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAE5158012E4343B0A699649FFFDFF928" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>underserved demographic</term> means a demographic designated as an underserved demographic by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs under section 5322(c) of title 38, United States Code (as added by subsection (b)).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCFC5009C7D9447EBA87B0337D2E10815"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Assessment and strategy for Office of Survivors Assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="HF1C2CA9CD35C4C7BAC35349581E869BE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct an assessment of the resources of the Office of Survivors Assistance of the Department of Veterans Affairs, or any successor office; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCC1555A1148749D8A5FDFED1E657FE96"><enum>(2)</enum><text>develop a strategy to ensure the availability of resources necessary for the function of such office, as determined by the Secretary as a result of the assessment.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H3859F67408B744ED9B38484F5B43804B" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Improvements to outreach services provided by Secretary of Veterans Affairs to individuals who served in the uniformed services and dependents of such individuals</header><subsection id="HA8B5DC35B8AB44F588ACFFF9A0391DE9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Survivor Solid Start Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H7FC092EB2F934B69946458A492307D00"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Expansion of outreach services</header><text>Subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/63">chapter 63</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="HE7F7806E70F94AE5A093D01E5CE0164C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 6301(b)—</text><subparagraph id="HF0F454C5B9C34B9D81755B9D3013A21A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (1) through (3) as paragraphs (2) through (4), respectively;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA3FF4A13004C4155914A1C797F711FDD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting before paragraph (2) (as so redesignated) the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H0B7933A7AD0647318DD009877F393F87" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H81BBCF914A894B0388EA6CE2E649CEF9"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <quote>covered individual</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="HFCB781080C7C4A1DA1A0858FC072134B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a veteran; or </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H93B797D67A3C4706BAC4FB0B5AC6E951"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an individual who served in the uniformed services (as defined in section 1965(6) of this title);</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEF4418A96F1A4AECAB3961D038917F69" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (2) (as so redesignated), by striking <quote>veterans</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>covered individuals</quote>; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5E20CFD6C56E46A98D0D6A7C37C3486B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in paragraph (4) (as so redesignated), by striking <quote>a person who served in the active military, naval, air, or space service</quote> and inserting <quote>a covered individual</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H887FA5B68C8B42DBAC50DE423E881765"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 6302(b), by striking <quote>eligible veterans</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>covered individuals</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H952DBD5C7181415591A4B07C238B1BA5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in section 6303—</text><subparagraph id="HEAD60B1B8130475A8C466A9105E35F8C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>eligible veterans</quote> and inserting <quote>covered individuals</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD66EA46DB2E84CC2888E9691699C9B6F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (c)(1)(A), by striking <quote>eligible veterans</quote> and inserting <quote>covered individuals</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H63353BEF41D84630A6985411A8E05477"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subsection (c)(2), by striking <quote>veteran or dependent</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>covered individual or eligible dependent</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD80369C082EE4CA69051F554878E039B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in subsection (d), by striking <quote>veterans</quote> and inserting <quote>covered individuals</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H80DA2E4C415C4B35955CE851DEFC9A9A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in section 6306—</text><subparagraph id="HB7C3C1AA0ECB4A7190966BC6E902F0EE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>eligible veteran</quote> and inserting <quote>covered individual</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE00B2FA8060A4201A71F0F996FD45586"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text><clause id="HA220D00E72A74ED3901EF0806527B145"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>opportunities for veterans</quote> and inserting <quote>opportunities for covered individuals</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="H93FBD34AB1B243E5A75CBBC1C087DF5A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>eligible veterans</quote> and inserting <quote>covered individuals</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBF990E51D96042D298D1ADCDD7A71C3C"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 6308, by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="HFA29A1EAE9BD477E9FAFDAC3AABF0839" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H4A34FCF8B3924A65AF825E89184751E1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Outreach services for surviving eligible dependents</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HD7A6D44677C14247AC3B8914D19C97F6"><enum>(1)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H129FD8C0002542B6B6EB21F2E4F2A8A8"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon receipt of notification of the death of a covered individual, the Secretary, acting through the Under Secretary for Benefits, shall provide outreach services, by mail, email, and telephone, to each eligible dependent of such individual not less than once each quarter calendar year until the eligible dependent files a claim for a benefit under laws administered by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H11D37B6C1FE24141AE656D7B272AE029" indent="up2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>In the case of an eligible dependent described in subparagraph (A) who is a minor child, the Secretary shall provide such outreach services to the legal guardian of the eligible dependent.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0E649D847BFC47AF99B09B2961B378DD" indent="up2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>If the Secretary does not have the contact information of an eligible dependent or legal guardian described in subparagraph (A) or (B), the Secretary shall make reasonable efforts to obtain such contact information to carry out this subsection.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1C93FB57A4FD4021A2BEC1B18C312CF4" indent="up2"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible dependent or legal guardian described in subparagraph (A) or (B) may elect to not receive, or to receive fewer, outreach services under this subsection. Not less than once each calendar year, the Secretary shall notify each such eligible dependent or legal guardian of the option to make such an election.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEAA904B4E5D24C43B1E41DB82E3FF92C" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Outreach services under this subsection shall provide an eligible dependent with information including the following:</text><subparagraph id="H7335FE364D9E47F788152FC46BD1A613"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Contact information for the Office of Survivors Assistance established under section 321 of this title.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF7EF5173DD594C0E8ECB0F6FD9F8D9B6"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Information regarding assistance in filing a claim for a benefit under laws administered by the Secretary furnished by—</text><clause id="HB9718E51255741F783556BF623D5EC7A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a veterans service organization recognized under section 5902 of this title; or</text></clause><clause id="H15ECEDA59F1244F6B2E2E4EB432ABE1A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an attorney, agent, or other entity recognized under section 5904 of this title.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7B353CE52A4442979C6CEAC245553286"><enum>(C)</enum><text>How to find an entity—</text><clause id="HF371A3DDC85F4595804FC5FA9E3EAEF2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>described in clause (i) or (ii) of subparagraph (B); and</text></clause><clause id="H084BE79D013649C3AFEBA776F7CEDBA0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>located near the residence of the eligible dependent.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6F8A53DAE2DD4CFAA606DECAA0059EE9" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In developing and revising materials used in outreach services under this subsection, the Secretary shall consult with entities including the following:</text><subparagraph id="H86EDCFF235754FB29D66FC735D142E73"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Veterans service organizations recognized under section 5902 of this title.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA5A7786A3408403E97C90DC01D8B3429"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Advisory Committee on Women Veterans established under section 542 of this title.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H16209DBEB70944D9A2267E66DEA9A4C7"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Advisory Committee on Minority Veterans established under section 544 of this title.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H72C447546F904427B2E37444BD437223"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Veterans’ Family, Caregiver, and Survivor Advisory Committee of the Department, or successor advisory committee.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8E4644CAB411483D8FF962391B4FE465" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Personnel</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall establish at least 5, but not more than 10, full-time equivalent positions at call centers of the Department of Veterans Affairs to carry out subsection (c) of section 6308 of such title, as added by subsection (b).</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

