<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H655A6DA0E1A145FE942CBEEF27193F2E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2360 IH: To permanently extend the exemption from the engine compartment portion of the pre-trip vehicle inspection skills testing requirement for school bus drivers, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2360</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250326">March 26, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001051">Mr. Carter of Texas</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001053">Mr. Cole</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001195">Mr. Smith of Missouri</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000450">Ms. Foxx</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000129">Mr. Valadao</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000026">Mr. Nehls</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001224">Mr. Self</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To permanently extend the exemption from the engine compartment portion of the pre-trip vehicle inspection skills testing requirement for school bus drivers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB86CD028B6D84CC0A021C15E32EB55A1" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H76E1418D1CFB48B891210ECC2A8EC4EA"><enum>1.</enum><header>Permanent extension of exemption from under-the-hood inspection testing requirement for school bus drivers</header> 
<subsection id="HB7BCEBFEC0014129B4F0463497E4BCB6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Transportation shall make permanent the exemption relating to pre-trip vehicle inspection skills test requirements for certain school bus drivers, as published in the Federal Register on December 2, 2024 (89 Fed. Reg. 95348), including the terms and conditions of the exemption described in paragraphs 2., 3., 4., 5., and 6. of section VII. B. of the notice granting the exemption (89 Fed. Reg. 95351).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H99C93891B57341BEBC5A7DF837F3A14B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text>For the 6-year period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Transportation shall require any State that participates in the exemption described in subsection (a) to submit to the Secretary an annual report for each those 6 years describing the number of drivers that obtain a commercial drivers’ license under such exemption.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

