<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2378411BD000491A84311EBBE21F7E24" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 763 IH: James J. Andrews and William H. Campbell Congressional Gold Medal Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 763</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250128">January 28, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000459">Mr. Fleischmann</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">House Administration</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To posthumously award the Congressional Gold Medal, collectively, to James J. Andrews and William H. Campbell in recognition of their extraordinary bravery and steadfast devotion to the Nation during the Civil War as the only civilian members of Andrews&#8217; Raiders, who launched a daring military raid that became known as the <quote>Great Locomotive Chase</quote>.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6CE188EE51FE4F2AAE86D7C4EB82B96C" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HD726F9E0938F4CE8BF5F3AA0F854296E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>SHORT TITLE</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>James J. Andrews and William H. Campbell Congressional Gold Medal Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H015A759EA735400FA377C4BE0D90C382"><enum>2.</enum><header>FINDINGS</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
<paragraph id="H741DBE6D0B734CA8A60728718A594C85"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">James J. Andrews was born in Holiday’s Cove, Virginia (now Weirton, West Virginia), in 1829. He eventually moved to Kentucky. During the Civil War, Andrews served as a civilian spy for the Union Army and was the leader and organizer of Andrews’ Raiders.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7FB20CAEC63E43D7BDC5A62AE2465EB6"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">William Hunter Campbell, born in Carroll County, Ohio, on September 9, 1839, was a unique addition to the raid. In 1862, he was visiting friends with the 2d Ohio Infantry in Kentucky when he was unexpectedly recruited for a daring mission.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1E11FF0D7F124DC28468C32EBDD57836"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On March 25, 1862, James J. Andrews developed a plan to cut off the Western and Atlantic Rail Line supply line from Marietta, Georgia, to Chattanooga, Tennessee, to allow the Union Army to attack and occupy the city. Andrews presented the plan to General Buell and General O.M. Mitchell, commanding the Union Army in North Alabama. The plan was accepted, and Andrews gathered 22 Union soldiers from 3 Ohio Regiments (2d Ohio Infantry, 21st Ohio Infantry, 33d Ohio Infantry). The plan was to work from northern Alabama in small groups, dressed in civilian clothes, and reach Marietta, Georgia, to gather and steal a train. They were to run the train toward Chattanooga, cut the telegraph lines, tear up railroad tracks, and, if possible, burn the bridges. This would cut off all troop movement and supplies from getting to Chattanooga. The capture of Chattanooga early in the war would cut off essential supplies and food from getting up to Virginia and the Confederate Army there.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCD242E6EFD11414FB3A81D5BD568FF13"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On April 12, 1862, 24 volunteers from the Union Army, led by civilian scout James J. Andrews, commandeered a Confederate locomotive named the <quote>General</quote> outside of Big Shanty, Georgia (now Kennesaw), and took it northward toward Chattanooga, Tennessee, doing as much damage as possible to the vital Western and Atlantic Railroad line as they went. Out of fuel, Andrews and his men abandoned the locomotive and scattered into the woods before being captured by Confederate troops.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE903B0E9FC42464CB0A5E52DB86224A8"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">All captured were put on trial and convicted for acts of <quote>unlawful belligerency</quote> or being unlawful combatants and spies. Shortly after that, Andrews and 7 of the Raiders were executed by hanging, with the remaining held as prisoners-of-war. Andrews’ body was taken down from the scaffold and buried. On October 16, 1887, his remains were recovered and taken to their final resting place at Chattanooga National Cemetery.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H73E46DEF285640D3B957FDEFCC65FB5E"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">William H. Campbell was hung with 6 of the military men on June 18, 1862. In April 1866, these men were relocated and interred in Chattanooga National Cemetery.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H966F53D9C6794EFCBC87930481B379FF"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On March 25, 1863, 6 members of Andrews’ Raiders were awarded the first Medals of Honor in our Nation’s history. Ultimately, 21 of the 24 members of Andrews’ Raiders would receive the Medal of Honor for their actions on that day. On July 3rd, 2024, President Biden awarded the most recent Medals of Honor to members of Andrews’ Raiders, stating <quote>Their heroic deeds went unacknowledged for over a century, but time did not erase their valor</quote>. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA35A0EB9AE15467997AE6370034943E1"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Chattanooga, Tennessee, is recognized as the birthplace of the Medal of Honor.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC63A469835C94A53B575491D306C0B2B"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In 1956, Walt Disney made a movie about Andrews’ Raiders’ exploits called <quote>The Great Locomotive Chase</quote>, starring Fess Parker as Andrews. Buster Keaton's 1927 feature-length comedy masterpiece <quote>The General</quote> was loosely based on the incident.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4DAFACC15FE84B529CFF3A6B6EA8A369"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Today, the hijacked locomotive, <quote>General</quote>, is on display at The Southern Museum in Kennesaw, Georgia. <quote>Texas</quote>, the locomotive used to give chase, is on display at the Atlanta History Center in Atlanta, Georgia.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HDC314DCCCFC34D69B92A833DF1CA5234"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The civilians of the Andrews’ Raiders, James J. Andrews and William Hunter Campbell, acted with extraordinary bravery and unwavering devotion to their Nation as they attempted to turn the tide of the Civil War. </text></paragraph></section> <section id="H45428DEB74DF43A78B82E2A44D7D68C3"><enum>3.</enum><header>CONGRESSIONAL GOLD MEDAL</header> <subsection id="HED67BB601A144BBF8FFBADFCA2FF48AF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Presentation Authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President pro tempore of the Senate shall make appropriate arrangements for the presentation, on behalf of Congress, of a single gold medal of appropriate design collectively in commemoration of James J. Andrews and William H. Campbell, in recognition of their extraordinary bravery and steadfast devotion to the Nation during the Civil War as the only civilian members of Andrews’ Raiders, who launched a daring military raid that became known as the <quote>Great Locomotive Chase</quote>. </text></subsection>
<subsection id="H404D3BBE9DB843E0A0BC75BF1E64062A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Design and Striking</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purposes of the presentation referred to in subsection (a), the Secretary of the Treasury (referred to in this Act as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall strike a gold medal with suitable emblems, devices, and inscriptions to be determined by the Secretary.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H9BC9BE1F10B14BADB386631418F11125"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Smithsonian Institution</header> <paragraph id="HF0C365A755594CB391A5A9B49396AE89"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Following the award of the gold medal under subsection (a), the gold medal shall be given to the Smithsonian Institution, where it shall be available for display as appropriate and made available for research.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H3BD47D217B7C45738BA36F94212561FE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that the Smithsonian Institution shall make the gold medal received under paragraph (1) available for—</text> <subparagraph id="H9EE41E3692A84DF389380F7D032DFCE3"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">display, particularly at the Charles H. Coolidge National Medal of Honor Museum; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H6DA78056FD974382958BFEFB84D598E0"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">loan, as appropriate, so that the medal may be displayed elsewhere.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HF23EBD44FBD541029AC2F7F73D76B834"><enum>4.</enum><header>DUPLICATE MEDALS</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary may strike and sell duplicates in bronze of the gold medal struck pursuant to section 3, at a price sufficient to cover the cost thereof, including labor, materials, dies, use of machinery, and overhead expenses.</text></section>
<section id="H5602C0D411184F06B5D3150C2F8ECE70"><enum>5.</enum><header>STATUS OF MEDALS</header>
<subsection id="H2E247A521C2D491BAA879F92C8F52CDB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>National Medals</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Medals struck under this Act are national medals for purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/51">chapter 51</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HAC3ADBD22FCE44E2A2CEE034CF9A4557"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Numismatic Items</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of sections 5134 and 5136 of title 31, United States Code, all medals struck under this Act shall be considered to be numismatic items.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="HF0979F0B012F41FB9F086587F2574B28"><enum>6.</enum><header>AUTHORITY TO USE FUND AMOUNTS; PROCEEDS OF SALE</header>
<subsection id="H695B66B9AF6A4EC49BEDE5EEA9094BC6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority To Use Fund Amounts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be charged against the United States Mint Public Enterprise Fund such amounts as may be necessary to pay for the costs of the medals struck under this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HC64EE536A9B94238AFA62003B10FA536"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Proceeds of Sale</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts received from the sale of duplicate bronze medals authorized under section 4 shall be deposited into the United States Mint Public Enterprise Fund.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

