<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-FLO25366-YSH-MS-RJM"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1279 IS: To redesignate the Hulls Cove Visitor Center at Acadia National Park as the George J. Mitchell Visitor Center.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1279</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250403">April 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S363">Mr. King</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S252">Ms. Collins</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To redesignate the Hulls Cove Visitor Center at Acadia National Park as the George J. Mitchell Visitor Center.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="id3f5dd1e92848416e9e745f7cd4023c7f"><enum>1.</enum><header>Redesignation of the Hulls Cove Visitor Center at Acadia National Park as the George J. Mitchell Visitor Center</header><subsection id="id6b416b5341b44693a44d576e0ecde9bf"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Redesignation</header><text>The Hulls Cove Visitor Center at Acadia National Park located in Bar Harbor, Maine, or any successor to that visitor center that is constructed after the date of enactment of this Act and serves as the primary visitor center for Acadia National Park, shall be known and designated as the <quote>George J. Mitchell Visitor Center</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="ida2df4247267c404796ca8db6d511f18e"><enum>(b)</enum><header>References</header><text>Any reference in a law, map, regulation, document, paper, or other record of the United States to the visitor center referred to in subsection (a) shall be deemed to be a reference to the <quote>George J. Mitchell Visitor Center</quote>. </text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

