<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB6EBC1EF3E714D45BA9FDCB2F4256B8B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3369 IH: Wild Olympics Wilderness and Wild and Scenic Rivers Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3369</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20250513">May 13, 2025</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000621">Ms. Randall</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To designate and expand wilderness areas in Olympic National Forest in the State of Washington, and to designate certain rivers in Olympic National Forest and Olympic National Park as wild and scenic rivers, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H7944C6BB10724DC8A157C4B64C869583" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H1D3B305246714208996AF1807197A240"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Wild Olympics Wilderness and Wild and Scenic Rivers Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H31C0A9DB9F1049E78514ADAD6BF6F4A6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Designation of Olympic National Forest wilderness areas</header> <subsection id="H014126F8106340579E2BE9E6A7863EE9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In furtherance of the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.</external-xref>), the following Federal land in the Olympic National Forest in the State of Washington, comprising approximately 126,554 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Proposed Wild Olympics Wilderness and Wild and Scenic Rivers Act</quote> and dated April 8, 2019 (referred to in this section as the <quote>map</quote>), is designated as wilderness and as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System:</text> 
<paragraph id="H3CCDD573846E47F58E4E1EA84D332501"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Lost creek wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land managed by the Forest Service, comprising approximately 7,159 acres, as generally depicted on the map, which shall be known as the <quote>Lost Creek Wilderness</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF8C18AFE09614C3296BA359FB0F43E03"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rugged ridge wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land managed by the Forest Service, comprising approximately 5,956 acres, as generally depicted on the map, which shall be known as the <quote>Rugged Ridge Wilderness</quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1C48A77662274593B7BF09F9A71CA582"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Alckee creek wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land managed by the Forest Service, comprising approximately 1,787 acres, as generally depicted on the map, which shall be known as the <quote>Alckee Creek Wilderness</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD3F196DA3E214298A66B72445EC5C3E0"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Gates of the elwha wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land managed by the Forest Service, comprising approximately 5,669 acres, as generally depicted on the map, which shall be known as the <quote>Gates of the Elwha Wilderness</quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDFC730888F4C4B6C8D105C44587428D0"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Buckhorn wilderness additions</header><text>Certain Federal land managed by the Forest Service, comprising approximately 21,965 acres, as generally depicted on the map, is incorporated in, and shall be managed as part of, the <quote>Buckhorn Wilderness</quote>, as designated by section 3 of the Washington State Wilderness Act of 1984 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1132">16 U.S.C. 1132</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/98/339">Public Law 98–339</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H38A4C79BE0264A4C84C4DC0B3F7B722B"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Green mountain wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land managed by the Forest Service, comprising approximately 4,790 acres, as generally depicted on the map, which shall be known as the <quote>Green Mountain Wilderness</quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEE2E0FFFF94E48CF89BF15308B04D064"><enum>(7)</enum><header>The brothers wilderness additions</header><text>Certain land managed by the Forest Service, comprising approximately 8,625 acres, as generally depicted on the map, is incorporated in, and shall be managed as part of, the <quote>The Brothers Wilderness</quote>, as designated by section 3 of the Washington State Wilderness Act of 1984 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1132">16 U.S.C. 1132</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/98/339">Public Law 98–339</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB0459DDBC19449CBA8BDC6A6F7795DB3"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Mount skokomish wilderness additions</header><text>Certain land managed by the Forest Service, comprising approximately 8,933 acres, as generally depicted on the map, is incorporated in, and shall be managed as part of, the <quote>Mount Skokomish Wilderness</quote>, as designated by section 3 of the Washington State Wilderness Act of 1984 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1132">16 U.S.C. 1132</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/98/339">Public Law 98–339</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB8169560B53947F98C250B408928B6F9"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Wonder mountain wilderness additions</header><text>Certain land managed by the Forest Service, comprising approximately 26,517 acres, as generally depicted on the map, is incorporated in, and shall be managed as part of, the <quote>Wonder Mountain Wilderness</quote>, as designated by section 3 of the Washington State Wilderness Act of 1984 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1132">16 U.S.C. 1132</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/98/339">Public Law 98–339</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEF7C3045E49B457092E26887BFB11DDB"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Moonlight dome wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land managed by the Forest Service, comprising approximately 9,117 acres, as generally depicted on the map, which shall be known as the <quote>Moonlight Dome Wilderness</quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9F631862AAC24AB6A06AEC049EFD1C30"><enum>(11)</enum><header>South quinault ridge wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land managed by the Forest Service, comprising approximately 10,887 acres, as generally depicted on the map, which shall be known as the <quote>South Quinault Ridge Wilderness</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H47FAE3E703604BA7BA2300300F8F4155"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Colonel bob wilderness additions</header><text>Certain Federal land managed by the Forest Service, comprising approximately 353 acres, as generally depicted on the map, is incorporated in, and shall be managed as part of, the <quote>Colonel Bob Wilderness</quote>, as designated by section 3 of the Washington State Wilderness Act of 1984 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1132">16 U.S.C. 1132</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/98/339">Public Law 98–339</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6F02E1CB3D274125A84A9865A22FF363"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Sams river wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land managed by the Forest Service, comprising approximately 13,418 acres, as generally depicted on the map, which shall be known as the <quote>Sams River Wilderness</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFAABFD0BE59449BFABB7BCD721EDF819"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Canoe creek wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land managed by the Forest Service, comprising approximately 1,378 acres, as generally depicted on the map, which shall be known as the <quote>Canoe Creek Wilderness</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3AFBEB9145F241C9AA7AB8A23A420D5E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Administration</header> 
<paragraph id="H409A0C3B9E104012B63CAC4320F16B9A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Management</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, the land designated as wilderness by subsection (a) shall be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture (referred to in this section as the <quote>Secretary</quote>), in accordance with the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.</external-xref>), except that any reference in that Act to the effective date of that Act shall be considered to be a reference to the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF91B13A30A104E5AAA8ED5CDF6C44264"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Map and description</header> <subparagraph id="H366D25A2308149DCAC32C335963F618D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>As soon as practicable after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall file a map and a legal description of the land designated as wilderness by subsection (a) with—</text> 
<clause id="HA453E67FE3674573BFB206E3CEFD73B1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives; and</text></clause> <clause id="H492E9781656C40A6B2742FC711873979"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H695DBF7E75E24098893D17388047A026"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Effect</header><text>Each map and legal description filed under subparagraph (A) shall have the same force and effect as if included in this Act, except that the Secretary may correct minor errors in the map and legal description.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H949AF3985AA7486CBA80F9693C8FC108"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>Each map and legal description filed under subparagraph (A) shall be filed and made available for public inspection in the appropriate office of the Forest Service.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE78515A66AF747D98CD6349AF49134D5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Potential wilderness</header> 
<paragraph id="H189DA3C6B3C64C09A81E1A13CE64DA2F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In furtherance of the purposes of the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.</external-xref>), certain Federal land managed by the Forest Service, comprising approximately 5,346 acres as identified as <quote>Potential Wilderness</quote> on the map, is designated as potential wilderness.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC487F8A94ACC4D8F93C43B1E59692000"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Designation as wilderness</header><text>On the date on which the Secretary publishes in the Federal Register notice that any nonconforming uses in the potential wilderness designated by paragraph (1) have terminated, the potential wilderness shall be—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H65C5E228FDB043FD9D990EE23CA90BBD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>designated as wilderness and as a component of the National Wilderness Preservation System; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE3A9C18BF628405A91F5AF08EC5BFA70"><enum>(B)</enum><text>incorporated into the adjacent wilderness area.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3E0EF41C9F6A41A68BBCEDBFF347F2D5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Adjacent management</header> 
<paragraph id="H9608F28C0BA1426D93796309F41CDEFA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>No protective perimeters or buffer zones</header><text>The designations in this section shall not create a protective perimeter or buffer zone around any wilderness area.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC7503B5C22574E9A945C4A8C6282C00C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Nonconforming uses permitted outside of boundaries of wilderness areas</header><text>Any activity or use outside of the boundary of any wilderness area designated under this section shall be permitted even if the activity or use would be seen or heard within the boundary of the wilderness area.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H16DBCEDADC594834BC36B3FE59EF8B97"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Fire, insects, and diseases</header><text>The Secretary may take such measures as are necessary to control fire, insects, and diseases, in the wilderness areas designated by this section, in accordance with section 4(d)(1) of the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1133">16 U.S.C. 1133(d)(1)</external-xref>) and subject to such terms and conditions as the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H03BC67EBAC36423C8D3809CACB30FE6A"><enum>3.</enum><header>Wild and scenic river designations</header> <subsection id="H1D63F765DCC344D7B031396D983C9541"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3(a) of the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1274">16 U.S.C. 1274(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H44C055C5FE5F4CD099DF8A4E5ACF086B"> 
<paragraph id="HB9947B63EF454039B877F0B698CD740F"><enum>(233)</enum><header>Elwha river, washington</header><text>The approximately 29.0-mile segment of the Elwha River and tributaries from the source to Cat Creek, to be administered by the Secretary of the Interior as a wild river.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC30559D92F604B9F8DF483BE40332C90"><enum>(234)</enum><header>Dungeness river, washington</header><text>The segment of the Dungeness River from the headwaters to the State of Washington Department of Natural Resources land in T. 29 N., R. 4 W., sec. 12, to be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture, except that portions of the river within the boundaries of Olympic National Park shall be administered by the Secretary of the Interior, including the following segments of the mainstem and major tributary the Gray Wolf River, in the following classes:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HEE60D3461E2E4258A3E267F951EDF486"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The approximately 5.8-mile segment of the Dungeness River from the headwaters to the 2870 Bridge, as a wild river.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H249DC0E5A1404D30A6AF737683A7A392"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The approximately 2.1-mile segment of the Dungeness River from the 2870 Bridge to Silver Creek, as a scenic river.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB9D29D045F2A4D2D9621895A48A4A553"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The approximately 2.7-mile segment of the Dungeness River from Silver Creek to Sleepy Hollow Creek, as a wild river.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDCB22ED1B46C4620AD60811011F09691"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The approximately 6.3-mile segment of the Dungeness River from Sleepy Hollow Creek to the Olympic National Forest boundary, as a scenic river.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD760F3210E6541D488293EB985C1A779"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The approximately 1.9-mile segment of the Dungeness River from the National Forest boundary to the State of Washington Department of Natural Resources land in T. 29 N., R. 4 W., sec. 12, to be administered as a recreational river through a cooperative management agreement between the State of Washington and the Secretary of Agriculture, as provided in section 10(e).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE58DC549E1984BBBA248FB23AB4F2A61"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The approximately 16.1-mile segment of the Gray Wolf River from the headwaters to the 2870 Bridge, as a wild river.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA92836F5FA5A4B3C817A6C7B4AFEAD8E"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The approximately 1.1-mile segment of the Gray Wolf River from the 2870 Bridge to the confluence with the Dungeness River, as a scenic river.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB1810300F2F4430F919BAE8938A26F0E"><enum>(235)</enum><header>Big quilcene river, washington</header><text>The segment of the Big Quilcene River from the headwaters to the City of Port Townsend water intake facility, to be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture, in the following classes:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HFD39B8D724E84669BA1B90CEC58C72B7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The approximately 4.4-mile segment from the headwaters to the Buckhorn Wilderness boundary, as a wild river.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H91C29B77450642EF8647C5C691D30524"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The approximately 5.3-mile segment from the Buckhorn Wilderness boundary to the City of Port Townsend water intake facility, as a scenic river.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4AB9AFF3298A4FBB9B2643E3308F0DB9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Section 7(a), with respect to the licensing of dams, water conduits, reservoirs, powerhouses, transmission lines, or other project works, shall apply to the approximately 5-mile segment from the City of Port Townsend water intake facility to the Olympic National Forest boundary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3532AA373EB148399A5AFE78C71CBE37"><enum>(236)</enum><header>Dosewallips river, washington</header><text>The segment of the Dosewallips River from the headwaters to the private land in T. 26 N., R. 3 W., sec. 15, to be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture, except that portions of the river within the boundaries of Olympic National Park shall be administered by the Secretary of the Interior, in the following classes:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H0250510F117347288785C655165346BA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The approximately 12.9-mile segment from the headwaters to Station Creek, as a wild river.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H308B0664485148DBBAB90CA0BA3EC342"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The approximately 6.8-mile segment from Station Creek to the private land in T. 26 N., R. 3 W., sec. 15, as a scenic river.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1AA1F2CD50E7400FA47171861306D388"><enum>(237)</enum><header>Duckabush river, washington</header><text>The segment of the Duckabush River from the headwaters to the private land in T. 25 N., R. 3 W., sec. 1, to be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture, except that portions of the river within the boundaries of Olympic National Park shall be administered by the Secretary of the Interior, in the following classes:</text> <subparagraph id="H691FAB802E5E477FAA1C3DB5A4646023"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The approximately 19.0-mile segment from the headwaters to the Brothers Wilderness boundary, as a wild river.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H84D1943D56D94ED8B852894393D03EE6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The approximately 1.9-mile segment from the Brothers Wilderness boundary to the private land in T. 25 N., R. 3 W., sec. 1, as a scenic river.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H04B547EFEFDC403EBEAC302D21AFB3F0"><enum>(238)</enum><header>Hamma hamma river, washington</header><text>The segment of the Hamma Hamma River from the headwaters to the eastern edge of the NW<fraction>1/4</fraction> sec. 21, T. 24 N., R. 3 W., to be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture, in the following classes:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HDD5E3077BFD048DC82DAAA9A34CC8622"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The approximately 3.1-mile segment from the headwaters to the Mt. Skokomish Wilderness boundary, as a wild river.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA2E5F93FA3D4484C961171358D0B6B06"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The approximately 5.8-mile segment from the Mt. Skokomish Wilderness boundary to Lena Creek, as a scenic river.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2A0D565A68224E2B9912AB64E0C64F82"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The approximately 6.8-mile segment from Lena Creek to the eastern edge of the NW<fraction>1⁄4</fraction> sec. 21, T. 24 N., R. 3 W., to be administered as a recreational river through a cooperative management agreement between the State of Washington and the Secretary of Agriculture, as provided in section 10(e).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD55A8B76288147739F61862B1611EB45"><enum>(239)</enum><header>South fork skokomish river, washington</header><text>The segment of the South Fork Skokomish River from the headwaters to the Olympic National Forest boundary to be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture, in the following classes:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H2D7922AF8FEA460EBE5E98CDC3434A70"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The approximately 6.7-mile segment from the headwaters to Church Creek, as a wild river.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAEB8E8FD21044545A42A95AFA3715B26"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The approximately 8.3-mile segment from Church Creek to LeBar Creek, as a scenic river.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC98FA188FF5F4D76913A51F12EB123C6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The approximately 4.0-mile segment from LeBar Creek to upper end of the gorge in the NW<fraction>1/4</fraction> sec. 22, T. 22 N., R. 5 W., as a recreational river.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H749A2E71ACED4001B918DB72144D2112"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The approximately 6.0-mile segment from the upper end of the gorge to the Olympic National Forest boundary, as a scenic river.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H26CED13F893B4186881E9D3E49B19A4D"><enum>(240)</enum><header>Middle fork satsop river, washington</header><text>The approximately 7.9-mile segment of the Middle Fork Satsop River from the headwaters to the Olympic National Forest boundary, to be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture, as a scenic river.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC157BCA5963E477A9356CCD0979050A5"><enum>(241)</enum><header>West fork satsop river, washington</header><text>The approximately 8.2-mile segment of the West Fork Satsop River from the headwaters to the Olympic National Forest boundary, to be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture, as a scenic river.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H33E2DBD58F754E08A89A91186CFD80D4"><enum>(242)</enum><header>Wynoochee river, washington</header><text>The segment of the Wynoochee River from the headwaters to the head of Wynoochee Reservoir to be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture, except that portions of the river within the boundaries of Olympic National Park shall be administered by the Secretary of the Interior, in the following classes:</text> <subparagraph id="HBA1B9198E8CE424EB9DAD334EBA0ADC0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The approximately 2.5-mile segment from the headwaters to the boundary of the Wonder Mountain Wilderness, as a wild river.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H10F2228D80B441B880BAB143F83E1C34"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The approximately 7.4-mile segment from the boundary of the Wonder Mountain Wilderness to the head of Wynoochee Reservoir, as a recreational river.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8E5A5FE37CEE4CDBAA5757A1B66035CA"><enum>(243)</enum><header>East fork humptulips river, washington</header><text>The segment of the East Fork Hump­tu­lips River from the headwaters to the Olympic National Forest boundary to be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture, in the following classes:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H825CDF5FE93749BB82A2759B066E6D83"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The approximately 7.4-mile segment from the headwaters to the Moonlight Dome Wilderness boundary, as a wild river.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9EFF0DD4F89C4766AE42E0D8204EB32B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The approximately 10.3-mile segment from the Moonlight Dome Wilderness boundary to the Olympic National Forest boundary, as a scenic river.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0AAF0AED7B2D43048B16D848C4F225D5"><enum>(244)</enum><header>West fork humptulips river, washington</header><text>The approximately 21.4-mile segment of the West Fork Humptulips River from the headwaters to the Olympic National Forest Boundary, to be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture, as a scenic river.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H04FA2848CAFB4DB38B533A9DD90F71C0"><enum>(245)</enum><header>Quinault river, washington</header><text>The segment of the Quinault River from the headwaters to private land in T. 24 N., R. 8 W., sec. 33, to be administered by the Secretary of the Interior, in the following classes:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H85DFC9D07E96414881E570BB0AA40C72"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The approximately 16.5-mile segment from the headwaters to Graves Creek, as a wild river.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5BFB20DF6C32491BAE510DE70DAF7341"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The approximately 6.7-mile segment from Graves Creek to Cannings Creek, as a scenic river.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBAE82A2BC0BE4C449FE4D2BDEA18DFD1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The approximately 1.0-mile segment from Cannings Creek to private land in T. 24 N., R. 8 W., sec. 33, as a recreational river.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H02074073602247A68DDB0B74398F6DB2"><enum>(246)</enum><header>Queets river, washington</header><text>The segment of the Queets River from the headwaters to the Olympic National Park boundary to be administered by the Secretary of the Interior, except that portions of the river outside the boundaries of Olympic National Park shall be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture, including the following segments of the mainstem and certain tributaries in the following classes:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE30C252306604709ADCD873B410C553A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The approximately 28.6-mile segment of the Queets River from the headwaters to the confluence with Sams River, as a wild river.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5C21E4CD028C47AFB061F9D6B3FB5F50"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The approximately 16.0-mile segment of the Queets River from the confluence with Sams River to the Olympic National Park boundary, as a scenic river.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3D52235D0E404A8F8625AE8639B94EB0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The approximately 15.7-mile segment of the Sams River from the headwaters to the confluence with the Queets River, as a scenic river.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCC18C0CF6A4244EDAD07E9DD1B932726"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The approximately 17.7-mile segment of Matheny Creek from the headwaters to the confluence with the Queets River, to be administered as a scenic river through a cooperative management agreement between the State of Washington and the Secretary of Agriculture, as provided in section 10(e).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4CDF614268CB47C19FCD9FDAE6E11300"><enum>(247)</enum><header>Hoh river, washington</header><text>The segment of the Hoh River and the major tributary South Fork Hoh from the headwaters to Olympic National Park boundary, to be administered by the Secretary of the Interior, in the following classes:</text> <subparagraph id="H6D04C777ACE44BEA8DE61F5B6E25E1DA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The approximately 20.7-mile segment of the Hoh River from the headwaters to Jackson Creek, as a wild river.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8241441AA7D94DCB85F3CC816AF73A4E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The approximately 6.0-mile segment of the Hoh River from Jackson Creek to the Olympic National Park boundary, as a scenic river.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H176C7552756E4A078D967698BAE3374D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The approximately 13.8-mile segment of the South Fork Hoh River from the headwaters to the Olympic National Park boundary, as a wild river.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB735D0C4DEB94320AD44A0B1F63BADF0"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The approximately 4.6-mile segment of the South Fork Hoh River from the Olympic National Park boundary to the Washington State Department of Natural Resources boundary in T. 27 N., R. 10 W., sec. 29, to be administered as a recreational river through a cooperative management agreement between the State of Washington and the Secretary of Agriculture, as provided in section 10(e).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA299E3A3AFCF4975B116676681B8CA6D"><enum>(248)</enum><header>Bogachiel river, washington</header><text>The approximately 25.6-mile segment of the Bogachiel River from the source to the Olympic National Park boundary, to be administered by the Secretary of the Interior, as a wild river.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE38A9245F7E54BAA8F75A299D1039721"><enum>(249)</enum><header>South fork calawah river, washington</header><text>The segment of the South Fork Calawah River and the major tributary Sitkum River from the headwaters to Hyas Creek to be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture, except those portions of the river within the boundaries of Olympic National Park shall be administered by the Secretary of the Interior, including the following segments in the following classes:</text> <subparagraph id="HC4A36FB412BE416C87A3FACCB1530C33"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The approximately 15.7-mile segment of the South Fork Calawah River from the headwaters to the Sitkum River, as a wild river.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF2D1B8504B2841B5B279A0FF506EDD4A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The approximately 0.9-mile segment of the South Fork Calawah River from the Sitkum River to Hyas Creek, as a scenic river.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H01D08ED86F3944DB90B1017908A4A8B1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The approximately 1.6-mile segment of the Sitkum River from the headwaters to the Rugged Ridge Wilderness boundary, as a wild river.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB75BE4E295BF4279B49A2B85E523D819"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The approximately 11.9-mile segment of the Sitkum River from the Rugged Ridge Wilderness boundary to the confluence with the South Fork Calawah, as a scenic river.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD1484F695C934E7D8F114B9E5F0FCBD2"><enum>(250)</enum><header>Sol duc river, washington</header><text>The segment of the Sol Duc River from the headwaters to the Olympic National Park boundary to be administered by the Secretary of the Interior, including the following segments of the mainstem and certain tributaries in the following classes:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H19019E85256A4B79BCB57474DDC2814A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The approximately 7.0-mile segment of the Sol Duc River from the headwaters to the end of Sol Duc Hot Springs Road, as a wild river.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEED62FDE6CB945E294FC8C42496731BE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The approximately 10.8-mile segment of the Sol Duc River from the end of Sol Duc Hot Springs Road to the Olympic National Park boundary, as a scenic river.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1587C6833D514B74B84FD682138FA2A3"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The approximately 14.2-mile segment of the North Fork Sol Duc River from the headwaters to the Olympic Hot Springs Road bridge, as a wild river.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4F39121A083B46E0920E08D39B292C99"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The approximately 0.2-mile segment of the North Fork Sol Duc River from the Olympic Hot Springs Road bridge to the confluence with the Sol Duc River, as a scenic river.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2FEE7ACF48F14497939559DBDA823626"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The approximately 8.0-mile segment of the South Fork Sol Duc River from the headwaters to the confluence with the Sol Duc River, as a scenic river.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2DD5E8F2B0D84204A2CE90082D2A6421"><enum>(251)</enum><header>Lyre river, washington</header><text>The approximately 0.2-mile segment of the Lyre River from Lake Crescent to the Olympic National Park boundary, to be administered by the Secretary of the Interior as a scenic river.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB4FAFF50D4114AF68F89BAAEC9D872C1" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Restoration</header><text>Consistent with the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1271">16 U.S.C. 1271 et seq.</external-xref>) (including any regulations promulgated under that Act), the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Agriculture, as applicable, may authorize, with respect to a river segment designated by the amendment made by subsection (a), an activity or a project, the primary purpose of which is—</text> <paragraph id="H156F694E327941D6A9F8FCB2B9AD161B" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>river restoration;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H22928976B54044D1A533C016533C0931" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the recovery of a species listed as endangered or threatened under the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1531">16 U.S.C. 1531 et seq.</external-xref>); or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1A8D29FC154D4FC7AC10A6F299C3E268" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><text>restoring ecological and hydrological function.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9548383261C943C9A2955A3475FAAB24"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Updates to land and resource management plans</header> 
<paragraph id="HA8B55BB94A584E70B41CDED02C5214A0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Agriculture shall, with respect to the designations made under subsection (a) on lands under the jurisdiction of the Secretary, incorporate such designations into updated management plans for units of the National Forest System in accordance with applicable laws (including regulations).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H18235B7627604E7880A08F01C20E5266"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The date specified in paragraph (1) shall be 5 years after the date of enactment of this Act if the Secretary of Agriculture—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE753111DB78A42A6BE4BA7D56C55731A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is unable to meet the requirement under that paragraph by the date specified in such paragraph; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFC273A19D7A9467E87DA43783670F4FD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, includes in the Department of Agriculture annual budget submission to Congress a request for additional sums as may be necessary to meet the requirement of that paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H929A2EBBB15E460D961DBD7140ED01AE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Comprehensive management plan requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Updated management plans under paragraph (1) or (2) satisfy the requirements under section 3(d) of the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1274">16 U.S.C. 1274(d)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H88A4B69C4DC14E8A9862FD677A1D6F18"><enum>4.</enum><header>Existing rights and withdrawal</header> <subsection id="H6BE8F0CE58154402B1B9B11FBAC15133"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In accordance with section 12(b) of the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1283">16 U.S.C. 1283(b)</external-xref>), nothing in this Act or the amendment made by section 3(a) affects or abrogates existing rights, privileges, or contracts held by private parties, nor does this Act in any way modify or direct the management, acquisition, or disposition of land managed by the Washington Department of Natural Resources on behalf of the State of Washington.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HEC36C5440DC742C598D2C5697A73E7F3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Withdrawal</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, the Federal land within the boundaries of the river segments designated by this Act and the amendment made by section 3(a) is withdrawn from all forms of—</text> <paragraph id="HFFBA1FE6C9B645A6A13B0718D611E719"><enum>(1)</enum><text>entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF80FBA09D5614F98A193CA57FB66BFB3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H063173D52D0A4264B1011C238CAE52BD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>disposition under all laws relating to mineral and geothermal leasing or mineral materials.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="HCBC86DC2C6BD442191D0E8287DE52867"><enum>5.</enum><header>Treaty rights</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act alters, modifies, diminishes, or extinguishes the reserved treaty rights of any Indian Tribe with hunting, fishing, gathering, and cultural or religious rights as protected by a treaty.</text></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

