<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5C91540C11FA45B481AD7A94A8A05E73" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 284 IH: Expressing support for the goals and ideals of National Child Abuse Prevention Month.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 284</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250401">April 1, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001282">Mr. Barr</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="W000795">Mr. Wilson of South Carolina</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001214">Mr. Mrvan</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the goals and ideals of National Child Abuse Prevention Month.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas children are fundamental to the success of our Nation and will shape the future of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas elected representatives and leaders in our communities must be ever vigilant and proactive in support of evidence-based means to prevent child abuse and support families;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas adverse childhood experiences (ACEs) are traumatic experiences that occur during childhood with lasting long-term effects and include experiences such as child abuse and neglect, witnessing violence, or growing up in a household with a family member with a substance use disorder;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas at least 5 of the top 10 leading causes of death are associated with ACEs;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas preventing ACEs could reduce many health conditions, including up to 21,000,000 cases of depression, 1,900,000 cases of heart disease, and 2,500,000 cases of overweight and obesity;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas every child is filled with tremendous promise, and we all have a collective responsibility to prevent ACEs, foster the potential of every child, and promote positive childhood experience;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas preventing child abuse and neglect before they happen can reduce the costly lifetime economic burden associated with child maltreatment;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas investments in primary prevention pay off as studies show that the total lifetime economic burden associated with treating the consequences of child maltreatment is approximately $2,000,000,000,000;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas economic adversity has been observed as an increased risk for potential abuse of children;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2023, an estimated 7,782,600 children were referred to child protective services agencies, alleging maltreatment;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, approximately 1 in 7 children in the United States has experienced child abuse or neglect annually;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2023, the National Center for Missing and Exploited Children’s CyberTipline received 36,210,368 reports of suspected online child sexual abuse exploitation, a 12-percent increase from 2022; </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas reports indicate that 1 in 4 girls and 1 in 13 boys experience sexual abuse before their 18th birthday;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 93 percent of child sexual abuse victims are abused by a person they know and trust;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas children who are sexually abused, when not provided appropriate treatment, often suffer from lifelong problems, such as physical and mental health challenges, and higher risk of drug and alcohol misuse, and suicide;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas education and awareness of possible signs of child abuse should be prioritized for purposes of prevention;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Prevent Child Abuse America has a national network of Chapters and Healthy Families America sites providing prevention services and family support in our local districts;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas by intervening to prevent adversity and build resilience during a child’s most critical years of development, voluntary, evidence-based, home-visiting programs like Healthy Families America, the signature home-visiting program of Prevent Child Abuse America, have shown positive impact on reducing the recurrence of child abuse and neglect, decreased low-birthweight babies, improved school readiness for children, and increased high school graduation rates for parents; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Prevent Child Abuse America has a national network of Chapters and Healthy Families America sites providing prevention services and family support in our local districts: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="OLC" id="H3C733E6E62014622A654B17A24C77889"><section id="H38A5358547AD4D71AA61405733E1FFB4" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the House of Representatives— </text><paragraph id="HED3CB107D7654C4A939E5D22C5CB9B67"><enum>(1)</enum><text>expresses support for the goals and ideals of National Child Abuse Prevention Month;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBF7F7B5A051E4B3C8CFB51D1302806B6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes child abuse and child sexual abuse is preventable and that a healthy and prosperous society depends on strong families and communities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7BBF775CD5454BC28E8CCF525F0C5A39"><enum>(3)</enum><text>supports efforts to increase the awareness of, and provide education for, the general public of the United States, related to the prevention of child abuse and protective factors for families;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4170060F5053487AB0453E1F63056F97"><enum>(4)</enum><text>supports the efforts to help survivors of childhood sexual abuse heal;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCB40283F7D404137A162F94596DE8826"><enum>(5)</enum><text>supports justice for victims of childhood sexual abuse; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6D6AB183A5D04C3FBDCF1F4B13A007DC"><enum>(6)</enum><text>recognizes the need for additional investments and Federal legislation for prevention, healing, and justice efforts related to childhood abuse and sexual abuse.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

