<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2734E7E5FDBA48FCBF23D5F127BEFA74" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3810 IH: Stopping Klepto-card and Identity Misuse Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3810</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250606">June 6, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000480">Mr. Fong</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="V000129">Mr. Valadao</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000397">Mrs. Kim</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001240">Mr. McDowell</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Attorney General to report to Congress on Federal, State, and local efforts to combat access device fraud, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H2250A470A991412DBD035D8F68B4187A" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H273330656E10499882C98005AA315DA0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stopping Klepto-card and Identity Misuse Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SKIM Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H0FF39A41114E463CA693BCD61D614A02"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sentencing guidelines</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the United States Sentencing Commission shall revise of the United States Sentencing Commission Guidelines Manual—</text> <paragraph id="H0E2DC6585AE2475DBAFF6AAE4290EDAA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 2B1.1(b)(11) to provide that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H1F567540D8C24F5B92068E19C7239811"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the baseline increase described in that paragraph shall be an increase by 4 levels; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCD248F88D8A448AB93FAE9D2188F9325"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the resulting offense level is less than level 14, the offense shall be increased to level 14; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H108C7A35FC9B4DC2A8EB5B04083D0AC3"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the notes related to the application of subsection (b) of section 2B1.1, that in a case involving 10 or more counterfeit access devices or unauthorized access devices, loss includes any unauthorized charges made with any such counterfeit access device or unauthorized access device in any amount.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H19AC1FC8DD4C4CB29D486C4B0CA15715"><enum>3.</enum><header>Report to Congress</header> <subsection id="H218C3FC0FA5D4D64A8607EDA64692EC5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report to congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Attorney General, in coordination with the Secretary of Homeland Security, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the coordinated efforts of the Department of Homeland Security and Department of Justice, along with State and local law enforcement agencies to prevent, investigate, prosecute, and sentence fraud offenses involving the use of access devices.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HAA907DA596424BBAB5B35E5F8CA957A3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report under this section shall include the following:</text> <paragraph id="H8651F8C737CA41679DA608B5CE05A911"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of cooperative operations of Federal and State law enforcement agencies to identify and prosecute fraud involving the use of access devices under subsections (a)(1), (2), (3), (4), and (8), and (b)(2) of section 1029 of title 18, United States Code.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H38F6EF66694645EC926814FD97C3D7C2"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of technologies and techniques used by perpetrators of fraud using counterfeit access devices, which may facilitate such fraud or prevent its detection by law enforcement personnel.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE6347DAF76C6428493655002ADEC1C99"><enum>(3)</enum><text>For the one-year period preceding the report, the number of requests for assistance that State or local law enforcement agencies made to the Department of Justice or the Department of Homeland Security related to fraud involving the use of counterfeit access devices, including the number of such requests for which the Department of Justice or the Department of Homeland Security provided assistance, and the number of such request for which neither agency provided assistance.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1352B42C65574DB7BFAF1DEF182CA78F"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">States and counties in which fraud involving the use of counterfeit access devices remains unaddressed or of particular concern to the Secretary and Attorney General.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF67C0055C0394798B34D48A26B29FC88"> <enum>(5)</enum> <text>Legislative recommendations for cooperation between Federal and State law enforcement agencies to address such fraud.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7F62113F1E24429A99BA0766CE3BBD7C"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Recommendations on best practices for State and local law enforcement agencies and business owners to combat such fraud.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H7C92D3B0BE1247189B03A9FA5154B739"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H63D2C4F7CEF4424A8C4E2F4751A4DD20"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The terms <term>access device</term> and <term>counterfeit access device</term> have the meaning given such terms in section 1029 of title 18, United States Code.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8B51B04362D74396AB8B96D8878E91EA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H0E311CB757FC40C1BE6E5A031EEC6EEE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H270108730E3446F9A6D79DADFA73949D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2DADF2411BA64739823691879525BCAC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE1B0B75F0353460781D29DFBAADAC748"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

