<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9336F268F962402A97E7BC006BBBFD76" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 392 IH: Providing Real-world Education and Clinical Experience by Precepting Tomorrow’s Nurses Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 392</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250114">January 14, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000399">Mrs. Kiggans of Virginia</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="T000478">Ms. Tenney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000295">Mr. Joyce of Ohio</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to create a tax credit for nurse preceptors.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF937C93BA58848CA917F64BA9E68DBAA" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="H6F5D7A5D7FE94DCA91ED320717C5E203"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Providing Real-world Education and Clinical Experience by Precepting Tomorrow’s Nurses Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>PRECEPT Nurses Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3CBFBA0573B54EBC9FF65960A6010573" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Credit for nurse preceptors</header><subsection id="HEA05724F7F3644ED9A4EA0314BB55CFE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subpart A of part IV of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting after section 25E the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H22CC8B48182A42999A373447D531F939"><section id="H268F6E5BB2BD4143B0B1D015E6918DF8"><enum>25F.</enum><header>Credit for nurse preceptors</header><subsection id="H3522288D21864F8CB45CF86964322164"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of any eligible nurse preceptor, there shall be allowed as a credit against the tax imposed by this chapter for any taxable year an amount equal to $2,000.</text></subsection><subsection id="H019B947C10264D788CBCCB42F28D2ECE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section, with respect to any taxable year—</text><paragraph id="H8132A6CE9839400289CC3A993BAF4C7B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible nurse preceptor</header><text>The term <term>eligible nurse preceptor</term> means an individual who serves not less than 200 hours during the taxable year as a nurse preceptor in a community which is designated as a health professional shortage area under section 332 of the Public Health Service Act. The Secretary shall publish on an annual basis on the website of the Internal Revenue Service a list of the areas which are so designated.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEC672E18862D4113B3977FD355980E9B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Nurse preceptor</header><text>The term <term>nurse preceptor</term> means a licensed registered nurse or health care provider (as defined in section 3000(3) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300jj">42 U.S.C. 300jj(3)</external-xref>)) who provides supervision and personalized experiential learning, training, instruction, and mentoring opportunities in the clinical practice of nursing (as defined by the applicable State Board of Nursing, applicable state agency, or written agreement between the relevant academic institution and clinical site) to a student of nursing, student of advanced practice registered nursing, or newly hired licensed nurse.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF8E9EB7D8832495B94EAA461328F4AF6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Relevant academic institution</header><text>The term <term>relevant academic institution</term> means a school of nursing (as defined in section 801(2) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/296">42 U.S.C. 296(2)</external-xref>)) in which a student of nursing or student of advanced practice registered nursing is enrolled.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFD96045980D7426E958AF07D32ACE6DF"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Newly hired</header><text>The term <term>newly hired</term> means within the first 6 months of employment. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA07A2EE0AACD47E9B92C56E3669670AD"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Minimum required hours of preceptorship</header><text>The term <term>minimum required hours of preceptorship</term> means 200 hours of serving as a nurse preceptor. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE80831C3C054468C9844A9A9EE7E34FB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reporting requirement</header><paragraph id="H074D94C554B143C2B7A6B11185338580"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>No credit shall be allowed under subsection (a) unless the eligible nurse preceptor has received a certification indicating that the eligible nurse preceptor has completed the minimum required hours of preceptorship for the taxable year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7509BA5E4C6147CE9A86E58A4A21E8D4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents of certification</header><text>A certification under paragraph (1) shall include—</text><subparagraph id="HD946A39FA32240AD824ADB666DDE1218"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a certification from the relevant partnering academic institution stating the number of hours the preceptor served as a nurse preceptor to a student of nursing or student of advanced practice registered nursing during the taxable year, or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0D841CB1F0D04EE2812468D31FD1E0E1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a certification from the clinical site at which the preceptor is employed stating the number of hours the preceptor served as a nurse preceptor to a newly hired nurse during the taxable year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC3C0F0A712814BECA3ED8980EEB4F742"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Multiple certifications</header><text>A nurse preceptor may receive multiple certifications from multiple entities under paragraph (2) to establish the completion of the minimum required hours of preceptorship. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC67F65AA9C084D358EA57930419CAA98"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>This section shall not apply to any taxable year beginning after December 31, 2032.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H62A33A02D60E42B7AFCBAE48C5E27644"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for subpart A of part IV of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 25E the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H8C499EEC29CD4FA3A8802A889BAB92B3"><toc><toc-entry level="section" idref="H268F6E5BB2BD4143B0B1D015E6918DF8">Sec. 25F. Credit for nurse preceptors.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HCFEA00DF11F142D48AFAE3FF3BFA62DE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2025.</text></subsection><subsection id="HFE4858A84B1B49DCA47014B45DD72D6C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report and evaluation</header><paragraph id="HEA59E9680FF8466EA36D47E0FB74BD0B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For taxable years beginning in calendar year 2026, and each calendar year thereafter through 2032, the Secretary of the Treasury (or the Secretary’s delegate) shall report to the relevant committees of Congress for taxable years beginning in such calendar year on the credit under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/25F">section 25F</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as added by this section. Such report shall include—</text><subparagraph id="H9AF5D60744B047CF8F2BF0CE58DF4C6B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of taxpayers claiming such credit for taxable years beginning in such calendar year,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H745719DC22474965BD5B1A9965BE60FE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the total hours served and other aggregated and averaged data on the preceptorships served by taxpayers as an eligible nurse preceptor (as defined in section 25F(b) of such Code, as so added),</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H02C7374AE441409CB1862E6ABE8B8144"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the geographic distribution of taxpayers claiming such credit for the taxable year, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H119147BA816D4A5397D3C59B7625C9A7"><enum>(D)</enum><text>such other information as determined relevant by the Secretary (or the Secretary’s delegate).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7F314985913D4B95A04D30D649BE1E46"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text>Not later than June 30, 2033, the Secretary of the Treasury (or the Secretary’s delegate), in consultation with the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration, shall provide to the relevant committees of Congress an evaluation of the effectiveness of the credit under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/25F">section 25F</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as added by this section, in increasing the number of nurse preceptors in the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H915C7FF6332E424BAF5540F5E23385DF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Relevant committees of Congress</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>relevant committees of Congress</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H2D846AE239C44ECAA7518F6C56C87238"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Finance of the Senate,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H19867AD7F5124C5FA54C19B941DA4875"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H86BD0B17A0C241A2A445862CFDA7721C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAAC83A0A11FE489994BBB7F0A3B6C0FE"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Committee on Education and Workforce of the House of Representatives, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H32FE908B9AED4998986999CAFD45A642"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

