<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1BDB89D506D14A759D280425320936C6" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 175 IH: Deport Alien Gang Members Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 175</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action display="yes"> 
<action-date date="20250103">January 3, 2025</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001177">Mr. McClintock</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000478">Ms. Tenney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000026">Mr. Nehls</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001096">Ms. Hageman</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="O000175">Mr. Ogles</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act with respect to aliens associated with criminal gangs, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H47EDAB6272104998AB225F889064DED3" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H6321987F277C45DB96519B7CDF5802F3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Deport Alien Gang Members Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HE77CE03E941741D99B4F432859762563"><enum>2.</enum><header>Grounds of inadmissibility and deportability for alien gang members</header> <subsection id="H4188D6C579E64269BE23851E28FD2A27"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition of gang member</header><text>Section 101(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBB018857D6714F7A838A91853A6E0149" style="traditional"> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H00104727273D423F87D77298BD59D977" indent="up1"><enum>(53)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>criminal gang</term> means an ongoing group, club, organization, or association of 5 or more persons that has as 1 of its primary purposes the commission of 1 or more of the offenses described in this paragraph and the members of which engage, or have engaged within the past 5 years, in a continuing series of such offenses, or that has been designated as a criminal gang by the Secretary of Homeland Security, in consultation with the Attorney General, as meeting these criteria. The offenses described, whether committed, in whole or in part, within or outside of the United States and regardless of whether the offenses occurred before, on, or after the date of the enactment of this paragraph, are the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H02AB6FA9B202417588A5A03F85635C08" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A Federal, State, local, or Tribal offense that is punishable by imprisonment for more than 1 year and relates to a controlled substance (as so classified under the relevant Federal, State, local, or Tribal law), regardless of whether the substance is classified as a controlled substance under section 102 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/802">21 U.S.C. 802</external-xref>). </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9F2FCECA48734E858314CBCE6C89D60B" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A foreign offense that is punishable by imprisonment for more than 1 year and relates to a controlled substance as defined under section 102 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/802">21 U.S.C. 802</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2E389C5255F74E839B903AB471D692C8"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An offense that is punishable by imprisonment for more than 1 year and involves firearms or explosives (as defined under the relevant Federal, State, local, Tribal, or foreign law) or in violation of section 931 of title 18, United States Code (relating to purchase, ownership, or possession of body armor by violent felons).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6598168CD1FA4140B7D597CF2F371936"><enum>(D)</enum><text>An offense under section 274 (relating to bringing in and harboring certain aliens), section 277 (relating to aiding or assisting certain aliens to enter the United States), or section 278 (relating to importation of alien for immoral purpose).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2D7BE7EB9864461CB786D66A6E48E10E"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A crime of violence (as defined in section 16(a) of title 18, United States Code).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC92C9C26D29746F3801A95EB529542FD"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A crime involving obstruction of justice, tampering with or retaliating against a witness, victim, or informant, or burglary (as such terms are defined under the relevant Federal, State, local, Tribal, or foreign law).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H68417C032541402485565219B8694610"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any conduct punishable under sections 1028, 1028A, and 1029 of title 18, United States Code (relating to fraud, aggravated identity theft or fraud and related activity in connection with identification documents or access devices), sections 1581 through 1594 of such title (relating to peonage, slavery, and trafficking in persons), section 1951 of such title (relating to interference with commerce by threats or violence), section 1952 of such title (relating to interstate and foreign travel or transportation in aid of racketeering enterprises), section 1956 of such title (relating to the laundering of monetary instruments), section 1957 of such title (relating to engaging in monetary transactions in property derived from specified unlawful activity), or sections 2312 through 2315 of such title (relating to interstate transportation of stolen motor vehicles or stolen property).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H44E6EA89B44145AEB844E02DE618D996"><enum>(H)</enum><text>A conspiracy to commit an offense described in subparagraphs (A) through (G).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HC3D3F42AFEB7491EAB8438F8D0C502E0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Inadmissibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 212(a)(2) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(a)(2)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD02B89BA008F457390A6B543FD346F21" style="OLC"> 
<subparagraph id="H2C2F078AFFE64ABE9B9C359951569E90" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(J)</enum><header>Aliens associated with criminal gangs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any alien is inadmissible who a consular officer, an immigration officer, the Secretary of Homeland Security, or the Attorney General knows, or has reason to believe—</text> <clause id="HE8EFA36D978448FF8B6C293C6E06FC87" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is, or has been, a member of a criminal gang;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H10D425E19E004512A6C63B51721E1CB0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has promoted, conspired with, aided, or participated in the activities of a criminal gang, whether within or outside of the United States; or</text></clause> <clause id="H55C8F381944341B2B52F3A04E790C9FB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">seeks to enter the United States, or has entered the United States, in furtherance of the activities of a criminal gang, whether those activities take place within or outside of the United States.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HDBA5CFFD77C74E91BA275691B33197C0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Deportability</header><text>Section 237(a)(2) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1227">8 U.S.C. 1227(a)(2)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA1F9EE57372E4D51A1D06B93A6107279" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H9AB567234FAD420C95B96227E403B28D"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Aliens associated with criminal gangs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any alien is deportable who—</text> 
<clause id="H90CE74CA5C434A27B7C01EB328579BAA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is or has been a member of a criminal gang; or</text></clause> <clause id="HCA3CBFF9105F4E2289500C17C1D75625"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has promoted, conspired with, aided, or participated in the activities of a criminal gang, whether within or outside of the United States.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF172560A38B347D7BB772AA9AC49608D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Designation</header> 
<paragraph id="H59C9BD9EA3D742AF8FF99E1206865875"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Chapter 2 of title II of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 219 the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFE74B78C82FA47FC85DD77787144B719" style="OLC"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 220. Designation of criminal gang.</toc-entry></toc> <section id="H191A8E354522477E970B0D9CC032502D" display-inline="yes-display-inline"> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDCE52B8CCE054C86B139E132C83C48A9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation</header> <paragraph id="H155BDDA8404A4250923ED6292FFB58FC" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security, in consultation with the Attorney General, may designate a group, club, organization, or association of 5 or more persons as a criminal gang if the Secretary finds that their conduct is described in section 101(a)(53).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD86957EF4EE449F494BE863F4492D042" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Procedure</header> 
<subparagraph id="HD1FDFBC346004A20967C03B058692E1D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Notification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">7 days before making a designation under this subsection, the Secretary shall, by classified communication, notify the Speaker and minority leader of the House of Representatives, the president pro tempore, majority leader, and minority leader of the Senate, and the members of the relevant committees of the House of Representatives and the Senate, in writing, of the intent to designate a group, club, organization, or association of 5 or more persons under this subsection and the factual basis therefor.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H84C408BDD41544CF894CF726EC4C9184"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Publication in the Federal Register</header><text>The Secretary shall publish the designation in the Federal Register 7 days after providing the notification under subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H92C8547F917F461399709513A964F2EF" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Record</header> 
<subparagraph id="H06FB7F1DD00B43389311CDB7670A9E25"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In making a designation under this subsection, the Secretary shall create an administrative record.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H89EB7CA8985343A5A44B5531F52965FA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Classified information</header><text>The Secretary may consider classified information in making a designation under this subsection. Classified information shall not be subject to disclosure for such time as it remains classified, except that such information may be disclosed to a court ex parte and in camera for purposes of judicial review under subsection (c).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEAE993015ADE4C52A0948BD71534E3A4" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Period of designation</header> 
<subparagraph id="HA5DE8616165F420A89E99538C25B29E2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A designation under this subsection shall be effective for all purposes until revoked under paragraph (5) or (6) or set aside pursuant to subsection (c).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H922337651610404A90969D4112BE2050"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Review of designation upon petition</header> <clause id="H07DF4D25600642DA936CF52D4371F77A"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall review the designation of a criminal gang under the procedures set forth in clauses (iii) and (iv) if the designated group, club, organization, or association of 5 or more persons files a petition for revocation within the petition period described in clause (ii).</text></clause> 
<clause id="H71F53BA34EFE4BB3BBEC0B9EF5547C7E"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Petition period</header><text>For purposes of clause (i)—</text> <subclause id="H7484B86EA2E641819D5433AA79199E0C"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the designated group, club, organization, or association of 5 or more persons has not previously filed a petition for revocation under this subparagraph, the petition period begins 2 years after the date on which the designation was made; or</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H08482C3A5D8D4E809AD924F6B68AAEAD"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the designated group, club, organization, or association of 5 or more persons has previously filed a petition for revocation under this subparagraph, the petition period begins 2 years after the date of the determination made under clause (iv) on that petition.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H259CDDC20E764921A6484BE4720ED8B6"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Procedures</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any group, club, organization, or association of 5 or more persons that submits a petition for revocation under this subparagraph of its designation as a criminal gang must provide evidence in that petition that it is not described in section 101(a)(53).</text></clause> 
<clause id="H674E4231170642879956625986C61C11"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Determination</header> 
<subclause id="H36166F82095D402A817F3A220A37A3BA"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 30 days after receiving a petition for revocation submitted under this subparagraph, the Secretary shall make a determination as to such revocation.</text></subclause> <subclause id="H3BF8DD9649CD4947B6643608736DA304"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Classified information</header><text>The Secretary may consider classified information in making a determination in response to a petition for revocation. Classified information shall not be subject to disclosure for such time as it remains classified, except that such information may be disclosed to a court ex parte and in camera for purposes of judicial review under subsection (c).</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H044837E800384425AC83A1314A4D13E1"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Publication of determination</header><text>A determination made by the Secretary under this clause shall be published in the Federal Register.</text></subclause> <subclause id="HA730E9EACA19449F8B6BA63125BF28FB"><enum>(IV)</enum><header>Procedures</header><text>Any revocation by the Secretary shall be made in accordance with paragraph (6).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3B4ABDF865584CE29B6F0212287D39CA"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Other review of designation</header> 
<clause id="HAC65FAA71A324657964AC351FAA1D2C2"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If in a 5-year period no review has taken place under subparagraph (B), the Secretary shall review the designation of the criminal gang in order to determine whether such designation should be revoked pursuant to paragraph (6).</text></clause> <clause id="H236477F75DD24216A62F3E37CA5C65A2"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Procedures</header><text>If a review does not take place pursuant to subparagraph (B) in response to a petition for revocation that is filed in accordance with that subparagraph, then the review shall be conducted pursuant to procedures established by the Secretary. The results of such review and the applicable procedures shall not be reviewable in any court.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HDCDFE29C6D774998B64EAA40C657DEA4"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Publication of results of review</header><text>The Secretary shall publish any determination made pursuant to this subparagraph in the Federal Register.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBB6AF0DF7D0446FF8C562948899E63C3" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Revocation by act of Congress</header><text>The Congress, by an Act of Congress, may block or revoke a designation made under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF4AAEA6895444A0DAD81E956984F179E" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Revocation based on change in circumstances</header> 
<subparagraph id="HF6F893EFEDC64075BDE0BFA6E7D42061"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may revoke a designation made under paragraph (1) at any time, and shall revoke a designation upon completion of a review conducted pursuant to subparagraphs (B) and (C) of paragraph (4) if the Secretary finds that—</text> <clause id="HAA7ABE9F07004F0FAC33DDAF21EC7D5C"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the group, club, organization, or association of 5 or more persons that has been designated as a criminal gang is no longer described in section 101(a)(53); or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H73490F9211C94D7CBDD48197E379EC40"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the national security or the law enforcement interests of the United States warrants a revocation.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC24F18A1EAC04ADBB08C48D63AE806AD"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Procedure</header><text>The procedural requirements of paragraphs (2) and (3) shall apply to a revocation under this paragraph. Any revocation shall take effect on the date specified in the revocation or upon publication in the Federal Register if no effective date is specified.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4C74AAC3D1F34E40A624ACCBC756FE87" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Effect of revocation</header><text>The revocation of a designation under paragraph (5) or (6) shall not affect any action or proceeding based on conduct committed prior to the effective date of such revocation.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD28393E505BA45AAA601DA7D8A866140"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Use of designation in trial or hearing</header><text>If a designation under this subsection has become effective under paragraph (2) an alien in a removal proceeding shall not be permitted to raise any question concerning the validity of the issuance of such designation as a defense or an objection.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H83B4936463B24F72AD6ADD690F6B8A3F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Amendments to a designation</header> 
<paragraph id="H6FC31C2545344CAA93DD841BF8EDAD55"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may amend a designation under this subsection if the Secretary finds that the group, club, organization, or association of 5 or more persons has changed its name, adopted a new alias, dissolved and then reconstituted itself under a different name or names, or merged with another group, club, organization, or association of 5 or more persons.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6C9F2F4C79E2471182E43F6DEC0F1F42"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Procedure</header><text>Amendments made to a designation in accordance with paragraph (1) shall be effective upon publication in the Federal Register. Paragraphs (2), (4), (5), (6), (7), and (8) of subsection (a) shall also apply to an amended designation.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H593B4FE767DB4D03A778C4CDC64B1096"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Administrative record</header><text>The administrative record shall be corrected to include the amendments as well as any additional relevant information that supports those amendments.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8B11B38DE58C41A0B7604F5A448DBDD1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Classified information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may consider classified information in amending a designation in accordance with this subsection. Classified information shall not be subject to disclosure for such time as it remains classified, except that such information may be disclosed to a court ex parte and in camera for purposes of judicial review under subsection (c) of this section.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HBFFA76D445F849EDBD0B9790D3A9038D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Judicial review of designation</header> 
<paragraph id="HF3830854023E4DFB8D75C21A722BAD70"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after publication in the Federal Register of a designation, an amended designation, or a determination in response to a petition for revocation, the designated group, club, organization, or association of 5 or more persons may seek judicial review in the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H550DB7A4E45E45B89B8C1F870AAEFAF9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Basis of review</header><text>Review under this subsection shall be based solely upon the administrative record, except that the Government may submit, for ex parte and in camera review, classified information used in making the designation, amended designation, or determination in response to a petition for revocation.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD34148D9C7594114BE72F9C3099725D4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Scope of review</header><text>The Court shall hold unlawful and set aside a designation, amended designation, or determination in response to a petition for revocation the court finds to be—</text> <subparagraph id="HDE15D12BA5264B0CA887BD0EBFC3216F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>arbitrary, capricious, an abuse of discretion, or otherwise not in accordance with law;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFD376368F6E744E3863B909BC95BF76A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>contrary to constitutional right, power, privilege, or immunity;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEE10F1F74F8B43548DBA23C2F7C9B1CE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in excess of statutory jurisdiction, authority, or limitation, or short of statutory right;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEC5C5541670E4932B20E7D7C80BD33A5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>lacking substantial support in the administrative record taken as a whole or in classified information submitted to the court under paragraph (2); or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC67A10BF8060428581446B09D4DED8DC"><enum>(E)</enum><text>not in accord with the procedures required by law.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9A244116B244496B8DCB626D395AFECD"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Judicial review invoked</header><text>The pendency of an action for judicial review of a designation, amended designation, or determination in response to a petition for revocation shall not affect the application of this section, unless the court issues a final order setting aside the designation, amended designation, or determination in response to a petition for revocation.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD49E97E66FE7458AB0E1C1EB73325263" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Expedited review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It shall be the duty of the Court to advance on the docket and expedite to the greatest possible extent the disposition of any case considered under this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4FFCB8B7CB184763AF83D0C6196A59F9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>As used in this section—</text> <paragraph id="H9F989E794F164CA0BCB9969A9B2D1A53"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>classified information</term> has the meaning given that term in section 1(a) of the Classified Information Procedures Act (18 U.S.C. App.);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1AAE6A211A5C44058EF8331BBDC90963"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>national security</term> means the national defense, foreign relations, or economic interests of the United States;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9F1484A82919417D944BC59F71BC0F07"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>relevant committees</term> means the Committees on the Judiciary of the Senate and of the House of Representatives; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H65404D792330458BB9EDF26660655E87"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Homeland Security, in consultation with the Attorney General.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA779420DBDA143CDA9A75A4B5733F939"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents for such Act is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 219 the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCBEAF05A783942D0BEB3D02251A379D2" style="OLC"> 
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 220. Designation.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA8360B31C1074133B084472FD337B62B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Mandatory detention of criminal gang members</header> 
<paragraph id="H43220D3CC1FC4C2A9A4AF0CBEAC7A088"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 236(c)(1) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1226">8 U.S.C. 1226(c)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="HDE321B4CEFF14A60928D935D9BA4C8DB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEA4B62D8788F4B7D87CFBBAD6174EFE9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D), by inserting <quote>or</quote> at the end; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H49B71A79B6F74B3FA88906801521AFF6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (D) the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H694D2D2BA2A84ADB8595595765A7F5E3" style="OLC"> 
<subparagraph id="HEEB481A30FA74B9191608166E348B7BD"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is inadmissible under section 212(a)(2)(J) or deportable under section 217(a)(2)(G),</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2A5C3ADFBCCF43519F2D786BB7130475"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>Not later than March 1 of each year (beginning 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act), the Secretary of Homeland Security, after consultation with the appropriate Federal agencies, shall submit a report to the Committees on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and of the Senate on the number of aliens detained under the amendments made by paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC68E82488A7F44B2840E33046D32B228"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Claims based on gang affiliation</header> 
<paragraph id="HE3E3FF17FDD74E89973EA1EB41E888D7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Inapplicability of restriction on removal to certain countries</header><text>Section 241(b)(3)(B) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1251">8 U.S.C. 1251(b)(3)(B)</external-xref>) is amended, in the matter preceding clause (i), by inserting <quote>who is described in section 212(a)(2)(J)(i) or section 237(a)(2)(G)(i) or who is</quote> after <quote>to an alien</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFE9C451F630B436B9033EDB814A0F969"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Ineligibility for asylum</header><text>Section 208(b)(2)(A) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1158">8 U.S.C. 1158(b)(2)(A)</external-xref>) (as amended by section 201 of this Act) is further amended—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H85FAF9BDDE7140A2828902FD25BC5FE4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in clause (v), by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4904BD8562AE4A91B17D6C6B7DBF5C73"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating clause (vi) as clause (vii); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H74D4C88ADD184FE58EE015C2914C174A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after clause (v) the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1DC9A7F810AE4470B3F8303EE58EB5AD" style="OLC"> <clause id="H20723966123746009E8D5E56552C1FFA"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the alien is described in section 212(a)(2)(J)(i) or section 237(a)(2)(G)(i); or</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3C37F91F53DE4580896909047D753DBA"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Temporary protected status</header><text>Section 244 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1254a">8 U.S.C. 1254a</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H1D77BD2CDCFB4AFE970ABDBDB0BFBC7A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Attorney General</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>Secretary of Homeland Security</quote>;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3DDEDECD6DE14936A0085B2735AB64DD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (c)(2)(B)—</text> <subparagraph id="HD4D9141ABF4E4663A75F1D3C438E4692"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in clause (i), by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H507EBA1F89F44064B47135BB2C24D963"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in clause (ii), by striking the period and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H35499036F17946FC981E29BF581E038A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBCCE7BD616F1467B821D16BAAEC32B48" style="OLC"> 
<clause id="H2829D40C1D214857A99ECD5E70CBAB97"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the alien is, or at any time has been, described in section 212(a)(2)(J) or section 237(a)(2)(G).</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9EC1BFCDFA0345B1B250D78490EC6FC2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (d)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HDB2F959429DF49EB9EF26F5CA90653A6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (3); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H366A039A5A3E48BDA735E0659F40E875"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by adding at the end the following: <quote>The Secretary of Homeland Security may detain an alien provided temporary protected status under this section whenever appropriate under any other provision of law.</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HDEB91BCEB9564073B5E883F8D4BFDB27"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Special immigrant juvenile visas</header><text>Section 101(a)(27)(J)(iii) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(27)(J)(iii)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H677003CAD2D54895B61093B3C770F92B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subclause (I), by striking <quote>and</quote>;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7FAC81A0439944F0A164B45650F436EA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subclause (II), by adding <quote>and</quote> at the end; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H76BB33BB6C894FE49B783B08DBBC07EA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H10DBB621587F4444A885E5596D069BFA" style="OLC"> 
<subclause id="H144EF49C19EE40FE84C453A78FC7CFB3"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">no alien who is, or at any time has been, described in section 212(a)(2)(J) or section 237(a)(2)(G) shall be eligible for any immigration benefit under this subparagraph;</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H73D20C8759234A4889440D214415966D"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Parole</header><text>An alien described in section 212(a)(2)(J) of the Immigration and Nationality Act, as added by subsection (b), shall not be eligible for parole under section 212(d)(5)(A) of such Act unless—</text> 
<paragraph id="HC2C5CD3EBB6848C8879DBE8204485C10"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the alien is assisting or has assisted the United States Government in a law enforcement matter, including a criminal investigation; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD4E2629AFABD4613BD08F512AB96C20C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the alien’s presence in the United States is required by the Government with respect to such assistance.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2030F80506BE429D9428C934DAA089FE"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Ineligibility for other relief</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An alien described in section 212(a)(2)(J) or 237(a)(2)(G) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(a)(2)(J)</external-xref> or 1227(a)(2)(G)) shall be ineligible for any other relief under the immigration laws, including under section 2242 of the Omnibus Consolidated and Emergency Supplemental Appropriations Act, 1999 (and any regulations issued pursuant to such section).</text></subsection> <subsection id="HD18536A2BEDB44619037C68B2BE49B9D"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act and shall apply to acts that occur before, on, or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 


