<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCD4CD9D35FC8493C9A8E436F4D4A6A90" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 822 IH: Supporting the designation of October 23, 2025, as “National Marine Sanctuary Day”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
        <congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session display="yes">1st Session</session>
        <legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 822</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
        <action display="yes">
            <action-date date="20251021">October 21, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001301">Mr. Bergman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms.
                    Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>,
                    <cosponsor name-id="C001112">Mr. Carbajal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001055">Mr. Case</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr.
                    Panetta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</cosponsor>,
                    <cosponsor name-id="S000510">Mr. Smith of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000168">Ms. Salazar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms.
                    Norton</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="J000305">Ms. Jacobs</cosponsor>)
                submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural
                Resources</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
        <official-title display="yes">Supporting the designation of October 23, 2025, as
                <quote>National Marine Sanctuary Day</quote>.</official-title>
    </form>
    <preamble>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas, on October 23, 1972, the Marine Protection, Research, and Sanctuaries Act of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1401">33 U.S.C. 1401 et seq.</external-xref>) became law and ushered in a new era of ocean conservation;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas the National Marine Sanctuary System is a nationwide network of underwater parks that conserves nationally significant natural, historical, and cultural resources in marine and Great Lakes waters and promotes access to exploration and world-class outdoor recreation;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas conservation, economic prosperity, and human well-being are deeply woven together in our national character as a maritime nation, and the ocean, coasts, and Great Lakes are central to the way of life of the people of the United States;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas national marine sanctuaries provide vital habitats for countless species of fish and wildlife, safeguard historic shipwrecks and sacred cultural places that tell the story of America’s history, and provide access for abundant recreational opportunities;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas the conservation of marine and Great Lakes ecosystems is vital for maintaining healthy fishing grounds and sustaining productive coastal economies;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas national marine sanctuaries anchor marine and coastal economies by generating billions of dollars annually and supporting numerous jobs and businesses in the fishing, tourism, recreation, and scientific sectors;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas national marine sanctuaries drive economic growth by creating world renowned tourism destinations, promoting visitation, access, and outdoor recreation industries;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas national marine sanctuaries connect people and communities through recreation, science, education, and stewardship and inspire community-based solutions that help individuals understand and protect spectacular underwater habitats, wildlife, archaeological resources, and cultural seascapes of the United States;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas national marine sanctuaries are hubs for developing innovative technologies to improve resource management, power the ocean enterprise, and advance public-private partnerships;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas national marine sanctuaries can safeguard coastal communities from flooding and storms by increasing resilience;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas engaging communities as stewards of these shared waters makes national marine sanctuaries unique and provides a comprehensive, highly participatory approach to managing and conserving marine and Great Lakes environments for current and future generations;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas many of the greatest relics representing America’s past as a seafaring nation lie at the bottom of the sea and lakes in our national marine sanctuaries and as the United States approaches its 250th anniversary, the National Marine Sanctuary System offers a unique opportunity to honor history and heroes while celebrating underwater treasures; and</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas, October 23, 2025, is recognized as <quote>National Marine Sanctuary Day</quote> to celebrate our connection to America’s public waters in our ocean and Great Lakes that hold our shared maritime heritage and majestic wildlife and provide many recreational opportunities for the enjoyment of these treasured waters: Now, therefore, be it</text>
        </whereas>
    </preamble>
    <resolution-body style="traditional" id="HAF8D285149834FE489B93E9FBADA0771">
        <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H9ACE45DBBF7548638BB29114AA527FBF">
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="HE0C14591D74F4C74957B530D85E29B41"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>supports the designation of <quote>National Marine Sanctuary Day</quote>;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HE39C57CAC4B14CA99F265C5304FEA50F">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>encourages the people of the United States and the world to responsibly visit, experience, recreate in, and support the treasured national marine sanctuaries of the United States;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H88A355305BBA41E7BDBAD291058454DC">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>recognizes the importance of national marine sanctuaries for their recreational opportunities and contributions to local and national economies across the United States;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H3E666AED33D84553A935DAB338B1CEF2">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>acknowledges the importance of national marine sanctuaries for conservation, increasing access to our public waters, and cultural preservation;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H52AA6A3132904BD89870A2242B445FB2">
                <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text>celebrates the ability of the National Marine Sanctuary System to protect nationally significant places in the ocean and Great Lakes; and</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H98797A5D996349C083C48D1D7F9914DE">
                <enum>(6)</enum>
 <text>encourages Federal agencies to balance priorities and work together to support the priorities of the Marine Protection, Research, and Sanctuaries Act of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1401">33 U.S.C. 1401 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
            </paragraph>
        </section>
    </resolution-body>
</resolution>

