<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ELL25439-97X-S3-Y3D"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2188 IS: ATF Data and Anti-Trafficking Accountability Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2188</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250626" legis-day="20250624">June 26 (legislative day, June 24), 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the publication of data sets regarding firearm trace data.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HCA267479C8DC46D489001A865A7D8473"><section section-type="section-one" id="HB7B8577C0B3445BD9AC79F9B305AF2F0"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>ATF Data and Anti-Trafficking Accountability Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>ATF DATA Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H3585764ABAFE49EA868F40EFC9218348"><enum>2.</enum><header>Requiring the publication of data sets regarding firearm trace data</header><subsection id="H87FACC18C8EF42168ABC0FA1A892F7EE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaa12332f4350436e8b378f9540463490"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Bureau</header><text>The term <term>Bureau</term> means the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCF1AC8771DFC4279A3C054DCF36A715B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Firearm, importer, manufacturer, licensed manufacturer, dealer, handgun, rifle, shotgun</header><text>The terms <term>firearm</term>, <term>importer</term>, <term>manufacturer</term>, <term>licensed manufacturer</term>, <term>dealer</term>, <term>handgun</term>, <term>rifle</term>, and <term>shotgun</term> have the meanings provided the terms, respectively, in section 921(a) of title 18, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7CE131AFEB7C4703B75727C0539CED53"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Multiple sale</header><text>The term <term>multiple sale</term> means the sale or other disposition of 2 or more firearms at one time, or within 5 consecutive business days, that is required by law to be reported to the Attorney General.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd5f8e40cb09a481b8dea8defb59c9e24"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Covered period</header><text>The term <term>covered period</term> means the most recently completed calendar year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD9E6B6B8792F44BCA423676DC04D8A87"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Privately made firearm</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>privately made firearm</term> means a firearm that—</text><subparagraph id="H52D3D79AE6B2433D885BD309B1605826"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is assembled or otherwise made by a person other than a licensed manufacturer; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE91F5F5470E041AA869DBF99244E9B8C" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is not identified by means of a serial number or other mark engraved or cast on the receiver or frame by a licensed manufacturer or licensed dealer. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC706BF54B9144859AFB9900463D2F682"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Source licensee</header><text>The term <term>source licensee</term> means, with respect to a firearm, the person licensed under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/44">chapter 44</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, who made the initial sale of the firearm to an unlicensed person.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H88AC165B723047C9988B531347A0C6C9"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Source State</header><text>The term <term>source State</term> means, with respect to a firearm, the State or other territory of the United States where the initial retail sale of the firearm occurred.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8C9ACD57D9184FD59AEFAC6D1E0A6E0B"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Time-to-crime</header><text>The term <term>time-to-crime</term> means, with respect to a firearm, the length of time between the date of the initial retail sale of the firearm and the date of the trace request for the firearm. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H84618C523A66495BA387F7A894108804"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act and not less frequently than annually thereafter, the Attorney General, through the Bureau shall submit to Congress and make available to the public through electronic means a report that contains, at a minimum, the following information with respect to the covered period for which data is available:</text><paragraph id="H366510F2F226464799E0F68C7689B7A9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Aggregated firearm trace data collected by the Bureau during the covered period, disaggregated by the license type of the source licensee.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA6E7D1870F0846F099A052B7A743FE3B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A list of the 200 source licensees to whom the highest number of firearms were traced during the covered period, including—</text><subparagraph id="HC2884D417AB2454A8BFDE43169799399"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the aggregate number of firearms traced to each such licensee, disaggregated by handguns, rifles, and shotguns;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H318AF52A8C5A49D48A9A6BCF8367ECCC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the cities from which the firearms were recovered;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H45EB24E336404AC1A99EDC3AFF637451"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the average time-to-crime of the firearms traced to each such licensee;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4A87BF9B79B34561866FAD8B7DEFED42"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the categories, determined by the Attorney General, of crimes committed with the firearms traced to each such licensee, if such information is available;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H44D66291BFE3464597C96EED67FF87A6"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the number of traced firearms transferred by each licensee in any multiple sale; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H356A84BA2DAF49AC821CAA064EBB4E34"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the number of firearms traced to each licensee that the licensee reported, pursuant to section 923(g)(6) of title 18, United States Code, as lost or stolen.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H97DCE09F0E724473812930DDA67D0852"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Aggregated data for the covered period on—</text><subparagraph id="H2211A63672A54C3898C41A3F3CBF1DCB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the distribution among source licensees of the following, disaggregated by licensee type, by total number, by percentage, and by source State—</text><clause id="HE7E3F4453CBC409E99DFB3D3824C88D7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>0 or more traced firearms;</text></clause><clause id="H9AA56B91A91F43DE87E4B2866DB4C804"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>1 or more traced firearms;</text></clause><clause id="HF72967BAE4B34C33B59FDFF76B7DDBA0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>2 or more traced firearms;</text></clause><clause id="H45201B5A33CF4821B3CC88252C2BD319"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>5 or more traced firearms;</text></clause><clause id="H3BD5C48B203E481EB648384F66527CC2"><enum>(v)</enum><text>10 or more traced firearms;</text></clause><clause id="H9CBA69B696304397BCBF0B39288F4968"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>25 or more traced firearms; and</text></clause><clause id="HC6893662E29D4E979FAD991982E274D4"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>50 or more traced firearms; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4446959A8CB74A91AF89553CF05B8B5E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of source licensees with any firearms traces, disaggregated by State.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB16BF24DB8064987921B0236AF660575"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Aggregated firearm trace data for the covered period, disaggregated by the 50 Metropolitan Statistical Areas, as defined by the Office of Management and Budget, with the highest overall homicide rates, as determined by the Attorney General, for the covered period and by the 50 such areas with the highest per capita homicide rates, as so determined, for the covered period, as listed in the Federal Bureau of Investigation report, entitled <quote>Crime in the U.S.</quote>, covering the covered period or other national crime data used by the Bureau for the covered period, including—</text><subparagraph id="H294018174A1C4FAFAF3A07704F27BD26"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the total number of firearms recovered;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H07168DA829EE47E5BB37749D699DAB44"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number and percentage of firearms recovered from the 10 source States where the 10 greatest numbers of initial retail sales of the firearms occurred;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3BA70BAF364347D897B1880E21FB3CB8"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the 20 source licensees who made the 20 greatest numbers of initial retail sales of the firearms recovered;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE161754571C641488169670C423F8D81"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the number of recovered firearms traced to each of the 20 licensees referred to in subparagraph (C), further disaggregated by—</text><clause id="H180AC57D188E4AAF8E544AE55BF7670C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the average time-to-crime for the firearms traced to the licensee; and</text></clause><clause id="HEFFE969C8C114E76822FD44DCCA1CA54"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the number of firearms traced to the licensee with respect to which the time-to-crime was less than 3 years;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD1619E4AA9BE46058D7CA1254BCBF8D8"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the identities of the Federal, State, or local government agency that recovered the firearms;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H928768A523674625B873870D19DDF691"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the types of firearms recovered; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEB3D94AEBE30470896BC80168431AB03"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the total number of recovered firearms with a time-to-crime of—</text><clause id="H546994B8FFF44717B561CF43E53174CA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>less than 3 years;</text></clause><clause id="H1B887BEFDD5A4BD998210B4D5917815C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>less than 2 years; and</text></clause><clause id="H1B4B64E90C884855AC7E783A6B743941"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>less than 1 year.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDFD93B03F3844DCF80578892BEE3201A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Data, aggregated by State, related to the types of firearms traced during the covered period, including—</text><subparagraph id="H2EC3494FED6348B7A844DE2A15CEA01A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the category, as determined by the Attorney General, of crime leading to recovery, where the information is available;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCD8B20D1E00042E3B80149FD49C83996"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the 10 manufacturers who made the 10 greatest numbers of the firearms, the firearm models of the 10 greatest numbers of the firearms, the 10 most recovered finishes or colors of the firearms, and the 10 most recovered barrel lengths of the firearms; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC070742D527646608B73E0E3775F2A47"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the average time-to-crime for each subcategory, as determined by the Attorney General, of crime committed with the firearms.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H44E4732797224313BA8D0329031547CA"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The number of traced firearms sold as part of a multiple sale recovered during the covered period, disaggregated by State and by—</text><subparagraph id="H1AD4015546C347AB962565321D3CA355"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of—</text><clause id="HD0BD47164DA54B7682E5CCABF435080A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>handguns; and</text></clause><clause id="H0F4F0497EA894FA9B8CC009FB1E05E1C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>rifles the source State of which requires the reporting of rifle sales that are part of a multiple sale of rifles;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2E81455644814FE9B806ABB420E1F9AC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the average time-to-crime for the firearms; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H029780198F0445D3B402BEF4B74CAB24"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the percentage of the firearms recovered in the State in which initially purchased.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC814404360D448BC842AC67CF0A53C77"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The following data on traced firearms determined to have been lost by or stolen from a licensee during the covered period, disaggregated by State:</text><subparagraph id="H7DFB116D3B934FA2B1091172E87C8E9C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The number of the firearms, further disaggregated by licensee type.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBB549814E7DD48BBA708735B81B350CD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The number of the firearms, further disaggregated by average time-to-crime.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3D6C7E7A68BA4FB995FD3091586F6874"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The percentage of the firearms not reported by licensees as lost or stolen before the date of the trace request for the firearm involved.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H77C6484CF8F94ED9B08BAE5E6997F9FF"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The percentage of the firearms recovered in the State in which the business premises from which the source licensee conducts business subject to the license is located.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD8C0F646C0A94E7F85FBADB2F6BBDC2D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The number of licensees who have had 2 or more firearms lost or stolen in the 5 years preceding the covered period.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3DC031736DFB455EA36F6722ADE11FC9"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The number of firearms lost or stolen from licensees referred to in subparagraph (E).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H720742ADE95541989E4C9977F6C1F978"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number of reports of lost or stolen firearms filed by licensees referred to in subparagraph (E).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC5582DDCA67348F09302F2EBFDAB1FC4"><enum>(H)</enum><text>The number of incidents of theft or loss referred to in subparagraph (E) reported by licensees before the date of the trace request for the firearm involved.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H67DAF2957C4F458D9F346A5E730FD765"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The total number of privately made firearms recovered during the covered period, disaggregated by—</text><subparagraph id="H898BA30EF3E648FF98FC711106C1EE9D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the State in which the firearm was recovered;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAA3C63865C6045B7AE4253E25A36E9B9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the type of firearm; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5B06098BEA244427BEF84133207309A2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the firearm brand, if known.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD33F4FAE1A2D4B1BB8D2BB0771B511F0"><enum>(9)</enum><text>A list, disaggregated by whole number and by per capita, of—</text><subparagraph id="H8C73670F71B3431799F5AB3C433224B6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the 50 law enforcement agencies in the United States that requested the greatest number of firearm traces during the covered period; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3C4ED23884AF4CC6B1C00242B430868F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the 10 law enforcement agencies in the United States that requested the greatest number of traces per State during the covered period.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB96C0FB8A6FD4FD0989560E5055FC061"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The aggregate number of traces during the covered period of firearms with serial numbers engraved or cast on the receiver or frame of the firearm in accordance with section 923(i) of title 18, United States Code, that were recovered in a foreign country and submitted to the Bureau for tracing, disaggregated by—</text><subparagraph id="HB9E56CAE3F0644E3A53852366ABDBCAE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the foreign country in which they were recovered;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1F2C97F03F7B45ECAA221875E4A17762"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number and percentage that were originally purchased in the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE5E3A72F09DA41D6943B41110795ED9E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the average time-to-crime for the firearms;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCDE165A5ED0A4624A0A79C9119C420DF"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the number of firearms sold as part of a multiple sale; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD0248C6A5DCE4BB7BA0ACC169018A05D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the type of firearm.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9902EEAC84244E3FB6118DE32916265E"><enum>(11)</enum><text>An overview and analysis of—</text><subparagraph id="HCD1428030A9648BAA09769A63A0237ED"><enum>(A)</enum><text>firearms trafficking patterns in the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H748FF2E0362C477A84C995F9CE921582"><enum>(B)</enum><text>firearms trafficking investigations undertaken by the Department of Justice, including at a minimum—</text><clause id="H91AFF4FCEBBC4254AEA0EB050D515D97"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of firearms diverted from legal to illegal commerce by the targets of firearms trafficking investigations;</text></clause><clause id="H9212E89204B54CC995BB5B161A038CAC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a description of how the trafficking investigations were initiated, including the number and percentage that were initiated through—</text><subclause id="HE4A20CD809CA48AD96BFA0C278AFFFBE"><enum>(I)</enum><text>multiple sales records;</text></subclause><subclause id="H33029DB74B7B4FD6A9499BA44301CE7B"><enum>(II)</enum><text>crime gun trace data analysis;</text></subclause><subclause id="H3634AE8F5F564027AB7AB4F82D9C66B7"><enum>(III)</enum><text>inspections of licensees; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H287A97222D384D2F86613FE6502C636B"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>licensee reporting of lost or stolen firearms;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HF64CEE5A8F314860BFBB662EC7E29232"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the number and percentage of firearms trafficking investigations in which youth and juveniles were involved as possessors, straw purchasers, thieves, robbers, or traffickers;</text></clause><clause id="H4B43EF5921114A418ACC01AE5B8273CC"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a description of the crimes firearms traffickers were charged with, and convicted of, and the number of investigations that involved those crimes and defendants that were charged in those crimes; and</text></clause><clause id="H5A108CB61C1643EC826EE674D28C669F"><enum>(v)</enum><text>a breakdown by State of the number and percentage of firearms trafficking investigations; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5F7E2B10D4E141F681E49657B9984B10"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the role of sales by unlicensed individuals or entities in firearms trafficking, including sales facilitated—</text><clause id="H5563A5D4FF684505A51B76D3071A4650"><enum>(i)</enum><text>at gun shows; or</text></clause><clause id="H5799DD31DE6F4D07908A85341F2BFA6E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>through online forums.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

