<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H903321DD752046DAAF7FA02FF5B64831" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1477 IH: Animal Cruelty Enforcement Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1477</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250221">February 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000295">Mr. Joyce of Ohio</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="N000191">Mr. Neguse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001133">Mr. Ciscomani</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish an Animal Cruelty Crimes Section within the Department of Justice&#8217;s Environment and Natural Resources Division, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE68066F41B9E40D28814D9B6315F41D9" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HF346F391B5A3430CBEE8D88C0BF89BF9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Animal Cruelty Enforcement Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H46FB7CFEC8804445A6F767971A8FB31A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
<paragraph id="H4F354A233FBD4D75AF6265972AA76D0C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is a significant connection between animal cruelty and violence against humans, domestic violence, child abuse, sexual abuse, homicide, gang activity, drug trafficking, and other crimes.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE5829002CBB540B792FD5C43A63B4153" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Animal fighting activity may increase the spread of diseases transmitted between animals and people. </text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H37C9C269C2D544A2A1FDC8132E68C427"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A number of Federal laws have been enacted to address cruelty to animals.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6AE7EC645D314091AD60BCD4A63617EA"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Recognizing the connection between animal cruelty and serious crimes the Federal Bureau of Investigation tracks animal cruelty crimes.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HCAF45C55E4324F8DAC00C2201B8B3B6A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>There is bipartisan and widespread public support for addressing animal cruelty.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA4FF91824A2048D5A21ED71FAF873B86"><enum>(6)</enum><text>There is a government interest in ensuring laws are robustly enforced for the betterment and protection of society.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2B12073169934A24AC5E678BA95E0CCE"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The lack of a dedicated animal crimes enforcement unit within the Department of Justice has resulted in unacceptable delays in prosecutions, and an overall lack of prosecution, of animal crimes. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H14AC0E6277514B3EAAC9F456CE727C5A"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Dedicated staff and resources at the Department of Justice will facilitate successful enforcement of animal cruelty laws, which often have unique investigative elements, by providing specialized knowledge and focus, and streamlining the handling of these offenses.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="HD3FCDF98C31149E8B7EC782A9C0A5747"><enum>3.</enum><header>Animal Cruelty Crimes Section of the Department of Justice</header>
<subsection id="HC0CB24ED4D414CF795B5895245C8B418"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established an Animal Cruelty Crimes Section within the Department of Justice’s Environment and Natural Resources Division to enforce Federal laws prohibiting animal cruelty under the jurisdiction of the Department of Justice. </text></subsection> <subsection id="H30B15586FC374621A57B0E14E424AEA6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The purpose of the Animal Cruelty Crimes Section is to enforce Federal laws prohibiting animal cruelty under the jurisdiction of the Department of Justice and to vigorously pursue investigations and prosecutions under such laws. </text></subsection>
<subsection id="H37F06CC4FA184607B78E525202351A66"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Animal Cruelty Crimes Section shall coordinate with the Department of Agriculture, the Office of Inspector General of the Department of Agriculture, the Federal Bureau of Investigation, the United States Marshals Service, U.S. Customs and Border Protection, and other agencies, as appropriate.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H4F5B8597149B4EA2AC5E24400F891A59"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On the date that is one year after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Animal Cruelty Crimes Section shall submit to Congress a report on, for the previous year—</text>
<paragraph id="H71E89A9AED134E6D8C8ACF2A5D983E23"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the number of charges that were filed for violations of laws described in subsection (b), disaggregated by the law alleged to have been violated, the State in which the violation was alleged to have occurred, and the number of convictions; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB327FC2AA09A41B9AFB30BB462356812"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the number of investigations of violations of laws described in subsection (b) for which charges were not filed. </text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

