<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-BAG25F32-NT8-YD-4X3"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2506 IS: SkyFoundry Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code>II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2506</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250729">July 29, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S355">Mr. Cruz</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S343">Mr. Boozman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S374">Mr.
                    Cotton</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S287">Mr. Cornyn</cosponsor>)
                introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the
                    <committee-name committee-id="SSAS00">Committee on Armed
                    Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Secretary of Defense to establish and carry out a program to
            enable the rapid development, testing, and scalable manufacture of small unmanned
 aircraft systems, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="idfa5a1928732c4c0782f01cf9ca76db72" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>SkyFoundry Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idd3acbeae4fe14a3bb23aa5c41ef43e41"><enum>2.</enum><header>SkyFoundry Program</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id208e53ad1e674be1a209fd4461af85ca"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaeda37aa2ac242c8a4b9745924ab483c"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Program required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense shall establish and carry out a program to enable the rapid development, testing, and scalable manufacture of small unmanned aircraft systems, with potential expansion to associated energetics and other autonomous systems as determined by the Secretary.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9cdc60a866384f1798da29ae8e4d6344"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Designation</header><text>The program established pursuant to paragraph (1) shall be known as the <quote>SkyFoundry Program</quote> (in this section the <quote>Program</quote>).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idef721fc62e00429487b1a0259fde69f3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id35da71d4b7a9438e956b9aefb80491a8"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">administer the Program through the Secretary of the Army; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida4b6c508024d4af482a3364e728a57f6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>establish the Program as part of the Defense Industrial Resilience Consortium.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4aeb9a1fe1c94f57929f49ab78c2486d"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Alternative acquisition mechanism</header><text>In carrying out the Program, the Secretary shall leverage alternative acquisition mechanisms to accelerate development and production. Such mechanisms shall include the use of other transaction authority under section 4022 of title 10, United States Code, and the use of the middle tier of acquisition pathway for rapid prototyping and rapid fielding as authorized by section 3602 of such title.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id539381dcc249406282e25b273a13ec48"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Components</header><text>The Program shall have two components as follows:</text><paragraph id="id3558509b0bae487e89f63e5c80c497db"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Innovation facility</header><text>A Government-owned innovation facility for the development of small unmanned aircraft systems that is operated by the United States Army Materiel Command in coordination with United States Futures Command and serves as the research, development, and testing hub, integrating lessons learned from global conflicts to rapidly evolve United States small unmanned aircraft systems designs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6fadb2dbd32246eb9e1b599c3e3bcb6a"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Production facility</header><text>The Commander of United States Army Materiel Command shall identify a Government-owned production facility with the competencies for producing various forms of small unmanned aircraft systems. The facility shall be operated by United States Army Materiel Command and have the capability to produce 1,000,000 small unmanned aircraft systems annually once fully established.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id5f8e04dffe51424db37d43ec69b2e348"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Government-Owned Government-Operated Contractor Augmented Model</header><text>The Secretary may—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5fe3d6efd1e442098194bc02a42351e3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">enter into multiyear contracts or agreements for contractor augmented support to the Program, including integrating specialized contractor personnel within Program facilities as part of hybrid teams alongside military and civilian personnel; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaccc021ae0574114bfe8aafa39dd0fc6"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">enter into public-private partnership agreements with private industry, academic institutions, and nonprofit entities in support of the Program.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id83c0d1f539e14d868093d2cbe3f3cfeb"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Facilities and infrastructure</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id26b9850134e649e093acf1952ed328b9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the Program, the Secretary shall prioritize utilizing or modifying existing Army Depot facilities and select at least two separate sites for the Program, one to house the innovation facility required by subsection (b)(1) and one to house the production facility required by subsection (b)(2).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id14612124ac8d422087f6be086d772376"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authority to renovate, expand, and construct</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may renovate, expand, or construct facilities for the Program using available funds, notwithstanding <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/169">chapter 169</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcefa4c2fdc7c4ce498bb6c52232be071"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Selection of sites</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">When selecting sites for the Program, the Secretary shall consider that the production facility required by subsection (b)(2) shall be housed at an existing Army Depot that meets the following requirements:</text><subparagraph id="ide4bb287deb1748c289e6ba3244ef58e7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Army Depot shall be comprised of 15,000 acres of land.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id19a857ea0efb45c09a921a169d10aa9b"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Army Depot shall have approximately 10,000 buildable acres of land.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb8152db56224487e9605e00542a3a70c"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Army Depot shall have approximately 8,000,000 square feet of facilities.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb1c6db1e76004f2f85420610a3f16450"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The Army Depot shall be located within 50 miles of four States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id931675597aa54ffdaefb1f8abbc5c6e6"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Intellectual property rights</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that the United States retains appropriate intellectual property and technical data rights for any systems or technologies developed under the Program. At a minimum, the Secretary shall secure Government purpose rights in intellectual property developed jointly with contractors, to enable the Government’s continued production, sustainment, modification, and competitive procurement of such systems.</text></subsection><subsection id="idfeee19f91f574e70ab783b4a55cf7f1d"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Defense Production Act designation</header><text>The President (or the Secretary of Defense under delegated authority) shall utilize authorities under title III of the Defense Production Act of 1950 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4531">50 U.S.C. 4531 et seq.</external-xref>) to prioritize and support domestic industrial base capacity for small unmanned aircraft systems and associated energetics and autonomous systems. Such items shall be deemed essential for the national defense industrial base, and Title III efforts may include investments in production scale-up, establishment of strategic materials stockpiles, and surge manufacturing capacity for these systems and components.</text></subsection><subsection id="id8f9dc11dd5a243f8b329262388db42e9"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Expedited approvals and waivers</header><text>The Secretary, or the Secretary of the Army under explicit delegated authority, may expedite, and as appropriate to waive or modify Department of Defense regulatory requirements and internal procedures that would otherwise impede the rapid development, acquisition, or production activities of the Program.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


