<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD8B19C09A2DB4C1EA80FB82A24A6E177" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 262 IH: Establishing the Select Committee to Defeat the Mexican Drug Cartels.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 262</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250327">March 27, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001120">Mr. Crenshaw</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001199">Mr. Mast</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000590">Mr. Green of Tennessee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000375">Mr. Arrington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001072">Mr. Hill of Arkansas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001108">Mr. Comer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001053">Mr. Cole</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001157">Mr. McCaul</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000289">Mr. Jordan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001291">Mr. Babin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001213">Mr. Steil</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000591">Mr. Guest</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000467">Mr. Thompson of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000821">Mr. Westerman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000575">Mr. Rogers of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000816">Mr. Williams of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001295">Mr. Bost</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000546">Mr. Graves</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000558">Mr. Guthrie</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001302">Mr. Biggs of Arizona</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001133">Mr. Ciscomani</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000581">Mr. Vicente Gonzalez of Texas</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Committee on Rules</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Establishing the Select Committee to Defeat the Mexican Drug Cartels.</official-title></form><resolution-body style="OLC" id="HA5371310FB664EC6BA418A662ABAC462"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H7993C48A10E64B12A1083F3944508D2C"></section> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H5BCF4C6527FC44D4AAD063FDAFCE4043"></section> 
<section display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="section-one" id="H17C334E5C4134872BBE7E5A679094B5B"><enum>1.</enum><header>Select Committee to Defeat the Mexican Drug Cartels</header> 
<subsection id="HEEE44C00DCF24E4A9F5E3FFBFFD935FC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment; composition</header> 
<paragraph id="HBD1EBED81D2C48DF8AC81DD423A396AA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is hereby established in the House of Representatives a Select Committee to Defeat the Mexican Drug Cartels (hereinafter in this section referred to as the <quote>Select Committee</quote>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H478510AD2D884133850D0492DFBEDE6A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Composition</header> <subparagraph id="H7C828523D8994523A09C552E78BFDDC3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Select Committee shall be composed of not more than 21 Members, Delegates, or the Resident Commissioner appointed by the Speaker, not more than 10 of whom shall be appointed after consultation with the minority leader. The Speaker shall designate one member of the Select Committee as its chair. A vacancy in the membership of the Select Committee shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2C0E818AD0954093808E31932D81DCDB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Other committee assignments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Select Committee shall include at least one majority Member, delegate, or the resident commissioner from each of the following committees:</text> <clause id="HD4419552D80E4DF0AA4223CDC9C5906C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The Committee on Appropriations.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H899CB4D320AB4DDA8697261D1B832872"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Committee on the Judiciary.</text></clause> <clause id="HECBB91812E1D433689C7C1F1C66A5E97"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Committee on Homeland Security.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H3E276DF1AF084E1199571A7BBE128794"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The Committee on Armed Services.</text></clause> <clause id="H3734B5166D984E808959513BFDB6D1FF"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Committee on Financial Services.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H831CF54FE54B42318E20DFECFB9C2D0F"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Designation of leadership staff member</header><text>The Speaker and the minority leader each may designate a leadership staff member to assist in their capacity as ex officio members, with the same access to Select Committee meetings, hearings, briefings, and materials as employees of the Select Committee and subject to the same security clearance and confidentiality requirements as staff of the Select Committee.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF5AB543E27844E49915FEF6CD8E740FB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Jurisdiction; functions</header> <paragraph id="H356BDC93AD8D4CB3B84DD83F5B842CE3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Legislative jurisdiction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Select Committee shall not have legislative jurisdiction and shall have no authority to take legislative action on any bill or resolution.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H167725E794184DA0A334858FD15B9BB7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Investigative jurisdiction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The sole authority of the Select Committee shall be to investigate and submit policy recommendations on the operations and capabilities of the Mexican drug cartels, to include the international networks that facilitate and enable the Mexican drug cartels and the United States, Mexican, and other government efforts to target and defeat the cartels. The Select Committee may, at its discretion, hold public hearings in connection with any aspect of its investigative functions.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H82301FA51E9940179CBAD92786622B4A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Procedure</header> <paragraph id="HDF92EBB0F9CC43A1B7197F445ABE1C6F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Clause 11(b)(4), clause 11(e), and the first sentence of clause 11(f) of rule X shall apply to the Select Committee. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD5990F9F131C4F1ABF26869D161BFCDA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Except as specified in paragraph (4), the Select Committee shall have the authorities and responsibilities of, and shall be subject to the same limitations and restrictions as, a standing committee of the House, and shall be deemed a committee of the House for all purposes of law or rule.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2CAFA6D8413B4C9E8CE0A381CB040363"><enum>(3)</enum> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HBC1C918466A84D53BFEE26708FE7FF5F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Rules X and XI shall apply to the Select Committee where not inconsistent with this subsection.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H678A42E2791644F8AFB7C63E4CCB8EB2" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Service on the Select Committee shall not count against the limitations in clause 5(b)(2) of rule X.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H29A2A7AE4BCE4E608D86D6A4BEBAF25C" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Clause 2(d) of rule X shall not apply to the Select Committee.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB3191D83E0FD476882B1FBF484C7D26E" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Clause 2(g)(2)(D) of rule XI shall apply to the Select Committee in the same manner as it applies to the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H3C6950C4932042F6905206A1F6132466"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Records; staff; travel; funding</header> <paragraph id="H7F2241A0057D47B0A144B915D9502407"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The appointment and the compensation of staff for the Select Committee shall be subject to regulations issued by the Committee on House Administration.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7505749AA0024175AE2D9B0E7E90719D"><enum>(2)</enum> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HEACFE57597DB4E48AD1805FACAAED045"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Staff of employing entities of the House or a joint committee may be detailed to the Select Committee to carry out this resolution and shall be deemed to be staff of the Select Committee.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1BAE9A78723F4701ADF0065CF0CC751C" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Select Committee may request the head of any Federal agency to detail, on a nonreimbursable basis, any of the personnel of the agency to the Select Committee. </text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3F420ABED5654688A2D637AAA632C0A5" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 202(i) of the Legislative Reorganization Act of 1946 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/4301">2 U.S.C. 4301(i)</external-xref>) shall apply with respect to the Select Committee in the same manner as such section applies with respect to a standing committee, except that the selection of any consultant or organization under such section shall be subject to approval by the Speaker.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H6FA5954CFD9345D9AC66D30AF08967C3"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Select Committee may report to the House or any committee from time to time the results of its investigations and studies, together with such detailed findings, policy recommendations, and legislative proposals as it may deem advisable. All such reports shall be submitted to the House by December 31, 2026. All policy recommendations shall be submitted to the relevant standing committees not later than December 31, 2025. The Select Committee shall submit all legislative proposals to the relevant standing committees not later than 60 days after their adoption by the Select Committee.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF44EE13E77EC42469EC17891D4530094"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Publication</header> 
<paragraph id="H141C26BB63FF4DE69875A963A13D05FE"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Select Committee shall ensure that reports and proposals prepared in accordance with this subsection shall, upon completion, be made available to the general public in widely accessible formats not later than 30 calendar days following the respective dates for completion set forth in subsection (e).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF69A032C41B54DFEBC4DB5B85E1432C2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Any report issued by the Select Committee shall be issued in unclassified form but may include a classified annex, a law enforcement-sensitive annex, or both.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

