<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4BBF9EEA40FC432B8B23C03FFA82FCFC" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4219 IH: National Wildlife Refuge System Invasive Species Strike Team Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4219</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250627">June 27, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001055">Mr. Case</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001219">Mr. Moylan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of the Interior to establish the National Wildlife Refuge System Invasive Species Strike Team Program.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H54FFD02EC885403CB2433D1711BAE594" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H39B629CC566948318E728E2457905A9B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>National Wildlife Refuge System Invasive Species Strike Team Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H66391E1BBE6B43ACBBA155E0DA48EF34"><enum>2.</enum><header>National Wildlife Refuge System Invasive Species Strike Team Program</header> <subsection id="H883746524BCD4FDBA6581C25110A5B68"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The purpose of this Act is to legislatively authorize the National Wildlife Refuge System Invasive Species Strike Team Program within the United States Fish and Wildlife Service to eradicate, control, and reduce the adverse effects of invasive species on and adjacent to National Wildlife Refuge System lands and waters, primarily through prevention, biosecurity, early detection, and rapid response.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H860F82F1EA6C406F8B5EDA6973CB4CA8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Invasive Species Strike Team Program</header> 
<paragraph id="H11DEE89FCFD941888448B23C90742C8D" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall carry out a program to identify and respond to priority invasive species threats within and adjacent to National Wildlife Refuge System lands and waters in coordination with partners, to be known as the <quote>National Wildlife Refuge System Invasive Species Strike Team Program</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5D55C0FB4FDF4765BDF2D6C836E882C1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>In carrying out the Program, the Secretary shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H3791A04A515C4B6BA9A266732AC3621E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish at least 1 invasive species strike team within each region of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service trained in early detection and rapid response for multiple invasive species taxa to—</text> <clause id="HE8FB7B53A49A4F14BBB98A3193C58EC6"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conserve, manage, and, where appropriate, restore, habitat conditions that help native biological communities flourish on and adjacent to National Wildlife Refuge System lands and waters;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA0B8837155CE4F488539876E9DB66733"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>conduct prevention, early detection surveillance, eradication, containment, mapping, monitoring, and active management of invasive species;</text></clause> <clause id="HE348B5F6D8D94F459271C66976AFE646"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>use integrated pest management techniques and tools;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H95C6A5CF5368468AA3A9B94155492C43"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>conduct inreach and outreach, including trainings and table-top exercises, including on the use of the Incident Command System, as part of their planning and operations; and</text></clause> <clause id="HD49EBE12A75B484081EB841800E8CDC5"><enum>(v)</enum><text>use risk assessments, research, innovations, management outcomes, monitoring, and evaluation to improve the effectiveness of detection and response activities;</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H954E173DA0E144B4902B1E0D80DA9651"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">engage in partnerships and collaborations with—</text> <clause id="H784FA18345444DE7A916AFA5B1E1CD88"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Federal, State, Tribal, and local governments;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HAE33B8715CED48E09760330C959AD413"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>nongovernmental institutions;</text></clause> <clause id="HBFD311D3F4274C3289C1571DC8F5E7B0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>nonprofit organizations; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H9D42B891C79F436A8F099A0319943F62"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>private individuals and entities to advance mutual priorities and promote efficiency and cost-savings;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDF24BB85FB8A400F8A31AB96CE465976"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">collaborate in the development of a set of consistent taxonomy standards and work with others to implement such standards among all Department of the Interior databases; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0CFF3011C9CB4679A2D44319C39E0341"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">utilize national and regional standardized reporting platforms, such as—</text> <clause id="H1DBC3917202F492F81AFF1453E0AFAC5"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the National Agricultural Pest Information System;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HEC93CA47C28B48B49FC1D15E100D1C62"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the National Data Repository of the National Plant Diagnostic Network;</text></clause> <clause id="H2B77BF4AF4FB4D4580972D9A79FB6729"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the Early Detection and Distribution Mapping System;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H6F9D4B2000D34FAFBBECA34F9470F618"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the Nonindigenous Aquatic Species Database of the United States Geological Survey;</text></clause> <clause id="H4B17DCA010514B378FB95179E8D8C76D"><enum>(v)</enum><text>iMapInvasives; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H8D0C3EDF04AE48038A293C74CE33621B"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>State databases.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEAEF94B6DB2C43EAA5B167D73794C808"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Provision of assistance</header><text>In carrying out the Program, the Secretary is authorized to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF2FA98B8E95646F4B42DBD18A74BCF51"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conduct outreach to Federal, State, Territorial, local, and Tribal governments, nongovernmental institutions, nonprofit organizations, and private individuals and entities to address the management of property adjacent to a unit of the National Wildlife Refuge System, including providing or entering into, upon request—</text> <clause id="HEDDD4C9C661D47EB9D74AA8D8979D6AA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>financial assistance, including direct expenditures;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HC5850806446743C1AC126D5EE05058C4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>technical assistance;</text></clause> <clause id="HBE31CE6EC86C4C0FACEEA360CAF81720"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>contracts; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="HAD736C1439A34BA6A612943AC1E630FB"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">grants or cooperative agreements; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H32F6DC759E3845CCBEACB0D9329E436C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">upon the request of another Federal department or agency or a State, Tribal, or Territorial agency, enter into an agreement within the mission and authorities of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service with such department or agency to provide the expertise and use of invasive species strike teams established under paragraph (2) to respond to invasive species under the jurisdiction of such department or agency, or to rapidly respond to a newly detected invasive species.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6ED92E1279D345B0A9162092D5222B2D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Coordination of management actions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall encourage the National Wildlife Refuge System to coordinate invasive species management actions of each Invasive Species Strike Team with adjacent landowners and the State agencies within the State of which Invasive Species Strike Team activities may occur.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H984C4A65E88C4E07A0EE37A58EDFB3CC"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Report</header> <subparagraph id="HB84A46C95CDB4A3F8A161FC5FD38ED20"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Appropriations and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Appropriations and the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate, and make available to the public on the website of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, a report regarding the Program 2 years after enactment and 5 years after enactment.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H85F37E00720E46888831121D7B424F62"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Contents of report</header><text>Each report submitted under subparagraph (A) shall include—</text> <clause id="H9DA72481E8014784B38D04B23BA8E2A6"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a summary of each Invasive Species Strike Team’s work to address priority invasive species within the National Wildlife Refuge System; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H6B1BF59383184434A08A94908413DE34"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">progress made by the Program toward the prevention, detection, control, or eradication of each priority invasive species.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HCE010EEBCC0F4B48983CE268FBCD9CD0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this section $15,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4ADD3483D12D42EEA8C776FE5B57E947"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H6B91E6CD3AA14A778CA3003445D14FA5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Invasive species</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>invasive species</term> means, with regard to a particular ecosystem, a non-native organism whose introduction causes or is likely to cause economic or environmental harm or harm to human, animal, or plant health.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3B89E44A8FD34924BAE0E3A3982285D3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Early detection</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>early detection</term> means a process of surveying for, reporting, and verifying the presence of a non-native species before the founding population becomes established or spreads so widely that eradication is no longer feasible.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H02AED590ABEE44E292773EF2786FE377"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Priority invasive species</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>priority invasive species</term> means an invasive species that is a major concern and necessary to map, monitor, and manage based on the following factors:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD4CCABDCF3274AC8A49A30A0847056BD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Potential impact on other native species.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD58F2D799DD841DFB59CFA2DB8842478"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Ability to alter habitats.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5DD9FC01B139441AAD9A68F93308DFD5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Ability to harm human health.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9728E14F9C3649F49A03901964791E58"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Severity of economic impact.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE96201F0DE0D4DF1938A55BD858BCC05"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Program</term> means the National Wildlife Refuge System Invasive Species Strike Team Program authorized under subsection (b)(1).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDCD9960F80444A2DA6E933F073FA03AE"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3E307E7B05494DA2A95FDC38FD04796E" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, and each territory and possession of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

