<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H94A82AB839A0405B8DB01916B5A7C207" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4074 IH: Optimizing Postpartum Outcomes Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4074</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250623">June 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="T000482">Mrs. Trahan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to issue guidance on coverage under the Medicaid program under title XIX of the Social Security Act of certain pelvic health services furnished during the postpartum period, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H48BA68B4E8104E18B62BB006FE476573" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H52D6821B3C37413593752F506DE9AB0D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Optimizing Postpartum Outcomes Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H96786FF4BA1D4A82A667DD5E876AC76E"><enum>2.</enum><header>CMS guidance</header> <subsection id="H9C56D78C6683463B840E3DA18A049D28"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall issue guidance on coverage under State plans (or waivers of such plans) under the Medicaid program under title XIX of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396">42 U.S.C. 1396 et seq.</external-xref>) or State child health plans (or waivers of such plans) under the Children’s Health Insurance Program under title XXI of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1397aa">42 U.S.C. 1397aa et seq.</external-xref>) of covered pelvic health services furnished during the prenatal or postpartum period. Such guidance shall include—</text>
                <paragraph id="H14096E95D79D406A853742CFF5E11510">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>best practices from States with respect to innovative or evidenced-based payment models to increase access to covered pelvic health services;</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HABD89DDFC5374DF8AA3925327CCA8DD1">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommendations for States on available financing options under—</text>
                    <subparagraph id="H3107E507A9124D9E953D0067B1E40374">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>the Medicaid program under title XIX of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396">42 U.S.C. 1396 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="HB3D9AF6660EB441281319FC3B269AA89">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>the Children’s Health Insurance Program under title XXI of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1397aa">42 U.S.C. 1397aa et seq.</external-xref>), specifically funds made available through a Children’s Health Insurance Program Health Services Initiative;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HC2115DF10DC544198D032BD524446D8F">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">guidance and technical assistance to State agencies responsible for administering State plans (or waivers of such plans) under the Medicaid program under title XIX of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396">42 U.S.C. 1396 et seq.</external-xref>) regarding additional flexibilities and incentives related to screening and referral for, and access to, covered pelvic health services; and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H154BD453281D486DB3EAEF9AEDD793D3">
                    <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">guidance regarding suggested terminology and diagnosis codes, such as the International Classification of Diseases code set, to identify women with pelvic floor dysfunction and disorders.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
<subsection id="H0D90519600ED42E791A689CA748D608F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>GAO study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a study on, and submit to Congress a report that addresses, gaps in coverage for—</text> <paragraph id="H99B8072396334F41ADEF1DC1E636F1FD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>covered pelvic health services under State plans (or waivers of such plans) under the Medicaid program under title XIX of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396">42 U.S.C. 1396 et seq.</external-xref>) for postpartum women; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H875EA72A8EC9491EA4F9103077EE8E86"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">other services for postpartum women who received medical assistance under a State plan (or a waiver of such plan) under the Medicaid program under title XIX of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396">42 U.S.C. 1396 et seq.</external-xref>) during their pregnancy.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H7244F71A6B8E41F7B059DD88863817DE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text>
<paragraph id="H3A852D9389A14E669DF225F60409FEB1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>postpartum period</term> means the longer of the period of lactation or the 6-month period beginning on the last day of a woman’s pregnancy.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD5F8B78A50F140649172380A74A9091B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>covered pelvic health services</term> means—</text>
<subparagraph id="HC2F7F58074C64B24AF8D666187C9602F">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">pelvic floor examinations (as defined in section 317L–2 of the Public Health Service Act, as added by section 2 of this Act); and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H7CC710EB5927440E96949255A66BF191"><enum>(B)</enum><text>pelvic health physical therapy (as defined in such section 317L–2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H51098FE9DD0540248FD32C841BC99866"><enum>3.</enum><header>Postpartum pelvic health education campaign</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part B of title III of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/243">42 U.S.C. 243 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 317L–1 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/247b-13a">42 U.S.C. 247b–13a</external-xref>) the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HCED205823F8A469FB2480C86AD530BFF" display-inline="no-display-inline">
<section id="H46847925C93A47B2993B4B0F5A5082AD"><enum>317L–2.</enum><header>Postpartum pelvic health education campaign</header>
<subsection id="H13DC1A7B37B24C8BA770B1F5D28DA43E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, in collaboration with the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration and the heads of other agencies, and in consultation with appropriate health professional associations, shall develop and carry out a program—</text> <paragraph id="H6D2F3D0710DD4D7E8B633CCC83ABCCB4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to educate and train health professionals on pelvic floor examinations and the benefits of pelvic health physical therapy; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF5551502F9414C49A2FE9E734F21F56E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to educate postpartum women on—</text> <subparagraph id="H29FD63DEC2D4483FABC0931E0F4706B9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>with respect to pelvic floor examinations—</text>
<clause id="HC736E36F894140ABA45D5D37B43F25D9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the importance of such examinations during the postpartum period;</text></clause> <clause id="HCC6EEC9DA7D448EAA18F45010574E4FC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>how to obtain such an examination, including information relating to obtaining referrals; and</text></clause>
<clause id="HC747BD3559554E408D373C827CDBA05E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>what is involved in such an examination; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H177EF4F5634C4810A01C1A56CB75A945"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to pelvic health physical therapy—</text>
<clause id="H2B99E2CCF3724AB7B823C867CF5FE4B6"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the benefits of, and availability of such physical therapy; and</text></clause> <clause id="H139B96D196C14CBD8A60269A58E22622"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>how to obtain a referral for such physical therapy.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HD23638616D3246F1977205A845735C7D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HCD01DEAB4B7049E8B69B21C77B19DEB7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>pelvic floor examination</term> means an examination to assess a patient for pelvic health related conditions that is composed of—</text>
<subparagraph id="H384EB15571FF4982BF098AF8959F8188"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an external evaluation that includes analysis of posture, joint integrity, muscle performance, quality of movement, and palpation and observation of the pelvic floor; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H37BF1E8144024FF88F419847F2FD2354"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if deemed necessary based on the health care professional’s clinical reasoning, an internal vaginal or rectal examination, or both, to gather relevant information about the tone, strength, control, ability to contract and relax the muscles of the pelvic floor individually and together, the condition of the surrounding fascia, and the position of the organs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H278A6766542848DEAEF4B38E0A062B28"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>pelvic health physical therapy</term> means a personalized physical therapy plan implemented by a pelvic health physical therapist, after performing a pelvic floor examination and making a diagnosis, that is based on best available evidence to improve the patient condition, with respect to the anatomy of the pelvic floor, improve mobility, recover from injury, prevent future injury, and manage pain and chronic conditions.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9026EFEAE9544E6B851F911DA2D97026"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>pelvic health related condition</term> includes urinary dysfunction, bowel dysfunction, musculoskeletal dysfunction, sexual dysfunction, cancer-related rehabilitation, and the pre-partum state and pre-partum conditions.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H9AFF2B64BF8D4E9D98E72A0539453B10"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $2,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> </legis-body></bill>

