<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-EHF25092-LN9-G0-H0S"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S323 IS: Proper Leadership to Align Networks for Broadband Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">ii</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 323</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250129">January 29, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S318">Mr. Wicker</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S409">Mr. Luján</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S422">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To direct the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Communications and Information to develop a National Strategy to Synchronize Federal Broadband Programs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="H810647F6DC4240DC9DE0D94B709BF058"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Proper Leadership to Align Networks for Broadband Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>PLAN for Broadband Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="ida45509a3704f4ec9a66798727a330455"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="id22e43664c40b4a0abb70f09fc6e788ab"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of Congress</header><text>The term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="id86870a3cc0174f05b5431c4bb2d31120"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id51dcef2bfceb43c3914acf9ed908dd87"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9dc7722b62054c1f98ea8b6dacf7615a"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Assistant Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Assistant Secretary</term> means the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Communications and Information.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8c0ee7d5a4964d11a806ad61cb664378"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Broadband internet access service</header><text>The term <term>broadband internet access service</term> has the meaning given the term in section 8.1(b) of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor regulation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6baa235fb7e042a28546f5c51185babb"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Covered agencies</header><text>The term <term>covered agencies</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="id8061aa601591475e8d3c80c564a5cce0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Federal Communications Commission;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id254d3d66f5ef484cab32f44a25db0123"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Department of Agriculture;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2e4f0ea4c0164e46baa67252f387affe"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the National Telecommunications and Information Administration;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idef15e2ad09b5453ebce780f3630afd14"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Department of Health and Human Services;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida0d63c06db844aa8b7c66a873064e28e"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the Appalachian Regional Commission;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6d6f1c04421944f0b7aa3cb81b6e201a"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the Delta Regional Authority;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf20888b1bde44466b1c45cb1aae8c236"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the Denali Commission;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5a6ecd9181db47249375cad6925ed63f"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Economic Development Administration;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8ff0c0a238a64f969d6e80ce3ca3ca9f"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the Department of Education;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5e85f4f1d14d48c29bce3eea4a6341c4"><enum>(J)</enum><text>the Department of the Treasury;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id194d2f06e1b34d31a6537f0b83b69db0"><enum>(K)</enum><text>the Department of Transportation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1fd3c64b42c9417abed25d1167ec312d"><enum>(L)</enum><text>the Institute of Museum and Library Services;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5227c98e425c435abe7db160d3153235"><enum>(M)</enum><text>the Northern Border Regional Commission;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddc44e5dd9d17402f844cf324dd189c09"><enum>(N)</enum><text>the Department of Housing and Urban Development; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id71f64357fc584876a41b84ec39a18e83"><enum>(O)</enum><text>the Department of the Interior.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ida8c54cd3157c45c687483f0c930522a2"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Deployment Locations Map</header><text>The term <term>Deployment Locations Map</term> has the meaning given the term in section 60105(a) of the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1704">47 U.S.C. 1704(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id307d5dd320d54db18f1e75f5cd2f4b63"><enum>(6)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Federal broadband program</header><text>The term <term>Federal broadband program</term> means any program administered by a covered agency that is directly or indirectly intended to increase the deployment of, access to, the affordability of, or the adoption of broadband internet access service.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id33ad3e8c87364720bc4894a1d7d5b591"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Federal land management agency</header><text>The term <term>Federal land management agency</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="id60c6f126a6964982ae063a34519ef85e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the National Park Service;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id502555b424354666812129c474ccee3d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Bureau of Land Management;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idaa0ce81999494554825aa60eb5a963f3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Bureau of Reclamation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida3a728c82a64410e8d620058207b9240"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the United States Fish and Wildlife Service;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd2d4d6cf4de943c58c397b7488772516"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the Bureau of Indian Affairs; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7e0981b1c1ba4bebb7212e0f0e37da6a"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the Forest Service.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idb5e5a6e4e7114969bbb1500412086944"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Implementation plan</header><text>The term <term>Implementation Plan</term> means the implementation plan developed under section 4(a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddfdc3a6cb1e7493a922ca5684b31a7f1"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Strategy</header><text>The term <term>Strategy</term> means the National Strategy to Synchronize Federal Broadband Programs developed under section 3(a).</text></paragraph></section><section id="id7bff71a6e6524606acb7f4f5c99ecbda"><enum>3.</enum><header>National strategy to synchronize Federal broadband programs</header><subsection id="idcf63265657ad44d892fcca927926cb4f"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Assistant Secretary, in consultation with the covered agencies, shall develop and submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a National Strategy to Synchronize Federal Broadband Programs to—</text><paragraph id="id6dab1a3333d044dc9e15fd78e2c2be25"><enum>(1)</enum><text>support better management of Federal broadband programs to deliver on the goal of providing access to high-speed, affordable broadband internet access service to all individuals in the United States, while ensuring that funding for Federal broadband programs is used in the most efficient and fiscally responsible manner;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8260ac1b83b048abb63bca7f7395acee"><enum>(2)</enum><text>synchronize interagency coordination among covered agencies for Federal broadband programs;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd448536d605f48d48c199b8cfdd874ba"><enum>(3)</enum><text>synchronize interagency coordination regarding the process for approving the grant of any permit, easement, right of way, or lease to, in, over, or on a building or any other property owned by the Federal Government for the right to install, construct, modify, or maintain infrastructure with respect to broadband internet access service; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idddc05cb1c5e44cb19d0bac1c1a54c22f"><enum>(4)</enum><text>reduce unnecessary barriers, eliminate unnecessary costs, and ease administrative burdens to participate in Federal broadband programs.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idc077dded94e74fbfb08d42f32e98704a"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The Strategy shall—</text><paragraph id="idfafc8636b5ba48ae820ecd2b7f15daa4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>list all—</text><subparagraph id="idee60236f3453498db8ee4375db0f03af"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Federal broadband programs; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb188eccfec3c486a80f5916e09f08bbe"><enum>(B)</enum><text>programs that exist at the State and local levels that are directly or indirectly intended to increase the deployment of, access to, the affordability of, or the adoption of broadband internet access service;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id7c8c6006a5144558b547fbbd04e37037"><enum>(2)</enum><text>describe current, as of the date on which the Strategy is submitted, Federal efforts to coordinate Federal broadband programs;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id238aa763653b4f8f8b3f861c321aa323"><enum>(3)</enum><text>identify gaps and limitations, including laws, regulations, and covered agency policies and practices, that hinder, or may hinder, coordination across Federal broadband programs;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0e84c8d5c8354a46bf3f43891ad81a09"><enum>(4)</enum><text>establish clear roles and responsibilities for the covered agencies, as well as clear goals, objectives, and performance measures, for—</text><subparagraph id="id6316eaab764340f19724cff0d067e9b4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the management of all Federal broadband programs; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3f4555f050574aec8b8665539074576c"><enum>(B)</enum><text>interagency coordination efforts with respect to Federal broadband programs;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ida511ed45656f4320a89f2fae68bde854"><enum>(5)</enum><text>address the cost of the Strategy, the sources and types of resources and investments needed to carry out the Strategy, and where those resources and investments should be targeted based on balancing risk reductions with costs;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbef82b889fb04eb8ac13d4fec3bae3f6"><enum>(6)</enum><text>address factors that increase the costs and administrative burdens of participation in Federal broadband programs, including with respect to access to infrastructure necessary for deployment of broadband internet access service;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc885b1942217414d97c992e86272ead0"><enum>(7)</enum><text>report information on the effectiveness of each Federal broadband program in terms of how many locations received broadband internet access service or other assistance under each Federal broadband program;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc209e1d115844191a9ef476b11163e43"><enum>(8)</enum><text>address the extent to which covered agency policies and practices do or do not establish a technologically neutral program;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id614dda886534476ca755d65b89d98492"><enum>(9)</enum><text>recommend incentives, legislative solutions, and administrative actions to help State, local, and Tribal governments more efficiently—</text><subparagraph id="id9d3d11494fbc4ede927dff95a6182e4e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>distribute, and effectively administer, funding received from Federal broadband programs and avoid duplication of— </text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc388691ec2a54029a5bd62a166f7c87d"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">existing infrastructure with respect to broadband internet access service; and </text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id85dacdc2882145ebac5086819f95d5e0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">funded projects with respect to broadband internet access service or such projects otherwise subject to enforceable deployment obligations;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id36377c2cde8945e3b9cae86903e68590"><enum>(B)</enum><text>resolve conflicts with respect to the funding described in subparagraph (A); </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id714e87b714d8410c9410982b0a40a933"><enum>(C)</enum><text>use the Deployment Locations Map as a key resource in carrying out subparagraphs (A) and (B); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idcd99b66458414901bf272e2a28d6bcb8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>promote access to infrastructure or rights of way necessary for deployment of broadband internet access service, whether privately or government owned or cooperatively organized for broadband communications; </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1116f3b0900e4a21b0a77648d16903c5"><enum>(10)</enum><text>recommend incentives, legislative solutions, and administrative actions to—</text><subparagraph id="idc091e7180a1f40ce89fa410bd7c91714"><enum>(A)</enum><text>improve the coordination and management of Federal broadband programs; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idff4589650ff24d6994e3859bd7016f43"><enum>(B)</enum><text>eliminate duplication with respect to Federal broadband programs and non-Federal programs with respect to broadband internet access service;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide28a1e9de7174870ad0a32fff15cf607"><enum>(11)</enum><text>describe current, as of the date on which the Strategy is submitted, efforts by covered agencies, Federal land management agencies, and State, local, and Tribal governments to streamline the process for granting a permit or access to an easement, right of way, or lease to, in, over, or on a building or any other property owned or controlled by a government for the right to install, construct, modify, or maintain infrastructure with respect to broadband internet access service;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf7e5153cc6164f628dcc9f89ff4d8c92"><enum>(12)</enum><text>identify gaps and limitations with respect to allowing regional, interstate, or cross-border economic development organizations to participate in Federal broadband programs;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5d743333e4f240ada1e667e258b1bc7b"><enum>(13)</enum><text>address specific issues relating to closing the gap on Tribal lands with respect to broadband internet access service; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd9aaeb91d27a4243ba33f1710e588e5a"><enum>(14)</enum><text>identify measures to prevent fraud and misuse of amounts made available to carry out Federal broadband programs, ensure accountability for the use of such funding, and implement effective reporting requirements to measure the success of Federal broadband programs.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ida3cc0c20e8c8427a92e450436081c3a3"><enum>4.</enum><header>Implementation plan</header><subsection id="id3d17f51624eb4f2ab0eec1cc6020b4fb"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date on which the Assistant Secretary submits the Strategy to the appropriate committees of Congress under section 3(a), the Assistant Secretary shall develop and submit to the appropriate committees of Congress an implementation plan for the Strategy.</text></subsection><subsection id="id70638ef49005483f8845094eb7bfd82f"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Implementation plan</header><text>The Implementation Plan shall, at a minimum—</text><paragraph id="id1f8076ba7c0d4a65b29d1f6c0e302b46"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide a plan for implementing the roles, responsibilities, goals, objectives, and performance measures for the management of Federal broadband programs and interagency coordination efforts identified in the Strategy;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd91dbabc0933445c9f42cafa9a063a43"><enum>(2)</enum><text>if the Strategy identifies policy and practices that result in programmatic differences among covered agencies with respect to Federal broadband programs, provide a plan to streamline and create consistent policies and practices across all covered agencies for the purposes of Federal broadband programs;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4e079dbfddf94f59a810444822f161bd"><enum>(3)</enum><text>for Federal broadband programs that are not technologically neutral, determine a ceiling on the amount of a subsidy or funding award to provide broadband internet access service to a single location, to be consistently applied and adopted by all covered agencies for the funding of infrastructure with respect to broadband internet access service;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id343a11aed91b40749b89f03d52f8a4fb"><enum>(4)</enum><text>provide a plan for holding the covered agencies accountable for the roles, responsibilities, goals, objectives, and performance measures identified in the Strategy;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id522795fbc25c4197a5ec14476a5ccc33"><enum>(5)</enum><text>describe the roles and responsibilities of the covered agencies, and the interagency mechanisms, to coordinate the implementation of the Strategy;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6f08c6f085e14b1fbb80bbf30160c1d1"><enum>(6)</enum><text>provide a plan for coordination among Federal broadband programs and for permitting processes for infrastructure with respect to broadband internet access service;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id093b4cff7af64a2780294bf4652e6ec0"><enum>(7)</enum><text>provide a plan for regular evaluation and public reporting of Federal broadband programs against clear objectives and performance measures, permitting processes for infrastructure with respect to broadband internet access service, and progress in implementing the Strategy;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idadb79fd0703d4227845ce60f7b786279"><enum>(8)</enum><text>with respect to the awarding of Federal funds or subsidies to support the deployment of broadband internet access service, provide a plan for the adoption of—</text><subparagraph id="id54ca96ad79c74f9e8e6e8b6929ea94e7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>common data sets regarding those awards, including a requirement that covered agencies use the maps created under title VIII of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/641">47 U.S.C. 641 et seq.</external-xref>) and the Deployment Locations Map;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3bd083ae3c4d45e7adc2107e10aa4ef9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>applications regarding those awards, as described in section 903(e) of the ACCESS BROADBAND Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1307">47 U.S.C. 1307(e)</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4d2980a1fbce4381a613b08165436eba"><enum>(C)</enum><text>rules for prohibiting awards by covered agencies in areas identified as served by the maps created under title VIII of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/641">47 U.S.C. 641 et seq.</external-xref>) or in areas already subject to an award or enforceable deployment obligations by a covered agency under a Federal broadband program or a State, local, or Tribal program with respect to broadband internet access service;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id757d7e2677bd4496ae66e55c3f58fde6"><enum>(9)</enum><text>provide a plan to monitor, publicly report, and reduce waste, fraud, and abuse in Federal broadband programs, including wasteful spending resulting from fragmented, overlapping, and duplicative programs;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd7f85ab41fd14d7a91953f4893dc6195"><enum>(10)</enum><text>require consistent obligation and expenditure reporting by covered agencies for Federal broadband programs, which shall be consistent with section 903(c)(2) of the ACCESS BROADBAND Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1307">47 U.S.C. 1307(c)(2)</external-xref>) and the Deployment Locations Map;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7dcb25c2b7214b4585b2275c6ebf26e1"><enum>(11)</enum><text>provide a plan to increase awareness of, and participation in, Federal broadband programs relating to the affordability and adoption of broadband internet access service; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbf3237c61cb440adaf3f337204066f4d"><enum>(12)</enum><text>describe the administrative and legislative action that is necessary to carry out the Strategy.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id6953cfe1844f46a48bf4cac7aeb02ac0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Public comment</header><text>In developing the Implementation Plan, the Assistant Secretary shall publish a draft version of the Implementation Plan in the Federal Register for a period of notice and comment (and reply comment) that is not less than 60 days.</text></subsection></section><section id="id28e64d2e44f745b29f10ccf96280f3aa"><enum>5.</enum><header>Briefings and implementation</header><subsection id="id45d426dbf5554b4890aabdc04c9fc91b"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Briefing</header><text>Not later than 21 days after the date on which the Assistant Secretary submits the Implementation Plan to the appropriate committees of Congress under section 4(a), the Assistant Secretary, and appropriate representatives from the covered agencies involved in the formulation of the Strategy, shall provide a briefing on the implementation of the Strategy to the appropriate committees of Congress.</text></subsection><subsection id="idb5752f23ab0b40e099ecd837afb0dbe4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Implementation</header><paragraph id="id59a2126092e140a8b6891b9966fa5d03"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Assistant Secretary shall—</text><subparagraph id="ida8527cfcdeb7470cbd1daeca50fec89b"><enum>(A)</enum><text>implement the Strategy in accordance with the terms of the Implementation Plan; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5ff84a30404645e9a66a46f3c1c69ff2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not later than 90 days after the date on which the Assistant Secretary begins to implement the Strategy, and not less frequently than once every 90 days thereafter until the date on which the Implementation Plan is fully implemented, brief the appropriate committees of Congress on the progress in implementing the Implementation Plan.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idfea171a1e8df4327b8e815b5543a72fb"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this subsection may be construed to affect the authority or jurisdiction of the Federal Communications Commission or confer upon the Assistant Secretary or any executive agency the power to direct the actions of the Federal Communications Commission, either directly or indirectly.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id6e3ef008e4904977abe98947b4c6ea52"><enum>6.</enum><header>Government Accountability Office study and report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date on which the Assistant Secretary submits the Implementation Plan to the appropriate committees of Congress under section 4(a), the Comptroller General of the United States shall commence a study— </text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfef4fba23d844a57b7795ea488fcfad1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that shall—</text><subparagraph id="id10f1d27516304dd684ca5f3db3d9de52"><enum>(A)</enum><text>examine the efficacy of the Strategy and the Implementation Plan in coordinating funding across the Federal Government with respect to broadband internet access service;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6077fbd8775349bb9c6e13df15292ea9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>make recommendations regarding how to improve the Strategy and the Implementation Plan;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id77181ce57b09474fae470256a26c52be"><enum>(C)</enum><text>examine any existing or new performance goals and measures for Federal broadband programs; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id278d716fd2504b3b9c692c15473db3c0"><enum>(D)</enum><text>examine any awards made by covered agencies under Federal broadband programs, or under State, local, and Tribal programs with respect to broadband internet access service— </text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ideac29a1eea2e40e4add05e571839efbb"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in areas identified as served with respect to broadband internet access service; or </text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6e6354b5395a49f79f3a6d98a82adc66"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that are duplicative of other awards under such a program; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaf6bd5fb96944fb587be2383ac2d9cdc"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify programmatic changes that would prevent occurrences described in subparagraph (D) in the future; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id3ab0148d32554efa9e43965e6485390e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the results of which the Comptroller General shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress. </text></paragraph></section><section id="idC3B65D19C2934067AE5F6F785D4BA137"><enum>7.</enum><header>Broadband funding map reporting</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idccdbdc8e4d344b2e8b7921ed691b7832"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the head of each covered agency shall submit to the Assistant Secretary and the appropriate committees of Congress a report containing a comprehensive update on the measures that each respective covered agency has taken since May 15, 2023, to coordinate with the National Telecommunications and Information Administration, pursuant to subsection (c)(2)(A) of the ACCESS BROADBAND Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1307">47 U.S.C. 1307(c)(2)(A)</external-xref>), and the Federal Communications Commission to populate the Deployment Locations Map.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcefe950711ca4d08b8245122f59bd6d0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Each report required under subsection (a) shall include—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id76105ed6a8a544adad059192b0847dd1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a description of the extent to which the covered agency submitting the report is submitting the data necessary to populate the Deployment Locations Map in a complete and timely manner; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1cf57869684447ac803534f7e7b9278f"><enum>(2)</enum><text>identification of any outstanding challenges associated with the requirement for the submission of data described in paragraph (1). </text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id2798B86E7B6E489E99EB9FCAA04BAABE"><enum>8.</enum><header>Tracking and improving processing times for communications use applications</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 6409(b)(3) of the Middle Class Tax Relief and Job Creation Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1455">47 U.S.C. 1455(b)(3)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB5518EA7B9B445C9A3E9C128EB86469E"><subparagraph id="id9A6D1325613D415681002C22B07FA720"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Tracking and improving processing times</header><clause id="id05468F959BF94215A1C17E01B50D1A00"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Data controls</header><text>An executive agency shall develop controls to ensure that data is sufficiently accurate and complete to track the processing time for each application described in subparagraph (A).</text></clause><clause id="id57D5951EB7C54B8D8D7F69C4CF59A784"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Requirement to analyze, address, and report on delay factors</header><text>With respect to the factors that contribute to delays in processing applications described in subparagraph (A), an executive agency shall—</text><subclause id="idDCEBC1DAA9834178B5A6D3C63671CFDC"><enum>(I)</enum><text>analyze the factors as the delays are occurring;</text></subclause><subclause id="idC8E647ECF8994E7092085EDF17C8ACD8"><enum>(II)</enum><text>take actions to address the factors; and</text></subclause><subclause id="idCEBE180119384B768D1E33D1021CEFD0"><enum>(III)</enum><text>provide an annual report on the factors to—</text><item id="idF1405BE8EC1342D1BFC60CDB7BA14E2D"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate;</text></item><item id="id3C896945491942EB89605AD2995BB36B"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate;</text></item><item id="idDBD89B8DFC674EF0BBAFD3582DBED462"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives;</text></item><item id="id2BFC1BB69BF241198CDC915770FE27BF"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives; and</text></item><item id="idA85845784BD7417B92B655963CEC56BE"><enum>(ee)</enum><text>each committee of Congress with jurisdiction over the executive agency.</text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="idc5142d5f2d9842aeb9abbdc39ab4c71a"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Method for alerting staff to at-risk applications</header><text>An executive agency shall establish a method to alert employees of the executive agency to any application described in subparagraph (A) with respect to which the executive agency is at risk of failing to meet the 270-day deadline under that subparagraph.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="idc910e7e943494a06878f7cf7511ffbf9"><enum>9.</enum><header>Minimum broadband project cost</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 41001(6)(A) of the FAST Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4370m">42 U.S.C. 4370m(6)(A)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="id57F42071D13A45E3A8FE87D77696E8B3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in clause (iii)(III), by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id91643A1B4F1143F6B52FCB5FEE8982DA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating clause (iv) as clause (v); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idDCB7EC6329AD4BE6A387284D24BD9D0B"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting after clause (iii) the following:</text><quoted-block id="idaca2b95db3be4ce495444b4acf0e425d" display-inline="no-display-inline" style="OLC"><clause id="idfcc738aa3416485ab360eb37e8b34040"><enum>(iv)</enum><subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id11F059650DF24E08B45A93D21D805C7D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is subject to NEPA;</text></subclause><subclause indent="up1" id="id85B896962703450BA7EA44352D6C2DE7"><enum>(II)</enum><text>involves the construction of infrastructure for broadband; and</text></subclause><subclause id="idE94E08261EE743AEAD0D440C8273E4DB" indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(III)</enum><text>is likely to require a total investment of more than $5,000,000; or</text></subclause></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide00873eb6b6344e7ab7a70b083213c81"><enum>10.</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act, or any amendment made by this Act, may be construed to confer authority on the Federal Government, or any State, local, or Tribal government, to regulate broadband internet access service.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

