<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="H01AAC6AED4B9447BB65AC6305452CCDF"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3447 IH: Chip Security Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3447</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250515">May 15, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001058">Mr. Huizenga</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="F000454">Mr. Foster</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001194">Mr. Moolenaar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001087">Mr. Crawford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Lieu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000585">Mr. LaHood</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Commerce to issue standards with respect to chip security mechanisms for integrated circuit products, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H7714BFE5C13F4985A6374991E6F3CA0B"><section id="HEA76117BC2D9485E9B9C25B527E37242" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Chip Security Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H4C0031DF328E4F148430989D35E176ED"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="H998C87D852514040B29489B401147DF5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>technology developed in the United States should serve as the foundation for the global ecosystem of artificial intelligence to advance the foreign policy and national security objectives of the United States and allies and partners of the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2E08CE307C47482BBF6DEB4DDEBE6A3D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the United States can foster goodwill, strengthen relationships, and support innovative research around the world by providing allies and partners of the United States with advanced computing capabilities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6020E4B5585344999766AEDFAD5E72A7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>advanced integrated circuits and computing hardware that is exported from the United States must be protected from diversion, theft, and other unauthorized use or exploitation in order to bolster the competitiveness of the United States and protect the national security of the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1BF5332075754CD78AF7E60161BC0599"><enum>(4)</enum><text>implementing chip security mechanisms will improve compliance with the export control laws of the United States, assist allies and partners with guarding computing hardware, and enhance protections from bad actors looking to access, divert, or tamper with advanced integrated circuits and computing hardware; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2BA144BFB37A4672997C5B21B69B87DB"><enum>(5)</enum><text>implementing chip security mechanisms may help with the detection of smuggling or exploitation of advanced integrated circuits and computing hardware, thereby allowing for increased flexibility in export controls and opening the door for more international partners to receive streamlined and larger shipments of advanced computing hardware.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H9B7560C66944428AB662EBD5CF5414FC"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H2E2FF0073E9B4C7CBEAAD44AC2706F5E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="H5AF3870E60CB4174B34B7FA7202C658F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB01DA43BA9FC4CA790E0EA1828148950"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9929A9F00A5B45A281638284B522DD24"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Chip security mechanism</header><text>The term <quote>chip security mechanism</quote> means a software-, firmware-, or hardware-enabled security mechanism or a physical security mechanism.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H338B96E490384A2A89AED8A9D2A9CCF5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered integrated circuit product</header><text>The term <quote>covered integrated circuit product</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="HD103194D1554412FAE45ECC1DF924418"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an integrated circuit classified under Export Control Classification Number 3A090 or 3A001.z;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7F3C596F8C004674938C858FE0C19926"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a computer or other product classified under Export Control Classification Number 4A090 or 4A003.z; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC0A4CA61C431405FA40B248CC58B4DE2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an integrated circuit or computer or a product containing an integrated circuit or computer that is classified under an Export Control Classification Number that is a successor or substantially similar to the numbers listed in subparagraphs (A) and (B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCA3E2AFC1DCA48B2A7507E02EF3176FD"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Export</header><text>The term <quote>export</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 1742(3) of the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4801">50 U.S.C. 4801(3)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAFB2996335A24F3EAE6A0668650B0564"><enum>(5)</enum><header>In-country transfer</header><text>The term <quote>in-country transfer</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 1742(6) of the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4801">50 U.S.C. 4801(6)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB68B4043E166435EBEFF3D789446C124"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Reexport</header><text>The term <quote>reexport</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 1742(9) of the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4801">50 U.S.C. 4801(9)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA4BBE60940C048DF937221DF862338D9"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of Commerce.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H0A622DC7DEEB460194369CB2AD1BF43D"><enum>4.</enum><header>Requirements for security mechanisms for export of integrated circuit products</header><subsection id="HD0097164778D4A13A1062C42C576BD59"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Primary requirements for chip security mechanisms</header><paragraph id="HD32F815C7B0345768951A9EB3885AA6A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall require any covered integrated circuit product to be outfitted with chip security mechanisms that implement location verification, using techniques that are feasible and appropriate on such date of enactment, before it is exported, reexported, or in-country transferred to or in a foreign country.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC4E335BED1B44621AF6EFE71572B48CA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notification requirement</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall require any person that has received a license or other authorization under the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4811">50 U.S.C. 4811 et seq.</external-xref>) to export, reexport, or in-country transfer a covered integrated circuit product to promptly report to the Under Secretary of Industry and Security, if the person obtains credible information that the product—</text><subparagraph id="H3FD1CBA755954099A0CCFD68886F853A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is in a location other than the location specified in the application for the license or other authorization;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H556684B0C9414F8F9216B4CCAA1700F4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has been diverted to a user other than the user specified in the application; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFBE331A78A7149AD89314E13E120C794"><enum>(C)</enum><text>has been subjected to tampering or an attempt at tampering, including efforts to disable, spoof, manipulate, mislead or circumvent location verification mechanisms or other chip security mechanisms.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8AAB9D01790D4A22BC2F1D052C10AC93"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Development of secondary requirements for chip security mechanisms</header><paragraph id="H186BDA16A7CA40CB9CE13B5E036989DD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Assessment</header><subparagraph id="HDAAA79603A294B06BE18701EA0C857BF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall—</text><clause id="H2744F0B5B1D1492D89091CBF36A4E26C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>conduct an assessment to identify what additional mechanisms, if any, should be added to the primary chip security mechanisms required under subsection (a)(1)—</text><subclause id="H17CC71B1838B445E8AD92160B04DBE93"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to enhance compliance with the requirements of the Export Control Reform Act of 2018;</text></subclause><subclause id="H7677A98520814A2C9A3317301A52BE11"><enum>(II)</enum><text>to prevent, hinder, and detect the unauthorized use, access, or exploitation of covered integrated circuit products;</text></subclause><subclause id="H5A07854CF3D64390906B5C5080EEE65E"><enum>(III)</enum><text>to identify and monitor smuggling intermediaries; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HFA443569CF3D49199B559BD2CF62660D"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>to achieve any national security or foreign policy objective of the United States that the Secretary considers appropriate; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H8B9B7EB5612F4250AD4EAE1A756DC8F5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if the Secretary identifies any such mechanism, develop requirements for outfitting covered integrated circuit products with that mechanism.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H30D624A8109A4A658329F6EA29EB471D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The assessment required by paragraph (1) shall include—</text><clause id="H70D1860990A542BF8052E7173EFB6766"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an examination of the feasibility, reliability, and effectiveness of—</text><subclause id="H595B6C49CF28418290393CB0BA55E419"><enum>(I)</enum><text>methods and strategies that prevent the tampering, disabling, or other manipulating of covered integrated circuit products;</text></subclause><subclause id="HEBD1B322FF0E4C5BA94BC8DD929A7102"><enum>(II)</enum><text>workload verification methods;</text></subclause><subclause id="HA8E1CE52FB2D4132B92036917E12709E"><enum>(III)</enum><text>methods to modify the functionality of covered integrated circuit products that have been illicitly acquired; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H3CA794860D0E44698DA41844330031F4"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>any other method the Secretary determines appropriate for the prevention of unauthorized use, access, or exploitation of covered integrated circuit products;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H5C57D920801F493EA6C6595FDFA91601"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an analysis of—</text><subclause id="H5B051B63388E48BDABB49CEDB8D90CFC"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the potential costs associated with implementing each method examined under clause (i), including an analysis of—</text><item id="HC560283048E0495E8A8B6ED65CD49566"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the potential impact of the method on the performance of covered integrated circuit products; and</text></item><item id="HE89497953EE3494FBD8DD6481F7E0387"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the potential for the introduction of new vulnerabilities into the products;</text></item></subclause><subclause id="H420A6A69F8C048CF93E42B04B9BFF477"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the potential benefits of implementing the methods examined under clause (i), including an analysis of the potential increase—</text><item id="HE67004EC997B4608AA29CC7DFD93EEE8"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>in compliance of covered integrated circuit products with the requirements of the Export Control Reform Act of 2018; and</text></item><item id="H96BD8135B9BE47E69C37B3E6BF242AA4"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>in detecting, hindering, and preventing unauthorized use, access, or exploitation of the products; and</text></item></subclause><subclause id="H7A346F8B035C4BD2A8E0FE9CC9E13119"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the susceptibility of the methods examined under clause (i) to tampering, disabling, or other forms of manipulation; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HCB952E6FD31C41AF8CFAB7E7832FCBFD"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>an estimate of the expected costs to implement at-scale methods to tamper with, disable, or manipulate a covered integrated circuit product, or otherwise circumvent the methods examined under clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H70F22F73FF3C4FC89A2CD0578B377D40"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report to congress</header><subparagraph id="H47EA5F86593C4C57BA06B2C39810D01D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the results of the assessment required by paragraph (1), including—</text><clause id="H0A50549E91924BEABCF600FC200DE749"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an identification of the chip security mechanisms, if any, to be included in the requirements for secondary chip security mechanisms; and</text></clause><clause id="H8105AF3552974DE0B06BD90A71E5FF44"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if applicable, a roadmap for the timely implementation of the secondary chip security mechanisms.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H25DBB660FA27456FA9669DA93868308A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required by paragraph (1) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCE5D396A844447349CCD340D9F2A8B06"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Implementation</header><subparagraph id="H5D6984FD7E07438C9621542496726E00"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If any mechanisms are determined by the Secretary to be appropriate, the Secretary shall, not later than 2 years after the date on which the Secretary completes the assessment required by paragraph (1), require any covered integrated circuit product to be outfitted with the secondary chip security mechanisms identified pursuant to paragraph (1)(A) before the product is exported, reexported, or in-country transferred to or in a foreign country.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H30433775B6C0437A9B638161D24F4D00"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Privacy</header><text>In implementing requirements for secondary chip security mechanisms under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall prioritize confidentiality.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCDF83206D3C64730AF2B040C45355B76"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Enforcement authority</header><text>In carrying out this section, the Secretary may—</text><paragraph id="HDBE7C01802634F3F895B728B8DBA69C0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>verify, in a manner the Secretary determines appropriate, the ownership and location of a covered integrated circuit product that has been exported, reexported, or in-country transferred to or in a foreign country;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA90795E8692843F48791553986443DE3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>maintain a record of covered integrated circuit products and include in the record the location and current end-user of each such product; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8470A7D9129347A0A6305134792B030C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>require any person who has been granted a license or other authorization under the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 to export, reexport, or in-country transfer a covered integrated circuit product to provide the information needed to maintain the record.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H913C19FAB51A48A6ADE2080444A2A399"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Annual assessment and report on new chip security mechanisms</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter for 3 years, the Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="H117FE7862D4348EE9A231E5DB76E4052"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct an assessment of new chip security mechanisms that have been developed in the year preceding the date of the assessment; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF5D682E1909045ECB650A5A962E0BF22"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that includes—</text><subparagraph id="H37EEC003391E42F297A5C88FC4D4D10F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a summary of the results of the assessment required by paragraph (1);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7F714EBB6AE04C3994B7AD7C9211DFEA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an evaluation of whether any of the new mechanisms assessed under paragraph (1) should be added to or replace any of the existing requirements for secondary chip security mechanisms developed under subsection (b)(1); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5A2CD75248434D39B845B9DCA10BEC11"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any recommendations for modifications to relevant export controls to allow for more flexibility with respect to the countries to or in which covered integrated circuit products may be exported, reexported, or in-country transferred if the products include chip security mechanisms that meet the requirements developed under subsection (b)(1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

