<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-LIP25509-C4G-0F-TJN"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1796 IS: Housing Acquisitions Review and Transparency Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1796</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250515">May 15, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S366">Ms. Warren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S394">Ms. Smith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S313">Mr. Sanders</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To modify the premerger notification requirements under the Clayton Act with respect to certain acquisitions of residential property, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Housing Acquisitions Review and Transparency Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>HART Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id307668b8db484893bd46d6f7f7193b8e"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcc77a3116c27434fb959a861ff4043db"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Residential property</header><text>The term <term>residential property</term>—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id61145049399d432a866a8e79e996d63a"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means property that is zoned or intended to be used as a dwelling for individuals or households, including multifamily housing, condominiums, manufactured homes, or single-family homes; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8fa128f67fe445e18631e45227234fdc"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not include any place of short-term lodging.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf65c8e31508243249e37abe5869e452a"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Investment rental property</header><text>The term <term>investment rental property</term> means real property that—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf374ee9499334a489253d7316c553bef"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">will not be rented to an entity, including any entity of the acquiring person, except for the sole purpose of maintaining, managing, or supervising the operation of the real property; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id987c439a1e514e4b9375473d240fccd5"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">will be held solely for rental or investment purposes.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id324b8574551f44fead98d7c58a569336"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Place of short-term lodging</header><text>The term <term>place of short-term lodging</term> means a hotel, motel, inn, short-term rental, or other place of lodging that advertises at a price that is a nightly, hourly, or weekly rate.</text></paragraph></section><section id="id6e294b74166f4149b6c60b617b37c846"><enum>3.</enum><header>Housing transactions reportable</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfcf2b5ee89ee4851aa045f5ab65ab203"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Single acquisition</header><text>Section 7A(a) of the Clayton Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/18a">15 U.S.C. 18a(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following: <quote>For purposes of this subsection, all acquisitions of residential property (as defined in section 2 of the <short-title>HART Act</short-title>) by any person within a single calendar year shall be deemed to be a single acquisition and notification pursuant to this subsection shall be filed by the acquiring person upon acquiring the property that brings such single acquisition within any requirement described in paragraph (2) when aggregated with all other prior acquisitions of residential property by the person in that calendar year.</quote></text></subsection><subsection id="id4edb4da4e79a4afdb800da0dc14d75be"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exemption</header><text>Section 7A(c)(1) of the Clayton Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/18a">15 U.S.C. 18a(c)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>, unless the transaction includes residential property or investment rental property (as defined in section 2 of the <short-title>HART Act</short-title>), including in the form of a real estate investment trust, that is not solely intended for the personal use of an individual.</quote></text></subsection><subsection id="id9ac9841c0c6546d882059c241fa0729e"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Code of Federal Regulations</header><text>The Federal Trade Commission, with the concurrence of the Assistant Attorney General in charge of the Antitrust Division of the Department of Justice and by rule, in accordance with section 553 of title 5, United States Code, shall amend part 802 of title 16, Code of Federal Regulations to conform with the amendments to section 7A(a) of the Clayton Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/18">15 U.S.C. 18(a)</external-xref>) made by this Act.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id22dfeb8ce0174bf68b9ccc6434395c4f"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text>The Federal Trade Commission, with the concurrence of the Assistant Attorney General in charge of the Antitrust Division of the Department of Justice and by rule, in accordance with section 553 of title 5, United States Code, shall issue rules relating to the form and documentary material and information relevant to any acquisition or aggregated acquisitions of residential property is necessary and appropriate under section 7A(a) of the Clayton Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/18a">15 U.S.C. 18a(a)</external-xref>), as amended by subsection (a), to enable the Federal Trade Commission and the Assistant Attorney General to determine whether such acquisition or aggregated acquisitions may violate the antitrust laws, as defined in subsection (a) of the first section of the Clayton Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/12">15 U.S.C. 12</external-xref>). </text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

