<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD4BAC3EB1AEB4508BF2F27A5ED38566A" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 608 IH: Recognizing the importance of the Interstate Highway System and supporting the development of an interstate through southern Ohio.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 608</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250723">July 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000490">Mr. Taylor</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing the importance of the Interstate Highway System and supporting the development of an interstate through southern Ohio.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, on June 29, 1956, President Dwight D. Eisenhower signed the Federal-Aid Highway Act of 1956 to establish a 41,000-mile National System of Interstate and Defense Highways, known as the Interstate Highway System;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2025, this web of superhighways, now spanning a total of 46,876 miles throughout the United States, has had a powerful and positive impact on our national life;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Interstate Highway System has proven vital in transporting people and goods from one region to another speedily and safely;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Interstate Highway System has brought communities throughout the United States closer together and kept us connected to one another, as well as the larger world;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Interstate Highway System remains one of our country’s paramount assets as well as a symbol of human ingenuity and freedom;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Interstate Highway System is vital to our national security by ensuring quick transportation for our military, equipment, and critical resources;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Interstate Highway System has facilitated trade both within our national borders and globally, and helped create unprecedented economic expansion and opportunities for millions of Americans;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas many areas in Appalachia, including in southern Ohio, have faced economic hardships over recent decades, an interstate could increase economic opportunities for Appalachian communities;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the development of an interstate through southern Ohio could go directly past the Portsmouth Gaseous Diffusion Plant in Pike County, Ohio;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Portsmouth Gaseous Diffusion Plant and personnel were an integral part of the United States nuclear deterrent during the Cold War;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Portsmouth Gaseous Diffusion Plant is now being redeveloped, restored, and reopened for businesses, some of which have already started production at the site;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas an American company has started enriching uranium on site, which allows for the United States to become more energy independent and strengthens national security;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas a leading defense technology company is building an advanced manufacturing facility south of Columbus, Ohio, as well;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas these sites, and the entire southern Ohio region, could greatly benefit from an interstate going south from Columbus, Ohio; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Ohio legislators have already supported a resolution to study a future interstate through the region to improve connectivity, safety, and economic growth in the State: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H36DB04E2CB894116B27FFF39990CE458"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H3AA936B2FB684388B578FA964F1C5051"><enum/><text>That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="H98A99BB74B31439F8C8F556C239CD86D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognizes the importance of the Interstate Highway System;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCC59AFE874D04054A95C195648792B0F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the economic boost and increased national security that an interstate could provide to a region; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF6C6448C06C548759585ABA98A576312"><enum>(3)</enum><text>supports the planning, designing, and development of an interstate in southern Ohio going south from Columbus, Ohio.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

