<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-SIL25981-505-6L-G84"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2718 IS: To amend the Community Development Banking and Financial Institutions Act of 1994 to provide for capitalization assistance to enhance liquidity.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code>II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2718</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250904">September 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S327">Mr. Warner</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S266">Mr. Crapo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S394">Ms. Smith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S410">Ms. Lummis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S380">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S395">Mrs. Hyde-Smith</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Community Development Banking and Financial Institutions Act of
 1994 to provide for capitalization assistance to enhance liquidity.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="ida5c282fbc4274a9e88fae4ecff96e1a3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Capitalization assistance to enhance liquidity</header><subsection id="idEC1030D736494903A843FF95C571E83E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 113 of the Community Development Banking and Financial Institutions Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/4712">12 U.S.C. 4712</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="id29f843c7bfac499da00e2289439ebc6d"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking subsection (a) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id596ad54d21484f08b750d7e799c22dc2"><subsection id="id6f40e80c4e404d1eb951969e973c8b90"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Assistance</header><paragraph id="idab992cbacec948cd983d400790504a31"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Fund may provide funds to organizations for the purpose of—</text><subparagraph id="id9E6EB52CFACC44709DB9AC09A7F6AF5E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>purchasing loans that are originated by community development financial institutions, loan participations, or interests therein from community development financial institutions;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id19F601CBEC994723A91B0F3973A46D7F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>providing guarantees, loan loss reserves, or other forms of credit enhancement to promote liquidity for community development financial institutions; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4BA8775E660A4A8FB0F9E06142B0B8A4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>otherwise enhancing the liquidity of community development financial institutions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id2c6362a83a41420895c48ba1dec8a1d3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Construction of Federal Government funds</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, notwithstanding section 105(a)(9) of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5305">42 U.S.C. 5305(a)(9)</external-xref>), funds provided pursuant to such Act shall be considered to be Federal Government funds.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="id647a1995b111467f8295f049c9eef402"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking subsection (b) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7A06AFEAC3F44ECAB6EE867A17BF53C3"><subsection id="idea077386ba4d41228ca477f49c36d79b"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Selection</header><paragraph id="id212ea2c284ff4ce886248832fd4f5bfc"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The selection of organizations to receive assistance and the amount of assistance to be provided to any organization under this section shall be at the discretion of the Fund and in accordance with criteria established by the Fund.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8a254e6327f341eeb7295394ebaaf746"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>Organizations eligible to receive assistance under this section—</text><subparagraph id="id2005d5234255453dbe35f31f3816b670"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall have a primary purpose of promoting community development; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4e0747a16fd94fd3a13535631d6a6500"><enum>(B)</enum><text>are not required to be community development financial institutions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id7e93820840c34333a9fb2d22388d9bae"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Prioritization</header><text>For the purpose of making an award of funds under this section, the Fund shall prioritize the selection of organizations that—</text><subparagraph id="idc571ff50f02d4b03800cc2c64da7d190"><enum>(A)</enum><text>demonstrate relevant experience or an ability to carry out the activities under this section, including experience leading or participating in loan purchase structures or purchasing or participating in the purchase of, assigning, or otherwise transferring, assets from community development financial institutions;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id863a7e32d5b940bfa5b318b0a028ef85"><enum>(B)</enum><text>demonstrate the capacity to increase the number or dollar volume of loan originations or expand the products or services of community development financial institutions, including by leveraging the award with private capital; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9155f6a68ea348ffb781001e0173d387"><enum>(C)</enum><text>will use the funds to support community development financial institutions that represent broad geographic coverage or that serve borrowers that have experienced significant unmet capital or financial services needs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="id6fb2b749a1fd4a54a08acc8a00561013"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (c), in the first sentence—</text><subparagraph id="id4750aca71b88458da7f5c5157eddb3ad"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>$5,000,000</quote> and inserting <quote>$20,000,000</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1fb652e538fd40b193e318db051ce308"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>during any 3-year period</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idfce491b588c54c4fa0b9fa166ab70eff"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idE81D2E7E91FE4F4897C0D33906BFA2E6"><subsection id="id747b589332b14f25bf400f3c10a04e2c"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary may promulgate such regulations as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the authorities or purposes of this section.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idc804c1f69d614329b9436e9323c8db30"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Emergency Capital Investment Funds</header><text>Section 104A of the Community Development Banking and Financial Institutions Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/4703a">12 U.S.C. 4703a</external-xref>) is amended by striking subsection (l) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3a1c2c072365485d8ef6de4323a944c3"><subsection id="id36b97323a63d451ba5697eba193fb3bc"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Deposit of funds</header><text>All funds received by the Secretary in connection with purchases made pursuant of this section, including interest payments, dividend payments, and proceeds from the sale of any financial instrument, shall be deposited into the Fund and used—</text><paragraph id="idc207f41971684b4fbd1c23fed7ec8d7d"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to provide financial assistance to organizations pursuant to section 113; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id724bbb992d764b0c9268d0526157dcba"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to provide financial and technical assistance pursuant to section 108, except that subsection (e) of that section shall be waived.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="id57DEF91707004ADFB652196009ED4CB1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Annual reports</header><paragraph id="idA99208062EF44985AB526174802E7AA2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection, the terms <term>community development financial institution</term> and <term>Fund</term> have the meanings given the terms in section 103 of the Community Development Banking and Financial Institutions Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/4702">12 U.S.C. 4702</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idF70B5FE7E9A04551A2166BBE210766E3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date on which assistance is first provided under section 113 of the Community Development Banking and Financial Institutions Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/4712">12 U.S.C. 4712</external-xref>) pursuant to the amendments made by subsection (a) of this section, and annually thereafter through 2028, the Secretary of the Treasury shall submit to Congress a written report describing the use of the Fund for the 1-year period preceding the submission of the report for the purposes described in subsection (a)(1) of such section 113, as amended by subsection (a) of this section, which shall include, with respect to the period covered by the report—</text><subparagraph id="id7AFDAA77941643E3B959659286F3E027"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the total amount of— </text><clause id="id6A0DD903462042BB88A5E72C3861564F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>loans, loan participations, and interests therein purchased from community development financial institutions;</text></clause><clause id="id705c59798289429381b406e7fd75fe97"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>loans that support affordable housing construction; and</text></clause><clause id="id8C3DFAF778FA4CFCAD670492B0FECEA5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>guarantees, loan loss reserves, and other forms of credit enhancement provided to community development financial institutions;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idED1A3C99F4014D04A37C9C9634FC673B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the effect of the purchases and guarantees made by the Fund on the overall competitiveness of community development financial institutions; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id39441B9A6F0D4FC3ADD45997B5C71CC4" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the impact of the purchases and guarantees made by the Fund on the liquidity of community development financial institutions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


