<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H09B99D5B9459486C83EFCFAF8FC0BBB2" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 578 IH: Honoring the memory of the victims of the 1967 Newark riots and acknowledging the enduring impact on the Newark community.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 578</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250714">July 14, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001229">Mrs. McIver</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001136">Mr. Conaway</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Honoring the memory of the victims of the 1967 Newark riots and acknowledging the enduring impact on the Newark community.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the 1967 Newark riots were a significant period of civil unrest that occurred from July 12 to July 17, 1967, in Newark, New Jersey, resulting in the loss of 26 lives, injuries to over 700 individuals, and more than 1,400 arrests;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the unrest was sparked by the arrest and brutal treatment of a Black taxicab driver, John William Smith, by White police officers, igniting longstanding frustrations related to systemic racism, economic disparities, discrimination, and police brutality within the Black community;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the events that followed led to widespread protests, looting, violent clashes, and extensive property damage across Newark, with most of the destruction impacting Black neighborhoods and businesses;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the deployment of the National Guard and State Police, involving approximately 7,900 personnel, was marked by reports of excessive force and further escalated tensions between law enforcement and Newark residents;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Newark riots exposed the deep racial tensions and poverty that disproportionately affected Black residents, who faced unemployment, substandard housing, and lack of access to quality education and health care;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the events in Newark were part of the broader <quote>Long Hot Summer of 1967</quote>, during which over 150 instances of civil unrest occurred across the United States, highlighting pervasive racial inequities and injustices;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, despite the significant loss and suffering caused by the riots, the events also served as a catalyst for change, sparking local and national conversations about racial justice, police accountability, and the need for meaningful economic and social reforms in underserved communities;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Governor Richard J. Hughes created the Governor’s Select Commission for the Study of Civil Disorder in New Jersey, also known as the <quote>Lilley Commission</quote>, which cited neglected social, political, and economic issues and frustrations as key factors to the urban unrest;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the 1968 report by the National Advisory Commission on Civil Disorders, known as the Kerner Commission, identified systemic racism, economic inequality, and inadequate political representation as root causes of the unrest in Newark and other cities;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the community in Newark organized sufficiently to negotiate with Federal, State, and local officials to conceive of and implement long term partial solutions for low income housing, access to job training, jobs, and access to better health care; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the legacy of the 1967 Newark riots continues to influence the social, economic, and political landscape of Newark, serving as a poignant reminder of the necessity for ongoing efforts toward racial justice and equality; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas we must honor the memories of those affected by the riots, recognize the historical significance of the events, and acknowledge the ongoing struggles faced by communities impacted by systemic inequality in New Jersey and nationwide and the ability of the community to design and implement solutions with the help of State and Federal resources: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="OLC" id="H3674B01D623041A8A952FCB6A62B8036"> 
<section id="HE8262A15263342FFB2AD70FEBDD3A125" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="H9FCC046A4F474AC2B426974B332DB0C4"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">honors the memory of the individuals who lost their lives and acknowledges the suffering of those injured and affected during the 1967 Newark riots;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC46DBA50FF0A49DF88AC6F205D5D6961"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the profound and enduring impact of the 1967 Newark riots on the community of Newark and the broader national discourse on civil rights and social justice; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H45286B10C8A44B118943F1D849578E40"><enum>(3)</enum><text>commits to supporting initiatives that address racial and economic disparities, promote equitable law enforcement practices, and foster community engagement to prevent the recurrence of such unrest.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

