<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC552CCBBB8DD4EA4AEEAF034C085CA76" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3241 IH: Defense Workforce Integration Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3241</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250507">May 7, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000399">Mrs. Kiggans of Virginia</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="C001069">Mr. Courtney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for greater defense workforce integration, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H82AB19E8317D4EA6B06E64101AB1400F" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H3AC351187F614298AB3AC839365E7FF9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Defense Workforce Integration Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H1762F806724547AB93B09FC87991BBBF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Integration of military and civilian hiring processes</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1CE3D8B250F74FBC8F11C8842CEB8992"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense, in coordination with the Secretaries concerned shall establish a pathway for medically disqualified entry-level service members to enter civilian positions for which they are qualified in the Department of Defense or any of its components.</text></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD7050FB77C94409BB12C5B1AADB49558">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Air Force DRIVE program</header>
 <text>The Air Force’s Develop, Redistribute, Improve, Vault, Expose (DRIVE) program shall be considered sufficient to meet the requirements of subsection (a) and may, but need not, serve as a baseline from which the other military departments design their programs.</text>
            </subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD92B2CEF1C7840BEA67D6BA1E36F2BEA">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Entry-Level service member defined</header>
 <text>In this section, the term <term>entry-level service member</term> means a regular or reserve member of the Armed Forces who is currently attending or has military orders to attend within 90 days—</text>
                <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                    id="H73CFB6EF2517458CB1588ACE413D857F">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>basic training;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3FA2D44F608F4684B9FE7A2EEE329AEC"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>a technical school of the Armed Forces;</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                    id="HBA66FE9EEA134519BF74B0D543AB41EE">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>a service academy;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H5AD014F653BD48FA82127F591CCEB49A"> <enum>(4)</enum> <text>the Reserve Officer Training Corps (ROTC); and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HEFE847A8651943F5A09C2BFCDD5C3399">
                    <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text>an officer accession program, including officer candidate school, officer training school, officer development school, or equivalent program.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection></section> 
<section id="HD46DC17E614943BF9AB89E0A5E508F96"><enum>3.</enum><header>Provision of information on career opportunities in the defense industrial base to persons ineligible for military service</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/50">Chapter 50</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB64E7DBB286540629F180CA42828BA70"> <section id="H44A8CDEDE780495BBF0D9B255A0BD219"><enum>996.</enum><header>Provision of information on career opportunities in the defense industrial base to persons medically disqualified for military service</header> <subsection id="H4A31DCE3C60C4D3BB989A422B4052EFA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Secretary of Defense shall establish and implement a program to provide individuals who are not medically qualified for military service with information on employment opportunities in the defense industrial base or other employment opportunities in support of the national interests of the United States.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HEF4E6F3F83E6475AAA416D1501357B27"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Program</header><text>The program established under subsection (a) shall inform and refer persons described in subsection (a) to employment, apprenticeship, and training opportunities in—</text> <paragraph id="H8770075AF5C642BFA06ECCC793A75447"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the defense industrial base;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H54AD4CC2E8CB4B89B75892DF39E65A3D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>cybersecurity or intelligence support roles;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5BA0CA2F289843C5A12AA45776EC7DAB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>research and development in defense technologies;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H246A8B850AB94F64ABFAB2029DAC87EC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>national emergency and disaster preparedness; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6169A8BAC00849B5A399BF7C90D1A0EA"><enum>(5)</enum><text>any other non-military opportunity the Secretary considers in the national interests of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6900B9217F1A4B93AB4925BF41F11027"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Collaboration</header><text>The Secretary of Defense shall consult with entities in the defense industrial base, other Federal agencies, and academic institutions to carry out this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB78E64B881054C2DBD6956E2BEEF61DA"><enum>4.</enum><header>Provision to Navy personnel of information on career opportunities at Military Sealift Command</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of the Navy shall provide information about career opportunities at Military Sealift Command and workforce training programs for shipbuilders to all Navy personnel as part of the Transition Assistance Program process.</text></section> 
<section id="HEDC5E42DCA1944328AB5FD6FCBA8C918"><enum>5.</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives a report describing implementation of the requirements under sections 2 and 4 of this Act and section 996 of title 10, United States Code, as added by section 3 of this Act.</text></section> </legis-body></bill>

