<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Engrossed-in-House" dms-id="H9608D3B2CCFB4E4E9753EAD897907CB7" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H" stage-count="1">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 668 EH: Directing the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform to continue its ongoing investigation into the possible mismanagement of the Federal government’s investigation of Mr. Jeffrey Epstein and Ms. Ghislaine Maxwell, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">IV</distribution-code>
<congress display="no">119th CONGRESS</congress>
<session display="no">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 668</legis-num>
<current-chamber display="yes">In the House of Representatives, U. S.,</current-chamber>
<action>
<action-date date="20250903">September 3, 2025</action-date>
</action>
<legis-type display="yes">RESOLUTION</legis-type>
<official-title display="no">Directing the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform to continue its ongoing investigation into the possible mismanagement of the Federal government’s investigation of Mr. Jeffrey Epstein and Ms. Ghislaine Maxwell, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<resolution-body style="OLC" id="HDB45C35DC3244F769EEF79EC290B4479"> 
<section display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="section-one" id="H4A16898E07314F398C63D9E3635D96C1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Committee on Oversight and Government Reform Epstein Investigation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Committee on Oversight and Government Reform is directed to continue its ongoing investigation into the possible mismanagement of the Federal Government’s investigation of Mr. Jeffrey Epstein and Ms. Ghislaine Maxwell, the circumstances and subsequent investigations of Mr. Epstein’s death, the operation of sex-trafficking rings and ways for the Federal Government to effectively combat them, and potential violations of ethics rules related to elected officials in order to inform, among other things, legislative solutions to improve Federal efforts to combat sex trafficking and reform the use of non-prosecution agreements and plea agreements in sex-crime investigations.</text></section> <section id="H900B6E15A1B44B8E836BA06FA3A7532F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Investigative proceedings by the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</header> <subsection id="H2BD1986E713244C7B61E07FB886422EF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The House of Representatives supports the subpoenas and investigatory actions authorized by the chair of the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform as of the date of the adoption of this resolution with respect to the investigation described in section 1 and encourages all recipients to fully comply with them in a timely manner.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD5F06C9BD297441788D45A9E185EF15D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Issuance of investigative reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Committee on Oversight and Government Reform shall issue such investigative reports with respect to the investigation described in section 1 as it deems necessary.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H459E263F8961494DAAE03AB61B19D534"><enum>3.</enum><header>Release of documents relating to Jeffrey Epstein</header> <subsection id="HB5C3423417FE4A2A81D917FCAAA18396"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The chair of the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform shall make publicly available all unclassified committee records received from the Attorney General, the Secretary of the Treasury, and the Epstein estate, and any other custodians related to the investigation described in this resolution, as well as any written declarations, or other evidence that relates to the investigation described in this resolution, including those referring or relating to any of the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H85EB8E6AC0EF40A491E802C144BAAD63"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Jeffrey Epstein, including all investigations, prosecutions, or custodial matters.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFEB22311C2414F6CA55128A3011AA656"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Ghislaine Maxwell.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB33D47CBC9E44F4A89DC82B61C85B4AD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Flight logs or travel records, including but not limited to manifests, itineraries, pilot records, and customs or immigration documentation for any aircraft, vessel, or vehicle owned, operated, or used by Jeffrey Epstein or any related entity.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE25B468429C34A7E9D0C7389598F9264"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Individuals, including government officials, named or referenced in connection with Epstein’s criminal activities, civil settlements, immunity or plea agreements, or investigatory proceedings.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H13D644E097174AAC866BB15048AF9308"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Entities (corporate, nonprofit, academic, or governmental) with known or alleged ties to Epstein’s trafficking or financial networks.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H996D705C946949A799A9C906D4F9E93F"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Any immunity deals, non-prosecution agreements, plea bargains, or sealed settlements involving Epstein or his associates.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H122EDBB54F3F479499D4A4E137AE6A94"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Internal DOJ communications, including emails, memos, and meeting notes, concerning decisions to charge, not charge, investigate, or decline to investigate Epstein or his associates.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H69205220A66741E2B433931C69C77059"><enum>(8)</enum><text>All communications, memoranda, directives, logs, or metadata concerning the destruction, deletion, alteration, misplacement, or concealment of documents, recordings, or electronic data related to Epstein, his associates, his detention and death, or any investigative files.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF801757D194548F8805EA0E46B1D6078"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Documentation of Epstein’s detention or death, including incident reports, witness interviews, medical examiner files, autopsy reports, and written records detailing the circumstances and cause of death.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H56CD4962A3A845358C62D1961B9D413F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Withholding, delay, or redaction</header> <paragraph id="H7931D5A2728F40029392E2CC1DE59481"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Prohibited grounds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No committee record described in <internal-xref idref="HB5C3423417FE4A2A81D917FCAAA18396" legis-path="3.(a)">subsection (a)</internal-xref> shall be withheld, delayed, or redacted on the basis of embarrassment, reputational harm, or political sensitivity, including with respect to any government official, public figure, or foreign dignitary.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2069B2039D0F44DE9D00454F32689B0B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Permitted withholdings or redactions</header> 
<subparagraph id="H1F2C369DFB8346BFA3FA33CB73026607"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The chair of the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform may withhold or redact the segregable portions of committee records described in <internal-xref idref="HB5C3423417FE4A2A81D917FCAAA18396" legis-path="3.(a)">subsection (a)</internal-xref> that—</text> <clause id="H856DF233ED314683AA8BAF88C909F576"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">contain personally identifiable information of victims or victims’ personal and medical files and similar files the disclosure of which would constitute a clearly unwarranted invasion of personal privacy together with materials that could likely be used or reconstituted to unveil and identify a victim;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HDBEE33D8382145F0A3413929C853DF92"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>depict or contain child pornography, other child sexual abuse materials, or similar materials;</text></clause> <clause id="H9DCF47A6373743D4BD400CD7766C397A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>would jeopardize an active Federal investigation or ongoing prosecution, including whistleblower investigations, provided that such withholding is narrowly tailored and temporary;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HCFAB7CA6829F4DBFA55AC24CD222C9DD"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>depict or contain images of death, physical abuse, or injury of any person; or</text></clause> <clause id="HC1E3DB44583F4E4AA1234263ACB6699E"><enum>(v)</enum><text>contain information specifically authorized under criteria established by law or executive order to be kept secret in the interest of national defense or foreign policy and are in fact properly classified pursuant to such law or executive order.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H51F222A095E14C7FBA7110048614E263"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Written justification requirement</header> 
<clause id="HAB07AEC4E55C47CEB359D46E3ED3E36D"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>All withholdings or redactions made by the chair under <internal-xref idref="H1F2C369DFB8346BFA3FA33CB73026607" legis-path="3.(c)(1)">subparagraph (A)</internal-xref> shall be accompanied by a written justification for such withholding or redaction accompanying the release.</text></clause> <clause id="H694D68712AC246929B18455EA4E960BB"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Record custodian written justification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the chair of the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform receives any records described in <internal-xref idref="HB5C3423417FE4A2A81D917FCAAA18396" legis-path="3.(a)">subsection (a)</internal-xref> that already include redactions or if the chair knows any of the records described in such subsection are being withheld, the chair shall request the custodian of such records to provide written justifications for each redaction or withholding, and shall make each such justification publicly available promptly upon receipt.</text> </clause></subparagraph> </paragraph></subsection> </section> 
</resolution-body>
<attestation><attestation-group><attestor display="no">Kevin F. McCumber,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation>
</resolution> 


