<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H331B74EC1A0A427081BE911BEAB7B24C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3389 IH: Alzheimer’s Law Enforcement Education Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3389</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250514">May 14, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001260">Mr. Buchanan</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Director of the Office of Community Oriented Policing Services of the Department of Justice to establish a training course relating to Alzheimer’s disease and similar forms of dementia.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H573F6A35DADE4D59AB088E7A1441A4A4" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H6B4CCC76E2DF429B8DD2021E7763C092" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Alzheimer’s Law Enforcement Education Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H3CCD94D3076441358587B766D1B26EA9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Training course relating to alzheimer’s disease and similar forms of dementia</header> <subsection id="H2DD90E161EBE4A9CA6056A4A48B6FF4B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director of the Office of Community Oriented Policing Services of the Department of Justice, in consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services and the Administrator for the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services, shall establish a training course relating to Alzheimer’s disease and similar forms of dementia and such training course shall be available online.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H8E13F876A428430B9D14E00B2B27DDB4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Development</header><text>The training course shall include the following:</text> <paragraph id="H30B2C84D05D24768841666CE85921E26"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Instructions on interacting with persons with Alzheimer’s disease or a similar form of dementia.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1F75AFCCB2CA4F05A7BB619E82C4D8A2"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Techniques for recognizing behavioral symptoms and characteristics of Alzheimer’s disease or a similar form of dementia.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HABC9E64D45774F43811CC9292261D57F"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Techniques for effectively communicating with persons with Alzheimer’s disease or a similar form of dementia.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE4FCA8EC7C44420AAE977FE87E488AA8"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Effective use of alternatives to physical restraints when interacting with persons with Alzheimer’s disease or a similar form of dementia.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB3D8D73CF42E47D793E66A3D3DF65E2E"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">How to identify signs of abuse, neglect, or exploitation of persons with Alzheimer’s disease or a similar form of dementia.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HC57C942144684E3BBFEF4344B800C249"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Completion</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall recommend that applicable State departments and agencies count participation in the course under this section towards the required hours of instruction for continued employment, or for appointment, as a law enforcement officer, correctional officer, or correctional probation officer.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

