<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HBC4B6BF6EE2B4D699A6350684B03C5EA" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5114 IH: No Foreign Fundraising at United States Embassies Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5114</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250903">September 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000310">Ms. Johnson of Texas</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="M001238">Ms. McBride</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the use of United States embassies or consulates in raising funds for foreign political parties or candidates.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H70C5D0AB20DC4DFBA61B14B5C5BB4B02" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H4DA67FDE72214658AE98E68AD112567D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No Foreign Fundraising at United States Embassies Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H19A43A4096D54A7B9D50A5DF2ABE0FEE"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text> 
<paragraph id="H19B0C4ECC1FB4ED29CB56A5D03082B2B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Department of State’s mission is to protect and promote security, prosperity, and democratic values, not to pursue the interests of any political party in the United States or abroad.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H02D35BCA48E843E4A6E23D364EF3DBE0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Meeting with and building relationships with a range of political parties in foreign countries are appropriate and important functions consistent with the duties of any United States Ambassador or representative of the United States Government abroad.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFD3E1C48FD8D4EAC9104F69EA4575A8B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>It is the longstanding and bipartisan practice of the United States to encourage the rule of law and free speech abroad, without regard for political party or affiliation.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H39068B6FE93646D0829B8F52C4754983"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The use of United States embassy or consulate grounds, or the grounds of any other United States diplomatic post, to raise funds for any foreign political party or candidate in a foreign democratic electoral process is inappropriate and distinct from longstanding Department of State efforts to stand against corruption and advance democratic institutions and values around the world.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HD9DA367C7EBE4DF598CCEBB55AC18375"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibition on hosting of foreign party political events at United States embassies</header> 
<subsection id="H3F1C9BDAD0534652BB244C8E0A24123C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the policy of the United States to maintain strict political neutrality in the internal electoral processes of foreign countries, and to ensure that diplomatic resources, including embassies, consulates, and other posts, are not used to confer financial or electoral advantage to any foreign political party or candidate.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="HFF6CB5BA4C044ED091918BE357E40C90"><enum>(b)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No Federal funds, and no personal funds of a United States Ambassador or other United States official, may be obligated or expended to host a fundraising event for, or on behalf of, a foreign political party or candidate at a United States embassy or consulate or any other United States diplomatic post, or at the residence of such Ambassador or other official.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1EC1905C50B34335B323F3CA702BAF95"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Fundraising event defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>fundraising event</term> means an event intended to raise funds for, or on behalf of, a political party or candidate, including by knowingly facilitating contact between potential donors and political parties or candidates for fundraising purposes.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H2F0CCF1F2AB84330BD7B5120EAB16F83"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Restriction on entertainment and representation expenses</header><text>Section 905 of the Foreign Service Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/4085">22 U.S.C. 4085</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following: <quote>The Secretary may not provide for official receptions or pay expenses related to activities by the Department or the Service, hosted by a United States embassy or consulate or other United States diplomatic post, intended to raise funds for or on behalf of a foreign political party or candidate.</quote>.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H73B34B59B64940199133FE3CCEBDF8FD" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Additional restriction on expenditures</header><text>Section 4(b)(2)(H) of the State Department Basic Authorities Act of 1956 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2671">22 U.S.C. 2671(b)(2)(H)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>, other than functions at a United States embassy or consulate or any other United States diplomatic post intended to raise funds for or on behalf of a foreign political party or candidate</quote> after <quote>allowances</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H7DCFD1604540479787D69BD6C08B778E"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Revision of DSSR and FAM</header> <paragraph id="H17A8BACE8ED149F4B538EE0243B12BFC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of State shall revise the Department of State Standardized Regulations (DSSR) and the Foreign Affairs Manual (FAM) to prohibit the use of a United States embassy or consulate or any other United States diplomatic post in a manner intended to raise funds for or on behalf of a foreign political party or candidate, reflect the prohibitions on expenditures under this section, and discourage any activity hosted by a United States embassy or consulate or other United States diplomatic post that could be construed as promoting the financial interest of any foreign political party or candidate relative to others engaged in a democratic electoral process.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB0A505774FA24A89826B1F894648404D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Certification</header><text>Not less than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall certify to the appropriate congressional committees that the revisions required under paragraph (1) have been made.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAD844E00E358493C9817D27CFA448204"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

