<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HBFD92AE232A94A9FA28DD5552C4C5A63" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4314 IH: Farmers Feeding America Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4314</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250710">July 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001039">Mrs. Cammack</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 to require that supplemental Nutrition assistance program (SNAP) benefits be used for the purchase of food products grown, produced, and manufactured in the United States.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF1BF3EB6D4664CDCBB4EBAF1674774F1" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H46219637B29B40098405A0FC2B28DDB5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Farmers Feeding America Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HBB4A561BC01A4865B6A186C697663ECB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This purpose of this Act is to support domestic agriculture, strengthen American food production, and ensure that supplemental nutrition assistance program (SNAP) benefits are used to purchase foods that are grown, processed, and manufactured in the United States.</text></section> 
<section id="HA1CCDA5ADB224C77952909B8321C4907"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H07946A5129424AB4B157D2BB451EEEC8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <quote>American food product</quote> means any food that is—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H9603AED1D76C4D6895CAEB931C292118"><enum>(A)</enum><text>grown, harvested, or produced within the United States; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0A0A9815A88846ADA56891EBA8227754"><enum>(B)</enum><text>processed or manufactured in the United States with at least 51 percent of such food ingredients sourced domestically.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2C2E8D87C43A430AABE6EBC3C94D284F" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>retailer Compliance</quote> means to the requirement that SNAP-authorized retailers make a good faith effort to prioritize the availability of American food products for purchase with supplemental nutrition assistance program benefits issued under the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2011">7 U.S.C. 2011 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H368BCC36B6D941A281CDD2587521D098"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <quote>SNAP</quote> means supplemental nutrition assistance program established under of the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2011">7 U.S.C. 2011 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H0B95207B67BC468E8478E286DD405623"><enum>4.</enum><header>Requirement for snap purchases</header> 
<subsection id="H7B71131335DD4B15BDF6005775F4B7E7"><enum>(a)</enum><text>Any food purchased with supplemental nutrition assistance program benefits issued under the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2011">7 U.S.C. 2011 et seq.</external-xref>) shall be an American food product unless—</text> <paragraph id="H87661FB90C0B47E9AD44FB65D2D7057A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the specified food item is not commercially available in sufficient quantities or reasonable quality within the United States; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF3C29B7788704CE3AC5652204BDE3227"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Secretary of Agriculture grants an exemption based on an undue burden on households participating in the supplemental nutrition assistance program, including cost or regional availability of food.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H92CCD4265145403397617310E0643E4A"><enum>(b)</enum><text>The Secretary of Agriculture shall maintain a list of exempted foods and update it regularly based on domestic production trends and market conditions.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H134E4B6136B04755AF260589CDA3F436"><enum>5.</enum><header>Retailer obligations</header> 
<subsection id="H498A1D0BD61F4BEB9A88B0E28F326981"><enum>(a)</enum><text>SNAP-authorized retailers shall—</text> <paragraph id="H86FC2EF1C8404AFAB8C344194E6D17EB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>make reasonable efforts to stock American food products in relevant food categories; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDE2AC156E87C4CDC962F4F3736A2A971"><enum>(2)</enum><text>report on retailer compliance efforts upon request by the Department of Agriculture.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H77C2F7124EBF4FE083C402DEE9A9DA1E"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Noncompliance with this Act by retailers may result in warnings, required corrective action, or, in repeated or egregious cases, suspension of SNAP authorization.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HB650929F8CB344B5B05F46AEBCF27EBC"><enum>6.</enum><header>Enforcement and implementation</header> 
<subsection id="H6B794FF32336410CB2FC9E6E4D52FFEA"><enum>(a)</enum><text>The Secretary of Agriculture, in coordination with relevant Federal and State agencies, shall establish regulations and guidance to ensure retailer compliance with this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H8BCFDFB7B0F64D51B8C54C43E607EC16"><enum>(b)</enum><text>A public awareness campaign shall be conducted to educate SNAP recipients and retailers on the benefits and requirements of purchasing American food products.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5DB5A28350FE4EE49B52583BB85E4BF5"><enum>(c)</enum><text>An annual review shall be conducted to assess the economic impact and effectiveness of this Act, with recommendations for potential adjustments.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HCD375D4152994CD6883AC989069414AB"><enum>7.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act shall take effect 1 year after enactment to allow for retailer adaptation and public education.</text></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

