<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4A6688435F744697BB66B9198A3960D1" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3243 IH: Therapeutic Fraud Prevention Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3243</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250507">May 7, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Lieu</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001156">Ms. Sánchez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000015">Mr. Neal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000601">Mr. Landsman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001220">Mr. McGarvey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001157">Mr. David Scott of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001211">Mr. Stanton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001110">Mr. Correa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000216">Ms. DeLauro</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001159">Ms. Strickland</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001226">Ms. Salinas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000454">Mr. Foster</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001066">Mr. Horsford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000788">Ms. Williams of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001217">Mr. Moskowitz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000629">Ms. Davids of Kansas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000305">Ms. Ross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001130">Ms. Crockett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001117">Mr. Casten</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000617">Mrs. Ramirez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000606">Mr. Latimer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000530">Mr. Deluzio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001207">Ms. Sherrill</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000173">Ms. Omar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000310">Ms. Johnson of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001223">Mr. Magaziner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001231">Ms. Simon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001081">Mrs. Hayes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000197">Ms. DeGette</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001190">Mr. Schneider</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000476">Mr. Frost</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001221">Ms. Scholten</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="I000058">Mr. Ivey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001318">Ms. Balint</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001223">Mrs. Sykes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000579">Mr. Ryan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000402">Mr. Kennedy of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001225">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000617">Ms. Pressley</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000602">Ms. Lee of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit commercial sexual orientation conversion therapy, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H597C16B134944BE9A3886BCD8966C6DA" style="OLC"> 
<section commented="no" id="H8C3D437BA034437FA4E05A46CFE657B2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Therapeutic Fraud Prevention Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HFE23FEB59EF344D1AE6495EFADD69100"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text>
<paragraph id="H53F84F98585A4A00950E41FD884825DF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Being lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, or gender nonconforming is not a disorder, disease, illness, deficiency, or shortcoming.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H622044AB5C82411C8AFDE40F242C4653"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The national community of professionals in education, social work, health, mental health, and counseling has determined that there is no scientifically valid evidence that supports the practice of attempting to prevent a person from being lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, or gender nonconforming.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H426378013465426E885B9A18DF10AA96"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Such professionals have determined that there is no evidence that conversion therapy is effective or that an individual’s sexual orientation or gender identity can be changed by conversion therapy.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H31D4AAD097414CAA96A2EFE505FE60FA"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Such professionals have also determined that the potential risks of conversion therapy are not only that it is ineffective, but also that it is substantially dangerous to an individual’s mental and physical health, and has been shown to contribute to depression, self-harm, low self-esteem, family rejection, and suicide.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H14C9D522D9F54017B09CC9DE1A4E4444"><enum>(5)</enum><text>It is in the interest of the Nation to prevent lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, and gender nonconforming people and their families from being defrauded by persons seeking to profit by offering this harmful and wholly ineffective therapy.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H2CE9A015E2684EB28F52AEA8DA1B8BA0"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
<paragraph id="HF142DD7D63BB4F0A852964B3611F28DA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Conversion therapy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>conversion therapy</term>—</text> <subparagraph id="H2BA9751B4585408CAFEAE20F85045EC8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means any practice or treatment by any person that seeks to change another individual’s sexual orientation or gender identity, including efforts to change behaviors or gender expressions, or to eliminate or reduce sexual or romantic attractions or feelings toward individuals of the same gender, if such person—</text>
<clause id="HB0941402BCC3483786FDFC6EF0A5DDC3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>receives monetary compensation in exchange for such practice or treatment; or</text></clause> <clause id="H51E73BCED4914D0DBE8267F4876176F6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">instead of, or in addition to, receiving monetary compensation in exchange for such practice or treatment directly, receives monetary compensation in exchange for a product or service that is integral to the provision of such practice or treatment by such person, unless such product or service is protected by the First Amendment to the Constitution; and</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H0A4829F431B24327A10FF26B18F3D91F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include any practice or treatment, which does not seek to change sexual orientation or gender identity, that—</text> <clause id="HCCF3E3587A5943898922CD27885C4104"><enum>(i)</enum><text>provides assistance to an individual undergoing a gender transition; or</text></clause>
<clause id="H00140DAA984349CE859E725E418EEEC0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provides acceptance, support, and understanding of a client or facilitation of a client’s coping, social support, and identity exploration and development, including sexual orientation-neutral interventions to prevent or address unlawful conduct or unsafe sexual practices.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H245FED4BE32C4EE5A170A23DDFE1BC3C"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Gender identity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>gender identity</term> means the gender-related identity, appearance, mannerisms, or other gender-related characteristics of an individual, regardless of the individual’s designated sex at birth.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H97494FE318B24EAD87FBF25900168D17"><enum>(3)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Person</header><text>The term <term>person</term> means any individual, partnership, corporation, cooperative, association, or any other entity.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H54BA6B1F269F4AA6BD16CD60F7F8BB63"><enum>(4)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Sexual orientation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>sexual orientation</term> means homosexuality, heterosexuality, or bisexuality.</text></paragraph></section>
<section commented="no" id="HD58B65D9F874423486BB4E3A3716E3F5"><enum>4.</enum><header>Unlawful conduct related to conversion therapy</header>
<subsection commented="no" id="H0EEBF5A48C9E44EFA470ABF821553871"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It shall be unlawful for any person—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="HFB40C91AC51C4345BFDEC319490F5530"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to provide conversion therapy to any individual;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H798DA6E285DF4ED39DCFA10F7D6EA6E3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to advertise for the provision of conversion therapy and claim in such advertising—</text> <subparagraph id="H5A504150005740208D0B0D1D41ED7362"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to change another individual’s sexual orientation or gender identity;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HC71740E485CC48A688F45D05FF06702D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to eliminate or reduce sexual or romantic attractions or feelings toward individuals of the same gender; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9BD32421945E481BA2B8DEC5D750577A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>that such efforts are harmless or without risk to individuals receiving such therapy; or</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H59554D2A3E7A4C6986D009287E4CA481"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to knowingly assist or facilitate the provision of conversion therapy to an individual if such person receives compensation from any source in connection with providing conversion therapy.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H50AC8C20F36B499C96B9B7031B2040A4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Enforcement by Federal Trade Commission</header> <paragraph id="H3BE2165698E24C989E45233DCBA92BCD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Violation of rule</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A violation of subsection (a) shall be treated as a violation of a rule defining an unfair or deceptive act or practice prescribed under section 18(a)(1)(B) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/57a">15 U.S.C. 57a(a)(1)(B)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H81B0C68A8FBE4522B56B53C3EA09AEF9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Powers of commission</header>
<subparagraph id="HE82BAAEE67BB4A08AA3CC47C957D27E2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Federal Trade Commission shall enforce this section in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though all applicable terms and provisions of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>) were incorporated into and made a part of this Act.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H58EAF7A6840942BA9647ACD93DE2A136"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Privileges and immunities</header><text>Any person who violates subsection (a) shall be subject to the penalties, and entitled to the privileges and immunities, provided in the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>). Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed to limit the authority of the Federal Trade Commission under any other provision of law.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H042D5B49878A476F9B70EEBB087BE370"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Federal Trade Commission may promulgate, in accordance with section 553 of title 5, United States Code, such regulations as the Commission considers appropriate to carry out this section.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H634B0237ABC24E599E4F064FA6A7679A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Enforcement by Attorney General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General may bring a civil action in the courts of the United States against a person who engages in a violation of subsection (a), for appropriate relief.</text></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" id="H458D44702A4444AFA907E3B1619EC6CB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Enforcement by States</header>
<paragraph commented="no" id="H0FD2F0034ADB4579A1C47EC59D1A20EC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the attorney general of a State has reason to believe that an interest of the residents of the State has been or is being threatened or adversely affected by a practice that violates subsection (a), the attorney general of the State may, as parens patriae, bring a civil action on behalf of the residents of the State in an appropriate district court of the United States to obtain appropriate relief.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEC17D49288F44B7FBFF246A19A368973"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rights of Federal trade commission</header> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HFC68E2EDC15A4920828D48C158AE75CA"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Notice to Federal trade commission</header> <clause commented="no" id="HFBE7A9E54D6A4C9DB5345FBBCD5E298B"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in clause (iii), the attorney general of a State, before initiating a civil action under paragraph (1), shall provide written notification to the Federal Trade Commission that the attorney general intends to bring such civil action.</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" id="HBA12866FB53042CE9F133D038FBEEF63"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The notification required under clause (i) shall include a copy of the complaint to be filed to initiate the civil action.</text></clause> <clause commented="no" id="H1972EA1D9AC347BBA762EFA33B974DDA"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>If it is not feasible for the attorney general of a State to provide the notification required under clause (i) before initiating a civil action under paragraph (1), the attorney general shall notify the Commission immediately upon instituting the civil action.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H9732E6B498C04A7D9F496375CD82786E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Intervention by Federal trade commission</header><text>The Commission may—</text> <clause commented="no" id="HE3675A5D3F1F42DF8AA8A0DBFD84767B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>intervene in any civil action brought by the attorney general of a State under paragraph (1); and</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" id="HC59B542F1568470EA785D5216393D6AE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>upon intervening—</text> <subclause commented="no" id="H62B3E6D844CB4A518636C8DDCF0D388E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>be heard on all matters arising in the civil action; and</text></subclause>
<subclause commented="no" id="H4C9DD8C6B83F40DFB8BB68BD42B7E3CE"><enum>(II)</enum><text>file petitions for appeal of a decision in the civil action.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H10A958D8E8144F1A8E821C6594BB78DF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Investigatory powers</header><text>Nothing in this subsection may be construed to prevent the attorney general of a State from exercising the powers conferred on the attorney general by the laws of the State to conduct investigations, to administer oaths or affirmations, or to compel the attendance of witnesses or the production of documentary or other evidence.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" id="H5186E003E2094DA2988F48D5AE573DFE"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Preemptive action by Federal trade commission</header><text>If the Federal Trade Commission institutes a civil action or an administrative action with respect to a violation of subsection (a), the attorney general of a State may not, during the pendency of such action, bring a civil action under paragraph (1) against any defendant named in the complaint of the Commission for the violation with respect to which the Commission instituted such action.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H183A343A9BF949D9A5E631E78F3E08F0"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Venue; service of process</header> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H7E5C493B07E64F2E9DABECAE045DC2E1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Venue</header><text>Any action brought under paragraph (1) may be brought in—</text>
<clause commented="no" id="HE97E9F9A101A4F45BFA7663A265E64B6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the district court of the United States that meets applicable requirements relating to venue under section 1391 of title 28, United States Code; or</text></clause> <clause commented="no" id="H69FEBF84C3934D32BC04B70A20F3A426"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>another court of competent jurisdiction.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HACF6BD214B6344169481F2B5843812A4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Service of process</header><text>In an action brought under paragraph (1), process may be served in any district in which—</text> <clause commented="no" id="HBF988FFF75B54A7EB1D07B1FCBC82658"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the defendant is an inhabitant, may be found, or transacts business; or</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" id="H18DC103DA38D4CC88774BAA1E4398232"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>venue is proper under section 1391 of title 28, United States Code.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="HD3F92E6ADEA645DBAA98CE4BA8F18A17"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Actions by other state officials</header> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H033D6704A9AC4315A4904F77F5EDC306"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In addition to a civil action brought by an attorney general under paragraph (1), any other officer of a State who is authorized by the State to do so may bring a civil action under paragraph (1), subject to the same requirements and limitations that apply under this subsection to civil actions brought by attorneys general.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HEFE59A41EFF84DF19CEA5BC9839D74B6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Savings provision</header><text>Nothing in this subsection may be construed to prohibit an authorized official of a State from initiating or continuing any proceeding in a court of the State for a violation of any civil or criminal law of the State.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H6F0E862F58314190BA0DACA1A57B4B08"><enum>5.</enum><header>Severability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any provision of this Act, or the application of such provision to any person or circumstance, is held to be unconstitutional, the remainder of this Act, and its application to any person or circumstance shall not be affected thereby.</text></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

