<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" dms-id="HE83C26A23C7841DCBBA9EE8D07201C27" public-private="public" key="G" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3481 : Delivering Digitally to Our Veterans Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3481</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250918" legis-day="20250916">September 18 (legislative day, September 16), 2025</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSVA00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to provide for electronic communication relating to educational assistance benefits under the laws administered by the Secretary, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" style="OLC" id="H28034177670D41AEA1316C4ABFADA8F4"><pagebreak></pagebreak><section id="HE6BCB91C39C2494E834DAB9ADC441B6B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Delivering Digitally to Our Veterans Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HA81700634B0848D9AFD6DAF7CB7ED100"><enum>2.</enum><header>Improvement to certain outreach under Solid Start program of Department of Veterans Affairs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 6320(b) of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="H9AF2C07015014A82A634B79E20158EE6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)(B)—</text><subparagraph id="HF37FAC1E6592425283A5A173990E526B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>calling</quote> and inserting <quote>communicating with</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H206E85F8A3AF417DA7AF645D856DBFE9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>through the use of tailored lines of communication, including mailings, text messaging, virtual chatting, and other electronic forms of messaging</quote> after <quote>Armed Forces</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1B617605E341417DB39DA7A738218B5E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>tailored mailings</quote> and inserting <quote>tailored lines of communication, including mailings, text messaging, virtual chatting, and other electronic forms of messaging,</quote>.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H0E357753796847A6B57F04CA4763CA4B"><enum>3.</enum><header>Department of Veterans Affairs use of tailored lines of communication for correspondence relating to educational assistance benefits</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 3680 of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block id="HAA2BC90B185D4AFBB45C7A201D2373E4" style="OLC"><subsection id="H40FED47F27CE4EC2816BA4A5CB2CCE68"><enum>(i)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HDF3B50B636404D07B3BAB1708EF6E3A3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Secretary shall provide a mechanism by which an eligible veteran or eligible person may use tailored lines of communication to send and receive correspondence with the Department of Veterans related to entitlement to and use of educational assistance benefits under the laws administered by the Secretary. The Secretary shall ensure that an eligible veteran or eligible person is provided with an opportunity to opt into sending and receiving such correspondence using such lines of communication rather than by mail.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5D4CC2FB91EE44F7966C83DB2B096C68" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Secretary shall provide to eligible veterans and eligible persons who are enrolled in a course or program of education or training notice of the opportunity to opt in to sending and receiving correspondence using tailored lines of communication pursuant to paragraph (1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H08C729E44219476CA733C52B3937323E" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, the term <quote>tailored lines of communication</quote> includes mailings, text messaging, virtual chatting, and other electronic forms of messaging.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H5FADF47DCDF74C7A82B73AFE9655E9E0"><enum>4.</enum><header>Extension of certain limits on payments of pension</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 5503(d)(7) of title 38, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>November 30, 2031</quote> and inserting <quote>January 31, 2033</quote>.</text></section></legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20250917" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives September 17, 2025.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Kevin F. McCumber,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation></bill> 

