<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE83C26A23C7841DCBBA9EE8D07201C27" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3481 IH: Delivering Digitally to Our Veterans Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3481</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250519">May 19, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001321">Mr. Barrett</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor
          name-id="T000491">Mr. Tran</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred
        to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans’
        Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to provide for electronic communication relating to educational assistance benefits under the laws administered by the Secretary, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H4D277264E8C347FBA91F653CFDA40307" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HA8B1B229A06D42B48BB35A64434299BF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Delivering Digitally to Our Veterans Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H18BDF5F01F5B45BCB21F2B5FFE774706"><enum>2.</enum><header>Department of Veterans Affairs electronic communication relating to educational assistance benefits</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 3680 of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="H9277B33BD8E142FD97B8DD5CDBB9C606" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="H85BCC2B493F64C05A7FD8774AA70CE3F"><enum>(i)</enum> 
<paragraph id="H6B2030CAB6F24739A73869A6A1472FB9" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Secretary shall provide a mechanism by which an eligible veteran or eligible person may electronically send and receive correspondence with the Department of Veterans related to entitlement to and use of educational assistance benefits under the laws administered by the Secretary. The Secretary shall ensure that an eligible veteran or eligible person is provided with an opportunity to opt into sending and receiving such correspondence electronically rather than by mail.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFAF92564FAD34E718F87D193C84D8A0F" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Secretary shall provide to eligible veterans and eligible persons who are enrolled in a course or program of education or training notice of the opportunity to opt in to sending and receiving correspondence electronically pursuant to paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </section> 
</legis-body></bill>

