<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE0DDF63FEA894D1C948BA9B9501CB54C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4992 IH: FEMA Critical Staffing Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4992</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250819">August 19, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001131">Mr. Casar</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="N000191">Mr. Neguse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000380">Mr. Amo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001217">Mr. Moskowitz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001094">Ms. Hoyle of Oregon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001211">Mr. Stanton</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000399">Mr. Doggett</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Federal Emergency Management Agency to use appropriated funds to restore agency staffing levels, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H3E6B4247FAEC4A5B90E84171B653B847" style="OLC">
<section id="HC6E89C91B6784879850927E848CB5039" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>FEMA Critical Staffing Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H50A4D90544814AC1ABD17261398DDA81" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds that—</text> 
<paragraph id="H96B49C37BBA74CD7BEC7D970A2E50845"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Federal Emergency Management Agency supports communities before disasters happen to help understand and prepare for possible risks, during disasters to assist the public and provide recovery centers, and after a disaster to support recovery and mitigating future hazards; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H491932AE9A354BCEB1E23378ED28DDD2"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">due to frequent climate change-fueled disasters like winter wildfires, hail from thunderstorms, and hurricanes, the Federal Emergency Management Agency works year-round to support communities across the United States.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H7D9779944C164E14840EB8F394617285"><enum>3.</enum><header>Federal weather monitoring and disaster response workforce level require</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act and notwithstanding any other provision of law, funds appropriated or otherwise made to for the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall be used to reinstate to a position in the Federal Emergency Management Agency each individual who—</text> <paragraph id="HA198C0C08F974C058798DDCED7CE6D19"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">during the period beginning on January 20, 2025, and ending on the date of the enactment of this Act, was involuntarily separated from service in a position in the Federal Emergency Management Agency; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAF3EBB0EA9E544E498C4353A441F6782"><enum>(2)</enum><text>elects to be so reinstated.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HB17B947CC9D2443E923D4381D8AAB67E"><enum>4.</enum><header>Continuation of authorized FEMA programs</header> <subsection id="H0EBF1A02108441C1B2C0FBDA1C8C0132"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency—</text> 
<paragraph id="HBBC5212493B44C73BD22B2C20D76161C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall continue to carry out any programs for which funds have been appropriated that support State and local efforts to prepare for and respond to extreme weather events; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H006E205B5D4F47B8A3294D0AA9BE52E4"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may not make any changes to existing congressionally mandated programs that will reduce access to extreme weather resources.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8591D16075814A8D842B5412F82EA593"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Actions required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out subsection (a), the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall—</text> <paragraph id="H007FE18A57EC498EB352A019848F3D91"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">immediately reinstate the Building Resilient Infrastructure and Communities program (established pursuant to section 203(i) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5133">42 U.S.C. 5133(i)</external-xref>)) and carry out any project under such program for which funds have been made available; and</text>
                </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6B99770C78494AA59498345E23E3EBC5"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">immediately reinstate the flood mitigation assistance program authorized under section 1366 of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4104c">42 U.S.C. 4104c</external-xref>) and carry out any project for which funds have been made available under such program.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

