<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCDDC423039EC419E80805C98D262E666" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5698 IH: District of Columbia Clemency Home Rule Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5698</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251006">October 6, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide that the authority to grant clemency for offenses against the District of Columbia shall be exercised in accordance with law enacted by the District of Columbia.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF7D338449FF3404C8645A7EAA5574D5B" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H8A4EEF8808504F918673650466662114" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>District of Columbia Clemency Home Rule Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H8BDB4C2C06FB4B25A41F64F3974E52DC"><enum>2.</enum><header>Authority to grant clemency for crimes under laws of the District of Columbia</header> <subsection id="H2E8325E2FD1E44508D392841716E2655"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The authority to grant clemency for crimes under the laws of the District of Columbia shall be exercised by such person or persons, and under such terms and conditions, as may be provided under law enacted by the District of Columbia.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC576160782B240BF9D9DE0BF6AD08DD7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rule of Construction</header><text>Nothing in this Act may be construed—</text> <paragraph id="HF3C2D7A097744FF298688C0838F87D09"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to affect any authority exercised by the President or the Mayor of the District of Columbia prior to the effective date of any law enacted by the District of Columbia pursuant to this Act with respect to the authority to grant clemency for crimes under the laws of the District of Columbia; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H387BBBEDC53048C1A6346791C9BDCB2E" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to limit the authority described in subsection (a) from being exercised with respect to crimes committed before, on, or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H10EB272AE92248199A2C5B125FA8152B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clemency Defined</header><text>In this Act, the term <term>clemency</term> means a pardon, reprieve, or commutation of sentence, or a remission of a fine or other financial penalty.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

