<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H83BC60E4CE4A477798D45DDC1232D8D5" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2308 IH: FEMA Independence Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2308</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250324">March 24, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001217">Mr. Moskowitz</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="D000032">Mr. Donalds</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish the Federal Emergency Management Agency as a cabinet-level independent agency, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8D0C1BDD429949C384A2B3F1186B1F50" style="OLC"><section id="HAAAA5CD716CE49A6B783A072E16E6727" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header><subsection id="HCAFF8E1DD7184478AF4681EFB0C55F98"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>FEMA Independence Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H862B2D974C6D4E1689C8DE18D16AFEFD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents of this Act is as follows:</text><toc container-level="legis-body-container" quoted-block="yes-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"><toc-entry idref="HAAAA5CD716CE49A6B783A072E16E6727" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H7D22929E78DB4327971E8910463604C2" level="section">Sec. 2. Establishment of FEMA as cabinet-level independent agency.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HE19AF37CCACE4ED08D3FD294D8946A3D" level="section">Sec. 3. Director; deputy directors; regional offices.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H94C746CC0E264344B15F251B0ED1AB0A" level="section">Sec. 4. Authority and responsibilities.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HF488B543372342E09E6DD32B3B4571C3" level="section">Sec. 5. Office of the Inspector General.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HD21AD8F904B54571A24631211B02216C" level="section">Sec. 6. Transfer of functions.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H41801FB4F96F443CB98408F976090824" level="section">Sec. 7. Personnel and other transfers.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H862BED09F13B49EABBA943573B1EA1A8" level="section">Sec. 8. Savings provisions.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HC2BF00F8A3264B8483CE8617611CBD21" level="section">Sec. 9. References.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H41A4DC5D1BE14FDC965DED1CA8219D56" level="section">Sec. 10. Offices and functions of Department of Homeland Security.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HF72EA59416A14F4ABA068C465B5CAAAE" level="section">Sec. 11. Homeland security grants.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H76460E8B02B2488FBEAA3E184259C587" level="section">Sec. 12. Conforming amendments to other laws.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H730238177E3A4EE1A84BA3741040691F" level="section">Sec. 13. Report on recommended legislation.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H635029F922B64497A2BF2329E425856D" level="section">Sec. 14. Definitions.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section><section id="H7D22929E78DB4327971E8910463604C2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Establishment of FEMA as cabinet-level independent agency</header><subsection id="HFE0C8C9DB76445A898232C4B53B46BD6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal Emergency Management Agency is established as a cabinet-level independent establishment in the executive branch.</text></subsection><subsection id="H40D0A96A65DE42A797EC5691A998EC9A" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Mission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The primary mission of the Agency is to reduce the loss of life and property and protect the Nation from all hazards, including natural disasters, acts of terrorism, and other man-made disasters, by leading and supporting the Nation in a risk-based, comprehensive emergency management system of preparedness, protection, response, recovery, and mitigation.</text></subsection></section><section id="HE19AF37CCACE4ED08D3FD294D8946A3D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Director; deputy directors; regional offices</header><subsection id="H5F8D7382F5854FEEBCE04FD41C8367D8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Director</header><paragraph id="H6590325C3A1F43FBAA2A7E4ED4FF4601"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Agency shall be headed by a Director, who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, and who shall report directly to the President.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB29271DA679F448798A51D109FDD3696"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualifications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall be appointed from among individuals who have—</text><subparagraph id="HE44FE9232AA74E92A828E03899A073B9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a demonstrated ability in and knowledge of emergency management and homeland security; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAB860578BCA54198B0D59E112F579327"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not less than 5 years of executive leadership and management experience in the public sector and 5 years of such experience in the private sector.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC3AFDB3508734F4F8E386848F4DBCEF4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Executive schedule</header><text>Title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text><subparagraph id="HBC839F7C645E47AC988F098CF03883BE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in section 5312 by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HC61B59F49BD84735BC60C1060FB8252E" style="USC"><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Director of the Federal Emergency Management Agency.</text><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2CDB3FDD1C4B43DFBA0DB6407F60DC79"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in section 5313 by striking the item relating to <quote>Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency.</quote>. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6CC8D5CC0A7B4BC2B3C9B9942930A565"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Deputy directors</header><paragraph id="H82439EADC34E4F4E8995AEBE9D7E9A1E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may appoint, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, not more than 4 Deputy Directors to assist the Director in carrying out the functions and authorities of the Director.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5CFDE40960AC475CAB8FB4C47B514F18"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Executive schedule</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 5314 of title 5, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>Deputy Administrators, Federal Emergency Management Agency</quote> and inserting <quote>Deputy Directors, Federal Emergency Management Agency</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H43C059B2E2B24C22B4460BDB1104A50E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Regional offices</header><paragraph id="H95393B81B6DE4B209359BC1EC86CAC0E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There shall be in the Agency 10 Regional Offices, as identified by the Director.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0D2A2D018AC144659CE7E369F7F04895"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Regional Directors</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each Regional Office shall be headed by a Regional Director who shall be chosen by the Director.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H94C746CC0E264344B15F251B0ED1AB0A"><enum>4.</enum><header>Authority and responsibilities</header><subsection id="H41B0EB8B08A845A2B746C72ABAF4D0FF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall provide the Federal leadership necessary to prepare for, respond to, recover from, and mitigate hazards.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2C4721A0E3204195B28E03FD8E4D5581"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Stafford Act</header><text>The Director shall assist the President in carrying out the functions under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5121">42 U.S.C. 5121 et seq.</external-xref>) and carrying out all functions and authorities given to the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency under that Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H989249308D2E435285C1715F845C5DC0" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Mission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The responsibilities of the Director shall include carrying out the mission of the Agency by leading and supporting the Nation in a comprehensive emergency management system of—</text><paragraph id="H82BD4A42871344B99B2C570B51B66EE4" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">mitigation, by taking sustained actions to reduce or eliminate long-term risks to people and property from hazards and their effects;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF305EBDA41604A61A67450E5E0FF0E1D" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">preparedness, by planning, training, conducting exercises, and building the emergency management profession to prepare effectively for mitigating, responding to, and recovering from any hazard;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD02472376A6E431BB6688D412473AA06" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">response, by conducting emergency operations to save lives and property through positioning emergency equipment, personnel, and supplies, through evacuating potential victims, through providing food, water, shelter, and medical care to those in need, and through restoring critical public services; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB0A5EDAA981D43AA8BAC59F89AB192EE" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recovery, by rebuilding communities so individuals, businesses, and governments can function on their own, return to normal life, and protect against future hazards.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2AC0A0C2A3C24148B35872948D46EE59" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Response duties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out subsection (c)(3), the Director, at a minimum, shall—</text><paragraph id="H89EEB40057C74DC7AB804A7069A4D146" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">help to ensure the effectiveness of emergency response providers in responding to a hazard;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAF33C660BE214BD68EA80A071B271DC6" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">coordinate and provide the Federal Government’s response to hazards;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCB99240740CA434A860703E71887724D" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">build a comprehensive national incident management system with Federal, State, and local government personnel, agencies, and authorities to respond to hazards;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEC6FEDD368B544E5B865AC0FA6A90CD0" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consolidate existing Federal Government emergency response plans into a single, coordinated plan to be known as the National Response Plan;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6B02284C80FE485A8EF531440B838C2F" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">administer and ensure the implementation of the National Response Plan, including coordinating and ensuring the readiness of each emergency support function under the National Response Plan; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H613385534E00410CB4AF12C62D61B6E7" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">help ensure the acquisition of operable and interoperable communications capabilities by Federal, State, local, and tribal governments and emergency response providers.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE0C1DB34930F4D858F10828604CF2E4C" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Continuity of Government</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall prepare and implement the plans and programs of the Federal Government for—</text><paragraph id="H73B2DEAF19C34BF1885955225D6CA0AA" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>continuity of operations;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H49FBCF9A5DA140DA9ED75073A03DE719" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>continuity of Government; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8004BCD847AD4C20AFAC591D93A8FB82" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>continuity of plans.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1DADBC74173947ECAD06AF8241E52F9F" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Other duties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall—</text><paragraph id="H676268DFD6544077810AF1D52DE8EF9F" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">coordinate the National Advisory Council;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5996567A069042448BEE417E0499F3BE" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>maintain and operate within the Agency the National Response Coordination Center (or its successor);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H002BECF9070842CF8A8ECC6EAC3E1A01" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop and maintain a national emergency management system that is capable of preparing for, responding to, recovering from, and mitigating hazards of all magnitudes, including catastrophic disasters; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA36B54714F134CA1AB2C626A87EA62FB" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supervise grant programs administered by the Agency.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H16D834520765493D85BB3891D7AAE11B" commented="no"><enum>(g)</enum><header>All-Hazards approach</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the responsibilities under this section, the Director shall coordinate the implementation of an all-hazards strategy that builds those common capabilities necessary to prepare for, respond to, recover from, and mitigate hazards.</text></subsection></section><section id="HF488B543372342E09E6DD32B3B4571C3"><enum>5.</enum><header>Office of the Inspector General</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Agency shall have an Office of the Inspector General, headed by an Inspector General, in accordance with <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/4">chapter 4</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Inspector General Act of 1978</quote>).</text></section><section id="HD21AD8F904B54571A24631211B02216C"><enum>6.</enum><header>Transfer of functions</header><subsection id="H1BB3F7CD9CA745C2B30D89B235924880"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There shall be transferred to the Director all functions of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, as such Agency was constituted on the day before the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H7EFA2D4AD2374DF3B5C05C04922B28CC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Inspector General</header><text>There shall be transferred to the Inspector General all functions relating to the Inspector General that were transferred from the Federal Emergency Management Agency to the Department of Homeland Security on or after January 1, 2003.</text></subsection><subsection id="H33E6C887259743DAB2E72203D6888940"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Transition period</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The transfers under this section shall be carried out not later than 365 days following the date of enactment of this Act. During the transition period, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall provide to the Director such assistance, including the use of personnel and assets, as the Director may request in preparing for the transfer.</text></subsection></section><section id="H41801FB4F96F443CB98408F976090824"><enum>7.</enum><header>Personnel and other transfers</header><subsection id="H78AAA91862C64D158AC85F0976BD0262"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Personnel appointments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director may appoint and fix the compensation of such officers and employees as may be necessary to carry out the respective functions transferred by section 6.</text></subsection><subsection id="H776E576A31084D8FA0A2F2F2AEFD1FED"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Transfer and allocations of appropriations and personnel</header><text>Except as otherwise provided in this Act, the personnel employed in connection with, and the assets, liabilities, contracts, property, records, and unexpended balances of appropriations, authorizations, allocations, and other funds employed, used, held, arising from, available to, or to be made available in connection with the functions transferred by section 6, subject to section 1531 of title 31, United States Code, shall be transferred to the Agency. Unexpended funds transferred pursuant to this subsection shall be used only for the purposes for which the funds were originally authorized and appropriated.</text></subsection><subsection id="H65EBF21E73744C7A984F5CC8C8AAD909"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Incidental transfers</header><text>The Director of the Office of Management and Budget, in consultation with the Director of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, may make such determinations as may be necessary with regard to the functions transferred by section 6, and may make such additional incidental dispositions of personnel, assets, liabilities, grants, contracts, property, records, and unexpended balances of appropriations, authorizations, allocations, and other funds held, used, arising from, available to, or to be made available in connection with such functions, as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this Act. The Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall provide for the termination of the affairs of all entities terminated by this Act and for such further measures and dispositions as may be necessary to effectuate the purposes of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="HDA7A53318D974AC8B8443BC25F039BBB" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effect on personnel</header><paragraph id="H14C931A0D978468C9FDABE4EEFEA7514" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as otherwise provided by this Act, the transfer pursuant to this Act of full-time personnel (except special Government employees) and part-time personnel holding permanent positions shall not cause any such employee to be separated or reduced in grade or compensation for 1 year after the date of transfer of such employee under this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC709E62266594ECD9CE5D2E742AA74B7" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Executive schedule positions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as otherwise provided in this Act, any person who, on the day preceding the date of the transfers of functions by section 6, held a position compensated in accordance with the Executive Schedule prescribed in <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/53">chapter 53</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, and who, without a break in service, is appointed in the Agency to a position having duties comparable to the duties performed immediately preceding such appointment shall continue to be compensated in such new position at not less than the rate provided for such previous position, for the duration of the service of such person in such new position.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H862BED09F13B49EABBA943573B1EA1A8"><enum>8.</enum><header>Savings provisions</header><subsection id="HAD29377E95A043EDB3FB6B40E162C95B" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Continuing effect of legal documents and actions</header><paragraph id="HF15DF1F5B3D244B996223259175A817C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The legal documents and actions described in paragraph (2) shall continue in effect according to their terms until modified, terminated, superseded, set aside, or revoked in accordance with law by the President, the Director, other authorized official, a court of competent jurisdiction, or by operation of law.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H952F8666D4414700883525F42D3CDA02"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Legal documents and actions described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The legal documents and actions described in this paragraph are all orders, determinations, rules, regulations, permits, agreements, grants, contracts, certificates, licenses, registrations, privileges, and other administrative actions that both—</text><subparagraph id="H38A497E380434C07BCFBB0582AB94DEB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>have been issued, made, granted, or allowed to become effective by the President, any Federal agency or official thereof, or by a court of competent jurisdiction, in the performance of functions that are transferred by section 6; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6D2228C0D7E542B2A42D1FD7B533FD3B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are in effect on the date of the transfers of functions by section 6, or were final before such date and are to become effective on or after such date.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H34CC17C1ACA643C8894080F1E3291A41"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Proceedings not affected</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The provisions of this Act shall not affect any proceedings, including notices of proposed rulemaking, or any application for any license, permit, certificate, or financial assistance pending before the Agency on the date of the transfers of functions by section 6, with respect to functions transferred by section 6, but such proceedings and applications shall continue. Orders shall be issued in such proceedings, appeals shall be taken therefrom, and payments shall be made pursuant to such orders, as if this Act had not been enacted, and orders issued in any such proceedings shall continue in effect until modified, terminated, superseded, or revoked by a duly authorized official, by a court of competent jurisdiction, or by operation of law. Nothing in this paragraph shall be considered to prohibit the discontinuance or modification of any such proceeding under the same terms and conditions and to the same extent that such proceeding could have been discontinued or modified if this Act had not been enacted.</text></subsection><subsection id="H31262CD99C9F4C158ED99A8F47292468"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Causes of action not affected</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The provisions of this Act shall not affect any cause of action commenced before the date of the transfers of functions by section 6, and in all such causes of action, proceedings shall be had, appeals taken, and judgments rendered in the same manner and with the same effect as if this Act had not been enacted.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA58E07391E40486393802AE4E45EB714"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Nonabatement of causes of action</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No cause of action commenced by or against the Agency, or by or against any individual in the official capacity of such individual as an officer of the Agency, shall abate by reason of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H50F0569F6FE04263928AD8246A66B294"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Administrative actions relating to promulgation of regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any administrative action relating to the preparation or promulgation of a regulation by the Agency relating to a function transferred by section 6 may be continued by the Agency with the same effect as if this Act had not been enacted.</text></subsection></section><section id="HC2BF00F8A3264B8483CE8617611CBD21"><enum>9.</enum><header>References</header><subsection id="HB65FEB5651324A698F1F08EED042879F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>References to FEMA</header><text>Any reference to the Federal Emergency Management Agency in any law, Executive order, rule, regulation, certificate, directive, instruction, delegation of authority, or other official paper shall be considered to refer and apply to the Agency established by section 2.</text></subsection><subsection id="H207BC2975DE3407D956FA3D07973141E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>References to Director or Administrator of FEMA</header><text>Any reference to the Director or the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency in any law, Executive order, rule, regulation, certificate, directive, instruction, delegation of authority, or other official paper shall be considered to refer and apply to the Director established by section 3(a)(1).</text></subsection><subsection id="HC35E18707F8446AAA6ECF5F11D9F21C4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>References to Inspector General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any reference to the Inspector General of the Federal Emergency Management Agency or to the functions relating to such office that were transferred from the Federal Emergency Management Agency to the Department of Homeland Security on or after January 1, 2003, in any law, Executive order, rule, regulation, certificate, directive, instruction, delegation of authority, or other official paper shall be considered to refer and apply to the Inspector General established by section 5 or to the functions related to such office.</text></subsection></section><section id="H41A4DC5D1BE14FDC965DED1CA8219D56"><enum>10.</enum><header>Offices and functions of Department of Homeland Security</header><subsection id="H4B33E10E3EAB4D6EB12AA86C163D9B8F" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Repeals</header><text>The following provisions of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/101">6 U.S.C. 101 et seq.</external-xref>) are repealed:</text><paragraph id="H9A21A62640FD4FB69309703492E1793A" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Section 501 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/311">6 U.S.C. 311</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1B346D7960F24EC49B8CF7693FDD67F3" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Section 503 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/313">6 U.S.C. 313</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1FFC00DAB2C541FA9F0D358CDD8DCD70" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Section 504 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/314">6 U.S.C. 314</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HABF7C92EC3B54C9CAAA383E6E161A143" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Section 505 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/315">6 U.S.C. 315</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEF3B89D2E36F4B809DD4C71934562B95" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Section 506 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/316">6 U.S.C. 316</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5EB1DDA610504D5A90B8FEA2A50154B1" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Section 507 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/317">6 U.S.C. 317</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8061D3EB7F2944C0A76159FB697973E4" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Section 508 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/318">6 U.S.C. 318</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H57597A97853946EC802442D5D420EC4B" commented="no"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Section 509 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/319">6 U.S.C. 319</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H28F623939706404E9FF08C1110C4FD6E" commented="no"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Section 510 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/320">6 U.S.C. 320</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE7B3A357C8F04ADC90F792DBDE97C863" commented="no"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Section 513 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/321b">6 U.S.C. 321b</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6C55EC4577B9433C980776BF9D19870E" commented="no"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Section 514 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/321c">6 U.S.C. 321c</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H57931F377AFF4411BA6AA5EA4710EE78" commented="no"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Section 519 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/321h">6 U.S.C. 321h</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6DAE6E62FBAF437D8CF7B97AED7027D5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Redesignations</header><text>Sections 502, 511, 512, 515, 517, 518, 520, 521, 522, 523, 524, 525, 526, 527, 528, and 529 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/312">6 U.S.C. 312</external-xref>, 321, 321a, 321d, 321f, 321g, 321i, 321j, 321k, 321l, 321m, 321n, 321o, 321p, 321q, and 321r) are redesignated as sections 501 through 516, respectively.</text></subsection><subsection id="HBC31B91C79AF4CD39341D081142747AE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Title heading</header><text>The heading for title V of such Act is amended by striking <quote><header-in-text level="title" style="OLC">National Emergency Management</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="title" style="OLC">Other Offices and Functions</header-in-text></quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H710B83D9EF414FA0B285DCE54B1AC8D9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents contained in section 1(b) of such Act is amended by striking the items relating to title V and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H9944C159AEB84D67B45D804D0DEBDD54" display-inline="no-display-inline"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="title">TITLE V—OTHER OFFICES AND FUNCTIONS</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 501. Definition.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 502. The National Infrastructure Simulation and Analysis Center.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 503. Evacuation plans and exercises.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 504. National Operations Center.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 505. Nuclear incident response.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 506. Conduct of certain public health-related activities.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 507. Use of commercially available technology, goods, and services.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 508. Procurement of security countermeasures for strategic national stockpile.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 509. Model standards and guidelines for critical infrastructure workers.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 510. Guidance and recommendations.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 511. Voluntary private sector preparedness accreditation and certification program.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 512. Acceptance of gifts.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 513. Integrated public alert and warning system modernization.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 514. National planning and education.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 515. Coordination of Department of Homeland Security efforts related to food, agriculture, and veterinary defense against terrorism.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 516. Transfer of equipment during a public health emergency.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H4E8FD26B5A6E475DAE6E71B53D1E2680" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall take effect on the date on which the transfers of functions by section 6 are carried out.</text></subsection></section><section id="HF72EA59416A14F4ABA068C465B5CAAAE"><enum>11.</enum><header>Homeland security grants</header><subsection id="H462D033E7E234F11B4945452FFC35F5B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>References to Administrator</header><text>Title XX of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/601">6 U.S.C. 601 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H36BE2B3093B44EEEA2E3C1AB72DF9D14"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 2002(a) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/603">6 U.S.C. 603(a)</external-xref>) by striking <quote>, through the Administrator,</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H807ED5D77D0B4485A73D2841F0993D4D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 2009(a) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/609a">6 U.S.C. 609a(a)</external-xref>) by striking <quote>, acting through the Administrator,</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H994C62B9BAE845F3BF0757373BACC977"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in the subsection heading for section 2022(c) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/612">6 U.S.C. 612(c)</external-xref>) by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">by the Administrator</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD7C9DACBC0AB4DC3A89382929EC02629"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Administrator</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>Secretary</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDF6CD786FFF848BC9ED7616934870C7B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>Title XX of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/601">6 U.S.C. 601 et seq.</external-xref>), as amended by subsection (a), is further amended—</text><paragraph id="H677755DB50254377B815A73195DA6029"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 2001(1) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/601">6 U.S.C. 601(1)</external-xref>) by striking <quote>Secretary</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>Director</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6C72CFA606794C6D98BDE95F9D87E862"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 2006(b)(4)(F) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/607">6 U.S.C. 607(b)(4)(F)</external-xref>) by striking <quote>Secretary</quote> and inserting <quote>Director</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0F0E0BFB7D4646FF8BA3151C0FEE773C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in section 2006(b)(5) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/607">6 U.S.C. 607(b)(5)</external-xref>) by striking <quote>Secretary</quote> and inserting <quote>Director</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7189140956C348C3B4E73E6E0B557EB8" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this section shall take effect on the date on which the transfers of functions by section 6 are carried out.</text></subsection></section><section id="H76460E8B02B2488FBEAA3E184259C587"><enum>12.</enum><header>Conforming amendments to other laws</header><subsection id="H16F9398220BB4017B934F390FC575024" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Improvements to information technology</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 640(a) of the Post-Katrina Emergency Management Reform Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/727">6 U.S.C. 727(a)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>, in coordination with the Chief Information Officer of the Department,</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA837A489DA6B4D3DA6928CBA45A22131"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Chief Financial Officer</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 901(b)(2) of title 31, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H2DE3B9BAD2DD48B89866C503B93F7E4B" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="HAE3094739F73480A928FF6B87C4C14D6" indent="up1"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal Emergency Management Agency.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H96AA2B974E65474093BFA7CB93666241"><enum>(c)</enum><header>References</header><text>Subsection (c) of section 612 of the Post-Katrina Emergency Management Reform Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/313">6 U.S.C. 313</external-xref> note) is repealed.</text></subsection><subsection id="H381B8485BCD54AC88A4E1A9A1D301CBE" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this section shall take effect on the date on which the transfers of functions by section 6 are carried out.</text></subsection></section><section id="H730238177E3A4EE1A84BA3741040691F"><enum>13.</enum><header>Report on recommended legislation</header><subsection id="H9C5338D446BF48C4B7B5038972AF9422"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After consultation with Congress, the Director shall prepare a report describing recommended legislation for additional technical and conforming amendments to reflect the changes made by this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H525E9E678F204C3DA1C626807D83DA61"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Submission to Congress</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the last day of the transition period referred to in section 6(c), the Director shall submit to Congress the report referred to in subsection (a).</text></subsection></section><section id="H635029F922B64497A2BF2329E425856D"><enum>14.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H34ACFA7CF4F14986BA6DEAEAF0F2BB13"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Agency</quote> means the Federal Emergency Management Agency established by section 2. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC25E4508216349488CD61C15F25AE458"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The term <quote>Director</quote> means the Director of the Federal Emergency Management Agency established by section 3(a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H17FC607AD127459CACCFF7324E64B35C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Hazard</header><text>The term <quote>hazard</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 602(a) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5195a">42 U.S.C. 5195a(a)</external-xref>) and includes any major disaster or emergency.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H19E80EB90B494A3BBFC3643F15B04EAE"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Inspector General</header><text>The term <quote>Inspector General</quote> means the Inspector General of the Federal Emergency Management Agency established by section 5.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

