<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H715D0C6A88D64289A78C11C694302261" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4945 IH: Growing Opportunities in Agriculture Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4945</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250808">August 8, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000467">Mr. Thompson of Pennsylvania</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="A000379">Mr. Alford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001063">Mr. Cuellar</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Education to award grants for new agricultural education programs in secondary schools.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD9B3625ACE2D4FC180DAA43F442BEF71" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HDD484F31DB894FBC8F6AFC077C39644C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Growing Opportunities in Agriculture Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>GO Ag Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H16B091E8DACA49A0875CB05C981E9F20"><enum>2.</enum><header>Grant program for new agricultural education programs</header> <subsection id="H91E4AD36AB9549BB8BF729E19C799A00"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grant program authorized</header> <paragraph id="HD578865618FE4091907A29BBE80F86AF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall award, on a competitive basis, grants to eligible entities to support the creation of new agricultural education programs in secondary schools.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8E181B0E4CE7494086AFC963EA883BC9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Grant duration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A grant awarded under this section may not exceed a 5-year grant period.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H3C4850796A864747B6C150349F7B5911"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header> <paragraph id="H63AFF2E2CDE64D2E8935C1BC33553388"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To receive a grant under this section, an eligible entity shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require, including—</text>
<subparagraph id="H88672DFC8D7E40A1B145DBC9FF7038A2"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an identification and the role with respect to each program to be funded under the grant of any eligible partners of the eligible entity, including an assurance the grant under this section will not be used to prepare students for employment with solely one or more of such eligible partners;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1B386CFA4B394CA894B5DC60C21592CB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an assurance that each program that will receive assistance under the grant is not yet in operation and such grant will be used to start such program;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HCB5221E3EA3D4B459D01D987FEE9343C"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of the grant budget, how each program will fund necessary expenses for the program not covered by the grant (such as any funds to be provided by State, local, or private entities), and how the eligible entity will continue each such program after the grant is exhausted;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0FEC7AA1323C4713B0594461F528374A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a description of how grant will directly benefit students, including special populations, served by the eligible entity;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H98BBCAB38BE74D9EA114FA541E1691F5"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of how each such program will be coordinated with the activities carried out under section 124 or 135 of the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/2344">20 U.S.C. 2344</external-xref>; 2355);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB17BA5B8F5114885BCC66A46494D015A"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of how each such program reflects the needs of regional, State, or local employers, as demonstrated by the comprehensive needs assessment under section 134(c) of the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/2354">20 U.S.C. 2354(c)</external-xref>) carried out by the eligible entity; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H42EF04E2E16343CEB929BDDBA4DB165A"><enum>(G)</enum><text>an assurance that the eligible entity will—</text> <clause id="HB3C08B13E2C04BFDBF08C8156C321658"><enum>(i)</enum><text>provide information to the Secretary, as requested, for the evaluation under subsection (d) and any evaluations that the Secretary may carry out; and</text></clause>
<clause id="HA378A543EADA42A79B2CE7FE958AFB23"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>make data available to third parties for validation, in accordance with applicable data privacy laws, including section 444 of the General Education Provisions Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1232g">20 U.S.C. 1232g</external-xref>, commonly known as the <quote>Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act of 1974</quote>).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5D60783822E24D01A95304061B595595"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Process</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall create a process for evaluating applications submitted under paragraph (1) and determining the amount of each grant for successful applications, except that in no case may an eligible entity receive a grant exceeding $100,000.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HA84305E116044338B66CCDF04960FEF6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Uses of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each eligible entity receiving a grant under this section shall use such grant for the creation of new agricultural education programs in secondary schools, which may include—</text> <paragraph id="H44AA5B66C99B492BB29CC8B27A900D46"><enum>(1)</enum><text>curriculum development and delivery, including classroom or laboratory instruction, work-based learning, and leadership education delivered through career and technical student organizations;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H02187A96A46543B184BF8495A0784E04"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the purchase of equipment, technology, and course materials; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA7F57DF41F7E427EAD8CE784AB8D4614"><enum>(3)</enum><text>other costs the Secretary may determine to be eligible.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HEBC699D51FD04BEFB0A7BEF7E51FB117"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Evaluation and annual report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each eligible entity receiving a grant under this section shall provide for an independent evaluation of the activities carried out using such grant and submit to the Secretary an annual report that includes—</text> <paragraph id="HB652AA7E61F540EAACD24C2905855FF0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a description of how the grant was used;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7DED498A4B2344CEAA12C6072F476487"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the performance of each program assistance with such grant with respect to, at a minimum, the performance indicators described under section 113 of the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/2323">20 U.S.C. 2323</external-xref>), as applicable, and disaggregated—</text> <subparagraph id="HAE1B18DD7D924B9EBB834AE7C01DB514"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by subgroups of students described in section 1111(c)(2)(B) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6311">20 U.S.C. 6311(c)(2)(B)</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD15A6A2DE53F422985A5163F7FF296F7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by each special population; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H26EF992CE0884096A691BBC28CE618A0" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a quantitative analysis of the effectiveness of each such program.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HD96D629DC5D74B7CAD6EE1EFE69A2DF1"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HB18DED94A5A44CB091399921BBEBE8D0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agricultural education</header><text>The term <term>agricultural education</term> means career and technical education that is focused on agriculture, including classroom or laboratory instruction, work-based learning, and leadership education delivered through career and technical student organizations.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HEEB6D65F46A84E58B1576883F5C8368E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> has the meaning given the term <term>eligible recipient</term> in section 3(21)(A) of the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/2302">20 U.S.C. 2302(21)(A)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5DF1770AC5F0462B970715BFC4377C63"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligible partner</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible partner</term> means—</text>
<subparagraph id="H2815BC9871CF4B2995FE28F94854572D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an institution of higher education or a consortium of such institutions; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H818F2C1D645B4140A4E0C68D22299851"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a community stakeholder relevant to a program to be funded under this section, including a labor organization, a local or regional business or industry, or a local workforce development board.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HF82663918CEF45E8B43FEA8992546DD8"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $5,000,000, to remain available through fiscal year 2028.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

