<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9C704A1AEF9545778ED8E1164B4A0C9C" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 701 IH: Of inquiry requesting the President of the United States to furnish certain information to the House of Representatives relating to the Department of Government Efficiency’s access to and usage of NUMIDENT and other personally identifiable information in the possession of the Social Security Administration.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 701</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250911">September 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000557">Mr. Larson of Connecticut</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="N000015">Mr. Neal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000399">Mr. Doggett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001156">Ms. S&#225;nchez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001296">Mr. Boyle of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001190">Mr. Schneider</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000585">Mr. Gomez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001066">Mr. Horsford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000610">Ms. Plaskett</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001201">Mr. Suozzi</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Of inquiry requesting the President of the United States to furnish certain information to the House of Representatives relating to the Department of Government Efficiency&#8217;s access to and usage of NUMIDENT and other personally identifiable information in the possession of the Social Security Administration.</official-title></form><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H5308417FA2D84CB0A5409EA30BBE35FC"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H60620D604A6B4F3CB64389883065B86B"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the President of the United States is requested to furnish the House of Representatives, not later than 14 days after the date of adoption of this resolution, copies of any document, record, audio recording, memorandum, call log, correspondence (electronic or otherwise), audit trails and audit logs, written agreements, or other communication in his possession, or any portion of any document, record, audio recording, memorandum, call log, correspondence (electronic or otherwise), or other communication, that refers or relates to the following:</text> <paragraph id="H6DE58813F7384734856611DFDCEB9459"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The development of a cloud environment that hosts a copy of the Social Security Administration’s Numerical Identification System (hereafter referred to as <quote>NUMIDENT</quote>), including risk assessments and security protocols.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA18B1F3C50BF4BD39AFF7AA895383D52"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The purpose of creating a cloud environment that hosts a copy of the NUMIDENT, including whether the copy will be used to:</text> <subparagraph id="H13577240D98B47009EA56F13BC8F003F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>conduct Federal audits and investigations;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8BD3E33E31D74EBC90CD0A3781596BDE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>restrict or deny Social Security benefits, Medicare coverage, or any other benefits;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDC341E9BE94247B68E217C6CE98E7796"> <enum>(C)</enum> <text>develop a centralized database for the Federal Government that compiles citizens’ personal information across Federal agencies and departments;</text>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H80A7553844014BA68A08F0D635C3989C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>sell or make available information contained in the copy for private purchase; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1D9117A326D74EE3B97A286AA526B915"><enum>(E)</enum><text>train and enhance artificial intelligence.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H567C080D7A1D49BAB86D1609878B961C"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Access to, and usage of, NUMIDENT information hosted in such cloud environment by Edward Coristine, Aram Moghaddassi, John Solly, Michael Russo, or any other individual, including those acting for or on behalf of the Department of Government Efficiency (hereafter referred to as <quote>DOGE</quote>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H77A9A85530F84E10925485A725E8B795"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Access to, and usage of, personally identifiable information inside the Social Security Administration’s Enterprise Data Warehouse on or after March 14, 2025, by Payton Rehling, Aram Moghaddassi, or any other individuals acting for or on behalf of DOGE. </text></paragraph> </section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

