<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7792B701CEFA426D98FD5789CAA7F6F2" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5726 IH: DOD Entrepreneurial Innovation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5726</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251010">October 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C000059">Mr. Calvert</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/303">chapter 303</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code, to require the Secretary of each military department to identify promising research programs of the Small Business Innovation Research Program or Small Business Technology Transfer Program for inclusion in the future budgets and plans of the Department of Defense, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H153B834429FA4881978AA5D24A08498D" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HB08A120237E747548E53AA24F9ECADB1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>DOD Entrepreneurial Innovation Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H7F95CDB418E84A9D88F4E702EF37E09F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Entrepreneurial Innovation Project designations</header> <subsection id="H4767B4900B5D49AAB516678BD71100D8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header> <paragraph id="H60F11F411D0346CEA77C3768414F4582"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Designating certain SBIR and STTR programs as Entrepreneurial Innovation Projects</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/303">Chapter 303</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/4062">section 4062</external-xref> the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8FF6384914E840B5840EFCDD557E145C"> 
<section id="H4CDFB20429BE4560BDAEDE25403B59BB"><enum>4063.</enum><header>Entrepreneurial Innovation Project designations</header> 
<subsection id="HD156C0CB999B4A35AE31CD80E04E22BC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the first fiscal year beginning after the date of the enactment of this section, and during each subsequent fiscal year, each Secretary concerned, in consultation with each chief of an armed force under the jurisdiction of the Secretary concerned, shall designate not less than five eligible programs as Entrepreneurial Innovation Projects.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H930AF2428CCC40B1A86A064F3DBE86AD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text>An eligible program seeking designation as an Entrepreneurial Innovation Project under this section shall submit to the Secretary concerned an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary concerned determines appropriate.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2B58C4E35D134AEEAF841667F5F10087"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Designation criteria</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In making designations under subsection (a), the Secretary concerned shall consider—</text> <paragraph id="H9EC420140EE242D5AAB8538DF63475E4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the potential of the eligible program to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF3F5E07D25584CB6A9A315BEEC18EE5F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>advance the national security capabilities of the United States;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H08B1ED4958D14888961715E925485531"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide new technologies or processes, or new applications of existing technologies, that will enable new alternatives to existing programs; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H917FEA98BFB14C46B3BD2F151F726B74"><enum>(C)</enum><text>provide future cost savings;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4DB81CABEDEB4046984C846D572888A3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>whether an advisory panel has recommended the eligible program for designation; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBA061FA6FE814ED6AC62E5AA3A904BC1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such other criteria that the Secretary concerned determines to be appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H21AFB96A723F49B5A9920C47280E0639"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Designation benefits</header> <paragraph id="HED8819FA2C9F496C8E7CCE9C7A35DA44"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Future years defense program inclusion</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to each designated program, the Secretary of Defense shall include in the next future-years defense program the estimated expenditures of such designated program. In the preceding sentence, the term <term>next future-years defense program</term> means the future-years defense program submitted to Congress under section 221 of this title after the date on which such designated program is designated under subsection (a).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H64A8B0046202491B87AC44D0BC79A416"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Programming proposal</header><text>Each designated program shall be included by the Secretary concerned under a separate heading in any programming proposals submitted to the Secretary of Defense.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3350D610B24B4BB7ACA18BA46ACDD855"><enum>(3)</enum><header>PPBE component</header><text>Each designated program shall be considered by the Secretary concerned as an integral part of the planning, programming, budgeting, and execution process of the Department of Defense.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HACE5A852DCE240349BADE1EEB6810866"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Entrepreneurial Innovation Advisory Panels</header> 
<paragraph id="H94AF57739BE149A594D5D577DD5BC552"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For each military department, the Secretary concerned shall establish an advisory panel that, starting in the first fiscal year beginning after the date of the enactment of this section, and in each subsequent fiscal year, shall identify and recommend to the Secretary concerned for designation under subsection (a) eligible programs based on the criteria described in subsection (c)(1).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0475349C736842C48AA11CA22BD10211"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Membership</header> <subparagraph id="H945CC581D3B8415B8910FAD7C2F4693E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Composition</header> <clause id="H2924EB01303F4E91AB92B5F70DD4FD7B"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each advisory panel shall be composed of four members appointed by the Secretary concerned and one member appointed by the chief of the relevant armed force under the jurisdiction of the Secretary concerned.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H294EDAE428884176AF03A36DDC4860BC"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Secretary concerned appointments</header><text>The Secretary concerned shall appoint members to the advisory panel as follows:</text> <subclause id="HFD73F195E1EB4DEA94335C5E5C148148"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Three members who—</text> 
<item id="H01C5F0BFCC844E8BA86118332C4219B9"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>have experience with private sector entrepreneurial innovation, including development and implementation of such innovations into well established markets; and</text></item> <item id="H682C86976A9B42EAB172772808ADC5AC"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>are not employed by the Federal Government.</text></item></subclause> 
<subclause id="HD722D40878D2492F89BD2F31DB5E508A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>One member who is in the Senior Executive Service in the acquisition workforce (as defined in section 1705 of this title) of the relevant military department.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HE76170F3C2F245759DD814F580626EFD"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Service chief appointment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The chief of an armed force under the jurisdiction of the Secretary concerned shall appoint to the advisory panel one member who is a member of such armed forces.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HED0EE5FD7519484EADB4B84A6B3CA823"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Terms</header> 
<clause id="H40806ED63E224212870FFAF95DDA6FB3"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Private sector members</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Members described in subparagraph (A)(ii)(I) shall serve for a term of three years, except that of the members first appointed—</text> <subclause id="H8D20F3E4CA5F4008B32606CEB82D69A6"><enum>(I)</enum><text>one shall serve a term of one year;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H71A2814BE4C245F385759678BDACF1D6"><enum>(II)</enum><text>one shall serve a term of two years; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H87BB7A7D5522463DB0C493A25D053C2C"><enum>(III)</enum><text>one shall serve a term of three years.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H469BF22C00634CBAA88E3F3D3B3D2418">
                      <enum>(ii)</enum>
                      <header>Federal Government employees</header>
 <text>Members described in clause (ii)(II) or (iii) of subparagraph (A) shall serve for a term of two years, except that the first member appointed under subparagraph (A)(iii) shall serve for a term of one year.</text>
                    </clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD265766402724BECBD2AB5D1BB576744"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Chair</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The chair for each advisory panel shall be as follows:</text> <clause id="HA2B1E3E35512476AACD15CC841400752"><enum>(i)</enum><text>For the first year of operation of each such advisory panel, and every other year thereafter, the member appointed under subparagraph (A)(iii).</text></clause> 
<clause id="H5D6010A5E0AA40CDAF08CC13E8C8499D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>For the second year of operation of each such advisory panel, and every other year thereafter, the member appointed under subparagraph (A)(ii)(II).</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE2E23993584D4C9CA19CE1AD016F7F9F"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Vacancies</header><text>A vacancy in an advisory panel shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3DA1822D5E8C4D03BC70EA5458ED6E84"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Conflict of interest</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Members and staff of each advisory panel shall disclose to the relevant Secretary concerned, and such Secretary concerned shall mitigate to the extent practicable, any professional or organizational conflict of interest of such members or staff arising from service on the advisory panel.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H755A4893742F4810A2E3C67826B2D409"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Compensation</header> <clause id="HE21301565EEA45DC991B68C17E4A9A7D"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Private sector member compensation</header><text>Except as provided in clause (ii), members of an advisory panel, and the support staff of such members, shall be compensated at a rate determined reasonable by the Secretary concerned and shall be reimbursed in accordance with section 5703 of title 5 for reasonable travel costs and expenses incurred in performing duties as members of an advisory panel.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HE49CE8BBF99042CBA0AC8952B9CD73E2">
                      <enum>(ii)</enum>
                      <header>Prohibition on compensation of Federal employees</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Members of an advisory panel who are full-time officers or employees of the United States or Members of Congress may not receive additional pay, allowances, or benefits by reason of their service on an advisory panel.</text>
                    </clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4491B68E348047B3BDA1E5F0FF25E445"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Selection process</header> 
<subparagraph id="H54B57AB2B3C24064B293A9308264B583"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Initial selection</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each advisory panel shall select not less than ten eligible programs that have submitted an application under subsection (b).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAE1DE250B5754B16B76E63077E4F641A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Program plans</header> <clause id="H259D6CBF411045FBA501B622C96EB9F8"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each eligible program selected under subparagraph (A) may submit to the advisory panel that selected such eligible program a program plan containing the five-year goals, execution plans, schedules, and funding needs of such eligible program.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H88FF71D5ACBC47F8A6DB43B3B84DE4B1"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Support</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each Secretary concerned shall, to the greatest extent practicable, provide eligible programs selected under subparagraph (A) with access to information to support the development of the program plans described in clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H825E5FF0A7184655A7BD3023F6D30926"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Final selection</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each advisory panel shall recommend to the Secretary concerned for designation under subsection (a) not less than five eligible programs that submitted a program plan under subparagraph (B) to such advisory panel. If there are less than five such eligible programs, such advisory panel may recommend to the Secretary concerned for designation under subsection (a) less than five such eligible programs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCC810DBABF224CE2BBF6A536AD884BCF"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Administrative and technical support</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary concerned shall provide the relevant advisory panel with such administrative support, staff, and technical assistance as the Secretary concerned determines necessary for such advisory panel to carry out it duties.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDA60F6AEA8274C10B6816C9EBB7BE16A"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>The Secretary of Defense may use amounts available from the Department of Defense Acquisition Workforce Development Account established under section 1705 of this title to support the activities of advisory panels.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAC9A9F59DDF746C5A83F05A9DDE4B868"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Inapplicability of FACA</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/10">Chapter 10</external-xref> of title 5 shall not apply to the advisory panels established under this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE6C790D65E41446AB3FD5242EF6F46E7"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Revocation of designation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary concerned determines that a designated program cannot reasonably meet the objectives of such designated program in the relevant programming proposal referred to in subsection (d)(2) or such objectives are irrelevant, such Secretary concerned may revoke the designation.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB633F14A559A48368A57BF8A494FAC4C"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Report to congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense shall submit to Congress an annual report describing each designated program and the progress each designated program has made toward achieving the objectives of the designated program.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H945636EC5C504EF9A7BAE30EDD594976"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H1F47F8D699A74B72B93A2968796D202D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Advisory panel</header><text>The term <term>advisory panel</term> means an advisory panel established under subsection (e)(1).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9BB2F68FDCAC4FED83B511CE46069D37"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Designated program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>designated program</term> means an eligible program that has been designated as an Entrepreneurial Innovation Project under this section.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB0326EFA82C14FF98B7C09EFFC5F1F4E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligible program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible program</term> means work performed pursuant to a Phase III agreement (as such term is defined in section 9(r)(2) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/638">15 U.S.C. 638(r)(2)</external-xref>)).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEC09394230A3471988FAC59C9B4CDFB6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections at the beginning of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/303">chapter 303</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code, is amended by striking the item relating to section 4063 and inserting after the item relating to section 4062 the following new item:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1EA2F51968FE433B99B70D5BEDE9BE6A"> 
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry level="section">4063. Entrepreneurial Innovation Project designations.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2A2B6A7135B54C23B651C7DEB6F6316B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment deadline</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretaries of each military department shall establish the advisory panels described in section 4063(e) of title 10, United States Code, as added by subsection (a).</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

