<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H037791E582874880A4788342027FF3E6" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 126 IH: Celebrating the legacy and contributions of immigrants and opposing discriminatory immigration policies.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 126</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250212">February 12, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000635">Ms. Dexter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000399">Mr. Doggett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Celebrating the legacy and contributions of immigrants and opposing discriminatory immigration policies.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the United States of America was founded by immigrants seeking freedom, security, and opportunity;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States is best when it serves as a haven for those seeking a better, more secure, more prosperous life;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas President George Washington said, <quote>[Let] the poor, the needy, and oppressed of the Earth, and those who want Land, resort to the fertile lands of our western country, the second land of Promise, and there dwell in peace, fulfilling the first and great commandment.</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas President Ronald Reagan said, <quote>Our nation is a nation of immigrants. More than any other country, our strength comes from our own immigrant heritage and our capacity to welcome those from other lands.</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas President George W. Bush said, <quote>It says something about our country that people around the world are willing to leave their homes and leave their families and risk everything to come to America. Their talent and hard work and love of freedom have helped make America the leader of the world.</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas immigrants have enriched American society in countless ways, contributing to its economy, culture, arts, and sciences;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas immigrants have served in the United States Armed Forces in disproportionate numbers, defending the Nation with bravery and distinction;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas immigrants have played a vital role in the growth and prosperity of the American economy, filling critical labor shortages and starting businesses that create jobs and drive economic growth;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas immigrants have strengthened United States communities, bringing diverse perspectives, skills, and talents that enrich the social fabric of the United States and make it a more vibrant and inclusive Nation;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas discriminatory immigration policies, including family separation, arbitrary detention of asylum seekers, and the targeting of immigrants based on their race, religion, or national origin are contrary to the values of freedom, justice, and equality upon which the Nation was founded;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas such anti-immigrant policies have a devastating impact on immigrant families and communities, causing trauma, fear, and economic hardship, as well as to the national economy;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas arbitrary anti-immigrant travel bans fail the security and economic needs of the United States causing unnecessary harm and confusion; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas a welcoming and inclusive immigration system is essential for the continued prosperity and strength of the United States: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HBC07CDC99BDD426EA1EB6DCE9B65B84F"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HD9CAB38E701A459DBDB17FFB80613021"><enum/><text>That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="H5FEEF79BE5CF416CA713DEB25E906D83"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recognizes and celebrates the invaluable contributions of immigrants to the United States of America;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1FE33E47D2604E11A782CCB241404DA5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>condemns all forms of discrimination against immigrants, including racial profiling, religious discrimination, and the targeting of immigrants based on their national origin;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H079CC31EACDD44F1821A93880E10B3CE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>urges the Administration to uphold the rights and dignity of all immigrants, including asylum seekers and refugees;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF2265D03C75D4CDF88F290678C6A46FD"><enum>(4)</enum><text>calls for the implementation of humane immigration policies that prioritize family unity, protect human rights, and promote a pathway to citizenship for longtime residents; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEF9AC55BC3D542079BB1729BDF7C6094"><enum>(5)</enum><text>supports comprehensive immigration reform that addresses the needs of the United States economy, strengthens its communities, and reflects the values of compassion, fairness, and opportunity for all.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

