<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Placed-on-Calendar-Senate" dms-id="HDE597C48785348269C7D2EE618966B0D" public-private="public" key="G" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1402 PCS: Transparency In Charges for Key Events Ticketing Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><calendar>Calendar No. 163</calendar><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1402</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250430">April 30, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Received</action-desc></action><action><action-date date="20250916">September 16, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Read twice and placed on the calendar</action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require sellers of event tickets to disclose comprehensive information to consumers about ticket prices and related fees, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9CE9FFF35CDC464AA1F18882FBD2D8B9" style="OLC"><section id="H14957A5BA38A498DAA52B62529D99CF1" commented="no" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Transparency In Charges for Key Events Ticketing Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>TICKET Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H67C32F94560C433EBD7353DE81885AFA" commented="no"><enum>2.</enum><header>All inclusive ticket price disclosure</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Beginning 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, it shall be unlawful for a ticket issuer, secondary market ticket issuer, or secondary market ticket exchange to offer for sale an event ticket unless the ticket issuer, secondary market ticket issuer, or secondary market ticket exchange—</text><paragraph id="H31CBECF5A8F34C7E88F25296FF6C37D9" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>clearly and conspicuously displays the total event ticket price, if a price is displayed, in any advertisement, marketing, or price list wherever the ticket is offered for sale;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H70F770F4A28144A19A0ECC057BDBCE99" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>clearly and conspicuously discloses to any individual who seeks to purchase an event ticket the total event ticket price at the time the ticket is first displayed to the individual and anytime thereafter throughout the ticket purchasing process; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3A881693A76C4E739FBF177905464359" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provides an itemized list of the base event ticket price and each event ticket fee prior to the completion of the ticket purchasing process.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HFA5498F0B2A24ACE81C832A5308C9E50" commented="no"><enum>3.</enum><header>Speculative ticketing ban</header><subsection id="HE9E735884D694334B6C242893CFE3582" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>Beginning 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, a ticket issuer, secondary market ticket issuer, or secondary market ticket exchange that does not have actual or constructive possession of an event ticket shall not sell, offer for sale, or advertise for sale such event ticket.</text></subsection><subsection id="H922FE8D1A7C74870BDE43145250246F8" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Services permitted</header><text>Notwithstanding subsection (a), a secondary market ticket issuer or secondary market ticket exchange may sell, offer for sale, or advertise for sale a service to an individual to obtain an event ticket on behalf of such individual if the secondary market ticket issuer or secondary market ticket exchange complies with the following:</text><paragraph id="HCE8F9D350C364F7F8544040A968FBE24" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Does not market or list the service as an event ticket.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF499C778ACE6470CA94425446A26CF2C" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Maintains a clear, distinct, and easily discernible separation between the service and event tickets that persists throughout the entire service selection and purchasing process.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H53AD1CFF3E35481BAAC222B709E85116" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Clearly and conspicuously discloses before selection of the service that the service is not an event ticket and that the purchase of the service does not guarantee an event ticket.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H62E41195D4404DACBFC6ABF99309A758" commented="no"><enum>4.</enum><header>Disclosures</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">A ticket issuer, secondary market ticket issuer, or secondary market ticket exchange—</text><paragraph id="H10CD21803A0F4E97B8768377866B9296" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>if offering an event ticket for resale, shall provide a clear and conspicuous statement, before a consumer purchases the event ticket from the ticket issuer, secondary market ticket issuer, or secondary market ticket exchange, that the issuer or exchange is engaged in the secondary sale of event tickets;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1623F960391345E68E7AB6EA8E062A3B" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall not state that the ticket issuer, secondary market ticket issuer, or secondary market ticket exchange is affiliated with or endorsed by a venue, team, or artist, as applicable, including by using words like <quote>official</quote> in promotional materials, social media promotions, or paid advertising, unless a partnership agreement has been executed or the issuer or exchange has the express written consent of the venue, team, or artist, as applicable; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7E7620068FDF415A9018EA12F5178E12"><enum>(3)</enum><text>shall not include the name of the venue, including any misspelling of any such name, in a domain name, or any subdomain thereof, in the URL of the secondary market ticket issuer or secondary market ticket exchange unless authorized by the owner of the venue.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HE0FF0357E1444570ACC456383A622D84" commented="no"><enum>5.</enum><header>Refund requirements</header><subsection id="H9E29CEB06F2A42C78D7529DDA36CF59B" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Cancellation</header><text>Beginning 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, if an event is canceled or postponed (except for a case in which an event is canceled or postponed due to a cause beyond the reasonable control of the issuer, including a natural disaster, civil disturbance, or otherwise unforeseeable impediment), a ticket issuer, secondary market ticket issuer, or secondary market ticket exchange shall provide the purchaser of an event ticket from the issuer or exchange for the canceled or postponed event, at a minimum—</text><paragraph id="HBD37840A34F14056B4DE0F2F051D2AB6" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>if the event is cancelled, a full refund for the total event ticket price;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1878C21F1309491DA3D61000D1DAB067" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>subject to availability, if the event is postponed for not more than 6 months and the original event ticket is no longer valid for entry to the rescheduled event, a replacement event ticket for the rescheduled event in the same or a comparable location once the event has been rescheduled; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H89C988B2FFDD4FAD917F97B35CF1E538" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the event is postponed for more than 6 months, at the option of the purchaser—</text><subparagraph id="HB0ED9B1913B340CF804D83B4213C1BEB" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a full refund for the total event ticket price; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE8D227CFC8A543E8BA5F51580548C3D7" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the original event ticket is no longer valid for entry to the rescheduled event, a replacement event ticket for the rescheduled event in the same or a comparable location once the event has been rescheduled.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H84BC7B897DAC4DABB2D738B1CE892428" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Disclosure of guarantee and refund policy required</header><text>Beginning 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, a ticket issuer, secondary market ticket issuer, or secondary market ticket exchange shall disclose clearly and conspicuously to a purchaser before the completion of an event ticket sale the guarantee or refund policy of such ticket issuer, secondary market ticket issuer, or secondary market ticket exchange, including under what circumstances any refund issued will include a refund of any event ticket fee.</text></subsection><subsection id="H0120737E5D4C40F1BFD3FEF1F48586C8" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Disclosure of how To obtain a refund required</header><text>Beginning 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, a ticket issuer, secondary market ticket issuer, or secondary market ticket exchange shall provide a clear and conspicuous explanation of how to obtain a refund of the total event ticket price.</text></subsection></section><section id="HDDEADB84102B4830BAFAD6A4CA86089A" commented="no"><enum>6.</enum><header>Report by the Federal Trade Commission on BOTS Act of 2016 enforcement</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 6 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Commission shall submit to Congress a report on enforcement of the Better Online Ticket Sales Act of 2016 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/274">Public Law 114–274</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/45c">15 U.S.C. 45c</external-xref>), including any enforcement action taken, challenges with enforcement and coordination with State Attorneys General, and recommendations on how to improve enforcement and industry compliance.</text></section><section id="H445FF925912F43BCB141168FEECF43A3" commented="no"><enum>7.</enum><header>Enforcement</header><subsection id="H679E3F47F6644A19A4FB1116D1B79A3F" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Unfair or deceptive act or practice</header><text>A violation of this Act shall be treated as a violation of a rule defining an unfair or deceptive act or practice under section 18(a)(1)(B) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/57a">15 U.S.C. 57a(a)(1)(B)</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection id="HAFC8FD435CE44207A89C87982DADCA87" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Powers of commission</header><paragraph id="HC4A0A1FCB71A42538B786DCB24C9FF9A" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission shall enforce this Act in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though all applicable terms and provisions of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>) were incorporated into and made a part of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC184A843C17F48C3BA946DB696244DAF" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Privileges and immunities</header><text>Any person who violates this Act shall be subject to the penalties and entitled to the privileges and immunities provided in the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HECF9D62CDDB94329A6441FEFB311813D" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Authority preserved</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to limit the authority of the Commission under any other provision of law.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H2118C5845AF748DF9A01C808C0BA196B" commented="no"><enum>8.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H07B4CD90B84B45B980B7922F271AE793" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Artist</header><text>The term <term>artist</term> means any performer, musician, comedian, producer, ensemble or production entity of a theatrical production, sports team owner, or similar person.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF54924AEC7C44266BFB05425AE48AD20" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Base event ticket price</header><text>The term <term>base event ticket price</term> means, with respect to an event ticket, the price of the event ticket excluding the cost of any event ticket fees.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H90A34876436F498184A21107C65573B0" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Federal Trade Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H001F0AE9D8DB4C71B8EA086FADACA159" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Event</header><text>The term <term>event</term> means any live concert, theatrical performance, sporting event, show, or similarly scheduled live activity, that is—</text><subparagraph id="HB888DE4A6FEC4947B4801D093433CAB8" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>taking place in a venue with a seating or attendance capacity exceeding 200 persons;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCF1BE77F1B3C4666BBB2DF3F3505C506" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>open to the general public; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H91AE2B447DBD4B7A99C75BE4105D6C26" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>promoted, advertised, or marketed in interstate commerce, or for which event tickets are generally sold or distributed in interstate commerce.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD1461B670A644B0F95BEBEA151C877D5" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Event ticket; ticket issuer</header><text>The terms <term>event ticket</term> and <term>ticket issuer</term> have the meaning given those terms in the Better Online Ticket Sales Act of 2016 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/274">Public Law 114–274</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC005CD4FAC584763B09A56C058861D00" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Event ticket fee</header><text>The term <term>event ticket fee</term>—</text><subparagraph id="H0C1DA287F2404C22BC41FB2853EDEAE0" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means a charge for an event ticket that must be paid in addition to the base event ticket price in order to obtain an event ticket from a ticket issuer, secondary market ticket issuer, or secondary market ticket exchange, including any service fee, charge and order processing fee, delivery fee, facility charge fee, tax, and any other charge; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7ACD3361854F40229953F7AEEFA1DEEC" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include any charge or fee for an optional product or service associated with the event that may be selected by a purchaser of an event ticket.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8698F54004204DDE8A74FB80725DD480" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Optional product or service</header><text>The term <term>optional product or service</term> means a product or service that an individual does not need to purchase to use or take possession of an event ticket.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0EC411AF1D964127A17FF5EBA2FC2A04" commented="no"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Resale; secondary sale</header><text>The terms <term>resale</term> and <term>secondary sale</term> mean any sale of an event ticket that occurs after the initial sale of the event ticket by a ticket issuer.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H40DEA2CDDA9D45948445D90154102E45" commented="no"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Secondary market ticket exchange</header><text>The term <term>secondary market ticket exchange</term> means any person that in the regular course of trade or business of that person operates a platform or exchange for advertising, listing, or selling resale tickets, on behalf of itself, vendors, or a secondary market ticket issuer.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF9BD22047EDB4100B88FCACC5CDBAEB6" commented="no"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Secondary market ticket issuer</header><text>The term <term>secondary market ticket issuer</term> means any person, including a ticket issuer, that resells or makes a secondary sale of an event ticket to the general public in the regular course of the trade or business of the person.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC18313D5123346939BDCB7F90156CD91" commented="no"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Total event ticket price</header><text>The term <term>total event ticket price</term> means, with respect to an event ticket, the total cost of the event ticket, including the base event ticket price and any event ticket fee.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF02D8996A25C4A3990AF65682798E5A1"><enum>(12)</enum><header>URL</header><text>The term <term>URL</term> means the uniform resource locator associated with an internet website.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5D860DD2505E4EC184B2D0605C673C38" commented="no"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Venue</header><text>The term <term>venue</term> means a physical space at which an event takes place.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20250429" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives April 29, 2025.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Kevin F. McCumber,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation><endorsement display="yes"><action-date date="20250916">September 16, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Read twice and placed on the calendar</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

