<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0C357F3501F94E03AAE081D3806C8D19" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5264 IH: Streamlining Permitting to Enable Efficient Deployment for Broadband Infrastructure Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5264</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250910">September 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000601">Mr. Goldman of Texas</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Natural Resources</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to provide that certain projects for the placement and installation of communications facilities are not subject to requirements to prepare certain environmental or historical preservation reviews, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB314801AF51540BA8C1082333F272857" style="OLC"><section id="H7AC545843684400B8C9FEBDF550BF620" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Streamlining Permitting to Enable Efficient Deployment for Broadband Infrastructure Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SPEED for Broadband Infrastructure Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H2E755E22E80D4EB7B6000781F8F2A86C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Exemption from review for certain communications facilities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title I of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/151">47 U.S.C. 151 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H6336DDEACE094F94892E73B1A240AEEE" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="HF32C7D98FCC54D2F80816DE1E217B19C"><enum>14.</enum><header>Exemption from review for certain communications facilities</header><subsection id="HC1CD4FD031074206993AD8D3CA8F68D4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Permitting of covered projects</header><paragraph id="H0481B2FCBC1D435E896563D5BD9787B0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>NEPA exemption</header><text>A Federal authorization with respect to a covered project may not be considered a major Federal action under section 102(2)(C) of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4332">42 U.S.C. 4332(2)(C)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H605BF8F5961D416FAC47F8501C185404"><enum>(2)</enum><header>National Historic Preservation Act exemption</header><text>A covered project may not be considered an undertaking under section 300320 of title 54, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H17F605E1441E4DC881109DF18023A7DA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Savings clause</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this subsection may be construed to affect—</text><subparagraph id="HA23C96E78D204C7A9682EF8D29BC949A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the obligation of the Commission to evaluate radiofrequency exposure under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4993EA2328A34810BCD05D5693429372"><enum>(B)</enum><text>except as explicitly provided in this subsection, the obligation of a provider of a communications service to comply with the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 or division A of subtitle III of title 54, United States Code;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEF5888EAFA0A4A40B34ACFDF93496C6B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the authority of a State or local government to apply and enforce the zoning and other land use regulations of the State or local government to the extent consistent with this subsection and sections 253, 332(c)(7), and 621; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB3FA33A1953F4BE1B0C73E2B4732D4CC"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the authority or obligations established under section 20156(e) of title 49, United States Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0DCB8245A6984116BC4CF31738C66780"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grant of easement on Federal property</header><paragraph id="HD6C5ABEA5EE946D8B39888D287820327"><enum>(1)</enum><header>NEPA exemption</header><text>A Federal authorization with respect to a covered easement for a communications facility may not be considered a major Federal action under section 102(2)(C) of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4332">42 U.S.C. 4332(2)(C)</external-xref>), if a covered easement has previously been granted for another communications facility or a utility facility with respect to the same building or other property owned by the Federal Government.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H53E38961131243829140455D57B3CD9C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>National Historic Preservation Act exemption</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A covered easement for a communications facility may not be considered an undertaking under section 300320 of title 54, United States Code, if a covered easement has previously been granted for another communications facility or a utility facility with respect to the same building or other property owned by the Federal Government.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H09178DEA30844E859D197DAF81CF4E1C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H0CB630ED0ECE4D009DCB3EA0431C700F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Antenna</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>antenna</term> means communications equipment that transmits or receives electromagnetic radio frequency signals used in the provision of wireless services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC8F10EE9B4514E9F92E64FB655A07D94"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Communications facility</header><text>The term <term>communications facility</term> has the meaning given the term <term>communications facility installation</term> in section 6409(d) of the Middle Class Tax Relief and Job Creation Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1455">47 U.S.C. 1455(d)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H99A3CCBA018B4C2AA5ABF3D2238F78E6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered easement</header><text>The term <term>covered easement</term> means an easement, right-of-way, or lease with respect to a building or other property owned by the Federal Government, excluding Tribal land held in trust by the Federal Government (unless the Tribal Government with respect to such land requests that the Commission not exclude the land for purposes of this definition), for the right to install, construct, modify, or maintain a communications facility or a utility facility.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8D7799722AC7412DB424DA28A2E76F9A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Covered project</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered project</term> means the placement and installation of a new communications facility if—</text><subparagraph id="H712BDEC8404A48589095B579419D0CEB" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such new facility—</text><clause id="H8438D90E761A4EC68F3902D44C81F91F" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>will be located within a public right-of-way; and</text></clause><clause id="H2876F8572E664234A5788CA97AF57AAD" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is not more than 50 feet tall or 10 feet taller than any existing structure in the public right-of-way, whichever is higher;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H54A66F15B07144B6AB1E0BF800DB3AB3" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such new facility is—</text><clause id="HE3BAD5887498409C9B4B67ED5F91C958" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a replacement for an existing communications facility; and</text></clause><clause id="H1389CF9DF82F48B2A61E822D70675D4F" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the same as, or substantially similar to (as such term is defined by the Commission), the existing communications facility that such new communications facility is replacing;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H98C153C325D8407EA1610A5B8245A20E" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>such new facility is a type of communications facility that—</text><clause id="H1431CA6EE9B64164B09EF70FB24290A6" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is described in section 6409(d)(1)(B) of the Middle Class Tax Relief and Job Creation Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1455">47 U.S.C. 1455(d)(1)(B)</external-xref>); and</text></clause><clause id="H1C76DFC939B9487B83FA0559FD44D61D" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>meets the size limitation of a small antenna established by the Commission; or</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2218D96FC6064C0899F91D891E4A2535" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the placement and installation of such new facility involves the expansion of the site of an existing communications facility not more than 30 feet in any direction.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCCFD6E344C8B4F45B1AC006D28F03F6E"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Federal authorization</header><text>The term <term>Federal authorization</term>—</text><subparagraph id="HD5654C19C30C4EE0BB7F50BE76A7BC62"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means any authorization required under Federal law with respect to a project; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB7945C3D57E24489B50B67074A2A8591"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes any permits, special use authorizations, certifications, opinions, or other approvals as may be required under Federal law with respect to a project.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB08817AA000D425B86B80FD6C1CDE8A7"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Public right-of-way</header><text>The term <term>public right-of-way</term>—</text><subparagraph id="H80E3431844F841CBA2241F5EED594B58"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means—</text><clause id="H6DD8314C58F2410A9C73AF43B30C8F61"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the area on, below, or above a public roadway, highway, street, sidewalk, alley, or similar property; and</text></clause><clause id="H0EAD786DE3824E30B5ADBDD34A02F362"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any land immediately adjacent to and contiguous with property described in clause (i) that is within the right-of-way grant; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE392A02FAE8543DAB1D019C9E8CF0CD5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include a portion of the Interstate System (as such term is defined in section 101(a) of title 23, United States Code).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBCA9300821784997B3421F5AC66D0FD5"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Utility facility</header><text>The term <term>utility facility</term> means any privately, publicly, or cooperatively owned line, facility, or system for producing, transmitting, or distributing power, electricity, light, heat, gas, oil, crude products, water, steam, waste, storm water not connected with highway drainage, or any other similar commodity, including any fire or police signal system or street lighting system, that directly or indirectly serves the public.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1E33E079CCFB4BD48E8E729A9242F3F7"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Wireless service</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>wireless service</term> means the transmission by radio communication of voice, video, or data communications services, including Internet Protocol or any successor protocol-enabled services, or any combination of those services, whether provided on a licensed or permitted unlicensed basis.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill>


