<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0D5533205B364503B416DEACE5C8C38B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3531 IH: Sergeant Alfredo ‘Freddy’ Gonzalez Congressional Gold Medal Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
        <congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session display="yes">1st Session</session>
        <legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3531</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
        <action display="yes">
            <action-date date="20250521">May 21, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000594">Ms. De La Cruz</sponsor> introduced the
                following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title display="yes">To posthumously award a Congressional Gold Medal to Sergeant
            Alfredo <quote>Freddy</quote> Gonzalez, in recognition of his heroism in the Vietnam War
            in February 1968.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body id="HCB2DB5073202494CA0DF01CD5F08E615" style="OLC">
        <section id="HE30D8909E2B64688AAF5879FE5E6A7F2" section-type="section-one">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Sergeant Alfredo ‘Freddy’ Gonzalez Congressional Gold Medal Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section id="HD9A3C8B7B56540F49E8F957CCDDB866A">
            <enum>2.</enum>
            <header>Findings</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> <paragraph id="HE0AD118DB2754CE0832A85AA876D112C"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Alfredo Gonzalez was posthumously awarded the Medal of Honor for heroism in the Vietnam War in February 1968.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H4DA43522A3FC4CA4909979BB8CE94DF2">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Gonzalez was born May 23, 1946, in Edinburg, Texas. He graduated from Lamar Grammar School, 1955, and from Edinburg High School, 1965.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H90D7631B75604444B980ACA2498B6787">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Gonzalez enlisted in the U.S. Marine Corps Reserve at San Antonio, Texas, June 3, 1965, and was discharged to enlist as an active-duty Marine, July 6, 1965.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H5779ED4266F54AC49971C024BDB004D5">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">He completed recruit training with the 3d Recruit Training Battalion, Marine Corps Recruit Depot, San Diego, September 1965, and individual combat training with the 2d Battalion, 2d Infantry Training Regiment, Marine Corps Base, Camp Pendleton, California, October 1965.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HB648BC3B3B4F4620953E5BB07B9BD5A2">
                <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After completing individual combat training, he became a rifleman with Headquarters and Service Company, 1st Reconnaissance Battalion, 1st Marine Division, and served in that capacity until January 1966. Following this, he saw a one-year tour of duty as a rifleman and squadron leader with Company L, 3d Battalion, 4th Marines, 3d Marine Division. He was promoted to private first class on Jan. 1, 1966, to lance corporal on Oct. 1, 1966, and to corporal on Dec. 1, 1966.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H66BD7EC5249041EEA677BEF4DE241724">
                <enum>(6)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon returning to the United States in February 1967, he joined to 3d Replacement Company, Staging Battalion, Marine Corps Base, Camp Pendleton, for transfer to the Far East.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HDEBDC24254624BCDA73A0437A1D82FED">
                <enum>(7)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On July 1, 1967, he was promoted to sergeant, and later that month arrived in the Republic of Vietnam. He served as a squad leader and platoon sergeant with the 3d Platoon, Company A, 1st Battalion, 1st Marines, 1st Marine Division.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HB310D4F0547D4F459A4CCF508985FD15">
                <enum>(8)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">While serving as platoon commander, 3d Platoon, Company A, on 31 January 1968, during the initial phase of Operation Hue City, Sgt. Gonzalez’ unit was formed as a reaction force and deployed to Hue to relieve the pressure on the beleaguered city. While moving by truck convoy along Route No. 1, near the village of Lang Van Lrong, the marines received a heavy volume of enemy fire. Sgt. Gonzalez aggressively maneuvered the marines in his platoon, and directed their fire until the area was cleared of snipers. Immediately after crossing a river south of Hue, the column was again hit by intense enemy fire. One of the marines on top of a tank was wounded and fell to the ground in an exposed position. With complete disregard for his safety, Sgt. Gonzalez ran through the fire-swept area to the assistance of his injured comrade. He lifted him up and though receiving fragmentation wounds during the rescue, he carried the wounded marine to a covered position for treatment. Due to the increased volume and accuracy of enemy fire from a fortified machine-gun bunker on the side of the road, the company was temporarily halted. Realizing the gravity of the situation, Sgt. Gonzalez exposed himself to the enemy fire and moved his platoon along the east side of a bordering rice paddy to a dike directly across from the bunker. Though fully aware of the danger involved, he moved to the fire-swept road and destroyed the hostile position with hand grenades. Although seriously wounded again on 3 February, he steadfastly refused medical treatment and continued to supervise his men and lead the attack. On 4 February, the enemy had again pinned the company down, inflicting heavy casualties with automatic-weapons and rocket fire. Sgt. Gonzalez, utilizing a number of light antitank assault weapons, fearlessly moved from position to position firing numerous rounds at the heavily fortified enemy emplacements. He successfully knocked out a rocket position and suppressed much of the enemy fire before falling mortally wounded. The heroism, courage, and dynamic leadership displayed by Sgt. Gonzalez reflected great credit upon himself and the Marine Corps and were in keeping with the highest traditions of the U.S. Naval Service. He gallantly gave his life for his country.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H3FDEBFF6BBA74046BE35A76FEF8C9A31">
                <enum>(9)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">His complete list of medals and decorations include: the Medal of Honor, the Purple Heart, the Presidential Unit Citation, the National Defense Service Medal, the Vietnam Service Medal with two bronze stars, the Vietnamese Cross of Gallantry with star, the Vietnamese Cross of Gallantry with palm, the Military Merit Medal and the Republic of Vietnam Campaign Medal. He also serves as the namesake for USS Gonzalez (DDG 66).</text>
            </paragraph>
        </section>
        <section id="HC453ADDBC656428990FF1ACF7059F678">
            <enum>3.</enum>
            <header>Congressional gold medal</header>
            <subsection id="HC97BCCCCC1F6420393ED872F3E144C5E">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>Award authorized</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President pro tempore of the Senate shall make appropriate arrangements for the award, on behalf of the Congress, of a gold medal of appropriate design dedicated to Sergeant Alfredo Gonzalez, in recognition of his heroism in the Vietnam War in February 1968.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H1F283D471EF7485785995CBDCB9A2254">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Design and striking</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purposes of the award referred to in subsection (a), the Secretary of the Treasury (referred to in this Act as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall strike the gold medal with suitable emblems, devices, and inscriptions, to be determined by the Secretary.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H0E07A26DDBDF4B40B9370B93747C3DB1">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Museum of South Texas History</header>
 <text>Following the award of the gold medal described in subsection (a), the gold medal shall be given to the Museum of South Texas History, where it shall be displayed as appropriate and made available for research.</text>
            </subsection>
        </section>
        <section id="H740D7FCD69F34677AE9A62B9C80B9A8A">
            <enum>4.</enum>
            <header>Duplicate medals</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary may strike and sell duplicates in bronze of the gold medals struck under section 3, at a price sufficient to cover the costs thereof, including labor, materials, dies, use of machinery, and overhead expenses.</text>
        </section>
        <section id="H62BA6CA52947412C8D17AFD1D917AF8D">
            <enum>5.</enum>
            <header>Status of medals</header>
            <subsection id="H8F01C4908F2E4C3ABD56C3D4F063823E">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>National medals</header>
 <text>The medals struck under this Act are national medals for purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/51">chapter 51</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="HC1B58BE206284F4CB232F55A44195217">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Numismatic items</header>
 <text>For purposes of sections 5134 and 5136 of title 31, United States Code, all medals struck under this Act shall be considered to be numismatic items.</text>
            </subsection>
        </section>
        <section id="H34D2907FF59942C09E7B1F2B1BC16B31">
            <enum>6.</enum>
            <header>Authority to use fund amounts; proceeds of sale</header>
            <subsection id="H80447F9B9E964EE7A60E24189CF9884D">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>Authority To use fund amounts</header>
 <text>There is authorized to be charged against the United States Mint Public Enterprise Fund such amounts as may be necessary to pay for the costs of the medals struck under this Act.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="HD76476D5CB574E5EBEDA8A20FC905B8C">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Proceeds of sale</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts received from the sale of duplicate bronze medals authorized under section 3 shall be deposited into the United States Mint Public Enterprise Fund.</text>
            </subsection>
        </section>
    </legis-body>
</bill>

