<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H68DF1B4E6A2B43A7AAD19D215C096BBC" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4917 IH: Expanding the Voluntary Opportunities for Translations in Elections Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4917</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250805">August 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000788">Ms. Williams of Georgia</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="R000606">Mr. Raskin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001206">Mr. Morelle</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000629">Ms. Davids of Kansas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000185">Mr. Scott of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000370">Ms. Adams</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000380">Mr. Amo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001313">Ms. Brown</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001315">Ms. Budzinski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001055">Mr. Case</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001117">Mr. Casten</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001127">Mrs. Cherfilus-McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001130">Ms. Crockett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000230">Mr. Davis of North Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000530">Mr. Deluzio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000399">Mr. Doggett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000301">Ms. Elfreth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000110">Mr. Fields</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000481">Mr. Figures</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000468">Mrs. Fletcher</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000586">Mr. García of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001066">Mr. Horsford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000309">Mr. Jackson of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000400">Ms. Kamlager-Dove</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000557">Mr. Larson of Connecticut</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000602">Ms. Lee of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001227">Ms. McClellan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001229">Mrs. McIver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000687">Mr. Mfume</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001241">Mr. Min</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001225">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000610">Ms. Plaskett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000617">Ms. Pressley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000617">Mrs. Ramirez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001226">Ms. Salinas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001231">Ms. Simon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001211">Mr. Stanton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001159">Ms. Strickland</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001223">Mrs. Sykes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">House Administration</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To modify certain notice requirements, to study certain election requirements, to clarify certain election requirements, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA3266DDC89BB4999B246E96B6C541727" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H6CCA29027DEF41D1A0DE173A069E9963" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Expanding the Voluntary Opportunities for Translations in Elections Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Expanding the VOTE Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H498A21A4D7E04873803F50925A5DA5EB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Language minority notice requirements</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 203 of the Voting Rights Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/10503">52 U.S.C. 10503</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="HA7B7D01447DA44F0B6B28D6265D7C3C3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by amending subsection (b)(3)(A) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HC996A88211184F56990257C84D17E6CD" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subparagraph id="H811ADD8B4C764F669BD83480CA6A1F39"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <quote>voting materials</quote>—</text>
<clause id="H32C54DCFB73C41B896256D559E07F107"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means registration or voting notices, forms, instructions, assistance, or other materials or information relating to the electoral process, including ballots; and</text></clause> <clause id="H62C5439C50814D7B92923CDE12DD801D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes digital and printed material or information produced relating to the electoral process;</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H209F7704719D4B4F821C3D0719827705"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (e) as subsection (g); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEC0DAB8C2AEA478B9A1BE29C87F21049"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (d) the following new subsections:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HAD6395C05F794B97AD1A57749DFDF8B0" display-inline="no-display-inline">
<subsection id="H52B1F85F655D46588A8CE78256266D16"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Responsibility of States providing voting materials in covered political subdivisions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The prohibition under subsection (b) shall apply to any State that provides voting materials to a political subdivision subject to such prohibition.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HDFF2C57CE59B4427B65B4CA511D8EDD4"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Notice</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General shall submit a notice of the prohibition of subsection (b), and the threshold at which such prohibition applies, to each State or political subdivision that is—</text>
<paragraph id="HFA94058CF0114E74AF6D908F6FA1A817"><enum>(1)</enum><text>below the threshold requirement under subclause (II) of subsection (b)(2)(A)(i) by not more than 1,000; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H94B119D70CC4482F9D6F1B0511FDDA8F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">below the threshold requirement under subclause (I) or (III) of subsection (b)(2)(A)(i) by not more than 0.5 percent.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section>
<section id="H859A513E394943D79498CC696ED13806"><enum>3.</enum><header>Provisions related to American Indian and Alaska Native languages</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 203 of the Voting Rights Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/10503">52 U.S.C. 10503</external-xref>), as amended by section 2, is further amended—</text> <paragraph id="H4AF9204B61574841BDD2EBCA536B1323" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(3)(C), by striking <quote>1990</quote> and inserting <quote>most recent</quote>; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H3C8308483EAF4E7EAE2C19BC1F270FF6" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking subsection (c) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block id="HFAA310C029C745EA82F743488B68D85D" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H98C108C347974715B529DC3D890C0471" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Provision of voting materials in the language of a minority group</header> <paragraph id="HD080355E6E8248D5AFD024ED0C468123" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2), whenever any State or political subdivision subject to the prohibition of subsection (b) provides any registration or voting notices, forms, instructions, assistance, or other materials or information relating to the electoral process, including ballots, it shall provide them in the language of the applicable minority group as well as in the English language.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF442E49612EE47B1AE4D011B7EEF72D1" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exceptions</header>
<subparagraph id="HC77E6A09A08F4D7EAE068DCE9736BB41" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>When written American Indian and Alaska Native translations for voters are not required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a minority group that is American Indian or Alaska Native, if the Tribal government of that minority group has notified the Attorney General that the language is unwritten or the Tribal government does not want a written translation, a State or political subdivision subject to the prohibition of subsection (b) shall only be required to furnish that minority group, in the covered language, oral instructions, assistance, translation of voting materials, and other information relating to registration and voting.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H386D46F14C094410826216962CE20300" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Other minority groups with unwritten language</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a minority group that is not American Indian or Alaska Native, if the language of that minority group is unwritten, a State or political subdivision subject to the prohibition of subsection (b) shall only be required to furnish that minority group, in the covered language, oral instructions, assistance, translation of voting materials, and other information relating to registration and voting.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC95D4EB7E765433492803182927D3C83" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Written translations for election workers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding paragraph (2), a State or political division subject to the prohibition of subsection (b) shall provide written translations of all voting materials, with the consent of any applicable Tribal government, to election workers to ensure that the translations from English to the language of a minority group are complete, accurate, and uniform.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H57C49FC2D5C24762BE4A86A12D424B02" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Tribal government defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, the term <quote>Tribal government</quote> means the recognized governing body of any Indian or Alaska Native Tribe, band, nation, pueblo, village, community, component band, or component reservation, individually identified (including parenthetically) in the list published most recently as of the date of enactment of the <short-title>Expanding the VOTE Act</short-title> pursuant to section 104 of the Federally Recognized Indian Tribe List Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5131">25 U.S.C. 5131</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section>
<section id="H71C368E3BEC74469BE9B8E65A157831D"><enum>4.</enum><header>Grants to jurisdictions to incentivize the provision of voting materials in languages not triggering Section 203 coverage in applying jurisdiction</header>
<subsection id="H98880F36EB954DF996CE5952A0236802"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Availability of grants</header>
<paragraph id="H9B28951F11E242EBAF6B45CCE7832D5A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Election Assistance Commission (in this section, referred to as the <quote>Commission</quote>) shall make incentive grants under subsection (b) to States and political subdivisions to assist the States and political subdivisions in providing voting materials during an election cycle in the language of a covered language minority group.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8012FFA37B76464380036FD5CE03D2F3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In order to receive a grant under this section, a State or political subdivision shall submit to the Commission, at such time and in such form as the Commission may require, an application containing such information and assurances as the Commission may require, such as a plan for the State or political subdivision to engage stakeholders with a demonstrated experience of serving the relevant covered language minority group.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H3CC41E37484340D5BC8250E380422A56"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Incentive grants</header>
<paragraph id="H65474E9058F84BE690145761293A0C2B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>The Commission shall make an incentive grant under this subsection to a State or political subdivision to cover the reasonable costs incurred by the State or political subdivision in providing voting materials in the language of a covered language minority group for an election cycle.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBE379DB1BC3E45AEB86EF24F125602F0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Continuation of provision of materials for groups in succeeding election cycles</header><text>If a State or political subdivision receives an incentive grant with respect to a covered language minority group for an election cycle, the State or political subdivision will certify to the Commission that the State or political subdivision will continue to provide voting materials in the language of that covered language minority group for each succeeding election cycle unless the population of the group during the succeeding cycle has dropped by 0.5 percent or more from the population of the group during the first election cycle for which the State or political subdivision received an incentive grant with respect to the group.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H50A1840E68924B9AA37675CFCC1E085F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Prohibiting multiple grants for same language minority group</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a State or political subdivision receives an incentive grant with respect to a covered language minority group, the State or subdivision may not receive another incentive grant with respect to that same covered language minority group.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HA3D3E0D54F924F03B77609D7EBAA9067"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text>
<paragraph id="H47067257F4404C16827FF1E5F291E811"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <quote>covered language minority group</quote>—</text> <subparagraph id="H84FF22C1B33F49939689683548586327"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means, with respect to a State or political subdivision, the members of a single language minority who do not meet the requirements of clause (i) or (ii) of section 203(b)(2)(A) of the Voting Rights Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/10503">52 U.S.C. 10503(b)(2)(A)</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HC22F4E12261D4249A7580C5C11F40213"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes the language minorities described in section 203(g) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/10503">52 U.S.C. 10503(g)</external-xref>) and any other language minority;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H435809E0B2D64EEDA64BCFA60377B029"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <quote>election cycle</quote> means the period which begins on the day after the date of a regularly scheduled general election for Federal office and which ends on the date of the next regularly scheduled general election for Federal office;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H95585EB287E94B29A081397AAF661CAA"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <quote>State</quote> means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the United States Virgin Islands, American Samoa, Guam, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB3BA866A2D05428ABACFAC7E87E73A4D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the term <quote>voting materials</quote> has the meaning given under section 203(b)(3)(A) of the Voting Rights Act of 1065 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/10503">52 U.S.C. 10503(b)(3)(A)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HA6D70C6271374DD38B25CEC7804288DD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $15,000,000, to remain available until expended.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H7AF4AF17239A4CFFB2BDDAF4D17D7F0C" commented="no"><enum>5.</enum><header>Study on certain language minority notice requirements</header> <subsection id="H139C26CC172D4BBCBF29277308B2B78B" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Comptroller General of the United States, in consultation with the Director of the Census, the Attorney General, and the Election Assistance Commission, shall conduct a study on the impact of—</text>
<paragraph id="H346FF0E230A142D698F6B479238BE862"><enum>(1)</enum><text>reducing the threshold requirement—</text> <subparagraph id="H73C11C5DD96C4CC0A55A054E95C8A08A" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">under subclause (II) of section 203(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Voting Rights Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/10503">52 U.S.C. 10503(b)(2)(A)(i)</external-xref>) to 7,500 and 5,000, respectively; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE33F61A64A384301AA966F03C23DFF0B" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>under subclause (I) or (III) of section 203(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Voting Rights Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/10503">52 U.S.C. 10503(b)(2)(A)(i)</external-xref>) to 4 percent, 3 percent, 2.5 percent, and 2 percent, respectively; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H38409C32E07C4CE49300D68475015FEE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>expanding the definition of the term <quote>language minorities</quote> to include native speakers of Arabic, French and Haitian Creole, and any other language that the Comptroller General determines to be appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HC74E0BB999AB43AE868EF9A1F8093748" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report on the findings of the study conducted under subsection (a).</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

