<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H06A29D8376ED47E1949C75C62251FD2C" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 798 IH: Expressing support for the designation of the week of September 15 through September 21, 2025, as “Rail Safety Week” in the United States, and supporting the goals and ideals of reducing highway-rail grade crossing-related incidents, fatalities, and injuries.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 798</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251008">October 8, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of the week of September 15 through September 21, 2025, as <quote>Rail Safety Week</quote> in the United States, and supporting the goals and ideals of reducing highway-rail grade crossing-related incidents, fatalities, and injuries.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the first Rail Safety Week was held from September 24 through September 30, 2017, by the national education safety nonprofit Operation Lifesaver, the Department of Transportation, and other organizations;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Rail Safety Week was launched to raise awareness about the need for increased education on how to be safe around highway-rail grade crossings and railroad tracks and to highlight efforts to further reduce incidents, injuries, and fatalities;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the rail industry strives to safeguard drivers and pedestrians at highway-rail grade crossings through continuous maintenance, public safety campaigns with organizations like Operation Lifesaver, utilizing government and community collaboration, and heavy investment in technology;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas highway-rail grade crossing and trespassing incidents constituted approximately 97 percent of all rail-related fatalities during 2024;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, since 2005, the number of public highway-rail grade crossings has decreased by 1 percent; </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2024, 52 percent of all highway-rail grade crossing incidents and 68 percent of all fatal highway-rail grade crossing incidents occurred at gated highway-rail grade crossings;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas preliminary Federal statistics indicate that 2,260 highway-grade crossing incidents occurred in the United States in 2024, resulting in 260 deaths and another 762 individuals injured;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas many incidents between trains and motor vehicles or pedestrians could have been prevented by increased education, engineering, and enforcement;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Operation Lifesaver, the foremost public information and education program on rail safety, which administers a public education program about grade-crossing safety and trespassing prevention, enjoys broad bipartisan support;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, during Rail Safety Week, from September 15 through 21, and throughout the year, everyone is encouraged to take added caution as motorists or pedestrians approach tracks or trains;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States, Canada, and Mexico will concurrently observe Rail Safety Week; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas this important observance should lead to greater safety awareness and a reduction in highway-rail grade crossing incidents and other railroad incidents: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HCA4E3F4C9EA644228B506425328ACE84"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H0B9C4CA539174E2D9FD3B0134CFA5ACD"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="H6E067E75283B4594936391D10BB1BDC2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the designation of Rail Safety Week;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H35421A64C0D04944AA0AADC03D7CD28F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>expresses strong support for—</text><subparagraph id="HE0817453092D44B39A2A444E5710E679"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the goals and ideals of Rail Safety Week; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC8B5EFA3EBEB493E84795DEEFA30E6E2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>efforts to reduce rail-related incidents, fatalities, and injuries at highway-rail grade crossings; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB0BD0432BB854BDEB83C2301725DFDD0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>encourages the people of the United States—</text><subparagraph id="H826AAAA32B704151B6F8B128120D3C02"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to participate in Rail Safety Week events and activities; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H38C81AB8339E4857B365CF3752735614"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to educate themselves and others on how to be safe around railroad tracks and grade crossings.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

