<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0FA9754207BD4D22B3F1BDB615736B78" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1209 IH: End of GSE Conservatorship Preparation Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1209</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250211">February 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="O000175">Mr. Ogles</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of the Treasury to submit to the Congress completed proposals for the termination of the conservatorships of Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8B98CCE1A413452FBE5F221A0CB8871A" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HA12DD2A3A8224E56A6E8D485CCC3B3C1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>End of GSE Conservatorship Preparation Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HBAD9CF655A7246228C43BEDA45187BCB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Proposals for termination of conservatorships</header> <subsection id="H52B142ED0BA546CD821A2416D1F64FCA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Treasury shall submit a report to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate that identifies whether—</text> 
<paragraph id="H56195F7E61C3470A92A2393563FB8FC2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Department of the Treasury completed the proposal described in article IX of the Letter Agreement to the Amended and Restated Preferred Stock Purchase Agreement between the United States Department of the Treasury and the Federal National Mortgage Association, dated January 14, 2021, and the proposal described in article IX of the Letter Agreement to the Amended and Restated Preferred Stock Purchase Agreement between the United States Department of the Treasury and the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation, dated January 14, 2021; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4C7995C9116B42F393E1854458BDA5F1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>either or both of such proposals were completed and, if so, includes such completed proposal or proposals.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H03E38CCB1AF84962973AD39729E2CEAF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Proposals</header><text>If the report required under subsection (a) indicates that either or both of such proposals were not completed, the Secretary of the Treasury shall—</text> <paragraph id="HF8E3D1D84D614DD1B3A410FAA6A94BCA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>include in such report the latest incomplete draft or version, if any, of such incomplete proposal or proposals; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H53A1F67419104CD989BF5E905077DC73"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, complete and submit such proposal or proposals to the committees identified in subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

