<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H53874DBA585F488F96B18A34683EB92D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 3054 IH: Relieving Economic Strain to Enhance American Resilience and Competitiveness in Higher Education and Research Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3054</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250429">April 29, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001227">Ms. McClellan</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000602">Ms. Lee of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001127">Mrs. Cherfilus-McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000476">Mr. Frost</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000454">Mr. Foster</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy to develop a consistent set of policy guidelines for Federal research agencies to address financial instability of graduate researchers and postdoctoral researchers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6EBDEFDA9A004DB3B3211A5F074D8535" style="OLC"><section id="H71B5A85755214CACB861A5520ADFF994" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Relieving Economic Strain to Enhance American Resilience and Competitiveness in Higher Education and Research Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>RESEARCHER Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H6D955D60F2C94E23B8475F1FDE974310" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Policy guidelines for Federal research agencies to address financial instability of graduate researchers and postdoctoral researchers</header><subsection id="HD76E7FC207E24A6E8C2543BB53B53BA5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph id="HCA73B68847F64BE6AD340146E6BB865C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text>The term <quote>institution of higher education</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6AC6CDF1A7F44658ACE4DAA7CF17564C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Graduate researchers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>graduate researchers</quote> means individuals enrolled in a degree program leading to an advanced degree who receive stipends or other compensation to conduct research in any discipline at an institution of higher education that is a recipient of Federal funding.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3BB04C893CBB4728BB492C686FF63B58"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Postdoctoral researchers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>postdoctoral researchers</quote> means individuals in training-focused positions who have received a doctoral degree or equivalent and receive stipends or other compensation to conduct research in any discipline at an institution of higher education that is a recipient of Federal funding.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFD898EAF46A54B6BB375D8688494AEAF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>OSTP guidelines</header><paragraph id="H15EC721835C4459A91547E2ECDB95659"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than six months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy, in consultation with the National Science and Technology Council, the Committee on STEM Education, PCAST, institutions of higher education, graduate and postdoctoral organizations, and other relevant stakeholders, shall develop a consistent set of policy guidelines for Federal research agencies to address financial instability of graduate researchers and postdoctoral researchers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HED49232CDB4C49B19D7B4B9F94C9A5DC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>In developing the policy guidelines under paragraph (1), the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy shall include guidelines that address, to the extent practicable, the following:</text><subparagraph id="H3B26A7195E264E0A921E0B24BEFF5B81"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Opportunities to increase stipends for graduate researchers and postdoctoral researchers, including indexing based on location.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC45825FEF47A48469EB0C81B71914D41"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Increasing stipends for postdoctoral researchers conducting research in rural or underserved areas, or in States eligible to receive funding from the Established Program to Stimulate Competitive Research under section 113 of the National Science Foundation Authorization Act of 1988 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1862g">42 U.S.C. 1862g</external-xref>), to support the recruitment and retention of researchers in such regions.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5778085BBDF345578E4EA56E0A8314EC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Opportunities to increase access to quality, affordable medical, dental, and vision care.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H92F7A5313C7C4E1F930A3C768CC4F7F2"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Opportunities to increase access to affordable housing and transportation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H944C61F8507347C0B41AE948B5F59B5E"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Opportunities to reduce food insecurity.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H578EFAB2E870477ABF7657700B9F27FA"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Opportunities to address costs of caring for family members, including child care.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H845D4603D937481798128C30A19D8E7A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Application</header><subparagraph id="H2B68E0BFA4FD45AFA8F3E3D13F72D95D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy shall encourage and monitor efforts of Federal research agencies to develop and implement policies based on the policy guidelines under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H65F66558BEF4444793770AB3FA8A8599"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Federal research agency implementation</header><text>Not later than six months after receiving the policy guidelines under paragraph (1), the head of each Federal research agency shall—</text><clause id="H96BEB35D6D41477B8F5C93F50BD84D83"><enum>(i)</enum><text>develop and implement policies with respect to financial instability of graduate researchers and postdoctoral researchers that are consistent with such policy guidelines; and</text></clause><clause id="H24B90F0DD42B4175A78A3FDF6404A5FD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>broadly disseminate such policies to current and potential recipients of research and development awards made by such agency.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEB95C6B045B044E081E1721B382E43AC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Updates</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy shall update the policy guidelines under paragraph (1) as the Director determines necessary.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCE330B9755DB4C9C81C81C53DC2CE23A" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than one year after the date after the policy guidelines under paragraph (1) are developed and every five years thereafter, the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy shall submit to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate a report containing information relating to the following:</text><subparagraph id="H90421BEC29D14BE2B0F4915D5E19774D" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Such policy guidelines.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFE5D03C00FDA4FEC8A10244A5DDA6AB1" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Progress on the implementation of such guidelines by Federal research agencies.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H43525AC8A71D41B9BA3F83FFC4F3AC4E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Data collection</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Research and Development, Competition, and Innovation Act (enacted as division B of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/167">Public Law 117–167</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HD1C3C32BAF624EAFA591C2FA1A892D88"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 10314(b) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18994">42 U.S.C. 18994</external-xref>)—</text><subparagraph id="H6E5CA604C8244F27ACF5131A3CC0A801"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text><clause id="H966439E3B256409E98CC1E2382966226"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D), by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon;</text></clause><clause id="H456DFF76C9EA4C46ADBD44DBFCBCE9BE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (E) as subparagraph (F); and</text></clause><clause id="H6A0C9D7C8BA1468092DE14463983D4F9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (D) the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H884C37A7842F473D8DD9EF2A3B9E3AA4" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="HC753B07F266D48E4804B39F67BB90467"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">graduate researcher and postdoctoral researcher stipend amounts and financial instability (disaggregated, to the extent practicable, by demographics); and</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB849A7616B4C4D0289FDDC759278C120"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HF5FECFEAE750450CBB40CA4B598B41ED" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H32076584DABE4925A8A858BC599AC8A6"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection:</text><subparagraph id="H2BFDC80281B743D484EB4DB43F43FC17"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text>The term <quote>institution of higher education</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7A038223CA25491EB7D7A0E1761A104E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Graduate researchers</header><text>The term <quote>graduate researchers</quote> means individuals enrolled in a degree program leading to an advanced degree who receive stipends or other compensation to conduct research in any discipline at an institution of higher education that is a recipient of Federal funding.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDCB285DD42A54379BB10A68E57C6BFC1"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Postdoctoral researchers</header><text>The term <quote>postdoctoral researchers</quote> means individuals in training-focused positions who have received a doctoral degree or equivalent and receive stipends or other compensation to conduct research in any discipline at an institution of higher education that is a recipient of Federal funding. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H82332277DB024653B0800B4E040401F6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (1) of section 10502(a) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/19152">42 U.S.C. 19152(a)</external-xref>), by inserting <quote>graduate and postdoctoral research stipend amounts (disaggregated, to the extent practicable, by demographics),</quote> before <quote>and awarded budget</quote>. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC8E445D28ABC4852A1430458592AD237"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Data on financial instability of graduate researchers and postdoctoral researchers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the National Science Foundation shall make awards, on a competitive basis, to institutions of higher education or nonprofit organizations (or consortia of such institutions or organizations) to collect and analyze data on financial instability of graduate researchers and postdoctoral researchers (disaggregated, to the extent practicable, by demographics).</text></subsection><subsection id="H6CC2F6CA7C4A492EBD4B7F73D0A4B65A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>National Academies assessment</header><paragraph id="H812CE7F7443D45A688CA0C78C3CEDE81"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than two years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of the National Science Foundation shall enter into an agreement with the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine to undertake a study and issue a report on the status of financial instability of graduate researchers and postdoctoral researchers. To the extent feasible, the study shall include an assessment (disaggregated, to the extent practicable, by demographics) at a minimum of the immediately preceding five years of the following:</text><subparagraph id="HFC81C34F29944DCE8D0361EE435D59A3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Stipends relative to average local medical, dental, and vision expenses.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF8234A4CE92D40A9ADA49AADAA95BD62"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Stipends relative to average local housing and transportation costs.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H924CC8A69F4846F59CB05E03573EF973"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Stipends relative to average local food costs.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H276CA40505F44999A3844A986BF00A71"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Stipends relative to average local costs of caring for family members, including child care costs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCAFA8B7731304794AE72F3E4C5107050"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than two years after the date on which the agreement between the Director of the National Science Foundation and the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine is entered into pursuant to paragraph (1), the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine shall submit to Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate a report containing the results of the assessment under such paragraph and recommendations relating thereto regarding how Federal agencies, Congress, institutions of higher education, and other relevant entities may address financial instability of graduate researchers and postdoctoral researchers.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBAF1C9C73F4045D39DDF08418BD642EB"><enum>(f)</enum><header>GAO study</header><text>Not later than three years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate a report that—</text><paragraph id="H14C5E22A7382428EB4778246E06B3723"><enum>(1)</enum><text>assesses the degree to which Federal research agencies have implemented the policy guidelines under subsection (b) and the effectiveness of such implementation;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEEB719E3DFA340819826B67119553617"><enum>(2)</enum><text>includes recommendations on potential changes to practices and policies to improve such guidelines and such implementation; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H543F800F2A024BBC9DAFB2D32AAB5C3E"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes recommendations on additional data collection and research needed to monitor progress on reducing financial instability of graduate researchers and postdoctoral researchers.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

