<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H41424C32EA8941E8A725CBECFA781D1D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3620 IH: Southcentral Foundation Land Transfer Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3620</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250529">May 29, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001323">Mr. Begich</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for the conveyance of certain property to the Southcentral Foundation located in Anchorage, Alaska, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF56FC26CBF12464A8923BE70AD424DBA" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H846E06DBF9434F85B17D1DF0F182500F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Southcentral Foundation Land Transfer Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H3BD72B97C0804EEDA712D6B303D5BDE2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="H47E7DD50F3794899B3D2AC0A4991A4B8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>SCF</header><text>The term <term>SCF</term> means the Southcentral Foundation located in Anchorage, Alaska.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB512936BF9C049AE81A9CCD5AF778238"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H7AFD2B3840624299B37456209B9DFC29"><enum>3.</enum><header>Conveyance of property to SCF</header> 
<subsection id="HB74DAA522121491D8B15CA264B9D7975"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>As soon as practicable, but not later than 2 years, after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall convey to SCF all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to the property described in subsection (b) for use in connection with health and social services programs.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HA73424D0FB144E0DBD710B64002F3418"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Property described</header> <text>The property, including all land, improvements, and appurtenances, referred to in this section is the approximately 3.372 acres located in Lot 1A, Block 36 East Addition, Anchorage Townsite Subdivision in Anchorage, Alaska, according to the official plat thereof, filed under Plat No. 2025–11, records of the Anchorage Recording District, Third Judicial District, State of Alaska.</text>
      </subsection></section> 
<section id="H10630D4FFCF5497D9ECBF63EFA44AB4A"><enum>4.</enum><header>Conditions of conveyance</header> 
<subsection id="H7E21FB9DBBDD4178AECB213B3D104ED1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Conditions</header><text>The conveyance under subsection (a) of section 3—</text> <paragraph id="H87CD3BCF002F483C97A71817632094A7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall be made by warranty deed; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H523DF8D97741402C989E5BFD0DB6100E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall not—</text> <subparagraph id="H694EE0F243B748BABCC10892BF67ACF6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>require any consideration from SCF for the property described in subsection (b) of that section;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFE567232246346638A62AC48A71CEDB6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>impose any obligation, term, or condition on SCF relating to that property; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1507BA42A75742A1BE74F5FFE1AF41A5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>allow for any reversionary interest of the United States in that property.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA615B9C81B074104A2E87DFDF01EBC6F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effect on any quitclaim deed</header><text>The conveyance by the Secretary under subsection (a) of section 3 by warranty deed shall, on the effective date of the conveyance, supersede, and render of no future effect, any quitclaim deed to the property described in subsection (b) of that section executed by the Secretary and SCF.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H451DE2BFAB294238B10A9FD1D13D6513"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Easement</header><text>The Secretary shall be accorded any easement or access to the property conveyed under section 3(a) as may be reasonably necessary to satisfy any retained obligation or liability of the Secretary.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H544090376D3943B29A6713A8226027E1"><enum>5.</enum><header>Environmental liability</header> 
<subsection id="H0211AC530C5A43FE9EB10A00F3C71392"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, SCF shall not be liable for any soil, surface water, groundwater, or other contamination resulting from the disposal, release, or presence of any environmental contamination described in subsection (b) on any portion of the property described in section 3(b) that occurred on or before the date on which the property is conveyed to SCF under section 3(a), except that the Secretary shall not be liable for any contamination that occurred after the date that SCF controlled, occupied, and used the property.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H620B287432DC40B3839A9CFB2740173B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Environmental contamination</header><text>Environmental contamination referred to in subsection (a) includes any oil or petroleum products, hazardous substances, hazardous materials, hazardous waste, pollutants, toxic substances, solid waste, or any other environmental contamination or hazard as defined in any Federal or State of Alaska law.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6396B833138D4C0EB6704B05CE6458B6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Notice of hazardous substance activity and warranty</header><text>In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall comply with section 120(h) of the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9620">42 U.S.C. 9620(h)</external-xref>).</text></subsection> <subsection id="HA1AD44D42CA941368F91AD1DBCA8BE67"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limitation on applicability</header><text>This section shall only apply to the property conveyance specifically required by this Act.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

