<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0AF3F3232D7849AF81655389F8FF9EF3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3748 IH: Maintaining Area Rights and Integrity Through International Maritime Enforcement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3748</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250605">June 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001287">Mr. Bera</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001219">Mr. Moylan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001055">Mr. Case</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000600">Mrs. Radewagen</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of State to submit to Congress a report on the promotion of certain policies regarding the effects of sea level rise on the statehood and maritime zones of countries, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HCE56BB4FC509480D82A0D592C6B3FEC8" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H86E6D258D76F441D916C9B2F5B43BA28" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Maintaining Area Rights and Integrity Through International Maritime Enforcement Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>MARITIME Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H537C04BA10284575B9B876BB6950E936" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> <paragraph id="H949B8BEDF0844796861136E5F6265D71"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Increasing sea levels pose an existential threat to low-lying island States in the Pacific Ocean.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFA83C395DD2049D1BBB8415AF13EAB3F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Maritime zones are critical for the economies of the Pacific Islands, which depend on exclusive rights to resources.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H71CEA895A1884ADFAAEABBCC3014EDA8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>New trends are developing in the practices and views of States on the need for stable maritime zones in the face of sea level rise, as reflected in the approach taken by the members of the Pacific Islands Forum and the Alliance of Small Island States.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H3FD1D705F0B044B1A76AD3E3552049A2"><enum>3.</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the policy of the United States that—</text> <paragraph id="H8E2F14ACAF094449B25D695A18BBBB45"><enum>(1)</enum><text>sea level rise driven by climate change should not cause any country to lose its statehood or its membership in the United Nations, its specialized agencies, or other international organizations;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBD75F620E7204B3F944ABAFC04007A5B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the United States is committed to working with other countries on issues relating to sea level rise and statehood to advance these objectives;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H31D402B2CAF941C3895911A5481DB2E9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>sea level rise driven by climate change should not diminish the maritime zones on which island States and other coastal States rely, including for food and livelihoods;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H11785E704AA24843A612989460E79119"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the United States is committed to preserving the legitimacy of maritime zones, and associated rights and entitlements, that have been established consistent with international law as reflected in the United Nations Convention on the Law of the Sea and that are not subsequently updated despite sea level rise caused by climate change;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF8F238F7908F49F489DEFE467C3EC863" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>countries should support the initiative of the Pacific Islands Forum and the Alliance of Small Island States to take steps now to determine, memorialize, and publish their coastal baselines in accordance with the international law of the sea as set out in the United Nations Convention on the Law of the Sea; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H55A7B19987034FD18E2917D8217CDC4E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the United States will encourage countries to adopt similar policies on the issue of statehood and the preservation of maritime zones.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H0F67CB196E884B58931BB20B3C2EF2D8"><enum>4.</enum><header>Report</header> <subsection id="H109D51807CC3497A9CDB618844444B79" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State, in consultation with the heads of other relevant Federal agencies, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the efforts of the United States to promote the adoption, by foreign countries and international organizations, of policies that are complementary to United States policies regarding the effects of sea level rise on the statehood and maritime zones of countries.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H20B27CD8B3014F12BB0C92B0FBFBB170"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report contents</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall include the following:</text> <paragraph id="H7DEB92102C5B4FF88281AE7DC36AF79E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A comprehensive review of the initiatives of the Department of State and other relevant departments and agencies to promote the adoption of policies described in subsection (a) by foreign countries and international organizations.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H76470D316F404BD398888C5930490060"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of how the Department of State and other relevant departments and agencies are establishing or expanding bilateral and multilateral efforts to encourage the adoption of policies described in subsection (a) in international fora.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9228BD649F37426E930518322E07E45E"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of any legal, policy, logistical, financial, or administrative barrier to promoting the adoption of policies described in subsection (a).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H623371753E7A4F77AE57D4806FD0966F"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A list of countries and international organizations that have adopted policies described in subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H116FF401E653422DA8F737685D9CB63D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Form of report</header><text>The report required under subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5B49BAD4C14043C8A703288B49C89D35"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>In this section, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> <paragraph id="HA152FEF7177F406D92875BB1986C0A87"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCE9875C486334E93A5F3F88F37EA6AA9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

