<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H99CE9CE1371842ED9392F436C60EF3F5" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5708 IH: Federal Employees Civil Relief Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5708</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251008">October 8, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001296">Mr. Boyle of Pennsylvania</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="R000621">Ms. Randall</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001226">Ms. Salinas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and Workforce</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">House Administration</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To suspend the enforcement of certain civil liabilities of Federal employees and contractors during a lapse in appropriations, or during a breach of the statutory debt limit, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H202075D5B63748838959CE75F61C5AA1" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="HB23DFCB8B94A484EBE264E2E2DD617AD"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Federal Employees Civil Relief Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H88EE7BA5624A45F089520B125A1C8440"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purpose of this Act is to provide for the temporary suspension of judicial and administrative proceedings and transactions that may adversely affect the civil rights of Federal workers during a shutdown.</text></section> 
<section id="H643726BD46A2493CA51078C8F67409B7"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="HB13D8A5ACD0444C086674AE0C8ABBE78"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Consumer reporting agency</header><text>The term <term>consumer reporting agency</term> has the meaning given the term in section 603(f) of the Fair Credit Reporting Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1681a">15 U.S.C. 1681a(f)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE0CFDC6F53A244D68DFC538A45A78475"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contractor</header><text>The term <term>contractor</term> has the meaning given the term in section 7101 of title 41, United States Code.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H70EA24A013334E2BBC95969E7D4F3CCD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Court; judgment; State</header><text>The terms <term>court</term>, <term>judgment</term>, and <term>State</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 101 of the Servicemembers Civil Relief Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3911">50 U.S.C. 3911</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H44FB554400484B1586F04005EFEB6F9B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Covered period</header><text>The term <term>covered period</term> means the period beginning on the date on which a shutdown begins and ending on the date that is 30 days after the date on which that shutdown ends.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFDAAACDA526C44F99288E065AAD652B5"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Federal worker</header><text>The term <term>Federal worker</term>—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD85A7E0035784882A41E5524EE8B4980"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means an employee of a Government agency; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD8BC945A27E54D6A9F442BABBA128630"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes an employee of a contractor.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0B84092235BA4187A61E6184E99ECD3B"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Government agency</header><text>The term <term>Government agency</term> means each authority of the executive, legislative, or judicial branch of the Government of the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF60FDB29735042009AC162169C6B1D0D"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Shutdown</header><text>The term <term>shutdown</term> means any period in which—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1FB35F5BFE264287B850EEEAD5DDBE8F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">there is more than a 24-hour lapse in appropriations for any Government agency or Federal department as a result of a failure to enact a regular appropriations bill or continuing resolution; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1AD22034EAB84C499C2AF4E4D08E1317"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the debt of the United States Government is greater than the statutory limit under section 3101 of title 31, United States Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H53A70ACA6D2142D2959E18F8A1EFE3B6"><enum>4.</enum><header>Jurisdiction</header> 
<subsection id="H47852FFBA1F94965812103D58A584374"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Jurisdiction</header><text>This Act shall apply to—</text> <paragraph id="HD34FB646E6C54E8EA58B994D4D17A513"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the United States;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9A7DDA0CC91E4496BCF7D6B970565E49"><enum>(2)</enum><text>each of the States, including each political subdivision of a State; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2341932DD6004F84A467A09836C70674"><enum>(3)</enum><text>all territory that is subject to the jurisdiction of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4C05F1BD9A02493FA9CA72984E894785"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicability to proceedings</header><text>This Act—</text> <paragraph id="H56325E30EDA04C3882B595CEFCA3CBBC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall apply to any judicial or administrative proceeding that is commenced in any court or agency in any jurisdiction that is subject to this Act; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8FE9CBB37490471B9156563C9FD3DCB9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall not apply to criminal proceedings or with respect to child support payments.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H61C8667A580B427E9A7599440570D227"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Court in which application may be made</header><text>When, under this Act, any application is required to be made to a court in which no proceeding has already been commenced with respect to a matter, that application may be made to any court that would otherwise have jurisdiction over the matter.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFA59DDB627C64DC6992F679CD234D9C2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Notification</header> 
<paragraph id="HDC3FF57E31A2456BACA74438453817BA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The head of the Government agency that employs a Federal worker, or at which a Federal worker performs services, as applicable, shall provide the Federal worker with written notice regarding the benefits provided under this Act—</text> <subparagraph id="HD54C66AA2F9A4FF7BD741CC97240F85A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>on the date on which the individual becomes a Federal worker; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1D86A06F4924419F8E030BAED56B5BA2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>periodically after the date described in subparagraph (A), including on the date on which any shutdown begins.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H901287FD1C85467AB9DDABE202459CAF"> <enum>(2)</enum> <header>Legislative and judicial branch</header> <text>With respect to a Federal worker in a Government agency in the legislative branch or judicial branch (or, in the case of a Federal worker who is an employee of a contractor, who provides services at a Government agency in the legislative branch or judicial branch), the officer or employee at the Government agency who has the final authority to appoint, hire, discharge, and set the terms, conditions, or privileges of the employment of the Federal worker shall provide the notice required under paragraph (1).</text>
        </paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H56F4E5B617D74CB28F66D6F50F1B0A73"><enum>5.</enum><header>Anticipatory relief</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">A Federal worker who is furloughed or required to work without pay during a shutdown may apply to a court for a temporary stay, postponement, or suspension with respect to any payment of rent, mortgage, tax, fine, penalty, insurance premium, student loan repayment, or other civil obligation or liability that the Federal worker or individual, as applicable, owes or would owe during the duration of the shutdown.</text></section> <section id="HF298205816CB42B9A56DEEBDFEEED106"><enum>6.</enum><header>Evictions</header> <subsection id="H8EA5047C2A104413BA548E7477667D00"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Court-Ordered eviction</header><text>Except by the order of a court, a landlord may not, during a shutdown—</text> 
<paragraph id="H3D99B9DC05B9476FAD9AC4F68A19A083"><enum>(1)</enum><text>evict a Federal worker from premises that are occupied or intended to be occupied primarily as a residence; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBDCB6E1CA90B4E67B136702A4D0DDEBD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>subject premises described in paragraph (1) to a distress.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC63F5E0A064845D9961F6357C6FA5B9F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Stay of execution</header> 
<paragraph id="HD8217903F45140E6835DC7D01C9C13DD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Court authority</header><text>Upon an application for eviction or distress with respect to premises described in subsection (a)(1), a court may, upon motion of the court, and shall, if a request is made by or on behalf of a Federal worker, the ability of whom to pay the rent that is the subject of the action is materially affected by a shutdown—</text> <subparagraph id="H61B4A4299B944F46A56A6288CBB8D807"><enum>(A)</enum><text>stay the proceedings for a period of 30 days, unless, in the opinion of the court, justice and equity require a longer or shorter period of time; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H486A749E2C024470ABBD9E246F1E36A4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>adjust the obligation under the lease to preserve the interests of all parties.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8A59ED506DEE4FAFADB560B9B9A46DAA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Relief to landlord</header><text>If a court grants a stay under paragraph (1), the court may grant to the landlord (or other person with paramount title) such relief as equity may require.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H166FEFFE60C74193B5D265534A0DE857"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Misdemeanor</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (a), a person that knowingly takes part in an eviction or distress described in that subsection, or that knowingly attempts to take part in an eviction or distress described in that subsection, shall be fined as provided in title 18, United States Code, or imprisoned for not more than 1 year, or both.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H249685D453D344FEB0627B08A9A8402D"><enum>7.</enum><header>Mortgage protection and foreclosures</header> <subsection id="H950F998C5C0E4AE1B6BF91F7FD47728E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <term>covered action</term> means an action relating to an obligation—</text> 
<paragraph id="H924CCF4E41994C5CAF4D83A982781FC5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>with respect to real or personal property owned by a Federal worker; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H556D1791E2994A739C7489F86BAD8B1C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HA1EB5DCAB3D244369956F405E23BA3D7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>originated before the date on which a shutdown begins;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9073417B9ED8412C9AD7908B54AA412B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is in effect on the date on which a shutdown begins; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC6908113C63441B7945140C19DB86A5E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is secured by a mortgage, trust deed, or other security in the nature of a mortgage.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HED699870DBCF41FDBDF663F9651E6C63"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Stay of proceedings and adjustment of obligation</header><text>If a covered action is filed in a court during a covered period, the court may, after a hearing and upon the motion of the court, and shall, upon application by the Federal worker if the ability of the Federal worker to comply with the covered obligation is materially affected by the shutdown—</text> 
<paragraph id="H54A7DE4A192B4D50B3248B0E4B1BE7D7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>stay the proceedings for a period of time as justice and equity require; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7D12D922EC9147C39844DC3BFC711DAA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>adjust the obligation to preserve the interests of all parties.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H75DD7362A3CE4A959505063F8283AB7F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Sale or foreclosure</header><text>A sale, foreclosure, or seizure of property for a breach of an obligation described in subsection (a) by a Federal worker shall not be valid if made during a covered period except upon the order of a court that is granted before that sale, foreclosure, or seizure, as applicable, with a return made and approved by the court.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HA2EDCC7F7EBA4827B525647BF68F282C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Misdemeanor</header><text>A person that knowingly makes or causes to be made a sale, foreclosure, or seizure of property that is prohibited under subsection (c), or that knowingly attempts to make or cause to be made a sale, foreclosure, or seizure of property that is prohibited under that subsection, shall be fined as provided in title 18, United States Code, or imprisoned for not more than 1 year, or both.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H2F4A755CAB64478397E94229C86425FB"><enum>8.</enum><header>Liens</header> 
<subsection id="HA64DF3975F674CEB8F606C7B8D57BBC9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Liens</header> 
<paragraph id="H312884451C2C48098991CAC4CC44C219"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>lien</term> includes—</text> <subparagraph id="H6140435E4550486F8E7724B783426369"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a lien—</text> 
<clause id="H6F6A6FD415CD44C79DDC206BA168E58C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for storage, repair, or cleaning of the property or effects of a Federal worker; and</text></clause> <clause id="HE7A1F88287F542E9922ECE51E49B02BE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>on the property or effects described in clause (i) for any reason other than a reason described in that clause; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE13140CA71D448B2AC7BD05507B4C769"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a loan that a Federal worker has obtained with respect to a motor vehicle.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H74E0FE756C264895BCC90F45A6BAB701"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation on foreclosure or enforcement</header><text>A person holding a lien on the property or effects of a Federal worker may not, during a covered period, foreclose on or enforce that lien without the order of a court that was issued before the date on which that foreclosure or enforcement occurs.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8CBA92867BCA471280542083D318EC65"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Stay of proceedings</header><text>In a proceeding to foreclose on or enforce a lien that is subject to this section, a court may, upon the motion of the court, and shall, if requested by a Federal worker, the ability of whom to comply with the obligation resulting in the proceeding is materially affected by a shutdown—</text> <paragraph id="H809D2584C7864117BF2E4252A7BD805C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>stay the proceeding for a period of time as justice and equity require; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6FF98535939E4BC2AAD546F31EB83C2C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>adjust the obligation to preserve the interests of all parties.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H60047E3A5DEE433DB73F4A91DD648A7A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Misdemeanor</header><text>A person that knowingly takes an action that violates this section, or attempts to take an action that violates this section, shall be fined as provided in title 18, United States Code, or imprisoned for not more than 1 year, or both.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HBA302F2E5E66488296E4C548C3EE2085"><enum>9.</enum><header>Student loans</header> 
<subsection id="HD097B8A613354765BC4C1DF494FE100B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition of student loan</header><text>In this section, the term <term>student loan</term> means the following:</text> <paragraph id="H89C222590D5C42D9BA9FCE62A72995E9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A loan made, insured, or guaranteed under title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070">20 U.S.C. 1070 et seq.</external-xref>), including any Federal Direct Stafford Loan, Federal Direct Unsubsidized Stafford Loan, Federal Direct PLUS Loan, or Federal Direct Consolidation Loan.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H23568F9EC9CB492A95F1E7F141AA7175"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A private education loan, as such term is defined in section 140(a) of the Truth in Lending Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1650">15 U.S.C. 1650(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HDE3F2538719240A6B599EEC0FF3EE760"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application to student loans</header><text>This section shall apply to any situation in which—</text> 
<paragraph id="H408FC74E73114F698E27320E77BE159C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the student loan payment of a Federal worker falls due or remains unpaid during a shutdown; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9B699EA4E7414286B7FCE1BDF99E9323"><enum>(2)</enum><text>during the shutdown described in paragraph (1), the Federal worker described in that paragraph has been furloughed or required to work without pay.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H065737CE8FD546589F32ED5EAAB2ED76"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Deferment eligibility</header><text>During a covered period, a Federal worker shall be eligible for deferment, during which, with respect to a student loan, periodic installments of principal need not be paid and interest shall not accrue.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H45F2DC072C534B93B901423F6EF35244"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limitation on defaults</header><text>If the student loan payment of a Federal worker falls due and remains unpaid during a shutdown, the lender with respect to the student loan may not place the loan in default without the order of a court.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4D25E4629F834DD786B5C95D0F2CCDB0"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Limitation on collections</header><text>If the student loan of a Federal worker has been placed in default before the date on which a shutdown begins, the lender with respect to the student loan may not, without the order of a court, perform any of the following activities during the covered period with respect to the shutdown:</text> <paragraph id="H0FBA0CD45A6444C7ACD7F095D01B3EEB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Send the student loan to collection.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1E6F556089374C17B2C3821F9A1A0BCA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Report adverse information with respect to the Federal worker to a consumer reporting agency.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8D05965E877848549393FBBAAEE19D63"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Garnish wages, tax refunds, or government benefits.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H52ED5C6DF2C242EF82E7550A3CDE9FD9"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Court stay</header><text>In a proceeding to collect a student loan payment that is subject to this section, a court may, upon the motion of the court, and shall, if requested by a Federal worker whose ability to comply with the obligation resulting in the proceeding is materially affected by a shutdown—</text> <paragraph id="H22FE4F4E37A242088E2328BE0A38DD5A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>stay the proceeding for a period of time as justice and equity require; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE26F45F880D44685A6AF7F2BD312BC03"><enum>(2)</enum><text>adjust the obligation to preserve the interests of all parties.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFD03EC7F82454AB7812EE3F7BB9FED3D"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Misdemeanor</header><text>A person that knowingly violates this section, or attempts to violate this section, shall be fined as provided in title 18, United States Code, or imprisoned for not more than 1 year, or both.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H8A6FA98CF6E74037A1680D0707FA7253"><enum>10.</enum><header>Income taxes</header> 
<subsection id="H16FF97DDBF9A4D8D80FA6E72249D7930"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Deferral of tax</header><text>Upon notice to the Internal Revenue Service, the collection of Federal income tax on the income of a Federal worker falling due during a shutdown shall be deferred for a period of not more than 90 days after the date on which the shutdown ends if the ability of the Federal worker to pay the income tax is materially affected by the shutdown.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H2EFF199688CC40D79AB96D1977404A51"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Accrual of interest or penalty</header><text>No interest or penalty shall accrue during the period of deferment under subsection (a) by reason of nonpayment on any amount of tax deferred under this section.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H32DD49BDA6A348F28C97AB6E68BC7FE2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Statute of limitations</header><text>The running of a statute of limitations against the collection of tax deferred under this section, by seizure or otherwise, shall be suspended for the covered period with respect to the shutdown to which the collection applies.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="H6D6D5F385BD74C5ABC02E24BE3436EC0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Application limitation</header><text>This section shall not apply to the tax imposed on employees under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/3101">section 3101</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text></subsection></section> 
<section commented="no" id="H98C0B3A3990B4EBA90D111709B51F0EA"><enum>11.</enum><header>Insurance protection</header> 
<subsection commented="no" id="H8254CA87E211427D8382BEA2FFC2D436"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <term>covered insurance policy</term> means a policy—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="H0AADA6FFE44A4E0AAE665FC3FE885FCC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>for—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H5E5A7EECD4EF443D8431F6C117C91A2F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>health insurance;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HC1C53248B52F440E8952A85AA09C33C6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>life insurance;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H0419BB5F15EE4A9C8B374E20E681048F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>disability insurance; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HCE90DAD002D045DFBC4696DE45CB363D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>motor vehicle insurance; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H255DC95E1CA845FEA4F837DF66ADCA67"><enum>(2)</enum><text>that—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H4FC551E228CB435CBD01D0DDEE940EFD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a Federal worker enters into before the date on which a shutdown begins; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HF1EDFC2634BD4DC4B34B7158CCFDA865"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is in effect during a shutdown.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE833FF892F1B4E26B4F41B0FFBE5AC53"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Insurance protection</header><text>Without the order of a court, a covered insurance policy shall not lapse or otherwise terminate or be forfeited because a Federal worker does not pay a premium, or interest or indebtedness on a premium, under the policy that is due during a covered period with respect to a shutdown.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HDA3A6A5D72814078B61824B18DD752EE"><enum>12.</enum><header>Protection of rights</header> 
<subsection id="HFF5097338CE04488BDA301959B14AE57"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Exercise of rights under chapter not To affect certain future financial transactions</header><text>An application by a Federal worker for, or the receipt by a Federal worker of, a stay, postponement, or suspension under this Act with respect to the payment of a fine, penalty, insurance premium, or other civil obligation or liability of that Federal worker shall not itself (without regard to other considerations) provide the basis for any of the following:</text> <paragraph id="HD5D5B5A5E7724A7EB540E65F282389E9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A determination by a lender or other person that the Federal worker is unable to pay the civil obligation or liability, as applicable, in accordance with the terms of the obligation or liability.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H06B5E3CF2FDE41D5A2B7702744ED52E8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>With respect to a credit transaction between a creditor and the Federal worker—</text> <subparagraph id="HFCD66480366D4F498E5D009953198FD3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a denial or revocation of credit by the creditor;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7E1858EEECE449619BF458C57E300844"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a change by the creditor in the terms of an existing credit arrangement; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC0E389869DD6491A9E4CC2EAAF8DB214"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a refusal by the creditor to grant credit to the Federal worker in substantially the amount or on substantially the terms requested.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF08191B6544A423D89D826B6B39D0DF1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>An adverse report relating to the creditworthiness of the Federal worker by or to a person engaged in the practice of assembling or evaluating consumer credit information.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H65A41AF9D1EA42A7968DF4E5E105B684"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A refusal by an insurer to insure the Federal worker.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H04E42D085A1F49F4B36939AC5D844967"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A change in the terms offered or conditions required for the issuance of insurance.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H91A61B282FD745DA87E1FAE268064BC0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reduction or waiver of fines or penalties</header><text>If a Federal worker fails to perform an obligation arising under a contract and a penalty is incurred arising from that nonperformance, a court may reduce or waive the fine or penalty if—</text> 
<paragraph id="HDAADBE96A6734C8F9713E5F8947851D0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Federal worker was furloughed or required to work without pay during a shutdown on the date on which the fine or penalty was incurred; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCEEC841F91D0495D9984F78A0F47E6C3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the ability of the Federal worker to perform the obligation was materially affected by the shutdown described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H88183DF657314564918995E53907583A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Court action upon material affect determination</header><text>If a court determines that a Federal worker is materially affected by a shutdown in complying with a judgment or an order of a court, the court may, upon the motion of the court, and shall, on application by the Federal worker—</text> <paragraph id="HC4C06F1B09524CC1975D66B3C8368183"><enum>(1)</enum><text>stay the execution of any judgment or order entered against the Federal worker; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H109580EE87B24271A6B9638634320FAF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>vacate or stay an attachment or garnishment of property, money, or debts in the possession of the Federal worker or a third party, whether before or after the entry of a judgment.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H5AA81917BC3B45F099C8AAEFC426F50F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Dependents</header><text>Upon application to a court, a dependent of a Federal worker is entitled to the protections under this Act if the ability of the dependent to comply with a lease, contract, bailment, or other obligation is materially affected by reason of the impact of a shutdown on the Federal worker.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HEE31E560D4704F6FA48609DC40FDB92A"><enum>13.</enum><header>Enforcement</header> 
<subsection id="HDDFFE73459C243AE85CD795048EDFFCA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Civil action</header><text>The Attorney General may commence a civil action in any appropriate district court of the United States against any person that engages in—</text> <paragraph id="H137C78F844294776AA4BD250A0FA08B7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a pattern or practice of violating this Act; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEA5E7A1FD63F414FA67D9DF665529717"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a violation of this Act that raises an issue of significant public importance.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC5DD8BD4949F4348882ECDCE006E2421"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Relief</header><text>In a civil action commenced under subsection (a), a court may—</text> 
<paragraph id="HAD86CCF4406C4E0E9BFDF87760D31FA2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>grant any appropriate equitable or declaratory relief with respect to the violation of this Act;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H85ED3994CA1E42A5A523EE38ABFD0777"><enum>(2)</enum><text>award all other appropriate relief, including monetary damages, to any person aggrieved by the violation described in paragraph (1); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7CAAC7D8DC43484E828280465AB2E98A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to vindicate the public interest, assess a civil penalty—</text> <subparagraph id="H1C9A4A66B88D403DA0F188E8F0FBFDCB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in an amount that is not more than $55,000 for a first violation; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9892807CAD234E1F9FDE9B6637ABBDE8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in an amount that is not more than $110,000 for any subsequent violation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HB28A7E9392B0405DA59B9D4EA2A6633A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Intervention</header><text>Upon timely application, a person that is aggrieved by a violation of this Act with respect to which a civil action is commenced under subsection (a) may—</text> 
<paragraph id="H1C3F25EDFEC14F3FB29059A0E0AB2BB5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>intervene in the action; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8A3E30DAB9EF40AAA4D57EA3FA9C7E65"><enum>(2)</enum><text>obtain such appropriate relief as the person could obtain in a civil action under subsection (d) with respect to that violation, along with costs and a reasonable attorney fee.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H423268588A574DF1BC33BD8B89291797"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Private right of action</header><text>Any person that, after the date of enactment of this Act, is aggrieved by a violation of this Act may, in a civil action—</text> <paragraph id="H039AAB56325F4964B30E0357178CEA3A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>obtain any appropriate equitable or declaratory relief with respect to the violation; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7EE61C7938E147A595C01B30D2A3B199"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recover all other appropriate relief, including monetary damages.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HA7F51B802E994C588F85B5F33C56604C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Costs and attorney fees</header><text>A court may award to a person aggrieved by a violation of this Act that prevails in an action brought under subsection (d) the costs of the action, including a reasonable attorney fee.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H352ABA42B8C643E4B097AC33F63A4545"><enum>(f)</enum><header>No preemption</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to preclude or limit any remedy otherwise available under other law, including consequential and punitive damages.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

