<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-RIL25150-0K2-K0-DW1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 85 ATS: Congratulating the Jackson State University Tigers for winning the 2024 Celebration Bowl.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 85</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250219">February 19, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S318">Mr. Wicker</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S395">Mrs. Hyde-Smith</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Congratulating the Jackson State University Tigers for winning the 2024 Celebration Bowl.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, on Saturday, December 14, 2024, the Jackson State University football team won the 2024 Celebration Bowl, which is played every year between the conference champions of the Southwestern Athletic Conference and the Mid-Eastern Athletic Conference;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Celebration Bowl is widely respected as a national title game for Historically Black Colleges and Universities, succeeding the previous Pelican Bowl and Heritage Bowl;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Jackson State University Tigers defeated the South Carolina State University Bulldogs 28–7 and claimed the Celebration Bowl trophy for the first time in program history;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Jackson State University football team only lost 2 games during the 2024 college football season, finishing the season with a record of 12–2 and the first-ranked team in the Southwestern Athletic Conference;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Jackson State University football team averaged 36.43 points per game during the 2024 season;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Jackson State University football team completed a ground-breaking run through the postseason, finishing on top of 17 other universities in the Southwestern Athletic Conference and the Mid-Eastern Athletic Conference;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas running back Travis Terrell Jr. was named the 2024 Southwestern Athletic Conference Freshman of the Year and Special Teams Player of the Year;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas running back Irv Mulligan was named the Southwestern Athletic Conference Offensive Player of the Year;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas head coach T.C. Taylor was named the Southwestern Athletic Conference Head Coach of the Year;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas head coach T.C. Taylor, having led the Jackson State University football team for 2 seasons as its 22nd head coach, carried the team to a 19–6 record for the past 2 seasons;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Jackson State University football team’s home stadium, the Mississippi Veterans Memorial Stadium, honors military veterans and their families who have sacrificed their lives in service to the State of Mississippi and the United States; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Jackson State University football team displayed outstanding dedication, teamwork, and sportsmanship, bringing tremendous pride and honor to—</text><paragraph id="id5507f5a689c042d2921b31caf5f42454"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Jackson State University;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8bec65e467eb423d8f487d64587693f0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>loyal fans of the Jackson State University Tigers; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id477cd9f6ca2b438fb7df7cef8534a61b"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the entire State of Mississippi: Now, therefore, be it</text></paragraph></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="idf55ba7193af74026b07ca8a9de7f424a"><enum>(1)</enum><text>congratulates Jackson State University, as well as its athletes, coaching staff, administration, faculty, students, and alumni, for winning the 2024 Celebration Bowl;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6696209dcdb74fb6925a613568db0cf3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes Jackson State University for its excellence as an institution of higher education; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idee3eacb533e446668227d4c85dfc01cd"><enum>(3)</enum><text>respectfully requests that the Secretary of the Senate transmit an enrolled copy of this resolution to—</text><subparagraph id="id96a370f65ea84a3aaf7b5b5348ae6f9e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the president of Jackson State University, Dr. Marcus L. Thompson;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc20cf9ae6fa14745aee13e7f828dbdf4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the athletic director of Jackson State University, Ashley Robinson; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9c89542dccb24e35ad53037f48b87b5e"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the head coach of the Jackson State University football team, T.C. Taylor. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

