<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-EHF25027-7TY-7C-9DH"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S806 IS: Hatch Act Enforcement Transparency and Accountability Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 806</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250227">February 27, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S409">Mr. Luján</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S359">Mr. Heinrich</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend title 5, United States Code, to increase the accountability of the Office of Special Counsel in enforcing certain provisions of that title vigorously, consistently, and without regard to the political affiliation, career status, or personal characteristics of individuals subject to those provisions, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Hatch Act Enforcement Transparency and Accountability Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id441d01bf8053423b85fee3ec16e73271"><enum>2.</enum><header>Addition of definitions</header><subsection id="id0AC8A8BDD60440F39B0090D03608804F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/12">chapter 12</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="id84C144618B6946FF90BEF409EC09CF1D" act-name=""><section section-type="section-one" id="id3A3ED6B63FB8483E8D9A09459AA5CF84"><enum>1219a.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this subchapter:</text><paragraph id="id24BF273BAAD04FA18C88B282CF67590C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Career employee</header><text>The term <term>career employee</term> means an individual who is— </text><subparagraph id="id4CF6D0AC747E4ED3B571D11DD11AC151"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an employee, as that term is defined in section 7322; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idF6922A83E18342C5A59B95BE62887B46"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not a noncareer employee.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id606A5B6406CE40B7AFB6A7C8969A4876"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered allegation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered allegation</term> means an allegation concerning political activity prohibited under subchapter III of chapter 73.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idFFB027566A3B495B946E905D222ED9BE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Noncareer employee</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>noncareer employee</term> means an individual who is—</text><subparagraph id="id3F1E1041ABB14868A2BA7FE7B3AC405A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an employee, as defined in section 2105, serving in a position in the executive branch; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id81E3EFB745E3420BA827563AB3FA6890"><enum>(B)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idE99EC6D7CB3848BC897AB9F4146D32F9"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">serving in a position to which the President appointed the individual (without regard to whether the advice and consent of the Senate was required with respect to that appointment), other than an individual who is—</text><subclause indent="up1" id="idDBF0B40C16E74BE3835EFB123F324CF9"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a member of a uniformed service, as that term is defined in section 210(m) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/410">42 U.S.C. 410(m)</external-xref>); or</text></subclause><subclause indent="up1" id="idE90364C3FA094E57A678F5D6E3EB3A4E"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a member of the Foreign Service serving under a career appointment, as described in section 301 of the Foreign Service Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/3941">22 U.S.C. 3941</external-xref>);</text></subclause></clause><clause indent="up1" id="id552CA045B7344AFA915AB8D96F5125BB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a noncareer appointee, as that term is defined in section 3132(a); </text></clause><clause indent="up1" id="idE061F0962B9D4128BF18A103AAF00D56"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">serving in a position in a Federal executive system that is comparable to the Senior Executive Service, the appointment to which is not made through merit-based procedures, such as a position in the Transportation Security Executive Service; or</text></clause><clause indent="up1" id="id8A0E18798BA5499AB2DBE6D7EF206A0B"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">serving in a position with respect to which a determination has been made under section 7511(b)(2).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="idB1BBA4D36F5E466092FFFFB9CD5022A2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendment</header><text>The table of sections for subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/12">chapter 12</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idDE6C55CEAE6E4151A31D55BFD6B046D7"><toc><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">1219a. Definitions.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="id9ED2AD62FDD34DA69FDED69FB2624189"><enum>3.</enum><header>Notifying Congress in the event of a decision not to investigate a noncareer employee</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1217 of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id85037897816c45529845adeecb9ce9ef"><subsection id="id12d221075e824c51be602d5f74459a52"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Notification of Congress in the event of certain declinations</header><paragraph id="id5f7ff46a48234427884af92fbd4c07e8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this subsection, and once every 180 days thereafter, the Special Counsel shall submit to the Chair and Ranking Member of each of the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives a written report that contains, for the period covered by the report, the number of complaints received by the Special Counsel that the Special Counsel referred for disciplinary action.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbde70bba3c5249fc97f82748652319e0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Each report required under paragraph (1) shall—</text><subparagraph id="id420E53E2207047EF845DF484FE7E7D26"><enum>(A)</enum><text>include—</text><clause id="ida2764e4640a546b480f904fd708d9b5e"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a copy of the applicable complaint;</text></clause><clause id="id2a010d1ca56e462aa0e29d6e50f03caf"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the name and position of the employee who is the subject of the applicable complaint; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide143fd461bf74492ae57c01d209e2c37"><enum>(B)</enum><text>be organized to indicate whether the employee who is the subject of each complaint contained in the report is a career employee or a noncareer employee.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="ide0b141968a184a56a1ff5e19d7516060"><enum>4.</enum><header>Reporting to Congress</header><subsection id="id43EE9041207D405581985EEB3B97F8AF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1218 of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="id8DFC0ED4E96845E3BCAAE7AA43D98A72"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the section heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="USC">report</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="USC">reports</header-in-text></quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5550D8CAB1084FA886133A60AD6169DA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by striking <quote>The Special</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="id3717346309AD469C9CD3F4FDEE98888B" act-name=""><subsection id="id10FBC62351EF4F76A734D374EB2EABC4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Special</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="idda1ab4a11a7244a2b682216e70ac6564"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc6886a15af544d69af65cd78c8e96b70"><subsection id="id3cb43937f8d44006b5d380c715d2ab28"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report regarding allegations against noncareer employees</header><text>In addition to each report required under subsection (a), the Special Counsel shall submit to the Chair and Ranking Member of each committee of jurisdiction in Congress, on an annual basis, a report regarding the activities of the Special Counsel with respect to covered allegations against noncareer employees and former noncareer employees, which shall include—</text><paragraph id="id45ae61374f9b48799f9f0e238ed48dd7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>for the year preceding the submission of the report, the number of such covered allegations received by the Special Counsel;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id311aa047d70a47e7b5ab7b4574f939a1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the number of such covered allegations that have resulted in an investigation conducted by the Special Counsel, whether the investigation was initiated during the year covered by the report or thereafter; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id76181b1abd984877a7b9ac4ceb3429d6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in a confidential addendum submitted to the Chair and Ranking Member of each of the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives— </text><subparagraph id="idAB0F2F8FE2A1494780A690BDE3587AF4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>with respect to each such covered allegation not investigated, the name and position of the noncareer employee (or former noncareer employee) who was the subject of the covered allegation; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6b43e6f060644d82b7efa94bf4ed8dcf"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of each such covered allegation for which processing of the covered allegation ceased during the year covered by the report, without regard to whether the covered allegation was received during the year covered by the report or earlier, which shall include— </text><clause id="id67D257BD9A9347C1B88EF76F3E20DBD7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a description of the outcome of the covered allegation; and </text></clause><clause id="id1709B19896224DE88BF56870E4458D2F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case of a covered allegation against a noncareer employee who is not serving in a position with respect to which appointment by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, is required (or against a former noncareer employee who was not serving in such a position, as of the date on which the actions that are the subject of the covered allegation occurred), a statement as to whether— </text><subclause id="id2D1EFA6296144DA68BF7CD9A8A62BFE9"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the Special Counsel, under section 1215(a), presented a complaint to the Merit Systems Protection Board against the noncareer employee (or former noncareer employee) concerning the actions that are the subject of the covered allegation; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id8F8F7E4E6E5F49888E52BEDD9182576E"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any civil penalty assessed by the Merit Systems Protection Board under section 7326 with respect to the covered allegation has been collected in full.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id8EEF9AB38EC043EB850F6F2C4807A996"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendment</header><text>The table of sections for subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/12">chapter 12</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended by striking the item relating to section 1218 and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5D0436430FA44A5AB5107EB5F5FC11A5"><toc><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">1218. Annual reports.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="id51f23991be8641a9a6866ee65c36e3aa"><enum>5.</enum><header>Public transparency in Hatch Act enforcement</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1219 of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" id="id1D0E9587299A43C6A7133C9A4B7ED700"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="idf78e2b1315374390981a4212b2b13b08"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id8cb00ef49fda48db8ae4ed83a84c2ab4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id5f354a4eac374ca9b4ce461513e1d46b"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idF601E32232464EF896B33F53053CD189"><paragraph id="idc723151b743a49dc9ddc92d57fe34dbc"><enum>(5)</enum><text>a detailed written explanation of the complete basis for each decision of the Special Counsel not to present, under section 1215(a), a complaint to the Merit Systems Protection Board against any noncareer employee determined by the Special Counsel to have violated subchapter III of chapter 73, except that this paragraph shall not apply with respect to a noncareer employee who is serving in a position for which nomination by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, is required (unless such a noncareer employee is serving in a position in the Foreign Service).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id996883E6A1B54A959ECFEA196922C473"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (b) as subsection (c); and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id2aa7ce7e231d48bebc7d24ebaefa34da"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (a) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7c472572095f4bf8b148c379399bd410"><subsection id="ide5f163ffe3f44d87b249cbf0d2319c6b"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Publication of demographic statistics regarding certain enforcement</header><paragraph id="idac3520c46386413b844f867bf321ce98"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Special Counsel shall track, publish, and keep current on the official website of the Office of Special Counsel the following information, which shall remain on that website for a period of not less than 10 fiscal years, beginning with the fiscal year to which the information pertains:</text><subparagraph id="id3477FAA96B7C4FB39579FC28CF967AA8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>On an ongoing basis, the following anonymized information pertaining to covered allegations against career employees, which shall be organized by fiscal year:</text><clause id="id6e3d8a9ee5e64d5e97384efa5c99185d"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The number of career employees who were the subject of covered allegations received by the Special Counsel during the applicable fiscal year.</text></clause><clause id="idb03beae62e874c3f93424fcb097af5ce"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>With respect to the career employees identified under clause (i)— </text><subclause id="idB9F4E695534A41D0AC8F07FB844A5E12"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the number of those career employees who the Special Counsel investigated, without regard to whether the investigation occurred during the fiscal year in which the Special Counsel received the initial covered allegation with respect to such a career employee or during a subsequent fiscal year; and</text></subclause><subclause id="idc795f94d9dd546e78e8e04beb768d305"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the number of those career employees who were the subject of a complaint presented by the Special Counsel to the Merit Systems Protection Board with respect to the applicable covered allegation, without regard to whether the Special Counsel presented such a complaint during the fiscal year in which the Special Counsel received the initial covered allegation with respect to such a career employee or during a subsequent fiscal year.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id293b6ecfeacd449b9bb5fc39d2f7290f"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>For clauses (i) and (ii), demographic information pertaining to the race, sex, ethnicity, national origin, and disability status of the applicable career employees. </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id65D9056B7256411198F56443291E6BF0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>On an ongoing basis, the following anonymized information pertaining to covered allegations against noncareer employees, which shall be organized by fiscal year:</text><clause id="id3DB8BD80044E4FFBA2758A803B9C4E12"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The number of noncareer employees who were the subject of covered allegations received by the Special Counsel during the applicable fiscal year.</text></clause><clause id="id0F175462916746759CA6800EE53F576F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>With respect to the noncareer employees identified under clause (i)— </text><subclause id="id8D155F1F13E04A07AA97303E258718D9"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the number of those noncareer employees who the Special Counsel investigated, without regard to whether the investigation occurred during the fiscal year in which the Special Counsel received the initial covered allegation with respect to such a noncareer employee or during a subsequent fiscal year; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id750824BB3FBA4E45A781EBE90EF90A46"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the number of those noncareer employees who were the subject of a complaint presented by the Special Counsel to the Merit Systems Protection Board with respect to the applicable covered allegation, without regard to whether the Special Counsel presented such a complaint during the fiscal year in which the Special Counsel received the initial covered allegation with respect to such a noncareer employee or during a subsequent fiscal year.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id5DE43688725D4897ADEA382B103C9CB5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>For clauses (i) and (ii), demographic information pertaining to the race, sex, ethnicity, national origin, and disability status of the applicable noncareer employees. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ida505811d7b764ae08a1b08b626a048aa"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Demographic information</header><text>The Director of the Office of Personnel Management, the head of the agency employing an individual who is the subject of a complaint filed with the Special Counsel, and, as applicable, the White House Presidential Personnel Office shall, upon request, provide the Special Counsel with information pertaining to the race, sex, ethnicity, national origin, disability status, and status as a career employee or noncareer employee of that individual, if that information has already been collected in connection with the Federal employment or former Federal employment of that individual.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="id8bb048ad81a14671b401d71eccbf35cb"><enum>6.</enum><header>Severability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any provision of this Act, or of any amendment made by this Act, or the application of any provision of this Act, or of any amendment made by this Act, to any person or circumstance is held to be unconstitutional, the remainder of this Act, and the amendments made by this Act, and the application of the provision this Act, or of the amendment made by this Act, to any other person or circumstance shall not be affected by the holding.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

