<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4C1A745CC1F246BBB04DDB38EDA4F53F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4255 IH: Enhancing Safety for Animals Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4255</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250630">June 30, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000565">Mr. Gosar</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001302">Mr. Biggs of Arizona</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000825">Ms. Boebert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001132">Mr. Crane</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001096">Ms. Hageman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001098">Mr. Hamadeh of Arizona</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001100">Mr. Hurd of Colorado</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000578">Mr. LaMalfa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001212">Mr. Stauber</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000165">Mr. Tiffany</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="Z000018">Mr. Zinke</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To remove the Mexican wolf from the lists of threatened species and endangered species published pursuant to the Endangered Species Act of 1973, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8582C9F229AF4CDAA1DC9D1D0D14F51A" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H9B76B220F81A4F2EB36912348CCB3050" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Enhancing Safety for Animals Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H7F9BF8F9CA3B48BEB903BB531133AEDC" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Delisting of Mexican wolf</header> <subsection id="H18731A1996FC4EC6A0758E5782F3A463"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H3B260C0AE6964BF0A67CF6ABAC40B1E3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Mexican wolf population has increased for 9 consecutive years, growing by at least 11 percent in 2024.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H388E602582424B5185E27E1E42E3FDDE"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At the end of 2024, the United States Fish and Wildlife Service documented a presence of at least 286 wild Mexican wolves and approximately 350 captive Mexican wolves.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3E67EAA3547A4A728C3D60429FA3BEE8"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States Mexican Wolf population is thriving and will meet its recovery goals for gene diversity, population growth, and abundance.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9C834D33E3624EBE96B31CEFB2BC61D9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The United States Fish and Wildlife Service has repeatedly moved Mexican wolf recovery goalposts through amended recovery plans, revised population and genetic objectives, and reduced mitigation opportunities.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB3DB26796A99414DAE5760B4A466F0E3"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Current United States Fish and Wildlife recovery strategies and goals encompass not only the Mexican wolf population in the United States, but also in Mexico.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H10EDFDDCA6314A09B620CB50F5682E0D"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Americans in the Mexican Wolf Experimental Population Area bear the brunt of a rapidly growing United States Mexican wolf population without any chance of recovery because of failing conservation activities in Mexico, a foreign country.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H68709F31DCDA4D54A02846A97A92CC6A"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Mexican wolves in the United States routinely kill livestock, pose serious safety risks to humans and pets, excessively prey upon game animals, and reduce recreational opportunities.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF276F2A1FD3F47A1888518F265787728"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Depredation of cattle, horses, and other livestock by Mexican wolves financially burdens American farmers and ranchers living in and near the Mexican Wolf Experimental Population Area.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD0841535E8464DD68E0B793F57B1AFAD"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Rather than streamline Mexican wolf depredation evidentiary standards to ensure ranchers are properly compensated for livestock losses, the Wildlife Services division of the Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service imposed for a year a new standard requiring that subcutaneous hemorrhaging be present on carcasses as a condition of confirming that an animal was killed by a Mexican wolf.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD578CDD119B94998AA9F268C68FC2E0F"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Confirming that livestock were killed by Mexican wolves is often impossible under the newly adopted evidentiary standard because livestock grazing areas in and near the Mexican Wolf Experimental Population Area are often thousands of acres in size, depredations are commonly only discovered days after they occur, scavengers often devour livestock carcasses along with depredation evidence, and subcutaneous hemorrhaging remains preset for a short period of time following depredation.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2FCCF6B980FE4EA4AA4DC7DFBC559C84"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Requiring evidence of subcutaneous hemorrhaging is inconsistent with other widely accepted depredation evidentiary standards like bite marks, tracks, and signs of struggle, and significantly reduces the ability for livestock owners to be made whole financially after suffering losses through Mexican wolf depredation.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5F0334F78BBD44ABB0B677EEE8914EFF"><enum>(12)</enum><text>The Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service’s opaque depredation evidentiary standards are not subject to a public notice and comment process but are nevertheless blindly adopted by the United States Fish and Wildlife Service.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB370C48ECCF041FAB12CAB1FC25DDC76"><enum>(13)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States Fish and Wildlife Service has refused to take or approve sufficient lethal removal actions against Mexican wolves despite the deaths, injuries, and damage caused by Mexican wolves leading to at least 2 counties within the Mexican Wolf Experimental Population Area declaring a public disaster and emergency, and at least 1 Tribal government formally supporting such declaration</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H797C2671EECD48219B6765CBAEE1260C"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Delisting of Mexican wolf</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Mexican wolf (Canis lupus baileyi) is removed from the lists of threatened species and endangered species, as applicable, that are published pursuant to section 4 of the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1533">16 U.S.C. 1533</external-xref>).</text>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="HC2A88997C8C1493C827C903FAD8F2B10"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Nullification of rules relating to Mexican wolf</header><text>The following final rules issued by the United States Fish and Wildlife Service with respect to the Mexican wolf shall have no force or effect:</text> <paragraph id="HB3EE828354CB4619AA1C3FAF5AF03D33"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The final rule titled <quote>Endangered and Threatened Wildlife and Plants; Endangered Status for the Mexican Wolf</quote> (80 Fed. Reg. 2488; published January 16, 2015).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H82D3DA0CCA2C4D289993B56CA89C95EC"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The final rule titled <quote>Endangered and Threatened Wildlife and Plants; Revision to the Nonessential Experimental Population of the Mexican Wolf</quote> (87 Fed. Reg. 39348; published July 1, 2022).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H78E66E1D83384F2B9CAF47AEA4154B50"> <enum>(d)</enum> <header>Bifurcation of Mexican wolf population criteria</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Mexican wolf (Canis lupus baileyi) is listed as a threatened species or an endangered species under the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1531">16 U.S.C. 1531 et seq.</external-xref>) after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, may not reference or otherwise consider—</text>
                <paragraph id="H188604C93B214FFD869120414BB94BEA">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>the status of the recovery of the Mexican wolf in Mexico in developing or implementing under section 4(f) of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1533">16 U.S.C. 1533(f)</external-xref>) a plan for the Mexican wolf; or</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H58014EDCCB654599BDB94A6AF4F0F784">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the status of the Mexican wolf in Mexico in determining under section 4(c) of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1533">16 U.S.C. 1533(c)</external-xref>) whether the Mexican wolf should be—</text>
                    <subparagraph id="H2BBAD292DC2D4DEABF4A46FA4853F986">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>changed in status from an endangered species to a threatened species;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H36FA874E640B4CEF805FD348360226B1">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>changed in status from a threatened species to an endangered species; or</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H6A79703038364EA3806BF46AA4F2DEDD">
                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>removed from the lists of threatened species and endangered species, as applicable, that are published pursuant to section 4 of the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1533">16 U.S.C. 1533</external-xref>).</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection> </section> 
</legis-body></bill>

