<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Engrossed-in-House" dms-id="HC823BB669E4146CB8A726C3894085BBA" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H" stage-count="1">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 481 EH: Condemning the rise in ideologically motivated attacks on Jewish individuals in the United States, including the recent violent assault in Boulder, Colorado, and reaffirming the House of Representatives commitment to combating antisemitism and politically motivated violence.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">IV</distribution-code>
<congress display="no">119th CONGRESS</congress>
<session display="no">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 481</legis-num>
<current-chamber display="yes">In the House of Representatives, U. S.,</current-chamber>
<action>
<action-date date="20250609">June 9, 2025</action-date>
</action>
<legis-type display="yes">RESOLUTION</legis-type>
<official-title display="no">Condemning the rise in ideologically motivated attacks on Jewish individuals in the United States, including the recent violent assault in Boulder, Colorado, and reaffirming the House of Representatives commitment to combating antisemitism and politically motivated violence.</official-title>
</form>
<preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, on June 1, 2025, in Boulder, Colorado, a peaceful gathering held by the group <quote>Run for Their Lives</quote> was violently attacked by an individual armed with incendiary devices, resulting in multiple injuries, including to elderly participants, in what authorities have called a targeted, ideologically motivated act of terrorism;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas this attack represents the latest in a growing trend of politically and religiously motivated violence directed at Jewish individuals and institutions across the United States;</text></whereas> 
<whereas> <text>Whereas, on May 21, 2025, two Israeli Embassy staff members—Yaron Lischinsky and Sarah Lynn Milgrim—were fatally shot outside the Capital Jewish Museum in Washington, DC, following a reception for diplomats, and the suspect shouted <quote>Free, free Palestine!</quote> during his arrest;</text> </whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, on April 13, 2025, an individual set multiple fires using incendiary devices at the Pennsylvania Governor’s Residence while Governor Josh Shapiro and his family were inside following a Passover Seder; the suspect, motivated by hostility toward the Governor’s stance on Israel and Palestinians, admitted intent to cause harm and now faces charges including attempted murder, terrorism, and arson;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas these attacks, though distinct in method and geography, share a common pattern of targeting Jewish individuals or symbols of Jewish life and civic engagement;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas no American should be subjected to violence or intimidation because of their religion, heritage, or peaceful advocacy; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas acts of antisemitism—whether expressed through threats, vandalism, or violence—are fundamentally incompatible with the values of the United States and must be condemned unequivocally: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble> <resolution-body style="traditional" id="H13EF6E0056044AA28A63AA9476B0D668"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H4FCA0D10A7AC4B148867096852E194D3"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text> 
<paragraph id="H005DF73FA8304254AAF9365FB88BB903"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">condemns in the strongest possible terms the June 1, 2025, targeted act of terror in Boulder, Colorado, as a cowardly act of ideologically motivated violence;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7BD0958A848C4D219CFF05BBF9B1F9C0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes this attack as part of a disturbing pattern of targeted aggression against Jewish individuals in the United States;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5C4FB761BEB64644958B1C5292ED9EB0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>reaffirms its commitment to protecting the rights of all Americans to assemble peacefully and practice their faith without fear of violence;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA54A00CDA06A4876B40086A0129CC746"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">calls on Federal, State, and local law enforcement agencies to ensure thorough investigation and prosecution of all such incidents; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1C2197C8035F42CEABA6C6D113950D83"><enum>(5)</enum><text>urges elected officials, community leaders, and civil society to speak out against antisemitism and politically motivated violence in all forms.</text></paragraph> </section> </resolution-body> <attestation><attestation-group><attestor display="no">Kevin F. McCumber,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation> </resolution> 

