<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5336EDD5C97245FD82CBD1A65213EC86" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4343 IH: United States-Greece Security Cooperation Reporting Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4343</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250710">July 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="B001257">Mr. Bilirakis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M000317">Ms. Malliotakis</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Defense to submit a report on the security relationship between the United States and the Hellenic Republic, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H7243138F1B844AFCA2D8CD06BD9AB980" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H895EC61DD2994BE99E2E65F254AF9FC1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>United States-Greece Security Cooperation Reporting Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="HDC2C7DF7104A475287E6411C4D5D8D58"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
<paragraph id="HAB2F0FC3144C4C45B38662A170765D57"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The United States and the Hellenic Republic share a longstanding and robust security relationship, rooted in shared democratic values, mutual strategic interests, and joint membership in the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H862FE22154BD4616A91C25D06007C84C"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>The United States-Greece Mutual Defense Cooperation Agreement (MDCA), updated on October 14, 2021, reflects the deepening defense partnership between the two countries and enhances the United States ability to operate across the Eastern Mediterranean, Southeastern Europe, Eastern Europe, and the Middle East.</text>
      </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H218F5964C0B6403292E573745613F482"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Hellenic Republic occupies a strategically vital geographic position that supports regional security, energy diversification, and efforts to counter malign influence.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H155A525D6F0242428780916206B3DB27"><enum>(4)</enum><text>United States military investments and activities at key locations in Greece, such as Alexandroupolis, Larisa, Stefanovikio, and Souda Bay, have contributed to improved United States and NATO interoperability, operational flexibility, and deterrence posture.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0E97F4B206C9457295B0CF9CD7CC41FF"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Port of Alexandroupolis has emerged as a critical logistical hub for the United States and NATO, enabling the rapid deployment of forces and equipment to Eastern and Southeastern Europe and beyond.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCAEDECED9786412CB382BD1566377256"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Naval Support Activity (NSA) Souda Bay is one of the most strategically important United States naval facilities in the Eastern Mediterranean and helps support forward-deployed operations, maritime security, and the defense of multiple theaters, including Eastern and Southeastern Europe.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HCE0A9719CD9B4D8D94EBFD62DD4BEF00"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Subtitle B of title XIII of division A of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2022 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/81">Public Law 117–81</external-xref>), known as the United States-Greece Defense and Interparliamentary Partnership Act of 2021, mandated a framework to further strengthen bilateral defense cooperation, expand joint training opportunities, and promote interparliamentary engagement.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE50D569440F342A59C5142C1C97196E5"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Ongoing instability and increased geopolitical competition highlight the need for continued assessment and adaptation of the United States military posture and security cooperation with Greece.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="H35F38BBA8B0B48FEA15F266F30803FDB"><enum>3.</enum><header>Report on the security relationship between the United States and the Hellenic Republic</header>
<subsection id="H5683766D1DC84B7D86A07731A2B35663"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense, in coordination with the Commander of United States European Command, shall jointly submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the security relationship between the United States and the Hellenic Republic.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H2370F66D32514910AC6448B65255A147"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report contents</header><text>The report required under subsection (a) shall include the following:</text>
<paragraph id="HFC92BDFBD7DA40DABD37BC942D78F8D8"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of the basing rights granted to the United States under the updated United States-Greece Mutual Defense Cooperation Agreement (MDCA), signed October 14, 2021.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4A3C61D6888A435EAC7B09FFE7997ACA"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of United States activities and investment on the bases covered in the MDCA since such date.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H146FBCDAC13E49CD9A632778605982E6"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A project of investments needed in association with United States basing rights at Alexandroupolis.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBF85ECEBC9E94108B2BC2D56580AD361"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An analysis of the potential for additional bases or expanded United States military presence in the Hellenic Republic, particularly on Greek islands.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HCDA893E38469473F80C97372A1C8BB36">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of the status of the security cooperation mandated pursuant to subtitle B of title XIII of division A of the National Defense Authorization Act of Fiscal Year 2022 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/81">Public Law 117–81</external-xref>; relating to the United States-Greece Defense and Interparliamentary Partnership Act of 2021).</text>
        </paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H5FF9711DEA1348FAACA25AA00F00E0D4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means—</text> <paragraph id="HB55AADC19B354298A534826F4956B519"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The House Armed Services Committee; or</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9BB9C9B097E64EB9AF05D1440CB2EAF3"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Senate Armed Services Committee.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

