<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2DCCAFAC660D45A9AD39DF0FDA416AC4" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 834 IH: Disaster Assistance Fairness Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 834</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250131">January 31, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000603">Mr. Rouzer</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="T000486">Mr. Torres of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000620">Ms. Pettersen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to provide assistance for common interest communities, condominiums, and housing cooperatives damaged by a major disaster, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H1E43C3866223453B9EE47F121CDCBE81" style="OLC"><section id="HDBBCB51A69834484930B203EB8B0ACBC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Disaster Assistance Fairness Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H7E58731B2BF94A70BFC7A2EF3033BF23"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 102 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5122">42 U.S.C. 5122</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H07A4CD85E62C49CD899C2ADE2F8715C4" style="OLC"><paragraph id="HA2B0DCB395C844F0ABEDE9BB52C02313"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Residential common interest community</header><text>The term <quote>residential common interest community</quote> means any nonprofit mandatory membership organization comprising owners of real estate described in a declaration or created pursuant to a covenant or other applicable law with respect to which a person, by virtue of the person’s ownership of a unit, is obligated to pay for a share of real estate taxes, insurance premiums, maintenance, or improvement of, or services or other expenses related to, common elements, other units, or any other real estate other than that unit described in the declaration.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H87DB6745E83D4557BB26413BCD97CB7B"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Condominium</header><text>The term <quote>condominium</quote> means a multi-unit housing project in which each dwelling unit is separately owned, and the remaining portions of the real estate are designated for common ownership solely by the owners of those units, each owner having an undivided interest in the common elements, and which is represented by a condominium association consisting exclusively of all the unit owners in the project, which is, or will be responsible for the operation, administration, and management of the project.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7DC6523B1CC84F98A2D1EA1CAC6D4D48"><enum>(15)</enum><header>Housing cooperative</header><text>The term <quote>housing cooperative</quote> means a multi-unit housing entity in which each dwelling unit is subject to separate use and possession by 1 or more cooperative members whose interest in such unit, and in any undivided assets of the cooperative association that are appurtenant to such unit, is evidenced by a membership or share interest in a cooperative association and a lease or other document of title or possession granted by such cooperative as the owner of all cooperative property.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H21CE9E55E6DF416C82513918DFAD229B"><enum>(16)</enum><header>Manufactured housing community</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>manufactured housing community</quote> means a residential development or neighborhood specifically designed for the placement of manufactured homes, as that term is defined in 24 C.F.R. 3280.02, modular homes, prefabricated homes, or any combination of each.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H447764A2C509471B8C45801DE24DD337"><enum>3.</enum><header>Removal of debris resulting from a major disaster in residential common interest communities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 407 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5173">42 U.S.C. 5173</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H22B96C3904D2449097265FA8B17FDFA5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating subsections (d) and (e) as subsections (e) and (f); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H91A9F68306F9471CA46C0222AF7F8E12"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (c) the following:</text><quoted-block id="H3AD415DA9F724815A647B726EB6A543F" style="OLC"><subsection id="H6DC2F96369D1451DB1E87F2076024AE6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rules relating to residential common interest communities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall issue rules which provide that removal of debris or wreckage from real estate owned by a residential common interest community, condominium entity, manufactured housing community, or housing cooperative resulting from a major disaster is in the public interest when a State or local government determines in writing such debris or wreckage constitutes a threat to life, to public health or safety, or to the economic recovery of the residential common interest community.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="H21D4B05DA5764E37A765E24938CB6ACF"><enum>4.</enum><header>Condominiums, manufactured housing communities, and housing cooperatives damaged by a major disaster</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 408(c)(2)(A) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5174">42 U.S.C. 5174(c)(2)(A)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HC38F47763D4446A199146853CDC147F5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in clause (i) by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5D23AF0C4F9F456F9E1B7445D40EDEC3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating clause (ii) as clause (iii); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1F998F8FAF894741BAD4B729A4019525"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding after clause (i) the following:</text><quoted-block id="H6C9A4CA8CA8749168FD2C5142A5578C2" style="OLC"><clause id="H9E52A0DE66B345D38A10F329E00D4C37"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the repair of essential common elements of a condominium, manufactured housing community, or housing cooperative (such as a roof, exterior wall, heating and cooling equipment, elevator, stairwell, utility access, plumbing, and electricity) provided an individual’s or household’s pro rata share of essential common element repair costs are satisfactorily documented; and</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="HE1100833FA704C0C865B4885D4883829"><enum>5.</enum><header>Applicability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The amendments made by this Act shall apply to a major disaster or emergency declared by the President under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5121">42 U.S.C. 5121 et seq.</external-xref>) on or after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

