<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1FF3490BAABC4D439428F5C0CF500E47" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 472 IH: Condemning the antisemitic terrorist attack in Boulder, Colorado.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 472</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250604">June 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000484">Mr. Fine</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000048">Mr. Pfluger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000478">Ms. Tenney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001120">Mr. Crenshaw</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000575">Mr. Rogers of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001136">Mrs. McClain</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000589">Mr. Gooden</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000086">Mr. Owens</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001129">Mr. Collins</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000490">Mr. Taylor</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001321">Mr. Barrett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000596">Mrs. Luna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001216">Mr. Mills</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001291">Mr. Babin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001222">Mr. Miller of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000601">Mr. Goldman of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000392">Mr. Kustoff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000522">Mr. Smith of New Jersey</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001302">Mr. Biggs of Arizona</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Condemning the antisemitic terrorist attack in Boulder, Colorado.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, on Sunday, June 1, 2025, 12 innocent American citizens were the subject of a coordinated terrorist attack meant to take the lives of Jewish Americans;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas those attacked ranged between the ages of 52 and 88, with one of the victims of the attack being a survivor of the Holocaust;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the perpetrator of the attack, Mohamed Sabry Soliman, used Molotov cocktails and a makeshift flamethrower in an attempt to murder individuals specifically because of their Jewish heritage;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Mohamed Soliman was reported to have yelled, <quote>Free Palestine,</quote> as he initiated his attack against a crowd of innocent Americans peacefully bringing awareness to the hostages that remain captive in Gaza;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas this heinous terrorist attack comes amidst an alarming rise in antisemitic violence sweeping the United States;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, in the last 2 months alone, radical pro-Palestine activists have killed an engaged couple working at the Israeli Embassy and set fire to Governor Josh Shapiro’s home; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Mohamed Soliman had illegally overstayed his initial visa, and should have never been permitted to remain in the country as long as he was: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HE72637D48A5E4552A3E1B92A4C90F955"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H76B9B59D7B0049359EAAFD470D43BE09"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text> 
<paragraph id="HD80839E1094C42C4A01811B7F533D923"><enum>(1)</enum><text>unequivocally condemns the antisemitic terrorist attack that took place against innocent Americans in Boulder, Colorado;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5C5E4F90B61A41679F3E2974AB9563C3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>condemns antisemitism in all its forms, and expresses grave concern about the rise in antisemitic behavior and actions reported across college campuses, online, and in other public spaces;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE85D4781698F427DB6689BA200B4B419"><enum>(3)</enum><text>prays for the swift and full recovery of all those injured in the attack, and expresses thanks to the police and emergency responders for their immediate action;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H88BF1A0EB70C4EA48758810870E15B12"><enum>(4)</enum><text>calls for the perpetrator of the terrorist attack to be prosecuted under the full extent of the law; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2DFC472C14074DA98A2993AADABBDC1F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>urges Congress to take immediate action to secure the border and deport migrants who overstay their visas.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

