<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD02F839CA0E24AFA813CB3F4F6D8191D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2131 IH: Presidential Security Resources Reimbursement Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2131</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250314">March 14, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000398">Mr. Kean</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="F000462">Ms. Lois Frankel of Florida</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 18, United States Code, to authorize Secret Service to reimburse State and local governments for the use of services, personnel, equipment, and facilities.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE8C37A9E813F4A89A75D96BF498F38D4" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HEEBC56039EB7466AA6055CD091039E59" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Presidential Security Resources Reimbursement Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H6820FA93582047B9BC16E0CB642103A8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Authorization for reimbursement of State and local governments for the use of services, personnel, equipment, and facilities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 3056 of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following: </text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="HAD86B46A96AB4C16BE51097672C2B99C" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="HB2919CBEDCDB442E8C82B9C26D681979"><enum>(h)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the functions pursuant to paragraphs (3) and (7) of subsection (a), the Secretary of Homeland Security may utilize, with their consent, on a reimbursable basis, the services, personnel, equipment, and facilities of State and local governments, and is authorized to reimburse such State and local governments for the utilization of such services, personnel, equipment, and facilities. </text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section id="H499D575D297A4E608FFC9CA4C6A57636"><enum>3.</enum><header>Retroactive application</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For purposes of the application of section 3056(h) of title 18, United States Code, the Secretary of Homeland Security may in addition provide reimbursement for any utilization, for purposes of carrying out the functions pursuant to paragraphs (3) and (7) of section 3056(a) of such title, of the services, personnel, equipment, and facilities of State and local governments that occurred during the period beginning July 12, 2024, and ending on the effective date of this section.</text></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

