<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H057DFC1DEE3C4DC9997FF294E95E690E" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 135 IH: Affirming the nature and importance of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization and Article 5 commitments under the North Atlantic Treaty.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 135</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250213">February 13, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H000874">Mr. Hoyer</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Affirming the nature and importance of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization and Article 5 commitments under the North Atlantic Treaty.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the United States and our democratic allies and partners face unprecedented international challenges and evolving threats to global security;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) was founded on April 4, 1949, to counter Soviet expansion, prevent further world wars from emerging in Europe, and develop a commitment to transatlantic security, and is built on the democratic principles of freedom, security, and national sovereignty;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Article 5 of the North Atlantic Treaty underpins the principle of “collective defense” and has served as a guiding value and commitment of United States foreign policy for over 75 years;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas United States Article 5 commitments regarding collective defense augment United States deterrence capabilities against adversaries such as Russia, China, and Iran that seek to spread their malign influence;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the unifying nature of Article 5 commitments between allies create a stronger defense against threats to our collective defense and stability of democratic states;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas transatlantic cooperation through NATO serves as a bulwark against the proliferation of malign influence, technologies, and destabilizing operations from adversaries;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas authoritarian regimes such as Russia, China, Iran, and North Korea have increased collaboration in political, economic, and security sectors, sought to undermine democratic principles, and sow distrust in democratic institutions;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas in the only invocation of Article 5 of the North Atlantic Treaty, NATO allies provided troops, intelligence, resources, and support to United States forces following the September 11, 2001, attacks, and NATO allies incurred significant casualties under NATO-led operations in Afghanistan;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas NATO has been steadfast in its support for Ukraine in light of Russia’s full-scale invasion, with member countries providing ammunition, weapons, and significant non-security assistance increasing Ukraine’s ability to defend itself and imposing direct costs on Russia for its illegal invasion of Ukraine;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, following Vladimir Putin’s illegal invasion of Ukraine, Finland and Sweden made the sovereign decision to accede to the NATO alliance;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas NATO remains committed to addressing the systemic challenges posed by China to Euro-Atlantic interests and security; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas NATO member states have continued to strengthen and evolve capabilities in the realm of advanced defense and cyber technologies, including through the Defense Innovation Accelerator for the North Atlantic (DIANA) program with the inclusion and cooperation of leading researchers, and innovators: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H38065E4579474044A410215EE1340C03"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H6053D69E96534F75A0B384873815F058"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="HBDB862DF729445DDAF933B2542C0FB60"><enum>(1)</enum><text>reaffirms full and unwavering commitment to the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO); </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H19A389491F4648DEA007D84184CAFC60"><enum>(2)</enum><text>reiterates the importance of NATO and the vital commitment of the United States to the alliance and to defending United States allies under Article 5 of the North Atlantic Treaty;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE1F93212A9DE473C87A0D0CEF607CCC2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>reaffirms NATO’s open door policy and commitment to Article 10 of the North Atlantic Treaty, and reaffirms that every state has the right to choose its own security arrangements, including Ukraine;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF589A8AB9BE14D8EBFAE80D1D65272B3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>remembers the thousands of NATO coalition soldiers who sacrificed their lives in support of the United States following the invocation of Article 5 after the September 11, 2001, terrorist attacks against the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1EDE7CE24EE9422D83856F6557297806"><enum>(5)</enum><text>underscores the importance of all NATO allies dedicating at least 2 percent of their gross domestic product to their national defense or establish plans by the Washington Summit to meet their 2 percent obligations; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6FE09B7CC3914458B6A38221132CBBA7"><enum>(6)</enum><text>highlights the importance of coordination and collaboration in advanced defense technologies, counter-intelligence, and cybersecurity programs among NATO allies given the evolving threats posed by adversaries such as Russia, China, and Iran.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

