<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF3294ACED7A945FD9D7A5C2B102CEDB3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5161 IH: To establish in the Executive Office of the President an Office of Young Americans, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5161</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250904">September 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001200">Mr. Soto</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001220">Mr. McGarvey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001326">Ms. Bynum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000380">Mr. Amo</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000620">Ms. Pettersen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish in the Executive Office of the President an Office of Young Americans, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB9AB5E0F99494B5A805F10B7A74B92EF" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H62472D62B3E0464FA45D00C247A3AEAB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Office of Young Americans</header> 
<subsection id="HC4A0CD7A2EDF49DA9C463B08F5E8DB40"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established in the Executive Office of the President an Office of Young Americans (referred to in this section as the <quote>Office</quote>), which shall be headed by a Director (referred to in this section as the <quote>Director</quote>).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H886E58242BD34A70BF1A3A154110A99E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Office leadership</header> <paragraph id="H44F716334A684A6E8503BFDCA803E9FE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appointments</header> <subparagraph id="H8BD5B51AA8B74A7F843865BCD452804A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President shall appoint the Director and may appoint an Associate Director of the Office.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE7FA81FD0E0B47A298743886E1718D11"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Single Associate Director</header><text>The President may not appoint an Associate Director to serve in the Office concurrently with another Associate Director.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H01157D8AC54D4DFDBEC0438BB52B2550"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Functions of Director</header> <subparagraph id="H55D89BC95F0E40F8A8C36C5B9D7F0782"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The Director shall—</text> 
<clause id="HC4D8A9068A0F496DAEB61A32C70AC67E"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify issues that primarily and substantially affect young Americans, including employment issues, education, mental health, housing, and climate change;</text></clause> <clause id="H210D8B0010B043B48372279C16213A71"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>advise the President on—</text> 
<subclause id="H345B3963F4334487A674AE0CCCD435E3"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the engagement and involvement of young Americans in the Federal Government; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HCE9D2ED4C63C4E01963C18C24C713AF5"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the issues that primarily and substantially affect young Americans;</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H40F3A20C8FFC4CE5ABAF20EBA049923C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>support strategic coordination and communication between the Executive Office of the President and Federal agencies with respect to activities pertaining to issues primarily and substantially affecting young Americans;</text></clause> <clause id="H4E8912E02FF94FB68940934D534E10A6"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">serve as the principal advisor to the President on all issues primarily and substantially affecting young Americans;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H5EC5A15F99ED4C40A8C21718260B6D21"><enum>(v)</enum><text>make recommendations to the President regarding youth engagement in the Federal Government;</text></clause> <clause id="HD95E4B30581F455592B61D02FB86F9FD"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>coordinate Federal activities to prepare for, and respond to, issues affecting young Americans and engagement in the Federal Government, by—</text> 
<subclause id="H815FD067EB1C41E2BF64A170DB304A85"><enum>(I)</enum><text>providing strategic direction to the heads of applicable Federal departments, agencies, and offices;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H9E067305A8974447A0D7AA00C668EA78"><enum>(II)</enum><text>facilitating coordination and communication between such Federal departments, agencies, and offices to improve youth engagement and involvement across all Federal departments; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H3AEEF58614B347ADB75A9533C78DA38E"><enum>(III)</enum><text>ensuring that the authorities, capabilities, and expertise of each such department, agency, and office are appropriately leveraged to facilitate the whole-of-government response to issues related to young Americans;</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H14C6C8277E6A41F5AC0C98335CB64A7E"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>identify opportunities to leverage current and emerging technologies, including through public-private partnerships, as appropriate, to address the future of the Nation’s workforce through the development of skilled young Americans in these fields and advance the preparedness and response goals of the Federal Government;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H9AF29FD1B4D647F58870FC9179B8A384"><enum>(viii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">work with relevant Federal officials to request funding through the President’s Budgets and leverage programs of Federal Agencies to address the issues identified in the reports submitted under subparagraph (e); and</text></clause> <clause id="H27C187FF94DD4430940CB3374CB3D2C8"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>perform such other functions and activities as prescribed by the President.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9922B47AA46A4AC2AB5B7E9C454CBD0B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Associate Director</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Associate Director of the Office shall perform such functions as the Director may prescribe.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF937F3A6EEBA432B8C6FF5418722F80C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Compensation</header> <subparagraph id="H375FCBDFE1424DCF82AC40BAAEC1B7AA"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Director</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The annual rate of basic pay for the Director shall be the rate payable for level II of the Executive Schedule under section 5313 of title 5, United States Code.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4FEC899A7A664D59A770756EC724CE29"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Associate Director</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The annual rate of basic pay for the Associate Director shall be the rate determined by the Director not exceeding the rate payable for level III of the Executive Schedule under section 5314 of title 5, United States Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H1E76A39159D34732AC29AA2F52323A7C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Additional functions of the Director</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director, in addition to the other duties and functions set forth in this section—</text> 
<paragraph id="H9EA76FBA46FC4A9F8E70D70F299946B0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H93FDC972DB834F88BF9BF96BC13C64B1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">serve as a member of the Domestic Policy Council; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H595E9C4311A645658A21F4137EA88170"><enum>(B)</enum><text>seek to consult with State, Tribal, local, and territorial governments, industry, academia, professional societies, and other individuals and entities, as the Director deems appropriate, to identify issues that primarily and substantially affect young Americans; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5F128C8EC95F42239E60A8552414388D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB24A44E51A0E4698B9337B18C5ADDFC3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>use for the administration of the Office, on a reimbursable basis, the available services, equipment, personnel, and facilities of Federal agencies; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC4C29655446649E08D990584A6D9AC45"><enum>(B)</enum><text>hold such hearings in various parts of the United States as the Director determines necessary to determine the views of the entities and individuals described in paragraph (1)(B) and of the general public concerning national needs and trends in—</text> 
<clause id="H36DE09F6F554448CB22DA46D273C129D"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the engagement and involvement of young Americans in the Federal Government; and</text></clause> <clause id="H8C07D436D1224C1CA74A0E729295BA83"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>issues that primarily and substantially affect young Americans.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HCF6BD57D6D244B3C909853FB91653D92"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Staffing and detailees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out functions under this section, the Director may—</text> <paragraph id="HB2386BA00A6A406CB827DE15BBC1DA57"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">appoint individuals to not more than two full time equivalent positions in the Office;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBE52EB0BC4554C1391DAE527A8DF8958"><enum>(2)</enum><text>fix the compensation of individuals appointed to such positions at a rate to be determined by the Director, up to the amount of annual compensation (excluding expenses) specified in section 102 of title 3, United States Code; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA8956F759CF14393AD59B6FD98DA352C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>use the services of consultants, which may include by obtaining services described under section 3109(b) of title 5, United States Code, at rates not to exceed the rate of basic pay payable for level IV of the Executive Schedule under section 5315 of such title.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HEF5DF145C2DB46B2AC341DF87768092B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Preparedness outlook reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and not less frequently than once every five years thereafter, the Director, in consultation with the heads of relevant Federal agencies and other officials within the Executive Office of the President, shall submit to the President, the Committees on Finance and on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate, and the Committees on Financial Services and on Education and the Workforce of the House of Representatives, and make publicly available, a report—</text> <paragraph id="H9B6D2A96206548D09D55AD8861A5B0F0"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identifying and describing issues that warrant special attention from the President or the heads of such Federal agencies within the next 5 years regarding issues that primarily and substantially affect young Americans, including the effects of the policies, actions, and personnel of Federal agencies on the engagement and involvement of young Americans in the Federal Government; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H67562AB1C6CB46A38F040D18B10FB825"><enum>(2)</enum><text>providing recommendations and resource requirement for addressing the issues identified under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HCE750C1ADB7D4A19B88ADF8442B22310"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H6C6B3467E2E6482B88A33C605F1B4BFE" commented="no">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Federal agency</header>
 <text>The term <term>Federal agency</term> has the meaning given <quote>Executive agency</quote> in section 105 of title 5, United States Code.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0B174390181F4B8DBE87A345A0CC135E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Young American</header><text>The term <term>young American</term> means an individual who is a citizen or lawful permanent resident of the United States between the ages of 18 and 40 years old.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

