<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HBABF22B957CF44E98B7E3DF42D644C93" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 665 IH: End Congressional Stock Trading Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 665</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250829">August 29, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000596">Mrs. Luna</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Committee on Rules</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 1908) to prohibit stock trading and ownership by Members of Congress and their spouses and dependent children, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H9AE7E0EC825F4F8DBAFC07B816EE558C">
    <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"
      id="H5DF7AA8A866447488C53605261E20CE7">
 <text>That immediately upon adoption of this resolution, the House shall proceed to the consideration in the House of the bill (H.R. 1908) to prohibit stock trading and ownership by Members of Congress and their spouses and dependent children, and for other purposes. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived. The amendment specified in section 3 of this resolution shall be considered as adopted. The bill, as amended, shall be considered as read. All points of order against provisions in the bill, as amended, are waived. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the bill, as amended, and on any further amendment thereto, to final passage without intervening motion except: (1) one hour of debate equally divided and controlled by the chair and ranking minority member of the Committee on Financial Services; and (2) one motion to recommit.</text>
    </section>
    <section id="H2C0C00B665414BFD8882E058498DF379" display-inline="no-display-inline">
      <enum>2.</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Clause 1(c) of rule XIX shall not apply to the consideration of H.R. 1908.</text>
    </section>
    <section id="H0C9015B82D9145768F41B3B0E4FD44E2" section-type="subsequent-section"
      display-inline="no-display-inline">
      <enum>3.</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendment specified in this section is as follows.</text>
    </section>
    <section id="H2562B3226BC0464DBC858E9DCE3F556D" section-type="undesignated-section">
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Strike section 1 and all that follows and insert the following:</text>
      <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H731C0530B63D45448BCC191D23ABF405"
        display-inline="no-display-inline">
        <section id="HB397903FCCE8424EAD7A1E4A8DE46A16" section-type="section-one" commented="no">
          <enum>1.</enum>
          <header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>End Congressional Stock Trading Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section section-type="subsequent-section" id="H31721B28AB1F4F5D8E149BBEE069F275">
          <enum>2.</enum>
          <header>Bar on stock trading and ownership by Members of Congress and their spouses and
            dependent children</header>
          <subsection id="HAF25EC33275E438F9666E5474DBA1145">
            <enum>(a)</enum>
            <header>Definitions</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HD16F17CD961D40F3A14FB19033EF123F"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>Commodity</header> <text>The term <term>commodity</term> has the meaning given that term in section 1a of the Commodity Exchange Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1a">7 U.S.C. 1a</external-xref>).</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HEE05B8A5002241598C32F08568265545">
              <enum>(2)</enum>
              <header>Dependent child</header>
 <text>The term <term>dependent child</term> has the meaning given that term in section 13101 of title 5, United States Code.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H0FAE2AE1A9F74BA5969F4A11768704E1">
              <enum>(3)</enum>
              <header>Diversified</header>
 <text>The term <term>diversified</term>, with respect to an investment fund, means that the investment fund does not have a stated policy of overly concentrating its investments.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H1AAA1780C8C7464D85E48770D9FBA64C">
              <enum>(4)</enum>
              <header>Member of Congress</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Member of Congress</term> has the meaning given that term in section 13101 of title 5, United States Code.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H996B161815A74496AA4ACB96C08A215E">
              <enum>(5)</enum>
              <header>Qualified blind trust</header>
 <text>The term <term>qualified blind trust</term> has the meaning given that term in section 13104(f)(3) of title 5, United States Code.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H975F9BFC54D9446BBE8D460C6E5EBAD4">
              <enum>(6)</enum>
              <header>Security</header>
 <text>The term <term>security</term> has the meaning given that term in section 3(a) of Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78c">15 U.S.C. 78c(a)</external-xref>).</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HC2C0B937342F475B88C55F4B6E1EF7CE">
              <enum>(7)</enum>
              <header>Small business concern</header>
 <text>The term <term>small business concern</term> has the meaning given that term under section 3 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/632">15 U.S.C. 632</external-xref>).</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HA9FF3F08374042238ADA8B3E52062333">
              <enum>(8)</enum>
              <header>Widely held investment fund</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>widely held investment fund</term> means a widely held investment fund described in 13104(f)(8) of title 5, United States Code.</text>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection id="HACEABEA910F2423EA13067793EE35541">
            <enum>(b)</enum>
            <header>Divestment</header>
            <paragraph id="H2B0A33651BCA4DA5BC77CE3172D0077C" commented="no">
              <enum>(1)</enum>
              <header>In general</header>
 <text>A Member of Congress or a spouse or dependent child of a Member of Congress may not own an interest in or trade (except as a divestment) any stock, bond, commodity, future, or other form of security, including an interest in a hedge fund, a derivative, option, or other complex investment vehicle.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H0BA3E30E9F8D4ACEB68117C38DDDBAD0">
              <enum>(2)</enum>
              <header>Implementation</header>
              <subparagraph id="H53762EE50EF84476AF3F6139918B60A7">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
                <header>Current Members</header>
                <clause id="HDF6FF481BA4644EC8B1E9A3D4B81D3A4">
                  <enum>(i)</enum>
                  <header>In general</header>
 <text>Except as provided in clause (ii), an individual who is a Member of Congress or a spouse or dependent child of a Member of Congress on the date of enactment of this Act shall complete the divestment of any asset described in paragraph (1) by not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
                </clause>
                <clause id="H227D329962304F73908F3B325F7004EB">
                  <enum>(ii)</enum>
                  <header>Certain assets</header>
 <text>For an asset described in paragraph (1) that is an interest in a hedge fund, venture capital fund, or other privately held complex investment vehicle, an individual who is a Member of Congress or a spouse or dependent child of a Member of Congress on the date of enactment of this Act shall complete the divestment of the asset by not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
                </clause>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H7D519A611CF249F885007A9C70472F95">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
                <header>New Members</header>
                <clause id="H8AD7A859AAB54BADB8C9536F73C577E2">
                  <enum>(i)</enum>
                  <header>In general</header>
 <text>Except as provided in clause (ii), an individual who becomes a Member of Congress or a spouse or dependent child of a Member of Congress after the date of enactment of this Act shall complete the divestment of any asset described in paragraph (1) by not later than 180 days after the date on which the individual becomes a Member of Congress or a spouse or dependent child of a Member of Congress.</text>
                </clause>
                <clause id="HDE1BDF00FD0D4AA9BAD62FD54E4910BA">
                  <enum>(ii)</enum>
                  <header>Certain assets</header>
 <text>For an asset described in paragraph (1) that is an interest in a hedge fund, venture capital fund, or other privately held complex investment vehicle, an individual who becomes a Member of Congress or a spouse or dependent child of a Member of Congress after the date of enactment of this Act shall complete the divestment of the asset by not later than 2 years after the date on which the individual becomes a Member of Congress or a spouse or dependent child of a Member of Congress.</text>
                </clause>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H2DB3C893579540F39AEF835CE5D596E2">
                <enum>(C)</enum>
                <header>Divestment of assets received while a Member</header>
 <text>An individual serving as a Member of Congress or a spouse or dependent child of an individual serving as a Member of Congress who receives any asset described in paragraph (1) during the period of such service, such as from an inheritance, shall complete the divestment of the asset by not later than 180 days after the date on which the individual receives the asset.</text>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection id="H40241D97E0E84497AE10CD455071155B">
            <enum>(c)</enum>
            <header>Exceptions</header>
 <text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to prevent—</text> <paragraph id="H2C10D7175B9D4391AF47E43AB06F5DF9"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>a Member of Congress or a spouse or dependent child of a Member of Congress from owning or trading—</text>
              <subparagraph id="H07DFBAF57AF94CED951373B3F933CE7F">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>a widely held investment fund, if the widely held investment fund—</text> <clause id="HF0A8803E5579495CAB0EFB0B4D4960D6"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>does not present a conflict of interest; and</text>
                </clause>
                <clause id="H88EA59C8AF3C4084B32561E178A8EE50" commented="no"
                  display-inline="no-display-inline">
                  <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>is diversified;</text> </clause> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCE1096B9E797455BBA8EE124301DABB5"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>shares of Settlement Common Stock issued under section 7(g)(1)(A) of the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1606">43 U.S.C. 1606(g)(1)(A)</external-xref>);</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H4E81DFD04553412989748160AEF7D336">
                <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>shares of Settlement Common Stock, as defined in section 3 of the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1602">43 U.S.C. 1602</external-xref>);</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="HED1B42C85F0345F2B76E0A9296FC7FD5">
                <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>a United States Treasury bill, note, or bond;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H81E4EA61C44E4A4983E32B2CB4C8770E"> <enum>(E)</enum> <text>an investment fund held in a Federal, State, or local government employee retirement plan;</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="HF939A08AC15E4C74986BFB469FBB2757">
                <enum>(F)</enum>
 <text>an interest in a small business concern, if the small business concern does not present a conflict of interest; or</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H9203369F12594E3BA77105ACE6284981">
                <enum>(G)</enum>
 <text>any asset described in subsection (b)(1) received as compensation from the primary occupation of the spouse;</text>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HE985D6418C4C49B2855BC49AD6E0CD4B">
              <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>a spouse or dependent child of a Member of Congress from trading any asset described in subsection (b)(1) that is not owned by the spouse or Member of Congress in the course of performing the primary occupation of the spouse; or</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H69FBBA7E5EEA4C378142ED75C6FB5004">
              <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a Member of Congress or a spouse or dependent child of a Member of Congress from holding any stock, bond, commodity, future, or other form of security in a qualified blind trust operated on behalf of, or for the benefit of, the Member or the spouse or dependent child of the Member.</text>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection id="H1D4D18B8800544CEBB0F0889B2A07864">
            <enum>(d)</enum>
            <header>Civil fines</header>
            <paragraph id="H74A69E2062094E47810494E3F92E9619">
              <enum>(1)</enum>
              <header>In general</header>
 <text>The Attorney General or the Special Counsel may bring a civil action in the appropriate United States district court against any Member of Congress or spouse or dependent child of a Member of Congress who engages in conduct constituting a violation of this section and, upon proof of such conduct by a preponderance of the evidence, such Member of Congress or spouse or dependent child of such Member of Congress shall be subject to a civil penalty of not more than $100,000 for each violation or 10 percent of the most recent combined value of each stock, bond, commodity, future, or other form of security involved (whichever is greater). The imposition of a civil penalty under this subsection does not preclude any other criminal or civil statutory, common law, or administrative remedy, which is available by law to the United States or any other person.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H2594FD87B074412EA563EEFF8E61B674">
              <enum>(2)</enum>
              <header>Prohibiting use of office funds</header>
 <text>A Member of Congress may not use funds made available from the Members’ Representational Allowance (in the case of a Representative in, or Delegate or Resident Commissioner to, the Congress) or the Senators’ Official Personnel and Office Expense Account (in the case of a Senator) to pay a penalty imposed under paragraph (1).</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H75FED5B4DCDA40D49497A2E50264CFB9">
              <enum>(3)</enum>
              <header>Prohibiting use of campaign funds</header>
 <text>Section 313(b) of the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/30114">52 U.S.C. 30114(b)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
              <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HC984816D74CA4D508F4D8ED9458A0DEC"
                display-inline="no-display-inline">
                <paragraph id="H05EC3385BC6547E08CEA7A14167F7A15">
                  <enum>(3)</enum>
                  <header>Prohibiting use to pay certain penalties</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A contribution or a donation described in subsection (a) may not be used to pay a penalty imposed under section 2(d)(1) of the End Congressional Stock Trading Act.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
              </quoted-block>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection id="H4B41D8F6DFA5454681FF9175896C4F5F">
            <enum>(e)</enum>
            <header>Nonrecognition of gain</header>
            <paragraph id="H46C3BA429E6C4503824A9E0272DB6F5C">
              <enum>(1)</enum>
              <header>In general</header>
 <text>Paragraph (1) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/1043">section 1043(b)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended—</text>
              <subparagraph id="H32AA6E6B8E764CEA8369E1B52C7FDF75">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of subparagraph (A);</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4FB04FF966E44D04A2FA33F61FF4CDC7"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>by redesignating subparagraph (B) as subparagraph (C);</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H4A86B1575DAD438D895099835B2B3AA3">
                <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>by inserting after subparagraph (A) the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H62DCD6CEAC9E4F2C97A8A084E60DF033"> <subparagraph id="HB23F7A43ABF643C59BBB9815B395D6B0"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>any Member of Congress or any spouse or dependent child of a Member of Congress, but only with respect to a divestment of property required by the End Congressional Stock Trading Act and only if, not later than 60 days after the divestment of such property, the individual uses the proceeds of the divestment to obtain property which the individual is authorized to own or trade under section 2(c)(1) of such Act, and</text>
                  </subparagraph>
                  <after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block>
                </quoted-block>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="HC1FF182373324366AA45E2FCDFC3BB1E">
                <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>by striking <quote>subparagraph (A)</quote> in subparagraph (C), as so redesignated, and inserting <quote>subparagraph (A) or (B), whichever is applicable</quote>.</text>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H6E2F089A226D476B8FC35583D95ACE7F">
              <enum>(2)</enum>
              <header>Certificate of divestiture</header>
 <text>Subparagraph (B) of section 1043(b)(2) of such Code is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="HEAD8CDC21F8E442B997433EAA785C934"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>by striking <quote>or by</quote> and inserting <quote>by</quote>; and</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H5EEF86F5F49E4661B00C8FC1BD003CCC">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>by inserting <quote>, or by the applicable congressional ethics committee, as defined in section 13101 of title 5, United States Code, in the case of Members of Congress and spouses and dependent children of Members of Congress,</quote> after <quote>judicial officers</quote>.</text>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H59B9DA8214684F37AA1BC44566971B78">
              <enum>(3)</enum>
              <header>No effect on subsequent sale of property</header>
 <text>Nothing in the amendments made by this subsection shall be construed to provide for the nonrecognition of gain with respect to the sale of property obtained by a Member of Congress or any spouse or dependent child of a Member of Congress with the proceeds of a divestment required by this Act, as described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/1043">section 1043(b)(1)(B)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (as added by this subsection).</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HBB5E62D38B1B4F2286A5622EC1320C6D">
              <enum>(4)</enum>
              <header>Effective date</header>
 <text>The amendments made by this subsection shall apply to sales of property after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection id="H4E17A8C90EE3455D905E9CF6EB76959C">
            <enum>(f)</enum>
            <header>Interpretive guidance</header>
 <text>The Select Committee on Ethics of the Senate and the Committee on Ethics of the House of Representatives shall issue interpretive guidance regarding relevant terms not defined in this Act or elsewhere in statute.</text>
          </subsection>
        </section>
        <section id="H66419DDB365747E8A131FFF7F711D40A">
          <enum>3.</enum>
          <header>Annual certification of compliance</header>
          <subsection id="H031CC73B06E84B73BCF356779EEEA25D">
            <enum>(a)</enum>
            <header>Certification</header>
            <paragraph id="H5668065A766045E8AF1CA7357286A5DF">
              <enum>(1)</enum>
              <header>In general</header>
 <text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), not later than 60 days after the beginning of any session of Congress, each Member of Congress shall submit to the applicable official a written certification that the Member and the Member’s spouse are in compliance with the requirements of this Act.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HBBC5CBDF513A481390EBC821BAC0D5CB">
              <enum>(2)</enum>
              <header>Special rule for first session after enactment</header>
 <text>In the case of the first session of Congress which begins after the date of the enactment of this Act, paragraph (1) shall apply as if the reference to <quote>60 days</quote> was a reference to <quote>180 days</quote>.</text>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection id="H4B27166C8B9D48BEB752F0667A9C827F">
            <enum>(b)</enum>
            <header>Publication</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The applicable official shall publish the certifications submitted to the applicable official under paragraph (1) on a publicly available website.</text>
          </subsection>
          <subsection id="H689A4DE11071482C906D0F4D04A9A12B">
            <enum>(c)</enum>
            <header>Use of certifications for audits by Internal Revenue Service</header>
 <text>Upon receiving a certification under subsection (a), the applicable official shall transmit the certification to the Secretary of the Treasury, who shall carry out such actions, including audits and investigations, as the Secretary determines appropriate to ensure the accuracy of the certification.</text>
          </subsection>
          <subsection id="HB1B25DCF881548DDB20B9B36066ABA38">
            <enum>(d)</enum>
            <header>Applicable official defined</header>
 <text>In this section, the term <term>applicable official</term> means—</text> <paragraph id="HF3A55036E66F4935AC9F0EC5D7A19A25"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Clerk of the House of Representatives (in the case of a Representative in, or Delegate or Resident Commissioner to, the Congress or the spouse of a Representative in, or Delegate or Resident Commissioner to, the Congress); or</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H3BA2C4463EA74E5F8F4DFF8DC8E7EA49">
              <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>the Secretary of the Senate (in the case of a Senator and the spouse of a Senator).</text>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
        </section>
        <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
      </quoted-block>
    </section>
  </resolution-body></resolution>

