<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-KEL25690-YY5-W2-N73"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2810 IS: Retirement Freedom Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2810</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250916">September 16, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S355">Mr. Cruz</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S346">Mr. Lee</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To allow individuals to choose to opt out of the Medicare part A benefit.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HFAE21F5E60074FEF9EE1941E249DB2C1"><section section-type="section-one" id="idDA9D59667F19433CB245F8F1673F3977"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Retirement Freedom Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HAC06076000D14D6F9DA3CD1EDA51B723"><enum>2.</enum><header>Allowing individuals to choose to opt out of the Medicare part A benefit</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Any individual who is otherwise entitled to benefits under part A of title XVIII of the Social Security Act may elect (in such form and manner as may be specified by the Secretary of Health and Human Services) to opt out of such entitlement. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, in the case of an individual who makes such an election, such individual—</text><paragraph id="HC4DF31F2459E4CC6853721F5DFF640B8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>may (in such form and manner as may be specified by the Secretary) subsequently choose to end such election and opt back into such entitlement (in accordance with a process determined by the Secretary) without being subject to any penalty;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H659D8D6B385A45C7AE1867831498FAC2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall not be required to opt out of benefits under title II of such Act as a condition for making such election; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEE7CCE54F33147798B5C8459F2DABD5A"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall not be required to repay any amount paid under such part A for items and services furnished prior to making such election.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

