<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-OLL25329-27C-0H-X24"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1154 IS: Congressional Whistleblower Protection Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1154</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250326">March 26, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S313">Mr. Sanders</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S316">Mr. Whitehouse</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To provide protections for employees of, former employees of, and applicants for employment with Federal agencies, contractors, and grantees whose right to petition or furnish information to Congress is interfered with or denied.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Congressional Whistleblower Protection Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id5501265944D24273995FCC1C2433C735"><enum>2.</enum><header>Protections for covered individuals</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"> Section 7211 of title 5, United States Code, is amended— </text><paragraph id="id0B7598CA712546A8B01D6CC148F542E6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>The right of employees</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id857777129534416FB90F20D27C96E9C8"><subsection id="id3448899237C144BC968B0F710087EF2B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The right of covered individuals</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="idFCD96D93DE0F49C78048E579737E58E5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id633191CE1804483A97CA2429A857D60F"><subsection id="idE94A986AFCE548B0A947356584AD0F35"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Remedies</header><paragraph id="id682D8A817DFD40ED8D46D9EA2C68E3B0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrative remedies</header><subparagraph id="idA454A2D3F8294F148C68675D46B8CB4E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A covered individual with respect to a Federal agency (other than a covered individual described in subparagraph (B), (C), or (D)) who is aggrieved by a violation of subsection (a) may seek corrective action under sections 1214 and 1221 in the same manner as an individual who is aggrieved by a prohibited personnel practice described in section 2302(b)(8).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9ADDC338D7E54B3188B942A5E1C6D6A0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>FBI employees</header><text>A covered individual with respect to the Federal Bureau of Investigation who is aggrieved by a violation of subsection (a) may seek corrective action under section 2303.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1728DA3B6F3F470A98152AA115B2E734"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Intelligence community employees</header><text>A covered individual with respect to a covered intelligence community element (as defined in section 1104(a) of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3234">50 U.S.C. 3234(a)</external-xref>)) who is aggrieved by a violation of subsection (a) may seek corrective action under section 1104 of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3234">50 U.S.C. 3234</external-xref>) or subsection (b)(7) or (j) of section 3001 of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3341">50 U.S.C. 3341</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idDA5ED8B2D9CA4ED994C68FF63BD9D965"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Contractor employees</header><text>A covered individual with respect to a Federal agency who is an employee of, former employee of, or applicant for employment with, a contractor, subcontractor, grantee, subgrantee, or personal services contractor (as those terms are used in section 4701 of title 10 and section 4712 of title 41) of the agency and who is aggrieved by a violation of subsection (a) of this section may seek corrective action under section 4701 of title 10 or section 4712 of title 41.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idA9B703892326437D899C88504ADD25D4"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Burden of proof</header><text>The burdens of proof under subsection (e) of section 1221 shall apply to an allegation of a violation of subsection (a) of this section made under subparagraph (A), (B), (C), or (D) of this paragraph in the same manner as those burdens of proof apply to an allegation of a prohibited personnel practice under such section 1221.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id51904131FC224B9A9DA5A5539D54605B"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Class of individuals entitled to seek corrective action</header><text>The right to seek corrective action under subparagraph (A), (B), (C), or (D) shall apply to a covered individual who is an employee of, former employee of, or applicant for employment with, a Federal agency described in the applicable subparagraph or a contractor, subcontractor, grantee, subgrantee, or personal services contractor (as those terms are used in section 4701 of title 10 and section 4712 of title 41) of such a Federal agency, notwithstanding the fact that a provision of law referenced in the applicable subparagraph does not authorize one or more of those types of covered individuals to seek corrective action.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5148D722B9DE4AA3877CF6BFFC7E6C55"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Private right of action</header><subparagraph id="id89084E20809341FE9A2E8904119C048B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If a final decision providing relief for a violation of subsection (a) alleged under subparagraph (A), (B), (C), or (D) of paragraph (1) of this subsection is not issued within 180 days of the date on which the covered individual seeks corrective action under the applicable subparagraph and there is no showing that the delay is due to the bad faith of the covered individual, or if a final decision results in a denial of relief for a violation of subsection (a) alleged by a covered individual under subparagraph (A), (B), (C), or (D) of paragraph (1) of this subsection, the covered individual may bring an action at law or equity for de novo review in the appropriate district court of the United States, which shall have jurisdiction over the action without regard to the amount in controversy, for relief described in subparagraph (B) of this paragraph.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf5475f40fca247068845caafdae3d63a"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Relief</header><text>Relief described in this subparagraph is—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7af4dc934aff4fbd813e2b7265b9e2ab"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the sum of 200 percent of the amount of lost wages and 100 percent of the amount of lost benefits, with interest;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id55ea0198808041ccba074f2077c58e6e"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reinstatement;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4764da9123fd4e0e80f66fc9bd16d645"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">costs and attorney fees;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id50b6abc2205f44cba851c4368c381f27"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">compensatory damages;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd1a42557a2144dc0a23829b560e77dc3"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">equitable or injunctive relief; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id533d46f92b8a42c4b5b96f91de749585"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other relief that the court considers appropriate.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD349C0538F714CCC80F6E769AEF551A9"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Jury trial</header><text>An action brought under subparagraph (A) shall, upon the request of the covered individual, be tried by the court with a jury.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id317b1e18869549b1a25d6c7e7f967104"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Burden of proof</header><text>The burdens of proof under subsection (e) of section 1221 shall apply to an allegation of a violation of subsection (a) of this section in an action brought under this paragraph in the same manner as those burdens of proof apply to an allegation of a prohibited personnel practice under such section 1221.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4A9F7659A16C4A92A3A61BB8AFB2A2B4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text><paragraph id="idC02E298C2D984488BEA9B8B829A50D19"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>covered individual</term>, with respect to a Federal agency, means an employee of, former employee of, or applicant for employment with—</text><subparagraph id="idF8FCAA76D62A47EBAB0BDE1C63909601"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the agency; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id93D3723306744DC1BB6D1B4BE2A6F4DF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a contractor, subcontractor, grantee, subgrantee, or personal services contractor (as those terms are used in section 4701 of title 10 and section 4712 of title 41) of the agency; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idD2DFB99878BB4AB0A165447AB2D68645"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>Federal agency</term> means an agency, office, or other establishment in the executive, legislative, or judicial branch of the Federal Government.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

