<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H798B66DA7CEF46F4A1D6482F21D29060" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3089 IH: More Paid Leave for More Americans Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3089</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250430">April 30, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B000740">Mrs. Bice</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="H001085">Ms. Houlahan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001215">Mrs. Miller-Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001215">Ms. Stevens</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000595">Ms. Letlow</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000446">Mr. Feenstra</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000585">Mr. Gomez</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">House Administration</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Labor to carry out a grant program to award grants to States to carry out a paid family leave program, to establish the Interstate Paid Leave Action Network, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H11CCAE21D6CC43E6AB2ACD2C56F35C28" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H8969C2CF3906481EBD8F4A3077ACF3E6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>More Paid Leave for More Americans Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<title id="H28FEF8595E3C4E219F3C23ED37C8B110"><enum>I</enum><header>State Paid Family Leave Public-Private Partnership</header> 
<section id="H9FA3A15242764C49BD496F837E1F3CFA" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>101.</enum><header>Establishment of the State Paid Family Leave Public-Private Partnership Grant Program</header> 
<subsection id="HE08A78EC7B164F6E8DD15AF3006CA68F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Labor shall establish and administer a competitive grant program to provide grants to States that have enacted a law establishing a paid family leave program as described in subsection (d).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H85904A43B59A4D0DA7976F39834A605C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, a State shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H51E67EA93AC440F9B658FC629FCE8913"><enum>(1)</enum><text>have enacted a State law establishing a paid family leave program as described in subsection (d); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBBF21BF9E0F6414E84E9E4D9C3175045" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>participate in the Interstate Paid Leave Action Network established under section 202(a).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3918652BAAEE4E4BB37912C479F8F692"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header> 
<paragraph id="HCB89E239AF8E48C886E921ACFC5C8B26" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, a State shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require, including how the funds will be used, the working population of the State, the percentage of the State’s working population that is able to access a paid family leave benefit, and the source of such benefit.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H37EBFFFC6583441AA670D3960FFF517B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Priority</header> <subparagraph id="H1B8C48DDB4BD4918BB6C4846B86AB558"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall prioritize States—</text> 
<clause id="H0895B1B0ACD44925B52206098E0E86E9"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that indicate in the application submitted under paragraph (1) that the covered partnership will use software that is a commercially available off-the-shelf item (as defined in part 2.101 of the Federal Acquisition Regulation) to administer benefits;</text></clause> <clause id="HD724F81BC4B14220AC1C7057B2B1F9B6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that have, relative to other States that have submitted an application in a given year, a lower percentage of the working population of the State that have access to a paid family leave benefit at the time of the submission of the application;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HDF3AEE81578249ADB859BEE55B473640"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>that demonstrate in the application that the State has a plan to implement a financing mechanism that does not have long-term reliance on Federal funding; and</text></clause> <clause id="H69D2FFC6A06241AB9C52D131084A4435"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>that demonstrate in the application how the State paid family leave program serves low-income populations.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4D87E08B7A8D4B609465A7AE70C4491B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Consideration prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may not consider whether a State provides benefits in excess of those required under subsection (d) when deciding which States shall receive a grant under this title.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HED3ADC849BB94C06BB57B2CB4D2554FA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Paid family leave program requirements</header> <paragraph id="H08112495B7894E8AA898723091BA3CF8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Program requirements</header><text>A paid family leave program described in this subsection shall, at a minimum—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H6DAEC60A35EB44CEB4F8CA1D8A57EC80"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide, through the covered partnership, a paid family leave benefit to eligible employees because of—</text> <clause id="HC9BA64B7EDAB45089786A36BC33122D1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the birth of a son or daughter of an eligible employee and in order to care for such son or daughter; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H50DDFADE1B0143A8927E31F01C29D505"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the placement of a son or daughter with the eligible employee for adoption;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7902D49D4B1F43CCA90FC2BCEF41A00D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide 6 weeks of paid family leave benefits;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDB778B28CDC64654870E5B379D605B85" commented="no">
                            <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">annually establish a weekly maximum benefit amount that is equal to 150 percent of the State’s average weekly wage (based on the most recent calendar year for which data is available from the Quarterly Census of Employment and Wages program of the BLS);</text>
                        </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5F4AE378D84A41AD89F2995A0A48CD07"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">only permit an eligible employee to be entitled to a leave benefit under clauses (i) and (ii) of subparagraph (A) for a birth or placement of a son or daughter during the 12-month period beginning on the date of such birth or placement;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA8F637572D734319848EBC163699834C"><enum>(E)</enum><text>require the establishment and use of a covered partnership; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H14D07E7FE813418AA45F7BB055F25609" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text>establish premium rates or a financing method to fund the paid family leave program for employees, employers, or both to pay.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H66166EC6A0FA442D99D270840FDD2567"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Paid family leave benefit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purposes of this title, a paid family leave benefit provided to an eligible employee shall, at a minimum, include weekly compensation in an amount (not to exceed the amount described in paragraph (1)(C)) equal to the product of the average weekly earnings of the eligible employee and—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H7B963B9A991840148BA4173F9826E6A4"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of an eligible employee whose earnings for the 4 most recently completed calendar quarters that immediately precede the paid family leave benefit request are less than or equal to the poverty line (as defined in section 673 of the Community Services Block Grant Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9902">42 U.S.C. 9902</external-xref>)) applicable to a 4-person household, 67 percent;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HED3FC48D39A8422BA560CB9DEA477B7B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of an eligible employee whose earnings for such calendar quarters are more than such poverty line, but less than the amount that is double such poverty line, a percentage equal to—</text> 
<clause id="H60AB56FCF636471DA561C27342FD8795"><enum>(i)</enum><text>67 percent, minus</text></clause> <clause id="H5EC2141E4E934E1980F917F252398C28"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the product of—</text> 
<subclause id="H253A944925B64EAA8C941B46D5DAB5B7"><enum>(I)</enum><text>17 percent; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H42D23E4839614740B951C23DB0148DF9"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the percentage by which the employee’s earnings exceed such poverty line; or</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD6799C1B97BE4D92A7C4DFDEA901732C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in the case of any other eligible employee, 50 percent.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC1D3339D04F940DCA7F262B28CB79A25"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Recalculation of benefit amount</header><text>The weekly compensation calculated under paragraph (2) for an eligible employee shall be recalculated each time such employee applies for a paid family leave benefit.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE92850AA0FC74C0EA6993A935CBF60ED"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Employees with multiple employers</header><text>In the case that an employee is employed by multiple employers, such an employee is entitled to receive a benefit from each employer, but the employee may not receive a total combined weekly benefit in excess of the maximum benefit amount established by a State pursuant to paragraph (1)(C).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBFAA86D18F944AE89043B7276C970D8E"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Employer self-administration flexibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case that a State’s paid family leave program includes a requirement for employer participation, States shall be deemed to be in compliance with this section only if they allow employers to self-administer paid family leave benefits to eligible employees, provided such benefits meet or exceed the paid family leave program established by the State that meets the requirements of this subsection.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H20050E1F60124B8CBCAF2E398A99B1EE">
                        <enum>(6)</enum>
                        <header>Rule of construction</header>
 <text>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to limit the ability of a State to provide additional paid family leave benefits (including benefits for reasons described in section 102(a)(1) of the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/2612">29 U.S.C. 2612(a)(1)</external-xref>)) in excess of the benefits required to be provided under this subsection.</text>
                    </paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H81C99AF6B0744626BADEFBFF7702C002"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Use of Funds</header><text>Grants awarded under this section may be used by States for the following purposes:</text> <paragraph id="H65ED9B4DEC12451D86A1A025CEC4D0CA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Start up costs for the implementation of the paid family leave program.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1AABBB05CD034A97B0FAC623C227EF09" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>To pay out benefits to eligible employees, but only for the reasons described in subsection (d)(1)(A).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2A076297794A4EDAAF1A99E3BEF4A106"><enum>(3)</enum><text>To fund the covered partnership.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0F07AB2920014A5BA11C977B3DC9CA18"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Paid family leave program design.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H122C4FC2F4BA4D228C7ED4DB468C9B78"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Purchasing and maintaining any necessary software.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEDA4CB54B0344D1DB496A0C9CC51115C" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Establishing a covered partnership.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H99701A11564347E0A49D09402E43171A"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Obtaining technical assistance for the State or the covered partnership to carry out a paid family leave program.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2475E5045F4E40DD85F3716E39E0E590"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Outreach to employers, payroll providers, relevant professional or trade associations, and the general public to increase awareness of the State’s paid family leave program and to convey relevant information such as program eligibility, funding requirements, benefit information, the application process, and any other information the State deems relevant.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEE508CED94ED4A4E95E5F883A15C2C68"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Other activities to disseminate information about, and otherwise support, the accessibility of the State’s paid family leave program, including the operation and maintenance of a program website, running a call center, and sending marketing materials on the State’s covered partnership to the groups described in paragraph (8).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9E09F59F12B54E38B3E9FA6D8815D1B1"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Research to inform the establishment and operation of the State’s paid family leave program, including program evaluations, and the dissemination of such research to the public.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H85B3343C229B486EB755A387E36044F7"><enum>(11)</enum><text>To evaluate existing programs and models.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H35791F22C7F348DAB90D9B0CB7A23D7F" commented="no"><enum>(12)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To reduce administrative burdens on employers in the State.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H46AC549E9FF9419DB7057EECC42ABABA"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Grant amounts</header> <paragraph id="H0B87CECD6D7745A8B4281E00F00CC9CE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In determining the amount of a grant to be provided to a State, the Secretary shall consider—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H4F5132F0DFE34FCFBE11B8598DF1FF6C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the size of the working population of the State relative to the size of the working population of the other States that are receiving a grant;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H875B8734D30449BCB6A9A093B3A6AE0B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the birth rate of the State relative to the other such States;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6FC3976B38B6478692158903F0436EBF"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the share of low-income individuals in the State; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5A732C57F50D44709A3C9911273D216B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the demonstrated need of a State in the grant application.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H26478A8AE27649F786ADF76F8D80B117"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limits</header><text>A grant provided under this section may not be less than $1,500,000 and not more than $7,000,000.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H6A61C5EC402C4403A8560B70DD0FA4ED"><enum>102.</enum><header>Oversight</header> <subsection id="HE71862ECFF9B4A23803E460E83643400"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after a State receives a grant under this section, and on an annual basis thereafter, the State shall submit to the Secretary, and make publicly available, a report on—</text> 
<paragraph id="H582B84D4605D4A4F93483040C5AAC69A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>how the State has used the grant funds; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H69DFACCA3B374134BAC9A4E641541F65"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of individuals in the State that have used paid family leave benefits as a result of the grant program described in section 101.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA8A556F9403046E0B7D02DB68569CA84"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall, on an annual basis beginning on the date that is 1 year after the date the Secretary receives the first report under subsection (a), submit a report to the appropriate committees on the progress of States establishing paid family leave programs, the modification of existing paid family leave programs, and any changes in the levels of access workers have to paid family leave benefits in each State that receives a grant under section 101.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HF0D7726B745040F99F19C30A7970CCAF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Audit required</header><text>Not later than 1 year after a State receives a grant under section 101, and on an annual basis thereafter, the Inspector General of the Department of Labor shall conduct audits on States that received such a grant to determine whether such States—</text> 
<paragraph id="HE4C779A6BB034CDCA425011DE1018AF6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>are using the grant funds in compliance with the requirements described in section 101(e); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5642A98D6E6D40CBABE6F7625650F52A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>engaging in any waste, fraud, or abuse.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5246B8F59717494F8B6922173395D689"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Appropriate committees defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>appropriate committees</term> means—</text> <paragraph id="H13125ACACC854F3C9632245963382455"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Education and Workforce, the Ways and Means Committee, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE84084A75E494676AF3AFEDD4C17F9B8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions, the Committee on Finance, and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HC1C9DC13A630425E9330C4350DFD14D0" commented="no"><enum>103.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this title:</text> 
<paragraph id="H6DF570EC8FEF41AF932D5F168ADF3520"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Average weekly earnings</header><text>The term <term>weekly earnings</term>, with respect to an individual, means the quotient obtained by dividing—</text> <subparagraph id="H92E158BCE970400CB9DA7685052E48E6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the earnings of the individual, by</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8947E1AB241C486DBA0297A11265F123"><enum>(B)</enum><text>52.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3B1800BD16014312B802FE9F4DF43F50"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered partnership</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered partnership</term>—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB18363A9D74B4762A049A3602100A391"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means a partnership between a State and at least one private entity (such as an insurance company or other private entity handling specific functions of the paid leave program, such as the benefit application process), that provides a paid family leave benefit to eligible employees pursuant to the paid family leave program established by the State that meets the requirements of section 101(d); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1FF2E498E2D14BC0AD28410EE343BA09"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes a State that allows employers to self-administer paid family leave benefits, as described in section 101(d)(5).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0E7A067A57F04A6ABB34C2C08659AEA5" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Earnings</header><text>The term <term>earnings</term>, with respect to an individual, means all compensation for employment that is considered under the applicable State unemployment compensation law for the purpose of calculating the amount of unemployment compensation for the individual.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5B9B33C2A4814E52A8DF7635F428A12E" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Eligible employee</header> <subparagraph id="HFE0DF87745354496A68883C38552F9E4" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>eligible employee</term> means an employee who has been employed—</text> 
<clause id="HADC2ED0693E240EEACD48434CE310B98" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for at least 12 months by the employer with respect to whom leave is requested for the birth or placement of a son or daughter; and</text></clause> <clause id="HE888EC59372547119BDD3F8319434713" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for at least 1,250 hours of service with such employer during the previous 12-month period.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6D9F73D6B6E9463BAB76DC64D40B3D6C" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Determination</header><text>For purposes of determining whether an employee meets the hours of service requirement specified in subparagraph (A)(ii), the legal standards established under section 7 of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/207">29 U.S.C. 207</external-xref>) shall apply.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5ADB82A3D506436692E21B561C9CFEA7" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Employer</header><text>The term <term>employer</term> has the meaning given the term in section 101(4)(A)(i) and (ii) of the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/2611">29 U.S.C. 2611(4)(A)(i)</external-xref>–(ii)).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H789FD81920694777A9B80061804CC2EA" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>FLSA terms</header><text>The terms <term>employ</term> and <term>employee</term> have the meanings given the terms in section 3 of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/203">29 U.S.C. 203</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2D7BFA3A199846D98738671AB52ED604"><enum>(7)</enum><header>State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>State</term> includes any State of the United States, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, American Samoa, Guam, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBC885E5719964E90849BC2942F16EE13"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Son or daughter</header><text>The term <term>son or daughter</term> has the meaning given the term in section 101 of the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/2611">29 U.S.C. 2611</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HF71C64B1A7274107ABA81604CAC28F5A"><enum>104.</enum><header>Rescission and appropriation of funds</header> <subsection id="H91755D74E1EE46A0A215108A042E76B7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Tariff Act enforcement actions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 11334 of the James M. Inhofe National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2023 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1885a">16 U.S.C. 1885a</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>$20,000,000</quote> and inserting <quote>$10,000,000</quote>.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9CB60D1171384B76ABFE4DBFA401DDA7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Department of defense golf courses; limitation on use of appropriated funds</header><text>Section 2491a of title 10, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H59D2413271194A62A20EAD49BE456F7D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="USC"><enum-in-header>(a) </enum-in-header>Limitation.</header-in-text>—Except as provided in subsection (b), funds</quote> and inserting <quote>Funds</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9EDCDD4055B34F10BF264A535E446F55"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking subsection (b).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H4E8F9DE5B36B4FA08A71CF302D60172E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Contract modification</header> <paragraph id="H83A90195F6404616B209BB9F8DE8916A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Release</header><text>The head of each executive agency that, as of the day before the date of enactment of this Act, has entered into a contract or purchase order under Procurement Instrument Identifier GS03F047CA shall take such steps as may be necessary to terminate any such order or contract and release the unexpended balances of any funds obligated to carry out any such order or contract.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H65361FD9513A4E3BBBE8EE97AA186F16"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rescission</header><text>Any balance released from obligation pursuant to the termination of a contract or order pursuant to paragraph (1) shall be permanently rescinded as of the date of the termination of the applicable contract or order.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H39E9095929C243AAB6B8FC18E28BA3A8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Executive agency defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, the term <quote>executive agency</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 133 of title 41, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H53856EA9F63E473B8671A2106B0F460B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this title the following amounts:</text> <paragraph id="H638AA401B7E64AA3979F01B8F3A4D363"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$39,787,500 for fiscal year 2026.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF451922C4E6E46DB970978E6093BB03F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$79,575,000 for fiscal year 2027.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H062A70E82A334A14918C0CF764944F6E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>$145,887,500 for fiscal year 2028.</text></paragraph></subsection> </section></title> 
<title id="H2F8EB422E93245F498662FDB4A6A7BE0"><enum>II</enum><header>I–PLAN</header> 
<section id="H91759FD85BF94F12980AF2A8130F8DB4"><enum>201.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this title:</text> <paragraph id="H4BCC69C3901645EFADCF865FBBE86127" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>BLS</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>BLS</term> means the Bureau of Labor Statistics.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H175433CE33E241BC8CE7B85FEB9ABB65"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Employer-provided paid family and medical leave plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <term>employer-provided paid family and medical leave plan</term> and <term>employer plan</term> mean a plan that—</text> <subparagraph id="H88ADE97506254FFB98BBF1145CDD8EE5"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is provided by an employer to the employees of such employer (whether directly, under a contract with an insurer, or provided through a multiemployer plan);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H862C68994D444041A39B335D6C967C73"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is an option for an employer within the structure of a State paid family and medical leave program in such State; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1DAA9B4997E541ACB39C9701CFAAF521"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">meets or exceeds the requirements of the State paid family and medical leave program of the State in which such employee is employed.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFA688576DC8744478C107AEDA4CB433F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>I–PLAN</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>I–PLAN</term> means the Interstate Paid Leave Action Network established in section 202(a).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1000424AE40345729BF1A281578E20C1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>I–PLAN agreement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>I–PLAN Agreement</term> means the interstate agreement produced pursuant to section 202(b).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD6CE5EBC18134301BBA7340ED83EEDCF"><enum>(5)</enum><header>National intermediary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>national intermediary</term> means a national nongovernmental workforce organization that has extensive experience partnering with the Department of Labor to operate interstate technological systems and the electronic transmission of information and data for State workforce agencies and employers.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H999C84C7B8AD4613AA6893D16C7FDB4F"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Paid leave</header><text>The term <term>paid leave</term> means an increment of compensated leave that is provided, in the case of a State program, by such State or, in the case of an employer plan, by such employer for use during a period in which such individual is not working due to a qualifying reason.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2DEC4351BA1F4262A0777A77D53D2ACC"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Qualifying reason</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>qualifying reason</term> means, in relation to an individual, a reason described in subparagraphs (A) through (D) of section 102(a)(1) of the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/2612">29 U.S.C. 2612(a)(1)</external-xref>) (applied for purposes of this paragraph as if the individual involved were the employee referred to in such section).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC241A4B2FAA349AD831AC8E8E4D25688"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Labor.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB61689C4E0E1481ABBB3924B654CE9DF"><enum>(9)</enum><header>State focal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>State focal</term> means, with respect to a State, an individual—</text> <subparagraph id="HB2658CFA247E4E67AE64826561332987"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">designated by the State agency in charge of such State’s paid family and medical leave program to—</text> 
<clause id="H6CB0BF31CAD740768C68EDF35D048F3F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>participate in the I–PLAN;</text></clause> <clause id="HE612625B0D5F4C7184B9C2DEFEA087DA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>lead such State’s efforts to adopt and implement the I–PLAN Agreement; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H8FF04850868F4531A89BB7B7BA0391BE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">communicate with key paid leave stakeholders across the State; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H60DBE967029D41C7B2907E47FABA940A"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">who—</text> 
<clause id="H5D6C13C1B07B42B28C36FEC8C488B2D9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is employed by such State’s paid family and medical leave program; and</text></clause> <clause id="H566021DD9DF44E598C8F3D85CC51F7F9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has knowledge, experience, and authority in paid leave matters.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB03A9AACF33045F98D720D0E13F6E850"><enum>(10)</enum><header>State paid family and medical leave program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <term>State paid family and medical leave program</term> and <term>State program</term> mean a program under State law that provides, during any 24-month period, a total of not less than 6 weeks of paid leave to individuals—</text> <subparagraph id="H0769A157512F40F3AD8F40C0FC4017AD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for each qualifying reason; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H535E1407A5E44C89B8C1395D491C6217"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in aggregate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> <section id="HE70A8C73BD24476A8E76D52D90941065"><enum>202.</enum><header>Interstate Paid Leave Action Network</header> <subsection id="H1B6ED8B0C83A48CDAD20E581FF14EF14"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header> <paragraph id="H5C7D60C188C848FCBD23687C4AB56533"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established an Interstate Paid Leave Action Network the purpose of which is to provide support and incentives for the development and adoption of an interstate agreement in accordance with this title to benefit employees, States, and employers by—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HBBD4C2A56A094A7A8D6C1917CF04E1D6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>facilitating streamlined benefit delivery;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7A15D8714F784C01BE0C3EA01014D4EA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>reducing administrative burden; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H66ABD6B6910C42BF845AA48208C0C8DC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>coordinating and harmonizing State programs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2D9EEE1E7A6E4D1FAF8DBF40AA11D2C3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>The I–PLAN shall include a State focal from each State receiving a conforming grant under section 204(a).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE07B3C9E0FD54B20AC9AF7BB75A7419D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The I–PLAN shall meet not less than 3 times in each calendar year.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF78B73C269284900851CAE35BF2F6BC9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Processes</header> <subparagraph id="HED70C306FD6941C88111D0AA08546E5B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Certification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">States shall certify to the Secretary their participation in the I–PLAN.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H98F1325BA3364C99994B1BEC3261ABFD"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Procedures</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">State focals may determine, in coordination with the Secretary, the process for the following:</text> <clause id="HF5A8662AAD7F410498638F37D5C0E3A9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the order in which States approach the substance of each I–PLAN requirement;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HDF52F21E01F04C6093E6BAAD823F7D73"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the process by which States reach consensus on such substance and agree to the I–PLAN Agreement;</text></clause> <clause id="HEC58D3563F4E4418BE1E29EE74CCE5C6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the process by which a State may leave the I–PLAN; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H3B59381180EF49D59CDA5328FFD8EF31"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>other processes relevant to the success and administration of the I–PLAN as the Secretary determines.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H819160295BD749B1B90A00EE5F35EA65"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Roadmap</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The I–PLAN shall develop, and annually update, a roadmap for developing and implementing the interstate agreement described in subsection (b) including metrics for success.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD6979FB4C3194223B4754ECA57EE75A4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The duty of the I–PLAN shall be to produce an interstate agreement into which States offering a State paid family and medical leave program may enter and to periodically update such agreement as necessary to improve clarity and scope. Such agreement shall be publicly available and pursue each of the following requirements:</text> <paragraph id="HDA4811BC83F9427FAEB4BE93D5066F38" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Policy standard</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Create a single policy standard with respect to all participating States to facilitate easier compliance with and understanding of paid leave programs across States, including definitions for the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H8AE8D76A076A49269ABCAF8702C8E6B7" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Benefit day, week, and year.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H63427F36D24549D18C52942444A89866" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Base period.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9D2ED54F6CA041C5B97E74A156048E81" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Intermittent and reduced schedule leave.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0BAFCFA83FAE43C1AEFF76FC7682986C" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Place of performance.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE361599BAC46425EA9224187C9FA68EE" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Family members.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB5358215E84F48A5947A33B57E45B3D0" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Employee eligibility.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H191B6C2F515044539A43B97D7F48E523" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Employee coverage.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2A14E4141A0542028B45178E0C8D7ABE" commented="no"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Waiting period.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H732EF156DC3D4781A3C8BB0F75612CFD"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Covered wage.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H512286D27F584CE58576848CC4B1B776"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administrative standard</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Create a single administrative standard with respect to all participating States to facilitate easier compliance with and understanding of paid leave programs across States, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H6449C88E8ADB489B820E47ACA316A36B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the process by which employers respond to requests from States to verify and provide employee information for eligibility determinations, including wages and work history;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD2642E22D2064D849A6C8AA3AFA4CA25"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the process by which employers provide periodic and permanent notice of the availability of paid leave under a State program or employer plan to employees;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE23FC3A8793248ADAA8DAC3614DED7DC"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">employees’ responsibility to provide notices of leave to their employers;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEA245A00D0EC43BB8A92BBE459AEB5C0"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">timing of and process for collecting payroll contributions;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB700CFAF8985472985A6FE8F5CC14B3C"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">coordinating with other types of paid time off and leaves of absence;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0379C34900F04DF392B8492829095AED"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">continuing other benefits;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H27FB514D0E7E4D46A95C4A2589ABDEAF"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">accessing employee leave information;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAD60341B4F2C4917BB4E60DA2B0FCA95"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">protecting personal information;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3DEEE281F6754EE4BA7474FA99F52EBF"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">creating and updating written leave materials such as handbooks;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H554CE22552C64CCC91E28704F7842CAD"><enum>(J)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">maintaining records and documentation; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H110BDB79D0DD4FD0A0071BFCD304F04F"><enum>(K)</enum><text>if a State program permits employers to elect to provide employer plans, facilitating such election, including by creating a single equivalency standard with respect to all participating States to determine whether the maximum monetary value of an employer plan for the average weekly wage of workers in the State for total covered establishments in all industries (based on the most recent calendar year for which data are available from the Quarterly Census of Employment and Wages program of the BLS) is greater than or equal to the maximum monetary value of a State program (or that of multiple States), taking into account programmatic elements such as—</text> <clause id="H2691EED8D26C40A482B5677F7E7B0F62"><enum>(i)</enum><text>how benefit duration, wage replacement, absence of a weekly benefit cap, absence of a waiting week, and other factors interact in a quantitative manner; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H3E224F4A12514BA185D333C23914B348"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>how an individual taking paid family and medical leave for a qualifying reason affects the ability of such individual to take paid family and medical leave for another qualifying reason.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4D5500D4780E429C9C5A94D99C9A4942"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Coordination of benefits across State programs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Create a single process for State programs to process claims for an individual who has work history across multiple participating States so that a single State program may provide benefits to such individual on the basis of all such work history.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HF32C0C5231F145C58C569521D6A0286D"><enum>203.</enum><header>National intermediary to support the Interstate Paid Leave Action Network</header> 
<subsection id="H6CA9185F81174E5AB88DDDA4B687E1A6">
                    <enum>(a)</enum>
                    <header>Authority To make grants</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to the availability of appropriations under section 205(a), the Secretary, acting through the Employment and Training Administration, shall award a grant to one national intermediary to facilitate the activities of the I–PLAN.</text>
                </subsection> 
<subsection id="H0C4C35AF6BE340F39E237BC27177E1A7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A national intermediary awarded a grant under subsection (a) shall use funds for the costs related to each of the following:</text> <paragraph id="HBB8348315A4A4143BD571C562F887B64"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Meeting activities, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H0B6DB07225874F098C900377F14C655B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">convening the State focals as described in section 202(a)(3), including reasonable travel, transportation, and other expenses of State focals and staff of the national intermediary (and any necessary accompanying State personnel);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6169C5307AC24A25B8AAD9493C6B0057"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">making publicly available information on the agendas and outcomes of such meetings; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H76CDE2C79B5C4613BD71247B0319D7D8"><enum>(C)</enum> 
<clause id="H69E3C2F6E5734921A81ED39AE8EC7799" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(i)</enum><text>not later than 12 months after the date of enactment of this title, making publicly available the roadmap described under section 202(a)(5); and</text></clause> <clause id="H4A4353F53801461D8B4D1BB825AF9A89" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>making any updates to such roadmap publicly available.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB652574A11854545858F584A66D54D50"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Producing and making publicly available on an annual basis a report that compares State programs, including information on—</text> <subparagraph id="HB0E2F26A198A48918B1D2B03F13F16A9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>benefit eligibility;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H813458D1F6A84AAB8E3DC4699E7E1F35"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the maximum number of weeks an eligible employee is allowed to receive benefits—</text> <clause id="H4122F7F45E8E4F93A3A25F1CA1F3AF38"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for each qualifying reason; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA240539747E74216B7C1619F0080E281"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in aggregate;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2499CC5717AA4141A82462093CA20AD7"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">wage replacement rate and how that may vary based on prior earnings;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAAD8E2F7266741B6B42BCE004627848A"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">maximum weekly benefit amount;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA801CCAB300F4E48B7201250E8103B8E"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how such programs are financed by employees and employers, including the payroll tax rate and amount of wages subject to tax;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC5487BC5565A49D0A32D5466639F35FB" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether and how such programs allow employers to provide employer plans, taking into consideration elements such as—</text> <clause id="H7620527FF078448C9C2680E09B03BA7E" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>benefit payment timeliness; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H8F3D15939EF1489FA6B1CC3A2475016D" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>employer and employee administrative complexity;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H312AB60845F04A1DBF9F7E2C31D7EBAE"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether and how such programs coordinate with other types of paid-time off and leaves of absence;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2085AD521D5F477EB0372C884AB39A29"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the reasons, including qualifying reasons, under which an individual is eligible to take paid family and medical leave; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCAC493CF01FB4952BDAF9013A66B4934"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">other activities essential for the success, effectiveness, and sustainability of the I–PLAN.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF6B1339D1DF243A189EA612068523EEB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Outreach and coordination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Engagement, consulting, and gathering relevant information in coordination with I–PLAN States from a wide range of external stakeholders, including—</text> <subparagraph id="H270119D1EB404C039B5F7072B5B5FDB1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">State legislatures;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H21FA62084A4E463E91E8A70B2424E337"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Governors;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFD94782ABBE94261B2FD536D82E3CD41"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">employees;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H887F0D59C08F4B9E85200758F0F7CD18"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">representatives of employers, including—</text> <clause id="HC3ACBFC7811142A5880ED1A64BE7D27B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>employers with employees in multiple States; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H1A42AA427CE24D638574ADC089F04CEC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">employers with fewer than 50 employees;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4F6C46D498B44D9480AD78D22C04AB38"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">self-employed individuals;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H228239B197854382BB5A7DFCD166F1E7"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">policy experts and other organizations with expertise on paid leave and unemployment compensation programs; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8C2EFB0AAE1B4696AC0F40C2404E0B2F"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Tribal governments.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H67A83CBDC0FC4D038D33C06E6250A7AD"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Standardized and interoperable technology system for wages</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Providing a standardized technology-based system to facilitate States’ ability to carry out the I–PLAN Agreement, allowing States to process interstate claims and strengthen program integrity, that—</text> <subparagraph id="H84C8DC2FE33E42929B1275C2BD0BBBAE"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">adopts or leverages modular technology that—</text> 
<clause id="H5366E3C60FCF4B2FA80F99575456F2C5"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensures privacy, security, and prompt data availability;</text></clause> <clause id="H47BEFC9C5702479FAD19B7C27F9E7B4D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">enhances and streamlines the claimant, employer, and participating State experience; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA4EF5685E84C45E68EC3CE57086CA7D4">
                                <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is interoperable with other relevant State systems; and</text>
                            </clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H939D17A79D194DDEB33142CD5DD81F1E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">permits States to report on, to the extent reasonable and technologically feasible, and disaggregated by qualifying reason, on trends such as—</text> <clause id="H657C7E9A09C140609D2DB2A226A7B696"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the number of initial and continued benefit claims;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HDD3288F77F964C4285D313D3F7D851C9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>average duration of benefits;</text></clause> <clause id="HB22A7F77290D444F930728BB48474B9F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>average weekly benefit amount;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HAF37F040D67E45F3A39213B4D6C89ED6"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>average time between filing a claim and receiving an initial benefit payment; and</text></clause> <clause id="H28ADD58181D74A579A7E7D2AF878B9B6"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the accuracy of benefit payment amounts.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0F8B7F8D7E614304A992B69550C38C95"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Additional uses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Additional activities, including—</text> <subparagraph id="HDECB17E3565E4D9CA7C964D7A3E4EFEB"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">hiring and compensating staff;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H31CCE765D811489683F08E91F28769E7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>formulating guidance, recommendations, and best practices for States;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8A4C95311BB649A1A979D9644291EFAC"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">providing training on program administration;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H17C65C473441433F917DE1EC7DB28E2E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>providing technical assistance to States; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H485A440C87794D67856DA17E55629BD3"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">creating or leveraging technology essential for the success and effectiveness of the I–PLAN.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H976D0EEF57BC40679B1373FF40516B95" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duration of award</header> 
<paragraph id="H03DD23DC9AD647EEA02BDFC715D559D1" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2), the period during which payments are made to an entity from an award of a grant under subsection (a) shall be 5 years.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H319164EA141F4541B4A109CAF878256E" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Compliance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall annually evaluate whether the national intermediary is complying with the requirements of this title and, if the Secretary determines that the national intermediary is not so complying, shall withhold any payment or part of the payment to the national intermediary under this section for the following fiscal year unless and until the Secretary determines the national intermediary has remedied such compliance issue.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HCFB9071BE3A441C18D4AC9CBB63A4B5E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>National intermediary oversight</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall—</text> <paragraph id="HF8D1D2CF4C82430CA2EF15CECC423CD8"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">monitor the national intermediary to ensure compliance with the requirements of this title;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HED6E49B3613940B88FE5FFA21137F304"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide technical assistance to assist the national intermediary with such compliance; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0208FF53921147C8839FC82F5564AE38"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">require regular reports on the performance of the national intermediary, including on the roadmap under section 202(a)(5), the use of funds under section 203(b), and other methods of evaluation.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H1132ACAFAB9840249612DA0745005F22"><enum>204.</enum><header>Grants to eligible States</header> 
<subsection id="H5EB9D65D7E2E4673A6619E3EF7BB94F3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Conforming grants</header> 
<paragraph id="H9F55180E00FE47F1AF8051D7DF5818A9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header> 
<subparagraph id="H73BC41D0B4CB459E9CB632E9CC959717"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Authority to make grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to the availability of appropriations under section 205(b), the Secretary, acting through the Employment and Training Administration, shall, on an annual basis, make a conforming grant to each eligible State.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1D4F34F8E24E4CBE8E968A43B96D34D3"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Amount of grant</header> <clause id="H3858183A52364592B1D2EB4B2AA04B9F"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A grant to an eligible State under this subsection shall be—</text> 
<subclause id="HAF2287F471E24A0EB44C30D7373FA5F3"><enum>(I)</enum><text>not less than $1,500,000 and not more than $8,000,000; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HF4262E7AA98B4ACBAD3C4FB8D375FDEE"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">subject to subclause (I), awarded on the basis of the relative annual level of employment (as published by the Current Employment Statistics program of the BLS) of the eligible State, compared to the annual level of employment in all eligible States.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H091870F7C9774FC8AFB6512E4CA1B01A"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Adjustment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amounts specified in clause (i) shall be ratably increased or decreased to the extent that funds available under section 205(b) exceed or are less than (respectively) the amount required to provide the amounts specified in clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2ED2F10B411F48CDA383C2EFF1DD3FCD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible States</header> <subparagraph id="H6B58A79B23794CA5A13CF410CE1E6BD8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under paragraph (1), a State shall—</text> 
<clause id="H56F3E497C2104AFCB326056F208916F2"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have a State focal; and</text></clause> <clause id="H6604CF5FBF2C4A9FA8D88D146CA87107"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">participate in the I–PLAN in good faith.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9FAAA4FD374342CEA6AA406CBB8D5F7A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Good faith requirement</header> 
<clause id="HD9D9B4B2A1E1449BA7DB9A5EF0AF374A"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Withholding</header><text>If the Secretary, in consultation with the national intermediary awarded the grant under section 203(a), determines that a State is not participating in the I–PLAN in good faith, the Secretary—</text> <subclause id="H11090EA3A7374B359376FC60E40CF2EB"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall provide warning and feedback to States in a prompt manner; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H71D43B323C7E400DB5D18EAA6B119364"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if, six months after the date on which the Secretary provides such warning and feedback, the Secretary determines such State continues not to participate in the I–PLAN in good faith, the Secretary may elect to withhold a portion or the total amount of a grant under paragraph (1) to such State.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HD4669FEFAAA9487BA145F959F4A7C1DA"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Restoration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary elects to withhold an amount from a State under clause (i)(II), the Secretary may later elect to provide the amount so withheld to such State if the Secretary later determines that such State is participating in good faith.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H74F1526062AF4453B0623C977CBE1E6D" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Implementation grants</header> 
<paragraph id="HBF76760FF1D5488B9FB19D0B4673DA70"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header> 
<subparagraph id="HF9DDC1071AB64931942CA8B692744F49"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Authority to make grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to the availability of appropriations under section 205(c), the Secretary, acting through the Employment and Training Administration, shall, on an annual basis, make an implementation grant to each eligible State.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H30AD6896FDC7477699F35DE564302098"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Amount of grant</header> <clause id="H7586E0DF32404FD09EFD0B3DCD8BD6FB"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A grant to an eligible State under this subsection shall be—</text> 
<subclause id="H41E2989C09CA4D7AA07472BBF2F47BFF"><enum>(I)</enum><text>not less than $1,500,000 and not more than $8,000,000; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H7A2A6C69D6CB446291D3933ECC9E787F"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">subject to subclause (I), awarded on the basis of the relative annual level of employment (as published by Current Employment Statistics program of the BLS) of the eligible State, compared to the annual level of employment in all eligible States.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H81DA16E5EC6D4EA0AB083910776135BD"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Adjustment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amounts specified in clause (i) shall be ratably increased or decreased to the extent that funds available under section 205(c) exceed or are less than (respectively) the amount required to provide the amounts specified in clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD3904C8294164B3B961A2D62051A195B" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligibility</header> <subparagraph id="H04813F10D82245749BF44BFE1964824E" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (B), to be eligible to receive a grant under paragraph (1), a State shall—</text> 
<clause id="HA92FBAAAAEAA4A299BC9930C416D85EF" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>meet the requirements of subsection (a)(2)(A); and</text></clause> <clause id="H81AF826517834B9AA2C307D387663FC8" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have entered into the I–PLAN Agreement.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H075F13542CC14440924C61BF6C01C6D5" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>A State described in subparagraph (A) shall be ineligible to receive a grant for any fiscal year beginning after the date that is 4 years after the date on which such State enters into the I–PLAN Agreement in which such State does not meet the requirements of such Agreement.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H3C8B30F38A8540889C8510F1C87FFF62"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>A State may use grants received under this section—</text> 
<paragraph id="H04176631135E4A0A9BEE687B528A4CFF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to help pay administrative costs, including costs related to—</text> <subparagraph id="H9A90487F910146ABA05634D3143D2CA0"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">customer service;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H975999831AAE474D837350F4BBCC30F7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>staffing and training;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9E450928A5ED40F0945834B09BCE2BE8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>technology;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H617FAFEA7BCB419CAAF44C6A41A5F350"><enum>(D)</enum><text>data sharing;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0FCBE9D7866145EA963B993A1D0AF2BC"><enum>(E)</enum><text>identity validation; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB83F0FE97DDD40C0BD9B7D8F01B3F430"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">program awareness; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H491D5EEEA6B7485996848694E212C9B7"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to help small businesses, as defined by the State, afford employer payroll contributions or access other forms of technical and operational assistance related to State paid family and medical leave.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HD8FA471D226D4A099BEF0B9D0CDF4104"><enum>205.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header> 
<subsection id="H15816158A5974E5989322067F0315DD4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>National intermediary grant</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated not more than $8,824,106.36 for the purposes of section 203 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2028.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H652ECCF0DBC24EC3B76153D01F4A442F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated not more than $35,296,425.43 for the purposes of section 204(a) for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2028.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA0E94B5837824061BC26FD71C35CF981"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Implementation grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated not more than $35,296,425.43 for the purposes of section 204(b) for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2028.</text></subsection></section> </title> </legis-body></bill>

