<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H49A63691AC2D43539AA88E6EF9DBCFED" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 511 IH: Honoring the unbreakable spirit, bravery, and legacy of women veterans and supporting recognition of “Women Veterans Recognition Day”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 511</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250612">June 12, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000477">Mrs. Foushee</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Honoring the unbreakable spirit, bravery, and legacy of women veterans and supporting recognition of <quote>Women Veterans Recognition Day</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas women have answered the call to defend the Nation with unmatched bravery, resilience, and leadership by fighting, sacrificing, and making history every step of the way;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas these extraordinary women have shattered barriers, set new milestones, and inspired generations to serve and lead with pride, courage, and commitment;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas their stories are heroic and their legacies are enduring, demonstrating that women are powerful agents of change in every branch of the military;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas trailblazing women, such as Army General Ann E. Dunwoody, the first woman to rise to the rank of four-star General in the history of the Armed Forces, have proven that gender is no obstacle to the highest levels of leadership;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Mary Edwards Walker, a surgeon during the Civil War and the one woman to receive the Medal of Honor, exemplifies unwavering courage and devotion to service;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Loretta Perfectus Walsh broke new ground in 1917 by enlisting in the Navy Reserve, paving the way for countless women to serve in the Armed Forces;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Lieutenant Elsie S. Ott displayed extraordinary heroism during World War II by executing intercontinental aeromedical evacuations, saving lives, and demonstrating women’s vital role in military medicine;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Jeannie Marie Leavitt soared into history as the first female fighter pilot and commander of an Air Force combat wing, smashing stereotypes and inspiring future generations;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Captain Kathleen McGrath became the first woman to command a warship of the Navy, demonstrating women’s capacity to lead and serve in combat roles;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Colonel Linda McTague broke barriers as the first woman to command an Air National Guard wing and fighter squadron, exemplifying leadership and perseverance;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Simone Askew, at only 20 years old, became the first Black woman to serve as top cadet at West Point, exemplifying excellence and breaking racial and gender barriers;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the heroic 6888th Central Postal Directory Battalion, also known as the Six Triple Eight Battalion, an all-Black, all-female unit during World War II, delivered millions of pieces of mail, boosted troop morale, and demonstrated unwavering dedication to duty and service;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas women’s service in the Armed Forces dates back to the brave women of the Women’s Army Auxiliary Corps established in 1942, laying the foundation for women’s official roles in the Armed Forces;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas women have served as drill sergeants, leading with discipline, professionalism, and pride, symbolized by the iconic drill sergeant hat, emblems of strength and leadership; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas June 12 is <quote>Women Veterans Recognition Day</quote> in recognition of legacy, sacrifices, and groundbreaking achievements of women veterans: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H4A8B22A36EF8412EB1E8CBC53CAC5712"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HC901A09C0D0F4CDA8F52E306BB04AC31"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> 
<paragraph id="H3F43A75D409441A794B5343C12D7A103"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recognizes, honors, and celebrates the contributions, sacrifices, and achievements of women veterans, past and present; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE5B58B06ACC54F18A52C413A6ED39C67"><enum>(2)</enum><text>expresses support for the designation of <quote>Women Veterans Recognition Day</quote>. </text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

