<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD87A819B4EB84ED1917AD0CCE2D51C04" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 265 IH: Condemning the Trump administration for the use of an unauthorized method of communicating highly sensitive or potentially classified information regarding a United States military operation via the messaging platform “Signal”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 265</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250327">March 27, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000310">Ms. Johnson of Texas</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HIG00">Intelligence (Permanent Select)</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Condemning the Trump administration for the use of an unauthorized method of communicating highly sensitive or potentially classified information regarding a United States military operation via the messaging platform <quote>Signal</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Vice President J.D. Vance used an unauthorized method of communicating highly sensitive or potentially classified information regarding a United States military operation via the messaging platform <quote>Signal</quote>;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Secretary of Defense Pete Hegseth used an unauthorized method of communicating highly sensitive or potentially classified information regarding a United States military operation via the messaging platform <quote>Signal</quote>;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Secretary of State Marco Rubio used an unauthorized method of communicating highly sensitive or potentially classified information regarding a United States military operation via the messaging platform <quote>Signal</quote>;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Director of National Intelligence Tulsi Gabbard used an unauthorized method of communicating highly sensitive or potentially classified information regarding a United States military operation via the messaging platform <quote>Signal</quote>;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Presidential Advisor Stephen Miller used an unauthorized method of communicating highly sensitive or potentially classified information regarding a United States military operation via the messaging platform <quote>Signal</quote>;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Assistant to the President for National Security Affairs Mike Walz used an unauthorized method of communicating highly sensitive or potentially classified information regarding a United States military operation via the messaging platform <quote>Signal</quote>;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Secretary of the Treasury Scott Bessent used an unauthorized method of communicating highly sensitive or potentially classified information regarding a United States military operation via the messaging platform <quote>Signal</quote>;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency John Ratcliffe used an unauthorized method of communicating highly sensitive or potentially classified information regarding a United States military operation via the messaging platform <quote>Signal</quote>;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the National Security Council official Brian McCormack used an unauthorized method of communicating highly sensitive or potentially classified information regarding a United States military operation via the messaging platform <quote>Signal</quote>;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the White House Chief of Staff Susie Wiles used an unauthorized method of communicating highly sensitive or potentially classified information regarding a United States military operation via the messaging platform <quote>Signal</quote>;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the National Security Council official Steve Witkoff used an unauthorized method of communicating highly sensitive or potentially classified information regarding a United States military operation via the messaging platform <quote>Signal</quote>;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas members of the administration may not have properly documented highly sensitive and potentially classified information in accordance with chapters 21, 29, 31, and 33 of title 44, United States Code (commonly known as the Federal Records Act), enacted in 1950;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas foreign adversaries have previously accessed and consistently attempt to access highly sensitive and classified information relevant to United States National Security, such as China’s successful 2024 attempt to infiltrate the United States Treasury and Russia’s targeting of United States military plans and sensitive data, notably through operations like Moonlight Maze and espionage activities such as the Arc Electronics case, which include cyberattacks and illegal technology exports;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas top members of the administration used a publicly available commercial platform to form a <quote>small group</quote>, communicate highly sensitive or potentially classified information, and discuss openly their intentions, at risk of access by foreign adversaries;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the administration has in prior instances violated Federal law and basic guidance on handling of classified information, such as the President’s improper storage of classified documents at <quote>Mar-a-Lago</quote>; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas members of the administration discussed highly classified information regarding a United States military operation outside of a Sensitive Compartmented Information Facility, also known as a SCIF: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H79C0DC7EF4FC49B186D940A51FCD3428"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HAAACD0CFBB584969B840176A9B42BBC0"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="H92C4787E29BF4CDFBEA76A8AB2CE27FC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>condemns the administration for risking our national security by potentially exposing highly sensitive or potentially classified information to United States foreign adversaries like China and Russia, who have in the past have successfully accessed highly sensitive and confidential information pertaining to United States national interests;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD8B48690A6AE40DCA2F7DEAE8A377648"><enum>(2)</enum><text>condemns the administration for putting American servicemembers’ lives at risk by discussing military operations in an unsecured, unclassified setting and sharing this information with at least one nongovernmental party;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7529C414BF6D45E7BF47CC5478D2BF70"><enum>(3)</enum><text>calls on the administration to review its procedures and systems for the communication of classified information;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA0D13B89D2A14EE9BE96C5712792749B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>calls on the administration to investigate all communication methods being used by members of the administration and ensure they are aligned with proper procedure as it pertains to the communication of classified or highly sensitive information;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H51BF553A5BC94A74B916ECAFE9D09711"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">calls on the administration to initiate an investigation to uncover if any members of the administration violated any Federal laws regarding the communication of classified information;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9E14134E7BBE4BB3A21DCE537F181ABB"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">calls on the administration to hold any and all members of the administration accountable to the full extent of the law if any Federal laws were violated by members of the administration pertaining to the communication of classified information;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8215575745D24DA7A0DBD4EA6B1900A7"><enum>(7)</enum><text>calls on the administration to investigate on how many instances the National Security Council or any other relevant executive branch officials has used the <quote>Signal</quote> messaging service or any other messaging service application that has not been approved for the transmission of highly sensitive or classified information;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H83482447E7CE438CA23B02BC85C442AA"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">calls on the administration to ensure all members of the administration are communicating highly sensitive or classified information inside a SCIF to ensure members of the administration do not endanger United States National Security by communicating classified information through improper channels; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H737057CC3D6445D29F16E97588F2CBD6"><enum>(9)</enum><text>calls on the administration to inform all members of the administration that the communication of classified information outside of a SCIF, is strictly prohibited and that any members of the administration found to violate this procedure will be removed from office and subsequently be punished in accordance with any and all applicable laws pertaining to the communication of classified information.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

