<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-NEW25701-5TN-XL-2HF">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2181 IS: Securing Our Propane Supply Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>II</distribution-code>
        <congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session>1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. 2181</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action>
            <action-date date="20250626" legis-day="20250624">June 26 (legislative day, June 24),
                2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S380">Mr. Peters</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S375">Mr. Daines</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was
                read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on
                    Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title>To require the Secretary of Energy to conduct a study to determine the
            feasibility and effectiveness of establishing a national strategic propane
            reserve.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause">
        <section section-type="section-one" id="ide5c4386148ad424dabe6a8177553cbd6">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Securing Our Propane Supply Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6a2934f8f51d41fa88f1e3836be4fb07">
            <enum>2.</enum>
            <header>Department of Energy study on establishing national strategic propane
                reserve</header>
            <subsection id="id2E2819EE74A2416EB69A81DB1A132895">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>Study</header>
                <paragraph id="id8B166E6042B846BC902C084D0A939133">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                    <header>In general</header>
 <text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Energy, in consultation with the Administrator of the Energy Information Administration, shall complete a study to determine the feasibility and effectiveness of establishing a national strategic propane reserve, separate from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve established under part B of title I of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6231">42 U.S.C. 6231 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id6b6c8eb603ba405b97864c58dea906e4">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Elements</header>
 <text>The study under paragraph (1) shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="id7647dac96c054b0e89ee24e5bf1d88ab"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>an assessment of the current state of the propane supply chain in the United States to meet current and forecasted consumer demands;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id70f4f6a0b5b7468aab6000030f9836e4">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>an assessment of the risks of regional propane supply disruptions, including—</text>
                        <clause id="id75A25FBF7B364FC185CB18CD79CA1D2A">
                            <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>past causes of disruptions;</text> </clause> <clause id="idD761EEBD2CAA42779C279F41D2F2D14C"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>possible causes of disruptions in the future; and</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="idD66039A1213A49B5B316D046B01DE7C8">
                            <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>whether disruptions justify the establishment of a national strategic propane reserve;</text>
                        </clause>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id746ecbb4d5e644c79955bf2a4eda7506">
                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>an evaluation of—</text> <clause id="id47EC1EB60F314EDE9D1F6FCEC529CC10"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>appropriate and most suitable locations for a strategic propane reserve;</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="idADFD50D46CEB44FABA68071B339F8C5B">
                            <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>the quantity of propane storage that would be appropriate at each such location; and</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="id6b47fa8784d54fe4bb3631ac27e5e3b5">
                            <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>the suitability of existing infrastructure to facilitate transportation and delivery of propane from a strategic propane reserve during a drawdown;</text>
                        </clause>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id84ae5eb4ac724837beafda9ae3c0f6f4">
                        <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>an evaluation of the additional infrastructure needed for a strategic propane reserve to function properly;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id11ce838c4e8b4f15973bb5728821128f">
                        <enum>(E)</enum>
 <text>consideration of the means by which a strategic propane reserve would prevent and manage degradation of the propane in storage;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id9070c430c8dd4627a80ddf26dd5fe63c">
                        <enum>(F)</enum>
 <text>an evaluation of appropriate triggers (including price and supply) for making available propane from a strategic reserve;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="idbc39074e1da0442d82547f4fd2d56d72">
                        <enum>(G)</enum>
 <text>an evaluation of the appropriate manner of acquiring propane and propane storage for a strategic reserve, while minimizing market implications, including an assessment of—</text>
                        <clause id="idF86A27FBCC344E54A1DB0AB6272C009C">
                            <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>unutilized and under-utilized storage; and</text> </clause> <clause id="id3199A56F73E34A7FB658DD95A2528168"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>new storage opportunities;</text>
                        </clause>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="idb74953a384294ce1862008c7274a7dcb">
                        <enum>(H)</enum>
 <text>an evaluation of the appropriate transactions (including direct sales, exchanges, or other options) for delivering propane in a strategic reserve to the market when a release is triggered;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="idfba847b57916467f9859b57c48001289">
                        <enum>(I)</enum>
 <text>an evaluation of likely consumers (including individuals, agricultural producers, and the Armed Forces) of propane from a strategic reserve, including—</text>
                        <clause id="idBA864AF66A8940569520BEDE45FB2E18">
                            <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>identification and categorization of those consumers;</text> </clause> <clause id="idE9E3D101CD2A42BC911446FD8596660B"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>a State-by-State breakdown of propane usage by those consumers; and</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="ida50884afcf064b76b2562c137a38466f">
                            <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>an evaluation of the expected impacts of a strategic propane reserve on those categories of consumers and States;</text>
                        </clause>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id41a43fbc55924f9f9fd8897506ba9316">
                        <enum>(J)</enum>
 <text>an evaluation of the market implications of establishing and administering a strategic propane reserve, including an assessment of potential price and supply effects; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="ida173949cbcc9490d92d86912ee33ae25">
                        <enum>(K)</enum>
 <text>identification, preliminary assessment, and evaluation of alternatives to a strategic propane reserve that could provide supply and price relief during regional propane supply disruptions.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="idDD17DA76E8C84FAAA64939ADF1E01916">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
                    <header>Recommendations</header>
 <text>In conducting the study under this subsection, the Secretary of Energy shall develop recommendations with respect to each element of the study described in paragraph (2) regarding—</text>
                    <subparagraph id="idB75F50FD69AA418B9AD65AE09490472E">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>whether a national strategic propane reserve should be established; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="ida7721c2e2cad41bebe4cbf62aaf17994">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>if such a reserve should be established, the most practicable method of establishment.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id97ea90234e31474eb36543ee8dce0c2d">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Plan</header>
 <text>Not later than 180 days after the date of completion of the study under subsection (a), the Secretary of Energy shall develop a plan for implementing the recommendations developed under paragraph (3) of that subsection.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id01b636d781b6465da7465de572c1ae1b">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Industry coordination</header>
 <text>In conducting the study under subsection (a) and developing the plan under subsection (b), the Secretary of Energy is encouraged to coordinate with entities in the propane industry, including representatives from the entire propane supply chain.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id9D424B340BFC4EE8BCB1307A85A05AC6">
                <enum>(d)</enum>
                <header>Submission to Congress</header>
 <text>The Secretary of Energy shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives a report describing—</text>
                <paragraph id="id26209EC5EEAD41E38607E38D454DB567">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>the study completed under subsection (a); and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="id61BD41DB87BD4BD6B045F252C32023B2"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>the plan developed under subsection (b).</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id842c9de233054092b3dde9ed9533b926">
                <enum>(e)</enum>
                <header>Protection of national security information</header>
 <text>Before submitting the report under subsection (d), or otherwise publishing the study completed under subsection (a) or the plan developed under subsection (b), the Secretary of Energy shall adopt such procedures with respect to confidentiality (including procedures for redaction of information) as the Secretary determines to be necessary to ensure the protection of classified information relating to specific vulnerabilities to United States energy security or reliability.</text>
            </subsection>
        </section>
    </legis-body>
</bill>

