<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ERN25263-K3V-74-CWP"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2004 IS: Maternal and Infant Syphilis Prevention Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
 <distribution-code>II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2004</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250610">June 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S359">Mr. Heinrich</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S318">Mr. Wicker</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to issue guidance on best practices for screening and treatment of congenital syphilis under Medicaid and the Children’s Health Insurance Program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H3BD26C3F6BDC42D297E55CDEFAEE6417"><section section-type="section-one" id="H53203C2A76F94CCFA0FD57F0D1AC95AF"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Maternal and Infant Syphilis Prevention Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HD468D0C25EAF40F28D1FF87EBA8FF28F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="idbf08b1bf55c04ba0808ce00abda093f0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In 2023, there were 209,253 cases of syphilis in the United States, the highest number since 1950. This represents an 80 percent increase since 2018 and continuing a decades-long upward trend.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id35390a95a2ce41a9bd9add7018f182ba"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Untreated, syphilis can seriously damage the heart and brain and can cause blindness, deafness, and paralysis.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida337263ada2d4d2a919d0efbad0d7948"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The increased rise in syphilis cases is causing the rise in congenital syphilis with more than 3,882, a 3 percent increase from 2022, resulting in 252 stillbirths and 27 infant deaths. The cases are more than 10 times the number diagnosed in 2012.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2a1eed5efa7f40cb9a3372bc16bed890"><enum>(4)</enum><text>When transmitted during pregnancy, congenital syphilis can cause miscarriage, lifelong medical issues, and infant death. Congenital syphilis can present health issues for babies at birth, including neonatal death, meningitis, anemia, and problems with the spleen and liver. If not treated, congenital syphilis can cause bone and joint problems, vision and hearing problems, issues with the nervous system, and developmental delays.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida827964c41c645f4b4ce6d534986e6a6"><enum>(5)</enum><text>High incidence rates of congenital syphilis are often due to lack of timely testing or inadequate treatment during pregnancy. Timely syphilis testing and treatment during pregnancy might be able to prevent almost 90 percent of congenital syphilis cases.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id58aa932dd1434982a377413e0b786840"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Requirements for syphilis screening among pregnant women varies by State. The majority of States require syphilis screening in the first visit, significantly less States require syphilis screenings during the third trimester or at delivery.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide3fdb4c0337845549fb36e52405cc81f"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Screening during the third trimester and at delivery can lead to earlier detection of congenital syphilis and prevent adverse health outcomes for mothers and newborn infants.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idebd418b5670348bb8231c821f8288868"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Increased awareness and education are critical in reducing syphilis among pregnant women to prevent congenital syphilis.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H92B3A973F0F84A968AAC617F83A4A54E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Guidance and technical assistance under State Medicaid programs and State CHIPs</header><subsection id="H95FD47A1AB6040B3B7253875D62BCF9D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 12 months after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary shall issue guidance to State agencies responsible for administering State Medicaid programs, State CHIPs, or both such programs, the Indian Health Service, Indian Tribes, tribal organizations, and Urban Indian organizations, on best practices with respect to actions that State Medicaid programs, State CHIPs, Indian health programs, and urban Indian health programs operated by an urban Indian organization pursuant to a grant or contract with the Indian Health Service pursuant to title V of the Indian Health Care Improvement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/1601">25 U.S.C. 1601 et seq.</external-xref>) may take, including by using waivers under section 1115 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1315">42 U.S.C. 1315</external-xref>) and authorities under title XIX of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396">42 U.S.C. 1396 et seq.</external-xref>) and title XXI of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1397aa">42 U.S.C. 1397aa et seq.</external-xref>), for the following purposes:</text><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9587214B23BF4B979A415653370B0C69"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Improving access to expand syphilis screening for pregnant women and babies.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0C481DFB97A14FBBBDB0855B40A59EA6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Best practices for educating medical professionals and pregnant women with respect to syphilis.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB60F9BF1D8A34D54B44C87FFBF4996E0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Strategies for integrating telehealth services and training for providers and patients on the use of telehealth, including working with interpreters to furnish health services and providing resources with respect to congenital syphilis in multiple languages.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9C57ECA5CDCD4A22B102118C2AC9ACF5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Best practices for increasing testing for syphilis in the third trimester and at delivery.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA87DD6DD9722497682AA3D2FBDE6E88F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Improving treatment for syphilis and congenital syphilis.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H894C64A3B711453F8C31487ABD813566"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0f218b3a53f0439a82dd4f9d48371843"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>Indian Tribe, tribal organization, Urban Indian, Urban Indian organization, Indian health program</header> <text>The terms <term>Indian tribe</term>, <term>tribal organization</term>, <term>Urban Indian</term>, <term>Urban Indian organization</term>, and <term>Indian health program</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 4 of the Indian Health Care Improvement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/1603">25 U.S.C. 1603</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1620C2FE70E04A2BABAFEEEE0EE7D9BB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD22383302F694ED7A39D04D9F6BE5481"><enum>(3)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> has the meaning given such term in section 1101(a)(1) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1301">42 U.S.C. 1301(a)(1)</external-xref>) for purposes of titles XIX and XXI of such Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id573662e27d024a9db79da218fe593019"><enum>(4)</enum><header>State chip</header><text>The term <term>State CHIP</term> means a State child health plan for child health assistance under title XXI of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1397aa">42 U.S.C. 1397aa et seq.</external-xref>), and includes any waiver of such a plan.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd6ce91d6eb494960895965abb082f3ef"><enum>(5)</enum><header>State medicaid program</header><text>The term <term>State Medicaid program</term> means a State plan for medical assistance under title XIX of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396">42 U.S.C. 1396 et seq.</external-xref>), and includes any waiver of such a plan.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA066895A052048EDB8638BE630123D12"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Health, Education, Labor and Pensions of the Senate, and the Committee on Finance of the Senate, and shall make publicly available, a report analyzing the implementation of the best practices described in subsection (a).</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

