<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDC146BBD5CC2413896F35297C2E5649A" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 207 IH: Recognizing and commemorating the contributions of contemporary Latinas in the State of Illinois.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 207</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250310">March 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000617">Mrs. Ramirez</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing and commemorating the contributions of contemporary Latinas in the State of Illinois.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the United States commemorates National Women’s History Month every March to recognize and honor the contributions of women throughout the history of the United States and the women making history now;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Latinas contribute to the cultural, economic, and political power of the United States;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas there are approximately 32,244,214 Latinas living in the United States, and 1,165,312 Latinas live in the State of Illinois;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Latinas continue to be greatly underrepresented in elected office;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Latinas represent 9.6 percent of the United States population but only 2.6 percent of elected officeholders in State and 3.6 percent in Federal offices across the country;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the State of Illinois is a model for supporting and electing Latinas;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the State of Illinois has significantly increased the representation of Latinas at all levels of government, including electing the diverse and powerful Latinas of Illinois’ Third Congressional District, such as—</text> <paragraph id="HD5CCF2EF307E433D89F28B75B6D4F0AF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Village of Franklin Park Clerk, April Arellano; </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF4FCB59D2DAE4D54A27EBFFEA639FAB2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Village of Addison Trustee, Maria Reyes; </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H822B37FA78ED412283886724A13110FC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Bensenville Village Trustee, Rosa Carmona; </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8FEB8E99992A4FF69EECA4D08A4023EB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Hanover Township Trustee, Denise Noyola; </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4BFB5CF17735458DAE915DA597765BAD"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Council Member for the City of Elgin, Rosamaria Martinez; </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC783E63BD20B4CD28EB859533110AFD9"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Alderperson Ruth Cruz; </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB5FF7D203DFA425E86180C761C2EFB21"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Alderperson Jessie Fuentes; </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0AAE7613E4C145D8B0C87C52DA5C6462"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Alderperson Rossana Rodriguez-Sanchez; </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2F2E860904D34A12B686D38F74C89F24"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Metropolitan Water Reclamation District of Greater Chicago Board Commissioner Eira L. Corral Sepúlveda; </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC5E1DA5B34724C78A67D1A41D18FB992"><enum>(10)</enum><text>State Representative Eva Dina Delgado; </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H916FA43899D34AF5A40271C8F72D9BD1"><enum>(11)</enum><text>State Representative Lilian Jimenez; </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7E4350189131470599F75CF2BA064122"><enum>(12)</enum><text>State Representative Norma Hernandez; </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2792C18F974C40088B1AA802143DC909"><enum>(13)</enum><text>State Senator Karina Villa; </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6E298F531A7549A797A6436535D805D3"><enum>(14)</enum><text>State Senator Graciela Guzman; and </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD2E3EEFE0A3B4DC3AF4247DB8C2B8FC4"><enum>(15)</enum><text>State Senator Cristina Castro;</text></paragraph></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas many of the Latinas elected to their positions are the first Latinas in their roles or the first Latinas to serve in their communities;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the work of Latinas at all levels of government in the State of Illinois has resulted in the codification of women’s rights and the expansion of health care for undocumented people;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the grassroots, organizing, and political participation of Latinas resulted in the election of the first Latina from the Midwest to Congress;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the voices, lived experiences, and contributions of Latinas in the State of Illinois continue to have long-lasting, positive impacts for the communities that they serve;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Latinas representing Latinas is necessary to build a multicultural, multigenerational movement that acknowledges the shared humanity of others;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas significant progress has been made to increase the representation of Latinas in all decision-making spaces; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas there is still work that needs to be done until Latinas achieve equitable representation in all sectors, industries, and leadership roles: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H573CFAB11B494962B67BC9B2ADB6792A"> <section id="H5FCC9395FBA24DE180991D72CECDD0CA" section-type="undesignated-section" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text> 
<paragraph id="HE894B1AC39F54327B91221065865637D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>celebrates the impact and contributions of contemporary Latinas in the State of Illinois;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7D0E6E08F27841DC9D65CEA78AB3799A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>acknowledges the value of Latinas and the essential role they play in this Nation’s multicultural, multigenerational democracy; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0EA46685052F49F3AF24725B804CA1AB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recognizes the importance of accurate and timely data on Latinas living in the United States and the role that the United States Census Bureau plays in delivering data that impacts the political and economic power and influence of Latinas.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

