<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE8ADD85D0C8248FF99FDE6F2852A86BF" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1890 IH: Turkey Diplomatic Realignment Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1890</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250305">March 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001190">Mr. Schneider</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001257">Mr. Bilirakis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000317">Ms. Malliotakis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000614">Mr. Pappas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To administratively reassign responsibility for the Republic of Turkey within the Department of State and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H06C706FE026742B5BB952CBE75855DFF" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HB20AFFE00AF640CBB45D3B211FFCF307" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Turkey Diplomatic Realignment Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H353A3D002B4A4EB1AF4C3C1FDC27B6FF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HB634FBEDB7264D9186D8C2C6CC7220ED"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Republic of Turkey occupies a unique geopolitical position at the intersection of Europe and the Middle East, influencing security, economic, and diplomatic interests of the United States in both regions.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF05F6A83E2DC4EA4904C201B0E52277F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Department of State currently assigns responsibility for Turkey within the Bureau of European and Eurasian Affairs, despite Turkey’s extensive engagement in Middle Eastern affairs and security issues.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H37A9035DDD31493683EAC8CF72BD713C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A reassignment of Turkey to the Bureau of Near Eastern Affairs would better align diplomatic strategy and facilitate regional cooperation.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H857AE76AC87C4E189F0807C3BC937CCA"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Turkey’s foreign policy trajectory in recent years has distanced it from the European Union and The North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO), as evidenced by its strategic realignments and domestic political shifts that challenge European democratic norms.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFCF2DFE2773644DB81806F91D6525E49"><enum>(5)</enum><text>European institutions have increasingly sidelined Turkey from full integration, delaying accession talks and raising concerns over human rights, democratic governance, and rule of law.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDD032D488EC64F3D920535E1D97BA1C3"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Turkey’s growing partnerships with non-western powers, including Russia and China, along with its pursuit of BRICS membership, underscore its shifting priorities away from western alignment.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA2D0FE637E444ED59452498574CBA5BD"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The Turkish government’s increasing engagement with Islamist actors, its role in conflicts such as Syria and Libya, and its strained relations with Israel have deepened concerns over its long-term reliability as a western partner.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3B31F2B28D41454CAE437B3E46AFB634"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The reassignment serves as a diplomatic signal reflecting Turkey’s diminishing European prospects and encourages national debate within Turkey about its geopolitical future, particularly in light of its perceived marginalization from European strategic decision-making.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H55AC1189D1624AB2918B51A4760FDF0A"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Turkey has provided political and logistical support to Hamas, hosting members of the group and facilitating fundraising activities, further straining its relationships with western allies and contributing to concerns over its regional alignment.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFDB1629DF5C54675A7CD617109CD8EAF"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The United States remains committed to a strong relationship with Turkey but must recalibrate its diplomatic engagement in recognition of changing realities, ensuring U.S. regional policy remains consistent with evolving security and economic dynamics.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H614FC5E8D7C24967A48A444925839412"><enum>3.</enum><header>Administrative reassignment</header> 
<subsection id="H08C2C0EF5D44491B95C27D9D60AC65DB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall administratively reassign responsibility for the Republic of Turkey from the Bureau of European and Eurasian Affairs to the Bureau of Near Eastern Affairs within the Department of State.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H1E71E5CCFD934027BC5AB4CDA09349C4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report to congress</header><text>Not later than 5 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate a report—</text> 
<paragraph id="H260448AAA2C34A42B5B41A2B16FBB96F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>describing the effectiveness and implications of the reassignment required by subsection (a); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H087AA6E267954DA793224C74929AA07A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>providing recommendations for further changes regarding the assignment of responsibility for Turkey.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8C994EBF4CA649D9B231D757AC26B259"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to prevent the Secretary from modifying or discontinuing the use of regional bureaus as necessary to advance the diplomatic objectives of the United States.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

