<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="H37AB71CE73FE4E099E25845EB78DAAE8" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1069 RH: Promoting Responsible Oversight To Eliminate Communist Teachings for Our Kids Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 8</calendar><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1069</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 119–14]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250206">February 6, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001082">Mr. Hern of Oklahoma</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="K000401">Mr. Kiley of California</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250305">March 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsor: <cosponsor name-id="B001282">Mr. Barr</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250305">March 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on February 6, 2025</action-instruction></action><action><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the availability of Federal education funds for elementary and secondary schools that receive direct or indirect support from the Government of the People’s Republic of China.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HED00" reported-display-style="italic" id="HA39A808A4A3F47BD83B60FBDE73DA46E"><section id="HF782DBC4DD1F41048B597B9AD4E12748"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Promoting Responsible Oversight To Eliminate Communist Teachings for Our Kids Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>PROTECT Our Kids Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H6C1C76CBDDE14D59ADF4ABE1B2458AAF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on availability of funds</header><subsection id="H8F320060A4404612A798A722CF6B8B6D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no funds may be made available under an applicable program to any elementary school or secondary school that—</text><paragraph id="H5E0C961C74C444E7AAC6ADF1AAB1A3D3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>has a partnership in effect with a cultural or language institute directly or indirectly funded by the Government of the People’s Republic of China, including a Confucius Institute;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF4C982F0EDEB4D30AE7CA08138F5B0AA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>operates a learning center directly or indirectly supported by the Government of the People’s Republic of China (commonly referred to as a <quote>Confucius Classroom</quote>); or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3E94835DA5D44B93AF0222AA62BD75F7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>otherwise receives support from an individual or entity acting directly or indirectly on behalf of the Government of the People’s Republic of China, including support in the form of teaching materials, personnel, funds, or other resources.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H02ED921F3DE74325A8EF469D80CD0A8A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The prohibition under subsection (a) shall take effect on the date that is one year after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H4E1D04CBD8884648895E244E18EADB5C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Contracts made prior to date of enactment</header><paragraph id="HCD753527388F4F5CAB75ECF21395E813"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><subparagraph id="H5D27D069B1D544398CF9789E8DEF5AF2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Waiver request submission</header><text>In the case of an elementary school or a secondary school that is a party to a contract described in paragraph (2), the school timely shall submit to the Secretary a request for a waiver of the prohibition under subsection (a) that includes—</text><clause id="HFB23473807F34F72B18F53F7C71B78D7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the complete and unredacted text of the contract, and if the contract is not in English, a translated copy of the text into English; and</text></clause><clause id="H2017CC35469F444590CBB0DB8BE8BED4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a statement demonstrating that the contract is for the benefit of the school’s mission and students and will promote the security, stability, and economic vitality of the United States.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9A99A00D1DF44459AB8A3CF76E0CFDF1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Waiver issuance</header><text>the Secretary, upon receipt of a request submitted under subparagraph (A), may issue a waiver to the school for a period beginning on the effective date specified in subsection (b) and ending the date on which the contract terminates.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H98ED0389FA734696B55E8E55A085774A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contracts described</header><text>A contract is described in this paragraph if the contract—</text><subparagraph id="HA24DB58B158B4AB09AD7F18754433D3B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>takes effect before the date of the enactment of this Act;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFFE30E8708564010B1AA6FA9746D62B6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>continues to be effective after the effective date specified in subsection (b); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3C823F4F971B4CA0858FF611F5B40BC7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>relates to at least one of the circumstances described in paragraph (1), (2), or (3) of subsection (a).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE991443B2B5D4172A805F3D95C1FF7FB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Notice to affected schools</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall provide notice to elementary and secondary schools of the requirements of this section together with guidance for achieving compliance with such requirements.</text></subsection></section><section id="HF0BAECB4F8124DA6964105CA53CE9C44"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="HA799D3C0B86F41D487EF10759F5C0C42"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Applicable program</header><text>The term <quote>applicable program</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 400(c)(1) of the General Education Provisions Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1221">20 U.S.C. 1221(c)(1)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2A07D2DA9FF8481FBCC14E995A3FFB61"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Esea terms</header><text>The terms <quote>elementary school</quote>, <quote>secondary school</quote>, and <quote>Secretary</quote> have the meanings given those terms in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date date="20250305">March 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

