<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7F720BA471B44D13BE0C946C4A42D6EE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3183 IH: Supporting Access to Falls Education and prevention and Strengthening Training Efforts and Promoting Safety initiatives for Veterans Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3183</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250505">May 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001315">Ms. Budzinski</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="F000462">Ms. Lois Frankel of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000399">Mrs. Kiggans of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001301">Mr.
          Bergman</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001257">Mr. Bilirakis</cosponsor>)
        introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans’ Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to
        the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and
          Workforce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in
        each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the
 committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to establish the Office of Falls Prevention of the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H1E965682C7D040A8BD6AB8420FD0813C" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="HDB4BF918A3314844BA4CCD7951096727"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Supporting Access to Falls Education and prevention and Strengthening Training Efforts and Promoting Safety initiatives for Veterans Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SAFE STEPS for Veterans Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2F02C4C18B014FB2A79E13B7A1178063"><enum>2.</enum><header>Establishment of Office of Falls Prevention of Department of Veterans Affairs</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H278021CF07BD42B493C85E196158095B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment of office</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H02AABB3589224AF2B3BDDF03E4BE58D5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/73">chapter 73</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/7310A">section 7310A</external-xref> the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H63C3D39D8AA4481CAAA21BFEBC54D0D9"><section id="HA64268F3338E47E39F66CBCF68DB1E6B"><enum>7310B.</enum><header>Office of Falls Prevention</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H51218BFF29AC4857B045ECB2B7E507EB"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Office</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HCF1EAB23943B467DA0B27981B7D7FEF2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Under Secretary for Health shall establish and operate in the Veterans Health Administration the Office of Falls Prevention (in this section referred to as the <quote>Office</quote>).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3BE7293A49724CB186AD4DE2B6600A67" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Office shall be located at the Central Office of the Department.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7869F5AF129040BCB4DD9CCFA1A9B4E3" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H8351A9587AD84CA3B54A7485DDB97F20"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The head of the Office is the Chief Officer of Falls Prevention (in this section referred to as the <quote>Chief Officer</quote>). </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HB5F2DDB8E63D4C9189B12883C8E1AF32"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Chief Officer shall report to the Under Secretary for Health.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1C4F30C55D5041ADAC61F703DB236699" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Under Secretary for Health shall provide the Office with such staff and other support as may be necessary for the Office to carry out effectively the functions of the Office under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H478081EC8C0B48B0AFEAE5B9924C76A5" indent="up1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Under Secretary for Health may reorganize existing offices within the Veterans Health Administration as of the date of the enactment of this section in order to avoid duplication with the functions of the Office.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H85A49237FECA4ECBA75C35EEE6B51073"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Functions</header><text>The functions of the Office include the following:</text><paragraph id="HE2283CA6D07946E983F46CC46B646323"><enum>(1)</enum><text>To provide a central office for monitoring and encouraging the activities of the Veterans Health Administration with respect to the provision, evaluation, and improvement of health care services relating to falls prevention provided to veterans by the Department, with the goal of averting costly health care utilization while decreasing the incidence of falls.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H03DCCEB011B04B17A56BD47581FAE00D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>To develop and implement standards of care for the provision by the Department of health care services relating to falls prevention.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H193FA1EE4B8B46F8A9C3B4EC903A6E46"><enum>(3)</enum><text>To monitor and identify deficiencies in standards of care for the provision of health care services relating to falls prevention, to provide technical assistance to medical facilities of the Department, to provide technical assistance to programs of the Department that support veterans in their own homes, to address and remedy deficiencies of such facilities and programs, and to perform oversight of implementation of such standards of care.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD31777C1EA6B464FAB6F1CB353CCBA1C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>To monitor and identify deficiencies in standards of care for the provision of health care services relating to falls prevention through the community pursuant to this title and to provide recommendations to the appropriate office to address and remedy any deficiencies.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0635D3EE2D614B899544A02E623CCC81"><enum>(5)</enum><text>To oversee distribution of resources and information related to falls prevention for veterans under this title.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEDF8D2C09A994B01B238AB81205E4705"><enum>(6)</enum><text>To promote the expansion and improvement of clinical, research, and educational activities of the Veterans Health Administration with respect to health care services relating to falls prevention, including research activities on falls prevention conducted between the Office of Research and Development of the Department and the National Institute on Aging.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5E7BAAAE91794088BEB6B09BC28F4054"><enum>(7)</enum><text>To promote the development or expansion of rigorous quality assessment or improvement processes designed to prevent falls, including through coordination and collaboration with offices within the Department determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF75F566436A84D9D8947368A44653A63"><enum>(8)</enum><text>To coordinate home modification and adaptation programs administered by the Under Secretary for Benefits under chapter 21 of this title and the Under Secretary for Health under section 1717(a)(2) of this title.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA2163C97488E4088A759FCCC32FB0901"><enum>(9)</enum><text>To carry out such other duties as the Under Secretary for Health may require.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H97B00AA224D04FAD9F350CB6BA488242"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Public education campaign</header><text>The Chief Officer shall—</text><paragraph id="H0E41ADF7928345EDBECDF8A61EFB0F4C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>oversee and support a national education campaign that—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7034CB7B9CF842F491A152120C1E706D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is directed principally to veterans determined to be at risk for falls, their families, and their health care providers; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFF40A035182E405A9A7A1F8536D5FA77"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">focuses on—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H61E0864F9ADC4D7894822997C86FA1A4"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reducing falls, falls with major injury, and repeat falls for veterans receiving care under the laws administered by the Secretary; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H65816849889C4E54976B1828985BD881"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">increasing awareness of available benefits, grants, devices, or services provided by the Department that would aid veterans in reducing falls and preventing repeat falls; and</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE18A3AA1678A48FD9A05BC3FAD0F7EDD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>award grants or contracts to qualified organizations for the purpose of supporting local education campaigns focusing on reducing falls, falls with major injury, and repeat falls for veterans receiving care under the laws administered by the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H720F61F27EEC4734A8ADDBDF311CC587"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Research on falls prevention programs for veteran populations</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HE0CA3E567CBB44D0B3541676C64E436F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Chief Officer shall work with the Office of Research and Development of the Department and the National Institute on Aging to develop research for evidence-based falls prevention programs that will benefit veterans, including—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6C76388E46064120A3936FC550D29D95" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">programs that overlap with the priorities of the Department;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7EF97ED10419472594341554C60FD97F" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">programs that may focus on or be of particular benefit to veterans; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H744535021B1D49559051F54FB8E6A2F9" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">programs that may include participants with multiple comorbidities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAB6CDB55B166449D96FE62B9CB674C74" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The research required under paragraph (1) shall include the following:</text><subparagraph id="HAF3108FA4AC74F67BB214ABD43610979"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Research in supporting veterans with and without service-connected disabilities receiving home modification grants under section 1717 or 2101 of this title.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD7FE7004A40444B8B2388995084D81BB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Development of recommendations for falls prevention interventions for veterans with service-connected disabilities, including home modification interventions.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD3A0EC0C320D4C349A5441DC91A10436"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Research addressing medication management and polypharmacy as risk factors for falls prevention and developing recommendations for providers and electronic health records systems of the Department to monitor for veterans at risk of falls based on use of certain medications.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H88AA8C0266E247E6942D15EFB75169EC"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Research on improvements for safe patient handling and mobility among veterans, particularly in facilities (both medical and non-medical) that are not spinal cord injury centers.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H919847DA2B7D4B88A1739004C83E80B6" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H46D787728A264B1F98703FECF3F4E44E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary and the Director of the National Institute on Aging shall establish a joint subject matter expert panel to develop recommendations as required under paragraph (2)(B).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCE792111665749E69A536B0644821683" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The subject matter expert panel required under subparagraph (A) shall be comprised of eight members, of which—</text><clause id="HCCE6D170CE084C178D0CC98F3EABE963"><enum>(i)</enum><text>four shall be appointed by the Secretary; and</text></clause><clause id="HBBF579C8ADB64B6ABAB38639C0428C0D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>four shall be appointed by the Director of the National Institute on Aging.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC39D3F16DE7E4AB9A5C7218A6C9DE887"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Establishment of joint subject matter expert panel</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs and the Director of the National Institute on Aging shall establish the joint subject matter expert panel required under section 7310B(d)(3) of title 38, United States Code, as added by paragraph (1).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9F003A47743E48FB95E5C2425D6AF7CB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of such chapter is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 7310A the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H0215C2C2617D4C7F8429FECCB2EE012E"><toc><toc-entry level="section" idref="HA64268F3338E47E39F66CBCF68DB1E6B">7310B. Office of Falls Prevention.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8AC30BC8C2B2470387F400330973F9AB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Expansion of Interagency Coordinating Committee on Healthy Aging and Age-Friendly Communities</header><text>Section 203(c) of the Older Americans Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3013">42 U.S.C. 3013(c)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7DFA1A9829674CDAA839A7230BFAA46C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (2), by inserting <quote>the Secretary of Veterans Affairs,</quote> after <quote>the Commissioner of Social Security,</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H54EFB4CA8692490DB5D76D67230EDAF5"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (7), in the matter preceding subparagraph (A)—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H33984F367E98417DBEAFA1301C06161C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting <quote>the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives,</quote> after <quote>the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives,</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFCC8E54B67A2453AA0128F82FADFAC53" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting <quote>the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate,</quote> after <quote>the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate,</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEC38FAA2398D4609B764DCB55BB28C68"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Safe handling transfer techniques</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall issue or update directives of the Veterans Health Administration for facilities and providers relating to safe patient handling and mobility policies at the national, Veterans Integrated Service Network, and health-care system levels, which shall include the following:</text><paragraph id="HA3CA03F0D4D9466DA28AE607F3AA5AA1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Requiring biennial training for providers, including that all providers be trained in safe patient handling and use of mobility aids and mobility techniques.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H07BCA908A4DE4CCCBB4053426C070790"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Requiring that any medical facility where patients may need assistance with transfer or mobility have access to safe patient handling and mobility technology appropriate for the setting to enable safe transfer and mobilization for access to care and activities of daily living for veterans who are paralyzed or who need assistance with mobility.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6778BD8498FF49E2863FE03D70DC3086"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Requiring that all emergency settings have immediate access to safe patient handling and mobility technology to enable safe transfer, fall recovery, and repositioning.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFFA5CAA791F44C2A8C84065851C029C2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Pilot program on falls prevention interventions tied to residential adaptations and alterations</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE28B8468E3104E68B6650BFEBA035BD5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Determination</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall determine the feasibility and advisability of carrying out a pilot program to provide home improvements and structural alterations to prevent falls for all veterans eligible for those services under the laws administered by the Secretary.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H650C83184EFE48FEB035543700034856"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Plan</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7F932C825F314E8DBA97B25769D0494E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">indicating the plans of the Secretary to carry out a pilot program to provide home improvements and structural alterations to prevent falls for all veterans eligible for those services under the laws administered by the Secretary; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3C806AD363854E0ABC3AE78B695613F3"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">specifying why the Secretary determined under paragraph (1) that it is not feasible or advisable to carry out such a pilot program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H646759FD629A4DA085CC4D530F105BEE" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report on lessons learned</header><text>If the Secretary carries out the pilot program described in paragraph (1), not later than 180 days after the termination of the pilot program, the Chief Officer of Falls Prevention of the Department of Veterans Affairs established under section 7310B(a)(3)(A) of title 38, United States Code, as added by subsection (a)(1), shall submit to Congress a report on lessons learned from the pilot program and any recommendations on extending or expanding the pilot program.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1A7EA43F2E5B48359B0B6E5FFD06454E"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report on falls prevention initiatives</header><paragraph id="HDA5ED720B35746D88182CCF23E4CB6AB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than two years after the date of the enactment of this Act, or one year after the appointment of the Chief Officer of Falls Prevention of the Department of Veterans Affairs established under section 7310B(a)(3)(A) of title 38, United States Code, as added by subsection (a)(1), whichever occurs first, the Chief Officer, or the Under Secretary for Health of the Department of Veterans Affairs if a Chief Officer has not yet been appointed, shall submit to Congress a report on falls prevention initiatives within the Department.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7A20AC043F6846D1942429B0E6B421F3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report required by paragraph (1) shall evaluate, for the three-year period preceding the date of the enactment of this Act—</text><subparagraph id="H680150F45ABE4419B2692D4E1F04016A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>screening procedures at facilities of the Veterans Health Administration for risk of falls and the prevalence of resulting falls prevention interventions;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H98FDB178A720482699BF590C8F788C91"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the use by the Department of electronic health record documentation for risk of falls among veterans;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF2773DAFD3844FE7B45A7F89EF3C525B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the number of home modification grants provided under either the Home Improvements and Structural Alterations Program of the Department under section 1717 of title 38, United States Code, or the Specially Adapted Housing Program of the Department under section 2101 of such title;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H610C3B672D0341AD80FBCA31AFD94FC9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the extent to which grants provided under the programs specified under subparagraph (C) prevent falls among veterans and any recommendations with respect to such programs in the case of falls among veterans that were not prevented;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H274A1E2DB1724C8AA5CB6E60BAD71D68"><enum>(E)</enum><text>for veterans eligible for the Home Improvements and Structural Alterations Program of the Department under section 1717 of title 38, United States Code, pursuant to subsection (a)(2)(B) of such section, the number of home modification grants provided to each veteran in receipt of such a grant;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3AB6FF6301764B95920BACC52C46F7B6"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the types of providers that have conducted medical assessments leading to a recommendation for a home modification tied to medical necessity, and any recommendations for legislative or administrative action to expand the list of providers eligible to conduct medical assessments leading to a recommendation for a home modification;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7C6CD104AE484FD5BB1AA7E712E31A48"><enum>(G)</enum><text>home evaluation processes that are conducted in connection with awards made under the programs specified under subparagraph (C) and any recommendations for improving the evaluation and review process;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD8E4CEC34A9143B3A09E47715FD660EB"><enum>(H)</enum><text>reporting programs and software of the Department used to capture incidences of falls in care sites of the Veterans Health Administration and other veterans’ settings;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H36B80DD6AB954D498BF3F886EDDA202C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>limitations on uptake and use of current prevention, screening, and intervention programs designed to address falls prevention; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2CA6A0B99A8245E185DDF4AFD1AAD607"><enum>(J)</enum><text>recommendations for the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to work with the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, or other entities determined appropriate by the Secretary, to better capture data on falls by a veteran occurring in the home or in the community.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H5B35B65780164389AD1010AFA7B2A494"><enum>3.</enum><header>Establishment of falls assessment and fall prevention service requirements for veterans</header><subsection id="H818A4EFA7E9048F78E62876CA4B12605"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Required nursing home care</header><text>Section 1710A of title 38, United States Code, is amended by striking subsection (d) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF33E4D87944D4B138CCC5B4FBEB9E2D9"><subsection id="HC41825644517459B83F59238BCC65E94"><enum>(d)</enum><text>In the case of an individual determined by a physician to have fallen or to have been at risk of falling during the previous one-year period, the Secretary shall ensure that a licensed physical therapist or a licensed occupational therapist conducts a falls risk assessment for the individual and provides fall prevention services during the stay of the individual in the nursing home.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5BDBF0095BAE4CCEB0F771CF571D752C"><enum>(e)</enum><text>The provisions of subsection (a) shall terminate on September 30, 2028.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H32489F0BE5E3402ABA79D255D2B4BA1F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Extended care services</header><text>Section 1710B(a) of such title is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H770C95BDCDE4487CAA06E94D306AAE88"><paragraph id="H010FD2CE325749D4BACD5C5991B0EA8C"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The conduct of an annual falls risk assessment and the provision of fall prevention services by a licensed physical therapist or licensed occupational therapist.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

