<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HBA0D1FE3F654488B83F40EB8B3C04958" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 443 IH: Expressing support for the designation of May 2025 as “National Electrical Safety Month”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 443</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250523">May 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001326">Ms. Bynum</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="B001327">Mr. Bresnahan</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of May 2025 as <quote>National Electrical Safety Month</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas each year, electrical failure or malfunction accounts for thousands of home structure fires;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the safety and well-being of citizens is of utmost importance, and it is crucial to equip citizens with the necessary knowledge and understanding regarding potential electrical hazards in homes, schools, and the workplace;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas each year, fires caused by electrical failure or malfunction result in over 1,400 injuries, $1,300,000,000 in property damage, and nearly 500 deaths;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas each year, over 2,000 children are treated in hospital emergency rooms for electrical shock or burns caused by tampering with a wall outlet;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas citizens are encouraged to inspect their home and workplace for possible electrical hazards;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas citizens are advised to protect their homes and families with the latest safety technology, such as ground-fault circuit interrupters, arc-fault circuit interrupters, surge protective devices, and tamper-resistant receptacles;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas citizens are urged to install, test, and properly maintain an adequate number of smoke alarms in the home; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Electrical Safety Foundation is a nonprofit organization dedicated exclusively to promoting electrical safety in the home, school, and workplace through education, awareness, and advocacy: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H85E51BB4793F45FEA482935F98D3671E"> 
<section id="H4382D0A07235432496088247568C90F7" section-type="undesignated-section" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="H0129BA3BBC664C59AA494A22BCF20888"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">expresses support for the designation of <quote>National Electrical Safety Month</quote> to raise awareness of electrical hazards in homes, schools, and workplaces and actions citizens may take to protect against such hazards;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA3F843BDFBC341B1A056C3036B3E1906"><enum>(2)</enum><text>encourages all citizens to observe the importance of establishing and practicing electrical safety habits in the home, school, and workplace to reduce the number of electrically related fires, injuries, and deaths;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8856EE5433AD4F0981E2FF12E81165FC"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supports the efforts of the Electrical Safety Foundation to provide necessary and fundamental understanding of electrical hazards associated with emerging technologies; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H03CDE4EA53504C69BDBAAE2BF4310CD8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>requests that the President issue a proclamation calling upon citizens to observe the month with appropriate programs and activities.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

