<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H54D7B749782646DBB78CC0AE226F6A59" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 778 IH: Expressing support for the recognition of September 29, 2025, as “International Day of Awareness of Food Loss and Waste”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 778</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250930">September 30, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000598">Mr. LaLota</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the recognition of September 29, 2025, as <quote>International Day of Awareness of Food Loss and Waste</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas food waste results in the loss of more than $1,000,000,000,000 worth of food each year, representing nearly 40 percent of all the food that is produced globally;</text></whereas> <whereas> <text>Whereas, each year, 783,000,000 people are affected by hunger, and 150,000,000 children under the age of five experience stunted growth and development due to a chronic deficiency of essential nutrients in their diets, and better distribution of food could feed many of these people;</text>
        </whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas global food waste accounts for 8 to 10 percent of global greenhouse gas emissions (hereinafter referred to as <quote>GHG emissions</quote>);</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas food in landfills breaks down slowly and releases methane, a potent greenhouse gas with 86 times the global warming potential of carbon dioxide over a 20-year period, which causes the climate to warm faster than carbon dioxide alone;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas reducing methane emissions from food waste is one of the most effective ways to combat climate change in the short term;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas 1,050,000,000 tons of food were wasted across households, retail, and food services in 2022, of which 60 percent came from households, 28 percent came from food service, and 12 percent came from retail;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas reducing food loss and waste is a climate solution that the United States can use to lower GHG emissions and reduce food insecurity;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas halving food loss and waste by 2030 has the potential to reduce global agricultural GHG emissions by 4 percent and the number of undernourished people by 153,000,000;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the United States has committed to reducing 50 percent of food loss and waste by 2030, as stated in the strategy issued by the President titled the <quote>National Strategy for Reducing Food Loss and Waste and Recycling Organics</quote> (dated June 2024);</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the strategy outlines concrete goals for partners of the United States Government, retailers, and consumers to—</text> 
<paragraph id="HFBA532FE2D4F42E09D9EC135754B8BA3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>further prevent food loss and waste;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9ACCAA1B16D4461A9C2B32552B39B642"><enum>(2)</enum><text>enhance the recycling of food and other organic materials to promote a circular economy;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H440A97ABFC264BAC980048C4101C0A56"><enum>(3)</enum><text>reduce GHG emissions;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE295179E3A1A4C289E5BF4DF1C94CEEC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>save money for households and businesses; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2194740AFA2047319E210DA98B0BE15D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>create cleaner and healthier communities; and</text></paragraph></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas September 29, 2025, would be an appropriate day to establish as <quote>International Day of Awareness of Food Loss and Waste</quote>: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HE1B5279B250D48ACB6B90FF113947FBF"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HA151A7FD03BC4CF2A423E0F2D01D1C8F"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="H3F8467A3F0FE4916BADED5049B03EB88"><enum>(1)</enum><text>expresses support for the recognition of <quote>International Day of Awareness of Food Loss and Waste</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBAD11E166398490FAE4F1E1D21EC20B6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>acknowledges the importance of the implementation of food waste prevention methods.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

