<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-HEY25671-D3X-3W-SSG">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1867 IS: Closing the De Minimis Loophole Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>II</distribution-code>
        <congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session>1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. 1867</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action>
            <action-date date="20250522">May 22, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S316">Mr. Whitehouse</sponsor> (for himself and
                    <cosponsor name-id="S293">Mr. Graham</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill;
                which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title>To provide for phase-out of de minimis treatment under the Tariff Act of
            1930, and for other purposes.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H45020F87DCCB4188A292320DD13D33A0">
        <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="section-one" id="H533861D3F27443269AC7E40007CAC251">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Closing the De Minimis Loophole Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section id="H310522B924CA402482CD2DEF0E357883">
            <enum>2.</enum>
            <header>Elimination of de minimis treatment under the Tariff Act of 1930</header>
            <subsection id="H07B226BA002C4FC582B2ED0ADCBB280D">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 321(a)(2) of the Tariff Act of 1930 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1321">19 U.S.C. 1321(a)(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
                <paragraph id="HD7BC82E05E8B46C294EA6E66C399D357">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>, or</quote> and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H5AB090BE0F7840EB9B3B7220CC79BA9A">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>by striking subparagraph (C) and all that follows through <quote>subdivision (2); and</quote>.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9B680F27024645F38103750F4EC36279">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Delayed applicability date</header>
 <text>The amendments made by this section shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act and apply—</text>
                <paragraph id="HB977B32BC0E24FB882EB8D0AC9C014C9">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to articles originating in China, beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, except with respect to such articles that were loaded onto a vessel at the port of loading, or in transit on the final mode of transport prior to entry into the United States, during the 3-day period ending on such date of enactment; and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HEBB6EB36FF9D4FC69D36140294E11F8E">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to articles originating in any other country, to such articles entered, or withdrawn from warehouse for consumption, on or after the date that is 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H59BA1F7715644ADB85DB955A79965910">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Rulemaking required</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Pursuant to the authority under section 251 of the Revised Statutes (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/66">19 U.S.C. 66</external-xref>) and any other applicable provision of law, the Secretary of the Treasury shall, during the 120-day period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, carry out a rulemaking process to—</text>
                <paragraph id="H7E8ABD53F90547D8987B4D695123CFA6">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consistently implement the termination of privileges with respect to entry of articles that were authorized under section 321(a)(2)(C) of the Tariff Act of 1930 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1321">19 U.S.C. 1321(a)(2)(C)</external-xref>) before the date of the enactment of this Act, including with respect to entry procedures;</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H3AEAF0E67C5A4B83B0E19B34D93434E9">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure that data requirements and entry procedures for informal modes of entry are sufficient to ensure the effective enforcement of the laws of the United States and the efficient and accurate collection of duties, fees, and taxes, including by requiring entities making entry of an article under any of chapters 50 through 63 of the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States (HTS) to provide an identification of the HTS heading number or subheading number, including at the 10-digit level if applicable; and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H6BDCA11F0A604B9E959AA588B2463DA6">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>ensure that regulations and guidance establishing, implementing, and collecting penalties and liabilities associated with informal entry are sufficient to deter unlawful or fraudulent activity and to ensure the exercise of reasonable care in completing and providing accurate documentation.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H2D1ED04BC3A34750A3C39FD3B7474DC0">
                <enum>(d)</enum>
                <header>International postal agreements</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of shipments, the entry or release of which would have been made under section 321(a)(2)(C) of the Tariff Act of 1930 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1321">19 U.S.C. 1321(a)(2)(C)</external-xref>) before the date of the enactment of this Act, that are sent to the United States through the international postal network, the Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Postmaster General, shall determine appropriate fees and procedures to ensure, to the extent feasible, consistency between the treatment of shipments by the U.S. Postal Service and other shipments, and may prescribe such changes through regulation.</text>
            </subsection>
        </section>
    </legis-body>
</bill>

