<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6675045F8CC244A78C2D65915BCC40DF" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3681 IH: Leveraging Educational Opportunity Networks Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3681</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250603">June 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans of Pennsylvania</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="E000246">Mr. Edwards</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Labor to award grants to certain entities to establish workforce training programs.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA20BC43DABA14584A972A1B909F25012" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H02DDAB8294DF47C6B830E98BE510C86C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Leveraging Educational Opportunity Networks Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H7A3220B283FF406297EA927AE2D08B95"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> <paragraph id="HC122A2DFA31841818CF37FACA03955E9"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">About 60 percent of workers in the United States do not hold a 4-year college degree. These almost 70,000,000 workers in the United States without a bachelor’s degree have gained marketable skills through on-the-job training, boot camps, micro-credentialing programs, community colleges, and many other types of job training programs. Short-term workforce training programs have been growing in demand. Polling data finds that people in the United States are increasingly seeking education programs that are relevant for work and suited to their personal needs. Over the past 2 years, even as community college enrollment has dropped, boot camps, and online training programs are growing in size and market share.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H64C5F5A24DE3414A912FEB5AFC371F05"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Federal job training policy should focus on making more funding available to support high-quality sectoral training programs, including wraparound supports. Policymakers should prioritize options that boosts Federal funding for cohort-based sectoral training programs, including through the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act. Complementary models could include grant competitions that encourage cross-sector partnerships and support training investments for high priority roles (e.g. the Department of Commerce’s Good Jobs Challenge).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H85B80138F7C44617B1D740B81E2A6D3A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Further, the working poor are a pool of invisible talent and the source for a revitalized workforce to fill high-demand jobs in manufacturing, energy, health, technology, and science sectors of the economy. More than 32 percent of the United States labor force, or 51.9 million workers, currently make less than $15 an hour and 1.1 million workers earn wages at the prevailing Federal minimum wage ($7.25 an hour, or $14,137 a year).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1D79C5DF671A441F82109C39CD33137C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Using United States Census Bureau data, the Bureau of Labor Statistics determined that 6,300,000 workers were living at or below the official poverty level in 2020, which represented 4.1 percent of the total workforce (U.S. Department of Labor, September 2022) and 25 percent of working families can be considered working poor.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0616F64FD36D4531AA5BAF896B27AD6C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The United States is experiencing a long-term labor shortage, <quote>The Demographic Drought</quote>. As the size of the United States working age population shrinks, the country is experiencing record-low rates of labor participation, and it has the lowest birth rates in history.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB09AAE10261C49B5B6BE829164136E3A"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Economic growth is dependent on a reliable supply of skilled and ready to work employees. The economy is expected to add 12,000,000 jobs between 2020 and 2030. Science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (<quote>STEM</quote>) occupations will experience the highest growth rates. Occupations in the STEM field are expected to grow 8 percent by 2029, compared with 3.7 percent for all other occupations.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H94A3D4F27877407D8E299F7440E1C04D"><enum>(7)</enum><text>As of April 2023, there were 10,100,000 job openings and only 5,700,000 people looking for work (U.S. Department of Labor April 2023 Employment Report).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7F13FC23787E4687B21C397896B1B57A"><enum>(8)</enum><text>About 60 percent of workers do not have a bachelor’s degree, and about 45 percent of workers have a bachelor’s degree.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H58E36237A48242E5A9ED2E92061928BB"><enum>(9)</enum><text>More than 39 million people in the United States have attended some college but earned no degree.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD788E10A8D5344B5B647CB9B3118043C"><enum>(10)</enum><text>A 2015 evaluation by the Aspen Institute’s Economic Opportunities Program documented that poor, unemployed, and under employed students who earned an industry-recognized credential landed high skill entry level positions and earned 18 percent more in income than a similar group of people who did not receive this type of training.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3EC0873258DE40FA9B21759F5C7672F0"> <enum>(11)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">African American men face a range of challenges in the labor market which hinder their employment opportunities. African American men comprise about 13 percent of the male population, but 35 percent of those incarcerated. One in 3 African American men born today can expect to be incarcerated in his lifetime, compared to 1 in 6 Latino men and 1 in 17 White men. African American women are similarly affected where 1 in 18 African American women born in 2001 are likely to be incarcerated sometime in her life, compared to 1 in 111 white women. The effect of these realities is devastating and enduring, formerly incarcerated people are unemployed at a rate of over 27 percent which is higher than the total United States unemployment rate during any historical period, including the Great Depression.</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H55435C053250497AAFDC642173A8B5DC"><enum>(12)</enum><text>More must be done to break the cycle of generational poverty and reduce racial, economic, and social disparities in the United States.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H6F9AB359CBE94BA6B8CAACE20762C64A"><enum>3.</enum><header>Establishment of grant program</header> <subsection id="H099825039B0A4FAEB1825258199CD533"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grants authorized</header> <paragraph id="HB2931564A1D946F6BDBC34636A4AB122"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Labor shall award grants, on a competitive basis, to eligible entities to develop and implement workforce training programs.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6CCA6B6945AB448E80CB9995CFC87713"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Geographic diversity</header><text>To the maximum extent practicable, the Secretary shall ensure geographical diversity in selecting eligible entities to receive grants under subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H0208547BF7954AE9B48F1AA70F317762"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity is a consortium of the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HC95ABE78716D464E98642C8F351D6C11"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An organization described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">26 U.S.C. 501(c)(3)</external-xref>);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8EE5D08B23DE4729BA190C85966D28CF"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>A national training organization with dues paying affiliated members in at least 10 States;</text>
                </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3510537C2EAC480292ECC12C88D1EDC2" commented="no">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>An accredited institution, not including an institution of higher education (as defined in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/101">20 U.S.C. 101</external-xref>)); or</text>
                </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC1936BD66E224A61A32B82EA7194D752"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An institution that operates a post-secondary, career and technical network of accredited, dues paying institutions.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H032D94996095411981BF730E34B6BBFA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Uses of funds</header> <paragraph id="HDB1ADEC0F92D4376A95AF91F2E195502"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text>An eligible entity that receives a grant under this Act shall use such grant to—</text>
                    <subparagraph id="H8F665F8606A44A0CA7369F56546DFEB4">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>develop and implement a career and technical education program as described in subsection (d);</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="HA87A7F931852404F96B8C013FDB45EE7">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>offer a program to enrollees prior to the participation of such enrollees in a workforce training program that supports the enrollees in transitioning to a learning environment, which shall include—</text>
                        <clause id="H77B21AA872A243138D3AB51BED0F1483">
                            <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>opportunities to foster camaraderie among enrollees;</text> </clause> <clause id="H7754BAB633F645388F47854CA3975935"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>prepare enrollees for training success;</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="H53DE851F4576487FAD7F7A2EAAB20312">
                            <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>tutoring and employment readiness coaching; and</text> </clause> <clause id="HA079E7C417664344930B02AEA48F8D3F"> <enum>(iv)</enum> <text>cognitive behavioral techniques to support a change in the perception and thinking of enrollees;</text>
                        </clause>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H5099DC9DCF974C789F1DA602174A22B4">
                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>provide—</text> <clause id="HC3CFAB0F2E7647F5B6B137F0DF31B4AB"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>need-based stipends to enrollees in a workforce training program to assist enrollees in completing training programs;</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="H066779DDA1404E7D8D5F789DFCA8B36D">
                            <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>conflict resolution services and regular check-ins on a monthly basis to an employer that employs an enrollee who has completed a workforce training program offered by the eligible entity; and</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="H1C2217AD688442A9A5AFE5566DAA4070">
                            <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>supportive services to enrollees;</text> </clause> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1E4195CACA9F41BF995792870C016406" commented="no"> <enum>(D)</enum> <text>partner with an employer that—</text>
                        <clause id="H7B15270553304692A92B660461AB03B0" commented="no">
                            <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>pays a living wage;</text> </clause> <clause id="H7401CEAC37DA41A08446CFE1CFBADD05" commented="no"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>provides avenues for career growth and professional development to enrollees who complete a program of an eligible entity that the employer partnered with; and</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="H4C520E28242B464F826E7CFF276362FC" commented="no">
                            <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>engages in the career training process, including—</text> <subclause id="H51AA1A027ACF4429B9B424F512381FBD" commented="no"> <enum>(I)</enum> <text>serving on an industry advisory group;</text>
                            </subclause>
                            <subclause id="HAF50F28D6A0A4CB0A0452F33B2A97C23" commented="no">
                                <enum>(II)</enum>
 <text>assisting the eligible entity with establishing a career and technical education program as described in subsection (d);</text>
                            </subclause>
                            <subclause id="H20EE86404A15414194CF965A1BA2F675" commented="no">
                                <enum>(III)</enum>
 <text>sponsoring internships; and</text> </subclause> <subclause id="HBD084CEDF0824B0589DFE78BCB6D3316" commented="no"> <enum>(IV)</enum> <text>participating in mock interview hiring sessions and hiring fairs;</text>
                            </subclause>
                        </clause>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="HBD460F2655FF4AD1BC1748A07CABD913">
                        <enum>(E)</enum>
 <text>determine the qualifications and credentials required for employment by the employers identified in paragraph (4);</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H532B14780508409599475B51C8A68FFE">
                        <enum>(F)</enum>
 <text>assess and understand the demand of employers for employees in the local areas in which; </text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H01697FBABF8C47678BB27E02D84184A7">
                        <enum>(G)</enum>
 <text>identify employers that pay a living wage in the local areas in which an eligible entity operates a career and technical education program;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="HDE74DFD3137B458ABB761DA3B06351A8">
                        <enum>(H)</enum>
 <text>identify employers and industry sectors in which job growth is expected to occur;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H4A223F03B84144BD8E97F3BC663B2829">
                        <enum>(I)</enum>
 <text>produce—</text> <clause id="H7461DFF13FF5487D83A73D4795A22BBB"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>an analysis of existing and emerging in-demand industry sectors and occupations and the employment needs of employers in such industry sectors; and</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="H8760ADD8BF164BAE9118355FC7DA17FA">
                            <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>an analysis of the knowledge and skills needed to meet the employment needs of the employers in the States in which the entity operates a career and technical education program; and</text>
                        </clause>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H345F14A0751642CA93D7F5C8A814806C">
                        <enum>(J)</enum>
 <text>implement strategies to recruit individuals into the workforce training program and assess prospective enrollees.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H696E2F5D752E4F3288C42E59A91D8608"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Required allocation of funds</header><text>An eligible entity that receives a grant under this Act shall use at least 70 percent of such grant for the uses of funds described in subparagraphs (A) and (C)(i).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H48EBC907045848C5AF89C6F47F56B667"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Career and technical education program</header><text>A career and technical education program developed and implemented under this Act shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="HF9B08D96723F4966B0B2879DA086AC68"><enum>(1)</enum><text>be developed to meet the in-demand needs of employers in the local area in which such program is being implemented;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA35F974FDC104733B67DD219B973837C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>pay enrollees a living wage;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2B6C88B5A7D14432B5D743608BEE0CAE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>be at least 12 weeks in duration;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBE580E7B1711472095A394410509AD4F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>upon an enrollee completing such a program, result in the enrollee earning a recognized post-secondary credential;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2115D77017B946BAA03619B1936197B3"><enum>(5)</enum><text>operate in at least 10 States;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCB541594847F4516A899478507D501CA"> <enum>(6)</enum> <text>prioritize enrollees who read at no higher than the 6th grade reading level; and</text>
                </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7D7CC642D25747359035DE9834F917B1" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><text>ensure that at least 50 percent of the individuals enrolled the program are—</text> <subparagraph id="H77FEE1DA1EBB4FDBAD4EB869E459EDF4"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>offenders (as defined in section 3(38) of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3102">29 U.S.C. 3102(3)(38)</external-xref>));</text>
                    </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBEEA2499ED1844F59644E1D4EC7981FA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>low-income and economically isolated individuals (including individuals who are from rural, urban, and historically disadvantaged communities); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H252F26294E284283B01819A3F39C900F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>from populations that have been underserved or adversely affected by persistent poverty or inequality.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA19333FE56644953B46DC02457A725A1"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Application</header> 
<paragraph id="H7188BD682759434AA25DE198F52AFB48"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under this Act, an eligible entity shall submit an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H20A0C20D0C3440F3B1E389FE1BD8C7D8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>The Secretary shall prioritize eligible entities that propose to carry out a workforce training program in the following industries:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H2BAA63E9D87F43F88735CB9AF1742569"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Construction.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2DEDAC75A9F04E71A478DF572154321B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Disaster relief and recovery services.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4C5617B055B44FD4927C35ADAD4F46BA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Industrial manufacturing.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBD77AEDCC7C54C73AEBF6225B2D4C92F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Food manufacturing.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7424B0A7A9F24953BD635AC6CEB0868A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Supply chain management and services.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H272954A6080C4CCAACC9EE7668354D7E"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Information technology.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7D3A6DA8AFD8476F966A9AC50EE78AF8"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Financial services.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF2EC9D3092214AD59C3A7CE18C66285B"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Ship building and other defense-related industries.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE76921C9B3A4446297943E8296AE59A7"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Health care.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H6F69BFB84EA04D11A8E24EE850A48C1B"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after and eligible entity receives a grant under this Act, and on an annual basis thereafter, each eligible entity shall submit to the Secretary of Labor a report on the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H1C6C9B585D594B05B79E390E55E9DF9B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The earnings of each enrollee—</text> <subparagraph id="H5E711CC233D9475BABFA8B5E638676A8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>prior to entering into a career and technical education program operated by such eligible entity; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB11F7906E0314DEC829C16F440117D65"><enum>(B)</enum><text>6 months after completing such program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7EEDB56EBF334A52B3A62F11C340CE99"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The percentage of program participants who are in unsubsidized employment—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H88D229F08E1F449AA73D31526DC017C3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>after 30 days and prior to 90 days after exit from such program; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF1C6F3F6EB904E6392590E599091211D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>after 280 days and prior to 365 days after exit from such program;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H72FF9A964D3A482D9BC9FB4613F0BDA0"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The starting wages of the program participants described in paragraph (2)(A); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEFAE1B87191A4E9FB242AF2B4D0EFC2A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The percentage of program participants who obtain a recognized postsecondary credential during participation in, or within 1 year after exit from, the program.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H020AEECE94CA41CB80F71906907A8DEC"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H9710EEC5881E411FA97A614D61F73615"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Career and technical education</header><text>The term <term>career and technical education</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3(5) of the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/2302">20 U.S.C. 2302</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H75094A8E7737459B9977CB6D68A38784"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Living wage</header><text>The term <term>living wage</term> means a wage that one full-time worker earns that covers the cost of the minimum basic needs of the worker and the family of the worker for the area in which such worker lives.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA04D3836A0714CE9B362B3EE1D4988AA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Supportive services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>supportive services</term> means services such as transportation, child care, dependent care, housing, and needs-related payments, that are necessary to enable an individual to participate in a career and technical education program carried out under this Act.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2E79959626DC43548D9926931045A592" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>WIOA terms</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <term>local area</term> and <term>recognized postsecondary credential</term> have the meanings given the terms in section 3 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3102">29 U.S.C. 3102</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H63566879E15A48BE9241B5D065211310"><enum>4.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">To carry out this Act, there is authorized to be appropriated $30,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2026 through 2029.</text></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

