<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="HE38B5CCFA81F430E9C09432E781CB3B5" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3425 RH: POST Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 196</calendar><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3425</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 119–239]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250515">May 15, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000403">Mr. Kennedy of Utah</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250908">September 8, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsor: <cosponsor name-id="F000481">Mr. Figures</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250908">September 8, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on May 15, 2025</action-instruction><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Director of the Federal Protective Service to establish processes to strengthen oversight, performance, and accountability of contract security personnel engaged in the protection of certain buildings and grounds, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HPW00" reported-display-style="italic" id="H01F7521CEE084BA2AD62369E542E4F79"><section id="H22156487BDA642138EB9F328760503BE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Personnel Oversight and Shift Tracking Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote>POST Act of 2025</quote>. </text></section><section id="H12B9175A2EE64CDC8BFF4A12CB8A6E1D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Improved data collection and performance accountability</header><subsection id="H527C1F27CF0743D0B9FD1A1E0868A98F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director of the Federal Protective Service shall establish processes to strengthen oversight, performance, and accountability of contract security personnel engaged in the protection of buildings and grounds that are owned, occupied, or secured by the General Services Administration Public Buildings Service.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2B93805CCBFD4527A5C65767D8ECDBDE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Oversight of contract security personnel</header><text>In carrying out the activities described in subsection (a), the Director shall—</text><paragraph id="H2106E13E160C435FA672C85A3DDF3F72"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establish standards for the collection, maintenance, and analysis of covert testing data, including the creation of a comprehensive and uniform method for documenting test outcomes, identifying root causes of failures, and categorizing types of vulnerabilities detected;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6317C07C93C74940B7C51344C0880B36"><enum>(2)</enum><text>begin conducting quarterly analytical reviews of covert testing data to identify trends, recurring deficiencies, and opportunities for operational improvement across all covered facilities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1372B8AC3E6D40E28130E44FDEB09FB2"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">direct the security contractor who is providing security services to the Federal Protective Service to establish a mandatory, cause-specific corrective training and performance improvement plan for any contract security personnel who fail a covert test and review the security contractor’s performance improvement plan to ensure that the security contractor has and will provide appropriate training and procedures to avoid any future covert testing failures; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8340A6A4D2CA4899AF568B4235C25F6C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>develop updated security training guidance for contract security personnel to reflect findings from covert testing data, emerging threats, and best practices.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H139B3F376A884838B6BE4D418E5E0FB2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text>Upon completion of the activities described in subsection (b), and annually thereafter, the Director shall submit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate an report on the implementation of the requirements of this section, including any identified challenges and recommendations for additional legislative action.</text></subsection></section><section id="H3F845D0640DA47AC81B6BC1C51BAD642"><enum>3.</enum><header>Personnel shift management and system modernization</header><subsection id="H32989CF47F9E47D691F4F0C776608139"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Evaluation of the personnel tracking system</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director of the Federal Protective Service shall—</text><paragraph id="HCBB9696287B547358613E4FEEB3E356A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct a comprehensive evaluation of the personnel tracking system used to manage and monitor the deployment availability of contract security personnel;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAE7F512988754037B326557FCE0EAD37"><enum>(2)</enum><text>determine whether to replace the system described in paragraph (1) with a more reliable personnel tracking platform, including private sector solutions, or whether to implement corrective actions to improve the system described in paragraph (1), including technical, operational, or administrative fixes; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA7C2181344A740B59047BE6CED1AD123"><enum>(3)</enum><text>develop and publish an implementation plan that includes—</text><subparagraph id="HCF2B65DB901443C5A16BFDE83EBC2E6D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a timeline for completion of system replacement or corrective actions; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDAAA23F875364D168DC24E171D46914E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>procedures to ensure timely and accurate communication to building tenants regarding contract security personnel shortages or absences or security coverage gaps.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEFB8E4943B6A4C6FB4755F5155DD2879"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter for 3 years, the Director shall submit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a report that includes—</text><paragraph id="HFBFA3BD1BD1F4CCAB024EF3A63E188DB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the determination made under subsection (a)(2);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2D5DF1796A0C46ED9A5A46DC720B1594"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a detailed summary of any implementation actions undertaken pursuant to subsection (a);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H02143968F4A4437999A94AA8C736BECC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an evaluation of the effectiveness of tenant communication protocols; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5060BA6ABF0C4D31A7A4B86437E22C3A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>any recommendations for additional legislative or administrative actions.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H1502225EFF6C4815A90DA0BC9966C4FF"><enum>4.</enum><header>Savings clause</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed as designating an employee of a contractor of the Department of Homeland Security who is engaged in the protection of Federal property pursuant to section 1315 of title 40, United States Code, as a Federal employee.</text></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date date="20250908">September 8, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

