<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MCC25465-HLD-G6-3VY"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1403 IS: Bring the Space Shuttle Home Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1403</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250410">April 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S287">Mr. Cornyn</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S355">Mr. Cruz</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSRA00">Committee on Rules and Administration</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Discovery space shuttle to be transferred from the Smithsonian Institution to NASA's Johnson Space Center in Houston, Texas.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Bring the Space Shuttle Home Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id473678cecfa94068a7705782408f6f87"><enum>2.</enum><header>Transfer of Discovery space shuttle to Johnson Space Center in Houston, Texas</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id292bd788271a47fd84465a8a6edf64fb"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, under the direction of the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (referred to in this Act as the <quote>Administrator</quote>), the Discovery space shuttle shall be transferred from the Smithsonian Institution's Steven F. Udvar Hazy Center of the National Air and Space Museum, near Washington, DC, to the National Aeronautics and Space Administration's Johnson Space Center in Houston, Texas.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb99dad7328ec4c598814bddcacc29dc4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Plan</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf1fc4a54948d4ad59f29d5ccbb1bb297"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator and the Smithsonian Institution shall jointly develop a plan to transfer the Discovery space shuttle under subsection (a), which shall include an estimated timeline and cost estimate for such transfer.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7aacc59001ef47ad98b33e87deba1837"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Submission to Congress</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator and the Smithsonian Institution shall submit to Congress the plan developed under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd7dcea9bb41848f99055d7157225ede9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Transfer of title to NASA</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date on which the Discovery space shuttle is transferred under subsection (a), the Smithsonian Institution shall transfer the title to the shuttle to the National Aeronautics and Space Administration.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5eae49e45c4445599de55bd70dda5b2d"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Public exhibition</header><text>On the transfer of the Discovery space shuttle under subsection (a)—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id65c1f159abd940efb61272afcede8b02"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"> the shuttle shall be placed on public exhibition to advance science, technology, engineering, and mathematics learning at a location not more than 5 miles from the Johnson Space Center; and </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb9bfa36ba9bc413a9f5112caa3aa07aa"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Johnson Space Center shall be responsible for oversight of the shuttle until the date on which the shuttle is transferred to a nonprofit entity under subsection (e). </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7cf996898a94443492d9172ad42dda28"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Role of nonprofit entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On any date after the transfer of title under subsection (c), the Administrator shall transfer the title to the Discovery space shuttle to a nonprofit entity designated by the Administrator, on the condition that the nonprofit entity shall maintain the shuttle on public exhibition to advance science, technology, engineering, and mathematics learning in a location not more than 5 miles from the Johnson Space Center. </text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id56b6425aa5534e8e9f8d8f6f84c62e4c"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Administrator such sums as may be necessary to carry out this section, which shall be in addition to any amounts authorized to be appropriated by any other Act, and may be requested by the President as supplemental requirements, if needed, in the appropriate fiscal years. </text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

