<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB8E0AE67D5BB40C3A2B1D4C25885A731" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2164 IH: Dayton National Cemetery Expansion Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2164</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250314">March 14, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000463">Mr. Turner of Ohio</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to enter into an agreement with the Montgomery County Land Bank for the transfer of certain land near Dayton National Cemetery to the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE5AFA3B7242440ABB5BAE5C6960384CB" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H049AF23925914B3CB4A2315A7A2ED586" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Dayton National Cemetery Expansion Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H9CBEF20F882A4D59B0B87E1B963A8B87"><enum>2.</enum><header>Authorization of transfer of certain land near Dayton National Cemetery to Department of Veterans Affairs</header> <subsection id="HD45E9C13637F4B4982611F795D037014"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Transfer</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date on which the Montgomery County Land Bank makes an offer to transfer to the Department of Veterans Affairs the parcel of land described in subsection (b), the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall begin the process of entering into an agreement with the Land Bank to carry out such transfer. Under any such agreement—</text>
<paragraph id="H64B680F3074A424CADD2DBFA6662D5FA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Land Bank shall agree to transfer to the Department all right, title, and interest in such parcel at no cost of the land to the Department and for no consideration; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBCCA75E35E54441F9AEF89A348EB77A0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Secretary shall agree to accept such transfer—</text>
<subparagraph id="HC9FD849A1D504C41BAF253E87F01A914"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in order to use such parcel as a national cemetery; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8354D6EECE514392B5F5B087515C9676"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not later than three years after the date on which the Land Bank offers to transfer the parcel.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HFE9BBAEF8362456BA485E4E27AE61256"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Parcel described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The parcel of land described in this subsection is the approximately 58 acres of land located in Dayton, Ohio, across from Dayton National Cemetery, bound by the intersection of McCall St. and South Gettysburg Avenue, the intersection of McCall Street and Resaca Avenue, the intersection of South Gettysburg Avenue and U.S. Route 35 of the Interstate Highway System, and depicted on the map titled <quote>Dayton National Cemetery Proposed Land Transfer</quote> and dated January 26, 2024, and labeled on the map as <quote>Expansion Area</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HFFEC14A16FBE4FF997F2EC030EAE7A3C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rules of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to—</text>
<paragraph id="H2FCFF9AB7ABF4518968446C0B744F823"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">require or encourage the Secretary to acquire any parcel other than the parcel described in subsection (b); or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2522133355274928A851A339FE5DC86D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>require or encourage the Secretary to enter into any special agreement with an entity other than the Montgomery County Land Bank.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HBB980D940CFC4E4D879835271EC4D1CF"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Montgomery County Land Bank defined</header><text>In this section, the Montgomery County Land Bank means the land bank located at 130 W. Second Street, Suite 1425, Dayton, Ohio 45402.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

