<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-RIL25934-CFY-KH-XWR"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 371 IS: Honoring the victims and survivors of the mass shooting at the Annunciation Catholic Church and School in Minneapolis, Minnesota.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 371</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250902">September 2, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S394">Ms. Smith</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Honoring the victims and survivors of the mass shooting at the Annunciation Catholic Church and School in Minneapolis, Minnesota.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, on August 27, 2025, congregants gathered at the Annunciation Catholic Church in Minneapolis, Minnesota, for a mass to welcome back students for their first week of school;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas their sense of peace was shattered when a shooter opened fire while they were in prayer, killing 2 children and injuring 21 others;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas first responders, including members of the Minneapolis Police Department, emergency medical teams, hospital staff, and Federal law enforcement officers, community members, and volunteers responded with courage and compassion; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Annunciation Catholic Church and School community, local schools, families, and neighbors have shown strength and resilience in the face of this tragedy: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="idab79862383294de6a0bab441aeb43c8d"><enum>(1)</enum><text>condemns this senseless act of violence and offers its condolences to the families and loved ones of those killed and injured in the tragedy;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id00262dc8f0dd442bb6d595633d665a05"><enum>(2)</enum><text>honors the memory of the victims and stands in solidarity with survivors, the Catholic community, and the broader Minneapolis community;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id628a0b034c7e48c18415e3f40e3546a0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>commends the bravery and service of law enforcement, first responders, school and church staff, and community members who acted swiftly to protect and help others;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id228c01a0d2b84ec985f8f358c65ae4b7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>stands with the Annunciation Catholic Church and School community and all Minnesotans in the face of this terrible tragedy;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfad5cd932b004d2fa32924235c6a01d9"><enum>(5)</enum><text>expresses hope that the Annunciation community, together with other communities scarred by gun violence across the country, will heal through unity, compassion, and shared faith;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1b10fd4529df4007a659b589873a795b"><enum>(6)</enum><text>declares that there is no place for violence in our communities, and that everyone deserves to feel safe in their sacred places of worship and schools; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4c2c884908664ff8a125390b2d14be91"><enum>(7)</enum><text>expresses solidarity with all faith communities and schools that have been scarred by such violence.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

