<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H80389889E27A416A8119A6126CE94EF3" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 234 IH: Expressing support for the designation of “Zoroastrian Legacy and Heritage Month”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 234</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250321">March 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001110">Mr. Correa</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of <quote>Zoroastrian Legacy and Heritage Month</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Zoroastrianism is regarded as one of the world’s oldest monotheistic religions, originating in ancient Persia, and includes significant contributions to history and civilization, that has greatly influenced the development of global freedom, democracy, trade, and commerce;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Cyrus the Great, a follower of Zoroastrianism and mentioned in the Old Bible 23 times, recorded the first declaration of human rights on the famous Cyrus Cylinder in 539 B.C.E., emphasizing freedom of religion, equality, cultural and civil rights, and abolishment of slavery;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the last month of the original Zoroastrian Calendar in March, is devoted to Mother Earth, signifying equality, devotion to nature, humility, love, peace, and harmony for all humankind;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the spring festival of Nowruz, also referred to as <quote>Novruz</quote>, the day of the vernal equinox in March, is the most auspicious day in the Zoroastrian calendar and signifies the triumph of light, warmth, and life over darkness;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Zoroastrians are enjoined to preserve and protect the divine creations of earth, air, water, vegetation, cattle, and humans;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the first seven days of Spring in March are considered very auspicious for nature in the Zoroastrian calendar but traditionally celebrated till the thirteenth day after Nowruz;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Zoroastrian Legacy has also significantly benefited humankind throughout History in commerce, international trade, art, and culture; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas March will be commemorated as Zoroastrian Legacy and Heritage Month: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HFF85A355ED88416D9AE20E2E8C6AFBF4"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H116FE2076D234C8CBFF8ACDE69B33E3A"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives supports the designation of <quote>Zoroastrian Legacy and Heritage Month</quote>.</text></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

