<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6BF86943348C4A7EA7CCD7CCA24085A5" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5593 IH: To amend title 38, United States Code, to include eyeglass lens fittings in the category of medical services authorized to be furnished to veterans under the Veterans Community Care Program, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5593</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250926">September 26, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001228">Ms. Maloy</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="V000135">Mr. Van Orden</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to include eyeglass lens fittings in the category of medical services authorized to be furnished to veterans under the Veterans Community Care Program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H41B5D0F602A44A2592D09453C06BB016" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H003B5F7AEAB8468DA210E86F64346469" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Inclusion of eyeglass lens fittings in medical services authorized to be furnished under Veterans Community Care Program; report</header> 
<subsection id="HEC7368294E054E16969982F3FC98E81A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subparagraph (C) of paragraph (6) of section 1701 of title 38, United States Code, is amended by inserting <quote>services, fittings for eyeglass lenses,</quote> after <quote>Optometric</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H399ABF446D1C45659E03FABDABB5E320"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall establish policies and procedures and prescribe regulations to carry out the amendment made by subsection (a). Under such regulations, the Secretary shall ensure that a veteran eligible to receive medical services from a non-Department of Veterans Affairs provider under section 1703 of title 38, United States Code, can schedule an appointment for a fitting for eyeglass lenses at such a provider in geographic proximity to the veteran.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA5E1F12030234AA28EE6C4DD9AADFB53"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report that includes—</text> <paragraph id="HDA71D1B71F9344DDA54AEF2B124691D7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a statement of the status of the implementation of the amendment made by subsection (a);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H34B5DD0D3BA447BC839F43282592F9DF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a summary of any challenges faced with respect to such implementation;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF850E1DC5DFA4E4ABFEEC419F20A7B08"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a strategy to mitigate such challenges, if applicable; and </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD39A0636571C45908595528EA90D922D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>an assessment of the benefits for veterans resulting from such amendment.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

