<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-CAN25608-91X-LN-R4W"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2025 IS: CMV–22 Reliability and Readiness Enhancement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2025</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250611">June 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S355">Mr. Cruz</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S287">Mr. Cornyn</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To authorize the Secretary of the Navy to integrate nacelle improvement modifications into the CMV–22 aircraft fleet to improve readiness and reliability and sustain the tiltrotor industrial base, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>CMV–22 Reliability and Readiness Enhancement Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id0d5b3907c10f49b2af160b6e63973d7f"><enum>2.</enum><header>Integration of nacelle improvement modifications into CMV–22 aircraft fleet</header><subsection id="id4898260076174ba8978cd1deb8957a66"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority</header><text>The Secretary of the Navy may integrate nacelle improvement modifications into the CMV–22 aircraft fleet to enhance operational readiness, reduce maintenance burdens, and support contested logistics operations.</text></subsection><subsection id="idc67a5b770717403e8eeea219a35828a7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Implementation objectives</header><text>In carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary of the Navy shall seek to—</text><paragraph id="id1a23f2c5bc344849b0399deac0bd208f"><enum>(1)</enum><text>reduce aircraft downtime and increase reliability through structural, wiring, and systems improvements;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5bce87407513421c98c2c5b8c6e11c06"><enum>(2)</enum><text>incorporate lessons learned and performance data from the Air Force’s nacelle improvement modernization effort for CV–22 aircraft;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida1460150335240b4879a9badb8ad3996"><enum>(3)</enum><text>ensure operational availability of CMV–22 aircraft platforms in support of distributed maritime operations in the Indo-Pacific region; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5eeb51d09df842af8882591f76c60b2c"><enum>(4)</enum><text>sustain the specialized tiltrotor industrial workforce and supplier base during the transition from V–22 aircraft to future long range assault aircraft production.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ida4965781aafa4e1b89c5946a6498f84f"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary of the Navy shall prioritize nacelle improvement modifications for CMV–22 aircraft produced or maintained in fiscal years 2025 and 2026.</text></subsection><subsection id="idb8295dd713bb4e8fa4f70146c373d73b"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Industrial base considerations</header><text>In carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary of the Navy shall coordinate with relevant defense industrial base stakeholders to preserve workforce capacity, maintain supply chain continuity, and minimize production gaps.</text></subsection><subsection id="id6fb70d07d3534918ba52fad11c52c726"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Use of existing funds and authorities</header><text>The Secretary of the Navy shall carry out this section using funds and authorities otherwise available to the Secretary.</text></subsection></section><section id="ide4cb3fb98a1647c0bafef2a0057366f5"><enum>3.</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Navy shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report on—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc9c7ff383e2d4e04a2001fd01c7a329d"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the status and scope of nacelle improvement modifications implemented for CMV–22 aircraft;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id515c30e2c2bf40a39b5130331bb33dd6"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">readiness and performance metrics compared to pre-modification benchmarks;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id67ee1d85dc6149a0b328f923aeacbbc3"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">impacts to the industrial base and workforce; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaee9e7c516dd41da8df5cc3c10f439cb"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommendations regarding further sustainment, procurement, or legislative authority needed for fleet-wide implementation.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>

