<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDE19A99EAEA4432CBC1108DA57685D56" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3701 IH: Family Vaccine Protection Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3701</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250604">June 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000034">Mr. Pallone</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S001216">Ms. Schrier</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Public Health Service Act to codify the Advisory Committee on Immunization Practices, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF9122508277F4F1880F6DEE3A7BE23A8" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H39966AEB49E641FD81F06CA149BDFE6B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Family Vaccine Protection Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section>
<section id="HC401F050E2B049F794DD6CD58EBCDEA5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Codification of Advisory Committee on Immunization Practices</header> 
<subsection id="H63E416732B1649F48FA6A6C0D62B1CC7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title II of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/202">42 U.S.C. 202 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 222 (42 U.S.C. 2l7a) the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HA9C31A7EEEA34709963D79E342CC0F78" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <section id="H9936E6F0048840CE8455DAA1C5273588"><enum>222A.</enum><header>Advisory Committee on Immunization Practices</header> <subsection id="HE9CE4FAED8D84A059CBEDE931843D1E5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Advisory Committee on Immunization Practices established pursuant to section 222 (referred to in this section as the <quote>Advisory Committee</quote>) shall carry out the duties specified in this section.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="HC9B154AC191F4C7EA1A360EBCAF406A4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/10">chapter 10</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code</header><text>The provisions of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/10">chapter 10</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code (other than section 1013), shall apply with respect to the Advisory Committee.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H466D18186C674B739913AC8691B871B3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Advice, guidance, and recommendations from Advisory Committee</header> <paragraph id="H6068A493E27C4709BAE8BA3168A5421A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Advisory Committee shall, based on a preponderance of the best available, peer-reviewed scientific evidence, provide advice and guidance, and make recommendations, to the Director regarding the use of vaccines and related agents licensed under section 351 for effective control of vaccine-preventable diseases in the civilian population of the United States.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6C1C4DE1F47E4EFE94C9E84CECCAC8E4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Procedure for publication</header> 
<subparagraph id="H710C9E435B6440BE93869681625EFB23">
                                    <enum>(A)</enum>
                                    <header>In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall review any recommendations received under paragraph (1). The Director shall adopt any such recommendation unless the Director determines such recommendation is not supported by a preponderance of the best available, peer-reviewed scientific evidence and publishes the results of that review.</text>
                                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9A00B922190149DCB351B4F312998D0D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Adopted</header><text>If the Director adopts such a recommendation—</text> <clause id="H32D93A9B43F549CA9C3A2E3CE951ABFA"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such recommendation shall be considered as an official recommendation of the Secretary, acting through the Director, upon such adoption; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H064C5BAB84AB44FCAE633FFAA106C59D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Director shall—</text> <subclause id="H163AFA7FC420481F89D856B99525D048"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">publish such recommendation on the public website of the Department of Health and Human Services; and</text> </subclause> 
<subclause id="HE06ECC542C0941AFA82E9FE659696688"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">inform the Secretary and the Assistant Secretary for Health, in writing, of such recommendation.</text></subclause> </clause> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC4853FFCDE41405583C373B7685643BE"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Not adopted</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Director does not adopt such a recommendation, the Director shall—</text> 
<clause id="HB812721807414AB88BE1F097849EF12C"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">publish the basis for not adopting such recommendation, including an explanation on why the Director found that the recommendation does not support the findings of a preponderance of the best available, peer-reviewed scientific evidence; and</text></clause> <clause id="HA62DD58DFE6240F3BAA2C8035DF9690E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 48 hours after such determination, submit a notification to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate containing the information described in clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3FA9C2F64D9B4A0AB9B6D37D8FAD5343"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Consideration of new vaccines</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon the licensure of any vaccine or any new indication for a vaccine under section 351, the Advisory Committee shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HB256D278AE5A460B843E9D22E2E5AC90"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consider the use of the vaccine not later than its next regularly scheduled meeting;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9328D17AFA46459AABAB0F95CE7E9B10"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 90 days after receiving a notification in writing from the holder of the license of the vaccine or new indication for a vaccine under section 351, make a recommendation with respect to the use of such vaccine under paragraph (1); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB22378A803254F0AB28AA4CB7EA338DB"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submit to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate an update on the status of the Advisory Committee’s consideration of the use of the vaccine.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H39F5C4D2D6A649AE9169F34C77EFFB25"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Consideration for breakthrough therapies and for potential use during public health emergency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Advisory Committee shall make recommendations under paragraph (1) with respect to the use of vaccines that—</text> <subparagraph id="HB262CCF7719441A4B87AC896766EF675"><enum>(A)</enum><text>are designated as a breakthrough therapy under section 506 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act and licensed under section 351 of this Act; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE68236E79B9346DBA7D0BDBCE712ECB7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>are intended to address a public health emergency as determined by the Secretary under section 319.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1B961431424A4E5697A0E513766A2E42"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary or the Director takes an action regarding the use of vaccines and related agents licensed under section 351 for effective control of vaccine-preventable diseases in the civilian population of the United States (including an action with respect to coverage under section 2713 or the listing of vaccines for purposes of the program under section 1928 of the Social Security Act) that is contrary to a recommendation of the Advisory Committee, the Secretary or the Director (as applicable) shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H60C8E87C34004458BD649EC25738FF01"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">publish the basis for the action, including an explanation on why the Secretary or the Director (as applicable) found that the action supports the findings of a preponderance of the best available, peer-reviewed scientific evidence; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7D09CDFD40D4421D9EE6AE013705A6B0"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 48 hours after taking such action, the Secretary or the Director (as applicable) shall submit a notification to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate containing the information described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF8BA3F7B526641F6AB2C10258501FFAE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Duties</header> 
<paragraph id="H75578EE5241341D39DC6DE8EAAF2DB56"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header> 
<subparagraph id="H101C8000C73D40C082A92B9C0F9C2E8D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Advisory Committee shall do the following:</text> <clause id="HE40FB454D40843E09F5786690DC72601"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Provide advice and guidance, and make recommendations, to the Director as specified in subsection (c)(1).</text></clause> 
<clause id="HAB1EEB8973A94750B48154E0A989BC42"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Make immunization recommendations for purposes of the requirement under section 2713 for group health plans and health insurance issuers offering group or individual health insurance coverage to provide coverage for immunizations that have in effect a recommendation from the Advisory Committee.</text></clause> <clause id="H0D8641EF6B3D4296B265A8AC8F4A904B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In accordance with section 1928 of the Social Security Act and this section, establish and periodically review and, as appropriate, revise the list of vaccines for administration to children and adolescents eligible to receive vaccines through the Vaccines for Children Program, along with schedules regarding the appropriate dose and dosing interval, and contraindications to administration of the pediatric vaccines.</text> </clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H295D8D26403A423FB3293D9DBE78D57C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Use of list</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, and as delegated, the Director, shall use the list established by the Advisory Committee for the purpose of the purchase, delivery, and administration of pediatric vaccines in the Vaccines for Children Program under section 1928 of the Social Security Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE70F87DE3F4143C991B80BC238A1E30A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Advice and guidance content</header><text>Advice and guidance provided under paragraph (1)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H9191355CB87E43CBBA97978F86379706"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall address—</text> <clause id="H477E3C5046EF43879D1C3C4BF861D6BC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the general use of vaccines and immune globulin preparations as a class of biologic agents;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H308327D7D97E4A43809B8871511D1BD9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the use of specific antibody products for prevention of infectious diseases; and</text></clause> <clause id="H5F348CBDBB2A4094877D0C68A43F9B21"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>special situations or populations that may warrant modification of the routine recommendations for vaccine use;</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD44F3C21D1984FEEAC0B8203BFA03F44"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may include recommendations for the administration of immune globulin preparations or antimicrobial therapy shown to be effective in controlling a vaccine-preventable disease for which a vaccine is available; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7E22C0E20A3F4E3DB7629E0501B7237B"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to each vaccine described in such paragraph, shall include—</text> 
<clause id="H0B5BC056DF0141F181D1C235EE677D9C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>population groups or circumstances in which a vaccine or related agent is recommended;</text></clause> <clause id="H69E62FB496FB4342BC1D0C631ABF70DF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">contraindications and precautions for use of the vaccine and related agents; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H3F3F17641E234B139B356F8EA56C48DF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information on recognized adverse events associated with the use of such vaccine.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB8252E5D5DEB4316B72E5A919C4FA16E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Emergency use authorization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Guidance for use of vaccines and related agents authorized for emergency use under section 564 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act may be developed by the Advisory Committee if circumstances warrant, including in the case of a public health emergency, as determined by the Secretary under section 319.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H71B7DC9729964EAF950EA73EA671AC12"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Considerations for recommendation development or withdrawal of recommendation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Advisory Committee, when making new recommendations under subsection (c)(1), or revisions or withdrawals of such recommendations under paragraph (5), shall review evidence in the following categories:</text> <subparagraph id="H2B98B0A0701C4B418D0E67C2E81E58C8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Identification of the specific intervention, including dosage and schedule.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD1367FDD762B431387EC0FB168D05ED0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The strength of the design of the study used to provide the evidence considered.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H71199183E35845A980CE65C94B0072F5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Randomized controlled trials or overwhelming evidence from observational studies.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H13D4A6AD797545FE96A7BCBFFCD0E12D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Comparison and outcome of the target population for the vaccine, including standard of care, existing vaccines, and other prevention options.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8B28611EB864478C99D011669D45276E"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Prevention outcome or scientifically verified adverse effects associated with vaccination.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H96BEFEA5122941349994F7755BB54B83"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Revision or withdrawal of recommendation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Advisory Committee may revise or withdraw any recommendation regarding a particular vaccine under this subsection if and when new information on disease epidemiology, vaccine effectiveness or safety, or other data become available, and as supported by a preponderance of the best available, peer-reviewed scientific evidence.</text></paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="H9D12047966F7434AA24E97F101E0DE7D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Administration</header> <paragraph id="H799A550E4E054C5A880C1C4FCE1621C0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Reporting structure</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Advisory Committee shall report to the Director. The Director shall inform the Secretary, the Assistant Secretary for Health, and the Administrator of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services of immunization recommendations made by the Advisory Committee.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H48EBE30327CC46BB83815D40D1E307D5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Agency support</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of supporting the Advisory Committee in carrying out this section—</text> <subparagraph id="H68B7061B188F4D718EADDB7134E51AB1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Office of the Director, National Center for Immunization and Respiratory Diseases of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention shall provide management and support services; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC8375DB804364EB69EA8DBD1DB700DD2">
                                    <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Advisory Committee may enter into an agreement with the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine to provide external support.</text>
                                </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H012BFEE8CAD64416B853D3CF0EA675C4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Designated Federal Officer</header> 
<subparagraph id="HF8E3A0010F084ECFB4CD6D2E2B1BEF3E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Selection</header><text>The Director shall select a full-time or permanent part-time Federal employee to serve as the Designated Federal Officer.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H814B23D182B241CAA8A55AE3B71682CA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Designated Federal Officer selected under subparagraph (A) shall—</text> 
<clause id="H84F637B12B074F79B8A185ECD7112F08"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">attend each meeting of the Advisory Committee (and any subcommittee thereof) or select a designee to attend such a meeting;</text></clause> <clause id="H1DFE52EA38604AF7A6A9411F62420D59"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>ensure that all procedures of the Advisory Committee for such a meeting are within applicable statutory, regulatory, and HHS General Administration Manual directives; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HBE434123B3D04E4E89BE1E21D9EA4934"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">approve and prepare all policies and agendas for each such meeting, call any such meeting, adjourn any meeting when the Designated Federal Officer deems adjournment to be in the public interest, and chair meetings when directed to do so by the official to whom the Advisory Committee reports.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4778610930B8462084CC0EA09A1600B7"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Assignment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the event that the Designated Federal Officer cannot fulfill the assigned duties of the Advisory Committee, one or more full-time or permanent part-time Federal employees shall be assigned as the Designated Federal Officer and carry out such duties on a temporary basis.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC14079E4F33441C59314B92AB4BCB2DF"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Meetings</header> 
<paragraph id="H90182FC521B74905B5D3E19FB87952D4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Frequency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Pursuant to the call of the Designated Federal Officer, in consultation with the Chair of the Advisory Committee, meetings shall be held—</text> <subparagraph id="HDEF6DC926DFE460FB0247F36F0006F10"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not less than three times per calendar year; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB9983C75AFFB4C8791D452B0C4421FE2"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">upon the licensure of any vaccine, or any new indication for a vaccine, under section 351(a), not later than 90 days after the date of the first marketing of such vaccine.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H64567A7A5AD042DB954BDC3585B8F5AD"> <enum>(2)</enum> <header>Open to the public</header> <text>Meetings of the Advisory Committee shall be open to the public except as determined otherwise by the Director, or other official, to whom the authority has been delegated, in accordance with sections 552b(c) and 1009 of title 5, United States Code. Notice of all such meetings shall be given to the public.</text>
                            </paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8FB57270DE02424EA7DFB7DEE514C7A6"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Membership</header> 
<paragraph id="H0434CBFADD344096B17FB0A3618DBA2D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall appoint at least 15 and not more than 19 individuals to serve as members (including the chairperson) of the Advisory Committee. Such individuals shall be appointed from among individuals recommended by the Comptroller General of the United States. Such members shall serve as Special Government Employees.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4FE94D1835DD43A0A4A694582EE0D2FF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Required expertise</header><text>The Comptroller General of the United States may only recommend as a member of the Advisory Committee an individual who has expertise or experience with respect to one or more of the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H25F02502930844BFB4070C9B60957A03"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A prevalence of peer-reviewed and best available scientific research.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF22F3F786F4D4EBB803831138CA52761"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Expertise relating to epidemiology and vaccine-preventable disease burden.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDB4345185DF943E69D28B95F61C27711"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Expert experience to rigorously evaluate the best available scientific evidence with immunization recommendations and public health.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDB5FF76F517949858839A47E93DF6C33"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Expertise in immunology as evidenced by publications on the topic of immunology in peer-reviewed journals.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEA3119F48E7740FA8C1D63C36D3C487A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Expertise in the use of vaccines and other immunobiologic agents in clinical practice or preventive medicine.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8C09612AB73041E4B14A293D00E8D0D4"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Expertise in infectious diseases, particularly human immune responses to vaccines, assessment of vaccine efficacy or effectiveness, or vaccine safety, as evidenced by publications on the topic in peer-reviewed journals.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H13A67632339B44A3BAA01076826DCC7A"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Expertise with clinical or laboratory vaccine research.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8F27150065274BA2BCF51B71A9D3CC09"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Expertise in assessment of vaccine efficacy and safety.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1F7F769354E0464F805E2EBB7CB45F72"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Knowledge about consumer perspectives or the social and community aspects of immunization programs, or both.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H92B4359B489B4B1AAC004DB94031001D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Ex-officio members</header><text>In addition to the individuals appointed under paragraph (1), the membership of the Advisory Committee shall also consist of the following 6 non-voting ex-officio members (or their designees):</text> 
<subparagraph id="HBE71C4A4DE1340FB8CB8DB01B49F3C3A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7E35E2D40374484C80EEEA2FB198D4FD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Commissioner of Food and Drugs.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H251164904C864346907A0E2FD4D3A2B3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Administrator of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H590E376185104203865050F28248CA23"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The Director of the National Institutes of Health.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDE3929143C5B4E9593B1E33D298AEE5A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The Director of the Indian Health Service.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1F2B7C34DBB74FC19BCA644E91CC0582"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the National Vaccine Program Office.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HED009027D786438691C80174755A9EBE"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Quorum</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Two-thirds of the voting members of the Advisory Committee shall constitute a quorum for purposes of meetings of the Advisory Committee.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H94DFE706AD2D4808BBAE243AAD1F4C22"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Voting if less than quorum present</header><text>If fewer than a quorum of members of the Advisory Committee are eligible to vote due to absence or a financial or other conflict of interest at any meeting of the Advisory Committee, the Designated Federal Officer, or their designee, shall have the authority to temporarily designate the ex-officio members under paragraph (3) as voting members.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H59BA460AA8734C34B69E4FCA9F108F2B"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Non-voting liaison representatives</header><text>Meetings of the Advisory Committee may also be attended by non-voting liaison representatives who shall be deemed representatives from a stakeholder organization.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4A7E0ED13E144772953FFC1D70B75017"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Terms</header> <subparagraph id="H18560EDDB4CB4FF187B5C77B25516AAB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as specified in subparagraph (B), individuals appointed under paragraph (1) shall be invited to serve as members of the Advisory Committee for overlapping terms of 4 years, except that any member appointed to fill a vacancy for an unexpired term shall be appointed for the remainder of that term. A member of the Advisory Committee may continue to serve on the Advisory Committee for a period not to exceed 180 days after the expiration of that member’s term if a successor has not taken office.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7480EC8B78B64F89BB604C130A049089"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Chairperson</header><text>The term of the Chairperson of the Advisory Committee shall be 7 years.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H3E06B5276CE64C1182D09722643CD2B0"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Subcommittees</header> <paragraph id="H4A72521EDCE44E0C834F822FA0CEE958"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Advisory Committee may, subject to approval by the Secretary (or the Secretary’s designee), establish subcommittees composed, in part, of members of the Advisory Committee and other subject matter experts.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF98BCF0E93234CA4A6CEECF48F8332E3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The subcommittees shall report back to the parent committee and may not provide advice or work products directly to the Department of Health and Human Services.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB577A89C15AE485398DA7E2FBA34C17D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Department Committee Management Officer</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H52FB06A32B6F4DA0B33E82A80891CBB4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>notify the Department Committee Management Officer upon establishment of each subcommittee; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H546D764E8757403C95A8A0C43833705B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide to such Officer information on the name, membership, function, and estimated frequency of meetings of such subcommittee.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE12FF2329CC343838B55F3A5A5A5544E"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Recordkeeping</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The records of the Advisory Committee, established subcommittees, or other subgroups of the committee, shall be managed in accordance with General Records Schedule 6.2, Federal Advisory Committee Records, or other approved agency records disposition schedule. Such records shall be available for public inspection and copying, subject to section 552 of title 5, United States Code.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H55E920C35FE744BA9F6FD550AF7A2739"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H6310F612E2C04074A044C9FD8D2311E3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Stakeholder organization</header><text>The term <term>stakeholder organization</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H498807E5322D49F49057A83239AD4035"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the American Academy of Family Physicians;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8B65CB44C30144CD9893320205E6671D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the American Academy of Pediatrics;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAC7B4DDA7AAC4D4FA8ABB7868D553C6A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the American Academy of Physician Associates;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H225E236C1F2B4A3D8AD5241E628B3624"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the American College Health Association;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFA0A5C17919E44A28CDAD813342362B4"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the American College of Nurse Midwives;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H35FAC5301B384A9086D59C3D4BB3FD64"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3C2CF1F7B0AD455AA9E563EE3209937B"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the American College of Physicians;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H685F69EAED2E4F56B003E60426F3EA97"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the American Geriatrics Society;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H935C2FB306ED4846B1B6D2C797A3C930"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the America’s Health Insurance Plans;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF8C815462ED5427CB4A85D9985E9FDBC"><enum>(J)</enum><text>the American Immunization Registry Association;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1068E335207B4D37BC99D6F7A012DCAE"><enum>(K)</enum><text>the American Medical Association;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1820FE6419DF4C68ACDF21065CDC5724"><enum>(L)</enum><text>the American Nurses Association;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H33B1A26B66B5430B9A46155783F5C999"><enum>(M)</enum><text>the American Osteopathic Association;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4D8429908B1C48AF805097F84C0612B3"><enum>(N)</enum><text>the American Pharmacists Association;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5FFA6E6BAA1743A2BE953CCC6B4BB34E"><enum>(O)</enum><text>the Association of Immunization Managers;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC04C2E182AAF4ED0B4C7379C5515E48A"><enum>(P)</enum><text>the Association for Prevention Teaching and Research;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H50517E207F2E48FBAB852DECA0602415"><enum>(Q)</enum><text>the Association of State and Territorial Health Officials;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDBC1903DDAF646309A39250455EF69F4"><enum>(R)</enum><text>the Biotechnology Innovation Organization;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H55AAE61B83C244788294029AFD495D66"><enum>(S)</enum><text>the Council of State and Territorial Epidemiologists;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF61959D79ECC4B7EAB5C2D3E6D5658D7"><enum>(T)</enum><text>the Canadian National Advisory Committee on Immunization;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H756BA250CE004052B8E7CF37803106D4"><enum>(U)</enum><text>the Infectious Diseases Society of America;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFFCE6EB65F69436BBE6F42F2A22596C0"><enum>(V)</enum><text>the International Society of Travel Medicine;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCFCCA76924D846F9AF56F3BAA5459669"><enum>(W)</enum><text>the National Association of County and City Health Officials;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA77377AD06294BF6B44B249392AC22A2"><enum>(X)</enum><text>the National Association of Pediatric Nurse Practitioners;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H59C983E5B9F849708D59DB39FC74724D"><enum>(Y)</enum><text>the National Foundation for Infectious Diseases;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5ABEE1FBA6734308B65EA8661CEDEE66"><enum>(Z)</enum><text>the National Medical Association;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H35713F152BFD450EBF25F429F7A1B5F6"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>the Pediatric Infectious Diseases Society;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3789B8B1787247DBA4EEB4472F91099F"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>the Pharmaceutical Research and Manufacturers of America;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9049F713971D4980BCFB7F3F135E32FB"><enum>(CC)</enum><text>the Society for Adolescent Health and Medicine;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H48FD450EE9A5498FBCEB7453032FF3A0"><enum>(DD)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the American Public Health Association;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H238AFE952BD6416F8BFFF4166426E91B"><enum>(EE)</enum><text>the Society for Healthcare Epidemiology of America; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H04CBC3B93E404A3997467BEAB3EADDE2"><enum>(FF)</enum><text>such other non-voting liaison as the Secretary determines necessary to effectively carry out the functions of the Advisory Committee.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9A78472C5FDE4F33B4C1304D74651FC7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Vaccine</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>vaccine</term> means any substance (and any related agent) that is licensed under section 351 for the prevention of 1 or more diseases. Such term includes related agents that are administered prophylactically for active or passive antigen-specific immunity.</text></paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="HCA9DD24A9B5A45EE8706519D71A334F8"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section, including operating costs, compensation and travel expenses for members, and staff support of the Advisory Committee, $2,800,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2029.</text></subsection> </section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H282FD01FD8514D569B13CF796D8E0054"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as expressly provided in the amendment made by subsection (a), nothing in such amendment shall be construed as limiting the authority of the Advisory Committee on Immunization Practices, or the duties of such Advisory Committee, that were in effect as of the day before the date of the enactment of this Act, including with respect to subsections (c)(2)(B)(i) and (e) of section 1928 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396s">42 U.S.C. 1396s</external-xref>) and section 2713(a)(2) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg-13">42 U.S.C. 300gg–13(a)(2)</external-xref>) (as such sections were in effect on the day before the date of the enactment of this Act).</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H4BA6DD59EB864450A7746016AC3A36CA"><enum>3.</enum><header>National Vaccine Injury Compensation Program</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subsection (c) of section 2114 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300aa-14">42 U.S.C. 300aa–14</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HE65CE1BDBF7B430D9AAE0D08F6569D44" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="H6FDB9831C2294E00A969CB59480B8972"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any removal of a vaccine from the Vaccine Injury Table, or any other modification under paragraph (1), including any additions to the list of injuries, disabilities, illnesses, conditions, and deaths for which compensation may be provided, shall be supported by the preponderance of the best available scientific evidence regarding the safety or efficacy of the vaccine. Nothing in the preceding sentence shall be construed to limit the authority of the Secretary to amend the Vaccine Injury Table to include new vaccines pursuant to subsection (e).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

