<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Placed-on-Calendar-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MIR25956-0FC-XY-R37"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2748 PCS: Make the District of Columbia Safe and Beautiful Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><calendar>Calendar No. 155</calendar><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2748</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250909">September 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S420">Mr. Schmitt</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read the first time</action-desc></action><action><action-date date="20250910">September 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Read the second time and placed on the calendar</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To establish a program to beautify the District of Columbia and to establish the District of Columbia Safe and Beautiful Commission, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Make the District of Columbia Safe and Beautiful Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idedbef598229a4f15a65c5557a478c7b3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5554305a7a3247609007662a8acf9601"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="idabfa62108894414a9b4710968392843e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd55c67f910fa4b3989337ac53a76c2d9" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id60af9c1e00b1477f98227e4dba617862"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the District of Columbia Safe and Beautiful Commission established under section 4(a).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id23b622558c2d4c918def74b9bb7b9cc2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Program</header><text>The term <term>Program</term> means the program developed under section 3(a)(1).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id679d829f87964e50939ffc0490bd0cd8"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text></paragraph></section><section id="idcf6254e26e62440d9ac02f132d05b340"><enum>3.</enum><header>Program to beautify the District of Columbia</header><subsection id="idb2b2fcd6ab5f416eb0931881dbf05d41"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><paragraph id="idfc85561ac7a14370a2bdfab8a1e2d454"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall develop a program to beautify the District of Columbia.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6f744000ab6d4ad2a72ddc138647a405"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>The Secretary, when establishing the Program, shall consult with each of the following:</text><subparagraph id="ida97f3d95edab4258bff4f9f53758d7bd"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Attorney General.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id62939d1e37624c659d0956c1401797a2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Secretary of Transportation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd99169c1316e41c7a184a432491f56e1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Mayor of the District of Columbia.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id47d4cadb94b7414fad834514d81f54e9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The United States Attorney for the District of Columbia.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id774755c49e5e42c5bc2df5c4a32bfd38"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The Administrator of General Services.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9eda2fae6e8c4c499730881a95af5a4c"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The heads of such other Federal departments and agencies and District of Columbia officials as the Secretary deems appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idf8042c94c6aa4fd19b1340d208446f08"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of the Program is to establish a plan for Federal and local officials to—</text><paragraph id="id657dbbbdfaa7423fac131f42576c4bda"><enum>(1)</enum><text>coordinate, and maintain, the cleanliness of Federal and District of Columbia facilities, monuments, land, public spaces, sidewalks, parks, highways, roads, transit systems, and other commonly visited areas within the District of Columbia, including through the removal of graffiti;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id344be15446a448a7ab6d215d7eff6810"><enum>(2)</enum><text>restore Federal public monuments, memorials, statues, markers, and similar properties that have been damaged or defaced or inappropriately removed or changed; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb4fd4d193ce142f2a423d4795072f1c7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>encourage private sector participation in the efforts of the Program.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id5c6a9fb5397942ffb55312c905dc96fc"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs and on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate and the Committees on Oversight and Government Reform and on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives a report that includes a summary of the progress made toward achieving the purpose of the Program as described in subsection (b).</text></subsection><subsection id="id50b12db1ee4a4029a0b7a7a3aba3e170"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>This section, and the Program established by this section, shall terminate on January 2, 2029.</text></subsection></section><section id="id3dd7074e4f9a4a6ba85db9238f2ae1a7"><enum>4.</enum><header>District of Columbia Safe and Beautiful Commission</header><subsection id="ida5382fc7a0bf45dea7783e8a92425eba"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established in the executive branch a District of Columbia Safe and Beautiful Commission.</text></subsection><subsection id="iddc4a3c77db5c4e53b0513c23f6b25131"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership</header><paragraph id="id14db7178f09b4f85bfa03932af6e9e36"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission shall be comprised of representatives of each of the following entities:</text><subparagraph id="id265ac7df97da40e69d23272f6da1c04d"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Department of the Interior.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id47344576e5df48d0b6a6dcbccf2f1067"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Department of Transportation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8f119c1a804548cea1e1044795fcd949"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Department of Homeland Security.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id173bd634d9694116af745e8d8657eded"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The Federal Bureau of Investigation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id934a57c7ed83497094a98ee1ed21cad4"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The United States Marshals Service.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd9f43d8c1b7d466d9bc84ad42436d88b"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id895a81f0fc7d4fc18154e869588e469c"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The United States Attorney’s Office for the District of Columbia.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id55b2209aecbb4bbea8d72ef09dc88320"><enum>(H)</enum><text>The United States Attorney’s Office for the District of Maryland.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb1d1e2162e844cc296a3580877f532bc"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The United States Attorney’s Office for the Eastern District of Virginia.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3c6cb0f8162445b78c8a90942bda2782"><enum>(J)</enum><text>Such other entities of the Federal Government as may be determined by the Chair of the Commission.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id23536597ec094231b4ea9a81e32271de"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Designation of members</header><text>Not later than 45 days after the date of enactment of this section (or, in the case of an entity described in subsection (b)(1)(J), not later than 45 days after the Chair of the Commission designates the entity), the head of each entity described in subsection (b)(1) shall designate a representative of that entity to serve as the representative of the entity on the Commission.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id92779a5329ef41f4a1abf8dfc1e1031e"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Chair</header><paragraph id="id66139e7d34c848cd81f8768363728912"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Designation</header><text>Not later than 45 days after the date of enactment of this section, the President shall designate a senior level official from the Executive Office of the President to serve as the Chair of the Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idadded6a61a5145de9e7a2a5bb5afc7d6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Functions</header><text>The Chair of the Commission shall perform functions that include the following:</text><subparagraph id="id826015039e26480d8d6de41f60434ae2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Developing a schedule of meetings for the Commission.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id494876d66c8c47f5864fbc6ea15845aa"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Designating entities who shall be represented on the Commission under subsection (b)(1)(J).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6c668de375204efd9a44555ea449079f"><enum>(C)</enum><text>In consultation with the members of the Commission, developing a charter for the Commission and, not later than 7 days after the date on which the charter is completed, submitting the charter to the appropriate committees of Congress.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id3cac5a147c8e45f291747b8a52ba6539"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Functions and authorities</header><paragraph id="id36e2bec2d121454090a07fa5ee756206"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Functions</header><text>The functions of the Commission are to recommend actions, and review the effectiveness of such actions, with respect to the following:</text><subparagraph id="id3548e1644afe4d3db5781c76b3125827"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Developing and encouraging the implementation of polices that will direct the maximum enforcement of Federal immigration law within the District of Columbia, including policies to encourage the redirection of available Federal, State, or local law enforcement resources to apprehend and deport illegal aliens.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1b7f263740614e68a114057bf8071427"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Monitoring the District of Columbia’s sanctuary city status and compliance with the enforcement of Federal immigration law.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idcd96d098b4174b25a53bbc50eee87450"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Facilitating the prompt and complete accreditation of the District of Columbia’s forensic crime laboratory.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id67fdef365fce4d3792add4ed12a4555f"><enum>(D)</enum><text>In collaboration with its leadership and union, ensuring that the Metropolitan Police Department of the District of Columbia is provided with assistance to facilitate the recruitment, retention, and capabilities of its officers and facilitating the provision of Federal personnel, resources, and expertise to reduce crime.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc047d24235764740bd9fd26bfc3e0d9d"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Collaborating with appropriate local government entities to provide assistance to increase the speed and lower the cost of processing concealed carry license requests in the District of Columbia.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idad929a0620894b56b521b24f228f4f25"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Reviewing and, as appropriate, recommending revisions to Federal prosecutorial policies on pretrial detention of criminal defendants to ensure that individuals who pose a genuine threat to public safety are detained to the maximum extent permitted by law.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id04c0067fee64438dac73b25df40196c7"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Collaborating with appropriate local government entities to provide assistance to end fare evasion and other crime within the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority system.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc71483070ad24bcc8d487e9a6ee7ca26"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Facilitating the deployment of a more robust Federal law enforcement presence, and in coordination with local law enforcement agencies, facilitating the deployment of a more robust local law enforcement presence (as appropriate) within the District of Columbia, including the National Mall and Memorial Parks, museums, monuments, Lafayette Park, Union Station, Rock Creek Park, Anacostia Park, the George Washington Memorial Parkway, the Suitland Parkway, and the Baltimore-Washington Parkway.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ida2d31433f5bc4949a46dd5458140d2ad"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Coordination with other authorities</header><text>The Commission may, to the extent permitted by law, request operational assistance from and coordinate with Federal and local officials as appropriate, including the Metropolitan Police Department of the District of Columbia, the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority, the United States Park Police, and the Amtrak Police.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id35499c9d30ae4267bdcc9bda744fda59"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report</header><text>The Commission shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report that includes a summary of the functions and authorities carried out pursuant to subsection (d), and shall include in the report such recommendations for legislation as the Commission considers appropriate.</text></subsection><subsection id="id8e834f6e36c4463c9a680041d7606289"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>This section, and the Commission established by this section, shall terminate on January 2, 2029.</text></subsection></section></legis-body><endorsement><action-date date="20250910">September 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Read the second time and placed on the calendar</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

