<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-FLO25082-VHN-L6-186"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S392 IS: Sloan Canyon Conservation and Lateral Pipeline Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 392</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250204">February 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S385">Ms. Cortez Masto</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Sloan Canyon National Conservation Area Act to adjust the boundary of the Sloan Canyon National Conservation Area, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H9A2AEA377FA0462683ACEC7F7D17E4D8"><section section-type="section-one" id="H8FDD06E2338443778015B7187605B488"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Sloan Canyon Conservation and Lateral Pipeline Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HA279AA56DA0A425ABE1E436205F471AC"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="HC4BF23C7FF0947C38EC3FE033242DEF5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Conservation Area</header><text>The term <term>Conservation Area</term> means the Sloan Canyon National Conservation Area.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8A8DDCC382A24D4AA2AFB30B6B7CE7CB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the Bureau of Land Management.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H81AA0148B3A8484DB4C2C4CD96CFCE78"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sloan Canyon National Conservation Area boundary adjustment</header><subsection id="H619F37F9F4D34B61AD698C431342651F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Boundary adjustment</header><paragraph id="HBE5EFBFF0BF6402EA40C6FA09A81DC8B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Map</header><text>Section 603(4) of the Sloan Canyon National Conservation Area Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/460qqq-1">16 U.S.C. 460qqq–1(4)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>map entitled <quote>Southern Nevada Public Land Management Act</quote> and dated October 1, 2002</quote> and inserting <quote>map entitled <quote>Proposed Sloan Canyon Expansion</quote> and dated May 20, 2024</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H995099FCAF30428481783FFDE127D88D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Acreage</header><text>Section 604(b) of the Sloan Canyon National Conservation Area Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/460qqq-2">16 U.S.C. 460qqq–2(b)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>48,438</quote> and inserting <quote>57,728</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2F4B5A4BF62049179AE6E988BD54192D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Right-of-Way</header><text>Section 605 of the Sloan Canyon National Conservation Area Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/460qqq-3">16 U.S.C. 460qqq–3</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H9E94E1A2D1AE4C11B04FBA3FB69CD1E8"><subsection id="HC6FFF972E1994834BBDA13C0D2F69F10"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Horizon lateral pipeline right-of-Way</header><paragraph id="HC6E756FB2BF54F25A3B1C43D185474D6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding sections 202 and 503 of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1712">43 U.S.C. 1712</external-xref>, 1763) and subject to valid existing rights and paragraph (3), the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the Bureau of Land Management (referred to in this subsection as the <term>Secretary</term>), shall, not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this subsection, grant to the Southern Nevada Water Authority (referred to in this subsection as the <term>Authority</term>), not subject to the payment of rents or other charges, the temporary and permanent water pipeline infrastructure, and outside the boundaries of the Conservation Area, powerline, facility, and access road rights-of-way depicted on the map for the purposes of—</text><subparagraph id="H5B251944FC9A4E03AD9B2D0D7D0E2BE9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>performing geotechnical investigations within the rights-of-way; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H85A80BE64C5448E8B902600081242475"><enum>(B)</enum><text>constructing and operating water transmission and related facilities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE0000F64A3CB4C319B499B0646647407"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Excavation and disposal</header><subparagraph id="H73B13F5C4A21481DBA61630DDE0F713F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Authority may, without consideration, excavate and use or dispose of sand, gravel, minerals, or other materials from the tunneling of the water pipeline necessary to fulfill the purpose of the rights-of-way granted under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCFC29087E43842248B3563A9A6480B66"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Memorandum of understanding</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date on which the rights-of-way are granted under paragraph (1), the Secretary and the Authority shall enter into a memorandum of understanding identifying Federal land on which the Authority may dispose of materials under subparagraph (A) to further the interests of the Bureau of Land Management.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H879B31CB9929475E9152EAA4B0542001"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>A right-of-way issued under this subsection shall be subject to the following requirements:</text><subparagraph id="HD698D8CE183447D188F8EA95221147E0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Secretary may include reasonable terms and conditions, consistent with section 505 of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1765">43 U.S.C. 1765</external-xref>), as are necessary to protect Conservation Area resources.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD0FFFD11A37C4230812882FE8071E5F7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Construction of the water pipeline shall not permanently adversely affect conservation area surface resources.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAED5B941B35A4C148E506809114213FE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The right-of-way shall not be located through or under any area designated as wilderness.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HF8E93E9015194172B36CFFE12613AAD3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Preservation of transmission and utility corridors and rights-of-Way</header><text>The expansion of the Conservation Area boundary under the amendment made by subsection (a)—</text><paragraph id="H4A976CE8056846799A75E320BDD72A82"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall be subject to valid existing rights, including land within a designated utility transmission corridor or a transmission line right-of-way grant approved by the Secretary in a record of decision issued before the date of enactment of this Act; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H429EB13610D64209908690169E8E8302"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall not preclude—</text><subparagraph id="HFC8A4D4E61A94BE99F1EEA1E7C0A9941"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any activity authorized in accordance with a designated corridor or right-of-way referred to in paragraph (1), including the operation, maintenance, repair, or replacement of any authorized utility facility within the corridor or right-of-way; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3FB516C1281A4E14B10FC3C0C0706050"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary from authorizing the establishment of a new utility facility right-of-way within an existing designated transportation and utility corridor referred to in paragraph (1)—</text><clause id="H78A314C3544A4797829C89C631C8E64D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in accordance with the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>) and other applicable laws; and</text></clause><clause id="HE0D19E805D0B4AAAA4FD1886CC03CD22"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>subject to such terms and conditions as the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H888DE97DA64A4B74B635827853E6E3B3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Management of the Conservation Area</header><text>Except as provided in the amendment made by subsection (b), nothing in this Act or the amendments made by this Act shall modify the management of the Conservation Area pursuant to section 605 of the Sloan Canyon National Conservation Area Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/460qqq-3">16 U.S.C. 460qqq–3</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

