<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HED841A6E766E41D8AE896F1CACE7C342" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1511 IH: To direct executive branch agencies to conduct a review of redundant positions, to limit civil service hiring, to require agency plans for reductions in force or reorganization, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1511</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250221">February 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000134">Ms. Van Duyne</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct executive branch agencies to conduct a review of redundant positions, to limit civil service hiring, to require agency plans for reductions in force or reorganization, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H7DB8B510CB9A40D0AC9996A80F1EE270" style="OLC"><section id="H15E5EF1887914CD1A0203E87B5A35F24" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Reducing Expensive Departments &amp; Unnecessary Civil Employees Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>REDUCE Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="HB7BA9CDB96F042908275C99DFE5FC7AF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Review of redundant agency activities and positions; limitation on hiring; agency plans for RIF or reorganization</header><subsection id="HEF853EA03D124AD7B3A6342238A0331E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the head of each agency of the executive branch of the Federal Government shall review each position within such agency and submit a report to Congress on which such positions are redundant and unnecessary.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE3994164E77C443A91766C333DE153B4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Hiring limitation</header><paragraph id="H553CC4FCC84C4B10B55126A347702947"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the head of each such agency may appoint no more than 1 employee for every 4 employees of the agency retiring, transferring, or otherwise separating from the agency after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3810A3E289DF41B69670F974EB999407"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application</header><text>The limitation in paragraph (1) shall apply until the date that the total number of employees at an executive branch agency is equal to or less than 80 percent of the total number of such employees at such agency on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF04E45D333DC47ADAC868AD12D1D018D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>RIF or reorganization plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The head of each such agency shall determine which agency components should be eliminated or combined with another component, and establish a plan to so eliminate or combine (as the case may be) such components under a reduction in force or through a reorganization.</text></subsection><subsection id="H7AD80E0830AB43F791D3559804144F94"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section shall not apply to any position or agency component that is critical to national security, public safety, law enforcement, or immigration enforcement, as determined by the head of each executive branch agency.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

