<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-WAL25756-LWN-K7-F85"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2820 IS: Same Day Registration Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2820</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250916">September 16, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S428">Ms. Alsobrooks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S330">Mr. Bennet</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S385">Ms. Cortez Masto</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S331">Mrs. Gillibrand</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S426">Mr. Kim</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S313">Mr. Sanders</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S366">Ms. Warren</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSRA00">Committee on Rules and Administration</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to require States to provide for same day voter registration.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Same Day Registration Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="H9790437121BD49DBAE1A9A78672A7919"><enum>2.</enum><header>Same day registration</header><subsection id="H10441AE46D854855AD94DF293C8C4635"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Title III of the Help America Vote Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/21081">52 U.S.C. 21081 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H7B90F8AEDA494646AD78E222772EA62A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating sections 304, 305, and 306 as sections 305, 306, and 307, respectively; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB921DF33057F48E1B18BB69247D2517B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after section 303 the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H709F6AD884424508A874AD2A8BF10B9E"><section id="H9D24DD8489F54EAAA4EAC49E35370B11"><enum>304.</enum><header>Same day registration</header><subsection id="HA39F4381B5194FC98E8EE0B473313249"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><paragraph id="H8C1D93D448B740DE9D67978A9154A6D1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Registration</header><text>Each State shall permit any eligible individual on the day of a Federal election and on any day when voting, including early voting, is permitted for a Federal election—</text><subparagraph id="H9AC2AD8E3CF34840B61D5967B05DE197"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to register to vote in such election at the polling place using a form that meets the requirements under section 9(b) of the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/20508">52 U.S.C. 20508(b)</external-xref>) (or, if the individual is already registered to vote, to revise any of the individual’s voter registration information); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6B2286E3ADC0481CACA25C8B6C1CBB30"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to cast a vote in such election.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H26E220770DC844A8BC1DF05B46312D7E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The requirements under paragraph (1) shall not apply to a State in which, under a State law in effect continuously on and after the date of the enactment of this section, there is no voter registration requirement for individuals in the State with respect to elections for Federal office.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H63A16C97B25146ECAAD7538FC00F5E1A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible individual</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>eligible individual</term> means, with respect to any election for Federal office, an individual who is otherwise qualified to vote in that election.</text></subsection><subsection id="H45156812FB9B46398DABC1C1A4FD6CD2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Ensuring availability of forms</header><text>The State shall ensure that each polling place has copies of any forms an individual may be required to complete in order to register to vote or revise the individual’s voter registration information under this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="idA126136D08C04355892C1BA89B732661"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><paragraph id="idE67EAECB632941149F57B89A7866B445"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2), each State shall be required to comply with the requirements of this section for the regularly scheduled general election for Federal office occurring in November 2026 and for any subsequent election for Federal office.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idE052A8BB059641558A25EE86FF6F0809"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Special rules for elections before November 2030</header><subparagraph id="id921D15EC3C1148C1B4404EECBD84B59F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Elections prior to November 2028 general election</header><text>A State shall be deemed to be in compliance with the requirements of this section for the regularly scheduled general election for Federal office occurring in November 2026 and subsequent elections for Federal office occurring before the regularly scheduled general election for Federal office in November 2028 if not fewer than 1 location for each 15,000 registered voters in each jurisdiction in the State meets such requirements, and such location is reasonably located to serve voting populations equitably across the jurisdiction.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id68346D2557704B5EBAC14F5A766FA2D9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Additional elections prior to November 2030 general election</header><text>If a State certifies to the Commission not later than November 7, 2028, that the State will not be in compliance with the requirements of this section for the regularly scheduled general election for Federal office occurring in November 2028 because it would be impracticable to do so and includes in the certification the reasons for the failure to meet such requirements, the State shall be deemed to be in compliance with the requirements of this section for the regularly scheduled general election for Federal office in November 2028 and subsequent elections for Federal office occurring before the regularly scheduled general election for Federal office in November 2030, if not fewer than 1 location for each 15,000 registered voters in each jurisdiction in the State meets such requirements, and such location is reasonably located to serve voting populations equitably across the jurisdiction.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H79FB72718323499CB84AABDD5AC4A4A3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment relating to enforcement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 401 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/21111">52 U.S.C. 21111</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>sections 301, 302, 303, and 304</quote> and inserting <quote>subtitle A of title III</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5F590E9A02374D9581610CD6BD3D7595"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendments</header><text>The table of contents of such Act is amended—</text><paragraph id="HC680981D40E34A37A6DD18D3CDD69A27"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating the items relating to sections 304, 305, and 306 as relating to sections 305, 306, and 307, respectively; </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcd4c701f004e4d1a8796d5ace8cd8c41"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the item relating to section 305, as so redesignated, by striking <quote>Confirming access</quote> and inserting <quote>Access</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H04A75DA27BF04799919B6C77131F7B29"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after the item relating to section 303 the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H661730BFC09643C6B5B5227BBCFF2595"><toc><toc-entry idref="H9D24DD8489F54EAAA4EAC49E35370B11" level="section">Sec. 304. Same day registration. </toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

