<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HFE220A4947154638B67ADAE20E0A0870" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 23 IH: Proxy Voting for New Parents Resolution</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 23</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250109">January 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000620">Ms. Pettersen</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="L000596">Mrs. Luna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000305">Ms. Jacobs</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000585">Mr. Gomez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000273">Ms. Leger Fernandez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001133">Mr. Ciscomani</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000600">Ms. Perez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000397">Mrs. Kim</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000133">Mr. Van Drew</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="N000191">Mr. Neguse</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Committee on Rules</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Permitting parental remote voting by proxy, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><resolution-body style="OLC" id="H500F1C1E2640445DA06C02FC0179EB4C"><section id="H8B92D6D5D2814E9283BAB5F742504DFA" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This resolution may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Proxy Voting for New Parents Resolution</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="HC636B7B6E56A4C16BEE857948ED93286"><enum>2.</enum><header>Authorization of remote voting by proxy in House and in Committee of the Whole for Members becoming parents</header><subsection id="HC20E7B6D8FC8433F996F06C7272302BA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization</header><paragraph id="H02C9115D72B94974A1CD72A59802039E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding rule III, in the case of a Member who has given birth or whose spouse has given birth, such Member may designate another Member as a proxy who may cast the vote of such Member or record the presence of such Member in the House and in the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union in accordance with this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H33BCEA4C4D11468B98296EC16883554C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Period of authorization</header><subparagraph id="HD38CD3071C5C44579A95AB90BC15C56C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided under subparagraph (B), the authority to vote by proxy or record a presence pursuant to paragraph (1) shall begin on the date of the birth and shall terminate 12 weeks thereafter.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFEDE34DA72FF459AA6446067AB477233"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Designation prior to birth</header><text>Notwithstanding subparagraph (A), a Member may instead make a designation prior to the birth of a child in the event that such Member’s health care provider advises that her pregnancy presents a serious medical condition or that she is unable to travel safely. Such authority to vote by proxy or record a presence shall terminate 12 weeks after the initial designation. Each week prior to the birth of the child during which a Member does not have a designated proxy shall not constitute a week for purposes of this subparagraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDDFB77E20AB44E569C68251966629B93"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements for designation by Member</header><paragraph id="H1E128EA2D2724F33AADFC2EF844E8C38"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In order for a Member to designate another Member as a proxy under subsection (a), the Member shall submit to the Clerk a signed and dated letter (which may be in electronic form). Such letter must be submitted prior to the start of the first vote in which the Member wishes to vote by proxy and must include—</text><subparagraph id="HAD5C6C5E3CFE4973B6D446EABAEA1D62"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an affirmative statement of—</text><clause id="HA1368C0AE3784F7AA18CC051A0FE939E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the birth of a child in the case of a designation under subparagraph (A) of subsection (a)(2); or</text></clause><clause id="HAA2A1E9379DE4F12B3ECC4B4AA1D4379"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the existence of a medical condition related to pregnancy as stipulated by the Member’s health care provider in the case of a designation under subparagraph (B) of subsection (a)(2);</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H75CADC9DBD6045288BDEF9A3928C85B8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a statement of intent to vote by proxy, including the name and State of the Member who has agreed to be designated as a proxy; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H406701A6CD5140D88CFAA05CF3C1628D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an original signature of the Member making the designation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H862C94D3396B4448B99060B09BD3FFC5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Alteration and revocation</header><text>At any time after submitting a letter to designate a proxy under paragraph (1), such Member may submit to the Clerk a signed letter (which may be in electronic form) altering or revoking the designation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9B97E9AB62C440BAB3A8700327CF4FCB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Automatic revocation upon casting of vote or recording of presence</header><text>If a Member who has designated another Member as a proxy under this section casts the Member’s own vote or records the Member’s own presence in the House or in the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union, the Member shall be considered to have revoked the designation of any proxy under this section. Revocation of proxy does not prohibit a Member from designating a proxy at a later time.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H42DBC353700B49689181237418814C0D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Responsibilities of Clerk</header><paragraph id="H21BA4791E4854EB6A189E051BD16C732"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon receipt of a letter submitted by a Member pursuant to subsection (b), the Clerk shall—</text><subparagraph id="HCBC62F4F10C9458D816FADDF76C61517"><enum>(A)</enum><text>verify the letter;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4830EF47CF9047609042340AFB8544B6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>notify the Speaker, the Majority Leader, the Minority Leader, and the other Member or Members involved in the designation, alteration, or revocation; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H984AB4FA690D4C38B1D6446976C24A6C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>if a letter is missing any of the items under subsection (b)(1), notify the submitting Member of the deficiency, which shall result in the proxy being unable to vote on the Member’s behalf.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0EA9F33A2ED84958AADDA48A0D40000A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Maintenance of list</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Clerk shall maintain an updated list of the active designations, alterations, and revocations pursuant to this section and shall make such list publicly available in electronic form.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0F7F7FB0AD4F4349A868A5950D96CA60"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Procedures for casting votes or recording presence by proxies</header><paragraph id="H73ED88E11BD042FF8D9734DF96479E6B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Use of ballot card</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a vote by electronic device, a Member who casts a vote or records a presence as a designated proxy for another Member under this section shall do so by ballot card, indicating on the ballot card “by proxy”.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7244D015E68749D3B5B1D76EBB8F509C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Instructions from Member</header><text>Prior to casting the vote or recording the presence of another Member as a designated proxy under this section, the Member shall obtain an exact instruction from the other Member with respect to such vote. The Member voting by proxy, to the maximum extent practicable, shall provide written voting instruction to the Member serving as proxy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2E70E1B23D924436A5C0EFBE60A221FA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Recognition by chair</header><text>Immediately prior to casting the vote or recording the presence of another Member as a designated proxy under this section, the Member shall seek recognition from the Chair to announce the intended vote or recorded presence pursuant to the exact instruction received from the other Member under paragraph (2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF3A3BF7E669D4FEDA50309A94943F958"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Following instructions from Member</header><text>A Member casting the vote or recording the presence of another Member as a designated proxy under this section shall cast such vote or record such presence pursuant to the exact instruction received from the other Member under paragraph (2).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H37DED6720A654960A5FA1DFD4E43DE99"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Prohibiting use of proxy To establish quorum</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any Member whose vote is cast or whose presence is recorded by a designated proxy under this section shall not be counted for purposes of establishing a quorum under the rules of the House.</text></subsection></section><section id="HB9094BB549C6450AB0F1A2D4D8C141FB"><enum>3.</enum><header>Authorization of remote voting by proxy in committee for Members becoming parents</header><subsection id="HC1335374F47548C08A61620939CE8524"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding rule XI, a Member who has designated another Member as a proxy who may cast the vote of such Member under section 2 may designate a member of each committee on which the Member sits as a proxy who may cast the vote of such Member in committee in accordance with this section during the same period in which another Member is authorized to cast the vote of such Member under section 2.</text></subsection><subsection id="H8C350116E9864B54B51A20316146A9E7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements for designation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In order for a Member to designate a committee member as a proxy under subsection (a), the Member shall submit to the chair and ranking minority member a signed and dated letter (which may be in electronic form) specifying by name the other Member who is designated as a proxy for such Member. Such letter must be submitted prior to the start of the first committee meeting in which the Member wishes to vote by proxy.</text></subsection><subsection id="H22DC4A6DBDE540379FA379054F1BDA07"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Alteration and revocation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At any time after submitting a letter to designate a proxy under subsection (b), such Member may submit to the chair and ranking minority member a signed letter (which may be in electronic form) altering or revoking the designation.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD1B7120D7AAE46F79E1456FD88DB8439"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Automatic revocation upon casting of vote or recording of presence</header><text>If a Member who has designated another Member as a proxy under this section casts the Member’s own vote in a committee, the Member shall be considered to have revoked the designation of proxy in that committee under this section. Revocation of proxy does not prohibit a Member from designating a proxy at a later time.</text></subsection><subsection id="H8EEF96D3D73043B2B119BE98C2896EB0"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Instructions from Member</header><text>Prior to casting the vote of another Member as a designated proxy under this section, the Member shall obtain an exact instruction from the other Member with respect to such vote. The Member voting by proxy, to the maximum extent practicable, shall provide written voting instruction to the Member serving as proxy.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA2059B610B4747698F5D0058275DA65D"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Prohibiting use of proxy To establish quorum</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any Member whose vote is cast in committee by a designated proxy under this section shall not be counted for purposes of establishing a quorum under the rules of the committee.</text></subsection></section><section id="HE5DD8D46CCC2439EAB19D22B36B055D4"><enum>4.</enum><header>Application to Delegates and the Resident Commissioner</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For purposes of sections 2 and 3, the term <term>Member</term> shall include a Delegate and the Resident Commissioner and the term <term>State</term> shall include the District of Columbia and a territory, except that—</text><paragraph id="H7A3B6E1226FB460FA22A86413B6B259C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">nothing in this section authorizes a Delegate or the Resident Commissioner to cast a vote in the House or record their presence in the House; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3F67C880257E4644AA0B5FCD269B925E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a Delegate and the Resident Commissioner may be designated as a proxy for purposes of section 2 only by a Delegate or the Resident Commissioner. </text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

