<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-DAV25918-5H9-DY-TKH">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1783 IS: Combating Global Poverty Through Energy Development Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>II</distribution-code>
        <congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session>1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. 1783</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action>
            <action-date date="20250515">May 15, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S317">Mr. Barrasso</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S410">Ms. Lummis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S423">Mr.
                    Ricketts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>,
                    <cosponsor name-id="S355">Mr. Cruz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S346">Mr.
                    Lee</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S407">Mr. Hagerty</cosponsor>)
                introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the
                    <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign
                    Relations</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title>To support financing of affordable and reliable energy projects by
            international financial institutions, and for other purposes.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause">
        <section section-type="section-one" id="S1">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Combating Global Poverty Through Energy Development Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section id="id784C66E978EE4AEB9DD6D73A43625434">
            <enum>2.</enum>
            <header>Opposition to restrictions by international financial institutions on financing
                of certain energy projects</header>
            <subsection id="id42D3C989CD4940CE92A83A6CF2576D09">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
 <text>The Secretary shall instruct the United States Executive Director of each covered international financial institution to use the voice, vote, and influence of the United States—</text>
                <paragraph id="idf382a2d818bb4433bea9f8c0db7436ae">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>to oppose any rule, regulation, policy, or guideline that would restrict, prohibit, or have the effect of restricting or prohibiting, the financing of coal, oil, natural gas, or civil nuclear energy projects; and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="ide2d6ebb4ec174ed09406ba18683aba8d">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>to rescind each rule, regulation, policy, or guideline that, as of the date of the enactment of this Act, restricts or prohibits such financing.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id44867109c5514fb7807221196947c028">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Reversal of policies at International Bank for Reconstruction and
                    Development</header>
 <text>The Secretary shall instruct the United States Executive Director of the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development to immediately and vigorously pursue policy changes at the Bank, through formal initiatives and through bilateral discussions, that will result in the reversal of the Bank’s—</text>
                <paragraph id="id9C9D258F21514EB68462C999507EFBDF">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>restrictions on financing coal power generation;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="idF4380CB70AF848C5AF7538E09EEAEB11"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>prohibitions on financing upstream oil and gas exploration and production; and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="idC47B44614BE14011B9633D681201927B">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>prohibition on financing of civil nuclear energy projects.</text> </paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="idA7C39F54790E4E998BA6ED96AFEE3E5B"> <enum>(c)</enum> <header>Limitation on funds for International Bank for Reconstruction and Development</header> <text>Not more than 50 percent of amounts made available for the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development for fiscal year 2026 or any fiscal year thereafter may be obligated or expended until the Secretary certifies to the appropriate congressional committees that the Bank—</text>
                <paragraph id="id34912bb03a9148e3879017e01ebbeb48">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>has rescinded any rule, regulation, policy, or guideline that restricts or prohibits, or would have the effect of restricting or prohibiting, the financing of any coal, oil, natural gas, or civil nuclear energy project; and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="idc4c0f058c9144807b1f19af19a94d5d5">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>has in effect a policy promoting the financing of coal, oil, natural gas, and civil nuclear energy projects.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="idFE427D0E2E4E47098D92438BB1181B44">
                <enum>(d)</enum>
                <header>Promotion of financing of energy projects</header>
 <text>The Secretary, in collaboration with the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Energy, the President of the Export-Import Bank of the United States, the Chief Executive Officer of the United States International Development Finance Corporation, and the heads of other appropriate Federal agencies, shall identify steps the United States can take to promote international financing of energy projects, including coal, oil, and natural gas projects, in order to help developing countries access affordable and reliable power.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id7fe6aef90fdc4181be4314b961486c36">
                <enum>(e)</enum>
                <header>Report required</header>
 <text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that includes the following:</text>
                <paragraph id="id56b464bd77324e9eb8dfb211f43240b7">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>A list of all of the rules, regulations, policies, or guidelines of each covered international financial institution that would restrict, prohibit, or have the effect of restricting or prohibiting, the financing of coal, oil, natural gas, or civil nuclear energy projects.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id4364b1295d9c42a990afea8bf5ea8d4a">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>A detailed description of the efforts of the United States Executive Director of each such institution to eliminate those rules, regulations, policies, or guidelines.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id77C76302E04249C3A9EF68CF33EB0816">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>A description of the steps identified under subsection (d) and progress made in implementing those steps.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="idC0DF32D22FCD4E42A3BDFF7B497FCD40">
                <enum>(f)</enum>
                <header>Definitions</header>
 <text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="id503E622884BA453096B270D73E8800A4"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>Appropriate congressional committees</header> <text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id7EB9FA088EBD469CA172F86182135267">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Covered international financial institution</header>
 <text>The term <term>covered international financial institution</term> means any of the following:</text>
                    <subparagraph id="id345B03B6B17F4B4EA2F1F839AF1AE99E">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>The International Bank for Reconstruction and Development.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idD8AAF72A932A48C59A3D81AB6943AC8B"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>The International Development Association.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="idAB6376617C25465EA28E376A2AF5B42A">
                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>The International Finance Corporation.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id285F04E8E1DB4245A8D702272D3660CA"> <enum>(D)</enum> <text>The International Monetary Fund.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="idEBAE2894672C48D69AFB493F3D6DA058">
                        <enum>(E)</enum>
 <text>The Inter-American Development Bank.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idDC55D32FEB524155844241CF7321B285"> <enum>(F)</enum> <text>The Inter-American Investment Corporation.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id39BAE8330F54497D96F3F97034F2CB35">
                        <enum>(G)</enum>
 <text>The North American Development Bank.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id8864F2E9738C462F8D41354A8D0556FF"> <enum>(H)</enum> <text>The European Bank for Reconstruction and Development.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="idA0E714025D0746AB9515723A6ABEDA28">
                        <enum>(I)</enum>
 <text>The African Development Bank.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id3B378FBD04CB4233901B0D3E55EDD44F"> <enum>(J)</enum> <text>The African Development Fund.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id7CF57A332F6244349813F209D612528F">
                        <enum>(K)</enum>
 <text>The Asian Development Bank.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="id3F110CC0D4174B15B29DD83527F92EDE"> <enum>(3)</enum> <header>Secretary</header> <text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Treasury.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
        </section>
    </legis-body>
</bill>

