<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA671E9B6DB684F14928D4DEF66829E10" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 709 IH: Condemning the September 10, 2025, political assassination of Charlie Kirk and honoring his life and legacy.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 709</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250915">September 15, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001218">Mr. McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000583">Mr. Loudermilk</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001189">Mr. Austin Scott of Georgia</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001116">Mr. Clyde</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Condemning the September 10, 2025, political assassination of Charlie Kirk and honoring his life and legacy.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Charlie Kirk was a devoted husband to Erika, and loving father to a precious son and daughter;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Charlie Kirk had accepted Jesus Christ as his Savior and was a faithful servant;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Charlie Kirk was a defender of his faith and a soldier for the truth;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Charlie Kirk was a true patriot and believed in the American dream;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Charlie Kirk was a tireless advocate for the right to life, strong families, and the importance of marriage;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Charlie Kirk had a relentless work ethic and was largely self-educated;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Charlie Kirk founded Turning Point USA at the young age of 18 years old, which became the single most impactful political organization in America for young conservatives;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Turning Point USA Action encouraged young voters to get involved in the political process;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Turning Point USA has a presence on over 3,000 high school and college campuses nationwide;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Turning Point USA has over 650,000 lifetime student members;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Turning Point USA hosted America Fest and Student Action Summit, which brought thousands of young conservatives together from across the country to learn and be inspired;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, in September 2025, Charlie Kirk had launched his American Comeback Tour to have engaging conversations on college campuses across the Nation and encourage college students to engage in the political process;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Charlie Kirk visited Georgia as part of national speaking tours, including events at the University of Georgia and rallies in Duluth, where he encouraged students and young voters to engage in civil debate and the political process;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Charlie Kirk sought to have civil and peaceful conversations, even with those whom he disagreed;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, on September 10, 2025, Charlie Kirk was mercilessly gunned down at the first event of his American Comeback Tour while peacefully speaking at a campus event at Utah Valley University;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas shortly before this tragedy, Kirk’s wife Erika had posted Psalm 46:1 on her X account, <quote>God is our refuge and strength, a very present help in trouble</quote>; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas this moment must be a turning point for the Nation, and be proof that Charlie Kirk did not die in vain: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H67097842223B46D5AC0674B4BFEF3CF1"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H19D85CD4F6E04DC5A29B1FE876AC2517"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> 
<paragraph id="H283FC5A19F3F4549868DE8D18FAC520D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">condemns, in the strongest possible terms, the September 10, 2025, assassination of Charlie Kirk;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9AEEDA0D948A4048B9961045003EAE56"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">applauds the quick response and dedicated service of the first responders and hospital medical team who cared for Charlie Kirk;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC69C82F559574B6AA6C68DA01383C3A4"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">expresses sorrow and heartfelt condolences to the Kirk family; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCDBC4CAC0CC747E5BBE14426385B2B1B"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reaffirms its commitment to protecting the rights of all Americans to assemble peacefully and to express their political views without fear of violence.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

