<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-HLA25674-N28-NM-6JW"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 360 IS: Honoring the life of Deputy Elijah Ming and expressing condolences to his family.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 360</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250731">July 31, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S411">Mr. Marshall</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S347">Mr. Moran</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Honoring the life of Deputy Elijah Ming and expressing condolences to his family.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas Elijah Ming was a brave law enforcement officer who sacrificed his life to keep his local Kansas community safe;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Elijah Ming was born to Mark and Sonji Ming in February 1991;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, while attending F.L. Schlagle High School in Kansas City, Kansas, Elijah distinguished himself as a dedicated student and a standout athlete;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, after graduating high school, Elijah Ming pursued athletics at the collegiate level, playing baseball at several schools, including Fort Scott Community College in Bourbon County, Kansas;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, while at Fort Scott Community College, Elijah Ming was crowned homecoming king for his contributions to the community;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, during his collegiate career, Elijah Ming was voted the “most inspirational player” by his teammates, and his coaches remarked that his energy and smile were contagious;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, after college, Elijah Ming returned to Kansas City, Kansas, and joined the Wyandotte County Sheriff’s Office;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Elijah Ming served for 9 years with distinction and honor and was an active force for good in Wyandotte County;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on July 26, 2025, Elijah Ming responded to a civil standby call in Kansas City, ultimately losing his life in the line of duty; </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Elijah Ming was and remains a true American hero whose courage, character, and unwavering commitment to others have left an indelible mark; and </text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas Mr. Ming's legacy will continue to inspire his family, community, and a grateful nation: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id304581609d6f4950b8e6ba41229a9b01"><enum>(1)</enum><text>highly respects and appreciates all that Deputy Elijah Ming did to protect and serve his Kansas community;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id01bf16e5df794e0daca315565aae29da"><enum>(2)</enum><text>offers condolences to the family of Elijah Ming;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0db4b3ee6c34409c9619abc1ad10a594"><enum>(3)</enum><text>pays tribute to Mr. Ming's noble sacrifice in the line of duty; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2f1635156ba6457580b6c99aef822291"><enum>(4)</enum><text>calls on all levels of government to support the family of this fallen officer.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

