<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF19487AB87A34378B7D43D8CAEEF64D1" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4844 IH: Farmworker Smoke and Excessive Heat Protection Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4844</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250801">August 1, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000635">Ms. Dexter</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish an occupational safety and health standard to protect farmworkers from wildfire smoke and excessive heat, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6E9C5F6D2F944444A879AAAD5D09A933" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H0841642A48714097A55BD49BCE9DA1DF"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Farmworker Smoke and Excessive Heat Protection Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HF347FB86B10344F6BE87BD6ACD1E719C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that, as of the date of enactment of this Act—</text>
<paragraph id="HD3A8D83E8BE64B33B685F68ECE136D01"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the wildfire season has increased by over 2 months since the 1970s, and wildfires have become increasingly prevalent across the United States due to prolonged droughts and extreme temperatures;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7E0B697B596342169E464D9C3D5E30E7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the average annual temperatures in the western United States have increased by 1.9 degrees Fahrenheit since 1970;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HCA80A5EF54E14E3C97744E7FBEF4A0A8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>wildfire smoke often contains toxic chemicals and particulates, creating hazardous air quality conditions;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB9C4B9957D67415CBEB7CFA893FF88D4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>wildfire smoke often persists for extended periods of time and can travel hundreds of miles;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H891BB08F904845DD997265CF372E6308"><enum>(5)</enum><text>wildfire smoke inhalation is harmful to human health, particularly for vulnerable populations, including outdoor workers;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H80B5B699BFFF4C33B70B6A738611F719"><enum>(6)</enum><text>excessive heat poses a potentially deadly threat to those without protection from the heat, including outdoor workers; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H41FFB80C6F434DF9B7528A2F63D7CB6E"><enum>(7)</enum><text>more than 100 people died during the June 2021 heat wave in Oregon, including a farmworker.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HE3F934E972074A75B4872898EF4B4408"><enum>3.</enum><header>Occupational safety and health standard to protect farmworkers from wildfire smoke and excessive heat</header> <subsection id="H11BDE38F49F446B590F1D861D73BA11F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text>
<paragraph id="H72CA440ADC1E4D4E881A4CFDEDA3ABD5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agricultural operation employer</header><text>The term <term>agricultural operation employer</term> means an employer, as defined in section 3 of the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/652">29 U.S.C. 652</external-xref>), engaged in farming or agricultural operation.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE5A090C61C9A4C2486DC2A5D51350850"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Excessive heat</header><text>The term <term>excessive heat</term> includes outdoor or indoor exposure to heat at a level that exceeds the capacities of the body to maintain normal body functions and may cause heat-related injury, illness, or fatality (including heat stroke, heat exhaustion, heat syncope, heat cramps, or heat rashes).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1FFC2AC4BC9D4B8D829D931BD85E1B98"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Farmworker</header><text>The term <term>farmworker</term> means an employee, as defined in section 3 of the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/652">29 U.S.C. 652</external-xref>), engaged in farming or other agricultural work for an agricultural operation employer.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1A562A1DC8294A7D917B26DDC20299D0"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Labor.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H27E01AF06D1E46F69A803008A0FA9FD9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Initial occupational safety and health standard</header>
<paragraph id="HD92A9BD5AF294929BBFD9D07E0E63234"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>During the period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act and ending on the date of the promulgation of the occupational safety and health standard under subsection (c), the Secretary shall deem the initial standard to protect farmworkers from wildfire smoke and excessive heat described in paragraph (2) to be an occupational safety and health standard under section 6 of the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/655">29 U.S.C. 655</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB8FFB51294D34C31AB9F3A9C83CDB689"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents of initial standard</header><text>The initial standard described in this subsection shall require that an agricultural operation employer—</text>
<subparagraph id="H18FF863B875A42B1837C6E01AF254DBE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide farmworkers with appropriate equipment to protect from wildfire smoke when air quality at the workplace reaches a level determined by the Secretary to be dangerous to human health;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB2B4D75BDABB49E59B7252F45552034E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensure that the equipment provided under subparagraph (A) includes a N95 respirator or N100 respirator or other equipment certified by the National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health to protect from wildfire smoke exposure;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HEA670692134146D1B99ACEBFD92366E8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>require mandatory use of the equipment described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) when air quality at the workplace reaches an extremely dangerous level, as determined by the Secretary;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H82A6604A65F0498AB35E3AA20B4356AD"><enum>(D)</enum><text>provide farmworkers with appropriate equipment to protect from excessive heat when the heat reaches a level determined by the Secretary to be dangerous to health;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H38B30C39278A48E893AE7E791C9F3628"><enum>(E)</enum><text>ensure that the equipment provided under subparagraph (D) includes water and cooling facilities to protect from excessive heat;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H627261B1BC1648FA9432774DEC75F343"> <enum>(F)</enum> <text>require mandatory use of the equipment described in subparagraphs (D) and (E) when the excessive heat reaches an extremely dangerous level, as determined by the Secretary;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD5AD8570792B4ECE85EEEDC14F7C550C"><enum>(G)</enum><text>provide, with protective equipment provided under any of subparagraphs (A) through (F)—</text> <clause id="H430E8BEFCFC34F89BA463EEFE76C8FF2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>training and education materials to farmworkers, in a language understood by the farmworkers, regarding—</text>
<subclause id="H0509F03AF91D4D64AEF5DE2828C3412B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>how to properly use the protective equipment;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H0588C0B6F7CF4E05BC4F87D387DFF545"><enum>(II)</enum><text>how long and under what conditions the protective equipment is effective; and</text></subclause>
<subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC7EAF4A7CA1C49C493B323A922F06E41"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the potential health impacts of breathing wildfire smoke without proper protection or the signs of heat illness, as applicable; and</text></subclause></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB0B89FE8E72740E6A22BC9BC1A0CB075"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an opportunity for the farmworkers to ask questions and receive responses regarding the training and education materials described in clause (i); and</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF1A0BD6B3D0B40538E8394353C16DCA6"><enum>(H)</enum><text>require that, once the air quality or heat level has reached a dangerous or extremely dangerous level, as determined by the Secretary under subparagraph (A), (C), (D), or (F), farmworkers be provided mandatory rest breaks—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9005F60382C7449480A2804ED0ABBD05"><enum>(i)</enum><text>of at least 10 minutes every 2 hours; and</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB5B42C1B24154284A710B41A5B42FB8B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in shaded areas where the exposure to smoke is decreased or the temperature is decreased, as applicable.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCD1EC42DE89F46A7AAC0320156D8726A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text>The initial standard described in this subsection shall be enforced in the same manner as a standard promulgated under section 6 of the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/655">29 U.S.C. 655</external-xref>), including the prohibition on discrimination under section 11(c) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/660">29 U.S.C. 660(c)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H8BEABB0C316C4FC6A48BE294A003C15A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Occupational safety and health standard</header>
<paragraph id="H12F611256BAF4AD19CFA2B89697E0F77"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>By not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall begin promulgating an occupational safety and health standard under section 6 of the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/655">29 U.S.C. 655</external-xref>) to protect farmworkers from wildfire smoke and excessive heat.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4EA65729FAA04165B1152D7FF795B853"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The standard promulgated under paragraph (1) shall—</text>
<subparagraph id="HEB204445DCDD425BBBD7BC69E416A165"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide safety and health protections for farmworkers working for agricultural operation employers that provide at least the same level of health and safety protection as the requirements under subsection (b)(2);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8897E8D70F694BFEB8D21EFF7281CE5E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide no less protection than the most protective smoke or heat protection standard adopted by a State;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HAEEE93B9CEC24D7BB6248A09277F30F5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>detail the potential health impacts of breathing wildfire smoke without proper protection; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HED384EB95A164F4789924D05ED6DA111"><enum>(D)</enum><text>detail the potential health impacts of working in excessive heat without proper protection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H2137F31DC1494D6A90121FC2E03F1BA1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Collaboration and technical assistance</header>
<paragraph id="HCFF32303B78B416DBC97766529116CF7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An agricultural operation employer may seek advice or assistance from the Secretary of Labor or a State or local health department regarding the equipment and training and education materials needed to meet the requirements under subsection (b)(2) (or any similar requirement of a standard promulgated under subsection (c)).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H43F9FEF72C4B49EFBE637159BB7DDB47"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Department of Labor duties</header> <subparagraph id="H965478EA833F4BABBD23180ADE3195B9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text>
<clause id="H01BC0C9B701C45AAA63F644C22B4389C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>provide technical assistance, upon the request of an agricultural operation employer, regarding how to meet the employer requirements of this section; and</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H711FFC11C02641E2B6FA6561028DA9CB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>develop sample training and education materials that may be used by agricultural operation employers to meet the requirements of subsection (b)(2)(G) (or any similar requirement of a standard promulgated under subsection (c)).</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H42361F9231AA43DA9B51963CFC1D6422"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Collaboration</header><text>In developing training and education materials under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall—</text> <clause id="H0B766BB3031C4240A0B9AD01452C53FC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>work with community organizations for hard-to-reach farmworkers due to geographic isolation, language barriers, or literacy issues; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H962F0E9027BF43B1A0CB4CC7EAA95303"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>seek input in the development of the training and education materials in alternative languages, including indigenous languages.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBB48BA53E1E245F896E26C84756EA36B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Collaboration with community organizations</header><text>The Secretary may, upon request, provide the training and educational materials developed under paragraph (2)(A) to relevant community and nonprofit organizations.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

