<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H36EF33DA4829452B8B19CD4B344CC5E4" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3574 IH: To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to permit qualified distributions from section 529 plans for certain transportation and parking expenses.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3574</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250523">May 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001227">Ms. McClellan</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S001156">Ms. Sánchez</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to permit qualified distributions from section 529 plans for certain transportation and parking expenses.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6B0F1EA0A5E6422D9B027F35CF596F3B" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HB1386F3A47D14EC78FD62BE65E91F819" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Qualified distributions from section 529 plans for certain transportation and parking expenses</header>
<subsection id="H9444A7FB6FF94114BC71391407BF92ED"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/529">Section 529(e)(3)(A)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of clause (ii), by striking the period at the end of clause (iii) and inserting <quote>, and</quote>, and by inserting after clause (iii) the following new clause:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H07C0B0C057C042C2B3960BB4FE3B2AE5" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <clause id="HBC9E9ABED7A747E79F5CA743A53C7521"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reasonable expenses for transportation (including parking) to such eligible educational institution, not in excess of the allowance (applicable to the student) for transportation included in the cost of attendance (as defined in section 472 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087ll">20 U.S.C. 1087ll</external-xref>), as in effect on the date of the enactment of this clause) as determined by such eligible educational institution.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection>
<subsection id="HC78FD830BC5B40048F47C8E819E37CBD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Apprenticeship programs</header><text>Section 529(c)(8) of such Code is amended by inserting <quote>and to reasonable expenses for transportation (including parking) in connection with such participation</quote> before the period at the end.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HA498381EA265474BA25684BDEFCF34AC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to distributions made after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

