<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-SIL25954-XVF-51-TMX">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2776 IS: To amend the Justice for United States Victims of State Sponsored Terrorism Act to provide rules for payments to Havlish Settling Judgment Creditors.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>II</distribution-code>
        <congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session>1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. 2776</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action>
            <action-date date="20250911">September 11, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S418">Mr. Fetterman</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S433">Mr. McCormick</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which
                was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee
                    on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title>To amend the Justice for United States Victims of State Sponsored Terrorism
            Act to provide rules for payments to Havlish Settling Judgment
            Creditors.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause">
        <section section-type="section-one" id="ida41cc4dfaa164b0683e6a4e076cc8948">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Justice for United States victims of state sponsored terrorism</header>
            <subsection id="id04a74dd98ecd44f68be3af99deef8ade">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
 <text>The Justice for United States Victims of State Sponsored Terrorism Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/20144">34 U.S.C. 20144</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
                <paragraph id="id223d2e335b60497d8eea90aa50ec543b">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>in subsection (e)(2)(B), by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id101327a16ea248f3b31e05a165d39847"> <clause id="idb35a46395eeb46f68a25d169d31165f8"> <enum>(vi)</enum> <header>Exception for the Havlish Settling Judgment Creditors</header> <subclause id="id51e2701255da4be28711f391175af7df"> <enum>(I)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text>This subsection does not apply with respect to—</text>
                                <item id="id4430a7b56a4f4d28b75b86b1ebf730fe">
                                    <enum>(aa)</enum>
 <text>a Havlish Settling Judgment Creditor who previously elected to participate in the Fund in accordance with clause (iii) or who submitted an application for conditional payment in accordance with clause (iv); or</text>
                                </item>
                                <item id="id9eb69c2005e54ef189e5f3887cf1847a">
                                    <enum>(bb)</enum>
 <text>the assets, or the net proceeds of the sale of properties or related assets, attributable to a person described in item (aa).</text>
                                </item>
                            </subclause>
                            <subclause id="id8ee1c4b56f814ebda1d1c4566efe861e">
                                <enum>(II)</enum>
                                <header>Release of funds held in escrow</header>
 <text>All funds allocated to a Havlish Settling Judgment Creditor and withheld from distribution under clause (iv) shall be released and paid to the Havlish Settling Judgment Creditor to whom such withheld funds had been allocated.</text>
                            </subclause>
                            <subclause id="ida5746e7b507c4916a63e73dfe3197284">
                                <enum>(III)</enum>
                                <header>Future payment eligibility</header>
 <text>Each Havlish Settling Judgment Creditor shall be entitled to participate in future rounds of payments in the same manner as all other claimants described in paragraphs (10) through (14) of subsection (j), irrespective of any application for conditional payment submitted under clause (iv).</text>
                            </subclause>
                        </clause>
                        <after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block>
                    </quoted-block>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id1c14733e5e864de192548d16fa2dccbe">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>in subsection (j), by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida50acf69186849568ec8af67091ba896"> <paragraph id="id292809c239984b8b9082794460d73a39"> <enum>(17)</enum> <header>Havlish settling judgment creditor</header> <text>The term <term>Havlish Settling Judgment Creditor</term> means a plaintiff, an estate or successor in interest thereof, who—</text>
                            <subparagraph id="id3a39d0d559e641a38777e873cea0c523">
                                <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>has an eligible claim under subsection (c) that arises out of the September 11, 2001, terrorist attacks against the United States; and</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <subparagraph id="id593d2b331fbe4eb18c5d7103d9caa6e1">
                                <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>is a Settling Judgment Creditor identified in the Order dated April 16, 2014, in the proceedings captioned In re 650 Fifth Avenue and Related Properties, No. 08–CV–10934 (S.D.N.Y.).</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                        </paragraph>
                        <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
                    </quoted-block>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="idfed37343aed64435a1633a36fee66304">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Effective date</header>
 <text>The amendments made by subsection (a) shall take effect as if enacted on December 29, 2022.</text>
            </subsection>
        </section>
    </legis-body>
</bill>

