<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDF71E0623F404ED5AFE155F679C83037" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2052 IH: Combating Houthi Threats and Aggression Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2052</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250311">March 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000590">Mr. Green of Tennessee</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001157">Mr. McCaul</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000605">Mr. Perry</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000397">Mrs. Kim</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To impose sanctions on the Houthis for attacks on international shipping, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HFBD7FE6DBCAB4CBA8039ABEDF1924868" style="OLC"><section id="H7AFBF87A1AD94A9CB5CABBF597911A8D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Combating Houthi Threats and Aggression Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HDF68A762DF33402BBE45C7B445CBB98F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the policy of the United States to work with United States allies and partners to safeguard maritime security in the Red Sea and the Gulf of Aden, including by supporting interdiction efforts and by opposing attacks on international shipping that threaten the free flow of commerce, endanger innocent mariners, and violate international law, as such attacks harm the global economy, destabilize the Middle East and Africa region, and undermine United States national security interests.</text></section><section id="H6C98936B708D49F4BAB94258E7976C63"><enum>3.</enum><header>Report on capability of the houthis to threaten united states national security and foreign policy goals</header><subsection id="H6FFE03CAFF3B4E15A22E216A6A2530EB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the capability of the Houthis (also known as <quote>Ansar Allah</quote>) to threaten United States national security and foreign policy goals.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5FDC39DFD7B441D89DCA7D12BB14A783"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Matters To be included</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall include the following:</text><paragraph id="HCB12C54400A5457199EDFE62C9FDD152"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An assessment of senior Houthi leadership’ intentions and capacity to conduct and sustain military operations from Yemen that target the United States, Israel, or global shipping.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9B2D5F595B8B45C2BFC2A7756D255D3D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A description of the funding, materiel, training, and other forms of support the Houthis receive from Iran, Hezbollah, or any other entity acting for or on behalf of Iran, including contributions to advance the Houthis’ indigenous weapons production capability and existing weapons arsenal.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB40FA7CB8D7D4E1D8F215657F7B33E05"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A description of the Houthis’ ballistic missile and unmanned delivery systems, including those that are covered under Category 1 or Category 2 of the Missile Control Technology Regime and the precision and reach of such weapons.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H18C45CA4F5304300AFCF442D75323820"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A description of the Houthis’ maritime capabilities, including sea missiles and drones.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF24F0C257C494CC6BA517097C591DCE9"><enum>(5)</enum><text>An analysis of the Houthis’ current indigenous weapons production capabilities and how their control over the Al-Hudaydah port and Sana’a international airport enables them to sustain weapons production.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF2571FE9F5E9450BB74A7B936376CBC5"><enum>(6)</enum><text>An assessment of the Houthis’ stockpiles and employment of commercial off-the-shelf (COTS) dual-use drone technology, and the countries of origin for these products.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFC01D9699F2D4DC4A2ED9B13D8307CAE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means—</text><paragraph id="HA12EF11BBF154C41AA11DEF03C0D3254"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAE289D3AA22640E189EA1E644763761D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H35300D8CD9324D51A4DA55659387F7B2"><enum>4.</enum><header>Report on houthi attacks that threaten freedom of navigation in the red sea and gulf of aden</header><subsection id="H64E5F05139C34B33AACB6482BC695938"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the day of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the following:</text><paragraph id="HB4D8AEC7FBDF4C758646684A2A6C8B6D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A summary of Houthi (also known as <quote>Ansar Allah</quote>) attacks that threaten freedom of navigation in the Red Sea and Gulf of Aden.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD7755D23DD444F98BAE58CA0068D19AA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An assessment of the impact that Houthi threats to freedom of navigation in the Red Sea and Gulf of Aden have on United States security interests.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCCF30B75B6B848849B4BFD320D67C5B1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>An assessment of the impact that Houthi threats to freedom of navigation in the Red Sea and Gulf of Aden have on the global economy, including the United States economy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H645D3D09C6034D2989F834759B305D1E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An assessment of Iran’s role in the Houthis’ attacks that threaten freedom of navigation in the Red Sea and Gulf of Aden, including Iran’s provision of targeting assistance to the Houthis.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD49353B8300B4A60A177BCEE0C05B9F3"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A description of China’s presence in the Red Sea and Gulf of Aden during the reporting period.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H24D444643A004A2FB0FD5709314EF4CE"><enum>(6)</enum><text>An assessment of how the Houthis’ attacks in the Red Sea and Gulf of Aden impact Russia, China, and Iran’s freedom of navigation in those waterways relative to the United States and our partners’ freedom of navigation.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDEA166E315AD45F09CD1D8AD26AB51DA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Scope</header><text>The initial report required by subsection (a) shall address the period beginning on October 7, 2023, and ending on the date that is 90 days after date of the enactment of this Act, and each subsequent report shall address the one-year period following the conclusion of the prior report.</text></subsection><subsection id="H88309B13C0B2482AAF58B0097C534939"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means—</text><paragraph id="HF32BE4DADC574422B2DCA949DF3BEE56"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDC23D68B6272439CB1E2B280C097441C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H739EE21BBE51426D876BEC2ED82E77F9"><enum>5.</enum><header>Report on violations of the united nations arms embargo against yemen authorized under united nations security council resolution 2216</header><subsection id="H9A84C4E9EBC944CEAAE9213DFEC158FD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the following:</text><paragraph id="HCE48E1CCEA77411B92E775E8A08EEDCF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A description of violations or attempted violations of the United Nations arms embargo against Yemen authorized under United Nations Security Council Resolution 2216 (2015) and successor resolutions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDDA760026D7E49FCB5E2A42E811FEE38"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A list of incidents in which the United States or other countries interdicted weapons and related components believed to be intended for the Houthis, including—</text><subparagraph id="H12F5B33E8F1A49EE96BE431184E7EEF7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for each interdiction incident, what specific entity conducted the interdiction, the circumstances and location of such interdiction, what weapons or components were seized and the believed origins of such components, and under what authority each such seizure took place;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8F762203B3D2436381C0C8D74F165A4B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of what United States Government resources are currently devoted to identifying, disrupting, interdicting, or otherwise dismantling the flow of illicit weapons intended for the Houthis, and identifying under what authorities these activities take place; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H36F2658AAEF34DD5B3063C40C6D7616D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>United States coordination with international partners on efforts to identify, disrupt, dismantle or interdict illicit weapons flows to the Houthis, including identifying United States security assistance and cooperation programs that contribute to the interdiction efforts of such partners.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9CEE2919870D4932A1BA2203CDAFE567"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Scope</header><text>The initial report required by subsection (a) shall address the period beginning on January 1, 2022, and ending on the date that is 90 days after date of the enactment of this Act, and each subsequent report shall address the one-year period following the conclusion of the prior report.</text></subsection><subsection id="H93BACF9515D24CB1A2A781522C635D87"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means—</text><paragraph id="H49AB2671AC324C9D8B4BF4535874BA1E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAECFC889EE234689902FBF881DBC3116"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HB3F652F1C45E42368BC6287711DD6F2D"><enum>6.</enum><header>Sanctions with respect to any attacks by the houthis on international shipping in the red sea and gulf of aden and other military support to the houthis</header><subsection id="H5174F126664A4ABD81EAFE71EB231C45"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President shall impose the sanctions described in subsection (b) with respect to any foreign person the President determines, on or after the date of enactment of this Act—</text><paragraph id="H9780FC783C07468AB133069B180D3F61"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to be responsible for or complicit in, or to have directly or indirectly engaged in, any attacks by the Houthis (also known as <quote>Ansar Allah</quote>) that threaten international shipping in the Red Sea or Gulf of Aden;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H747CD0FDAA7D4AC4B45F5F058D91BAB6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>knowingly engages in, or attempts to engage in, activities or transactions that have materially contributed to, or pose a significant risk of materially contributing to the conduct described in paragraph (1); or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2978EAD78B374A7B9F76BDD5C06F3B74"><enum>(3)</enum><text>knowingly engages in any activity that materially contributes to the supply, sale, or transfer directly or indirectly of arms and related materiel of all types, including weapons and ammunition, military vehicles and equipment, paramilitary equipment, and spare parts for the aforementioned, and technical assistance, training, financial or other assistance, to any foreign person engaging in the conduct described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9526E652D28944F596C8C434A9DC4A7F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sanctions described</header><text>The sanctions described in this subsection are the following:</text><paragraph id="H55E1E6438DDC488EAB4113FEF65CE407"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Blocking of property</header><text>The President shall exercise all authorities granted under the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>) to the extent necessary to block and prohibit all transactions in property and interests in property of the foreign person if such property and interests in property are in the United States, come within the United States, or come within the possession or control of a United States person.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H99DC87650E2E4A8EB1080E1F635C3D9D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Ineligibility for visas, admission, or parole</header><subparagraph id="HD2142571242A4A1DBD79A4C7AB5C6F12"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Visas, admission, or parole</header><text>An alien described in subsection (a) shall be—</text><clause id="HB1749FB577C6498A9B61F48136BB2DC9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>inadmissible to the United States;</text></clause><clause id="H5E04E40742954109AF17A85F576128C6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>ineligible to receive a visa or other documentation to enter the United States; and</text></clause><clause id="H08E6C23FC9894621BCBF3C3EE16B7F24"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>otherwise ineligible to be admitted or paroled into the United States or to receive any other benefit under the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5DF9355D133E404AB09F1C966776CF57"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Current visas revoked</header><clause id="H5293313C242A4A37A34768270EFF6401"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The visa or other entry documentation of any alien described in subsection (a) is subject to revocation regardless of the issue date of the visa or other entry documentation.</text></clause><clause id="H9D9DF5D25F8D47DF91DD66C5363EFEE2"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Immediate effect</header><text>A revocation under clause (i) shall, in accordance with section 221(i) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1201">8 U.S.C. 1201(i)</external-xref>)—</text><subclause id="H5BFBD7E86FC14FBEB3A92BB4FD4A9E89"><enum>(I)</enum><text>take effect immediately; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H3403BB17DEA14B4BB494E1C00B5B195C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>cancel any other valid visa or entry documentation that is in the possession of the alien.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0FBE3EEE08F04F05A9C86BC1AEAE5E77"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text>Any person that violates, or attempts to violate, subsection (b) or any regulation, license, or order issued pursuant to that subsection, shall be subject to the penalties set forth in subsections (b) and (c) of section 206 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1705">50 U.S.C. 1705</external-xref>) to the same extent as a person that commits an unlawful act described in subsection (a) of that section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H538EBBD52FD847C1A93AC049D51626B5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Waiver</header><paragraph id="H8375ADD2AB7C4E1B9F8829C9D0D586DD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President may waive, on a case-by-case basis, the application of sanctions under this section for periods not to exceed 180 days with respect to a foreign person only if, not later than 15 days prior to the date on which the waiver is to take effect, the President submits to the appropriate congressional committees a written determination and justification that the waiver is in the national security interests of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE62345555CF94FA483D46030A30B12E9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Briefing</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the issuance of a waiver under paragraph (1), and every 180 days thereafter while the waiver remains in effect, the President shall brief the appropriate congressional committees on the reasons for the waiver.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H515532B0ADAE4D5187A94081E45CD85D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>The President may exercise all authorities provided under sections 203 and 205 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1702 and 1704) to carry out this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1BFE82481AB8496CAA653511691EA4BE"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Regulations</header><paragraph id="H7EB19BD0B01048E794C28D32D46707F3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President shall, not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, promulgate regulations as necessary for the implementation of this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1CBB9D32740F4555BE5C2B8708491DB0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notification to congress</header><text>Not later than 10 days before the promulgation of regulations under this subsection, the President shall notify the appropriate congressional committees of the proposed regulations and the provisions of this section that the regulations are implementing.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H631997B0021A4575B9E6B281400DA0BF"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><paragraph id="H7BE9EB38551E462487B6D768FB4061CA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Exception for intelligence activities</header><text>Sanctions under this section shall not apply to any activity subject to the reporting requirements under title V of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3091">50 U.S.C. 3091 et seq.</external-xref>) or any authorized intelligence activities of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4C491CB29FFD4956BDCE786F07B42674"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception to comply with international obligations and for law enforcement activities</header><text>Sanctions under this section shall not apply with respect to an alien if admitting or paroling the alien into the United States is necessary—</text><subparagraph id="HF92C580DD39747E9870CBC0419B89CCD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to permit the United States to comply with the Agreement regarding the Headquarters of the United Nations, signed at Lake Success June 26, 1947, and entered into force November 21, 1947, between the United Nations and the United States, or other applicable international obligations; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF752B532FEAF4B7182B0F00BE9E1058B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to carry out or assist authorized law enforcement activity in the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HB7C231D68F7B4D8F9B8DD730AD6B95DD"><enum>7.</enum><header>Sunset</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act shall terminate on the date that is 5 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

