<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" slc-id="S1-NEW25354-V4X-N7-1XV"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>103 SRES 150 IS: Supporting the goals and ideals of “Countering International Parental Child Abduction Month” and expressing the sense of the Senate that Congress should raise awareness of the harm caused by international parental child abduction. </dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 150</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250401" legis-day="20250331">April 1 (legislative day, March 31), 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S384">Mr. Tillis</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S364">Mr. Murphy</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Supporting the goals and ideals of <quote>Countering International Parental Child Abduction Month</quote> and expressing the sense of the Senate that Congress should raise awareness of the harm caused by international parental child abduction. </official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas thousands of children have been abducted from the United States by parents, separating those children from their parents who remain in the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas it is illegal under section 1204 of title 18, United States Code, to remove, or attempt to remove, a child from the United States or to retain a child (who has been in the United States) outside of the United States with the intent to obstruct the lawful exercise of parental rights;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 9,816 children were reported abducted from the United States between 2010 and 2020;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, during 2023, 1 or more cases of international parental child abduction involving children who are citizens of the United States were identified in 105 countries around the world;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States is a party to the Convention on the Civil Aspects of International Child Abduction, done at The Hague, October 25, 1980 (TIAS 11670) (referred to in this preamble as the <quote>Hague Convention on Abduction</quote>), which—</text><paragraph id="idd1f5542bb1084fa2b81033c52c23259b"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the prompt return of wrongly removed or retained children; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb738ce450118472c9b924605eb147265"><enum>(2)</enum><text>calls for all participating parties to respect parental custody rights;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the majority of children who were abducted from the United States have yet to be reunited with their custodial parents;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2023, Argentina, Belize, Brazil, Bulgaria, Ecuador, Egypt, Honduras, India, Jordan, the Republic of Korea, Montenegro, Peru, Poland, Romania, the Russian Federation, and the United Arab Emirates were identified pursuant to the Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/9101">22 U.S.C. 9101 et seq.</external-xref>) as engaging in a pattern of noncompliance (as defined in section 3 of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/9101">22 U.S.C. 9101</external-xref>));</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, between 2015 and 2023, a total of 19 countries were previously identified as engaging in a pattern of noncompliance (as so defined), including Austria, the Bahamas, the People’s Republic of China, Colombia, Costa Rica, the Dominican Republic, Guatemala, Japan, Lebanon, Morocco, Nicaragua, Oman, Pakistan, Panama, Saudi Arabia, Slovakia, Trinidad and Tobago, and Tunisia, showing the importance of continued enforcement of United States law by the executive branch to ensure the return of abducted children; </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Supreme Court of the United States has recognized that family abduction—</text><paragraph id="idf18ac04e507540e489c2950b32b73bd0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is a form of child abuse with potentially <quote>devastating consequences for a child</quote>, which may include negative impacts on the physical and mental well-being of the child; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id78fad3cc6ce844f5a350dfd584fb82c5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may cause a child to <quote>experience a loss of community and stability, leading to loneliness, anger, and fear of abandonment</quote>;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to the 2010 Report on Compliance with the Hague Convention on the Civil Aspects of International Child Abduction by the Department of State, an abducted child is at risk of significant short- and long-term problems, including <quote>anxiety, eating problems, nightmares, mood swings, sleep disturbances, and aggressive behavior</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas international parental child abduction has devastating emotional consequences for the child and for the parent from whom the child is separated;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States has a history of promoting child welfare through institutions, including—</text><paragraph id="ide07d2084359e4c878a5de7dda0a1f221"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Children’s Bureau of the Administration for Children and Families of the Department of Health and Human Services; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id27293e19131b4be1b4d10b4394dd6eaa"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Office of Children’s Issues of the Bureau of Consular Affairs of the Department of State;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Coalition to End International Parental Child Abduction, through dedicated advocacy and regular testimony, has highlighted the importance of this issue to Congress and called on successive administrations to take concerted action to stop international parental child abduction and repatriate kidnapped United States children;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Bring Abducted Children Home, Bring Our Kids Home, iStand Parent Network, and the Coalition to End International Parental Child Abduction have been recognized by the Department of Justice as nonprofit organizations specializing in international parental child abduction;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Congress has signaled a commitment to ending international parental child abduction by enacting—</text><paragraph id="id7808a490902c4ac6bbd41171d6870d16"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the International Child Abduction Remedies Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/9001">22 U.S.C. 9001 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc56a90ead10a4067adc7a270f80855a5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the International Parental Kidnapping Crime Act of 1993 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/103/173">Public Law 103–173</external-xref>; 107 Stat. 1998), which enacted section 1204 of title 18, United States Code; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb30a399f73a943b7974d5ccfb902f70d"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/9101">22 U.S.C. 9101 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Senate adopted Senate Resolution 543 (112th Congress), agreed to December 4, 2012, condemning the international abduction of children;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Senate adopted Senate Resolution 431 (115th Congress), agreed to April 19, 2018, to raise awareness of, and opposition to, international parental child abduction;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Senate adopted Senate Resolution 23 (116th Congress), agreed to April 11, 2019, to raise awareness of the harm caused by international parental child abduction;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Senate adopted Senate Resolution 568 (117th Congress), agreed to July 21, 2022, to raise awareness of the harm caused by international parental child abduction;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Senate adopted Senate Resolution 115 (118th Congress), agreed to May, 10 2023, to raise awareness of the harm caused by international parental child abduction;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Congress calls on the Department of State to fully use the tools available under the Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/9101">22 U.S.C. 9101 et seq.</external-xref>) to negotiate, and make publicly available, bilateral agreements or memorandums of understanding—</text><paragraph id="ide83925fa2bf14839be18745bfc7eb24d"><enum>(1)</enum><text>with countries not parties to the Hague Convention on Abduction to resolve abduction and access cases; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id52702b32d5604e2eaedb83ce0632d3b7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>regarding open abduction and access cases predating the Hague Convention on Abduction with countries that have thereafter become parties to the Hague Convention on Abduction;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas all 50 States and the District of Columbia have enacted laws criminalizing parental kidnapping;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2023, the Prevention Branch of the Office of Children’s Issues of the Department of State—</text><paragraph id="id3782d79e143d4ae09501d0a9a542acf7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>fielded more than 4,600 inquiries from the general public relating to preventing a child from being removed from the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id727f0ce9455d4b6898e9ff042f3a4650"><enum>(2)</enum><text>enrolled more than 3,700 children in the Children’s Passport Issuance Alert Program, which—</text><subparagraph id="id701e25f681354bea8aea702285f4122d"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is 1 of the most important tools of the Department of State for preventing international parental child abduction;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7f96470eacf14381b2902f783f217b9e"><enum>(B)</enum><text>allows the Office of Children’s Issues to contact the enrolling parent or legal guardian to verify whether the parental consent requirement has been met when a passport application has been submitted for an enrolled child; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf76c32ff03b54bdb8ab0b8ec4f68b2d0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>has enrolled a total of over 66,600 children in the program since its inception;</text></subparagraph></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Department of State cannot track the ultimate destination of a child through the use of the passport issued by the Department of State if the child is transported to a third country after departing from the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas a child who is a citizen of the United States may have another nationality and may travel using a passport issued by another country, which—</text><paragraph id="id3b0e109b5ac94756bcf219e432e5a8ad"><enum>(1)</enum><text>increases the difficulty of determining the whereabouts of the child; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id547cb0e5d99945dc823fa5cd420994e2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>makes efforts to prevent abduction more critical;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, during 2023, 205 children were returned to the United States, and an additional 119 abduction cases, involving 147 children, were resolved without the children being returned to the United States; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2023, the Department of Homeland Security, in coordination with the Prevention Branch of the Office of Children’s Issues of the Department of State, enrolled 341 children in the Prevent Abduction Program, which is aimed at preventing international parental child abduction through coordination with U.S. Customs and Border Patrol officers at the airport, seaport, or land border ports of entry by intercepting the child before departure: Now, therefore, be it </text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="S1"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id5e2feef0fe784baa8dafe15f1c491b78"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognizes and observes <quote>Countering International Parental Child Abduction Month</quote> during the period beginning on April 1, 2025, and ending on April 30, 2025, to raise awareness of, and opposition to, international parental child abduction; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbff054ca4ae44b3b8f63a94db1c5f72f"><enum>(2)</enum><text>urges the United States to continue playing a leadership role in raising awareness about the devastating impacts of international parental child abduction by educating the public about the negative emotional, psychological, and physical consequences to children and parents victimized by international parental child abduction. </text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

