<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-FLO25128-3L1-F7-C81"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1366 IS: Boundary Waters Wilderness Protection Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1366</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250409">April 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S394">Ms. Smith</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAF00">Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To protect, for current and future generations, the Boundary Waters Canoe Area Wilderness and interconnected Federal land and waters, including Voyageurs National Park, within the Rainy River Watershed in the State of Minnesota, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H5E623FC5F0F14F2FADE686B5FBF79D72"><section section-type="section-one" id="H3CAEB2D75B804B84A38DAFFFB8359CA7"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Boundary Waters Wilderness Protection Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H21BCF4EFB1DC447AACD4610D5250CAD8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Withdrawal of certain Federal land and waters in the State of Minnesota</header><subsection id="idb5d09e97c2ea4b6ab1813c0dd89ed71a" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id78beb6d39be74d1cb01974b27d44e085"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Map</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Map</term> means the map attached to Public Land Order No. 7917 (88 Fed. Reg. 6308 (January 31, 2023)).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8f470f7a11884c5a893dffc8bc0c8b54"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Boundary</header><text>The term <term>Boundary</term> means the boundary labeled <quote>Withdrawal Application Boundary</quote> in the legend of the figure entitled <quote>Withdrawal application area</quote> and identified as figure 1, as included in the environmental assessment prepared by the Forest Service entitled <quote>Rainy River Withdrawal Environmental Assessment</quote> and dated June 2022.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4f101cba96b74523b4189a430aaf5d24"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Withdrawal</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (c), subject to valid existing rights, the approximately 225,504 acres of Federal land and waters in the Rainy River Watershed of the Superior National Forest in the State of Minnesota, as depicted on the Map (including any land or waters or interest in land or waters that are acquired by the United States after the date of enactment of this Act within the Boundary), are withdrawn from—</text><paragraph id="id662b23cff6764eadad1e2685cfeab224"><enum>(1)</enum><text>all forms of entry, appropriation, and disposal under the public land laws;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfdacd39bc65d4d33b42b49bd668394c0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id426433d44762486e9ff6f20a37cc3964"><enum>(3)</enum><text>operation of the mineral leasing, mineral materials, and geothermal leasing laws.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idf9a9859d818940ed932c1098e725de0d"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Removal of sand, gravel, granite, iron ore, and taconite</header><text>The Chief of the Forest Service may permit the removal of sand, gravel, granite, iron ore, and taconite from National Forest System land within the area withdrawn under subsection (b) if the Chief of the Forest Service determines that the removal is not detrimental to the water quality, air quality, and health of the forest habitat within the Rainy River Watershed.</text></subsection><subsection id="id9acebd0629c9479b9123b9737c5ceed8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Availability of Map and figure</header><text>The Map and the figure depicting the Boundary shall be kept on file and made available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of the Forest Service and the Bureau of Land Management.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

