<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ALL25086-LXT-3F-V2V"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1079 IS: Restoring Law and Order Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1079</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250314">March 14, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S407">Mr. Hagerty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S355">Mr. Cruz</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S437">Mr. Justice</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to establish a grant program for law enforcement agencies, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Restoring Law and Order Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id73729541C560413A9FDD29B581C5A69A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Grant program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10101">34 U.S.C. 10101 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id616CDA82EFED493C89559EE216761393"><part id="idA901D26E7A734A61A4C273F6B63FEAFE" style="OLC"><enum>PP</enum><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="id78FB77A33ED84AF1A0F2AFF9D8A3179B"><enum>3061.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Eligible entity defined</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this part, the term <term>eligible entity</term> means an agency of a State, unit of local government, or Indian Tribe that is authorized by law or by an agency of a State, unit of local government, or Indian Tribe to engage in or supervise the prevention, detection, investigation, or prosecution of any violation of criminal law.</text></section><section id="idF0BCC62F29344A228D0181FE9EE3E26A"><enum>3062.</enum><header>Establishment of make America safe again grant program</header><subsection id="idB5E566D07DB44D47AE1C402D541A2D6B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Attorney General shall award grants to eligible entities to—</text><paragraph id="idFAC17A13BCCC4C5290A15E7131B06056"><enum>(1)</enum><text>hire and retain law enforcement officers, including by awarding bonuses to law enforcement officers;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id964301ED3A9A4462BBA363AFF13CC249"><enum>(2)</enum><text>target, combat, and prosecute vehicle thefts, including carjackings;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3B99F362C2564E34B73F87F456858EB5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>prevent violent crime by prioritizing stringent sentences for repeat offenders, including juvenile offenders;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idB6C749B5648A487D8EFFB594C9F83F3C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>use public safety tools such as bail and pretrial detention to prevent dangerous offenders from returning to communities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7D4E54ECF13149E692196E15C5440D54"><enum>(5)</enum><text>acquire resources to better target drug and fentanyl crimes;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idBF690EB262474E358CE9C2D2BA2BE214"><enum>(6)</enum><text>detain and deport illegal aliens who have committed criminal offenses in the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5DB92563129C47C5ADF6C43208508C02"><enum>(7)</enum><text>eliminate investigatory backlogs and more quickly process criminal evidence; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id22856d6ef54b43cf8ef42c10c5aadf68"><enum>(8)</enum><text>combat interstate child trafficking.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id5173B36438D8438682E536563C82BF4B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applications</header><text>An eligible entity seeking a grant under this section shall submit to the Attorney General an application at such time and in such form as the Attorney General may require.</text></subsection></section><section id="id0c50a9a9d2424433bf847d3e25ab7b65"><enum>3063.</enum><header>Administrative provisions</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc50f42362596456e9c6953087e92fe1c"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Regulations</header><text>The Attorney General may promulgate guidelines, regulations, and procedures to carry out this part, including guidelines, regulations, and procedures relating to the submission and review of applications for grants under this part.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide828b2c89355432aa8298bb7bc83bb7b"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Accountability</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf94de45187db4b158d0621017adcb327"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Records</header><text>An eligible entity that receives a grant under this part shall maintain such records as the Attorney General may require to facilitate an effective audit relating to the receipt of the grant, the use of amounts from the grant, or outsourcing activities. </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id22cbe11e699c42448272ca433a5e4f2f"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Access</header><text>For the purpose of conducting audits and examinations, the Attorney General shall have access to any book, document, or record of an eligible entity that receives a grant under this part, a State or unit of local government within which the eligible entity operates, and any entity to which the eligible entity outsources work using amounts from the grant if the Attorney General determines that the book, document, or record relates to—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idff4d57e4dc004ee1b5cfc6aad9621866"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the receipt of the grant; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8350194aa8514325a72a20323719af76"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the use of amounts from the grant.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idF79AB0A392554E8EB297E1C3A4B58790"><enum>3064.</enum><header>Appropriations; funding</header><subsection id="id3867D440BC2F40079B65B647A9517112"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Rescission</header><text>Effective on the date of enactment of the <short-title>Restoring Law and Order Act of 2025</short-title>, any unobligated balances made available under section 10301(1)(A)(ii) of the Act titled <quote>An Act to provide for reconciliation pursuant to title II of S. Con. Res. 14</quote> are rescinded.</text></subsection><subsection id="id50d0d3d156604139817e479551386826"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Appropriation</header><text>Of the unobligated balances rescinded under subsection (a)—</text><paragraph id="idd9176c8d667442c7b96b6a4b92bf6e97"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$500,000,000 is appropriated to the Attorney General for fiscal year 2026 to carry out this part, to remain available until September 30, 2030; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide6743eb5fcf0437ca5275f59bddaf9c9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the remainder shall be deposited in the Treasury.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id037F6ECE3DF74A348E37C78B97B4A7B6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Redirection of funds</header><text>Notwithstanding any other law, the Attorney General shall use amounts appropriated to the Attorney General for the purpose of carrying out a diversity, equity, or inclusion initiative established pursuant to Executive Order 14035 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000e">42 U.S.C. 2000e</external-xref> note; relating to diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility in the Federal workforce), including through the award of grants, to carry out this part.</text></subsection></section></part><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

