<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HAF6A53703F5E4924A70F0BFA18BF41DD" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4371 IH: Kayla Hamilton Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4371</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250714">July 14, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000478">Mr. Fry</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="N000026">Mr. Nehls</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001212">Mr. Moore of Alabama</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the William Wilberforce Trafficking Victims Protection Reauthorization Act of 2008 to enhance efforts to combat the trafficking of children.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H911E577FBC61442A95743984FAF25FA3" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HA6D7EBEAE64B441E9FC331498B023C8B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Kayla Hamilton Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HED202F91D3304247B96C49FB5F53BD3A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Enhancing efforts to combat the trafficking of children</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 235(c) of the William Wilberforce Trafficking Victims Protection Reauthorization Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1232">8 U.S.C. 1232(c)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HC494DCF1C26B476491FBF17D1B9F63B8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text> <subparagraph id="HC8651027944B4E1E8C62028218E4FC6C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>Subject to section 462(b)(2)</quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="clause" style="OLC"><enum-in-header>(i) </enum-in-header></header-in-text><header-in-text level="clause" style="OLC">In general.—</header-in-text>Except as provided in clause (ii), subject to section 462(b)(2)</quote>;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H32E86721334D46308B8E43F29EB5EF1C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>In making such placements, the Secretary may consider</quote> and inserting <quote>In making such placements, the Secretary shall consider</quote>;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC2785F8586A54F5A83E632B84D81C605"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking <quote>A child shall not be placed</quote> and inserting <quote>Except as provided in clause (ii), a child shall not be placed</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9DAFA6E5D94C4157A22D18323B272EE1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HF55C1539BBFC40BEBC112D6F1C8C2192" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <clause id="HB9CD9E387AEE4A828F29E7DD744A473A"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Additional safeguards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except in the case of a unaccompanied alien child who is 12 years of age or younger—</text> 
<subclause id="H7C8691CC1AD440D08A5C0E6D63C7CD86"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prior to making a placement under clause (i), the Secretary shall—</text> <item id="HAC0D30122FA446AEBE6039001FDC3F58"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>contact the consulate or embassy of the country of nationality or last habitual residence of an unaccompanied alien child in the custody of the Secretary of Health and Human Services to request such unaccompanied alien child’s criminal record; and</text></item> 
<item id="H61862379FA1E45B6AFDB4E7BB9DDACD3"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>shall conduct an examination of the unaccompanied alien child for gang-related tattoos and other gang-related markings, and</text></item></subclause> <subclause id="H22695E9811F64004B4EEFB2E3842ADCE"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the Secretary determines that the unaccompanied alien child has a gang-related tattoo, any other gang-related marking, or an arrest record, pending criminal charge, or conviction in his or her country of nationality or last habitual residence relating to gang affiliation or activity, the unaccompanied alien child shall be placed in a secure facility.</text></subclause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="clause">Notwithstanding clause (i), the Secretary is not required to review the placement of an unaccompanied alien child in a secure facility under this clause. </continuation-text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1399663B09024EA29E6055ACA1C35B3B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)—</text> <subparagraph id="H67A648751F8548D4AA821EDC5C6287C7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)—</text> 
<clause id="H4012C89036C3449EAA196647840DEFEC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Subject to the requirements of subparagraph (B)</quote> and inserting <quote>Subject to the requirements of subparagraphs (B) and (D)</quote>; and</text></clause> <clause id="H7DA79E71025D46ABB8B18B3508CD6934"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by inserting at the end the following: <quote>A child shall not be placed with an individual who is unlawfully present in the United States.</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5D80C7AB3E1D465DB6EE397B810C0F94"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H5B867C3CD48D45C2AB261D5BDB63F838" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="HE830F6F97FCE4911B06BFE0F9FFEB5E7"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Information about individuals with whom children are placed</header><text>Before placing a child with an individual, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall provide to the Secretary of Homeland Security, regarding the individual with whom the child will be placed and all adult residents of the individual’s household, information on—</text> 
<clause id="H6D12CD6C8EAD484C91531699F4743628"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the name of the individual and all adult residents of the individual’s household;</text></clause> <clause id="HDB066E4F965E408A8EE39E3709CCCD5D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the social security number of the individual and all adult residents of the individual’s household;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H031B4A6E167A4DA088E0F472DE0FE85C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the date of birth of the individual and all adult residents of the individual’s household;</text></clause> <clause id="H3ED4FA02FD034D468D9D45213799059A"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the location of the individual’s residence where the child will be placed;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HDAE0110258724AE09581966C1F33C8AF"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the immigration status of the individual and all adult residents of the individual’s household;</text></clause> <clause id="H498BC0120F784772ACC347862103A158"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>contact information for the individual and all adult residents of the individual’s household; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H031B810017734AE0B806F1D03C827ACD"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>the results of all background and criminal records checks for the individual and all adult residents of the individual’s household, which shall include at a minimum an investigation of public records sex offender registry conducted through the U.S. Department of Justice National Sex Offender public website, a public records background check, and Federal Bureau of Investigation National Criminal history check based on fingerprints.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

