<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="HAF6A53703F5E4924A70F0BFA18BF41DD" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>93 HR 4371 RH: Kayla Hamilton Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 297</calendar><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4371</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 119–345]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250714">July 14, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000478">Mr. Fry</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="N000026">Mr. Nehls</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001212">Mr. Moore of Alabama</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251017">October 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on July 14, 2025</action-instruction><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the William Wilberforce Trafficking Victims Protection Reauthorization Act of 2008 to enhance efforts to combat the trafficking of children.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HJU00" reported-display-style="italic" id="HF4B859DEFD9C41BC857011E96DA59EFB"><section id="H9C11F36E0EB14FDE89AB02F422FCDD97" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Kayla Hamilton Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H396E545CCB4049C296B5FA35447398E6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Placement determinations for unaccompanied alien children</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 462(b)(2) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/279">6 U.S.C. 279(b)(2)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HD92B8F814FE64E3CAEB018BCA12E6755" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HJU00"><paragraph id="HABCC2AB5570946B1A2A0EA2D363E3A68"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Placement determinations for unaccompanied alien children</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Office of Refugee Resettlement shall make determinations under paragraph (1)(C) in accordance with section 235(c)(2) of the William Wilberforce Trafficking Victims Protection Reauthorization Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1232">8 U.S.C. 1232(c)(2)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="HF2FBA14EB8934660A2EA529CE5F80490"><enum>3.</enum><header>Enhancing efforts to combat the trafficking of children</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 235(c) of the William Wilberforce Trafficking Victims Protection Reauthorization Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1232">8 U.S.C. 1232(c)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H2D9FC347DB46409D91ADD477DB34FFDA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), to read as follows:</text><quoted-block id="H1F24574B57B54AF79C67272A8BE90EB3" style="OLC" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HJU00"><paragraph id="HFEFAD2DD20DB40BDBED2F9BEC28F6DCE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Safe and secure placements</header><subparagraph id="H93399232B85845369767FF42E8B5BDAE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Initial actions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services may not make a placement determination under this paragraph for an unaccompanied alien child who is in Federal custody by reason of the immigration status of that child until the Secretary does the following:</text><clause id="H685C1034D884483B9436E15BC9F39CC1"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Consultations</header><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall consult with the Secretary of Homeland Security and the Attorney General (including appropriate juvenile justice officials)—</text><subclause id="H3384C93E54054F6E867F6B1DBF999198"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to ensure that the unaccompanied alien child will appear for all immigration, administrative, and judicial hearings or proceedings in which the child is involved;</text></subclause><subclause id="H1184528B3A2D44AFB1913A938E37B52A"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to ensure that the unaccompanied alien child will be protected from smugglers, traffickers, gangs, and others who might seek to victimize or otherwise engage the child in criminal, harmful, or exploitative activity; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H40D0FD31602D4317AB3ABDFD9152FDE1"><enum>(III)</enum><text>to determine if the unaccompanied alien child—</text><item id="H7E73F6B99D3A4056A21F21DF9FD94BD5"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>is a flight risk; </text></item><item id="HE41AC2538D8F4E7FA8D2F2A989175FB2"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>is a danger to self, another individual, or the community; or</text></item><item id="HFEA1F0953C4F44F18F2F20BD472E10C6"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>has been arrested for, charged with, or convicted of any criminal offense in the United States or in his or her country of citizenship, nationality, or last habitual residence.</text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="H8B3025D642C54B84A8C5CEB2E1C34FE3"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Screening for gang related activity; requirement to obtain criminal records</header><text>In the case of an unaccompanied alien child 12 years of age or older, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall—</text><subclause id="H3B46A2EE698342258176806E2808D064"><enum>(I)</enum><text>contact the consulate or embassy of the country of citizenship, nationality, or last habitual residence for the unaccompanied alien child to obtain any relevant arrest records, pending criminal charges, or conviction documents involving such child; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HED9937BCCFE44C11A03DFF9D318729A2"><enum>(II)</enum><text>conduct an examination of the unaccompanied alien child to determine if such child has any gang-related tattoos and other gang-related markings.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF9372154C87B4BD48C4635260D9D7E7A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Placement generally</header><clause id="H26F2608CA59F423A9AC3F7FDDDEB8F8C"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as otherwise provided in this paragraph, an unaccompanied alien child who is in the custody of the Department of Health and Human Services shall be promptly placed in the least restrictive setting that is in the best interest of the child. </text></clause><clause id="H561DB2BDC0D34AA7818A0AD682777A17"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Prohibition on release on own recognizance</header><text>An unaccompanied alien child may not be released on his or her own recognizance.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H53732E7547D144549BCD18953E1B2BB9"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Placement of certain unaccompanied alien children in secure facilities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an unaccompanied alien child 12 years of age or older, the unaccompanied alien child shall be placed in a secure facility for the duration of any immigration proceedings (and, if ordered removed, until such unaccompanied alien child is removed) if the unaccompanied alien child—</text><clause id="H2DADCC6FED9D41A185ED5BF1F95F9E15"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is a flight risk; or</text></clause><clause id="H06C570A270A64A3C97F20D3A8873F1C2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is a danger to self, other individuals, or the community, including if the unaccompanied alien child—</text><subclause id="H0490B21A074D4A6EA3A9766144A915BB"><enum>(I)</enum><text>has a gang-related tattoo or any other gang-related marking;</text></subclause><subclause id="H56F1A50001334972A8A8123E255D70AC"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has been convicted of a serious criminal offense (as defined in section 101(h) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(h)</external-xref>)) in any State or territory of the United States or in the unaccompanied alien child’s country of citizenship, nationality, or last habitual residence;</text></subclause><subclause id="H7762A8A78F3B47B8AF9BD89F75207298"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has been convicted of any aggravated felony (as defined in section 101(a)(43) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(43)</external-xref>); or </text></subclause><subclause id="H529B87FF423949E18343FE93446E917F"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has, for conduct in connection with gang affiliation or gang activity in any State or territory of the United States or in the unaccompanied alien child’s country of citizenship, nationality, or last habitual residence—</text><item id="HAD44336E92604FCAAD5C356E2EB870E9"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>any arrest record;</text></item><item id="H02F89529A0FC4E91BBF994CD9B14556C"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>any pending criminal charge;</text></item><item id="H4771B023B05B45FB9E6177048AB42E01"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>any other pending proceeding; or</text></item><item id="HDD22FB453F4D4465BB14D573FA5DDABD"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>any conviction.</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H35B4ED45F58C4E5C86D180CA54E1FF3B"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Prohibitions on placement of unaccompanied alien children with certain individuals</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall not place an unaccompanied alien child in the custody of any individual who is one or more of the following:</text><clause id="H88497725C5EA425892818C8FA8BFCF6E"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Secure and stable sponsors</header><text>An individual who is not a United States citizen or a lawful permanent resident of the United States.</text></clause><clause id="H2EF421BF0C804260AB326CC56DD8FF75"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Individuals with criminal history</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual who has been convicted of, or who resides in a household with an individual who has been convicted of—</text><subclause id="H069B0C6F49D742A88FBA9DFF71A4E1A4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a sex offense (as defined in section 111(5) of the Sex Offender Registration and Notification Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/20911">34 U.S.C. 20911(5)</external-xref>));</text></subclause><subclause id="H1F73A5CFD27D4F248F915229DAEB96D2"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a crime involving severe forms of trafficking in persons (as defined in section 103(11) of the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7102">22 U.S.C. 7102(11)</external-xref>));</text></subclause><subclause id="HA657B9B73D3E477195C8DDADD1CCDC00"><enum>(III)</enum><text>a crime of domestic violence (as defined in section 40002(a)(12) of the Violence Against Women Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/12291">34 U.S.C. 12291(a)(12)</external-xref>));</text></subclause><subclause id="HE7455794642F460AB40D2099E318B445"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>a crime of child abuse and neglect (as defined in section 3 of the Child Abuse Prevention and Treatment Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/93/247">Public Law 93–247</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5101">42 U.S.C. 5101</external-xref> note));</text></subclause><subclause id="H287CAAEB2B6A419E9939D5A4D268A7DE"><enum>(V)</enum><text>murder, manslaughter, or an attempt to commit murder or manslaughter (as defined in sections 1111, 1112, and 1113 of title 18, United States Code);</text></subclause><subclause id="HB83DBEAED97D48ECB8C57F174A0778A6"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>a crime involving the receipt, distribution, or possession of a visual depiction of a minor engaging in sexually explicit conduct (as described in section 2252 of title 18, United States Code);</text></subclause><subclause id="H0EB662F26FA44E15BE215DE2104E644B"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>any crime for which an alien is required to be taken into custody pursuant to section 236(c)(1) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1226">8 U.S.C. 1226(c)(1)</external-xref>);</text></subclause><subclause id="HB2369EEB71454CD191A6A80837A55410"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text>any aggravated felony (as defined in section 101 of the Immigration and Nationality Act);</text></subclause><subclause id="H39C251FDE4EB4B34AD9FF2EE8F5913BA"><enum>(IX)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any crime defined as a felony by the relevant jurisdiction (Federal, State, tribal, or local);</text></subclause><subclause id="H9D7D9FFC6C014C618E763E36342DF953"><enum>(X)</enum><text>any crime punishable by more than 1 year of imprisonment; or</text></subclause><subclause id="HD0C76E34752A469081121351E9A9F359"><enum>(XI)</enum><text>any other criminal offense as designated by the Attorney General, in the Attorney General’s sole and unreviewable discretion.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H6002E3ABDEF5482984279B7F38927F97"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)—</text><subparagraph id="HB97D09536EC5436DB631FC71E9EF09E0"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>Subject to the requirements of subparagraph (B)</quote> and inserting <quote>Subject to the requirements of subparagraphs (B) and (D)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H133690367B704723BD09C58A41F0E089"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H02F43E7535B3494780B60EB8EDCDD99B" style="OLC" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HJU00"><subparagraph id="HB5FD321523F541EDAA7FB023B56B7F9C"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Information about individuals with whom children are placed</header><text>Before placing a child with any individual, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall provide to the Secretary of Homeland Security, with regard to the individual with whom the child will be placed and each adult resident of the individual’s household, information on—</text><clause id="H5522207D11B249D08A8FF3D2E4995524"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the name of the individual and each adult resident of the individual’s household;</text></clause><clause id="H01ED58B96C2B425B98501C513A973635"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the social security number or individual taxpayer identification number of the individual and each adult resident of the individual’s household;</text></clause><clause id="HED6CD2E43CBA49349A1BC44E590ABC38"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the date of birth of the individual and of each adult resident of the individual’s household;</text></clause><clause id="HDF3A37E6516243E6BC3F7FCA4EF6FCA6"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the physical location and address of the individual’s residence where the child will be placed;</text></clause><clause id="H7CD804EED78F4ED6936DDB0E41494555"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the immigration status of the individual and each adult resident of the individual’s household;</text></clause><clause id="H734005263B194355903CD980170EC1FE"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>contact information for the individual and for each adult resident of the individual’s household, including telephone numbers, email addresses, and work telephone numbers (if available); and</text></clause><clause id="HE2A149CB918F44CC83BB303D3FA03F23"><enum>(vii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the results of all background and criminal records checks conducted on the individual and each adult resident of the individual’s household, which shall include at a minimum an investigation of the Dru Sjodin National Sex Offender Public Website, a public records background check, and a national criminal history background check based on fingerprints.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H487B155B41A045659DDFA71735C6C370"><enum>4.</enum><header>Construction; severability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Any provision of the this Act or an amendment made by this Act held to be invalid or unenforceable by its terms, or as applied to any person or circumstance, shall be construed so as to give it the maximum effect permitted by law, unless such holding shall be utterly invalid or unenforceable, in which event such provision shall be deemed severable from this Act and shall not affect the remainder of this Act, or the application of such provision to other persons not similarly situated or to other, dissimilar circumstances.</text></section><section id="HE41EB641914642AEA8FFAAAFB1C33063"><enum>5.</enum><header>Exemption from Paperwork Reduction Act and the Administrative Procedure Act</header><subsection id="H896B920DF78544F4BA595BFDCEDFAE51"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Paperwork reduction act</header><text>Nothing in this Act may be construed to require the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Secretary of State, or the Attorney General to comply with the requirements of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/44/35">chapter 35</external-xref> of title 44, United States Code (commonly referred to as the <quote>Paperwork Reduction Act</quote>) if such individuals determine that compliance would impede the immediate implementation of this Act or the amendments made by this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF0BBF991A0E14D3F9A8ADDEC929E480F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Administrative procedure act</header><text>Nothing in this Act may be construed to require the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Secretary of State, or the Attorney General to promulgate regulations under subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/5">chapter 5</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code (commonly referred to as the <quote>Administrative Procedure Act</quote>), if such individuals determine that compliance would impede the immediate implementation of this Act or the amendments made by this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="H5B8B0419E51745D09854FF656073C922"><enum>6.</enum><header>Effective date; applicability</header><subsection id="HBE8A5797C6F54D9E8EE5242FEF6AC111"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (b), this Act and the amendments made by this shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA4541F2C21F94E9BA3C1DC5E15502A82"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>This Act and the amendments made by this Act shall apply to any release and custody determinations for an unaccompanied alien child (as defined in section 642(g)(2) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002), that are pending or occur on or after the date of the enactment of this Act, and all release redeterminations.</text></subsection></section></legis-body><official-title-amendment>Amend the title so as to read: <quote>A bill to amend the William Wilberforce Trafficking Victims Protection Reauthorization Act of 2008 and the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to enhance efforts to combat the trafficking of children.</quote>.</official-title-amendment><endorsement display="yes"><action-date date="20251017">October 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

