<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ELL25080-KFY-GR-P81"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S698 IS: Federal Prisons Accountability Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 698</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250224">February 24, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S174">Mr. McConnell</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S153">Mr. Grassley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S348">Mr. Paul</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S378">Mr. Lankford</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Director of the Bureau of Prisons to be appointed by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="id38CABF776EAA4E31AA2CFD6DD6B94A01"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Federal Prisons Accountability Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section section-type="subsequent-section" id="id8023DD821A5E4B8998A572E7F000A220"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="idaeb90ad3820c467ba989541396328560"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Director of the Bureau of Prisons leads a law enforcement component of the Department of Justice with a budget that exceeded $8,390,000,000 for fiscal year 2024.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3e24eb861c3f4c76be11b46d4a2134f5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>With the exception of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, the Bureau of Prisons had the largest operating budget of any unit within the Department of Justice for fiscal year 2024.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7ff808242f5f4d5b955c26d1518f7279"><enum>(3)</enum><text>As of 2025, the Director of the Bureau of Prisons oversaw 122 facilities and was responsible for the welfare of more than 155,000 Federal inmates.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idaa133efe769440abb90210a46d76f331"><enum>(4)</enum><text>As of 2025, the Director of the Bureau of Prisons supervised more than 35,000 employees, many of whom operate in hazardous environments that involve regular interaction with violent offenders.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfd50288f5370412dbaa3e126d40ce193"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Within the Department of Justice, in addition to those officials who oversee litigating components, the Director of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives, the Director of the Community Relations Service, the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, the Director of the Office on Violence Against Women, the Administrator of the Drug Enforcement Administration, the Deputy Administrator of the Drug Enforcement Administration, the Director of the United States Marshals Service, 94 United States Marshals, the Inspector General of the Department of Justice, and the Special Counsel for Immigration Related Unfair Employment Practices, are all appointed by the President by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id07f07a0556b54814b9aae93315be9c13"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Despite the significant budget of the Bureau of Prisons and the vast number of people under the responsibility of the Director of the Bureau of Prisons, the Director is not appointed by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</text></paragraph></section><section section-type="subsequent-section" id="id4B5270989EE648B7B8D1F2A57AD21D70"><enum>3.</enum><header>Director of the Bureau of Prisons</header><subsection id="id22FA2F56974B4E9DB80AB267FAAEC0BE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 4041 of title 18, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>appointed by and serving directly under the Attorney General.</quote> and inserting the following: <quote>who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. The Director shall serve directly under the Attorney General.</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="idB5E62317DC514C37A7F5785A5B4214D4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Incumbent</header><text>Notwithstanding the amendment made by subsection (a), the individual serving as the Director of the Bureau of Prisons on the date of enactment of this Act may serve as the Director of the Bureau of Prisons until the date that is 3 months after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="idAE0B80EBE7B4452FAC2F4A3BB406A4BA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to limit the ability of the President to appoint the individual serving as the Director of the Bureau of Prisons on the date of enactment of this Act to the position of Director of the Bureau of Prisons in accordance with section 4041 of title 18, United States Code, as amended by subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="id3C9DECFCB59F4A1F973842FC1F736721"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Term</header><paragraph id="id35B6766B37E244E9B540E848F9F55F6C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 4041 of title 18, United States Code, as amended by subsection (a), is amended by inserting after <quote>consent of the Senate.</quote> the following: <quote>The Director shall be appointed for a term of 10 years, except that an individual appointed to the position of Director may continue to serve in that position until another individual is appointed to that position, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. An individual may not serve more than 1 term as Director.</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5a1461c253764a98bd00037dc01886c4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>The amendment made by paragraph (1) shall apply to appointments made on or after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

