<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-HEY25108-837-H2-Y5V"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S607 IS: Improving Veteran Access to Care Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 607</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250218">February 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S388">Ms. Hassan</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S343">Mr. Boozman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSVA00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to establish an integrated project team to improve the process for scheduling appointments for health care from the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Improving Veteran Access to Care Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="ideaaff62e252c400eb74734835714783d"><enum>2.</enum><header>Establishment of integrated project team of Department of Veterans Affairs to improve health care appointment scheduling</header><subsection id="id7bb8e3627c0749e1a54794adf8cbe6e5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs, through the Veterans Health Administration and the Office of Information and Technology of the Department of Veterans Affairs, or any successor offices or administrations of similar function, shall establish an integrated project team to improve the process for scheduling appointments for health care from the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id89e4adc5f5f34937af86ef82a7ba18ad"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The purpose of this section is to ensure the Department of Veterans Affairs delivers to patients and employees of the Department in a timely manner the scheduling capabilities developed by the integrated project team established under subsection (a) to immediately improve delivery of care, access to care, customer experience and service, and efficiency with respect to the delivery of care. </text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4ef17ca0cd0745adad61e9ac316de318"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Objectives</header><text>The objectives of the integrated project team established under subsection (a) are the following:</text><paragraph id="id287163ec9de34f8bb1de031b3dd1dcec"><enum>(1)</enum><text>To develop or continue the development of a scheduling system that enables both personnel and patients of the Department of Veterans Affairs to view available appointments for all care furnished by the Department, including— </text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id922028237e6d4d9a940602f3857c808e"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">available appointments for all providers of the Department;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0de505a3b4c44f44b184400d79459336"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">available appointments at all clinics, hospitals, and other health care facilities of the Department; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide9f119b9af7c4a8482580746b6e5e9dc"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">available appointments at all offices providing patient care within the health care system of the Department, including primary care and all forms of specialty care.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="iddd31e46fd23b4a18b627a8590dd8582d"><enum>(2)</enum><text>To develop or continue the development of a self-service scheduling platform, available for use by all patients of the Department, which shall— </text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc53176b06ab643f3b15747678ba38e49"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">enable such patients to view available appointments and fully schedule appointments for all care furnished by the Department, including—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8D41EBE51FC84B00B1BAAA5A81335579"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">appointments for all providers of the Department;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5B0994C36D0A49D6B2C17263BA576672"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">appointments at all clinics, hospitals, and other health care facilities of the Department; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idC29C5CC766984502927A33882C83B488"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">appointments at all offices providing patient care within the health care system of the Department, including primary care and all forms of specialty care; </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb54635ae8d934e8ebc4d62a0b4232c4d"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if a referral is required for an appointment, provide a method for the patient to request a referral and subsequently book an appointment if the referral is approved; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id57bddd530f0949368cbd7466f38d267f"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide such patients with the ability to cancel or reschedule appointments.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ideb65d37d7504455daeda7f3580e4117a"><enum>(3)</enum><text>To create a process through which all patients of the Department can telephonically speak with a scheduler who can assist the patient to determine appointment availability and can fully schedule appointments on behalf of the patient for all care furnished by the Department, including—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id12D34D561AD645CBB427A24058D3C2DA"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">appointments for all providers of the Department;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idC162BD2F978C4F3DAC0DBEE00E86C167"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">appointments at all clinics, hospitals, and other health care facilities of the Department; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0D8F495039DC4B5AA777B7DD7BD77CC9"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">appointments at all offices providing patient care within the health care system of the Department, including primary care and all forms of specialty care.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id39e875978a3b411f8c654750d24611f9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>To carry out such other functions, oversight, metric development and tracking, change management, cross-Department coordination, and other related matters as the Secretary determines appropriate as it relates to scheduling tools, functions, and operations with respect to health care appointments furnished by the Department.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id61496fa23fc147d5b219e65d52c95081"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Coordination with Electronic Health Record Modernization Program</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc1994402471840c6bf47afab8232aab3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The integrated project team established under subsection (a) shall carry out the objectives under subsection (c) in consultation and coordination with the deployment schedule and capabilities of the Electronic Health Record Modernization Program of the Department of Veterans Affairs to ensure a smooth transition to using the tools and features, where relevant and appropriate, that may be created pursuant to this section, along with the features in the Electronic Health Record Modernization Program.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7af51899990540419dd37a494ea6ac26"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to require the integrated project team established under subsection (a), the Veterans Health Administration, or the Office of Information and Technology of the Department to defer or delay the deployment of scheduling capabilities required by this section because of future potential planned capabilities of the Electronic Health Record Modernization Program.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id321535baa28e4870bb83f9d357abd058"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Deadlines</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id940cbb1e9ad74911a16abb26b8e2d60d"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, through the Veterans Health Administration and the Office of Information and Technology of the Department of Veterans Affairs, or any successor office, shall fully establish the integrated project team under subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id85d4089c09de4b5ab260b65c67eae85e"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Completion of objectives</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the integrated project team established under subsection (a) shall complete the objectives under subsection (c).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="ideaa7e4e973f0436aab5ba3806a76e3f5"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Report on objectives</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary of Veterans Affairs determines that an objective under subsection (c), or any feature or service in connection with that objective, cannot be implemented or otherwise incorporated into a final product, the Secretary shall, within 45 days of that determination, submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide12baeadb6904bca9cb4364c2a532a9a"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">detailing that objective, feature, or service and providing an explanation as to why that objective, feature, or service cannot be implemented or incorporated, as the case may be; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idad455744753343b1a18238c6f6df3f7e"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">setting forth a plan for implementing this section without that objective, feature, or service.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id307a762599d04010b32918d239783680"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Implementation reports</header><text>Not later than each of one year and two years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report on the progress of the Secretary in fulfilling the requirements of this section, including—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4d967e96c775471ab126e3cbca01ce6d"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">costs incurred to implement such requirements as of the date of the report;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3afbaa358a3449d5a076c90eff186f2c"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the expected costs to complete implementation of such requirements (including costs for management and technology);</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id413f23e24c6e42c7b06dae2dff82fbfb"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the schedule for deployment of any capabilities developed by the integrated project team established under subsection (a); and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7a7b0adb46974ca9a9360a5ec900a837"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">goals and metrics achieved, challenges, and lessons learned.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id2c1af475616c41f8ba26c2e9ec8a161f"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to preclude or impede the ability of a veteran to contact or schedule an appointment directly with a facility or provider through a non-online scheduling process, should the veteran choose to do so. </text></subsection><subsection id="id70b3c30c71e94270a2f9ccf5448db74a"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcba3ffda31f349788ffe07bbaa423d84"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Appropriate committees of Congress</header><text>The term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id62f75659227e4ea0837c1d2d7be42257"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Fully schedule</header><text>The term <term>fully schedule</term>, with respect to booking an appointment, means that the appointment booking is completed, rather than simply requested.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

