<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0694016D3C3B42228F82DE86283FEBF8" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 187 IH: Modernizing Access to our Public Waters Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 187</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250103">January 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001213">Mr. Moore of Utah</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000469">Mr. Fulcher</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for the standardization, consolidation, and publication of data relating to public outdoor recreational use of Federal waterways among Federal land and water management agencies, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF31D7F972DA24009B56CD38E5CF2DDAE" style="OLC"><section id="H20EB279E1837491EB8154D1EE504816E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Modernizing Access to our Public Waters Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>MAPWaters Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HB893512F1C0C421B9B92A4CBFD77D3CC"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H3FFDB9CA187045908D763721113A359B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Federal fishing restriction</header><text>The term <quote>Federal fishing restriction</quote> means a defined area in which all or certain fishing activities are temporarily or permanently prohibited or restricted by a Federal land or water management agency.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF9B09CD691DE4B2585EC01EE0B8D7A40"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federal land or water management agency</header><text>The term <quote>Federal land or water management agency</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="HD9E4C28103C341F48EC6E8BA721C461E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Bureau of Reclamation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H04D1CBBD775C4EB9AE610779475102E6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the National Park Service;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H72F71E4662794D32A0ACC5A2E32871C8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Bureau of Land Management;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H721DE2E3157F40EEAB2D670B2153C113"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the United States Fish and Wildlife Service; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H533AB976936C45C296853FE0264B613B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the Forest Service.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBD71D36073B0497B8286D5F47DE8C374"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Federal waterway</header><text>The term <quote>Federal waterway</quote> means waters managed by 1 or more of the relevant Secretaries.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3899579246BD42E280F68B5917808DC0"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Federal waterway restriction</header><text>The term <quote>Federal waterway restriction</quote> means a restriction on the access or use of a Federal waterway applied under applicable law by 1 or more of the Secretaries.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H41E25A1E988541ADBBF9E1D86590DBF7"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Secretaries</header><text>The term <quote>Secretaries</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="H71BD0F13F9A24CBBBF0A48D460914E7E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Chief of the Forest Service; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HACAA552782C84131A682CC8158919C72"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary of the Interior.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE762FEF88C6249FCADA724DCC5E0D04E"><enum>(6)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <quote>State</quote> means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, and each territory of the United States.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HD01D4DB2AA914D50BAE0B94FC35FFFC1"><enum>3.</enum><header>Interagency data standardization</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 30 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretaries, in coordination with the Federal Geographic Data Committee established by section 753(a) of the FAA Reauthorization Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/2802">43 U.S.C. 2802(a)</external-xref>), shall jointly develop and adopt interagency standards to ensure compatibility and interoperability among applicable Federal databases with respect to the collection and dissemination of geospatial data relating to public outdoor recreational access of Federal waterways and Federal fishing restrictions.</text></section><section id="HB19C584EDB0F49E280F7C71ABCF97682"><enum>4.</enum><header>Data consolidation and publication</header><subsection id="H07FAC9F5531642748AE3F61CA3A46764"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Federal waterway restrictions</header><text>Not later than 5 years after the date of enactment of this Act, each of the Secretaries, to the maximum extent practicable, shall digitize and make publicly available online, as applicable, geographic information system data that includes, with respect to Federal waterway restrictions—</text><paragraph id="H80267C26C0DA4B25A16145D04B980D23"><enum>(1)</enum><text>status information with respect to the conditions under which Federal waterways are open or closed to entry or watercraft, including watercraft inspection, decontamination requirements, low-elevation aircraft, or diving;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HADD631C07DBC4BD28A962584306D917F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the dates on which Federal waterways are seasonally closed to entry or watercraft;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFF563B0F232E47B6A8B74E17CFDEFC87"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the areas of Federal waterways with restrictions on motorized propulsion, horsepower, or fuel type;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H68081AE2C2A842F6A3B0BBFCD63C2886"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the areas of Federal waterways with anchoring restrictions, no wake zones, exclusion zones, danger areas, or vessel speed restrictions;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H624E8B96D2404AD8862C6AC34AD60850"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Federal waterway restrictions on the direction of travel, including upstream or downstream travel; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H28191EBC95334AB4B12D0A669174A2E5"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the uses, including by watercraft, that are restricted on each area of a Federal waterway, including the permissibility of—</text><subparagraph id="HB9EE3D9273274E34B68459B5ADB6E7AC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>canoes and other paddlecraft;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDA5BF665D4684BC5A28819BE4CD11BB3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>rafts and driftboats;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF213D44BDB874190AED2AC63926FD937"><enum>(C)</enum><text>motorboats;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H86419F8BBA744DD8BA95EEB66619A41C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>personal watercraft;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9E3FF44F0783433B8540B57BD353028A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>airboats;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEB98EC5A1CF74962A6CA3B7B7E8B957E"><enum>(F)</enum><text>amphibious aircraft;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H28E964A0C4A74FEB887026C02D0891B4"><enum>(G)</enum><text>hovercraft;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H49CF6CE867C549098011C11142A652E4"><enum>(H)</enum><text>oversnow vehicles and other motorized vehicles on frozen bodies of water;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC5563786C52A4708B0E0D5B7F2FFB887"><enum>(I)</enum><text>oceangoing ships;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF609F98726F04C5484D16E858E3ED721"><enum>(J)</enum><text>swimming; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H910D19EF7F5B40A08A3331EBA3EAE441"><enum>(K)</enum><text>other applicable recreational activities, as determined to be appropriate by the Secretaries.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9ABB1C988C614BC095D48E4073DF034B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Federal waterway access and navigation information</header><text>Not later than 5 years after the date of enactment of this Act, each of the Secretaries, to the maximum extent practicable, shall digitize and make publicly available online, as applicable, geographic information system data that includes, with respect to Federal waterway access and navigation information—</text><paragraph id="H5E208477F3AC421296E838116E8D6A10"><enum>(1)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HB9EA6567C2C447758A2B194C66D499A3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the location of boat ramps, portages, and fishing access sites under the authority of the Federal land or water management agency; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H250543AD06184410970F021249F35F1B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the identification of the dates on which the facilities and sites identified under subparagraph (A) are open or closed, as applicable; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEF9181F8BB8648D399B710BD8FFD33C5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>bathymetric information and depth charts, as feasible.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB55CFA5DDB6943DF9C661783B35597FA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Federal fishing restrictions</header><text>Not later than 5 years after the date of enactment of this Act, each of the Secretaries, to the maximum extent practicable, shall digitize and make publicly available online geographic information system data that describes, with respect to Federal fishing restrictions—</text><paragraph id="HF0A323A97D4D4D0484A6038ADF455849"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the location and geographic boundaries of Federal fishing restrictions on recreational and commercial fishing, including—</text><subparagraph id="H89D0798E23D746EF9F86CEC0B75EB02B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>full or partial closures;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4CD748604B7D44A5AA72F17A7C6E38B7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>no-take zones; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD3D2AC9F31E544F0B137BCAFF770828C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Federal fishing restrictions within or surrounding marine protected areas;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H69C45EE3B183421C86A3933E43F7B2CB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Federal fishing restrictions on the use of specific types of equipment or bait; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HABEA983B9BFE4F839B87F79EC44FA8D0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Federal requirements with respect to catch and release.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCF943DF868AA4CB98578BBB7806188C3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Public comment</header><text>The Secretaries shall develop a process to allow members of the public to submit questions or comments regarding the information described in subsections (a) and (b).</text></subsection><subsection id="H74C13CB8F9AB45A09BD219580C0BC293"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Updates</header><text>The Secretaries, to the maximum extent practicable, shall update—</text><paragraph id="H7D616DEA770A47B6B13B3891628A652D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the data described in subsections (a) and (b) not less frequently than 2 times per year; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6AAEE0426D5F4C789CD74A788C448D66"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the data described in subsection (c) in real time as changes go into effect.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3945599C2BC74FA485C3CC9847A1CBA0"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Exclusion</header><text>This section shall not apply to irrigation canals and flowage easements.</text></subsection><subsection id="HCBF15275D9D244EFBAE0F8E27E227DC6"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Disclosure</header><text>Any geographic information system data made publicly available under this section shall not disclose information regarding the nature, location, character, or ownership of historic, paleontological, or archaeological resources, consistent with applicable law.</text></subsection></section><section id="HE6FE82F4D3CA4368A1F1E51BBED3B668"><enum>5.</enum><header>Cooperation and coordination</header><subsection id="H9CA0D5E8D03A4D2D93AD389FD4AB2909"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Community partners and third-Party providers</header><text>For purposes of carrying out this Act, the Secretaries may—</text><paragraph id="H00723C9E2504492DBADD6DA06CD67B2E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>coordinate and partner with non-Federal agencies and private sector and nonprofit partners, including—</text><subparagraph id="H658110D7E9354064B07FECC11E1A4CF5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>State natural resource agencies;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFF22DCEFCE974FED9A19EBD226609783"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Tribal natural resource agencies;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H19E398D2D56D4082BBC29217FE9CE13E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>technology companies;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H18D98D6629FA47B29797FC61E5679259"><enum>(D)</enum><text>geospatial data companies; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HACC46FC0AA1244B7ABFB5D02A4ACC352"><enum>(E)</enum><text>experts in data science, analytics, and operations research; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3333343515A24050AB35E5DC4A29D2F8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>enter into an agreement with a third party to carry out any provision of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H52D4936EB8D847F78E09DF0A587BFB08"><enum>(b)</enum><header>United states geological survey</header><text>The Secretaries may work with the Director of the United States Geological Survey to collect, aggregate, digitize, standardize, and publish data on behalf of the Secretaries to meet the requirements of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H82180D37234544C68EBB632606AE662F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>With respect to data developed and distributed under this Act, the Secretaries shall—</text><paragraph id="H134A29F520584EBD9CEDD8BB855EF4E0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>develop the data in accordance with applicable Federal, State, and Tribal laws (including regulations); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA2977C04CC244B0EAF4641758C1D953F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>include a notice that any geospatial data are subject to applicable Federal, State, and Tribal laws (including regulations).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE8088ADD01474FDCB6D3F2681A3AAF49"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Existing efforts</header><text>To the extent practicable, the Secretary concerned shall use or incorporate existing applicable data, maps, and resources in carrying out this Act, including data, maps, and resources developed and published under—</text><paragraph id="H744BC4A1E47841768373663EE2C147B8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Modernizing Access to Our Public Land Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/6851">16 U.S.C. 6851 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC5D0826A01244CEEBCE969267C0FED44"><enum>(2)</enum><text>section 103 of division DD of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2023 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/776">43 U.S.C. 776</external-xref>); or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE1425456B5E84654B81DFFB5A67C8B4D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>other applicable law.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HFDD850D7AB5548BEBB735B967DEBE670"><enum>6.</enum><header>Reports</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act and annually thereafter through March 30, 2034, the Secretaries shall submit a report that describes the progress made by the Secretaries with respect to meeting the requirements of this Act to—</text><paragraph id="H49A419C4C3F84DC1946412685E6CE58A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H89A31B515714478F970C6534B64554CD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7FB05FE1416C446D92DD95D8F6F5451A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAA96A3FB4C64439AB51585D4C4F8EDA1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9983CD536F384CC68287C95C613BEAE3"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HF8713E992DD0475F88FAF344320FAD67"><enum>7.</enum><header>Effect</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act—</text><paragraph id="HF0EF72D1F7EB4722A451873FE2E13B2D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>modifies or alters the definition of the term <quote>navigable waters</quote> under Federal law;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9E2718A52CE54FFDAF68F345C9D1C088"><enum>(2)</enum><text>affects the jurisdiction or authority of State or Federal agencies to regulate navigable waters;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFB50754FCE8444518A8EAE25993A94A6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>modifies or alters the authority or jurisdiction of Federal or State agencies to manage fisheries; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3F7BCB2C7A114181B2775194E3D8801A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>authorizes or is intended to result in a change in the accessibility of waters open to hunting, fishing, or other forms of outdoor recreation as of the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

