<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE21C1778303A4EA4B045C2E0E2E6DA3E" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 754 IH: Recognizing the psychological impact of immigration enforcement overreach on individuals, their families, and their community.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 754</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250919">September 19, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000617">Mrs. Ramirez</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing the psychological impact of immigration enforcement overreach on individuals, their families, and their community.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas 66 percent of undocumented immigrants have lived in the United States for over a decade, making them deeply rooted in American communities;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas mass deportations would therefore cause serious harm for families, disrupt local economies, and destabilize essential labor markets;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas there are approximately 4,700,000 mixed-status households comprised of 16,700,000 people who share a home with at least 1 undocumented resident;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas an estimated 5,500,000 American-born, United States-citizen children live with an undocumented family member;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, since January 20, 2025, the Trump administration has established informal arrest quotas, revived family detention centers, and doubled detention capacity to nearly 100,000, including on military bases, vastly expanding the number of individuals and families experiencing immigration detention;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, since January 20, 2025, individuals have been wrongfully targeted, detained, and even deported;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, since January 20, 2025, the use of expedited deportation has been vastly expanded, stripping due process rights from immigrants who wish to contest their removal;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas 71.7 percent of people currently detained by U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement (hereinafter referred to <quote>ICE</quote>) have no criminal convictions;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas 93 percent of those detained by ICE have never been convicted of a violent offense;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas individuals are now experiencing elevating levels of anxiety, hypervigilance, and panic attacks due to immigration enforcement;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas family separation is a significant concern among migrants and their communities;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas ICE is stripping people of legal status and arresting them at courthouses;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas individuals are now experiencing increased social isolation and loneliness to avoid potential ICE activity;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas family separation caused by incarceration or deportation can be more detrimental to children’s health, behavior, and academic achievement than parental death or divorce, with children deportees displaying higher rates of depression, anxiety, and academic withdrawal;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas family separation caused by incarceration and deportation disproportionately affects poor people and racial minorities whose communities are already more likely to be under stress and unable to compensate for the parental loss, thereby exacerbating structural inequalities; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, on June 14, 2025, protests occurred across the Nation against stringent immigration enforcement: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HE898B059C1DC4317AAF5DC7C442B99B6"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H7E4B53D369E545F6923F5B75420EBFF6"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="H7C88CDAECFAB47EE8C5BE2A7CF1D7AC9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognizes the psychological impact of immigration enforcement overreach on individuals, their families, and their community;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H86373FA3F8F5453DBB05DF392A85F1EE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>acknowledges the significant contributions of nonprofit organizations in delivering crucial psychological and socioeconomic support to immigrant communities;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC02B33055A864F099DE2CAD5ABBF901D"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">condemns U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement tactics that allow for unreasonable searches and seizures, which are in direct opposition to the Fourth Amendment;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1DA0ABBA76464D2A94FC10354E242C24"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">condemns U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement tactics that erode due process, equal protection, and freedom from discrimination as guarded by the Constitution;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD98835E063304BD6A2B0BF6281D1A58F"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">affirms the role of Congress in—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HACE8A503E6AC4721BAC0F037B1F10898"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">holding Federal immigration officers accountable to upholding due process and equal protection, and recognizes that violations of due process and equal protection are physically and psychologically damaging to those residing in the United States;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB5415A3EF87A4DB0A005677E62600496"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conducting oversight investigations in U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement detention centers;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE6DCECFDDC824DD88185FFB37FC33A97"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">monitoring the implementation of immigration policy by U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement, the Department of Homeland Security, and other immigration-related agencies; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB9A820038DE246908ECC97B886C70EBC"><enum>(D)</enum><text>identifying and preventing abuses of Executive power;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4CD0F75F678F4D388A5DEC83292E69B2"><enum>(6)</enum><text>condemns President Trump and his administration, including Kristi Noem, Tom Homan, and Stephen Miller, who have carried out policies that are physically and psychologically damaging to those residing in the United States;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA9FE1A03B148478E9CEBF36905675A88"><enum>(7)</enum><text>calls on the Administrator of the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration to gather and report data demonstrating the impacts of immigration enforcement overreach on immigrant mental health; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H667375CF54AB4ADEAEDA354830D59B4E"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">calls on the Secretary of Health and Human Services to address the impacts of immigration enforcement overreach on immigrant mental health by working with nonprofits to provide culturally comprehensive mental health services to directly impacted communities.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

