<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-BOM25224-VFL-DP-0Y8"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1303 IS: Smithsonian American Women’s History Museum Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1303</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250403">April 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S410">Ms. Lummis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S385">Ms. Cortez Masto</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSRA00">Committee on Rules and Administration</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To permit the Smithsonian American Women’s History Museum to be located within the Reserve of the National Mall, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H0A664B24B0F64CA09701A687C39F7173"><section section-type="section-one" id="HFF342C58D2E84CB29BB6D00F9E557898"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Smithsonian American Women’s History Museum Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section section-type="subsequent-section" id="H2B3980BF048E434C9E0694AD191173FC"><enum>2.</enum><header>Site of Smithsonian American Women’s History Museum</header><subsection id="H6DAA4DD14D7046F88438D9083587C167"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorizing site within Reserve of National Mall</header><paragraph id="HB0763485A2F24D4689C4FBADE334F99A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law or regulation, including section 8908(c) of title 40, United States Code, the Smithsonian American Women’s History Museum may be located within the Reserve (as defined in section 8902(a) of title 40, United States Code).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3595C7FCAD50491CA4A39CECAD77B1D4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 107(d) of division T of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/80t-5">20 U.S.C. 80t–5(d)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>, except that</quote> and all that follows and inserting a period.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6CAC523CFA954B28A38AFAF99752F523"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of site under the jurisdiction of another Federal agency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 107(b) of division T of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/80t-5">20 U.S.C. 80t–5(b)</external-xref> is amended to read as follows: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H074CA3AAC8C944CA9C3A09F7740B88AE"><subsection id="H237C26FD873A4B4380BF4DA0DE420032"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Site under the jurisdiction of another Federal agency</header><paragraph id="HBB433BDD85D346078CE2C7C084AF740F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Notification to other agency or entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Board of Regents shall not designate a site for the Museum that is under the administrative jurisdiction of another Federal agency or entity without first notifying the head of the Federal agency or entity.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF46F150BE42F41278B41FFEF4E4A8924"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notification to Committees</header><text>Once notified under paragraph (1), the head of the Federal agency or entity shall promptly submit written notification to the Chair and ranking minority members of the Committee on Rules and Administration, the Committee on Appropriations, and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate, and the Committee on House Administration, the Committee on Natural Resources, the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives, stating that the Federal agency or entity was notified by the Board of Regents that a site under its jurisdiction was designated and that a transfer will be initiated as soon as practicable.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC2FD2DE1DE744AC288E102EFF5270D91"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Transfer</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As soon as practicable after the date on which the individuals described in paragraph (2) receive the written notification described in such subparagraph, the head of the Federal agency or entity shall transfer to the Smithsonian Institution its administrative jurisdiction over the land or structure that has been designated as the site for the Museum.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H7EEDA0EB51D04B69876A295FDF0B8AAB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Ensuring diversity of political viewpoints and authentic experiences</header><text>Section 104(b)(4) of division T of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/80t-2">20 U.S.C. 80t–2(b)(4)</external-xref> is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE624A77DB1EE4C2CBF85A4596FA2F637"><paragraph id="H6332AF26D058443BBCEDF3D133FFEAA3"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Ensuring diversity of political viewpoints and authentic experiences</header><subparagraph id="H67199B25F1B74835A54CC3103730D192"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Council shall ensure that the exhibits and programs of the Museum accurately and comprehensively represent the varied cultures, histories, events, and values held by women in the United States.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCE7E401D0E794D60AD5236B5E2A06AA4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Specific requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out its duties, the Council shall ensure that it seeks and utilizes to its maximum ability guidance from a broad array of knowledgeable and respected sources reflecting the diversity of the political viewpoints and authentic experiences held by women in the United States, and shall seek such guidance for both the creation and substantial revision of exhibits and programs.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBE6A724600B044F88785A9BB62A0C4B8"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subparagraph—</text><clause id="H779113A362E542D78FA441E218D5AF75"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>broad array</term> means a range of experts and publications that represent the broad spectrum of communities of women, to include varied viewpoints, political ideologies, cultures, and lived experiences in the United States; and</text></clause><clause id="H74A2A2409B32438CA95D14747319966D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>knowledgeable and respected source</term> means an individual who has gained through education, publication, or witnessing an important or historical event, the ability to advise on at least one unique viewpoint or experience of a particular community of women in the United States, and whose knowledge has been relied upon by a notable segment of that community for education, heritage preservation, or historical purposes, and includes the work of such an individual which reflects such ability and knowledge.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HBF90A66C29F04A9387981A7F78ABC62B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of this Act and every 2 years thereafter, the Secretary of the Smithsonian shall submit to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate, the Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate, the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate, a report on actions taken by the Director of the Smithsonian American Women’s History Museum and the Council of the Museum to comply with the requirements of the amendments made by subsection (c), including a description of actions taken with respect to substantial revisions of current exhibits and programs as well the planning of future exhibits and programs.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC592D8FCC5454313A113142AAA313C2A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section and the amendments made by this section shall take effect as if included in the enactment of title I of division T of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/80t">20 U.S.C. 80t et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

