<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-LIP25781-W84-J0-N96"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2284 IS: Keep Your Coins Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2284</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250715">July 15, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S417">Mr. Budd</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S346">Mr. Lee</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To prohibit Federal agencies from restricting the use of convertible virtual currency by a person to purchase goods or services for the person’s own use, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HB82ED68715D849FF9DED0392BF8B3DD0"><section section-type="section-one" id="HC76C3E1DE9D647059DBB311C6F044277"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Keep Your Coins Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HDA35B8620DC444789DE7D8A08F10BC9E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on restricting use of convertible virtual currency by a person to retain full control over convertible virtual currency</header><subsection id="H82BE559FFF254A9F968B963FCBBE87C9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The head of a Federal agency may not prohibit, restrict, or otherwise impair the ability of a covered user to—</text><paragraph id="H03201A8374324FBAA6567D657974E3F7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>use convertible virtual currency or its equivalent for such user’s own purposes, such as to purchase real or virtual goods and services for the user’s own use; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1BB39C9C363045C9818B2762A0E02E30"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">self-custody digital assets using a self-hosted wallet or other means to conduct transactions for any lawful purpose.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H14C1494589DC4F9D8D07DCE6210699AD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H2DB9034D48464AB79E3DD6DEC882242B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Convertible virtual currencies</header><text>The term <term>convertible virtual currency</term> means a medium of exchange that—</text><subparagraph id="H27A6403A5D8B4A1889A31BB8A017BC3D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has an equivalent value as currency (as defined in section 1010.100 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations)); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF6A2E9ACA79B4FF5A5372E6D9663E0D9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>acts as a substitute for currency but may not possess all the attributes (including legal tender status) specified under such section 1010.100 (or successor regulations).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4CB85ADD988840B28A3A50197AE84907"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered user</header><text>The term <term>covered user</term> means a person that obtains convertible virtual currency to purchase goods or services on that person’s own behalf, without regard to the method in which such covered user obtained such convertible virtual currency.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEBDDF496146F413E9FA0D548CA440613"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Self-hosted wallet</header><text>The term <term>self-hosted wallet</term> means a digital interface—</text><subparagraph id="H6E9DDE7106B9462B9DBA484D584F6908"><enum>(A)</enum><text>used to secure and transfer convertible virtual currency; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6443F2A4E05E4BF69CBE2D039275FEFC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>under which the owner of convertible virtual currency retains independent control over such convertible virtual currency that is secured by such digital interface.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

