<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-TAM25616-TR9-8G-MF4">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1838 IS: DeOndra Dixon INCLUDE Project Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>II</distribution-code>
        <congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session>1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. 1838</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action>
            <action-date date="20250521">May 21, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S408">Mr. Hickenlooper</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S347">Mr. Moran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr.
                    Booker</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S419">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>)
                introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the
                    <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and
                    Pensions</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title>To amend the Public Health Service Act to authorize the Secretary of Health
            and Human Services to carry out a program of research, training, and investigation
            related to Down syndrome, and for other purposes.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H9C1B33F3A6C94B0084013266C2C55636">
        <section section-type="section-one" id="HDEF00BD7DEFF4F63BB71DE072DB84B07">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>DeOndra Dixon INCLUDE Project Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section id="H1B2B8F0E0C5A408FBB197B4A03DA8B9F">
            <enum>2.</enum>
            <header>Findings</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> <paragraph id="H96022FFB71994BB59AD5C4364BEB1F76"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Down syndrome is the most common chromosomal disorder. Each year, about 6,000 babies born in the United States have Down syndrome, affecting about 1 in every 700 babies born.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HA315634D994B4E87B9CD28917E63D7B8">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>Individuals with Down syndrome have a full or partial extra copy of chromosome 21 that leads to certain physical, intellectual, and developmental challenges.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H3F5AF036B19E4D2B8BF47D74DF04FDFF">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Life expectancy of individuals with Down syndrome in the United States has increased dramatically in recent decades. In 1960, the average life expectancy was about 10 years. Today, the average life expectancy of an individual with Down syndrome is nearly 60 years.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H8C94E5861EC04614ADB0ED6BB7EF11C0">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>Individuals with Down syndrome can attend school, work, make their own life decisions, have meaningful relationships, vote, and contribute to society.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H6D154BAF74104D149513CAAFA209AB0D">
                <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Individuals with Down syndrome are at an increased risk for certain medical conditions, such as autoimmune disorders, leukemia, congenital heart disease, sleep dysfunction, and Alzheimer’s disease, but may be at a decreased risk for other conditions.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H3EEC3B22CD164DEDBB7AA46B0BD0D81E">
                <enum>(6)</enum>
 <text>Research and medical care supporting individuals with Down syndrome and their unique disease profile will improve health outcomes and may potentially lead to treatments for individuals born with or without Down syndrome who suffer from diseases associated with that unique profile.</text>
            </paragraph>
        </section>
        <section id="H69DC7EBD3349485198461D9B4DD00E62">
            <enum>3.</enum>
            <header>Down syndrome research</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part A of title IV of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/281">42 U.S.C. 281 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
            <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1DB8F3EFB37E43918EC3F73C51E44EAD">
                <section id="H3A690DFFBE7E46FA8EABD7068B795858">
                    <enum>404P.</enum>
                    <header>Down syndrome research</header>
                    <subsection id="HDFD388FAD7F7458BBB08EBD28C421251">
                        <enum>(a)</enum>
                        <header>In general</header>
 <text>The Secretary, acting through the Office of the Director of NIH, and in consultation with other Federal agencies and partners, shall carry out, directly or through grants or contracts, a program of research, training, and investigation related to Down syndrome to be known as the INvestigation of Co-occurring conditions across the Lifespan to Understand Down syndromE Project or the INCLUDE Project.</text>
                    </subsection>
                    <subsection id="H169E8154CA5F45C494D993D1FD5D69A3">
                        <enum>(b)</enum>
                        <header>Program elements</header>
 <text>The program under subsection (a) shall include research, training, and investigation related to—</text>
                        <paragraph id="HA44710FF0F0247C4BADBAA2622E9A752">
                            <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>high-risk, high reward basic science studies of the effects of chromosome 21 on human development and health;</text>
                        </paragraph>
                        <paragraph id="H8FA0175A948141CC8803E59ED781CD6C">
                            <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>assembling and maintaining a large study population of individuals with Down syndrome;</text>
                        </paragraph>
                        <paragraph id="H7BD00E9C491D4C60871A99814490E805">
                            <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>expanding the number of clinical trials that are inclusive of, or expressly for, individuals with Down syndrome, including novel biomedical and pharmacological interventions and other therapies designed to promote or enhance activities of daily living;</text>
                        </paragraph>
                        <paragraph id="H4C0E56C4B7D444C8BE757047A1B01E68">
                            <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>the biological mechanisms in individuals with Down syndrome responsible for structural and functional anomalies in cells, tissues, and organs, cognitive and behavioral dysfunction, and stunted growth;</text>
                        </paragraph>
                        <paragraph id="HFD509968001A4EE99DC63465AE0A4536">
                            <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text>the identification of biomarkers for the detection of risk factors, diagnosis, and customized interventions and treatments for conditions co-occurring with Down syndrome;</text>
                        </paragraph>
                        <paragraph id="H19B2090D11B94A58907D3D206F122AD6">
                            <enum>(6)</enum>
 <text>why several co-occurring conditions, such as Alzheimer’s disease and autoimmunity, are prevalent in individuals with Down syndrome and how such conditions can be treated concurrently with Down syndrome; and</text>
                        </paragraph>
                        <paragraph id="H5F9F24C5CFFC4C9ABE4CFC10C2403B88">
                            <enum>(7)</enum>
 <text>improving the quality of life of individuals with Down syndrome and their families.</text>
                        </paragraph>
                    </subsection>
                    <subsection id="H3BBFB368651645BB901E40F1746C2DF3">
                        <enum>(c)</enum>
                        <header>Coordination; prioritizing nonduplicative research</header>
 <text>The Secretary shall ensure that—</text> <paragraph id="HD5AD49B346DC4D3291838E38258051BF"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>the programs and activities of the institutes, centers, agencies, and offices of the National Institutes of Health relating to Down syndrome and co-occurring conditions are coordinated, including through the Division of Program Coordination, Planning, and Strategic Initiatives under sections 402(b)(7) and 402A(c); and</text>
                        </paragraph>
                        <paragraph id="HD2B67124EA164693910D74BE06D1C748">
                            <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such institutes, centers, agencies, and offices prioritize, as appropriate, Down syndrome research that does not duplicate existing research activities of the National Institutes of Health.</text>
                        </paragraph>
                    </subsection>
                    <subsection id="HB86B4BBBA8BD493B975306705FFC15F2">
                        <enum>(d)</enum>
                        <header>Technical assistance</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall provide technical assistance to grantees and other involved entities, as appropriate, for carrying out activities pursuant to this section.</text>
                    </subsection>
                    <subsection commented="no" id="HEBD0324B986844DE834BC821638D807F">
                        <enum>(e)</enum>
                        <header>Biennial reports to Congress</header>
                        <paragraph id="H13D6AD303B444B74BD4F0BDACE927B65">
                            <enum>(1)</enum>
                            <header>In general</header>
 <text>The Secretary shall submit, on a biennial basis, to the Committee on Energy and Commerce and the Subcommittee on Labor, Health and Human Services, Education, and Related Agencies of the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions and the Subcommittee on Labor, Health and Human Services, Education, and Related Agencies of the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate, a report that catalogs the research conducted or supported under this section.</text>
                        </paragraph>
                        <paragraph id="H258887D559754D3F843CCA72B292E75B">
                            <enum>(2)</enum>
                            <header>Contents</header>
 <text>Each report under paragraph (1) shall include—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H38DA3343ABFB42DAB846AED6EB1B8470"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identification of the institute, center, agency, office, or entity involved;</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <subparagraph commented="no" id="H69BA3829DAC2478EA6D363FE5B7F0DA9">
                                <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>a statement of whether the research is or was being carried out directly by the institute, center, agency, office, or entity or by multiple institutes, centers, agencies, offices, or entities; and</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <subparagraph commented="no" id="H92ADDE405FEB441A9C5C8F1EA65204E7">
                                <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>identification of any resulting real world evidence that is or may be used for clinical research and medical care for patients with Down syndrome.</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                        </paragraph>
                    </subsection>
                </section>
                <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
            </quoted-block>
        </section>
    </legis-body>
</bill>

