<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA744E0711A61462392BC06C7B61BA702" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2151 IH: Seizure Awareness and Preparedness Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2151</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250314">March 14, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000188">Mr. Norcross</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to authorize a grant program to support students who have epilepsy or a seizure disorder.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8823CBAF1536407794D240327E4234C3" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H2DDE8D6A0F3042B4A5516857E3AE3845"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Seizure Awareness and Preparedness Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H2E435364C4FC4247989A68A94510A8E8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Grant program to support students who have epilepsy or a seizure disorder</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE10D2C01A8AC4F93AB5FC164AFCA0625"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title IV of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7101">20 U.S.C. 7101 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following: </text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCE3363835085490EB8054579FDF6CB3E">
<part id="H95DB86C150C649C0B87AFC4DFDE0FA5A" style="OLC"><enum>G</enum><header>Grant program to support students who have epilepsy or a seizure disorder </header>
<section id="H7FCBDC64FD6B467186674C983A752F16"><enum>4701.</enum><header>Grant program to support students who have epilepsy or a seizure disorder</header>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA21B2E37D7054728B8BEC0A0AABC6533"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H8858C6EAA4304036B7889BB6C9FC06A0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Individualized emergency health care plan</header><text>The term <term>individualized emergency health care plan</term> means a document developed by a student's health care provider, in consultation with the parent of a student with epilepsy or a seizure disorder, other appropriate medical professionals who may be providing epilepsy or seizure disorder care to the student, and the school nurse, which outlines a set of procedural guidelines that provide specific directions about what to do in a particular emergency situation and is signed by the health care provider, the parent, and the school nurse.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC892DFB85CD84A81B04A98F53D053B76"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Individualized health care plan</header><text>The term <term>individualized health care plan</term> means a document developed by a student's health care provider, in consultation with the parent of a student with epilepsy or a seizure disorder, other appropriate medical professionals who may be providing epilepsy or seizure disorder care to the student, and the school nurse, which is consistent with the recommendations of the student's health care provider and which sets out the health services needed by the student at school and is signed by the health care provider, the parent, and the school nurse.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H3EB83AD64EB3449587F0DECF9C8B8423"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorization of grant program</header><text>The Secretary shall award grants to States, on a competitive basis, to enable the States to award subgrants to local educational agencies to carry out a program that supports students with epilepsy and seizure disorders in schools. </text></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD3F2A2D1119A49D69CAA41EAE60433C6"><enum>(c)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Applications for grants</header><text>A State that desires to receive a grant under this section shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and accompanied by such information as the Secretary may require.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H04CA9ECC154C4D1EA0175DF9770AD061"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Subgrants authorized</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB40CD4F4E02A4FEBBC57858DD4B93C89"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State that receives a grant under this section shall use the grant funds to award subgrants to local educational agencies to enable the local educational agencies to carry out a program that funds training of school personnel on seizure awareness and preparedness that covers individualized health care plans and individualized emergency health care plans for students who have epilepsy or a seizure disorder.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1C8C435AB5BA4EA38DFCDB5199E224FE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applications for subgrants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A local educational agency that desires to receive a subgrant under this subsection shall submit an application to the State at such time, in such manner, and accompanied by such information as the State may require.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE6E4D37AE4B54F2596577AF10F304B4D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Use of subgrant funds</header> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBC02A65E19A54CA1A8DD8D92304B1423"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3928B4B41FCB45B1850D8B3C2440B11E"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Required use</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A local educational agency that receives a subgrant under this subsection shall use the subgrant funds to carry out a program in the elementary schools and secondary schools served by such agency to fund training of school personnel on seizure awareness and preparedness that covers individualized health care plans and individualized emergency health care plans for students who have epilepsy or a seizure disorder.</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9176EC3372D74A38ABF35B856B755785"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Permissive uses</header><text>A local educational agency that receives a subgrant under this subsection may use the subgrant funds for—</text> <subclause id="H623E3C2486A647AAB50599A02E8BAF0F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>training of school personnel to administer or assist with the administration of seizure medications;</text></subclause>
<subclause id="HB29E2E7450AB46979A3959583E1374D1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>training and education of students on seizure awareness and preparedness; </text></subclause> <subclause id="H9599B45C2156433286FAE0873AA5315C"><enum>(III)</enum><text>recruiting, hiring, and retaining dedicated compliance staff who are responsible for ensuring that all training and program requirements related to seizure awareness, preparedness, and management are consistently met; and</text></subclause>
<subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7F68077D6A9340BFBE59A6DE2D86559A"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">other activities or programs determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDE2100AB18E24D628B803C44D2F485E5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Information included</header><text>It is recommended that each individualized health care plan and each individualized emergency health care plan include the following information:</text>
<clause id="H46CF6F8F10F74A8E9A8491947EB6A33F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Written orders from the student’s physician or advanced practice nurse outlining the epilepsy or seizure disorder care.</text></clause> <clause id="HA7325C1E585D49C59F9F7A171DD6A618"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The symptoms of the epilepsy or seizure disorder for that particular student and recommended care.</text></clause>
<clause id="H6D1522CAD5AF43B68BB2ED789554AA3E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Full participation in exercise and sports, and any contraindications to exercise, or accommodations that shall be made for that particular student.</text></clause> <clause id="H178729E05649466C97E68BFE21CA837A"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Accommodations for school trips, after-school activities, class parties, and other school-related activities.</text></clause>
<clause id="HE7E7AFB2C40242A0A63D239174926DFA"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Education of all school personnel about epilepsy and seizure disorders, how to recognize and provide care for epilepsy and seizure disorders, and when to call for assistance.</text></clause> <clause id="H32569CA8CB7D4449B3F82FAB4AC8AB11"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Medical and treatment issues that may affect the educational process of the student with epilepsy or the seizure disorder.</text></clause>
<clause id="H8E9845760E7444F6B337A52C7E85B79D"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>The student’s ability to manage, and the student’s level of understanding of, the student’s epilepsy or seizure disorder. </text></clause> <clause id="H87EAEA80D16F451C93E41623DC6E29F5"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>How to maintain communication with the student, the student’s parent and health care team, the educational staff, and the school nurse.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0CA586D9E16A436B8EB888AB7CFEA40B"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Training required</header>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4A86B61F201B44CD99CE5FBC80A475C4"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each local educational agency carrying out a program supported with subgrant funds shall ensure that the school nurse assigned to a particular elementary school or secondary school supported by the program—</text> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H43A7C6CC629B473E90295F1DB6F24184"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">coordinates the provision of epilepsy and seizure disorder care at such school; and </text></subclause>
<subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H283CF62BB85B4208AA6B247912980E06"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensures that all staff are trained not less often than every 2 years in the care of students with epilepsy and seizure disorders, including staff working with school-sponsored programs outside of the regular school day, as provided in individualized health care plans and individualized emergency health care plans.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H425726CD4A8D453D9CD11CA416B7E975"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Instruction</header><text>The training required under clause (i) shall include a Department of Education-approved on-line or in-person course of instruction provided by 1 or more nonprofit national organizations that support the welfare of individuals with epilepsy and seizure disorders.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H8F7A36BD2E714193A736315CE68A2D23"><enum>(D)</enum><header>School bus drivers</header><text>Each local educational agency carrying out a program supported with subgrant funds shall ensure that each school bus driver who transports a student with epilepsy or a seizure disorder receives notice of the student’s condition, information on how to provide care for epilepsy or the seizure disorder, emergency contact information, epilepsy and seizure disorder recognition and first aid training, and parent contact information.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBD7B193D23DC4756BE1CBEB0539B7DD2"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Release</header><text>Each local educational agency carrying out a program supported with subgrant funds shall ensure that the school nurse assigned to a particular elementary school or secondary school supported by the program obtains a release from each parent of a student with epilepsy or a seizure disorder who requests an individualized health care plan or an individualized emergency health care plan, to authorize the sharing of medical information between the student's physician or advanced practice nurse and other health care providers.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H28381FAFCB5347ED93EB12239C5E03B1"><enum>(F)</enum><header>No liability</header><text>No school employee, including a school nurse, a school bus driver, a school bus aide, or any other officer or agent of a local educational agency, shall be held liable for any good faith act or omission consistent with the provisions of this section. Good faith shall not include willful misconduct, gross negligence, or recklessness.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC46860E0D1CD4239A53189C98FCB3961"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Supplement; not supplant</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Grant and subgrant funds provided under this section shall be used to supplement, not supplant, other Federal or State funds available to carry out activities described in this section. </text></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC122D98F59514598A6087E98B28BFA7E"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $34,500,000 for the period of fiscal years 2026 through 2030.</text></subsection></section></part><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA73CB2BA3368461EAE792EB07C094B68"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents in section 2 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 4644 the following new items: </text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5A30A684817F415B9580215235BA9311">
<toc>
<toc-entry bold="off" level="part">Part G—Grant program To support students who have epilepsy or a seizure disorder</toc-entry>
<toc-entry bold="off" level="section">Sec. 4701. Grant program to support students who have epilepsy or a seizure disorder.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

