<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDE81B079E56F4686AE6F63B9E871BDB9" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2667 IH: Flexible Savings Arrangements for a Healthy Robust America Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2667</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250407">April 7, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001314">Mr. Bean of Florida</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001120">Mr. Crenshaw</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow distributions from a health flexible spending arrangement or health reimbursement arrangement directly to a health savings account in connection with establishing coverage under a high deductible health plan.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF5281E26928441D8908C3BD056D10231" style="OLC"><section id="HA04C814C97764300A1BFE28A3BD3CA41" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Flexible Savings Arrangements for a Healthy Robust America Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" id="H08E819EE9EDA473D9A09399DF4A81FF2" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header><enum-in-header>FSA</enum-in-header> and <enum-in-header>HRA</enum-in-header> terminations or conversions to fund <enum-in-header>HSAs</enum-in-header></header><subsection id="HF6A16569242D4EBDBE6B547411D4CDAF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/106">Section 106(e)(2)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block id="H875CC2F797BD44F88C727E5EC4DFB722" style="OLC"><paragraph commented="no" id="HFE78ABB4273D42C4BAAF9B5FCB84CD19"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualified HSA distribution</header><text>For purposes of this subsection—</text><subparagraph id="HF1D63BEA314545F4B63C191DEA373D9A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>qualified HSA distribution</term> means, with respect to any employee, a distribution from a health flexible spending arrangement or health reimbursement arrangement of such employee directly to a health savings account of such employee if—</text><clause id="H7FEEF5F315714917A7A4858CE01406F7"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such distribution is made in connection with such employee establishing coverage under a high deductible health plan (as defined in section 223(c)(2)) after a significant period of not having such coverage, and</text></clause><clause id="HC6055F0BEAF34A77A7E8050B141CCEAE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>such arrangement is described in section 223(c)(1)(B)(iii) with respect to the portion of the plan year after such distribution is made.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0336A5E52BB64708A4954B0EF0BF2D9A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Dollar limitation</header><text>The aggregate amount of distributions from health flexible spending arrangements and health reimbursement arrangements of any employee which may be treated as qualified HSA distributions in connection with an establishment of coverage described in subparagraph (A)(i) shall not exceed the dollar amount in effect under section 125(i)(1) (twice such amount in the case of coverage which is described in section 223(b)(2)(B)).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H4192E831ADD746AC87AD1F6DD227925E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Partial reduction of limitation on deductible HSA contributions</header><text>Section 223(b)(4) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of subparagraph (B), by striking the period at the end of subparagraph (C) and inserting <quote>, and</quote>, and by inserting after subparagraph (C) the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF51896DB366443F2B6DFE08AD6EB3385" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="H1D0AA28FD1CA4F5BADB4A349CA83AA70"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">so much of any qualified HSA distribution (as defined in section 106(e)(2)) made to a health savings account of such individual during the taxable year as does not exceed the aggregate increases in the balance of the arrangement from which such distribution is made which occur during the portion of the plan year which precedes such distribution (other than any balance carried over to such plan year and determined without regard to any decrease in such balance during such portion of the plan year).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H044FF38BF7294DCEA6876E01FEC53160"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conversion to HSA-Compatible arrangement for remainder of plan year</header><text>Section 223(c)(1)(B)(iii) of such Code is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4D775CD7B6B14AADB5EA99ED09AB84B6" style="OLC"><clause id="H3E7B7984A1464770A8CBF08CB97DF5B7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">coverage under a health flexible spending arrangement or health reimbursement arrangement for the portion of the plan year after a qualified HSA distribution (as defined in section 106(e)(2) determined without regard to subparagraph (A)(ii) thereof) is made, if the terms of such arrangement which apply for such portion of the plan year are such that, if such terms applied for the entire plan year, then such arrangement would not be taken into account under subparagraph (A)(ii) of this paragraph for such plan year.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HDE437CFE2FA4412295F2122B8635B3F4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Inclusion of qualified HSA distributions on <enum-in-header>W–2</enum-in-header></header><paragraph id="H5DC3ABF4E2BF4CBDA64FDBCFB9CC1992"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 6051(a) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of paragraph (16), by striking the period at the end of paragraph (17) and inserting <quote>, and</quote>, and by inserting after paragraph (17) the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H70059315C87A482DB7255260DE5F3296" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H835DD85A14E2461B977793D4252F78CE"><enum>(18)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the amount of any qualified HSA distribution (as defined in section 106(e)(2)) with respect to such employee.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H6D5230E567FB45DB980400D0EA07BC4A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 6051(a)(12) of such Code is amended by inserting <quote>(other than any qualified HSA distribution, as defined in section 106(e)(2))</quote> before the comma at the end.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H9FE39098995744C8908FEF297EA2A6AB"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to distributions made after December 31, 2025, in taxable years ending after such date.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

