<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD13DF2D8C7A649C29A0946EB02FA6C77" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HRES 690 IH: Expressing support for the designation of September 2025 as “National Workforce Development Month”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 690</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250910">September 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="G000558">Mr. Guthrie</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000467">Mr. Thompson of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of September 2025 as <quote>National Workforce Development Month</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas support for the education, development, and career advancement of the workforce in the United States, known as <quote>workforce development</quote>, is crucial to the ability of the United States to compete in the global economy;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas collaboration among multiple stakeholders, including State and local governments, workforce development boards, Governors, State and local education, workforce, and human services agencies, community colleges, local businesses, employment service providers, and community-based organizations, provides for long-term, sustainable, and successful workforce development across traditional sectors and emerging industries;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the number of jobs that require more than a high school diploma but not a 4-year degree is projected to increase by roughly 23 percent by 2030;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Bureau of Labor Statistics reported in July 2025 that there are approximately 7,400,000 unfilled jobs in the United States, which decreases corporate productivity, reduces the local tax base, and hinders global competitiveness;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 76 percent of business leaders say greater support for skills development would help their businesses;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2021, a record 47,400,000 Americans quit their jobs, many of whom did so to try to improve their employment situation;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, as of August 2025 in the United States—</text><paragraph id="HCFD1277AEF584DCF843C996583A1E20A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>roughly 7,200,000 individuals are unemployed; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCC682110F6894BEC91ED8B6E06CFCC78"><enum>(2)</enum><text>unemployment rates for Black and Hispanic adults are well above the unemployment rates for White adults; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H64ECE10519954542A63FC209F85863F4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>workers without postsecondary education and skills development are more likely to be unemployed;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to a recent poll, 44 percent of United States workers said their current job may be at risk because of new developments in technology and automation, while 50 percent said they would retrain for a career in a different field or industry if they had the opportunity;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2014, Congress reauthorized the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3101">29 U.S.C. 3101 et seq.</external-xref>) with overwhelming bipartisan support in recognition of the need to strengthen the focus of the United States on the skills necessary to effectively prepare individuals for employment in local and regional industries, and this legislation is now due for reauthorization;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3101">29 U.S.C. 3101 et seq.</external-xref>) supports employment, career exploration, skills development, and supportive services for approximately 2,700,000 individuals with barriers to employment, including— </text><paragraph id="H15686BA698C341868E1AF203831890B1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>individuals who earn low incomes;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3EFE557673FC4D0CA3767B18E9109A80"><enum>(2)</enum><text>individuals who are out of work, including the long-term unemployed;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1F1978F33E9F4ED2B72B10CA2CAF061B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>individuals displaced by outsourcing;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H99768429042142F19614360C6890711E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>individuals living in rural areas or areas with persistently high unemployment;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEC0378AE4C1A4E1AAA5CCE61851BBCDB"><enum>(5)</enum><text>individuals who seek employment after incarceration;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H961DB910585A4BF8A0D46CAD9BA18D8F"><enum>(6)</enum><text>individuals looking to learn new skills; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF29EF75FAA6C489D93BE7385475C285B"><enum>(7)</enum><text>individuals with disabilities;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the more than 550 workforce development boards and 2,300 American Job Centers are a driving force behind growing regional economies by providing resources and assistance to workers, often through apprenticeships, work experience opportunities, and on-the-job training, with over 70 percent of individuals receiving career and training services becoming employed;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas ongoing State and local implementation of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3101">29 U.S.C. 3101 et seq.</external-xref>) provides unprecedented opportunities to develop the skills of workers in the United States through access to effective, quality workforce education, including the development and delivery of proven strategies such as sector partnerships, career pathways, integrated education, work-based learning models, and paid internships;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2022, programs authorized under the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3101">29 U.S.C. 3101 et seq.</external-xref>) are estimated to have served 8,583,318 individuals and have the potential to serve many more if the delivery of such programs is improved;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas State programs established under the Wagner-Peyser Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/49">29 U.S.C. 49 et seq.</external-xref>)—</text><paragraph id="H60F490F7DF434EC3A4B761D2EF345D70"><enum>(1)</enum><text>ensured that nearly 2,500,000 workers, including more than 146,000 veterans and more than 120,000 individuals with disabilities, had access to career services virtually and through American Job Centers during the 2020 program year; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6D5A78F132B34FC2B34F0FC059E863BE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>are a foundational part of the workforce development system;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas community colleges and other workforce development providers across the United States are well situated—</text><paragraph id="H322C433C2E7D45508D99819915E01F7B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to train the next generation of workers in the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA887791992D648A4A60642D604A7EBA8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to address the educational challenges created by emerging industries and technological advancements;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas participation in a career and technical education (referred to in this preamble as <quote>CTE</quote>) program decreases the risk of students dropping out of high school, and all 50 States and the District of Columbia report higher graduation rates for CTE students, as compared to other students;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas community and technical colleges operate as open access institutions serving millions of students annually at a comparatively low cost;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Strengthening Career and Technical Education for the 21st Century Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/224">Public Law 115–224</external-xref>; 132 Stat. 1563) supports the development and implementation of high-quality CTE programs that—</text><paragraph id="H1016F2279B8040A4BB4BB9B0C1D20BC9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>combine rigorous academic content with occupational skills; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H348776B1C4964C0DA3218C6E7874294A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>serve approximately 12,300,000 high school and college students across the country;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas there are nearly 600,000 registered apprentices in the United States, and there is growing and bipartisan support for expanding quality earn-and-learn strategies to help current and future workers gain skills and work experience;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the federally supported workforce system and partner programs—</text><paragraph id="HF6D4944A235847678AC6026F8F908FED"><enum>(1)</enum><text>have helped rebuild the economy of the United States and provide increased economic opportunities; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0DC37D8E136D49838936E757BFF24CF6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide a pathway into 21st century jobs that support families while ensuring that businesses in the United States find the skilled workforce needed to compete in the global economy; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H012756A43B874AFC86042D362509AC55"><enum>(3)</enum><text>generate tax revenue, increase labor force participation, and reduce reliance on public assistance;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H60CD69ADB27543F5B02660D03362C4FF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>leverage additional resources from private philanthropy, business, community foundations, and other public and private sources; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB5E0283DE56747589F8072B7B5FA1212"><enum>(5)</enum><text>have the potential to serve many more if the delivery of such programs is improved; and</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas workforce development is crucial to sustaining economic security for workers in the United States: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HA122D7C3A2384508B19D4EA978FA37BE"><section id="HD4812E56591B473ABCEC6F202BDC8237" section-type="undesignated-section" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="H1244BB66D6894CDDAE124494A01E403A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>expresses support for the designation of <quote>National Workforce Development Month</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA7DB30AE354F471C9FD9BB45408B74B2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>supports Federal initiatives to promote workforce development; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC3D2C6257A46499EAA94923E785AF747"><enum>(3)</enum><text>acknowledges that workforce development plays a crucial role in supporting workers, increasing labor force participation, and growing the economy.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

