<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MCG25109-1HR-34-FJR"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S588 IS: Presidential Audit and Tax Transparency Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 588</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250213">February 13, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S366">Ms. Warren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S316">Mr. Whitehouse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S313">Mr. Sanders</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S275">Ms. Cantwell</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for examination and disclosure with respect to Presidential income tax returns, to amend <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/131">chapter 131</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, to require the disclosure of certain tax returns by Presidents and certain candidates for the office of the President, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Presidential Audit and Tax Transparency Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H552989F4D92540AFBD25A4F47E1CB32F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Examination and disclosure with respect to Presidential income tax returns</header><subsection id="H3E55415E1E234020801A8D816F71E481"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Audit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/78">chapter 78</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by redesignating section 7613 as section 7614 and by inserting after section 7612 the following new section: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1855FAD7B1DF43A4A60FD876D093D47A"><section id="H9710BDF1D2FE437182F5AE3F3E708431"><enum>7613.</enum><header>Examination with respect to Presidential income tax returns</header><subsection id="H52A12804F8D848A78A2A245A612017F2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As rapidly as practicable after the filing of any Presidential income tax return, the Secretary shall conduct an examination to ascertain the correctness of such return and enforce the requirements of this title with respect to the taxable year covered by such return.</text></subsection><subsection id="H3DDCBCDAC64B42D1AA35F42A53E3816B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reports</header><paragraph id="H76E5F709B6D14EDEBAF16AE1F0534688"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial report</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the filing of a Presidential income tax return, the Secretary shall disclose and make publicly available an initial report regarding the examination with respect to such return. Such report shall include—</text><subparagraph id="HCC6A71446DDB4DADA69E441F2987A24C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the name of the taxpayer,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H043B641681614FF8802D538D5425DB85"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an identification of the subparagraph of subsection (c)(1) which describes such return,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H800D91CED4EF45FDA57F1E6FDAB3663F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the date that such return was filed, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H581FF82D1D2143A6A0315C77B16BC8D0"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the date on which the examination with respect to such return commenced (or, if such examination has not commenced as of the date of such report, a detailed description of the reasons that such examination has not commenced).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC72A324BF9E24407B3E6F6118B2AB853"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Periodic reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the disclosure of the report described in paragraph (1) with respect to any Presidential income tax return and not later than 180 days after the most recent disclosure of a report described in this paragraph with respect to such return, the Secretary shall disclose and make publicly available a periodic report regarding the examination with respect to such return. Such report shall include—</text><subparagraph id="HCDD92D91AFEF4CCDBC45115DB07D4F2B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the information described in subparagraphs (A) through (D) of paragraph (1),</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE900E28CFD3A46D8B93919DDD75FA10E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of the status of the examination, including a description of the portions of the examination which have been completed, which are in process, and which are anticipated to take place, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0221BE22FFB440A5A5951E687D954491"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an estimate of the time frame for the completion of the examination, including an identification of factors which could alter such time frame, reasonable estimates of the likelihood of such factors (taking into account the specific facts and circumstances of the examination), and the likely specific effects of such factors on such time frame.</text></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">Notwithstanding the preceding sentence, a periodic report shall not be required under this paragraph with respect to any return after the date on which a final report is disclosed under paragraph (3) with respect to such return.</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2E849587DC4041F8A01ED4FD079E84B2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Final report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the completion of the examination described in subsection (a) with respect to any Presidential income tax return, the Secretary shall disclose and make publicly available a final report regarding such examination. Such report shall include—</text><subparagraph id="H305C50DF39714B80805AD4CD015BFC2C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the information described in subparagraphs (A) through (C) of paragraph (1),</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H21F69F9364824BEEAFCADAC36A55A748"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the date on which the examination with respect to such return was completed,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H628B2BC8DC074CA0B30D8B8D814138F0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a list of the audit materials (as defined in section 6103(q)(2)) with respect to such examination, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5467047B154341AD918B2E8914531953"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a description (including the amount) of each proposed adjustment, adjustment, and controversy with respect to such examination together with a description of how such proposed adjustment or controversy was resolved (or a statement that such proposed adjustment or controversy was not resolved, as the case may be).</text></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">For purposes of this paragraph, an examination shall be treated as complete on the date that the Secretary provides the taxpayer with a notice of deficiency, or any closing document referred to in section 6103(q)(2)(A)(v), with respect to such examination.</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB57B13A43C994DCFB8DE258EAE06A9FB"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Extension of due date report</header><text>If a request is made for an extension of the due date for filing any Presidential income tax return, the Secretary shall, not later than 90 days after such request is granted or denied, disclose and make publicly available an extension of due date report with respect to return. Such report shall include—</text><subparagraph id="H84D1AE344BED4B40AC93033911A53952"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the information described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (1),</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFBAB663343CB49B888AC1C85DDA96F88"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a statement that an extension of the due date for the filing of such return has been requested,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDB9F52FE8C3843E384C9C0FF6A2DC226"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the date that such request was received,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFE7F6096358E43E2B41FED31EDBD53CA"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a statement of whether such request has been granted or denied, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC40A422710114EF08A0C7F3A1CF212D1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the due date of such return (including any extensions).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD730529B1578459A9B2EBB7BB65BEC39"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Treatment of failure to file</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a failure to file a Presidential income tax return before the close of the 60-day period beginning with the date prescribed for filing of such return—</text><subparagraph id="H6172FB866FCF426790DBC0D5C2214784"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary shall conduct the examination described in subsection (a) with respect to the taxable year covered by the return to which such failure relates, </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H76829A575F414A7CB019F23E035DFF58"><enum>(B)</enum><text>reports made pursuant to this paragraph shall include a statement that such report is with respect to a return which the taxpayer failed to file, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H430E4D74D37B44228E533D8DBED218F6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>this section and section 6103(q) shall otherwise apply to such failure in the same manner as if a return were filed at the close of such period.</text></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">The application of this paragraph with respect to any failure to file a Presidential income tax return shall not prevent the application of this section with respect to such return at such time as such return may be filed.</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="H66C3954840584D7B8D7407E782B21786"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, a document shall not be treated as having been made publicly available unless made available on the Internet.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEA6554380D674F468142EDA8DA3F74E9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Presidential income tax return</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text><paragraph id="HB0445781C224459887214EBC6600EA87"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <quote>Presidential income tax return</quote> means any relevant income tax return of—</text><subparagraph id="HD295FA945F6B4E189B2B009A3775323F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a President,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBB38A8A106434B2F8D9DABFF95934F32"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an individual who is married (within the meaning of section 7703(a)) to a President for the taxable year to which such return relates,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD2FD2FBE22644878A33D4EF12632A4BC"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any corporation or partnership which is controlled by any individual described in subparagraph (A) or (B) at any time during the taxable year to which such return relates, </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4AA00C06CEFB42768D3BBA4A7A35A063"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the estate of any person described in (A) or (B) or any estate with respect to which any person described in subparagraph (A), (B), or (C) is an executor or beneficiary at any time during the taxable year to which such return relates, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9A8F48D4CFDD489699A5FACE85E3B53B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>any trust with respect to which any person described in subparagraph (A), (B), (C), or (D) is a grantor, fiduciary, or beneficiary, or for which another trust described in this subparagraph is a grantor or beneficiary, at any time during the taxable year to which such return relates.</text></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">Such term shall include any schedule, attachment, or other document filed with such return.</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3E0F6B6008614DD0B8BAFE24411D4228"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Relevant income tax return</header><text>The term <quote>relevant income tax return</quote> means, with respect to a President, any income tax return if—</text><subparagraph id="HC2D63EFFD213416F8AC86098AE1F9499"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any portion of the taxable year to which such return relates is during the period that such President is the President,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2D7BB451FCD343B1AD47EB0E3280B5C4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the due date for such return (including any extensions) is during such period, or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB97E23DFD00C43339FE34AC441BDDE05"><enum>(C)</enum><text>such return is filed during such period.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0A382C9E0247439681ED3A30E53CE1AA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Control</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of paragraph (1)(C)—</text><subparagraph id="HEA0EB95BF89E44A58829B6ADEE3B8D94"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as otherwise provided in this paragraph, control shall be determined under the rules of paragraphs (2) and (3) of section 6038(e) (determined without regard to subparagraphs (A) and (B) of such paragraph (2) and without regard to subparagraph (C) of paragraph (3) thereof).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H85325504175A4525AD7E13AA37339D1D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Restriction on family attribution</header><clause id="HA92011F01D684DA59C26DBC74AE137B2"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in clause (ii), for purposes of applying subparagraph (A)—</text><subclause id="HF0E6CB9B5E644DF599CCF694E2D00908"><enum>(I)</enum><text>section 318 shall be applied without regard to subsection (a)(1)(A)(ii) thereof, and</text></subclause><subclause id="H3ECED2A5E3A64238AEFD60C65C4ED740"><enum>(II)</enum><text>section 267(c) shall be applied by treating the family of an individual as including only such individual’s spouse (in lieu of the application of paragraph (4) thereof).</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H8E5FDDF355B748F98ECF0A5D28EB4941"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Exception for recent transfer to family members</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of determining whether any corporation or partnership is controlled by a President under paragraph (1)(C) for any taxable year, clause (i) shall not apply if such corporation or partnership was controlled by such President (after application of clause (i)) at any time during the 4 immediately preceding taxable years.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H71175ED4DE5747DB8C9AE72580EAF3EA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Application to amended returns</header><text>For purposes of this section and section 6103(q), any amendment or supplement to a return of tax shall be treated as a separate return of tax and the determination of when such amendment or supplement is filed, and whether such amendment or supplement is a relevant income tax return, shall be made without regard to the underlying return.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HAA4889953C974922A16410738C63446B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Disclosure</header><text>Section 6103 of such Code is amended by redesignating subsection (q) as subsection (r) and by inserting after subsection (p) the following new subsection: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H28FDA6B29F434FBFB07C89F249559D3C"><subsection id="H85D3B3B467E04652B2BB27B33B2B1246"><enum>(q)</enum><header>Disclosure with respect to Presidential income tax returns</header><paragraph id="H5F515A5D0ED64B96B1EA652C22FCC530"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall disclose and make publicly available (within the meaning of section 7613(b))—</text><subparagraph id="H29116ED4229945E48726433C421683A6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>each Presidential income tax return (as defined in section 7613(c)),</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1D877C556A72414E997EA98816417DFC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>each report described in section 7613(b), and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAA775DA7B79D497BAFF811952226EBE6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any audit materials with respect a return described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE2877F3E4BD046ABA0FA841FA657966C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Audit materials</header><text>The term <quote>audit materials</quote> means, with respect to any return:</text><subparagraph id="HF7EF1C27752B44BE99163BE04D52635D"><enum>(A)</enum><text> Any of the following which are provided by the Secretary to the taxpayer (or any designee of the taxpayer):</text><clause id="H7A4786808E2D47EC97EE30C3E4B5D031"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Any written communication which identifies such return as being subject to examination.</text></clause><clause id="H017FCA1B5BAD46BBA68047CB7904F52C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any written communication which proposes the adjustment of any item on such return, any report by an examiner related to such proposed adjustment, and any supervisory approval of any penalty proposed as part of such adjustment.</text></clause><clause id="H77C0E9E22B60452386D1A7B62838C916"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Any memorandum or report of the Internal Revenue Service Independent Office of Appeals with respect to such return, and any denial of any request described in subparagraph (B).</text></clause><clause id="H67595DF69BD44B828F2BB7037BC473A4"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Any notice of deficiency with respect to such return.</text></clause><clause id="HB221E915C2FF4521B82EF620907AFC66"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Any closing documents with respect to the examination of such return, including any closing agreement or no change letter.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H075B3F635B7A4007A5DBF13B8397A61B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Any request for referral to the Internal Revenue Service Independent Office of Appeals of any controversy with respect to such return.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H70A66EAB81774DA684AD45266695C5C7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Any petition filed with the Tax Court for a redetermination of any deficiency referred to in subparagraph (A)(iv).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H09D1223431EC4D8E925197D328D67C4F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exception for certain identity information</header><text>The information disclosed and made publicly available under paragraph (1) shall not include any identification number of any person (including any social security number), any financial account number, the name of any individual who has not attained age 18 (as of the close of the taxable year to which the return relates), the name of any employee of the Department of the Treasury, or any address (other than the city and State in which such address is located). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC1D4F0097E454D89AAB89793881AD0CB"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Timing of disclosures</header><text>Any information required to be disclosed under paragraph (1) shall be disclosed and made publicly available not later than—</text><subparagraph id="HF99AB5AA098545A897AA9AE5A5937944"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case of any income tax return referred to in paragraph (1)(A), 90 days after the date that such return is filed,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H22C5F35876C4445B81E9E3B282898C42"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of any report referred to in paragraph (1)(B), the deadline specified in section 7613(b) for disclosing such report, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1BFCF1489BFE4829BD156517266CFBCB"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of the audit materials referred to in paragraph (1)(C), 90 days after the completion of the examination (within the meaning of section 7613(b)(3)) with respect to the return to which such audit materials relate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H685A00EB95F94144BD3E0B7484C5282E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter A of chapter 78 of such Code is amended by redesignating the item relating to section 7613 as an item relating to section 7614 and by inserting after the item relating to section 7612 the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H932472CC48FA416085F43B0337BA5F84"><toc container-level="quoted-block-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" idref="H1855FAD7B1DF43A4A60FD876D093D47A" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"><toc-entry idref="H9710BDF1D2FE437182F5AE3F3E708431" level="section">Sec. 7613. Examination with respect to Presidential income tax returns.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H60B92F2D85C8456B9729B4DBA0856DAD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this subsection shall apply to returns, amendments, and supplements filed (and failures to file returns which occur) after the date of the enactment of this Act (and to reports and audit materials with respect to such returns, amendments, supplements, and failures).</text></subsection></section><section id="id96BA37441F7C4836BFFC9ED3F21AAB3A"><enum>3.</enum><header>Additional disclosure of tax returns by Presidents and certain Presidential candidates</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5fadb92ff06f44edac268a7a936edc77"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7fc6b422edc94ae0a69e3cf8c18672af"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Disclosure requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/131">Chapter 131</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text><subparagraph id="id0E307D76F4454FF888478138C2BC85BF"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting after section 13104 the following:</text><quoted-block id="idC5FEB7A54F094579BBF9264BF6E3DFD8" display-inline="no-display-inline" style="OLC"><section id="idEF75742302BE4A77B4812CC82CB94704"><enum>13104A.</enum><header>Disclosure of tax returns</header><subsection id="id0BCEF6C8CB57486BB663AA2208CEB569"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="id434B58BDA51E4A8D838751DC0D0BD1A3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Applicable income tax return</header><subparagraph id="ida2eb1469fe01480e90b6abcc1cfb9e25"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>applicable income tax return</term> means, with respect to any taxable year, any return (within the meaning of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6103">section 6103(b)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986) relating to Federal income taxes of—</text><clause id="id0e49073c48b74006a235dbc494e52374"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a covered candidate or covered individual;</text></clause><clause id="id5805b960cc934a828f96e97389b64ed2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an individual who is married (within the meaning of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/7703">section 7703(a)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986) to a covered candidate or covered individual for the taxable year;</text></clause><clause id="id30a6c99707954b44b50d5dda8c1d5dcd"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any corporation or partnership that was controlled (as determined under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/7613">section 7613(c)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986) by an individual described in clause (i) or (ii) at any time during the taxable year;</text></clause><clause id="id8edb396ed8f140f9b9138f959bc13123"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the estate of any person described in clause (i) or (ii) or any estate with respect to which any person described in clause (i), (ii), or (iii) is an executor or beneficiary at any time during the taxable year; and</text></clause><clause id="id6c447973a22b4438ba5ac2944798f613"><enum>(v)</enum><text>any trust with respect to which any person described in clause (i), (ii), (iii), or (iv) is a grantor, fiduciary, or beneficiary, or for which another trust described in this clause is a grantor or beneficiary, at any time during the taxable year.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idae7b6b0396ec46f5a2623aee0f2dcda5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusion of certain documents</header><text>Such term shall include any schedule, attachment, or other document filed with such return.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id027FF9A7959D4F62BF3A004E300C9C7C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered candidate</header><text>The term <term>covered candidate</term> means an individual—</text><subparagraph id="id139CE66DFB9C4237BC11F78E7BB3CC60"><enum>(A)</enum><text>required to file a report under section 13103(c); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id98B50DE9E13143A2A74DACA8424BD105"><enum>(B)</enum><text>who is nominated by a major party as a candidate for the office of President, regardless of whether the individual is nominated after May 15 of an applicable year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id25F04898585047148DCEFDC4DF354469"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered individual</header><text>The term <term>covered individual</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="id9015E44AF6414233A7A365D2054B646B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a President required to file a report under subsection (a) or (d) of section 13103; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE7B77D8201854AD5AEDA586494734091"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an individual who occupies the office of the President required to file a report under section 13103(e).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id754A2CCD9CFC483BAE1E1086878DF45A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Major party</header><text>The term <term>major party</term> has the meaning given the term in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/9002">section 9002</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id3D8B3E18F25E4F61869842FC1E618421"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Disclosure</header><paragraph id="id48c4d92ea463481a86099fb2f24e2d0c"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered individuals</header><subparagraph id="id437DF8965E004D1DBF2D3A6CCCECDF56"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In addition to the information described in subsections (a) and (b) of section 13104, a covered individual shall include in each report required to be filed under this title a copy of all applicable income tax returns for the 3 most recent taxable years for which a return has been filed with the Internal Revenue Service as of the date on which the report is filed.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id61EDE085A7384B3AAC61A68916E38EE5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Failure to disclose</header><text>If an income tax return is not disclosed under subparagraph (A), the Director of the Office of Government Ethics shall submit to the Secretary of the Treasury a request that the Secretary of the Treasury provide the Director of the Office of Government Ethics with a copy of the income tax return.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idF08EA7CE5621481C8A3CF7E9110C8073"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Publicly available</header><text>Each income tax return submitted or provided under this paragraph shall be filed with the Director of the Office of Government Ethics and made publicly available in the same manner as the information described in subsections (a) and (b) of section 13104.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3CA846208348477CA4489A825253E47F"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Redaction of certain information</header><text>Before making any income tax return submitted under this paragraph available to the public, the Director of the Office of Government Ethics shall redact such information as the Director of the Office of Government Ethics, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury (or a delegate of the Secretary), determines appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idDB905592829D4126AE53E2E49CFC6D20"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered candidates</header><subparagraph id="id27AE7F702B9249DE93D1678430507427"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 15 days after the date on which a covered candidate is nominated, the covered candidate shall amend the report filed by the covered candidate under section 13103(c) with the Federal Election Commission to include a copy of the applicable income tax returns for the 3 most recent taxable years for which a return has been filed with the Internal Revenue Service.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id779EDD78AC67411EB045F938D91C5CDC"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Failure to disclose</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an applicable income tax return is not disclosed under subparagraph (A), the Federal Election Commission shall submit to the Secretary of the Treasury a request that the Secretary of the Treasury provide the Federal Election Commission with the applicable income tax return.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id590F5984D3C749CFB76A346B2735F156"><enum>(C)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Publicly available</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each applicable income tax return submitted or provided under this paragraph shall be filed with the Federal Election Commission and made publicly available in the same manner as the information described in section 13104(b).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE1E0385C58CE4E49A8D7308320DA2481"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Redaction of certain information</header><text>Before making any applicable income tax return submitted under this paragraph available to the public, the Federal Election Commission shall redact such information as the Federal Election Commission, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury (or a delegate of the Secretary) and the Director of the Office of Government Ethics, determines appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id7340a66a80814ba083b0e43dcb343cb6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Special rule with respect to returns disclosed under other authority</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, in the case of any applicable income tax return that has been made publicly available pursuant to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6103">section 6103(q)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, the requirements of paragraphs (1)(A) and (2)(A) shall be satisfied with respect to such return if the covered individual or covered candidate (as the case may be) provides the location on the Internet where such disclosure has been made publicly available.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD276F9EE94DE44A599D7CBBB9ABD88A6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in section 13106—</text><clause id="idAEB7D9C7591E4E5586360CFE3777DCBC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text><subclause id="id9471EEDAF74C4FD283FAE6E4CC0591C9"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), in the first sentence, by inserting <quote>or any individual who knowingly and willfully falsifies or who knowingly and willfully fails to file an applicable income tax return that such individual is required to disclose pursuant to section 13104A of this title</quote> before the period; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id8BB1EA86FD324328824B16E50C799064"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)(A)—</text><item id="id7C8787005BAE41F8A6734383AA7ABA6D"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>in clause (i), by inserting <quote>or falsify any applicable income tax return that such person is required to disclose under section 13104A of this title</quote> before the semicolon; and</text></item><item id="idC4169830CDFE4FAAB76D1577440B5C13"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>in clause (ii), by inserting <quote>or fail to file any applicable income tax return that such person is required to disclose under section 13104A of this title</quote> before the period;</text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="idFBF101F0D6F74E8AA725CB0807AC6595"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subsection (b), in the first sentence, by inserting <quote>or willfully failed to file or has willfully falsified an applicable income tax return required to be disclosed under section 13104A</quote> before the period;</text></clause><clause id="idE404EAB1C8DC40C284531F573428A25F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in subsection (c), by inserting <quote>or failing to file or falsifying an applicable income tax return required to be disclosed under section 13104A</quote> before the period; and</text></clause><clause id="idD219C37348A24FADAEFBBC057BF5FCF4"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>in subsection (d)(1)—</text><subclause id="id7C16B14BBF1A4FBB95AE123B5CCA6CA2"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by inserting <quote>or files an applicable income tax return required to be disclosed under section 13104A</quote> after <quote>subchapter</quote>; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id9E9BE7614F4841119789150D52C34B73" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by inserting <quote>or such applicable income tax return, as applicable,</quote> after <quote>report</quote>.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb6de83a33fdb4532b9d2dda83443908e"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Special rule for individuals who are covered candidates on date of enactment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any individual who is a covered candidate (as defined in section 13104A of title 5, United States Code, as added by paragraph (1)) on the date of the enactment of this Act, section 13104A(b)(2)(A) shall be applied by substituting <quote>30 days after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Presidential Audit and Tax Transparency Act</short-title></quote> for <quote>15 days after the date on which a covered candidate is nominated</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id10c0a850c41b40abb03d801c5e4de7ec"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/131">chapter 131</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb3ba9a0bb6ca439eb11bb67cb61879da"><toc><toc-entry level="section" bold="off">13104A. Disclosure of tax returns.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfed23a56c5be479aa6856ff75efb9411"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authority To disclose information</header><paragraph id="id758A56B4D38842DB97C78EE169BC185A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6103">Section 6103(l)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB7CDFE7C1DB6498F9C2C6ACC773EEA59"><paragraph id="idA1D2E0C35B244E79BBA0F38C84161C65"><enum>(23)</enum><header>Disclosure of return information of Presidents and certain Presidential candidates under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/131">chapter 131</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code</header><subparagraph id="id6777EF09A141496C923498F98C53E76B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Disclosure of returns of Presidents</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id11007ECA98554A82AD6316256A202238"><enum>(i)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall, upon written request from the Director of the Office of Government Ethics pursuant to section 13104A(b)(1)(B) of title 5, United States Code, provide to officers and employees of the Office of Government Ethics a copy of each applicable income tax return with respect to any covered individual who has been identified in such request. </text></clause><clause id="id5E8BC4142290452FAE7168DF621B154D"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Disclosure to public</header><text>The Director of the Office of Government Ethics may disclose to the public any applicable income tax return required to be submitted to the Director pursuant to section 13104A(b)(1) of title 5, United States Code.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idBD323D8739F94EC59D343FA5B411F219"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Disclosure of returns of certain candidates for President</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idFF1A729806334BD798896B93F89F34B8"><enum>(i)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall, upon written request from the Chairman of the Federal Election Commission pursuant to section 13104A(b)(2)(B) of title 5, United States Code, provide to officers and employees of the Federal Election Commission a copy of each applicable income tax return with respect to any covered candidate who has been identified in such request. </text></clause><clause id="id2C33B01741B746938243A40F7DE3AAF4"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Disclosure to public</header><text>The Federal Election Commission may disclose to the public any applicable income tax return required to be filed with the Commission pursuant to section 13104A(b)(2) of title 5, United States Code.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idEFE6B587BFCA4A80ACE4247F6248C1B1"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the terms <quote>applicable income tax return</quote>, <quote>covered individual</quote>, and <quote>covered candidate</quote> have the meanings given those terms in section 13104A of title 5, United States Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="id857594c0b44b4ea48eacc5977bdfd084" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6103">Section 6103(p)(4)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, in the matter preceding subparagraph (A) and in subparagraph (F)(ii), is amended by striking <quote>or (22)</quote> and inserting <quote>(22), or (23)</quote> each place it appears. </text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

