<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H57A35A97731345A18338A038B475FABB" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 659 IH: Expressing support for the designation of August 15, 2025, as “Indian Independence Day: A National Day of Celebration of the World’s Two Largest Democracies”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 659</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250815">August 15, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000601">Mr. Landsman</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of August 15, 2025, as <quote>Indian Independence Day: A National Day of Celebration of the World’s Two Largest Democracies</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Republic of India achieved its independence from the British Empire on August 15, 1947, marking the end of the struggle which freed the Indian people;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, on said day, Jawaharlal Nehru, the inaugural Prime Minister of India, hoisted the Indian national flag above the Lahore Gate of the Red Fort in Delhi;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas members of India’s numerous ethnic groups, minorities, and religions including Hindus, Muslims, Sikhs, and Christians, all participate in the celebration of Independence Day;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, according to United Nations population estimates, India is the largest democracy in the world, with an estimated population of more than 1,464,000,000 people;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas India’s contributions to democracy have inspired leaders and movements across the globe, including civil rights leader Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr.;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas India, along with the United States, embraces a system where the ultimate authority to govern is vested in the people;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas these and other ideals have forged a close bond between our two nations and their peoples;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas India is a strategic partner in the Quadrilateral Security Dialogue (QUAD) and the I2U2 Group, seeking to promote topics like security, economic, and humanitarian issues;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Prime Minister Modi’s Official State Visits to the United States during his tenure has anchored the United States and India in a new level of trust and mutual understanding based on common interests and shared commitments to freedom, democracy, pluralism, the rule of law, and respect for human rights;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Americans with Indian heritage enhance public life in the United States as government officials, military personnel, and law enforcement officers who diligently uphold the principles of the United States Constitution and contribute to the enriching diversity of the Nation; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas it is proper and desirable to celebrate with the Indian people, and to reaffirm the democratic principles on which our two nations were born: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H403CB2A1B908428D8FADA6B58420A25C"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H2AF2B903BE814C63A20481DAED63BF2A"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> 
<paragraph id="HA9A3364B208E472C9DD11038F7EFBF9B" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>expresses support for the designation of <quote>Indian Independence Day: A National Day of Celebration of the World’s Two Largest Democracies</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8FB4567BADDB4DD2B67F175D375EAD0C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>offers heartfelt greetings to the people of India as they conclude their festivities commemorating the 78th anniversary of India’s liberation from the British Empire;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H64CD72F650FE42C398DF3B0683EF5405"><enum>(3)</enum><text>acknowledges the contributions of Americans of Indian descent to society in the United States; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H98FDE9A5AF3C4E56856F8582E56B2457"><enum>(4)</enum><text>expresses the belief that the strong partnership between the United States and India, rooted in shared democratic values, will continue to advance global democracy and foster peace, stability, and prosperity for all nations.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

