<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCB3B5024323941658FF5CEDC8FD2471E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3592 IH: Protect LNG Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3592</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250523">May 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001095">Mr. Hunt</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To address the effect of litigation on applications to export liquefied natural gas, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H3D7FC97C027C421287F82B2D7CAF628D" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H806467F5BC214D3CAF0E8C3E8A30897C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protect LNG Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H704AFBF797C84E1EAB3AFCC94BA24817"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
<paragraph id="H6FC493D050AF456BBB211DE4FB6EBE29"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered application</header><text>The term <quote>covered application</quote> means an application for—</text> <subparagraph id="H32E44CC3D9A940A3BCFA3FAEA61848C4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an authorization to export natural gas under section 3(a) of the Natural Gas Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/717b">15 U.S.C. 717b(a)</external-xref>); or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H167CEDA0E9C54AA09463649B1919CAB6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an authorization to site, construct, expand, or operate a covered facility under section 3(e) of the Natural Gas Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/717b">15 U.S.C. 717b(e)</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5BD78A6FE7BF49D69B68F50D7B1AD362"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered facility</header><text>The term <quote>covered facility</quote> means a liquefied natural gas facility for which a proposal to site, construct, expand, or operate is required to be approved by—</text>
<subparagraph id="H9CDC0DE44DF4434B8437D4D2A5D27BBF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H46DCB9FF63B74497A074072EFD18E39A"><enum>(B)</enum> <clause id="H7BCEC0E60CEE4841BAB05599BF15EAB1" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission; or</text></clause>
<clause id="H449130EE908449DB81A671C5E6FC4FA5" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Maritime Administration.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9504FEB2302C48F2A394856B951C57DE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of Energy.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="H6D1A13C43FFF4C40B41BE191CCD2320F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Effect of litigation on applications to export liquefied natural gas</header>
<subsection id="HDF9B1AD96D5D49028C40633288FE7E7E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Effect of litigation</header><text>A civil action relating to an environmental review under the Natural Gas Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/717">15 U.S.C. 717 et seq.</external-xref>) or the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>) with respect to a covered facility shall not affect the validity of a permit, license, or approval issued to the covered facility that is the subject of the civil action.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HFDD645AAC3204AEAB0722D3B75B49B45"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Remand; processing of covered applications</header><text>If, in a civil action described in subsection (a), the environmental review for a permit, license, or approval issued to the covered facility that is the subject of the civil action is found by the applicable court to violate the Natural Gas Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/717">15 U.S.C. 717 et seq.</external-xref>) or the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>)—</text>
<paragraph id="H840F668143A94D409CC7A514B18A128B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>notwithstanding chapter 5 or 7 of title 5, United States Code (commonly referred to as the <quote>Administrative Procedure Act</quote>), the applicable court shall not set aside or vacate the permit, license, or approval issued to the covered facility but instead remand the matter to the relevant Federal agency to resolve the violation; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBF4CC9A79C2D406BB44DAFA2CC317A2D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the relevant Federal agency shall continue to process all covered applications.</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="H69312BFBEDDB40AE9199C9B291922378"><enum>4.</enum><header>Action on covered applications</header>
<subsection id="H21EA70356387491E919C97AFE152A17F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Judicial review</header><text>Except for review in the Supreme Court of the United States, the court of appeals of the United States for the circuit in which a covered facility is, or will be, located pursuant to a covered application shall have original and exclusive jurisdiction over any civil action for the review of an order issued by a Federal agency with respect to the covered application.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H12F1EF7DC91E49C9A452E83256EF0770"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Expedited review</header><text>The applicable United States Court of Appeals under subsection (a) shall—</text>
<paragraph id="HB3D4B671626C4B3EAAA8CE465A4B2DB8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>set any civil action brought under this subsection for expedited review; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCFAD82F4675B48F4A71E7CD060AF797B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>set the action on the docket as soon as practicable after the filing date of the initial pleading.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H847200CF88944506BFD606748A3FED3C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Transfer of existing actions</header><text>In the case of a covered application for which a petition for review has been filed as of the date of enactment of this Act, the petition shall be—</text> <paragraph id="H8A069A407D6C43FDBD156B2FF9F7EFB5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>on a motion by the applicant, transferred to the court of appeals of the United States in which the covered facility that is the subject of the covered application is, or will be, located; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE25F2D5E319048D2BD4D8971C5CD1290"><enum>(2)</enum><text>adjudicated in accordance with this section.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H6554BEDE5B8146609C5718AA7C2E1357"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limitation on claims</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a claim arising under Federal law seeking judicial review of a permit, license, or approval issued by a Federal agency for a covered facility pursuant to a covered application shall be barred unless the claim is filed not later than 90 days after publication of a notice in the Federal Register announcing that the permit, license, or approval is final pursuant to the law under which the agency action is taken, unless a shorter time is specified in the Federal law pursuant to which judicial review is allowed.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H889F8EF4ABE44153A62B53617D894A53"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Savings clause</header><text>Nothing in this section establishes a right to judicial review or places any limit on filing a claim that a person has violated the terms of a permit, license, or approval.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

