<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H41B29F3E9839479DB1CA9784F978D868" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5271 IH: Pakistan Freedom and Accountability Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5271</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250910">September 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001058">Mr. Huizenga</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="K000400">Ms. Kamlager-Dove</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001194">Mr. Moolenaar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000310">Ms. Johnson of Texas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001229">Mr. Shreve</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To impose sanctions relating to undermining democracy in Pakistan.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC80B62D60D5C462E859E0A17B82138A9" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HF7B258985B924D8B8662765185614AC4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Pakistan Freedom and Accountability Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H6652E0941EEA4364A87F0341276E23F9" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HD0D32B7F5F4C478CBED3B99456C47BBB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Pakistan is an important and valued partner of the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1D06E4D8848F44A1A0722DF3D25188F9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>On December 10, 1948, Pakistan became one of the original signatories to, and supported the creation of, the Universal Declaration of Human Rights (UDHR).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H16DBF27CE74C470D982BF8D9D533172A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>On June 23, 2010, Pakistan ratified the International Covenant on Civil and Political Rights (ICCPR).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE7051B43DE1645DEA29A069E6EA9C977"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Following the end of the most recent period of military rule in 2008, Pakistan completed its first peaceful transition of power between civilian governments led by different political parties in 2013, but the military continues to exert undue influence on the politics of the country.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEC83F390F81440A8A6469C6773A6EC6A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>During previous elections, such as the ones held in 2018, election monitors expressed concern about constraints on the freedom of expression and freedom of association and noted allegations of influence by the military-led establishment on the electoral process.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9E6515BB310740B8BD4E286F54F007AC"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The Department of State’s Country Report on Human Rights Practices has often highlighted significant human rights issues in Pakistan across multiple years, including unlawful, arbitrary, and extrajudicial killings, forced disappearance and arbitrary detention by the state or its agents, the taking of political prisoners, serious restrictions on free expression and media, and substantial interference with the freedom of peaceful assembly and freedom of association.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9AD17211DCAC46729A96A81F3B8D685F"><enum>(7)</enum><text>On February 8, 2024, millions of Pakistanis participated in Pakistan’s most recent general election, with record numbers of women, youth, and members of religious and ethnic minority groups registered to vote Pakistan’s civil society—including women’s networks and youth groups—have continued to be resilient in their efforts to constructively engage political leaders and government institutions in more democratic, accountable, and responsive governance.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H60E40B7254464E3CB35C7FA767F2203F"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Pakistan’s 2024 general election was marked by allegations by credible international and local observers of interference in the electoral process, including electoral violence, intimidation, arrest of political actors, restrictions to freedom of assembly, restrictions on freedom of expression, and restrictions on access to the internet and telecommunications.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD664A8E456444972889BB18670A26D74"><enum>(9)</enum><text>On February 9, 2024, the Department of State noted that it shared the assessment of observers that the election included <quote>undue restrictions on freedoms of expression, association, and peaceful assembly</quote>, condemned <quote>electoral violence</quote> as well as <quote>restrictions on the exercise of human rights and fundamental freedoms</quote>, and called for the full investigation of fraud or interference in Pakistan’s general elections.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H494D8045138342F6AA143FC82A19B1F0"> <enum>(10)</enum> <text>In October 2024, the Government of Pakistan ratified the 26th Amendment to the Pakistani constitution, which increased political influence on the Judicial Commission of Pakistan and over the process to appoint the Chief Justice of Pakistan.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA3BCB00934BF4902BD38FDABCE4CCA01"><enum>(11)</enum><text>In November 2024, Pakistan adopted legislation extending the terms of military service chiefs for two years.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H42DA50C2E4DD46BCB2874EE625CD4E33"><enum>(12)</enum><text>On December 23, 2024, the Department of State criticized the use of military courts against Pakistani civilians, noting that they lack <quote>judicial independence, transparency, and due process guarantees</quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE11E1DAFA84244AAAAF8B0841F98DB60"><enum>(13)</enum><text>In August 2025, Pakistan enacted legislation to expand the powers of security and military forces to carry out <quote>preventive</quote> detentions that contravene international human rights and due process standards, including under the ICCPR.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3539B9D6B0FA40D695B50B56CB7990CF"><enum>(14)</enum><text>An essential safeguard of democracy is civilian command and control of apolitical military and security forces, and the Constitution of Pakistan states that <quote>the Federal Government shall have control and command of the Armed Forces</quote>, and the oath taken by members of the Armed Forces swears they will <quote>uphold the Constitution</quote> and <quote>not engage in any political activities</quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2C48621487A04A90A9BE4CBECD6D7C9C"><enum>(15)</enum><text>Democracy, development, rule of law, and respect for human rights and fundamental freedoms are interdependent and mutually reinforcing.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HBF73D3ED244E4E42B63B7E9F9DDB436C"><enum>3.</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress—</text> 
<paragraph id="HDCD6DC5603D249AE997CF6A9C0716318"><enum>(1)</enum><text>affirms its strong support for democracy in Pakistan, including free and fair elections reflecting the will of the people of Pakistan;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF0BA7F66FFAD4E038E56E4C107EE362F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>calls on the President and the Secretary of State to strengthen engagement with the Government of Pakistan to ensure democracy, human rights, and the rule of law are upheld;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H153C947829FF441EA78910655FE04FF0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>urges the Government of Pakistan to uphold democratic and electoral institutions, human rights, and the rule of law, and respect the fundamental guarantees of due process, freedom of press, freedom of assembly, and freedom of speech of the people of Pakistan; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1ACC0E0E76DC464795C688AA66E766FD"><enum>(4)</enum><text>condemns attempts to suppress the people of Pakistan’s participation in their democracy, including through harassment, intimidation, violence, arbitrary detention, restrictions on access to the internet and telecommunications, or any violation of their human, civil, or political rights.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H995AF39AA1D644688AEA0D955DA69FD8"><enum>4.</enum><header>Sanctions relating to undermining democracy in Pakistan</header> 
<subsection id="H2BC71BA2434B4E669A0DDF5170416C70"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation of persons responsible for undermining democracy in pakistan</header> 
<paragraph id="H7E210C044F584AAAB88D1FCF1BC3921F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall transmit to the appropriate congressional committees a report identifying—</text> <subparagraph id="H0F0FE63E162F461EA657E24AF2DE6268"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any senior official or former senior official of the government, military, or security forces of Pakistan who the President determines, based on credible evidence, is responsible for gross violations of human rights;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0EA3DB92E6A645D9B4D9FBC27FBBBE3A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any senior official or former senior official of the government, military, or security forces of Pakistan who the President determines has committed or directed gross violations of human rights associated with undermining democracy in Pakistan; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H11E5C59CC0DE423AA3EAFB79F0B6E985"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any entities owned or controlled by senior officials or former senior officials of the government, military, or security forces of Pakistan identified pursuant to subparagraphs (A) and (B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBFF3A70F54804C3C9DB29285A42F813E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Form of report</header><text>The report required under this subsection may be transmitted in classified form.</text></paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="HAE9BE5455E7C48DD831949E2169424E3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Imposition of sanctions</header><text>The President may impose any or all of the sanctions described in the Global Magnitsky Human Rights Accountability Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2656">22 U.S.C. 2656</external-xref> note) against any or all of the foreign persons identified in the report required by subsection (a).</text> 
<paragraph id="HCC706F2E989041C3871895CD233B2726"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Exception to comply with international obligations</header><text>Sanctions under paragraph (2) shall not apply with respect to the admission of an alien if admitting or paroling the alien into the United States is necessary to permit the United States to comply with the Agreement regarding the Headquarters of the United Nations, signed at Lake Success June 26, 1947, and entered into force November 21, 1947, between the United Nations and the United States, or other applicable international obligations.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE192B13EF09C40BF871171C43ED86F30"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception relating to the provision of humanitarian assistance</header><text>Sanctions under this section may not be imposed with respect to transactions or the facilitation of transactions for—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H1CB4899E742B4D91A23BFC951E19CEC9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the sale of agricultural commodities, food, medicine, or medical devices;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H78C51B63BD1E458EB0B48F145B9AE804"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the provision of humanitarian assistance;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8768A6A99D054145890C6D18C332DE9E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>financial transactions relating to humanitarian assistance; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCFECCE4BD7A34BA6B49A3DB37F3579A9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>transporting goods or services that are necessary to carry out operations relating to humanitarian assistance.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF45031D935E84FB8AE56B9F483F6B4A6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exception for intelligence, law enforcement, and national security activities</header><text>Sanctions under this section shall not apply to any authorized intelligence, law enforcement, or national security activities of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H170CC91C5DD24A469608374CF60F58D3"><enum>5.</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> 
<paragraph id="H251FB0E26ADD4F16A28DB933AC8ACB24"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5051B23B8F264605ADD52468858655AD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HAC16F91EB0DC4DA09FE9900A1977A2FC"><enum>6.</enum><header>Sunset</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act shall terminate on September 30, 2030.</text></section> </legis-body></bill>

