<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HAD3B0C999271458294256BAE979EF618" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1835 IH: Model Employee Reinstatement for Ill-advised Termination Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1835</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250304">March 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001229">Mrs. McIver</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="C001127">Mrs. Cherfilus-McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000477">Mrs. Foushee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001231">Mr. Mannion</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000510">Mr. Smith of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000598">Mr. Garcia of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000172">Ms. Ocasio-Cortez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000489">Mr. Turner of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000601">Mr. Landsman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000309">Mr. Jackson of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="I000058">Mr. Ivey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001231">Ms. Simon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001130">Ms. Crockett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000617">Ms. Pressley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000617">Mrs. Ramirez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000402">Mr. Kennedy of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001313">Ms. Brown</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="U000040">Ms. Underwood</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000490">Mr. Bishop</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000602">Ms. Lee of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000788">Ms. Williams of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000176">Mr. Olszewski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000370">Ms. Adams</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000586">Mr. García of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001205">Ms. Scanlon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000631">Ms. Dean of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000474">Mrs. Torres of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001324">Mr. Bell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000606">Mr. Latimer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000482">Mrs. Trahan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001227">Ms. McClellan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001136">Mr. Conaway</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001103">Mr. Hernández</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000187">Ms. Waters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000620">Ms. Pettersen</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000110">Mr. Fields</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the reinstatement of recently terminated probationary Federal employees, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE477D7B803E6473B8828658D13CB66F6" style="OLC"><section id="H322CB288736B45BBBE1C1F811A342E65" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Model Employee Reinstatement for Ill-advised Termination Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>MERIT Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H80D83E562E794117B7B0BB352F3C6190"><enum>2.</enum><header>Reinstatement of affected probationary employees</header><subsection id="HEB072D9DC79A45CC8C06969F5E1F5983"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each affected probationary employee, other than an affected probationary employee entitled to a payment under subsection (b), is entitled, in accordance with this Act, to an appointment to a position in the former employing agency of such affected probationary employee that is the same or similar to the previous Federal position of such affected probationary employee and, if such employee elects to accept an appointment under this subsection, a payment in an amount equal to the amount that such affected probationary employee would have been paid by such former employing agency during the period beginning on the termination date of such affected probationary employee and ending on the date on which such affected probationary employee is so appointed if such affected probationary employee had not become an affected probationary employee.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1F3515A7E939418591294DE54C1DB65A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Subsequent Federal employment</header><paragraph id="H331F8780EF5749A995A7FB0DC9498767"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (4)—</text><subparagraph id="H9D946B9357B24185B0E373CF0A6D9E38"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an affected probationary employee that was appointed to a new Federal position and holds such a position as of the date of the enactment of this Act is entitled to the payment described in paragraph (2); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1047C26D7ABD4E56AFCB9B8713231617"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an affected probationary employee that was appointed to a new Federal position and does not hold such a position as of the date of the enactment of this Act is entitled to—</text><clause id="H7AFD515C2717482984FBA9AFA7270136"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an appointment to a position in the former employing agency of such affected probationary employee that is the same or similar to the previous Federal position of such affected probationary employee; and</text></clause><clause id="HB9FE336C2F234629AD0AFABB0EDDE036"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if such affected probationary employee elects to accept an appointment under clause (i), the payment described in paragraph (3).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFEAF886D3FEF4FACAD5F0CD0CAB1AE64"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Current Federal employee payment described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The payment described in this paragraph is a payment in an amount equal to the difference between—</text><subparagraph id="H1066000E9D79414EBA29B806092160C5"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the amount that the affected probationary employee would have been paid by the former employing agency of such affected probationary employee during the period beginning on the termination date of such affected probationary employee and ending on the date on the date of the enactment of this Act; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H18445FC7DBF840658BC2C21271519097"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the amount equal to the sum of pay earned by such affected probationary employee in any new Federal position to which such affected probationary employee was appointed during such period.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF474557FF71E4545834661B4F752885E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Other affected employee payment</header><text>The payment described in this paragraph is a payment in an amount equal to the sum of—</text><subparagraph id="H30F89852B5664E6C9A73C8849993879A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the payment described under subparagraph (2); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H477CE7290E8047FC9CCCC0E29E82EDBF"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a payment in an amount equal to the amount that the affected probationary employee would have been paid by the former employing agency of such affected probationary employee during the period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act and ending on the date on which such affected probationary employee is appointed under paragraph (1)(B) if such affected probationary employee had not become an affected probationary employee.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H06DBF13F644B4C3B845F5DD7BCA92392"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>An affected probationary employee is not entitled to a payment under paragraph (1) if the amount of such payment is less than zero.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H12D4ED5E79A34A7E8FB3057221173952"><enum>(5)</enum><header>New Federal position defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, the term <term>new Federal position</term> means a position in the Federal Government to which the affected probationary employee was appointed after becoming an affected probationary employee.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H064B9756861F4655B5574233316FDEE8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Payment</header><paragraph id="HDF7B654405454AFA9C965241E7D110EA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The former employing agency of an affected probationary employee shall begin making any payment to which such affected probationary employee is entitled under this section not later than 90 days after the pay for each relevant position is determined in accordance with section 5.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3D71368889EE4380910906C00436ECFB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Method</header><text>A payment described in subsection (a) or (b) shall be paid in one lump sum.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC700FBFC47AB48F89750939811FAE0C8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Taxation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, any payment to an individual under subsection (a) or (b) shall be treated as wages paid with respect to the employment of such individual.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0539E342DEFF4A719759965AEE2099E4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Pay limits</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A payment to an affected probationary employee under this section shall be disregarded with respect to any limit on the pay of employees that is applicable to the affected probationary employee.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H26B41D2963CB4CB895AF6A4D2A972293"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Reinstatement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An appointment under subsection (a)(1) or (b)(1)(B) to a position in the competitive service (as defined in section 2102 of title 5, United States Code) shall be made without regard to the provisions of subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/33">chapter 33</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H597339C9427E44D98E12D028473B0A5E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Employment benefits</header><text>For the purposes of this section, a position is the same or similar to a previous Federal position with respect to an affected probationary employee only if the employment benefits, including retirement benefits, health insurance, and leave, available to such affected probationary employee in such position match or exceed the employment benefits available to such affected probationary employee in such previous Federal position.</text></subsection></section><section id="HACE3A12675D44CCC993A2F5B8E7DDDD4"><enum>3.</enum><header>Notice and selection</header><subsection id="H4C5EFFE6D0C64D19B8B82C2DC84628E3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Notice</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the head of each Executive agency shall notify each affected probationary employee for which such Executive agency is the former employing agency of the rights of affected probationary employees under this Act and the method by which such affected probationary employee may inform such Executive agency of the acceptance or rejection an appointment in accordance with subsection (b)(1).</text></subsection><subsection id="HD3F4C8C17D824F619DB57581B5B09FF3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Selection</header><paragraph id="H0A0379DD017D4B6992BB47899C889E2D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An affected probationary employee entitled to an appointment under section 2 must inform the former employing agency of such affected probationary employee of the acceptance or rejection of such appointment by such affected probationary employee not later than 30 days after receiving the notice required by subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDAA5534FFDC7432E9052220EB3D70F2B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Forfeiture</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An affected probationary employee entitled to an appointment under section 2 that does not inform the former employing agency of such affected probationary employee in accordance with paragraph (1) shall cease to be entitled to such an appointment.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD63C18523C0640DE9F855959D699AC14"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Agency compliance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an affected probationary employee accepts an appointment under section 2 and informs the former employing agency of such affected probationary employee of such acceptance in accordance with subsection (b), the head of such former employing agency shall make such appointment not later than 30 days after such affected probationary employee so informs such former employing agency.</text></subsection></section><section id="HCBF25458C61145A080025BEDB5FF1BAA" commented="no"><enum>4.</enum><header>Separation treatment</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Each affected probationary employee is deemed to have been involuntarily separated without cause from the previous Federal position of such affected probationary employee.</text></section><section id="H9CF391B728304A828942CF3EB7FBAB72"><enum>5.</enum><header>Payment determination</header><subsection id="HBA2364EA9A644F0EBF8F74D7290E1BE6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purposes of this Act, the Director of the Office of Personnel Management shall determine the pay for a position held by an affected probationary employee based on such evidence of the pay of such position as the affected probationary employee may provide, or if the Director determines sufficient evidence has not been so provided to adequately determine the pay for such position, the pay shall be determined by the Director based on such other information as the Director determines appropriate.</text></subsection><subsection id="H72D082DD7ABD47619BDA0DFE1D9F6F2E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Employee information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An affected probationary employee may provide evidence of the pay of a position to the Director of the Office of Personnel Management under subsection (a) until the earlier of—</text><paragraph id="HD71E3D8F948C4C5D8AF39837080A4310"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the date that is 60 days after the date on which such affected probationary employee received the notice described in section 3(a); or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H021089C763EB42BF8B70762588B1DC2F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the date on which the Director determines the pay for such positions for the purposes of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4FEC6C65A99548D88881BD2624EB30D5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Information sharing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The head of each Executive agency shall provide to the Director of the Office of Personnel Management such information as the Director may require to carry out this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="H4CA72A83C1CA449C80446F1DE89DB6E6"><enum>6.</enum><header>Reports</header><subsection id="H90EC70948B644DB995D4AC0BCBB55503"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Mass termination report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a report on the mass terminations during the period beginning on January 20, 2025, and ending on the date of the enactment of this Act, including—</text><paragraph id="H711F2A8896E043EBA30220E5084D3E88"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of employees (as defined in section 2105 of title 5, United States Code) voluntarily or involuntarily separated from Government service as part of such mass terminations, in total and disaggregated by Executive agency;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC5F3468A14C943D6891B528C064055C7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for employees described in paragraph (1) that were involuntarily separated from Government service as part of such mass terminations, the reasons provided for such involuntary separation;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE641190713B44F48B3F117B0064FDDCD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the number of affected probationary employees;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3D56C333C052479A8197DC59FF0EB721"><enum>(4)</enum><text>recommendations for employees described in paragraph (1), other than affected probationary employees, to which the provisions of this Act should apply; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H21DE159741904841B4D3427CDFCB4550"><enum>(5)</enum><text>such other information as the Comptroller General determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H58026B51F41D4E8E8A7EADBC125E7E4E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reinstatement report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of the Office of Personnel Management shall submit to Congress a report on the reinstatement of affected probationary employees under this Act, including the number of affected probationary employees notified under section 3(a) and the number of affected probationary employees that accepted an appointment under this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="HD09D58FC262B4E03A2756D82E9340FAD"><enum>7.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H7A6D527CF1FA4C1BB6F6E2CC3855CA36"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Affected probationary employee</header><text>The term <term>affected probationary employee</term> means an individual who—</text><subparagraph id="H4616B21F6EE648178B58AEBA29563D27"><enum>(A)</enum><text>was voluntarily or involuntarily separated from service in an Executive agency as part of a mass termination by an Executive agency during the period beginning on January 20, 2025, and ending on the date of the enactment of this Act; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7013200F860F4C21AFA010622E01D9ED"><enum>(B)</enum><text>immediately prior to such separation—</text><clause id="HD0180C01E46649CCBC60674DFD36651B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>held a position in the competitive service, excepted service, or Senior Executive Service, other than under a temporary appointment; and</text></clause><clause id="H043F2383C39248E3B534AF316F13E6FE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>was either—</text><subclause id="HB516764A777E425F8ADA198C0FCC9EB9"><enum>(I)</enum><text>serving a probationary or trial period under an initial appointment; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H02AD1CB1149746AF9B52580DF41B94F4"><enum>(II)</enum><text>otherwise not an employee (as defined in section 7511 of title 5, United States Code) because such individual had not completed the required years of current continuous service.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9EADECB9CFDD4B859744939CBA30709C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Competitive service</header><text>The term <term>competitive service</term> has the meaning given such term in section 2102 of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H293A67D9C44549DE9C571A308A6BBD53"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered separation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered separation</term> means a separation from Government service that is—</text><subparagraph id="H0673779629B44B9FBEE369F43DC65E51"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an involuntary separation from Government service, other than an involuntary separation for retirement under section 3382 of title 5, United States Code; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6C0C9A10AAA947888C40C5E97E26813F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a voluntary separation from Government service for compensation or other incentives offered by the Federal Government.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA431EC0261B143DDBC896232028098CA"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Excepted service</header><text>The term <term>excepted service</term> has the meaning given such term in section 2103 of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAA9A668A9DBF4CC8B856ABDCF7ED5C75"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Executive agency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Executive agency</term> has the meaning given such term in section 105 of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H90AB633648E14100932AD87006F5658B"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Former employing agency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to an affected probationary employee, the term <term>former employing agency</term> means the Executive agency from which the separation of such individual made such individual an affected probationary employee.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF6F766363CFE46E09E4C4707E5B0B7D8"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Mass termination</header><text>The term <term>mass termination</term> means not less than 15 covered separations from service in an Executive agency during a 30-day period pursuant to the same or related actions, directives, orders, or activities by the Federal Government.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0C070F441DBF4D129204676E319744C6"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Previous Federal position</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>previous Federal position</term> means the position in the Federal Government held by the affected probationary employee in the former employing agency immediately before becoming an affected probationary employee.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2594843467144AD8BF423BB55298CFF2"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Senior Executive Service</header><text>The term <term>Senior Executive Service</term> has the meaning given such term in section 2101a of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

