<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD7AF8CF8A3EE4F26853CD4D18D2D4072" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3235 IH: More Opportunities for Moms to Succeed Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3235</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250507">May 7, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000470">Mrs. Fischbach</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="F000475">Mr. Finstad</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001212">Mr. Stauber</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001211">Mrs. Miller of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001205">Mrs. Miller of West Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000478">Ms. Tenney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000806">Mr. Webster of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001086">Mrs. Harshbarger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000591">Mr. Guest</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001039">Mrs. Cammack</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001091">Mrs. Hinson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001239">Mr. McGuire</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001240">Mr. McDowell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001235">Mr. Moore of West Virginia</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="V000133">Mr. Van Drew</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Public Health Service Act to provide more opportunities for mothers to succeed, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H02E100B431B247F08D7B00D3D12FE707" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HFC477A64D3144159A9E0EAF5115077DC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6EB38777F21E4EE8A7919BF9E6F10210"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>More Opportunities for Moms to Succeed Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>MOMS Act</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0C30D1E060E44F8CB70DAAE2567A58BF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text> 
<toc> 
<toc-entry level="section" idref="HFC477A64D3144159A9E0EAF5115077DC">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="title" idref="H201ABC523E7A4B27AD18E7BFB084CD9A">TITLE I—Federal clearinghouse of resources for expecting moms</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section" idref="H72BA732C639340C68501A898C7065B91">Sec. 101. Pregnancy.gov.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section" idref="H8F4CC614C0FE40CBA7D642C6DA53CD1A">Sec. 102. National list of licensed child placement agencies.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section" idref="H769AF884C2A6475F856538EC872E25C3">Sec. 103. List of funding opportunities available to pregnancy support centers.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="title" idref="HBA2EE060C6F4426380BB785BC1BA21DC">TITLE II—Improving access to prenatal and postnatal resources</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section" idref="HEBECC44896744D70A9FB9DABD7598AC5">Sec. 201. Positive alternatives for women.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section" idref="HEF53EAB734D54E679073A89C0F8D2CC1">Sec. 202. Improving access to prenatal and postnatal telehealth care.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="title" idref="H869DB092DB494EDA8C27636B17DCAFD2">TITLE III—Unborn child support</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section" idref="H295D965213D4471CB1641D4407A8B74D">Sec. 301. Child support enforcement on behalf of unborn children.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section> 
<title id="H201ABC523E7A4B27AD18E7BFB084CD9A" style="OLC"><enum>I</enum><header>Federal clearinghouse of resources for expecting moms</header> 
<section id="H72BA732C639340C68501A898C7065B91"><enum>101.</enum><header>Pregnancy.gov</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/201">42 U.S.C. 201 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H4A19E20EAAFF494188AA8AED00279B90" display-inline="no-display-inline" style="OLC"> <title id="HD7B19AB5EC8F4591BEF670FCC6DFBBFC"><enum>XXXIV</enum><header>Resource directory for moms</header> <section id="H30A11D93241A4C85859283CAA7AED0FA"><enum>3401.</enum><header>Establishment of pregnancy.gov website</header> <subsection id="H2CEC58866A674A8EA522672A9CFF3A38"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Website</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary shall publish a public website entitled <quote>pregnancy.gov</quote>. The Secretary may not delegate implementation or administration of the website below the level of the Office of the Secretary. The website shall include the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H40D30110F0DF4249A3BAD186C32EAB53"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A clearinghouse of relevant resources available for pregnant and postpartum women, and women parenting young children.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H08D7E2923EA247ADA3A60C7833E224DA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A series of questions through which a user is able to generate a list of relevant resources of interest within the user’s ZIP Code.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7F53B72193554B10BDE1963438C9718D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A means to direct the user to identify whether to list the relevant resources of interest that are available online or within 1, 5, 10, 50, and 100 miles of the user.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H860955FC2F7540BBA94731063EC15ECE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A mechanism for users to take an assessment through the website and provide consent to use the user’s contact information, which the Secretary may use to conduct outreach via phone or email to follow up with users on additional resources that would be helpful for the users to review.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3580DD81650F4550929B4F7749335254"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Resource list aggregation</header> 
<paragraph id="H7EB170AC23794BF09A36BD1E61B29C44"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall invite each State to provide recommendations of relevant resources referred to in subsection (a)(3) for such State.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB0F1604166824D599D7C29FC8E27C7BB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Criteria for making recommendations</header><text>The Secretary shall develop criteria to provide to the States to determine whether resources recommended as described in paragraph (1) should appear on the website. Such criteria shall include the requirement that the relevant resource is not a prohibited entity.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7620D13442E84C42A3B85B0E25FB51DC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Grant program</header> 
<subparagraph id="HBBF99042418E4E6CA66031221BE82F62"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall provide grants to States to establish or support a system that—</text> <clause id="H14B7EF78AA5E470682D8DA70D8674AFC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>aggregates relevant resources referred to in subsection (a)(3), in accordance with the criteria developed under paragraph (2); and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HC57D880E0AE9455AB60288407A250862">
                      <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>may be coordinated, to the extent determined appropriate by the State, by a statewide, regionally-based, or community-based public or private entity.</text>
                    </clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8C5A2AAA997D4C69AAC0397CD7F5A493"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Applications</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under subparagraph (A), a State shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require, including a plan for outreach and awareness activities, and a list of relevant resources that would be included in the State system supported by the grant.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC9A9031AD563485493E5A624CA82D12E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Prohibition regarding certain entities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Relevant resources listed on the website, and any additional resources promoted by the Secretary, may not include any resource offered by a prohibited entity. No prohibited entity may receive a grant provided under subsection (b)(3).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD7A7230C349F4172BDF69F18D8C134B7"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Services in different languages</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that the website provides the widest possible access to services for families who speak languages other than English.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HA768F700F545415AA02475A97605BFAA"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header> <paragraph id="HA5F24BB79072499784C7DE74D7FBE8FE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date on which the website is established under this section, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE3B7FBA724524DF68460B8A3E26307AF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the traffic of the website;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9F7F465E92B54D5ABAF13943A5695DB2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>user feedback on the accessibility and helpfulness of the website in tailoring to the user’s needs;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H60E64AFAD0E54D28B5C52D49D483949B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>insights on gaps in relevant resources with respect to services for pregnant and postpartum women, or women parenting young children;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCB23B44DF2DB4D57915553E1F24FEE82"><enum>(D)</enum><text>suggestions on how to improve user experience and accessibility based on user feedback and missing resources that would be helpful to include in future updates; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF7D31114555C436B88172919A525C067"><enum>(E)</enum><text>certification that no prohibited entities are listed as a relevant resource or are in receipt of a grant under subsection (b)(3).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H93CD94D746684E2DA43115C27DB4755D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Confidentiality</header><text>The report under paragraph (1) shall not include any personal identifying information regarding individuals who have used the website.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H39A914FFBD374243A95405F1E8D24C80"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>To carry out this section, there are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary for each of fiscal years 2025 through 2030.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H9F6F52D77C634BD7A49258A9E4A16EA3"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H95112541308E4290953634879E5AA261" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Abortion</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>abortion</term> means the use or prescription of any instrument, medicine, drug, or any other substance or device to intentionally—</text> <subparagraph id="HA5DF2B38C20141D8988372D7BDC5017A" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>kill the unborn child of a woman known to be pregnant; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9AE8DA6B8C03401A95A0E394F50969AA" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>terminate the pregnancy of a woman known to be pregnant, with an intention other than—</text> <clause id="HBC0DC01175CA4C5F9030F0E994A5A995" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>after viability, to produce a live birth and preserve the life and health of the child born alive;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HC1A1AC28B0244621A390EE26719601D8" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to remove a dead unborn child; or</text></clause> <clause id="H045349CD2C22458CB4FA96A2AC15C2D3" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to treat an ectopic pregnancy.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H05681C0EA9B54AFDA49793D122F0AC0F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Born alive</header><text>The term <term>born alive</term> has the meaning given such term in section 8(b) of title 1, United States Code.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H95B1AC64AB934FFB90D0F64F9239BB7F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Prohibited entity</header><text>The term <term>prohibited entity</term> means an entity, including its affiliates, subsidiaries, successors, and clinics, that performs, induces, refers for, or counsels in favor of abortions, or provides financial support to any other organization that conducts such activities.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBE0077B02D5F4005A5BF86111CE48984"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Relevant resources</header><text>The term <term>relevant resources</term> means the Federal, State, local governmental, and private resources that serve pregnant and postpartum women, or women parenting young children in the categories of the following topics:</text> <subparagraph id="HFC8C99F4FCF44186AB0A25D5F6C8FC23"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Mentorship opportunities, including pregnancy and parenting help and case management resources.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H58943EBBE57D4298A2E2797A3478900D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Health and well-being services, including women’s medical services such as obstetrical and gynecological support services for women, abortion pill reversal, breastfeeding, general health services, primary care, and dental care.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAB93B990F09044BB8DA7B1BE587B75A7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Financial assistance, work opportunities, nutrition assistance, childcare, and education opportunities for parents.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5B936C2ABD594C72AADE3BBFA679074D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Material or legal support, including transportation, food, nutrition, clothing, household goods, baby supplies, housing, shelters, maternity homes, tax preparation, legal support for child support, family leave, breastfeeding protections, and custody issues.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3A66ABB071BF451B9CE998610827A2B0"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Recovery and mental health services, including services with respect to addiction or suicide intervention, intimate partner violence, sexual assault, rape, sex trafficking, and counseling for women and families surrounding unexpected loss of a child.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7BCA51E5AF3340AE93BB1D44A653D636"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Prenatal diagnostic services, including disability support organizations, medical interventions for a baby, perinatal hospice resources, pregnancy and infant loss support, and literature on pregnancy wellness.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1DB5BD6C1CDD48BA82FD39BD583B2836"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Healing and support services for abortion survivors and their families.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H25DCE7D4669740A097A2CB951EFFC2B3"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Services providing childcare, adoption, foster care, and short term childcare services and resources.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4D778CA386A64062BBF821BD316B68EF"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Comprehensive information on alternatives to abortion.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA47846B4FC234CF98B11EC4798B04EF0"><enum>(J)</enum><text>Information about abortion risks, including complications and failures.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF026B3116EBB4CA7B4E12ADB2F7439FF"><enum>(K)</enum><text>Links to information on child development from moment of conception.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDBD7EE9BFEBF43FEA80EEC1972CB2A71" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Unborn child</header><text>The term <term>unborn child</term> has the meaning given such term in section 1841(d) of title 18, United States Code.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H262BF6CD27A3410D889E4C33A96E7937"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Website</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>website</term> means the public website entitled <quote>pregnancy.gov</quote> required to be established under subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection></section></title><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
<section id="H8F4CC614C0FE40CBA7D642C6DA53CD1A"><enum>102.</enum><header>National list of licensed child placement agencies</header> 
<subsection id="HF9D68E72A4A64ABEA2B5B052474CE17D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 474 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/674">42 U.S.C. 674</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC54387168F2A4384970CDDEE1F0F973E"> <subsection id="H28F7EBE791F34650982EE33E0EE04A29"><enum>(h)</enum><header>National list of licensed child placement agencies</header> <paragraph id="H4BF53FF27C6A4525830ED207053CCCA9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>State reporting</header> <subparagraph id="H5E550B6A758B4CAA903F12945ADB5BAE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than January 1 of each fiscal year, a State with a plan approved under this part for the fiscal year shall submit to the Secretary a list of private child placement agencies that, as of the end of the preceding fiscal year, were licensed or accredited by, and in good standing with, the State and exempt from Federal income tax by reason of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA96A2423C0204AE7BDEDFBF601C7FA9C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Child placement agency</header><text>In subparagraph (A), the term <term>child placement agency</term> means an agency that places children in prospective adoptive homes.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD9852B2E4FB34E80A683B269B5371393"><enum>(2)</enum><header>National list</header><text>The Secretary, through the United States Children’s Bureau, shall compile and maintain on the public website entitled <quote>pregnancy.gov</quote> required to be established under title XXXIV of the Public Health Service Act, a publicly available list consisting of each list most recently submitted by a State under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD948B0FFD3FD47F8821B21C86D817648"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Annual reports to congress</header><text>Not later than the 2nd December 31 after the date of the enactment of this subsection, and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the Congress a written report that contains the list maintained under paragraph (2) and identifies any child placement agency that is licensed by a State and is not on the list, and a specification of any disciplinary actions that a State has taken against a private child placement agency.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HB188630F33CA49BF80020638CF9C3782"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Loss of eligibility for adoption and legal guardianship incentive payments for failure of state To comply with list submission requirement</header><text>Section 473A(b) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/673b">42 U.S.C. 673b(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H815BB49BBDB349408F35D1C32F39F095"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of paragraph (3);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE1F3D3F2097048288B4833A9A0828222"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end of paragraph (4) and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8393395789C140D785E95B5403CADA9E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCA9F0B4C1D6F4DCD94B0BA0CA8866989"> <paragraph id="H9D080BBDC5F14FF399CF9BD82B075114"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the State has complied with section 474(h)(1) with respect to the preceding fiscal year.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H769AF884C2A6475F856538EC872E25C3"><enum>103.</enum><header>List of funding opportunities available to pregnancy support centers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title XXXIV of the Public Health Service Act (as added by section 101) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD58DC4838AB84661A57AEB240B50597A"> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="HDF07C7C6E9F9429FADBFC033BE9F9107"><enum>3402.</enum><header>List of funding opportunities available to pregnancy support centers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary shall compile and maintain on the public website entitled <quote>pregnancy.gov</quote> required to be established under section 3401, a publicly available list of Federal funding opportunities available to nonprofit and health care entities for pregnancy support services that offer or provide the relevant resources (as defined in subsection (g) of such section).</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></title> 
<title id="HBA2EE060C6F4426380BB785BC1BA21DC" style="OLC"><enum>II</enum><header>Improving access to prenatal and postnatal resources</header> 
<section id="HEBECC44896744D70A9FB9DABD7598AC5"><enum>201.</enum><header>Positive alternatives for women</header> 
<subsection id="H4AE3760A65D5478CA3E159D18992180E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Program authority</header> 
<paragraph id="H0EC53B97C2904DA1ABAC32DF4C30C68B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The purpose of grants under this section shall be to support, encourage, and assist women—</text> <subparagraph id="H577C7AFA8A9E40229025B9FBEE19F7DE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to carry their pregnancies to term; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H610BA40FB4104355A353BDB72A7228AB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to care for themselves and their babies after birth.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4B6C876D3CF6465F8D9F867BA4F50876"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Grants</header><text>For the purpose described in paragraph (1), the Secretary shall award grants to eligible entities described in subsection (b) to provide information on, referral to, and direct services as described in subsection (c).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9E47B89E5BAC4293907AC97BEF80C884"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility</header> 
<paragraph id="H213E33B2903C4CFCB03E5DA476C10B1E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible entities</header><text>To be eligible for a grant under this section, an entity shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HB54225C96B5247F78C329716AE0C6A91"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be a nonprofit organization;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC376E40869894166A6B80092BE32FE01"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">support, encourage, and assist women as described in subsection (a)(1);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDBA0A43704294C658F00A0D850CF3545"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">agree to be subject to such monitoring and review as the Secretary may require under subsection (g);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD595ABCB4E1D4491930DCE03B041954F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>agree to not charge women for services provided through the grant;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB0D3C4E508874C169E93A47AA5627F70"><enum>(E)</enum><text>provide each pregnant woman counseled through the grant with accurate information on the developmental characteristics of babies and of unborn children, including offering printed information; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB41CFE6419A94339AF309B268276949D"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have a privacy policy and procedures in place to ensure that—</text> <clause id="H1659E82490BB49FD828BC9820E13BD4C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the name, address, telephone number, or any other information that might identify any woman seeking services supported through the grant is not made public or shared with any other entity without the written consent of the woman; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HD67356E070604F01B7BFAB33D8FCC6FA" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the grantee adheres to requirements comparable to those applicable under the HIPAA privacy regulation (as defined in section 1180(b)(3) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1320d-9">42 U.S.C. 1320d–9(b)(3)</external-xref>)) to covered entities (as defined for purposes of such regulation).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H77AEFD5857794185949AE8EA4716255A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Ineligible entities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An entity shall be ineligible to receive a grant under this section if the entity or any affiliate, subsidiary, successor, or clinic thereof—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H6BCCEE984B034396BEDC7B84C943EC86"><enum>(A)</enum><text>performs, induces, refers for, or counsels in favor of abortions; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA1D28736F4424023BE043DD1E96078B1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provides financial support to any other entity that conducts any activity described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H26C333C0926C45E4A4E9BFE7886E3014"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Financial records</header><text>As a condition on receipt of a grant under this section, an eligible entity shall agree to maintain and make available to the Secretary records, including financial records, that demonstrate that the entity satisfies the requirements of paragraph (1) and is not ineligible by operation of paragraph (2).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HACD5A87621D645F5B5310B3B56B47B45"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Covered services</header> <paragraph id="H56FAE6198DE341C596B7FB8A4092202A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Required information and referral</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purpose described in subsection (a)(1), an eligible entity receiving a grant under this section shall use the grant to provide to pregnant and postpartum women, or women parenting young children, information on, and referral to, each of the following services:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD1D4284AA7AF4239ADCE837FD0807C22"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Medical care.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5ADF32970029472699440B0586387B67"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Nutritional services.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF81B7E51A8E142A798DA6F8D5E2A2D01"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Housing assistance.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB4C81F6CF043426AA1157AB5558CA811"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Adoption services.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCB93BC24B16A46C2AE852A08F36D61B9"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Education and employment assistance, including services that support the continuation and completion of high school.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H165FEEB654F34D1386D3A915301830BF"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Child care assistance.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2CE5610526ED4A1B90BC369EB8F8EF5E"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Parenting education and support services.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H148E716803B545869029847449158BF3"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Voluntary substance abuse counseling and treatment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8B433C11E8D84573878C4A68E7AB7F2E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Permissible direct provision of services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purpose described in subsection (a)(1), in addition to using a grant under this section as described in paragraph (1), an eligible entity receiving a grant under this section may use the grant for the direct provision of one or more services listed in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H178ED16D4191423BB97A63C35EE07566"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Prohibited uses of funds</header><text>None of the funds made available under this section shall be used—</text> 
<paragraph id="H8CD0BA385BF34499B58BC6BE26F3D925"><enum>(1)</enum><text>for health benefits coverage that includes coverage of abortion;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H28EED3D406FD4A778145F1DD77798C56"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for providing or assisting a woman to obtain adoption services from a provider of adoption services that is not licensed; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7B2083212DD94CCAAE579EA39B6C3C76"><enum>(3)</enum><text>for any of the activities described in subsection (b)(2).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HBCADD0BA0CCB4FBEA133D4B60CCE0E7A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Consideration</header><text>In selecting the recipients of grants under this section, the Secretary shall consider each applicant’s demonstrated capacity in providing services to assist a pregnant woman in carrying her pregnancy to term.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7E8D1B4E72D7407D8E8C0670284136A4"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Monitoring and review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall—</text> <paragraph id="H7072C7FE09404354B6DBB64A68D2157F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>monitor and review each program funded through a grant under this section to ensure that the grantee carefully adheres to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE41FED08D1224E59BF520AD66E36471E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the purpose described in subsection (a)(1); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE913C22D869645E9AACDAD0DA588F727"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the requirements of this section; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H81726754440F498EB482AF468B081F54"><enum>(2)</enum><text>cease to fund a program under this section if the grantee fails to adhere to such purpose and requirements.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HFD1704D8685D4DC2A1CD9F0795004428"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="HCCC1EEAB81774D33930D31D23C46351A" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Abortion</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>abortion</term> means the use or prescription of any instrument, medicine, drug, or any other substance or device to intentionally—</text> <subparagraph id="H79EE10C11E344A14ADE4D34D155E75D7" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>kill the unborn child of a woman known to be pregnant; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H03B10CFA7A164625805E3E5146F8F35A" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>terminate the pregnancy of a woman known to be pregnant, with an intention other than—</text> <clause id="HF90EA257172F45948FBE8D8450C4FB76" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>after viability, to produce a live birth and preserve the life and health of the child born alive;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HE68893122E514611890E55B903F44ED7" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to remove a dead unborn child; or</text></clause> <clause id="H40D201F65BB645A2BB2A594CF6DDF1C5" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to treat an ectopic pregnancy.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H91E4F9341655428B9837A4C0433A2B09"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD336DDE50A394B9EA4B62F1F98A59B4A" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To carry out this section, there are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary for each of fiscal years 2025 through 2030.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HEF53EAB734D54E679073A89C0F8D2CC1"><enum>202.</enum><header>Improving access to prenatal and postnatal telehealth care</header> 
<subsection id="HC38F8AC0E0F341EC9FAF114FC975C625"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall award grants to, or enter into cooperative agreements with, eligible entities to purchase equipment necessary for carrying out at-home telehealth visits for screening, monitoring, and management of prenatal and postnatal care for the purpose of improving maternal and infant health outcomes, and reducing maternal mortality, by improving access to care in rural areas, frontier counties, medically underserved areas, or jurisdictions of Indian Tribes and Tribal organizations.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H931AD13552054F718624DC4D9DE550F0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Ineligible entities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An entity shall be ineligible to receive a grant or enter into a cooperative agreement under this section if the entity or any affiliate, subsidiary, successor, or clinic thereof—</text> 
<paragraph id="H24D57364CEF246169247419CC50B3EA1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>performs, induces, refers for, or counsels in favor of abortions; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3C157D174E574C3EB40A2FA998C89293" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provides financial support to any other entity that conducts any activity described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7169BEE4EBF14E7594D3F73343CA7F1A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A recipient of a grant or cooperative agreement under this section shall use the award funds as described in subsection (a), which may include purchasing or providing equipment necessary for carrying out at-home telehealth visits (such as remote physiologic devices and related services, including pulse oximeters, blood pressure cuffs, scales, and blood glucose monitors) to screen, monitor, and manage prenatal and postnatal care at home by means of telehealth visits and services for the purpose described in subsection (a).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H416C2E998D724CBF8744FD2E27E3B865"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text>Not later than September 30, 2029, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on activities supported through grants and cooperative agreements under this section, including—</text> 
<paragraph id="H51AA5AC5AB4448C68DC589BDCA4FFAF0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a description of the activities conducted pursuant to such grants and cooperative agreements; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA862979C507C4329A018A8643A50188B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an analysis of the effects of such grants and cooperative agreements on improving prenatal and postnatal care in areas and jurisdictions described in subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H46CA1FCCBD6740FDB3CE5FDBD02C31A7"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H7AF434C90DB6424B91080A6E77FCFAA7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means an entity that provides prenatal care, labor care, birthing, or postpartum care services in a rural area, a frontier county, a medically underserved area, or the jurisdiction of an Indian Tribe or Tribal organization.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB6FBA83363D041269B0B5FA4A0492A4B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Frontier county</header><text>The term <term>frontier county</term> has the meaning given such term in section 1886(d)(3)(E)(iii)(III) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395ww">42 U.S.C. 1395ww(d)(3)(E)(iii)(III)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2059B20FE3854F43BDF1BFF19CBCF86D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Indian tribe; tribal organization</header><text>The terms <term>Indian Tribe</term> and <term>Tribal organization</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5379A4CAA16543FFAB6028935E953731"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Medically underserved area</header><text>The term <term>medically underserved area</term> means a health professional shortage area designated under section 332 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/254e">42 U.S.C. 254e</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF1526609F3FD4E79980BC8F4DD1E9A75"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Rural area</header><text>The term <term>rural area</term> has the meaning given such term in section 330J(e) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/254c-15">42 U.S.C. 254c–15(e)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9BD389E0EE26446DBB0D8EB4517134BF"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H99B6E635A4994DA79A36945C93C76C54" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>To carry out this section, there are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary for each of fiscal years 2025 through 2030.</text></subsection></section></title> 
<title id="H869DB092DB494EDA8C27636B17DCAFD2" style="OLC"><enum>III</enum><header>Unborn child support</header> 
<section id="H295D965213D4471CB1641D4407A8B74D"><enum>301.</enum><header>Child support enforcement on behalf of unborn children</header> 
<subsection id="H358C1DEFF598488F9D1B4E1EF7126B9F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>State plan amendment</header><text>Section 454 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/654">42 U.S.C. 654</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H80F018EF78394B638299248D81A2C751"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)(A)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H5F4556F24B5B470DAE661F169036E199"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in clause (i)—</text> <clause id="HD3783060DBED4B99B637CB940D62F5DA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, including an unborn child,</quote> after <quote>child</quote>; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H7DD07802B75041D6BF4693B9CF4C497C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDABE751814254F8CA3FA8CBC85A3279E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in clause (ii), by inserting <quote>, including an unborn child</quote> after <quote>other child</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6E58773F0F034DA2937294E12E17EAEC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (33), by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB8FBD8658BAF4E6191451823A724111D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (34), by striking the period and inserting <quote>; and</quote>;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H927F974C1F6E482CB3DAAC3D7FAFA23F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (34), the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2ED9563EA4E1411692738A9BE9847DE1"> <paragraph id="HBD2795D62F0C41588A0DD5D85B596D16"><enum>(35)</enum><text>provide that the State will establish and enforce child support obligations of the biological father of an unborn child (and subsequent to the birth of the child) to the mother of such child provided that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD0BDE9062019472FB829373C69C31EFC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the mother has requested payment of such child support obligations;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5E569AA91CFB411F94CDC194E3B09252"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the start date for such obligations may begin with the first month in which the child was conceived, as determined by a physician (and shall begin with that month if the mother so requests);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDFE09B2585F744A7A1CA2225D9CFC8BA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>payments for such obligations may be retroactively collected or awarded, including in the case where paternity is established subsequent to the birth of the child;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H141582841256471F8ECC848B641AA076"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the payment amount for such obligations shall be determined by a court, in consultation with the mother, taking into account the best interests of the mother and child;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2B1A831426474798B480B9335452FDAC"><enum>(E)</enum><text>any measure to establish the paternity of a child (born or unborn) shall not be required without the consent of the mother; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H31025799A17C4C9794F502B50B5C161A"><enum>(F)</enum><text>any measure to establish the paternity of an unborn child shall not be taken if the measure poses any risk of harm to the child if unborn.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H08CAD83A021F447891E735CB74059005"><enum>(5)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following: <quote>For purposes of paragraphs (4) and (35), the term <term>unborn child</term> means a member of the species homo sapiens, at any stage of development, who is carried in the womb.</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H7C48A038155C4B9B85018591B0FAAE4F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitation of waiver authority</header><text>Section 1115 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1315">42 U.S.C. 1315</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HE9E49A69945F4ADFAB9E542AF13E8DDD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a), in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by striking <quote>In the case of</quote> and inserting <quote>Except as provided in subsection (c), in the case of</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF09DF64547BE4F9A983BFE847290C0A9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(1), in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>In the case of</quote> and inserting <quote>Except as provided in subsection (c), in the case of</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2363AAB6F6974AF7B842DDDA1DACD7CB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking subsection (c) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0960057ED9EB489BA4A75E4BF187C357"> <subsection id="H3E5D36A311E2477CB7D2F0C690A2B980"><enum>(c)</enum><text>No experimental, pilot, or demonstration project undertaken under subsection (a) to assist in promoting the objectives of part D of title IV, may permit modifications of paragraphs (4)(A)(ii) and (35) of section 454 to establish and enforce child support obligations of the biological father of an unborn child. For purposes of the preceding sentence, the term <term>unborn child</term> means a member of the species homo sapiens, at any stage of development, who is carried in the womb.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9D2C8E5F189C45E690317C3D350C44C9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall take effect on the date that is 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act and shall apply to payments under part D of title IV of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/651">42 U.S.C. 651 et seq.</external-xref>) for calendar quarters beginning on or after such date.</text></subsection></section></title> </legis-body></bill>

