<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-REI25126-731-J5-JC7"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 348 IS: Declaring August 14, 2025, as “National Save Social Security Day”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code>III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 348</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250730">July 30, 2025</action-date>
      <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S373">Mr. Cassidy</sponsor> submitted the following resolution;
        which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the
          Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Declaring August 14, 2025, as <quote>National Save Social
 Security Day</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, on August 14, 1935, President Franklin D. Roosevelt signed the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/301">42 U.S.C. 301 et seq.</external-xref>) into law, establishing a foundational commitment by the United States to provide economic security for its senior citizens;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas August 14, 2025, marks the 90th anniversary of the Social Security program, a program that has served as the cornerstone of retirement security for generations of individuals in the United States, providing vital retirement, disability, and survivor benefits to millions;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Social Security program has paid scheduled benefits throughout its 90-year history, delivering on the promise earned by workers in the United States and their families through a lifetime of contributions;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Social Security program remains the primary source of income for millions of seniors, individuals with disabilities, and surviving family members, and its continued strength is vital to the economic well-being of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Social Security program faces significant long-term financial challenges that require thoughtful and responsible action to ensure its continued stability and effectiveness;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas preserving and strengthening the Social Security program is a bipartisan responsibility that requires cooperation and leadership from policymakers; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas increased public awareness, education, and dialogue are essential to ensure that the Social Security program remains strong and solvent for current and future generations: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="idf1d34b8241b34161819fc18565f3dcb8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>designates August 14, 2025, as <quote>National Save Social Security Day</quote> in recognition of the 90th anniversary of the Social Security program and its enduring importance to the economic well-being of the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id997a8336ad7f4579adbb4ef597d420b0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>encourages all people of the United States to reflect on the value of the Social Security program, to learn about its history and future challenges, and to participate in civic activities that promote the protection and strengthening of the program;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id53255b2737004f05ac4f7a6c8a16697d"><enum>(3)</enum><text>urges Federal, State, and local governments, educational institutions, advocacy groups, and the private sector to engage in outreach, educational initiatives, and community events on this day, fostering dialogue about the future of the Social Security program and the need for timely, bipartisan solutions; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id074947acc5424526b5b7cb9845da5875"><enum>(4)</enum><text>calls upon Members of Congress to work in a bipartisan manner to develop and enact legislation that ensures the long-term solvency of the Social Security program and protects seniors, individuals with disabilities, and families in the United States for generations to come.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution>

