<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF5E00E8104A849A58C6F9A503B7D0B6C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1961 IH: Coordinated Agency Response Enhancement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1961</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250306">March 6, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000486">Mr. Torres of New York</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Public Health Service Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish and implement a department-wide after-action program and a risk communication strategy, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HFD7370FBAAB14C318CA89A19574D15E1" style="OLC"><section id="H15064CF173A349F4904FC85A6E66D943" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Coordinated Agency Response Enhancement Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>CARE Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H8F49FACF3891465B8C6EC5BF018F65AE"><enum>2.</enum><header>HHS after-action program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part P of title III of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/280g">42 U.S.C. 280g et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HFFD8A2AC054F429B89B16525408B5CDF"><section id="H03E15C4D10684D61852D830331662739"><enum>399V–8.</enum><header>Department-wide after-action program</header><subsection id="H8142C08FC4834F02BA05AD23851394BB" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish, maintain, and implement an after-action program to—</text><paragraph id="H0EC51D534D0143D9AF87D7D4FA6A010E" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identify and implement solutions for issues found following any response by the Department of Health and Human Services to a determination of a public health emergency under section 319(a); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF4D2B8E368934A66B818EEE6581F1690" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>encourage collaboration among the agencies of the Department, including by integrating any public health emergency after-action programs of such agencies.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5B19D10E90DB456FB68C1D967D88ECEA" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Deadline</header><text>The Secretary shall establish and begin implementation of the after-action program under subsection (a) not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H9CBA42406D9D4C158946B8F8A8FB12B2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Coordination with stakeholders</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The after-action program under subsection (a) shall include input from, and coordinate with, relevant external stakeholders involved in each public health emergency response of the Department of Health and Human Services, such as—</text><paragraph id="HD0DDA55F74854E6B9B53EBAC1A405DA4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>other Federal agencies;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H84AC4117FA3143658EDF26F603E78F16"><enum>(2)</enum><text>other jurisdictions, including the health departments of States, Indian Tribes, and territories of the United States and municipalities thereof; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC1EE1EB6B764408DA10177DC03281592"><enum>(3)</enum><text>nongovernmental partners.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H49876C9A9E1F495CADABB1D9532025BB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Oversight by Inspector General</header><text>The Inspector General of the Department of Health and Human Services shall, whenever the Inspector General determines appropriate, based on assessed risks and emerging needs—</text><paragraph id="H1537A8E4345345C6B1911699FA7130D6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>evaluate the efficacy of the after-action program under subsection (a), including by evaluating the ability of the program to identify challenges and propose solutions; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5DD16E84F97E4B7AAD348D1E30FCA2B7"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submit to Congress a report summarizing the evaluation under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H188EB3FD84114F7688B280494218FA87"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Comprehensive guidelines for after-Action program reports</header><paragraph id="H0DB8C11001224633A7E404359AEE5575"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall, as the Secretary determines appropriate, incorporate in any report of the after-action program under subsection (a) the elements described in subparagraphs (A) through (M) of paragraph (2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H978796732FB44E0A953EEAB7C14CB9F2" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements described</header><subparagraph id="H86B40DB66F314AEB998E4C304BEFD7A9" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Emergency operations plan, continuity of operations plan, and business continuity plan reviews</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of the process and outcomes of reviewing and updating emergency operations plans, continuity of operations plans, and business continuity plans both annually and after significant public health emergencies. Such description may include insights into the relevancy and efficiency of such plans in practice.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H68BEEA81378146C2ABFBF97330D3D36A" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Information sharing, situational awareness</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of the establishment and effectiveness of protocols for efficient information sharing (consistent with applicable disclosure laws) and situational awareness among health care facilities and partners, including the development and deployment of an integrated joint information system.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H31FA17FCE78843E39CC2FD22BEA4318D" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Coordination with national, State, and local coalitions and community partners</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Descriptions of—</text><clause id="H7AEB01205C1A4C44BC46ECAC05B68450" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>strategies for coordination with national, State, and local health care patient and public health coalitions and community partners, focusing on active engagement and information sharing (consistent with applicable disclosure laws);</text></clause><clause id="H46FE452103394A7B9A41C44930603E71" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>information technology solutions used for coordination during public health emergencies; and</text></clause><clause id="HFB3DB023492149F9A48C27DBDE096BD3" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>how medical operations coordination cells were implemented for effective patient load balancing during surges to assure regional health care coordination.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFA8D8FC2EFDA4CE0A0828A1B54246399" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Incident management</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of incident management structures, including the maintenance of the incident command system and the establishment of an incident action planning process.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H472261C6CDB54695858DC4F268951DE0" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Communications, information sharing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of strategies for the development and maintenance of a dynamic communications framework for real-time information sharing (consistent with applicable disclosure laws) and situational awareness.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H597469F416204A409E3F620DCB2BBE51" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Staff, space, and resident management</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of strategies for comprehensive staff management plans, scalable space management strategies, and policies adopted to maintain patient and resident well-being.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9DBAD5FBEEE74141B535213AA8DC6D9E" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Logistics and supply chain management</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of strategies for developing comprehensive logistics and supply chain management strategies to ensure a steady and sufficient supply of personal protective equipment, medical equipment, pharmaceuticals, and other items.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0AB24DE22B21495CB68E038B09A7B839" commented="no"><enum>(H)</enum><header>Resource management</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of strategies for implementing crisis standards of care protocols to optimize the allocation and use of medical and non-medical assets during emergencies, including guidelines for the conservation, reuse, or repurposing of supplies.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEE2F24B1652B42C6894647131114F888" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Infection prevention</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of strategies for enhancing infection prevention measures, including staff training, environmental cleaning, and patient screening, to mitigate the spread of infectious diseases within health care facilities.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6EE06560CED64B5781E5C3D510DB6BB0" commented="no"><enum>(J)</enum><header>Treatment, transport, and discharge protocols</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of how treatment, transport, and discharge protocols were standardized to ensure consistency and efficiency in patient care and movement, including the incorporation of telehealth and remote monitoring solutions where feasible, explaining the technologies used and the outcomes of the interventions.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8A4AC8BABC7349D19A201D01AB7E092D" commented="no"><enum>(K)</enum><header>Case management protocols</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Descriptions of—</text><clause id="HA6D646720BBA433B9530D8672AB55D87" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>how case management protocols were refined to address both clinical and non-clinical needs of patients and residents; and</text></clause><clause id="H7845A0B5266F4CCC957CCB3CA19A36FB" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the measures taken to ensure coordinated care and support throughout the treatment and recovery phases, detailing the challenges faced and the strategies employed to overcome such challenges.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6FC1C1D571144A2E81272AE647ECAF5C" commented="no"><enum>(L)</enum><header>Medical countermeasures</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Descriptions of—</text><clause id="HE2D68335B59E4EC1B1E7C3882E6C3CAA" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the strategy employed to accelerate the development, distribution, and administration of medical countermeasures, such as vaccines, therapeutics, diagnostic tests, and treatments; and</text></clause><clause id="H0FEFA11EFE3D433086779A6A4F0522A6" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the challenges encountered in making such medical countermeasures available for use during the public health emergency and how such challenges were addressed.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4DBADEE5CE5C4F40A58EC80EFF2C94E7" commented="no"><enum>(M)</enum><header>Recovery</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of any implemented recovery strategies focusing on administrative, financial, policy, and equity considerations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8F447F1EC3654CDFA2F20C254480F724"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated, to remain available until expended—</text><paragraph id="H98E0B490EE8C4C4EBBE2B6863AC0AAD9"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$3,500,000 to carry out subsections (a), (b), (c), and (e), including the first 4 reports of the after-action program; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD7277DB96D7B429D9C5088FD22D3738E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>such sums as may be necessary to carry out subsection (d).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H2F7D543D9BF84626A7AB8962D92CFBC7"><enum>3.</enum><header>Risk communication strategy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part P of title III of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/280g">42 U.S.C. 280g et seq.</external-xref>), as amended by section 2, is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H495EEAE358BB455EBC378CE744CE8D33" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="H5B30F2C58B804954A98208593702CA27"><enum>399V–9.</enum><header>Risk communication strategy</header><subsection id="HD7970E566D684E009B1C104FF52C0484"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish, maintain, and implement a comprehensive strategy to ensure that communications about infectious diseases and other public health risks by agencies and offices of the Department of Health and Human Services, including the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, are clear, accurate, and prioritize the populations most at risk.</text></subsection><subsection id="H64C92BC28E82445989EAA19C555F3851"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Components</header><text>The strategy under subsection (a) shall be designed to—</text><paragraph id="HE0C8E869A4164836A81A2B3382075C17"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">clearly identify at-risk populations during public health emergencies; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H392D858D778F4F65BDE3C2277E1C3FE0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>ensure that communications are targeted, understandable, and accessible.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9E86578E1F4B4716A404610D0A42A17F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Initial strategy</header><text>The Secretary shall establish and begin implementation of the initial strategy under subsection (a) not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

