<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4CCF76C36A7C4CA0B3A1DAF3F82054CC" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 302 IH: Water Rights Protection Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 302</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250109">January 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001228">Ms. Maloy</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="M001213">Mr. Moore of Utah</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000469">Mr. Fulcher</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001302">Mr. Biggs of Arizona</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="E000298">Mr. Estes</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the conditioning of any permit, lease, or other use agreement on the transfer of any water right to the United States by the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HFB2ADBA0A0AE42CD9CF2A84C6D32A726" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="H91BB154339B54436B56AE3087E4E8EE6"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Water Rights Protection Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H90533C18D13E4C0892A77AC9828ADE26"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H6481FBEABE64496DA3526CE1119F073C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means, as applicable—</text><subparagraph id="H2DA39E3CFC214A31A900A06EEFE65275"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary of Agriculture; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6F1C6A667A604A1ABA7A3C84B6FD36BB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary of the Interior.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H93A5500EA14045F5B93C29793F6C5775"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Water right</header><text>The term <term>water right</term> means any surface water, groundwater, or water storage use filed, permitted, certificated, confirmed, decreed, adjudicated, or otherwise recognized by a judicial proceeding or by the State, in which the user acquires possession of the water or puts the water to beneficial use, including water rights of federally recognized Indian Tribes. </text></paragraph></section><section id="H1E17B9B49920471BA372702933EEF93C"><enum>3.</enum><header>Policy development</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In developing any rule, policy, directive, management plan, or similar Federal action relating to the issuance, renewal, amendment, or extension of any permit, approval, license, lease, allotment, easement, right-of-way, or other land use or occupancy agreement, the Secretary—</text><paragraph id="H4BFDB67CEFC4414B91AEC5E5D3BC56DD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall—</text><subparagraph id="H6A5A5CB7E73844A4A336EC84F8C11843"><enum>(A)</enum><text>recognize the longstanding authority of the States relating to evaluating, protecting, allocating, regulating, permitting, and adjudicating water use; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA06481A42DAA4C12824AA5EA0134E4A5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>coordinate with the States to ensure that any rule, policy, directive, management plan, or similar Federal action is consistent with, and imposes no greater restriction or regulatory requirement, than applicable State water law; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFD333BB3AC744DCD8496A541305650E9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall not—</text><subparagraph id="HCFD28C11DD41408F9CA99527ADBD919A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>assert any connection between surface water and groundwater that is inconsistent with such a connection recognized by State water law; or </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFBA5B4B7D2CA4F449E6D09347C1A152E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>take any action that adversely affects—</text><clause id="H99E6176A91FC444288681CA5E61A7D06"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the authority of a State in—</text><subclause id="HE1EA1DB09DAF4E29B09871619A92FA4A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>permitting the beneficial use of water; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H9D50F74AD70E4E75A9E10AF67CE4BCFF"><enum>(II)</enum><text>adjudicating water rights;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H8DBDFBB7EF5245C78D8F981E7E74CD14"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any definition established by a State with respect to the term <term>beneficial use</term>, <term>priority of water rights</term>, or <term>terms of use</term>; or </text></clause><clause id="H25ADF410FA2841319F38E52B0AFAE7D3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any other right or obligation of a State established under State law.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="HEF1CB577B0BB44D0B160D88A927A4C1C"><enum>4.</enum><header>Treatment of water rights</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary shall not—</text><paragraph id="H5684A36A4C8C452799E379CD970493BC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>condition the issuance, renewal, amendment, or extension of any permit, approval, license, lease, allotment, easement, right-of-way, or other land use or occupancy agreement on the transfer of any water right (including joint and sole ownership) directly or indirectly to the United States, or on any impairment of title or interest, in whole or in part, granted or otherwise recognized under State law, by Federal or State adjudication, decree, or other judgment, or pursuant to any interstate water compact; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H43E50D1551BF45C1BDD0D7291707D910"><enum>(2)</enum><text>require any water user (including any federally recognized Indian Tribe) to apply for or acquire a water right in the name of the United States under State law as a condition of the issuance, renewal, amendment, or extension of any permit, approval, license, lease, allotment, easement, right-of-way, or other land use or occupancy agreement; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H533CCBA16A234B9EA9C8DD559BF24170"><enum>(3)</enum><text>condition or withhold the issuance, renewal, amendment, or extension of any permit, approval, license, lease, allotment, easement, right-of-way, or other land use or occupancy agreement, in whole or in part, on—</text><subparagraph id="H9A0D0E9ACC04425B95FB6B77A53E8A61"><enum>(A)</enum><text>limiting the date, time, quantity, location of diversion or pumping, or place of use of a State water right beyond any applicable limitations under State water law; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H59602C8A39D047B1BD0004AB24DF2C2B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the modification of the terms and conditions of groundwater withdrawal, guidance and reporting procedures, or conservation and source protection measures established by a State. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H298D993679904F158F79505A6AEF1AF5"><enum>5.</enum><header>Effect</header><subsection id="HAB6A990B6FBC4C64AC2D621329DA820F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reclamation contracts</header><text>Nothing in this Act in any way interferes with any existing or future Bureau of Reclamation contract entered into pursuant to Federal reclamation law (the Act of June 17, 1902 (32 Stat. 388, chapter 1093), and Acts supplemental to and amendatory of that Act).</text></subsection><subsection id="H8AC057CFEDCC4B7A8E4D7090BC5DDC9A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Endangered species act</header><text>Nothing in this Act affects the implementation of the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1531">16 U.S.C. 1531 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection id="HDBE4D6E5FBF14A7B9F13BEA2E4BD357F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Federal reserved water rights</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act limits or expands any existing or future reserved water rights of the Federal Government on land administered by the Secretary.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1475808000354BE2B0C7268B2121500F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Federal power act</header><text>Nothing in this Act limits or expands authorities pursuant to sections 4(e), 10(j), or 18 of the Federal Power Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/797">16 U.S.C. 797(e)</external-xref>, 803(j), 811).</text></subsection><subsection id="H2EBFAE3CA9954566B2E2F5E6221FA503"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Indian water rights</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act limits or expands any existing or future reserved water right or treaty right of any federally recognized Indian Tribe.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC44D5BC40C4E4F10B89498072F1DA088"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Federally held state water rights</header><text>Nothing in this Act limits the ability of the Secretary, through applicable State procedures, to acquire, use, enforce, or protect a State water right owned by the United States.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1FFB3D1A673445C48DEA8426655375AD"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Interstate Compacts</header><text>Nothing in this Act affects an allocation contained in, or limitations and requirements of, any interstate water compact or decree of the Supreme Court of the United States interpreting or enforcing an interstate water compact.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

