<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-AEG25268-2CK-37-LYW"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1558 IS: Understanding the True Cost of College Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code>II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1558</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250501">May 1, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S153">Mr. Grassley</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S394">Ms. Smith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S388">Ms.
                    Hassan</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S412">Mr. Tuberville</cosponsor>)
                introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the
                    <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and
                    Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require a standard financial aid offer form, and for other
 purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Understanding the True Cost of College Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id91062274f859458e8b5e0e9eeace7205"><enum>2.</enum><header>Financial aid offer form</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 484 of the Higher Education Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1092">20 U.S.C. 1092</external-xref> note) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc13e3542d82342499ff628357f579431"><section id="idf3afbcb5db92427c8956458b261fe34a"><enum>484.</enum><header>Financial aid offer form</header><subsection id="id8126f760a97445e8923ac46ed8c5b2d7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Standard form and terminology</header><text>The Secretary of Education, in consultation with the heads of relevant Federal agencies, shall develop standard terminology and a standard form for financial aid offers based on recommendations from representatives of students, veterans, servicemembers, students’ families, institutions of higher education (including community colleges, for-profit institutions, 4-year public institutions, and 4-year private nonprofit institutions), financial aid experts, secondary school and postsecondary counselors, college access professionals, nonprofit organizations, and consumer groups.</text></subsection><subsection id="id4cf1c59a730f423d874c083e68200af9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Key required contents for aid offer</header><text>The standard form developed pursuant to subsection (a) shall be titled <quote>Financial Aid Offer</quote> and shall include the following items in a consumer-friendly manner that is simple and understandable, with costs listed first followed by grants and scholarships, clearly separated from each other with separate headings:</text><paragraph id="id96eff8e99d9443a48219c332aeea9435"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Cost information</header><subparagraph id="idd08dc5b246a640efa27bfc6f1f17ae6b"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Information on the student's estimated cost of attendance, including the following:</text><clause id="idc7e7364b55384ad4a78ec760f670bc31"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Direct costs</header><text>The total cost of all items described in section 472 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087ll">20 U.S.C. 1087ll</external-xref>) that are billed to the student by the institution or otherwise required by the institution for enrollment, including such total cost disaggregated by the cost of each such item, including, as determined under such section—</text><subclause id="idc2de3f75ba414091be9171d80cddcf27"><enum>(I)</enum><text>tuition and fees (and other required expenses); and</text></subclause><subclause id="id2ae8eaa0964b4047a97beffa4a22d4b5"><enum>(II)</enum><text>housing and food for a student participating in institutionally owned or operated food services or institutionally owned or operated housing.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id27f0a3f27b974ce096739f01fed415ab"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Indirect costs</header><text>The total cost of all items described in section 472 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087ll">20 U.S.C. 1087ll</external-xref>) that are not billed to the student by the institution or otherwise required by the institution for enrollment, including such total cost disaggregated by the cost of each such item, including, as determined under such section—</text><subclause id="id6dc916ee049849f3a738b113635380bb"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the component totals each for housing and food costs for students who reside off-campus or off campus with family;</text></subclause><subclause id="ida9bc8e7e1f3a4147bc4d068bc649930c"><enum>(II)</enum><text>books, supplies, equipment, course materials, and rental or purchase of a personal computer; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id57a08fad4e0c4dd9be0c3de341212899"><enum>(III)</enum><text>transportation.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id26c3056aa7a9465996c391289773a7ef"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Academic period</header><text>The academic period covered by the Financial Aid Offer, and an explanation that the amount of financial aid offered may change—</text><clause id="idf4805b46dde946c8809f5fa562941501"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for academic periods not covered by the Financial Aid Offer; or</text></clause><clause id="id3eb039c0a0f840098643ddc337d000ad"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by program.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4901a99c52d9489881eb1adbb54abfe3"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Enrollment status</header><text>An indication of whether cost and aid estimates are based on full-time or part-time enrollment.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3d7b873b69a541ceab904c8d85affba7"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Estimated or set</header><text>An indication, as applicable, about whether the tuition and fees are estimated based on the previous year, or are set, for the academic period indicated in accordance with subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5e3935e2934b4ad0b59f01486b828099"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Grants and scholarships</header><text>The aggregate amount of grants and scholarships, differentiated by source, that the student does not have to repay, such as grant aid offered under title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070">20 U.S.C. 1070 et seq.</external-xref>) and grant aid offered through other Federal programs, grant and scholarship aid offered by the institution, grant and scholarship aid offered by the State, and, if known, grant and scholarship aid from an outside source to the student for such academic period, including—</text><subparagraph id="idc4c311c3a040420d848103c1bdc31575"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a disclosure that the grants and scholarships do not have to be repaid; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id690de98c14df40419d17ba9f87a13652"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if institutional aid is included—</text><clause id="id6d3e928f7a4847b6a804a849a2650945"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the conditions under which the student can expect to receive similar amounts of such financial aid for each academic period the student is enrolled at the institution; and</text></clause><clause id="idcda16389838b4ae382b0013e2880df48"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>whether the institutional aid offer may change if grants or scholarships from outside sources are applied after the student receives the Financial Aid Offer, and, if applicable, how that aid will change.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id98b449264f5c4391a865e6578b9bc726"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Net price</header><subparagraph id="id8c8431424607413f904f194bc4a4606e"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The net price that the student, or the student's family on behalf of the student, is estimated to have to pay for the student to attend the institution for such academic period, equal to—</text><clause id="id2facd1c5ef504d20a62d16ed3fda77b5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the cost of attendance as described in paragraph (1)(A) for the student for the period indicated in paragraph (1)(B); minus</text></clause><clause id="ida1266ba521284a67af31b90433464555"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the amount of grant and scholarship aid described in paragraph (2) that is included in the Financial Aid Offer.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbc49b2a60bfd4e9ab287406b591bb028"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Disclosure</header><text>A disclosure that the net price is an estimate of the total expenses for the year and not equivalent to the amount the student will owe directly to the institution.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id7729d1aae7d74c43860edcd92009ca18"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Loans</header><subparagraph id="id643de61ec22b4139978411853ed83f6f"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Information on any loan under part D of title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087a">20 U.S.C. 1087a et seq.</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087aa">20 U.S.C. 1087aa et seq.</external-xref>) (except a Federal Direct PLUS Loan under part D of that Act) that the institution recommends for the student for the academic period covered by the Financial Aid Offer, which shall be made—</text><clause id="id2c509af4c59442ba9992d5a6887177aa"><enum>(i)</enum><text>with clear use of the word <quote>loan</quote> to describe the recommended loan amounts; and</text></clause><clause id="idbfb4759715fb463daae39c7fc05b937f"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>with clear labeling of subsidized and unsubsidized loans.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id44b43663497448f4aca4bc929bc91e52"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Disclosure on repayment</header><text>A disclosure that such loans have to be repaid and a disclosure that the student can borrow a lesser or, if applicable, greater amount than the recommended loan amount.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2b5d5b2036d24aab9c748281b2fc6876"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Disclosure on interest rates and fees</header><text>A disclosure that the interest rates and fees on such loans are set annually and affect total cost over time, and a link to a Department of Education website that includes current information on interest rates and fees.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf686fa3a830442d69f7acba6d08e43eb"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Link to repayment calculator</header><text>A link to the Department of Education's repayment calculator website for students with instruction that this website contains customizable estimates of expected repayment costs under different loan repayment plans.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idad34b490859141fc9a60a13e292f669f"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Process for accepting, adjusting, or declining aid and next
 steps</header><subparagraph id="id0fec85950f11434eb4e74a804b0d9e3f"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The deadlines and a summary of the process (including the next steps) for—</text><clause id="ide275ab214b424938803ece1c0df381f4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>accepting the financial aid offered;</text></clause><clause id="id783ff8b3ec2e48959b40da4ccb78b58c"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>adjusting the amount of financial aid offered; and</text></clause><clause id="id5432521c9ae74ddaade1bb1faf94f8fa"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>declining the financial aid offered.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8446b80901b1407f91ebb7451f2fa6e7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Information on paying costs</header><text>Information on when and how costs described in paragraph (1)(A)(i) must be paid, including a clear indication of whether such cost is required or optional for the student.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf31098d2f424448b8f74fd298aee1de3"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Disclosure on verification of information</header><text>A disclosure that verification of information provided on the Free Application for Federal Student Aid may require the student to submit further documentation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0acd945927634236a7de96e88ffae8cf"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Contact information</header><text>Information about where a student or the student’s family can seek additional information regarding the financial aid offered, including contact information for the institution’s financial aid office and the Department of Education’s website on financial aid.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1f83eb94b585417ab8563311e4e3aade"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Additional information</header><text>Any other information the Secretary of Education, in consultation with the heads of relevant Federal agencies, including the Secretary of the Treasury and the Director of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection, determines necessary (based on the results of the consumer testing under subsection (g)(2)) so that students and parents can make informed loan borrowing decisions, which may include—</text><subparagraph id="id087f29965c764eb6bb0ed60dbbfee8ac"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the most recent cohort default rate, as defined in section 435(m) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1085">20 U.S.C. 1085(m)</external-xref>), with respect to an institution where more than 30 percent of enrolled students borrow loans to pay for their education, and a comparison to the national average cohort default rate;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id35a8795348474b4f84abd338db723af5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the percentage of students at the institution who borrow student loans;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id57ec9ec074ed44e59f7982307923246f"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the median loan debt at graduation for students at the institution (clearly marked as including only Federal loans if private loan data are not available to be included); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfcb61b2cb5544b73ba1c4625a2083779"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any additional calculations determined necessary for ensuring that students understand full college costs, financial aid gaps, and options for covering those gaps.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id5f03c1047da14c5482d2a00a9e86e3ff"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Other required contents for financial aid offer</header><text>The standard form developed under subsection (a) shall include, in addition to the information described in subsection (b), to be included on the Financial Aid Offer in a concise format determined by the Secretary of Education, in consultation with the heads of relevant Federal agencies and the individuals and entities described in subsection (a), the following information:</text><paragraph id="ida3f78307b2d04681b016991c391c163c"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Additional options</header><text>At the institution’s discretion—</text><subparagraph id="idc6ad990bd8e34168b2399ef9887b1bf8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>additional options and potential resources for paying for the amount listed in subsection (b)(3), such as tuition payment plans and the terms and conditions of those plans; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbb68a05062c543788c799550a7fb2a8e"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a disclosure that Federal Direct PLUS Loans made under part D of title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087a">20 U.S.C. 1087a et seq.</external-xref>), private education loans, or other financing products may be available to cover remaining need, except that the institution—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id62b6c00891ff4887aa7db1cd6420fbc5"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may not include an amount for such Federal Direct PLUS Loans, private education loans, or other financing products; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf1e5f6025c5744ecaa6131dce25906b9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall include a disclosure that such loans and agreements—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfc0b5e9fb1134ead8920df8793ba4d96"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are subject to an additional application process and have to be repaid by the borrower; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3984972223b1437a934c93e20a225281"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may not be eligible for all the benefits available for Federal Direct Stafford Loans or Federal Direct Unsubsidized Stafford Loans.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5d85d557b90a48669d7815a9f0fa4165"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Information on private education loans and other financing
 products</header><text>The following information relating to private education loans and other financing products:</text><subparagraph id="id81ab9663f8d14084b554419033faef67"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A disclosure that students considering borrowing to cover the cost of attendance should consider available Federal student loans prior to applying for private education loans or other financing products, including an explanation that Federal student loans offer generally more favorable terms and beneficial repayment options than private education loans and other financing products.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id52b7e475c34e4ef4b96029c7fdd1f688"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The impact of a proposed private education loan or other financing product on the student’s potential eligibility for other financial assistance, including Federal financial assistance under title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070">20 U.S.C. 1070 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc5a3e6c6b000457d8cbf4700635ccf35"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A statement explaining the student’s ability to select a private educational lender or other financing product provider of the student’s choice.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id71abf1ba492c4a0e845feedb4c3eb996" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Student employment</header><text>Information on work-study employment opportunities offered in accordance with part C of title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087-51">20 U.S.C. 1087–51 et seq.</external-xref>), institutional work-study programs, or State work-study programs, including—</text><subparagraph id="id7f5769710c9c4cf3bfc6f96457e6a3d1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the maximum annual amount the student may earn through the program; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfb3b260f4f6e489888e2284556fdab0c"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a disclosure that any work-study amount offered may be—</text><clause id="id7e1baded60a64cfbb9463a7957cd6598"><enum>(i)</enum><text>subject to the availability of qualified employment opportunities upon the student's enrollment; and</text></clause><clause id="id74a4858fd2e24b5498056bbde507767c"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>disbursed over time as earned by the student.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id47d329d59d7546ad8d7f5cdcb1ca2ed6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Additional requirements for financial aid offers</header><text>Each Financial Aid Offer shall meet the following requirements:</text><paragraph id="id2b526f596965486e8b564b281316af9f"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Include, in addition to the requirements described in subsections (b) and (c), a concise summary, in plain language, of—</text><subparagraph id="id0c0ea1147a9b49a4a27b3d8043d86fd2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the terms and conditions of financial aid recommended under paragraphs (2) and (4) of subsection (b) and subsection (c)(3), and a method to provide students with additional information about such terms and conditions, such as links to the supplementary information; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id54eab952b6fa496b91e4b6beea38a03c"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Federal, State, or institutional conditions required to receive and renew financial aid and a method to provide students with additional information about these conditions, such as links to the supplementary information.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id4416436f46ee4937887dca8fb845176d"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Clearly distinguish between the aid offered under paragraphs (2) and (4) of subsection (b) and subsection (c)(3), by including a subtotal for the aid offered in each of such paragraphs and by refraining from commingling the different types of aid described in such paragraphs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf940a96dc6064b348cbad2a0412a309e"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Use standard terminology and definitions, as described in subsection (e)(1) and use plain language where possible.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id330046a8ce3e4e06bacf216df1fcb79e"><enum>(4)</enum><text>If an institution’s recommended Federal student loan aid offered in subsection (b)(4) is less than the Federal maximum available to the student, the institution shall provide additional information on Federal student loans, including the types and amounts for which the student is eligible in an attached document or web page.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id59f95e686ffc4bbf914ea0b28d6768e9"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Use the standard offer form described in subsection (e)(2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id747db4122e1147eea74abda9f247bcac"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Include the standardized statement regarding the possible availability of Federal education benefits, as established by the Secretary in accordance with subsection (e)(3).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id375417b91f0c458d833052f73d22d687"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Include a delivery confirmation for electronic Financial Aid Offers, except that receipt of the Financial Aid Offer shall not be considered an acceptance or rejection of aid by the student.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id86705ebde1cd4a72859b72490743dc06"><enum>(8)</enum><text>With respect to dependent students, any reference to private education loans shall be accompanied by—</text><subparagraph id="idfd492f81bd7243b78b4e52bd4bbb13a7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>information about the availability of, and terms and conditions associated with, Federal Direct PLUS Loans under section 455 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087e">20 U.S.C. 1087e</external-xref>) for the student's parents regardless of family income; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd10d46e0be544fa5ba5197efee6b3231"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a notification of the student’s increased eligibility for Federal student loans under title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070">20 U.S.C. 1070 et seq.</external-xref>) if the student's parents are not able to borrow under the Federal Direct PLUS Loan program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ida4f45c15a20b4e818e8bcc1d2e779a2d"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Standard information established by the Secretary</header><paragraph id="id44f2878058ec4ca5aca2abd2f4342cdb"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Standard terminology and definitions</header><text>Not later than 3 months after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Understanding the True Cost of College Act of 2025</short-title>, the Secretary of Education, in consultation with the heads of relevant Federal agencies, including the Secretary of the Treasury and the Director of the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau, and the individuals and entities described in subsection (a), shall establish standard terminology and definitions for the terms described in subsection (b).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id47bd01c5a6cc45b49cbe1ed75f9ca27c"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Standard form</header><subparagraph id="idcf6892c384d542ee8239899e254a6feb"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Education shall develop multiple draft financial aid offer forms for consumer testing, carry out consumer testing for such forms, and establish a finalized standard financial aid offer form, in accordance with the process established under subsection (g) and the requirements of this section.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id24606f7829b94f92a229c244de1296da"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Separate financial aid offer forms</header><text>The Secretary may develop separate financial aid offer forms for—</text><clause id="id9082668534544af08a215052a69b33f6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>undergraduate students and graduate students; and</text></clause><clause id="id66bac62699894e2289a099f5d97f4b01"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>first-time students and returning students.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id90c4cf4ab7f641beb284167d78b8aaea"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Additional benefits</header><text>The Secretary of Education, in consultation with the heads of relevant Federal agencies, including the Secretary of the Treasury, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, the Secretary of Defense, and the Director of the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau, shall establish standard language notifying students that they may be eligible for education benefits (and where students can locate more information about such benefits) including benefits in accordance with each of the following:</text><subparagraph id="id5a623ee642a14089a5e64d95a2f1c2e7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Chapter 30, 31, 32, 33, 34, or 35 of title 38, United States Code.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb139828dd8094f45ab3f34056ed9748b"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Chapter 101, 105, 106A, 1606, 1607, or 1608 of title 10, United States Code.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id75b9507f23c84d2eb9c768431dac1ee9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Section 1784a, 2005, or 2007 of title 10, United States Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0df498d386a049768c38783576ff3966"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Supplemental information; removal of information</header><paragraph id="iddd4b9b963263477da8185fe7d968d8eb"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Supplemental information</header><text>Nothing in this section shall preclude an institution from supplementing the Financial Aid Offer with additional information if such additional information utilizes the same standard terminology identified in subsection (e)(1) and does not misrepresent costs, financial aid offered, or net price.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id19911cef25584d75a0e669a0b51f8563"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Removal of information</header><text>Nothing in this section shall preclude an institution from deleting a required item on a Financial Aid Offer if—</text><subparagraph id="id9a7923f56ec64dbbb83dd4820d2ef14b"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the student is ineligible for such item;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb63066b26b634fd3942eda6d7f3da6f1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the institution does not participate in the program related to such item; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6b5e2616ec8b41b38643bc59a98234b6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the cost of attendance item is not applicable to the student.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idd42a20fea9ca4af48f968a2ed95edafe"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Development of financial aid offer form</header><paragraph id="ide30684b56d3c4847b4399b0a829d511d"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Draft form</header><text>Not later than 9 months after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Understanding the True Cost of College Act of 2025</short-title>, the Secretary of Education, in consultation with the heads of relevant Federal agencies, including the Secretary of the Treasury and the Director of the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau, and the individuals and entities described in subsection (a), shall design and produce multiple draft financial aid offer forms for consumer testing with postsecondary students or prospective students. In developing that form, the Secretary shall ensure—</text><subparagraph id="id431f7b3de6c84d288c84d585dc36106f"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that the headings described in paragraphs (1) through (4) of subsection (b) are in the same font, appear in the same order, and are displayed prominently on the financial aid offer form, such that none of that information is inappropriately omitted or de-emphasized;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5a9d63ec1c6a42d8bdf89377e9b6d400"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that the other information required in subsection (b) appears in a standard format and design on the Financial Aid Offer; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id46325ac9efce4f5eacbd91d82347d053"><enum>(C)</enum><text>that the institution may include a logo or brand alongside the title of the Financial Aid Offer.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1790ce3ef90d4b1f941832ea9216a496"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consumer testing</header><subparagraph id="id2a1d17f80df94e6184e9fce53fb6d5d3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 9 months after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Understanding the True Cost of College Act of 2025</short-title>, the Secretary of Education, in consultation with the heads of relevant Federal agencies, shall establish a process to submit the financial aid offer form drafts developed under paragraph (1) for consumer testing among representatives of students (including low-income students, first-generation college students, adult students, veterans, servicemembers, and prospective students), students’ families (including low-income families, families with first-generation college students, and families with prospective students), institutions of higher education, secondary school and postsecondary counselors, and nonprofit consumer groups.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4e9de7bbe4b84bc2bccd4b8aaceca193"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Pilot</header><text>During such consumer testing, the Secretary shall ensure that not less than 16 and not more than 24 eligible institutions use the draft forms developed under paragraph (1), including institutions—</text><clause id="id4f58756e159045d480632a6c1ce03939"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that reflect a proportionate representation (based on the total number of students enrolled in postsecondary education) of community colleges, for-profit institutions, 4-year public institutions, and 4-year private nonprofit institutions; and</text></clause><clause id="idb1ce3afe80f3420d998a0dd86beb8adc"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that reflect geographic diversity.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc159b03beda6484f871ecc7f98d6d195"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Length of consumer testing</header><text>The Secretary of Education shall ensure that the consumer testing under this paragraph lasts no longer than 8 months after the process for consumer testing is developed under subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id2eb063f63e5b49abaf0b7aedb90e18ab"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Final form</header><subparagraph id="id82f9b25014c74546905a954333004a7d"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The results of consumer testing under paragraph (2) shall be used in the final development of the financial aid offer form.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1abe4931458e427dbc0de2f6ddf900b6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Reporting requirement</header><text>Not later than 3 months after the date the consumer testing under paragraph (2) concludes, the Secretary of Education shall submit to Congress and publish on its website the final standard financial aid offer form and a report detailing the results of such testing, including whether the Secretary of Education added any additional items to the standard financial aid offer form pursuant to subsection (b)(6).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id56648cf9862d4eed9b883c0b3e9409b1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Authority to modify</header><text>The Secretary of Education may modify or remove the definitions, terms, formatting, or design of the financial aid offer form based on the results of consumer testing required under this subsection and before finalizing the form, or in subsequent consumer testing. The Secretary may also recommend additional changes to Congress.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="ide51cbfc57d1244219ace649b3a7bb291"><enum>3.</enum><header>Mandatory form</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part B of title I of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1011">20 U.S.C. 1011 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idE95639FB7D2D4D28B490719B801DCD42"><section id="id1001d451dbd2485fad6f4dbcf6a63c1b"><enum>124.</enum><header>Use of mandatory financial aid offer form and terms</header><subsection id="id9db57e38a1254c568935293e74bda7e4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, each institution of higher education that receives Federal financial assistance under this Act shall—</text><paragraph id="idb287d38511514691b4f501e7d082c76b"><enum>(1)</enum><text>use the financial aid offer form developed under section 484 of the Higher Education Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1092">20 U.S.C. 1092</external-xref> note) in providing paper, mobile-optimized offers, or other electronic offers to all students who apply for aid and are accepted at the institution; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id32f8fa631416430cb5d746a857760d54"><enum>(2)</enum><text>use the standard terminology and definitions developed by the Secretary of Education under subsection (e)(1) of such section 484 for all communications from the institution related to Financial Aid Offers.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id93d6ad0bd3f84feab62c195f95a0b811"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective dates</header><text>The requirements under this section shall take effect at the start of the first award year after the Secretary of Education finalizes the standard terminology and form developed in accordance with section 484 of the Higher Education Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1092">20 U.S.C. 1092</external-xref> note).</text></subsection><subsection id="id2cc87aa3657c4410b0841cf6d92a6d8f"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Administrative procedures</header><text>Section 492 shall not apply with respect to regulations promulgated in accordance with this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill>


