<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H94E75D95C40E4EA19CD6D36079E82CDA" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 868 IH: Prison Staff Safety Enhancement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 868</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250131">January 31, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000597">Ms. Lee of Florida</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To address sexual harassment and sexual assault of Bureau of Prisons staff in prisons, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H45A0C310333643E8975C29B92D392243" style="OLC"><section id="H0D7C01D09A3F4517998C1D36D58B2A51" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Prison Staff Safety Enhancement Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HD3ED290D8EC24FDBB3859487A0B5A8DE"><enum>2.</enum><header>Addressing sexual harassment and sexual assault of Bureau of Prisons staff</header><subsection id="H5991C6DFFAA74F5084AE0543E94F7DDA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HB56440B2724B4BD796BC439F933BB551" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Correctional officer</header><text>The term <term>correctional officer</term> has the meaning given the term in section 4051 of title 18, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAE0DC4ADB02F4677A2C995D9C456E478"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Inspector General</header><text>The term <term>Inspector General</term> means the Inspector General of the Department of Justice.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0A35C8BFDE004623B435DEA4B676C3BA"><enum>(3)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Incarcerated individual</header><text>The term <term>incarcerated individual</term> has the meaning given the term <term>prisoner</term> in section 4051 of title 18, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H61E332E051744584A9A331ADCA316D16"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Sexual assault</header><text>The term <term>sexual assault</term> means an act described in subsection (b), (c), or (d) of section 920 of title 10, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H71039341DF1C4177A4E166595112A96C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Sexual harassment</header><text>The term <term>sexual harassment</term> means unwelcome sexual advances, requests for sexual favors, or other verbal or physical conduct of a sexual nature that explicitly or implicitly affect an individual’s employment, unreasonably interfere with an individual’s work performance, or create an intimidating, hostile, or offensive work environment.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H39CB325BFE584DDEABC035352589AF7A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Review and analysis</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H36C03B26B88E4EE589F35973455587C0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Inspector General shall carry out a comprehensive statistical review and analysis of the incidence and effects of sexual harassment and sexual assault perpetrated by incarcerated individuals against a correctional officer or other employee of the Bureau of Prisons.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5BE8170D38304238959E4D60420C8822"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Analysis</header><text>The review and analysis required under paragraph (1) shall include an analysis of punishments for sexual harassment and sexual assault as of the date of enactment of this Act in facilities controlled by the Bureau of Prisons, including data on the use of such punishments during the 5-year period preceding the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF663BED979434972B7BC10ADA078A429"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after completing the review and analysis under subsection (b)(1), the Inspector General shall submit to the Attorney General and to the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives a report that summarizes the findings of the review and analysis.</text></subsection><subsection id="H78E5373441EE428EB16F3E34E45F0CD5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text>Not later than 1 year after receiving the report under subsection (c), the Attorney General shall promulgate a rule adopting national standards for prevention, reduction, and punishment of sexual harassment and sexual assault perpetrated by an incarcerated individual against a correctional officer or other employee of the Bureau of Prisons.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

