<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H58198FDDB4BD489490B1671852B7C49B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3119 IH: ReConnecting Rural America Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3119</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250430">April 30, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000193">Mr. Nunn of Iowa</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="V000136">Mr. Vasquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001225">Mr. Sorensen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000475">Mr. Finstad</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001315">Ms. Budzinski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001194">Mr. Moolenaar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000804">Mr. Wittman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001237">Ms. McDonald Rivet</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001212">Mr. Stauber</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HAP00">Appropriations</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Rural Electrification Act of 1936 to establish the ReConnect program under that Act, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8CA2512D93A44618AD78B736CB206089" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H567B25610CD34856895156908A059BA4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>ReConnecting Rural America Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE3A3C9CCC001458580EBD3EADA2484D5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Access to broadband telecommunications services in rural areas</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9D7C5B3629724BBAA9D84D96811E90D0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 601 of the Rural Electrification Act of 1936 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/950bb">7 U.S.C. 950bb</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0816094738204B5FA70A27E086A04BF6"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking subsections (a) through (f) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFE0B7083BB7C4EEB9FE678C6BF472024"> <subsection id="HCECEFA35FB574FB083B5D8DF7B86323E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of this section is to provide assistance in the form of grants, loans, and combinations of grants and loans for the costs of the construction, improvement, and acquisition of facilities and equipment for broadband service in rural areas.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H080EE960EE754B2CBCCAA5F8A56CB4A1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HE810B0C10DF74FBEB6A2B6D84BE1D6A5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Broadband service</header><text>The term <term>broadband service</term> means any technology identified by the Secretary as having the capacity to transmit data to enable a subscriber to the service to originate and receive high-quality voice, data, graphics, and video.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF2F93B84E45741BBB340CFFCEDE8AABA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rural area</header>
<subparagraph id="H3287A11B290543CF905E606B8E4BC35A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>rural area</term> means any area other than—</text> <clause id="H992D09C353124BACB8C7ADF9700242EE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an area described in clause (i) or (ii) of section 343(a)(13)(A) of the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1991">7 U.S.C. 1991(a)(13)(A)</external-xref>); and</text></clause>
<clause id="HBAAF7A01814C42CCA2125E02BC8D6012"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a city, town, or incorporated area that has a population of greater than 20,000 inhabitants.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H62A3BDB47A844EE08EE93B9C0591FF30"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Urban area growth</header><text>The Secretary may, by regulation only, consider an area described in section 343(a)(13)(F)(i)(I) of that Act to not be a rural area for purposes of this section.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H423CA4B018BC4800B999A0E3641CE3C2"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Exclusion of certain populations</header><text>The term <term>rural area</term> does not include any population described in subparagraph (H) or (I) of section 343(a)(13) of the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1991">7 U.S.C. 1991(a)(13)</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HCCA2FB13254B4097BA7507226C86B63B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Grants, loans, and combinations</header> <paragraph id="H66C8B437EC7245AEA1C95AECBF1ECC1D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall make grants, loans, and combinations of grants and loans to eligible entities described in subsection (d) to provide funds for the construction, improvement, or acquisition of facilities and equipment for the provision of broadband service in rural areas.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H31A5746ED992454F931BA6F1A49E0453"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Project eligibility</header><text>To be eligible for a grant, loan, or grant and loan combination under paragraph (1), in addition to the requirements of subsection (d), the project that is the subject of the grant, loan, or grant and loan combination shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HF43FE5532614461397011F57B2219071"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide broadband service of at least—</text>
<clause id="HFA463831D3F9464D95AA583EA74256E3">
                    <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>a 100-Mbps downstream transmission capacity; and</text> </clause> <clause id="H50A1655994FB49E6A30EABDDAAA55334"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>a 100-Mbps upstream transmission capacity; and</text>
                  </clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H7C895ED6FDC14BB1A66E999B7636FE0A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>subject to paragraph (4), be carried out in a proposed service territory in which at least 75 percent of the households lack access to broadband service of at least—</text> <clause id="H77B38772EC5A4A8BB7279D18DA38738D"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>a 100-Mbps downstream transmission capacity; and</text>
                  </clause>
<clause id="HB37AA494511B4418A1E908331D2B8703">
                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>a 20-Mbps upstream transmission capacity.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H32326F6CE46148E986F5E64807314E52"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In making grants, loans, and grant and loan combinations under paragraph (1), the Secretary—</text>
<subparagraph id="H9105F5AB1C73430A8EEA2849D76C83CF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall give priority to applications for projects to provide broadband service in a proposed service territory in which at least 90 percent of households lack access to broadband service of at least—</text> <clause id="HD6674124BD33472E9309C44B6365C974"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>a 100-Mbps downstream transmission capacity; and</text>
                  </clause>
<clause id="H265477374CB243ECB3FAA41518307ADA">
                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>a 20-Mbps upstream transmission capacity; and</text> </clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H020A920B77AE45119B517E392AC9FF7A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may give priority to applications for projects to provide broadband service—</text>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5F4913A012DC417FB593743B73D258A9"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in proposed service territories—</text> <subclause id="HDC1DE3FDABC743AC9DFF1D36DCAB5A53"><enum>(I)</enum><text>with a population of less than 10,000 permanent residents;</text></subclause>
<subclause id="HE516B727DA674E8ABDE3990EAC04E2A2"><enum>(II)</enum><text>that are experiencing outmigration and have adopted a strategic community investment plan under section 379H(d) of the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2008v">7 U.S.C. 2008v(d)</external-xref>) that includes considerations for improving and expanding broadband service;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H54FD2329F8D34F80AD798BD55CC7EE15"> <enum>(III)</enum> <text>with a high percentage of low income families or persons (as defined in section 501(b) of the Housing Act of 1949 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1471">42 U.S.C. 1471(b)</external-xref>)); or</text>
                                        </subclause>
<subclause id="H9D029F4190A54816B495151F84755EA5"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>that are isolated from other significant population centers;</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HF03942B5117F4247B816FC9C5FFEFA3A" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that would ensure that all laborers and mechanics employed by contractors or subcontractors on the construction work performed on projects financed, in whole or in part, with the grant, loan, or grant and loan combination shall be paid wages at rates not less than those prevailing on similar construction in the immediate locality as determined by the Secretary of Labor in accordance with sections 3141 through 3144, 3146, and 3147 of title 40, United States Code;</text></clause>
<clause id="H8719A57D6911410BBF0938959C2E150A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>that would provide rapid and expanded deployment of fixed and mobile broadband service on cropland and ranchland within the service territory for use in various applications of precision agriculture; or</text></clause> <clause id="HBAE251FC80C443DC8D3B3300783C96F1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>submitted by an eligible entity that has provided broadband service or other utility service for not less than 5 years in rural areas in the State in which the project would be carried out.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H938FD091A3844C919FF94BDC097B5D5C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Additional requirements for grant-only awards</header><text>To be eligible for assistance under paragraph (1) in the form of a grant only, in addition to the requirements of subsection (d)—</text> <subparagraph id="H2C2FE3C743EF4F93918D4FB444D64C32"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an entity shall be—</text>
<clause id="HAF372F8288304E0E82CE788AF27CAE83"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a Tribal organization (as defined in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>));</text></clause> <clause id="H7B32F797CE9A49E3AEF1D2B33FC018B2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a colonia;</text></clause>
<clause id="H0A0DEA60C6FD424989E50F7D21311ED0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a persistent poverty county, as determined by the Secretary; or</text></clause> <clause id="HD6A3413378AC4470ACEE013E512865E1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a socially vulnerable community, as determined by the Secretary; or</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H82A097613D86426BA51C382F9DF91B8E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the project that is the subject of the grant shall be carried out in a proposed service territory in which at least 90 percent of households lack access to broadband service of at least—</text> <clause id="HDF10F3BA746544AC8AE2554BBB1C17F1"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>a 100-Mbps downstream transmission capacity; and</text>
                  </clause>
<clause id="HD2BF6131B38941C1B7650B3B9409BA8F">
                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>a 20-Mbps upstream transmission capacity.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H093877F9F4E24FAD893A63787639DB14"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Eligibility</header> <paragraph id="HDA72676C040540B7BCCEC55F14661C5F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible entities</header> <subparagraph id="H2B64A84DAAB04D8B8841E67AF3E24AE4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To be eligible to obtain a grant, loan, or grant and loan combination under subsection (c), an entity shall—</text>
<clause id="HF9BF74BE3E73471E90C3F5A3B6A429E9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require;</text></clause> <clause id="HBB8B4A6B30994B37A7FD66785D596661"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>agree to complete buildout of the broadband infrastructure described in the application by not later than 5 years after the initial date on which assistance under subsection (c) is made available; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H618ACC6A31BB4BCCAC0164C67FEB6BFF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>participate or agree to participate in—</text> <subclause id="H7467C53AC26341B9B541C90E17ACE254"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the Affordable Connectivity Program established under section 904(b) of division N of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1752">47 U.S.C. 1752(b)</external-xref>); </text></subclause>
<subclause id="H6E6A46A2738248669ACCA350CDA0B0D8"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the Lifeline program under subpart E of part 54 of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation); or</text></subclause> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBC3319497766493B923B592FE48E3856"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any successor Federal internet affordability assistance program. </text></subclause></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H6E5D0A2204CB4518BA9EA46CB7C6FB8A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text>An entity eligible to obtain a grant, loan, or grant and loan combination under subsection (c) may include—</text> <clause id="H6EB2B9B402654FA5BF4F85912F10FB62"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a State or local government, including any agency, subdivision, instrumentality, or political subdivision of a State or local government;</text></clause>
<clause id="H4F86C4310CF34C3FAFD1728DD8179234"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a territory or possession of the United States;</text></clause> <clause id="HA7016F8FD19F42B3A4ADBC11CCC06879"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>an Indian Tribe (as defined in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>));</text></clause>
<clause id="HAABB33C63CB44F96BB4CB1FFD827D58F"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a cooperative or mutual organization;</text></clause> <clause id="H32911833004C4342BD86BCC3313A8F54"><enum>(v)</enum><text>an organization of 2 or more incorporated areas that have established an intermunicipal legal agreement for the purpose of delivering communication services to residents;</text></clause>
<clause id="H28AE461173D34A0B945319E68E29E90D"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>a corporation; and</text></clause> <clause id="H7CC5FE898E15435F8EF3A14872C75340"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>a limited liability company or limited liability partnership.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H20A24B03D4164A82A7D92A0169A12F81"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Ineligible entities</header><text>An individual or legal general partnership that is formed with individuals shall not be eligible to obtain a grant, loan, or grant and loan combination under subsection (c).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFFB4EE72438F4AA793E4150F74719954"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Limitation</header> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0873FCDB25A6440C8933BDDA83B3D281"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity described in this paragraph that provides telecommunications or broadband service to at least 20 percent of the households in the United States may not receive an amount of funds under this section for a fiscal year in excess of 15 percent of the funds authorized and appropriated under subsection (i) for the fiscal year.</text></clause>
<clause id="H538CF06F809D4CE9B1DD1E8CCC81E0E6"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>States and State agencies and instrumentalities</header><text>A State or an agency or instrumentality of a State may not, in total, receive an amount of funds under this section for a fiscal year in excess of 15 percent of the funds authorized and appropriated under subsection (i) for the fiscal year. </text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H594EAA495FB0477C872C4086477B4810" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Previous awards</header><text>An entity to which a grant, loan, or grant and loan combination is made under subsection (c) shall not use the grant, loan, or grant and loan combination to deploy broadband service in a service area in which broadband service is deployed by any other entity that has received a broadband grant or loan from the Rural Utilities Service, the National Telecommunications and Information Administration, the Department of the Treasury, the Federal Communications Commission, or a State broadband grant program, unless the service provided by the other entity does not provide to at least 75 percent of the households in the service area access to broadband service of at least— </text>
<clause id="HF6987CC43531496EA4D0C0985C15D40B" commented="no">
                    <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>a 100-Mbps downstream transmission capacity; and</text> </clause> <clause id="H0AE195C8535F4F729D4064CE28C87268" commented="no"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>a 20-Mbps upstream transmission capacity.</text>
                  </clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6DBA8A8EBC004601B8213029B81F563D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Equity requirements</header>
<subparagraph id="H66EFE968C36340F79184018B0958919C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may require an entity to provide a cost share in an amount not to exceed 25 percent of the amount of the grant (including the grant in a grant and loan combination) under subsection (c) requested in the application of the entity.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE0F491C761004BB080F0C9CDDD4378E7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>The Secretary may waive the cost share requirement under subparagraph (A) for entities or projects described in subsection (c)(4).</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HBED1857E392845E5B53E8BE4AF7CF879"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Technical assistance and training</header>
<subparagraph id="H6D554CDC52BD4B2694E9966BB6123FB8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may provide to eligible entities described in paragraph (1) that are applying for assistance under this section for a project described in subsection (c)(3)(A) technical assistance and training—</text> <clause id="HA2FA34AF21064CDC95E45ED84BA5688D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to prepare reports and surveys necessary to request grants, loans, and grant and loan combinations under this section for broadband deployment;</text></clause>
<clause id="HEA3AD307C6AE4AA692360E22E5CC30AB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to improve management, including financial management, relating to the proposed broadband deployment;</text></clause> <clause id="H116DAF28F4DC4231854B7798242E7595"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to prepare applications for grants, loans, and grant and loan combinations under this section; or</text></clause>
<clause id="H970A978397A6407C8B67826BC9DF26B5"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>to assist with other areas of need identified by the Secretary.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB67D382343274252ABE4F202B5B39778"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>Not less than 3 percent and not more than 5 percent of amounts appropriated under subsection (i) to carry out this section for a fiscal year shall be used for technical assistance and training under this paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H073CB8420B134D96A23EBA4A02C124BE"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Broadband service</header>
<paragraph id="H546134696A944EFC8CD3350ABA5D461B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2), for purposes of this section, the minimum acceptable level of broadband service for a rural area shall be at least—</text> <subparagraph id="HBF0098D116654404AD674DC7ABAFA50B"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>a 100-Mbps downstream transmission capacity; and</text>
                </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H57E2094631994A8EA084CF1B7B9F1DF3">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>a 100-Mbps upstream transmission capacity.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H872A4C03788C40C5B8399C99E5DCFDA6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Adjustments</header><text>At least once every 2 years, the Secretary shall review, and may adjust through notice published in the Federal Register, the minimum acceptable level of broadband service established under paragraph (1) and broadband buildout requirements under paragraph (3) to ensure that high quality, cost-effective broadband service is provided to rural areas over time.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H145D7F3E9F6749D19D4F046FB5E4C798"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Broadband buildout requirements</header>
<subparagraph id="HA7A3A272030A4DBC80CAC616F372DEDD"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Definition of broadband buildout requirement</header><text>In this paragraph, the term <term>broadband buildout requirement</term> means the level of internet service an applicant receiving assistance under this section must agree, at the time the application is finalized, to provide for the duration of any project-related agreement between the applicant and the Department.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8B4B32176C6B42F6A9C710A6A09C9C3B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Establishment of broadband buildout requirements</header><text>The Secretary shall establish broadband buildout requirements that—</text>
<clause id="H8EE2EFDACDDA48A5AB68215CB3CE2A7A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>utilize the same metrics used to define the minimum acceptable level of broadband service under paragraph (1); and</text></clause> <clause id="HF353C647F5804316A3FC8CBC42184075"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>reasonably ensure—</text>
<subclause id="HAAA9BA9290E64D358A3B60836BF80C8A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the repayment of all loans; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HD569E09F0EC04489B661AA1644AAC540"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the financed network is technically capable of providing broadband service for the lifetime of any project-related agreement.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H4A4BE6DFBB8C4962AD08174BFB482D88"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Substitute service standards for unique service territories</header>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H38F6632E3EC14124916A5EEF75F50F04"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an applicant shows that it would be cost prohibitive to meet the broadband buildout requirements established under this paragraph for the entirety of a proposed service territory due to the unique characteristics of the proposed service territory, the Secretary and the applicant may agree to utilize substitute standards for any unserved portion of the project. </text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1DE548F158DB431EB6254AC88F0EC163"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any substitute service standards described in clause (i) should continue to consider the best technology available to meet the needs of the residents in the unserved area.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB832A4200CAB4DAAAC14C3D6BAF3A46A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (g), (h), and (i) as subsections (f), (g), and (h), respectively;</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H52AA3A9A51DF4EBDAAF77D1EF6A96442"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (f) (as so redesignated)—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H897F155176F34FC381539F43A015D7E4"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the subsection heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text style="OLC" level="subsection">Loans and Loan Guarantees</header-in-text>.—</quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text style="OLC" level="subsection">Loans</header-in-text>.—</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HACB1963F008847EBA4A79BC2800A3D17"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (1)—</text>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6F30A5C8348444F1A82C642CE303CD33"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>or loan guarantee</quote>; and</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0230BBC317DC4567B1057687EA653CE9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)—</text>
<subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H65528A34ABCB4CF5B8CAAA3953B64A38"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking clause (ii);</text></subclause> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H796E9CA1A8664407A051D791B463C04F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Secretary—</quote> in the matter preceding clause (i) and all that follows through <quote>in the case</quote> in the matter preceding subclause (I) of clause (i) and inserting <quote>Secretary in the case</quote>; and</text></subclause>
<subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF8210347494C4B55A7B99769BD08A3A1"><enum>(III)</enum><text>by redesignating subclauses (I) and (II) as clauses (i) and (ii), respectively, and indenting appropriately;</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1268297D046349399F6FC4FC091C624C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (g) (as so redesignated), by striking <quote>or loan guarantee</quote> each place it appears;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H71DFB7838A464B51A56B1C47E2CF8CF6"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in subsection (h) (as so redesignated), in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>1974)</quote> and inserting <quote>1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/661a">2 U.S.C. 661a</external-xref>))</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF3BF54CA6ACD45A3B1E83500D10AC5C0"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking subsections (j) and (k) and inserting the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF59D4388116E4F1AB938975147DCAF0F">
<subsection id="HECF05AAC2D2944A198456F91F4AE166A"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Funding</header>
<paragraph id="H2F9945E02B30463D8936E4F5F4FF83D7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out subsections (a) through (h) $650,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030, to remain available until expended.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEB582F6FA55B47D19201139EA034B678"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>Not more than 5 percent of the amounts made available under paragraphs (1) and (3) shall be available to the Secretary for the administration of subsections (a) through (h).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD2D68FF29066485DB3FE570509342C58"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Direct funding</header>
<subparagraph id="HF5011588D57D45A8ADF78349AC8E96AB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Rescission</header><text>There is rescinded the unobligated balance of amounts made available to carry out section 779 of division A of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/141">Public Law 115–141</external-xref>; 132 Stat. 399).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6BB5CA0B74EA41D1BA444F3997A75981"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Direct funding</header><text>On the day after the execution of the rescission in subparagraph (A), there is appropriated to the Secretary, out of amounts in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, an amount equal to the amount rescinded in subparagraph (A), to carry out subsections (a) through (h), to remain available until expended.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HD8038DDC0E3F4C7B98EC168B9C45E7B5"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Additional rural broadband program loans</header>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H83D6A81C74F24CE79590E341A392CF45"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>The Secretary may provide direct loans in accordance with the requirements under this section, as in effect on the day before the date of enactment of the <short-title>ReConnecting Rural America Act of 2025</short-title>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5BFA27CB14EB4AE89C710BFD7B8B4D9E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this subsection $350,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030, to remain available until expended.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H60274420A8C8425C9D684B08ED4535BB"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Termination of authority</header><text>No grant, loan, or grant and loan combination may be made under this section after September 30, 2030.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H40CB4ADA12C341FC8401D85A58E29B87"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>Beginning on the date that is 120 days after the date of enactment of this Act, section 779 of division A of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/141">Public Law 115–141</external-xref>; 132 Stat. 399), shall have no force or effect.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

