<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="H45DC6E5BE53344EC9CA573DD2C9AB7FE" key="H" resolution-type="house-resolution"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 494 IH: Condemning the Violent Attacks on Law Enforcement Officers and Military Servicemembers, and the Destruction of Personal Property in Los Angeles, California.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress> 
<session display="yes">1st Session</session> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 494</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action display="yes"> 
<action-date date="20250610">June 10, 2025</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="T000478">Ms. Tenney</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">Condemning the Violent Attacks on Law Enforcement Officers and Military Servicemembers, and the Destruction of Personal Property in Los Angeles, California.</official-title> 
</form> 
<preamble> 
<whereas>
 <text>Whereas, the Federal Government, through U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE), is mandated by law to enforce immigration statutes that safeguard national security, public safety, and national sovereignty;</text>
    </whereas> 
<whereas>
 <text>Whereas, on June 6, 2025, Federal immigration enforcement operations in Los Angeles prompted widespread protests that escalated into violent riots;</text>
    </whereas> 
<whereas>
 <text>Whereas, during these riots, Federal buildings and taxpayer-funded properties were vandalized, law enforcement officers were assaulted, and American flags were desecrated, resulting in significant damage and chaos in downtown Los Angeles;</text>
    </whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, rioters engaged in acts of destruction, including the looting of small businesses, blocking of public roadways, arson of police vehicles, and other forms of violence and disorder;</text></whereas> <whereas> <text>Whereas, sanctuary city policies adopted by certain municipalities—including Los Angeles—have undermined Federal immigration enforcement efforts by shielding individuals unlawfully present in the United States, including those with criminal backgrounds, from deportation;</text>
    </whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, these policies, championed by certain state and local officials, have contributed to the erosion of public order and safety;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, in response to the unrest, President Donald J. Trump authorized the deployment of 2,000 National Guard troops to Los Angeles to assist in restoring order and protecting public safety;</text></whereas> 
<whereas>
 <text>Whereas, this Federal response was supported by national security and law enforcement officials, but publicly opposed by California Governor Gavin Newsom and Los Angeles Mayor Karen Bass;</text>
    </whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, instead of condemning the violence and supporting efforts to restore order, Governor Newsom challenged the President’s actions and sought to prevent the National Guard from operating in the state;</text></whereas> <whereas> <text>Whereas, Mayor Bass and other city leaders have consistently promoted sanctuary city policies and opposed Federal immigration enforcement, thereby undermining the rule of law; and</text>
    </whereas> 
<whereas>
 <text>Whereas, public officials who actively obstruct lawful Federal operations and fail to condemn or prevent violent unrest bear responsibility for undermining public safety and eroding respect for the rule of law;</text>
    </whereas></preamble> 
<resolution-body style="traditional" id="H90CF8CF9FE9D4A76AB3B6259CE997C77"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H67B95D7A9ED744F1BDEF230513BBEAFD"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="H57B95D8A9ED744F1BDEF230513BBEAFD"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>condemns in the strongest possible terms the actions and decisions of Governor Gavin Newsom and Mayor Karen Bass to obstruct Federal immigration enforcement and allow the continuation of unlawful sanctuary policies;</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H77B95D7A9ED744F1BDEF230513BBEAFD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>denounces the acts of violence, arson, and civil unrest that occurred in Los Angeles, and affirms that such conduct constitutes a threat to public safety and national stability;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H58B95D7A9ED744F1BDEF230513BBEAFD"> <enum>(3)</enum> <text>affirms the constitutional duty of Federal agencies, including U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement, to enforce immigration laws, and condemns any state or local government efforts to interfere with or undermine those duties; and</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H57B95D7A9ED744F1BDEF240513BBEAFD">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>supports the lawful prosecution of any individual, regardless of immigration status, who engages in acts of violence against Federal agents or law enforcement personnel.</text>
      </paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body> 
</resolution>

