<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9AC7539CC5D045479726CC10324A2803" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1861 IH: Checkpoint Modernization Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1861</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250305">March 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000594">Mr. Tony Gonzales of Texas</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require renovation of certain U.S. Border Patrol checkpoints, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H031D39EB591E44E0BBE4FE9B03C8DB32" style="OLC"><section id="H91501A531AD048048BEDE2FF44DED109" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Checkpoint Modernization Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="HDD1F8CFDECF64F1A918019B1D0EFCCF0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Renovation of U.S. Border Patrol checkpoints</header><subsection id="H8DFF9B884FAB48989A05E31DB30D49C9" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to the availability of appropriations, the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection shall prioritize renovation projects at U.S. Border Patrol checkpoints that directly—</text><paragraph id="H3403E8D978484557A322B96BBC6A121D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>improve the safety and well-being of law enforcement personnel,</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFE105F42599C448A99A2A02B3068570B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>enhance the ability of U.S. Border Patrol agents to detect and deter human smuggling, contraband, and other illicit goods, and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1720D95C5F3C40A7BC9B068D71B779E7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>reduce traffic congestion and improve overall public safety,</text></paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection" commented="no">to accommodate the increasing volume of traffic along the southern border of the United States.</continuation-text></subsection><subsection id="HAB5EAFF352394EB290A71F8737C0474B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act and annually thereafter, the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a report on the cost estimates, statuses, justifications, and other relevant information as necessary of the renovation of U.S. Border Patrol checkpoints described in subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="H3C308F8C746C4C2DAFA895744C153450"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection not less than $150,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2025 through 2028 to carry out this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD769B628DFEC46459B646702B36EB75F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rescission of Inflation Reduction Act funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The unobligated balance of all amounts appropriated or otherwise made available to the Environmental Protection Agency to carry out section 138 of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7438">42 U.S.C. 7438</external-xref>; relating to environmental and climate justice block grants) is permanently rescinded.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

