<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H61EC2D6757904F91B086750029D36B70" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2950 IH: Disaster Relief Transparency Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2950</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250417">April 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001236">Mr. Moore of North Carolina</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="F000110">Mr. Fields</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to submit to the Congress a report that describes the methodology used to allocate amounts appropriated in covered provisions for the Community Development Block Grant Disaster Recovery Program and the Community Development Block Grant Mitigation Program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H794BDD8B0A914F65AC009782C0C62473" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HA4AA46481A2647009B9505F5527B2B6B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Disaster Relief Transparency Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HBEB54E27FFF6429EB180397547B8BD0B" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>HUD Report</header> <subsection id="HF2F9AD6C4570489DA4F831219C2375FA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (in this section referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>), after consultation with the Comptroller General of the United States, shall submit to the Financial Services, Oversight and Reform, and Transportation and Infrastructure Committees of the House of Representatives and Banking Committee of the Senate a report that—</text> 
<paragraph id="HE31E49F4325E40A498F0B8C6450A028B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>describes and explains the methodology used by the Department of Housing and Urban Development to allocate, to States, Tribes, Territories, and local governments, any amounts appropriated for the Community Development Block Grant Disaster Recovery Program and the Community Development Block Grant Mitigation Program;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H24CB1E843A6F4D17A31B8C3A3A34FD8F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">addresses why such methodology may result in allocations to States, Tribes, Territories, and local governments differing between appropriations; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAB44B54298254D8CBBA97AF174B5B544"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provides legislative and administrative recommendations for improving the consistency and timeliness of the allocation of amounts appropriated for the Community Development Block Grant Disaster Recovery Program and the Community Development Block Grant Mitigation Program.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HB6AE63069C964C84B0170F89C9AD0839"><enum>(b)</enum><header>First report</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="HD260798CEEB94CE480E2A1A90888BEC6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>submit the first report described in subsection (a) not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5E8209EAAF5246ED931FEAD6D5353360"><enum>(2)</enum><text>examine the amounts appropriated for fiscal years 2025 and 2024 in such report.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD8ADBA122BF1456DAF7BBBE579FB51E6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Subsequent reports</header><text>After the submission of the first report described in subsection (b), the Secretary shall—</text> <paragraph id="HB0F5A07D6555434C81191D3339130584"><enum>(1)</enum><text>beginning in fiscal year 2026, submit the report described in subsection (a) not later than the final day of each fiscal year; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEAFC5EE122614EC0BAA0B5946AE81984"><enum>(2)</enum><text>examine the amounts appropriated for the fiscal year. </text></paragraph></subsection> </section> </legis-body></bill>

