<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" slc-id="S1-NEW25491-CWH-11-MHC">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 213 IS: Expressing support for the designation of May 2025 as “Fallen Heroes Memorial Month”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>III</distribution-code>
        <congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session display="yes">1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. RES. 213</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action display="yes">
            <action-date date="20250508">May 8, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S412">Mr. Tuberville</sponsor> submitted the following
                resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSVA00">Committee on Veterans’ Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
        <official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of May 2025 as
                <quote>Fallen Heroes Memorial Month</quote>.</official-title>
    </form>
    <preamble>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas, since the signing of the Declaration of Independence and the founding of the United States, more than 1,300,000 members of the Armed Forces have given their lives for the cause of liberty, both in the United States and around the world;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas the people of the United States owe a profound debt to those who served the United States in uniform and made the ultimate sacrifice so that their countrymen could live freely;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas the people of the United States have an obligation to honor the memories of the fallen and to commemorate those brave men and women who gave their lives to the cause of freedom;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas President Abraham Lincoln said, <quote>[A]ll that a man hath will he give for his life; and while all contribute of their substance the soldier puts his life at stake, and often yields it up in his country’s cause. The highest merit, then is due to the soldier.</quote>;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas, in an address to the Armed Forces in 1945, President Harry S. Truman said, <quote>Our debt to the heroic men and valiant women in the service of our country can never be repaid. They have earned our undying gratitude.</quote>;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas the history of Memorial Day began 3 years after the American Civil War, with the Grand Army of the Republic establishing Decoration Day as a day for honoring the Civil War dead by decorating their graves with flowers, with the State of New York being the first to adopt it as a State holiday in 1873, and with all the Union States having adopted it by 1890;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas, in the aftermath of World War I and World War II, Memorial Day became a day to remember and honor all members of the Armed Forces who fought and died on behalf of the United States;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas Congress made the observance of Memorial Day, at the time still often called Decoration Day, a Federal holiday in 1971; and</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas the over 1,300,000 members of the Armed Forces who over the centuries gave their lives in service to the people of the United States have earned the enduring respect and gratitude of the United States: Now, therefore, be it</text>
        </whereas>
    </preamble>
    <resolution-body style="traditional" id="H5C430889FAC7473B86866128593E1D0E">
        <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H8FDC7AC6E8A741398783926AB09D0CED">
            <enum/>
 <text>That the Senate—</text> <paragraph id="H4DE0DAEDE6214DB1AFE05FF1FB81D323"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>honors the more than 1,300,000 veterans who gave their lives in service to the United States;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HEEE6EE54A9944FFCB668A8A48E3DBB92">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>recognizes the families and loved ones of the fallen heroes of the United States and lifts them up in prayer;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H65B036ECD4B2456CAF827F4557AF14BD">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>urges the people of the United States to reflect on the contributions of those heroes and to honor the memory of those who paid the ultimate sacrifice in securing the blessings of liberty for the United States; and</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H4202458C11804D07B168261308F3A5E2">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">requests that the President issue a proclamation—</text>
                <subparagraph id="H9B4A807152AA4E25A63C189A71B82302" commented="no">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>designating May 2025 as <quote>Fallen Heroes Memorial Month</quote>;</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H65CE0E317CED467F8EA71EF20E46C835" commented="no">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>affirming the everlasting gratitude of the United States for members of the Armed Forces who made the ultimate sacrifice; and</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H461D9B3F885E411E897115AB17F4C7DF" commented="no">
                    <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>calling on the people of the United States to remember and honor the fallen heroes of the United States and to pay tribute to them through volunteering and supporting veteran service organizations.</text>
                </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
        </section>
    </resolution-body>
</resolution>

