<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB8532ACC7EEB477BAA6FE4E1E7E1BFD1" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 851 IH: DOT Victim and Survivor Advocate Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 851</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250131">January 31, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish the position of National Roadway Safety Advocate within the Department of Transportation, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H09A8A3C8C5A8400E8DED1D923E31CE0F" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="HD7EFD4ED315A410D9ECB29218B0AE815"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>DOT Victim and Survivor Advocate Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H3909D9CA50D141CD87ECECB3086A3FED"><enum>2.</enum><header>Position of National Roadway Safety Advocate</header><subsection id="H3ECD0F1645024C96A93FEB39C019B669"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H19FB1F2E7B4C47C185FE7D42BA85D958"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Department</header><text>The term <term>Department</term> means the Department of Transportation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H753DBD76B3224F179EAC54543EB630D5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Transportation.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H258B8D4722684020B2141058F3761ED4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Stakeholder</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7B786D4543644C89BC7104AD6001CCCC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>stakeholder</term> means—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2DB43466E84F4FBCB30B5F55C16B13F1"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a victim or survivor of a road crash; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFD902CB941DD455BB98E17A550C1EBC2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a family member of a victim or survivor of a road crash.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7D73F0BC224340B68F0A8769C39BE25D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Family member</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A)(ii), the term <term>family member</term> shall not be limited to a parent, parent-in-law, grandparent, grandparent-in-law, sibling, spouse, child, or step-child of a victim or survivor of a road crash.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H393CB9B43FAE4B569EE385D7B308322C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H16D631A676974F64B6FF8263291686C1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall establish within the Office of the Under Secretary of Transportation for Policy of the Department a position, to be known as the <quote>National Roadway Safety Advocate</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC28A53DF72A942A3ACC30FB756FB1B09"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Career position</header><text>The position of National Roadway Safety Advocate shall be filled by a career appointment.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB4D4FCF75F814AA29B01A17A6B0A58B9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Purposes of the position</header><text>The purposes of the position of the National Roadway Safety Advocate are—</text><paragraph id="HE39C1EE0070A4929B5E62FD84C634C82"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to document and communicate recommendations from stakeholders to the Secretary on needs, objectives, plans, approaches, content, and accomplishments of the programs and activities carried out by the Department relating to roadway safety; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H07FF0383266044A3B728FB29F867DE6F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to serve as a resource and point of contact for stakeholders on relevant roadway safety issues.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H21A9C120D0AF477388E57F6A01E108E0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authority and limitations</header><paragraph id="H8B88A409D2C8449FB8E8670732BA6824"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authority</header><text>The National Roadway Safety Advocate may—</text><subparagraph id="H1960EFFD1D2B4F8DAE99DCE61C72B979"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide—</text><clause id="H02B9A29C0F8A4AB7B95109FD85EDFF9D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>education on Department activities to stakeholders; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC4705D3E40D7485BB6F2471251D68B8B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>means for stakeholders to provide the perspective of the stakeholders on roadway safety issues to the Department;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H77902EA1064542198C18B06933C4F062"><enum>(B)</enum><text>explain Department processes, procedures, scientific principles, and technical information to victims of roadway safety incidents and advocates in plain language;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC042B2ECC265489789D09FB8CA6D4745"><enum>(C)</enum><text>communicate the perspective of stakeholders within Department processes;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H456EB13266A3463E96E2857349F34C42"><enum>(D)</enum><text>provide aggregated feedback on the regulatory agenda and activities of the Department from stakeholders to the Secretary;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8A714B3FBABD4EBB9AF134FB81398113"><enum>(E)</enum><text>build relationships with individual stakeholders, through establishing consistent outreach and dialogue for feedback, to enhance the engagement in the mission of the Department;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD268E0E008FF45BDA2E277B8ED972974"><enum>(F)</enum><text>publish educational materials for enhancing stakeholder understanding of activities and procedures of the Department in accessible formats and venues, with clear and easy to understand wording, consistent with Department policy, in multiple languages;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H13E77F5EC680433EA7E8AAEE07097203"><enum>(G)</enum><text>consult with and make recommendations to the Secretary relating to the appointment of stakeholders who may be appropriate for roles in advisory roadway safety committees, in accordance with <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/10">chapter 10</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE9464723F4D647CCBEA810A45E2990C4"><enum>(H)</enum><text>meet not less frequently than once per quarter with the Secretary to highlight issues, make recommendations for resolving problems and alleviating stakeholder roadway safety concerns, and summarize input from stakeholders on proposed roadway safety initiatives;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCA5715F6F83744E6B6EF4ABE637043A1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>refer questions to the Office of the General Counsel or the Office of the Under Secretary of Transportation for Policy, as appropriate;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H03BEB57C901F4972B7E3ACCBB7E66447"><enum>(J)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">work collaboratively with other offices in the Department that are working to educate and communicate with stakeholders on roadway safety issues; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC06FDBBD7D9A42AB9968CB4F80DED970"><enum>(K)</enum><text>perform such other duties as may be determined by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6009E8C579B944DE821C4848B251AF56"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitations</header><text>The National Roadway Safety Advocate may not—</text><subparagraph id="H1B513FE2FD2A4F8C89C568B71EC3250B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide legal notice, counsel, or determinations of any kind;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9AC4DFFED60A4399AA1D5991DBD695BB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>set or delay any agency deadlines;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDEBA8603EF5248E9B1964F91755AE2F4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>make Department decisions;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H623D4372CCE2443295E54391EBE6B435"><enum>(D)</enum><text>create or authorize Department policies, priorities, or activities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H60D1A60DA46B4F22BF9AFB2CBFCFB140"><enum>(E)</enum><text>modify or interfere with any laws, regulations, related policies, practices, or procedures followed or enforced by the Department;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDA875C48BC9E405C9A7AE276B2911BE6"><enum>(F)</enum><text>prevent other Department staff from working directly with stakeholders;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9EC19DB84BB74B7783FB01351C2E8CF5"><enum>(G)</enum><text>disclose or discuss any enforcement matters that are under investigation, in litigation, or the subject of a civil penalty investigation or any other pre-litigation or litigation proceeding; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8DCD983F0DD1410189957FF580616301"><enum>(H)</enum><text>disclose or discuss any human resource matters with individuals outside of the Department.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H72EC20E70CEA4839A20DF45B27244848"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report to Office of the Under Secretary of Transportation for Policy</header><text>The National Roadway Safety Advocate shall report within the Office of the Under Secretary of Transportation for Policy of the Department.</text></subsection><subsection id="H38DFFFF23C194FBD857D6C9A986A5C06"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Support</header><text>The Office of the Under Secretary of Transportation for Policy of the Department shall provide necessary funding, logistics, and administrative support to the National Roadway Safety Advocate as necessary.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA3793809F98B46A6B0F180DA6F44912C"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Access to documents</header><text>The Department shall ensure that the National Roadway Safety Advocate has full and timely access to the documents of the Department, as necessary, to carry out the functions of the National Roadway Safety Advocate. </text></subsection><subsection id="H6ECE367878AE4D32B9BB0EC29030E739"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Reports required</header><paragraph id="H98231039C43E4D6CA7D25ED4C7E65B5D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>Not later than November 15 of each year, the National Roadway Safety Advocate shall submit to the Secretary an annual report—</text><subparagraph id="HEA604D6CE9F842A7A20E2D385500BC0A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>highlighting systemic issues relating to roadway safety based on information provided by stakeholders; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE9475283C32349A0B44830C29FC2C6F1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>making recommendations on how to remedy the issues highlighted under subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD1B78EFA89704B94B1075982CA3033DF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additional reports</header><text>In addition to the annual report required under paragraph (1), the National Roadway Safety Advocate may submit to the Secretary such additional reports, as determined necessary by the National Roadway Safety Advocate, in accordance with the requirements of that paragraph.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

