<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H73E36602C0034B44A9B5EC1F2BB14350" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5170 IH: Cable Access for Broadband and Local Economic Leadership Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5170</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250908">September 8, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001306">Mr. Balderson</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to preserve cable franchising authority, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB6AFF67B9D9949E68CE55C119C968EAB" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H7402FABB80A6430890199BDDE6601A67" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Cable Access for Broadband and Local Economic Leadership Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>CABLE Leadership Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HB7D2D0B03E244AE6B021E18C70737042"><enum>2.</enum><header>Request for new franchise</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 621 of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/541">47 U.S.C. 541</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="H430351CBDEE14B47B429E0EA5E0BF846" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="HFACD5E2D32D34EADB749C72387B1237C"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Timing of decision on request for franchise</header> 
<paragraph id="H1648C431D9944CCE8F825D4441386CAB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date on which a franchising authority receives a complete request for the grant of a franchise (other than a renewal thereof), the franchising authority shall approve or deny such request.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H268AFFA3AD934E7C852499DC428AD939"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Deemed grant of new franchise</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the franchising authority does not approve or deny a request under paragraph (1) by the day after the date on which the time period ends under such paragraph, such request shall be deemed granted on such day.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDD98D8F40D03419BB1A647BA2591BCDF" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>Notwithstanding any provision of this title, the timeframe under paragraph (1) shall apply collectively to all proceedings required by a franchising authority for the approval of the request.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCD4BBDAC0B6547988BB5799875BE5D9A" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>No tolling</header><text>The timeframe under paragraph (1) may not be tolled by any moratorium, whether express or de facto, imposed by a franchising authority on the consideration of any request for a franchise.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF25641AB81594DF3A6BA4DFE15C04CCC" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Written decision and record</header><text>Any decision by a franchising authority to deny a complete request for a franchise shall be—</text> <subparagraph id="H20ED072A64504E679EDC2BE4740B046C" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in writing;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5CA1E312E4E04D5CAB937BB0647A954D" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>supported by substantial evidence contained in a written record; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3E518EC166944CCAB08E00DD977B7FC6" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">publicly released, and provided to the requesting party, on the same day such decision is made.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA58231451DFA4712AF30091466CC065C"><enum>(6)</enum><header>When request considered complete; received</header> 
<subparagraph id="HC47E4F7E72264FA2AA966530EB2C5E38"><enum>(A)</enum><header>When request considered complete</header> 
<clause id="H66D85E507DC24E24BF3D4ABC42706824" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For the purposes of this subsection, a request to a franchising authority shall be considered complete if the requesting party—</text> <subclause id="H3580BEF00FB744BCA258E79630916461" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has taken the first procedural step within the control of the requesting party that the franchising authority requires as part of the process of the franchising authority for reviewing requests related to franchises; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HE47EFA72DF8B4434AE1AB8D100085F4D" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has not received a written notice from the franchising authority within 30 days after the date on which the request is received by the franchising authority—</text> <item id="HF5314EE0635943DA8DB5083239447B64"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>stating that all the information (including any form or other document) required by the franchising authority to be submitted for the request to be considered complete, has not been submitted;</text></item> 
<item id="H2BE14299658548D5ACC48FA491140225"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>identifying the information required to be submitted that was not submitted; and</text></item> <item id="H0F6879ED41814982842FC5B30CC9FD53"><enum>(cc)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that includes a citation to a specific provision of a publicly available rule, regulation, or standard issued by the franchising authority requiring that the information be submitted with such a request.</text></item></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H20640135964A46E79CAD19DB4A518F55"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this subparagraph, the term <term>the date on which the request is received by the franchising authority</term> means—</text> <subclause id="HAD76B5A05F5A4FAFABEB708535CD643E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in the case of a request submitted electronically, the date on which the request is transmitted;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HFDB79581CEFF4BE198F8DFE5D0F7B38F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in the case of a request submitted in person, the date on which the request is delivered to the individual or at the location specified by franchising authority for in-person submission; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H5A71A849147C419BB691496B19F71EFC"><enum>(III)</enum><text>in the case of a request submitted in any other manner, the date determined under regulations promulgated by the Commission for the manner in which the request is submitted.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB6D51016A0AD4896914AA13B955583D3" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>When complete request considered received</header><text>For the purposes of this subsection, a complete request shall be considered received—</text> <clause id="H7580FE44DDC24A00BA64FA06AF2E7CFE" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>except as provided in clause (ii), on the date on which the requesting party submits to the franchising authority all information (including any form or other document) required by the franchising authority to be submitted for the request to be considered complete; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H2EC777F48CE34F3EB0F74D679C1185AF" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a request with respect to which all such information is not submitted and that is considered complete under subparagraph (A)(i) because the requesting party has not received a written notice from the franchising authority within the period described in such subparagraph, on the day after the last day of such period.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> </legis-body></bill>

