<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ARP25059-PSK-72-S31"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>103 S476 IS: White Oak Resiliency Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 476</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250206" legis-day="20250205">February 6 (legislative day, February 5), 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S174">Mr. McConnell</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S327">Mr. Warner</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAF00">Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To direct the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Interior to carry out activities to provide for white oak restoration, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="id045D4C3FD4F141BEAD1240F6ED680968"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>White Oak Resiliency Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida820a662898d40079797f55a0ff3d013"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definition of land-grant college or university</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <term>land-grant college or university</term> means—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id94DD826CACC041D48C1638761B05F434"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an 1862 Institution (as defined in section 2 of the Agricultural Research, Extension, and Education Reform Act of 1998 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/7601">7 U.S.C. 7601</external-xref>));</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id650D0E8C3D9B4E39B0C09B429E172436"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an 1890 Institution (as defined in that section); and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id061BF01E6F22489D97E350981B6C26A9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a 1994 Institution (as defined in section 532 of the Equity in Educational Land-Grant Status Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/301">7 U.S.C. 301</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/103/382">Public Law 103–382</external-xref>)).</text></paragraph></section><section id="idc32acf7b738d4e558edea16fe662b50d"><enum>3.</enum><header>White Oak Restoration Initiative Coalition</header><subsection id="id92de0efb4ac342c5b1d26526d6cdd85e"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is established the White Oak Restoration Initiative Coalition (referred to in this section as the <term>Coalition</term>)—</text><paragraph id="ide19e7edf27464ecda3474acb6dd8d865"><enum>(1)</enum><text>as a voluntary collaborative group of public, State, private, and nongovernmental organizations to carry out the duties described in subsection (b); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb77e45efbe414f0591825e8fe3c2e673"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in accordance with the charter entitled <quote>White Oak Initiative Coalition Charter</quote> adopted by the White Oak Initiative Board of Directors on March 21, 2023 (or a successor charter).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idbd3ec4b222264007bae65105f8d8dd13"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>In addition to the duties specified in the charter described in subsection (a)(2), the duties of the Coalition are—</text><paragraph id="id717a9b9665764faaba7b21a748d5fec8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to coordinate public, State, local, private, and nongovernmental restoration of white oak in the United States; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddf9bd3cac1644183addb9523b701da49"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to make program and policy recommendations with respect to—</text><subparagraph id="id5e6125305d0f4e00b123a91e807df46e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>changes necessary to address Federal and State policies that impede activities to improve the health, resiliency, and natural regeneration of white oak;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id329911228fc842beaf7083106d365799"><enum>(B)</enum><text>adopting or modifying Federal and State policies to increase the pace and scale of white oak regeneration and resiliency of white oak;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddd7f84d593b74de88b9e4e73cdd3e0fc"><enum>(C)</enum><text>options to enhance communication, coordination, and collaboration between forest land owners, particularly for cross-boundary projects, to improve the health, resiliency, and natural regeneration of white oak;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6e50ce227e2647b1b938cb162a9ad97d"><enum>(D)</enum><text>research gaps that should be addressed to improve the best available science on white oak;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf0aab4ba3f144fe4b95c48f00abd335b"><enum>(E)</enum><text>outreach to forest landowners with white oak or white oak regeneration potential; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id16f5c36a6ccc477cb37e5108611ad7bf"><enum>(F)</enum><text>options and policies necessary to improve the quality and quantity of white oak in tree nurseries; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9f0838d84b3e49bc88d1c175399a03cd"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to submit the report under subsection (c).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="id474df4cd31184501ac5886f544d13fe2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Coalition shall submit to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources and the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives a report describing the activities of the Coalition during the period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act, including the recommendations described in subsection (b)(2).</text></subsection><subsection id="id60e45cb49e924b0cb0a8c1f6520fd5e8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Administrative support, technical services, and staff support</header><text>The Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture shall make such personnel available to the Coalition for administrative support, technical services, and development and dissemination of educational materials as the Secretaries determine to be necessary to carry out this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="id692a6680f67b4c3a86655b1d48f3817e"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Nonapplicability of Federal Advisory Committee Act</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/10">Chapter 10</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, shall not apply to the Coalition.</text></subsection><subsection id="id7b9ef968b11d4b139904bf70c8b671b8"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Private funding of white oak restoration projects</header><text>The Secretary of Agriculture may make available funds to the Coalition to carry out this section from funds in the accounts established pursuant to section 1241(f) of the Food Security Act of 1985 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/3841">16 U.S.C. 3841(f)</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section><section id="id7eff5d4240a04d3cbfe4f3e8bd9a17a4"><enum>4.</enum><header>Forest Service pilot program</header><subsection id="ida28c025d815b496d93b8ca6ad32da583"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Chief of the Forest Service, shall establish and carry out 5 pilot projects in national forests to restore white oak in those national forests through white oak restoration and natural regeneration practices.</text></subsection><subsection id="id80bc6255c82d4b5dbb2058c9c7e84a62"><enum>(b)</enum><header>National forests reserved or withdrawn from the public domain</header><text>At least 3 pilot projects required under subsection (a) shall be carried out in national forests reserved or withdrawn from the public domain.</text></subsection><subsection id="idac7ad62886454434a3db7a72d37a8a25"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authority To enter into cooperative agreements</header><text>The Secretary of Agriculture may enter into cooperative agreements to carry out the pilot projects required under subsection (a).</text></subsection></section><section id="idce5da7d1d30e448b9d4baba10dcd6b1d"><enum>5.</enum><header>Department of the Interior white oak assessment and pilot projects</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0c1144830acb4bc4ba336f166f2f3aaf"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8bf9e089651e44e693fd02b006bc7533"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered land</header><text>The term <quote>covered land</quote> means land under the administrative jurisdiction of the Secretary, including a unit of the National Wildlife Refuge System and abandoned mine land.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddb82114cc3de445c83637fba4e8b43ee"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id5ddad629df3e405a88b64b3283b5ea05"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Assessment</header><paragraph id="id9ea0c09cc1d6446e95752bb74c7d6c40"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>As soon as practicable after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall carry out an assessment of covered land to evaluate—</text><subparagraph id="id47d8ce6bf5c746c7bd5312f25d010786"><enum>(A)</enum><text>whether white oak is present on the covered land; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id24ef1168c16c408ea8076c49b9e5bd77"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the potential to restore white oak forests on the covered land.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id025e05b30ec94626b6f5e1d23b458d4b"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of information</header><text>In carrying out the assessment under paragraph (1), the Secretary may use information from sources other than the Department of the Interior, including information from—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7f2d3a9d99984a3db8e0d0e49a4d19fc"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the White Oak Restoration Initiative Coalition established by section 3(a); and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9f24905831024c4cafd771c8dce6f6fa"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Chief of the Forest Service.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idd0055b3e0bb54fed83b16e20095c27b1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress, and make publicly available on the website of the Department of the Interior, a report describing the results of the assessment carried out under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id9659299e918f4db5b750cde9c75ba67f"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Pilot projects</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6a08fa0db245459f8c271be8d635061d"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As soon as practicable after the date on which the Secretary submits the report required under subsection (b)(3), the Secretary shall establish and carry out 5 pilot projects on various areas of covered land, the purpose of which is to restore and naturally regenerate white oak.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id08027cdd80174210a24f4459fb390b6f"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authority to enter into cooperative agreements</header><text>The Secretary may enter into cooperative agreements to carry out the pilot projects required under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H30E10EEA3DF94D0AA240387206411176"><enum>6.</enum><header>White oak regeneration and upland oak habitat</header><subsection id="HCCFD6D2EA9334572A4662A035D8652E0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Agriculture (referred to in this section as the <term>Secretary</term>) shall establish a nonregulatory program to be known as the <quote>White Oak and Upland Oak Habitat Regeneration Program</quote> (referred to in this section as the <term>Program</term>).</text></subsection><subsection id="H373BA891037A4682834ED61D8FAE6297"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the Program, the Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="HDBBE9964E1944971BB07C2F7A18BE0B7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">draw upon the best available science and management plans for species of white oak to identify, prioritize, and implement restoration and conservation activities that will improve the growth of white oak within the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7177543675B6498D9DE2369FB2CE0501"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">collaborate and coordinate with the White Oak Restoration Initiative Coalition to prioritize white oak restoration initiatives;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H515D9BB010C444DD89AA68F0AE560EE1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">adopt a white oak restoration strategy that—</text><subparagraph id="HFD16BE65543748D9BAE2C19838B1A1A5"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supports the implementation of a shared set of science-based restoration and conservation activities developed in accordance with paragraph (1);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0D9EC5F46D13423A9ECD30FF56288F2D"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">targets cost-effective projects with measurable results; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H48A073E8E5FE42609FB45ECFF56F18FE"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">maximizes restoration outcomes with no net gain of Federal full-time equivalent employees; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H931C0DC7BA30416D8101FE7E4B9E43B6"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish the voluntary grant and technical assistance program in accordance with subsection (e).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2241D19A94904C5C893153A5039A3239"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In establishing the Program, the Secretary, acting through the Chief of the Forest Service, shall consult with—</text><paragraph id="H9FC2C87474B24236A3718623A2966F0B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the heads of Federal agencies, including—</text><subparagraph id="H5FCEB4744E564DBD8A1180F583CBB886"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5D7279C358F84514BCDF8B0274CF090A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Chief of the Natural Resources Conservation Service; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA1801153FF804F5B8B8632BBABADE14D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Governor of each State in which restoration efforts will be carried out pursuant to the Program.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7D7CD32FDDC549439056E831A135E96D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of the Program include—</text><paragraph id="H340C9B1813FC49318DEAAE60D95D6AD9"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">coordinating restoration and conservation activities among Federal, State, local, and Tribal entities and conservation partners to address white oak restoration priorities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H06FA2D70F2E44AFB944DB6A778148CB7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>improving and regenerating white oak and upland oak forests and the wildlife habitat such forests provide;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H17852CB0A1AB4B78AF81E6637CC0231C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>carrying out coordinated restoration and conservation activities that lead to the increased growth of species of white oak in native white oak regions on Federal, State, Tribal, and private land;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H39A9078D4E1C4EC5AC371BD4611014C1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>facilitating strategic planning to maximize the resilience of white oak systems and habitats under changing climate conditions;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB1F32EAF32064F91B8326EF7779BCFCF"><enum>(5)</enum><text>engaging the public through outreach, education, and citizen involvement to increase capacity and support for coordinated restoration and conservation activities for species of white oak; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC4B2489A34614B2A9C20B4C5BA3B2D97"><enum>(6)</enum><text>increasing scientific capacity to support the planning, monitoring, and research activities necessary to carry out such coordinated restoration and conservation activities.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8BD9CA88CF0144B08F9E2156D436AE3B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Grants and assistance</header><paragraph id="HF59B3DC22E7240C8861EBA5DFE8A2F07"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To the extent that funds are available to carry out this section, the Secretary shall establish a voluntary grant and technical assistance program (referred to in this subsection as the <term>grant program</term>) to achieve the purposes of the Program described in subsection (d).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7A354958202E40BAABC88836E4845419"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administration</header><subparagraph id="H42E888199318429CBD0E4BE559F95A9E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall enter into a cooperative agreement with the National Fish and Wildlife Foundation (referred to in this subsection as the <term>Foundation</term>) to manage and administer the grant program.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H23BF6087DD474B4E94C27D931C96A0AA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After the Secretary enters into a cooperative agreement with the Foundation under subparagraph (A), the Foundation shall—</text><clause id="HFC8DF717396B41AB9DA5F73AC33F0F62"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for each fiscal year, receive amounts to carry out this subsection in an advance payment of the entire amount on October 1, or as soon as practicable thereafter, of that fiscal year;</text></clause><clause id="H66DFB5B9C8A94DB4B387C5DCEF588EAF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">invest and reinvest such amounts for the benefit of the grant program; and</text></clause><clause id="H65CE619106014E6FA6BBEC4E09AF3F02"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">otherwise administer the grant program to support partnerships between the public and private sectors in accordance with this section.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1CBC0D5F37874E90B9F7DC73E7314DC9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Application of National Fish and Wildlife Foundation Establishment Act</header><text>Amounts received by the Foundation to carry out the grant program shall be subject to the National Fish and Wildlife Foundation Establishment Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/3701">16 U.S.C. 3701 et seq.</external-xref>), excluding section 10(a) of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/3709">16 U.S.C. 3709(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id8b381c2d8a154ae7952b0ecfd2fde21a"><enum>7.</enum><header>White oak tree nursery shortages</header><subsection id="id59ade47a014e436c950f1ad15f1b5f63"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Chief of the Forest Service, shall develop and implement a national strategy to increase the capacity of Federal, State, Tribal, and private tree nurseries to address the nationwide shortage of white oak tree seedlings.</text></subsection><subsection id="idb717bd9f37714ce892c6c9b2b018ab70"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The strategy required under subsection (a) shall—</text><paragraph id="id029c595a8ee242888eb5f745c92862d8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>be based on the best available science and data, as established by land-grant colleges and universities that have demonstrated—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf0bbd405665e42b884b9928d143f02c0"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">scientific expertise relating to white oak;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd5568c99b89f41b5b957d799376b9008"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the ability to rapidly transfer technologies to the stave industry;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide80da2f5cab74c61993f8fe36f2fbf21"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">geographic proximity to concentrated areas of white oak; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6ef31bec417c4342bc98760a3b963df8"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">support for regional economic development; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idcb63236ffbef4e7f8aa4d066f4cb0a58"><enum>(2)</enum><text>identify and address—</text><subparagraph id="idecfbf3e0eb47449291130f3ba12c9689"><enum>(A)</enum><text>regional shortages of bareroot and container white oak tree seedlings;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5e6f9658f84e4c30b01b00783ec70d9d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>regional white oak reforestation opportunities and the seedling supply necessary to fulfill those opportunities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9875823e71264fe6a700aa9dac6afbf5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>opportunities to enhance white oak seedling diversity and close gaps in seed inventories; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd0966710296f41da8d2ec1cff7b1169d"><enum>(D)</enum><text>barriers to expanding, enhancing, or creating new infrastructure to increase nursery capacity for white oak tree seedlings.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idc6ce2e05493d48d08c26d45f82b3a158"><enum>8.</enum><header>White oak research</header><subsection id="idee7f03df64fb46a7b77f756d5639969f"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Research</header><text>The Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Chief of the Forest Service, shall enter into a memorandum of understanding with a land-grant college or university to conduct research on—</text><paragraph id="id82f6f46a248046cbbafd05b010c33f98"><enum>(1)</enum><text>white oak genes with resistance and stress tolerance;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id91c49e42540546e0a3e80e76c994664b"><enum>(2)</enum><text>white oak trees that exhibit vigor for the purpose of increasing survival and growth;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id142ddfa82109425390fd8c7dcdfc6070"><enum>(3)</enum><text>establishing a diverse white oak seed bank capable of responding to stressors;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf3cb3223b6774eae993401e6c13581f4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>providing a sustainable supply of white oak seedlings and genetic resources;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3d698d4f60da49eba1ca84113d655f01"><enum>(5)</enum><text>reforestation of white oak through natural and artificial regeneration; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id59bdbc9a866b49e6ae2b06db58ed7b79"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the best methods for white oak reforestation on abandoned mine land sites.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4e9b434dc5da4ad0922144243d683dd4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In carrying out the research under subsection (a), the land-grant college or university may consult with such States, nonprofit organizations, institutions of higher education, and other scientific bodies as the land-grant college or university determines to be appropriate.</text></subsection></section><section id="idf82fdb8b68554e86804333d156b4201d"><enum>9.</enum><header>National Institute of Food and Agriculture</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id415cd9dd555449bf84040c76d974d256"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Partnerships</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4d1818e42dd04b6a9bc1cd611d90504f"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>The Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Director of the National Institute of Food and Agriculture, shall enter into a partnership with an eligible entity described in paragraph (2) to conduct research on improving white oak species resiliency, health, and preservation, including research on—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5bc677076525432d8547d533a419138d"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">population-scale sequencing;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id604558a44ac04a508e4312905f2270e6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>stress response traits;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1f58973b42ad46bba96319aad0343982"><enum>(C)</enum><text>seedling physiology and performance; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id789d9a52fbbf4f61bf201eb36bdccccf"><enum>(D)</enum><text>white oak product development.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide0b3e75a4e3e4f10886fcdca91d9e59d"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity referred to in paragraph (1) is a land-grant college or university that has demonstrated—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id580ADE4EFA6D48CAB104563115781C1B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">scientific expertise relating to white oak;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id72BE76803B0446BB832B16FD5E2B7941"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the ability to rapidly transfer technologies to the stave industry;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idC58114FE2C1443469AF0A3403A5A67FB"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">geographic proximity to concentrated areas of white oak; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5780B4FB58804C379727BF6D61A65A32"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">support for regional economic development.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida1c12654c00d4bd49678b99ff3dd054e"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Priorities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Director of the National Institute of Food and Agriculture, shall prioritize research relating to the resistance of white oak to disease, pest, heat, and drought in cultivated, new, and old-growth white oak timber stands.</text></subsection></section><section id="idf74e71279d384f75a0e06acb1b992271"><enum>10.</enum><header>Natural Resources Conservation Service initiative</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Chief of the Natural Resources Conservation Service, shall establish an initiative on white oak—</text><paragraph id="idd0fd5f08751b4499af78d3e8d29fae2b"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to re-establish white oak forests where appropriate;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id03fcea82644742faa9fcf5782e28e207"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to improve the management of existing white oak forests to foster natural regeneration of white oak; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idccdab1f7f0164255b5cdcc146ae46d69"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to provide technical assistance to private landowners to re-establish, improve management of, and naturally regenerate white oak.</text></paragraph></section><section id="idafa60b26d64e440caf7067739934e295"><enum>11.</enum><header>Authorities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">To the maximum extent practicable, to carry out activities under this Act and the amendments made by this Act, the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture shall use the authorities provided under this Act and those amendments, in combination with authorities under other provisions of law, including—</text><paragraph id="idb67a7e34e521400c88e65bc38dc4f25b"><enum>(1)</enum><text>good neighbor agreements under section 8206 of the Agricultural Act of 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/2113a">16 U.S.C. 2113a</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7a2f59c3298845f387444fd8cf6a82a9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>stewardship contracting projects under section 604 of the Healthy Forests Restoration Act of 2003 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/6591c">16 U.S.C. 6591c</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

