<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H49F15E3EF2BE4546B2A1157752DE0A93" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4752 IH: Reducing Hereditary Cancer Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4752</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250723">July 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="M001215">Mrs. Miller-Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001216">Ms. Schrier</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001260">Mr. Buchanan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide hereditary cancer genetic testing for individuals with a history of a hereditary cancer gene mutation in a blood relative or a personal or ancestral history suspicious for hereditary cancer, and to provide coverage of certain cancer screenings or preventive surgeries that would reduce the risk for individuals with a germline (inherited) mutation associated with a high risk of developing a preventable cancer.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9FA83582C29945D789172B3BFDE1D1F5" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HE5FEBCBE725E4D12BF82DBACA84C6B94" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Reducing Hereditary Cancer Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H02C9235CB2CB452C8B8947BB20F3AF8F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Hereditary cancer genetic testing of individuals with a family history of a hereditary cancer gene mutation or personal or family history suspicious for hereditary cancer</header> <subsection id="HC9C6FF2DA2884948B2C375BAA7BB5A29"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Coverage</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1861 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="H8AC5201915524658886E9AE56B836BB3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (s)(2)—</text> <subparagraph id="HCC4D3D4F198244DD8A91AC0DFA9E7AD8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of subparagraph (II);</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE798E4A554524520BC75CADFAA2E1A57"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking the period and inserting <quote>; and</quote> at the end of subparagraph (JJ); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE9D8745504D54834AC4110F9F5B6868F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (JJ) the following new subparagraph:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H5F2D0D13A38D46DCA3CCCE51DE68D6BC" display-inline="no-display-inline">
<subparagraph id="HA5E4268462A14B86A394C3F8C78C9E68"><enum>(KK)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of an individual with a personal or family history of a hereditary cancer gene mutation or a personal or family history suspicious for hereditary cancer, germline mutation testing.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3FCCD5BE93034007ADB389E3799DD1FA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H96C61FF1C6954B129F8786D5B9B04144" display-inline="no-display-inline">
<subsection id="H392C8970AE8C47D6A3BB2DFFB62AE97C"><enum>(nnn)</enum><header>Germline mutation testing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>germline mutation testing</quote> means genetic testing for germline mutations that is in accordance with evidence-based, clinical practice guidelines specifically addressing genetic testing, screening, and management of individuals with inherited mutations associated with increased cancer risk that—</text> <paragraph id="H48B84BB5458C460A8702FE842A66F8F3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>have been developed by a nationally recognized oncology professional organization, including the National Comprehensive Cancer Network, the American Society of Clinical Oncology, the Society of Gynecologic Oncology, or any other oncology professional organization specified by a medicare administrative contractor with a contract under section 1874A; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA13BAC76188F44B3A4C791C68FC5051B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the case of conflicting guidelines developed by more than one nationally recognized oncology professional organization, the least restrictive of such guidelines, as determined by such a medicare administrative contractor.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE629076B0C5642998CBAEBF459873AF0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Frequency</header><text>Section 1862(a)(1) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395y">42 U.S.C. 1395y(a)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="H23DCECA6CBF64B02993405A51E1CF949"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of subparagraph (O);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD38BD3A2175949FBB29DFC03B4C1B560"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding <quote>and</quote> at the end of subparagraph (P); and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HAE33A6E2AE7A4DA89B8C941D023E147C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block id="H9C383B223D344C22AEAFE0690FD0B82E" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H855E8985D20F466AAF6D449B82863191"><enum>(Q)</enum><text>in the case of germline mutation testing as defined in section 1861(lll), which is performed more than once with respect to an individual described in such section;</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H4E1CB2AA581348E4BB856BAA79A37E50"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to testing furnished on or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HDCC52650A2B5435180511B5519816BA0"><enum>3.</enum><header>Coverage of certain preventive surgeries</header> <subsection id="H90A52D9A7F074EC7B6CF4A15ED26CF34"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1862 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395y">42 U.S.C. 1395y</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
<quoted-block id="H11C5DA30C62D49759D571F0E4D26131E" style="OLC">
<subsection id="H588D26BF4A2D40AD9E7B121E1CBFFE1D">
            <enum>(p)</enum>
            <header>Coverage of certain risk-Reducing surgeries</header>
 <text>In the case of an individual described in section 1861(s)(2)(II) for whom, based on evidence-based, clinical practice guidelines described in section 1861(lll), surgery would reduce the risk of developing cancer, such risk-reducing surgery shall be considered reasonable and necessary for treatment of illness under subsection (a)(1)(A).</text>
          </subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection>
<subsection id="H0E0DBAD1FC4747DA974BA01CAB9AC42B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by subsection (a) shall apply to items and services furnished on or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H6778D75A7C314904995F024DA3F60F9B"><enum>4.</enum><header>Coverage of evidence-based screenings for individuals with a hereditary cancer gene mutation</header> <subsection id="HFE5743CEE160428CA91D30FD5CE27255"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1862 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395y">42 U.S.C. 1395y</external-xref>), as amended by section 3, is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
<quoted-block id="HEED82582831C4E11B57D23BCE79CCA6D" style="OLC">
<subsection id="HE08C6BAC12BE4D299977130155B3631E">
            <enum>(q)</enum>
            <header>Coverage of evidence-Based screenings for individuals with a hereditary cancer
              gene mutation</header>
 <text>In the case of an individual who is determined pursuant to genetic testing to have a hereditary cancer (germline) gene mutation, the Secretary shall increase any frequency limitations (or other limitations on coverage otherwise applicable under this title) for any evidence-based screenings furnished to such individual, to be in compliance with evidence-based, clinical practice guidelines described in section 1861(lll), or as determined appropriate by the Secretary, but not less frequently than on an annual basis. For the purposes of this subsection, evidence-based screenings shall include screening mammography, breast screening MRI, colonoscopy, PSA testing, and any additional evidence-based screening modalities appropriate for high-risk individuals as recommended by such guidelines.</text>
          </subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection>
<subsection id="H447B86B003804645A1224D627333F551"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment for screening mammography</header><text>Section 1834(c)(2)(A) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395m">42 U.S.C. 1395m(c)(2)(A)</external-xref>) is amended, in the matter preceding clause (i), by striking <quote>subparagraph (B)</quote> and inserting <quote>subparagraph (B) and section 1862(q)</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H96C35A0B23BA4BC9AD613545B15B3B1D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to items and services furnished on or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

