<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H635443CC80D448F88A643965AADA80A6" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5692 IH: Marine Energy Technologies Acceleration Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5692</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251006">October 6, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Natural Resources</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and Workforce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To accelerate the competitiveness of the United States in marine energy technologies, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HECBE7FADDBE2447FA4E55C8B3C57CF19" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HEEC64CFD1E5748B19AF7F520F7C70211" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Marine Energy Technologies Acceleration Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H607A4B9D059D494480FCCA038FDB2025"><enum>2.</enum><header>Marine energy acceleration</header> <subsection id="HB237B05BEE8E4A6AB09A0FD585AE7924"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H07F79FA74E1447B38C9AE8AF962E9187"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Fund</header><text>The term <term>Fund</term> means the Marine Energy Acceleration Fund established under subsection (b).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC8DAFC4A47EE4DB8B6E2433076996E6A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Marine energy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>marine energy</term> has the meaning given that term in section 632 of the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/17211">42 U.S.C. 17211</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H88D59ED7F37B4DC8A4F862B0D6052104"><enum>(3)</enum><header>National Marine Energy Centers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>National Marine Energy Centers</term> means the National Marine Energy Centers referred to in, or established under, section 636 of the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/17215">42 U.S.C. 17215</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H10CC8CA76716475C8A65734C76A9ABF5"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Energy.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1865310005FA422C9DA81387C1C9DE7E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Marine energy acceleration fund</header> 
<paragraph id="H842F3BAEFD85467A83A38427BF75AAF3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a fund, to be known as the <quote>Marine Energy Acceleration Fund</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFC9633649F004551AB62ED4FF7487D77"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Fund $1,000,000,000, to remain available until expended.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HBEBC81A458BA4135BFEFD9434A9BBAB6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Marine energy demonstration projects</header> 
<paragraph id="HC4EA55DD6B0F4A87A55E261F5E59A73E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall conduct competitive solicitations for not fewer than twenty marine energy demonstration projects that export power to microgrids, community grids, or utility-scale grids.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE9D5004740FA4D79AF26F10885AB3224"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>In carrying out this subsection, the Secretary may coordinate with the National Marine Energy Centers and other entities with proven technical expertise to support marine energy demonstration projects.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB1D0C42F70C94E47A1C457F31A7543A6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In carrying out this subsection, the Secretary shall prioritize—</text> <subparagraph id="HA30BD8C3E1BC45649D2172AE553BB7E3"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">projects that integrate marine energy technologies with existing onshore and offshore transmission infrastructure, nearshore and offshore marine structures, or projects with all necessary local, State, and Federal licenses or permits in place;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4D0BE87B8B9648E088853EF5CF17CDFA"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">open water prototype testing;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF7E1984F983349C496B1CBE89CBA38CF"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">projects that support energy resilience and economic opportunities for rural communities, remote areas, Tribal communities, and low-income communities; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFAE2F11E708545A58254A627EB725170"><enum>(D)</enum><text>projects that power ocean-based scientific research and education, and support workforce development, national security, and commercial activities limited by the availability of existing energy resources.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7F02F276666C43688E27E7FCEF6C2229"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Funds</header><text>Of the amounts in the Fund, $600,000,000 shall be available to the Secretary to carry out this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H44146B87D1A94244B5C6652935494348"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Advancement of marine energy technologies</header> 
<paragraph id="H652A017D05B74A52B3D340FCB27016F9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall conduct competitive solicitations for—</text> <subparagraph id="H7514B1A6A9A34A7AB051154C2A6D0DE4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>research and development projects to advance marine energy technologies; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H281F793C76D24030BC284169827459A0"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">upgrades to research and development facilities that advance marine energy technologies.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H57B5305E971C4B62A752F80C640DF99F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out this subsection, the Secretary may coordinate with industry, the National Marine Energy Centers, non-profits, entities with all necessary local, State, and Federal licenses or permits in place, National Laboratories, Federal agencies involved in the development of marine energy technology, other existing marine energy research and development programs, and other entities with proven technical expertise to support marine energy research, development, and demonstration.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE2787C3B85A548DEAEBD02AF1B9DA7CD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In carrying out this subsection, the Secretary shall prioritize research and development projects that—</text> <subparagraph id="H7D93DDDEBD9840F8A8DAFE84C19B37D1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>rapidly design, fabricate, and test marine energy systems, subsystems, components, controls, domestic manufacturing, and materials to improve efficiency, reduce costs, reduce environmental impacts, increase power production, and improve reliability at a variety of technology readiness levels that promote domestic manufacturing, a domestic supply chain, and energy independence;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H770EEDEA893F429387001098ADC15C06"><enum>(B)</enum><text>educate the public, policymakers, investors, educators, and other stakeholders about the potential for deployment of marine energy technologies, and identify the needs and concerns of local communities where marine energy projects may be placed; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBFC646A4D9C247889C01B7C93E1C6E4C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>support the development of technologies to monitor and mitigate impacts to marine and coastal ecosystems and communities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE611632B9C5B4996B371C138CF38B3EC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Funds</header><text>Of the amounts in the Fund—</text> <subparagraph id="H5B92755175DE434D9AFE8FDFFDA86102"><enum>(A)</enum><text>$230,000,000 shall be available to the Secretary for technology research and development activities under this subsection; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H04CB334DA985449581F694122AD16A0D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>$20,000,000 shall be available to the Secretary for providing marine energy and education activities under this subsection through the National Marine Energy Centers.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HA08D0344E08648FCAD18375E0A0A2E43"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Assessment of technical resource potential</header> <paragraph id="H21786B5A04AB42E28CD1CA7477139C3C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, in coordination with the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, the Bureau of Ocean Energy Management, and other agencies, as appropriate, shall assess the economic potential of marine energy at not fewer than 50 sites that previous agency assessments and modeling have determined to have significant marine energy potential.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC1C00B42FAD940189912FBD952275D49" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>In carrying out this subsection, the Secretary shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HBF56415EC8D74B2893DE82E0FE5A0E4D" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>develop, with input from interested parties, in-depth marine energy resource and conditions characterizations for each site;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H13D025FF31354BCDAA85C5D69519CB1A" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>deploy environmental monitoring technologies, tools, and data collection to understand and mitigate potential environmental risks, characterize potential conflicts with other users of the local marine resources, optimize marine energy devices and arrays, and reduce costs;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB95721F6FFDC4202861D5C22EFAA86D8" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>ensure, to the maximum extent practicable, that the sites are geographically distributed to assess marine energy resources and technologies in different regions of the United States;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H589C92D6783C4BB8BFF4A78CD7F657A0" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">where applicable, carry out technical resource assessments in coordination with Regional Ocean Partnerships of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration Office for Coastal Management; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H36246D7117234F56B68A438BED88E690" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">use such technical resource assessments to inform the location of the marine energy demonstration projects under subsection (c).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5251816A40264CE89B726AF677C4B680"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Data sharing</header><text>Data collected under this subsection shall be shared with public data repositories for use among regional ocean data portals and partnerships.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H558D671F92AA4270ADFCFFC11B331AF6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Funds</header><text>Of the amounts in the Fund, $50,000,000 shall be available to the Secretary to carry out this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HBD0B2446D3954319A46BD5E36E984BF0"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Improvement of permitting</header> 
<paragraph id="H08BE1DA8DE0046CBB031C28401C1989C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, in coordination with the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, the Bureau of Ocean Energy Management, the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, the Corps of Engineers, and other agencies as needed, shall convene a task force with the appropriate Federal and State agencies to prepare a report that—</text> <subparagraph id="HDB7D6ADA1FA44390B9ACBEA580906A8B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>describes any barriers under the jurisdiction of such agencies to the development of marine energy projects; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H13BF9AEA6FF646B18992E471C659D365"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provides recommendations on reducing such barriers, including identification and determination of opportunities to improve the regulatory process associated with the authorities required to deploy and license marine energy projects, consistent with the National Environmental Policy Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB642CFC3ECD04974A846D873C093580D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The task force convened under paragraph (1) shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H3C5527F46F0C4BC198170A7AE7B0DCDA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>develop recommendations for efficient permitting processes that reduce the time, cost, and uncertainty for marine energy projects, consistent with the National Environmental Policy Act;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3F82F189875E457B9858901EAA9F9A36"><enum>(B)</enum><text>determine whether additional staff are required to be hired and trained at the appropriate Federal agencies to process permits and conduct environmental reviews in a timely and efficient manner;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9F9C0681E5B343A295DA4E77A022B84E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>conduct outreach to stakeholders;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H38A7BAD3D539440CA83D6B7059315974"><enum>(D)</enum><text>facilitate Federal coordination with State permitting processes for marine energy projects, including by providing staff training for State and territory permitting agencies; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7D74493D39F04D0297B745C0B72EB126" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, submit to Congress the report prepared under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H42A5C960131E48AB938BB51CA9005D84"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Funds</header><text>Of the amounts in the Fund, to carry out this subsection—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD65896C6025143A38D8124D17029C0DC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>$5,000,000 shall be available to the Department of Energy;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8723CCE96A914A97A2563CB4FB579A7A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>$5,000,000 shall be available to the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE0294649AF2C4CDF99F429E80EDEE9A8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>$5,000,000 shall be available to the Bureau of Ocean Energy Management.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD125D65E70C24F35994E31105754B504"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Workforce</header> <paragraph id="HF3FEEE61E003438CB226A4B62894229B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Assessment</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall conduct a national assessment of the prospective marine energy workforce and hiring needs and the educational pathways and programs that would address those needs.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H339F2F919AD64AFDA178529EB096836B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Development programs</header><text>The Secretary shall launch workforce development programs based on the assessment conducted under paragraph (1), in partnership with the National Marine Energy Centers, the marine energy industry, institutions of higher education, labor unions, non-profits, and career and technical education programs.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3190B134D8EA44F584F720037075C229"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Priority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out this subsection, the Secretary shall prioritize workforce development programs in communities near the location of the marine energy demonstration projects under subsection (c).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H67DE08042E674D5D8971088A226C1B3E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Funds</header><text>Of the amounts in the Fund, $85,000,000 shall be available to the Secretary to carry out this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

