<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4252 IH: Extreme Risk Protection Order Expansion Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4252</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250630">June 30, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001112">Mr. Carbajal</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To support State, Tribal, and local efforts to remove access to firearms from individuals who are a danger to themselves or others pursuant to court orders for this purpose.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H121D5D21682E48D3A6BC2F7A5E04F739"><section section-type="section-one" id="H4E69AEC008024572BDF5785ECD2F7C1F"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Extreme Risk Protection Order Expansion Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HBC5BFE31ACE74EFE97A61F23FCED756B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Extreme risk protection order grant program</header><subsection id="H722CD24F8D9B467C8231CF4ABA05E635"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H0361E365C6EA44DAAF8CDD67F1308DED"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="HB5427AA340FE4DE19A9164A019B56090"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a State or Indian Tribe—</text><clause id="HD4AC59BB15264126AB3F521DDF35C3BA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that enacts legislation described in subsection (c);</text></clause><clause id="H938F87FEBFC84822A52A386D85227A89"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>with respect to which the Attorney General determines that the legislation described in clause (i) complies with the requirements under subsection (c)(1); and</text></clause><clause id="H4B478FDAD8824207A1D893272DB44C97"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>that certifies to the Attorney General that the State or Indian Tribe will, with respect to a grant received under subsection (b)—</text><subclause id="H7227634973074CFBBE9C1CAF33F91A79"><enum>(I)</enum><text>use the grant for the purposes described in subsection (b)(2); and</text></subclause><subclause id="H09551A89B07E42E6AD4C8F797BDB870D"><enum>(II)</enum><text>allocate not less than 25 percent and not more than 70 percent of the amount received under the grant for the development and dissemination of training for law enforcement officers in accordance with subsection (b)(4); or</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H584683DFEACE47C39D65DB19A04DAE13"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a unit of local government or other public or private entity that—</text><clause id="H74FD743C635E43DBAAC1CC44B28604D3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is located in a State or in the territory under the jurisdiction of an Indian Tribe that meets the requirements described in clauses (i) and (ii) of subparagraph (A); and</text></clause><clause id="H28F4202AE64C4C20AAB7A8F9D87BB8BF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>certifies to the Attorney General that the unit of local government or entity will, with respect to a grant received under subsection (b)—</text><subclause id="H3A4DD053568648259D2C24AF1A9A27AC"><enum>(I)</enum><text>use the grant for the purposes described in subsection (b)(2); and</text></subclause><subclause id="HB4B0DDD216E54533BC3796F77213BFC5"><enum>(II)</enum><text>allocate not less than 25 percent and not more than 70 percent of the amount received under the grant for the development and dissemination of training for law enforcement officers in accordance with subsection (b)(4).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAC0691C2EE454377A0E52E9A252BB1D0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Extreme risk protection order</header><text>The term <term>extreme risk protection order</term> means a written order or warrant, issued by a State or Tribal court or signed by a magistrate (or other comparable judicial officer), the primary purpose of which is to reduce the risk of firearm-related death or injury by doing 1 or more of the following:</text><subparagraph id="H283B3B3E821D41A98818BA57E7B568AD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Prohibiting a named individual from having under the custody or control of the individual, owning, purchasing, possessing, or receiving a firearm.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB6B66DD7A4554D82B36C56012FEBA401"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Having a firearm removed or requiring the surrender of firearms from a named individual.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2BC34BDDAEF7414DBE18C3D18B617F4B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Firearm</header><text>The term <term>firearm</term> has the meaning given the term in section 921 of title 18, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7F88DBDD8CA748ED9CEE0F37B1E4C2BE"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Indian Tribe</header><text>The term <term>Indian Tribe</term> has the meaning given the term <term>Indian tribe</term> in section 1709 of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10389">34 U.S.C. 10389</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5C2157056BFB401D846B40377481AD7C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Law enforcement officer</header><text>The term <term>law enforcement officer</term> means a public servant authorized by Federal, State, local, or Tribal law or by an agency of the Federal Government or of a State, local, or Tribal government to—</text><subparagraph id="H62803853645F4DA7861CFCFC1A0B5F20"><enum>(A)</enum><text>engage in or supervise the prevention, detection, investigation, or prosecution of an offense; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H02FA8EB4A77849D29DED9F229AA4CEF6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>supervise sentenced criminal offenders.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDB6776721BA64641BE11FF503C764EDB"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Petitioner</header><text>The term <term>petitioner</term> means an individual authorized under State or Tribal law to petition for an extreme risk protection order.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3079F2FB2FD843B8A327E12070AC7A37"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Respondent</header><text>The term <term>respondent</term> means an individual named in the petition for an extreme risk protection order or subject to an extreme risk protection order.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H59B5AC1820C24B718422516570F49160"><enum>(8)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="HB78747EB4CC24C5480B14837E261AC36"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a State;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE36CD9F8C19E4E43BA5EE096C489C87D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the District of Columbia;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBEA2BEC68D9C4918A95A657A0CCA79AA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1DCE59919B574168ABAD63014A9503EA"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any other territory or possession of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1756DF16D8754C86B47482C2880D626A"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Unit of local government</header><text>The term <term>unit of local government</term> has the meaning given the term in section 901 of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10251">34 U.S.C. 10251</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H75090908034043B6A2D3A1FA9E048441"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grant program established</header><paragraph id="HB3908C1F547C4D1791E3B84E3DE67A26"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Attorney General shall establish a program under which, from amounts made available to carry out this section, the Attorney General may make grants to eligible entities to assist in carrying out the provisions of the legislation described in subsection (c).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HECE653C5F2E0432B9484C9FE182A4350"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>Funds awarded under this subsection may be used by an applicant to—</text><subparagraph id="H01CE73CF8E544FEFA2591683091E6248"><enum>(A)</enum><text>enhance the capacity of law enforcement agencies and the courts of a State, unit of local government, or Indian Tribe by providing personnel, training, technical assistance, data collection, and other resources to carry out enacted legislation described in subsection (c);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H53F55FA2D2C04F138BF6A6E5976D1729"><enum>(B)</enum><text>train judges, court personnel, health care and legal professionals, and law enforcement officers to more accurately identify individuals whose access to firearms poses a danger of causing harm to themselves or others by increasing the risk of firearms suicide or interpersonal violence;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H63D0EBDA040B4B5DA0CD68C99489FA88"><enum>(C)</enum><text>develop and implement law enforcement and court protocols, forms, and orders so that law enforcement agencies and the courts may carry out the provisions of the enacted legislation described in subsection (c) in a safe, equitable, and effective manner, including through the removal and storage of firearms pursuant to extreme risk protection orders under the enacted legislation; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBB420A1C09C3404CB7CF57E99338AFCF"><enum>(D)</enum><text>raise public awareness and understanding of the enacted legislation described in subsection (c), including through subgrants to community-based organizations for the training of community members, so that extreme risk protection orders may be issued in appropriate situations to reduce the risk of firearms-related death and injury.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAC4265ECF2D2486DB980AA498F5F0325"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Application</header><text>An eligible entity desiring a grant under this subsection shall submit to the Attorney General an application at such time, in such manner, and containing or accompanied by such information as the Attorney General may reasonably require.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE75AE72378ED484A81B06F0B27304E23"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Training</header><subparagraph id="H00DC66E2649748FBB12F3B7AE97F2F0F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A recipient of a grant under this subsection shall provide training to law enforcement officers, including officers of relevant Federal, State, local, and Tribal law enforcement agencies, in the safe, impartial, effective, and equitable use and administration of extreme risk protection orders, including training to address—</text><clause id="HBD91BD03B5814924AD854152C572B845"><enum>(i)</enum><text>bias based on race and racism, ethnicity, gender, sexual orientation, gender identity, religion, language proficiency, mental health condition, disability, and classism in the use and administration of extreme risk protection orders;</text></clause><clause id="HCCE1B1C55C4149FD83BAF1D22BCAFBAD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the appropriate use of extreme risk protection orders in cases of domestic violence, including the applicability of other policies and protocols to address domestic violence in situations that may also involve extreme risk protection orders and the necessity of safety planning with the victim before a law enforcement officer petitions for and executes an extreme risk protection order, if applicable;</text></clause><clause id="HD99880C2B3C5495A9AFC74DBEBC7D2DE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>interacting with persons with a mental illness or emotional distress, including de-escalation and crisis intervention; and</text></clause><clause id="H2AE97D97DB4F4A6FBA91B4A4D03E82FB"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>best practices for referring persons subject to extreme risk protection orders and associated victims of violence to social service providers that may be available in the jurisdiction and appropriate for those individuals, including health care, mental health, substance abuse, and legal services, employment and vocational services, housing assistance, case management, and veterans and disability benefits.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFB8314BEB9E44495B998D8EBE05D6561"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Consultation with experts</header><text>A recipient of a grant under this subsection, in developing law enforcement training required under subparagraph (A), shall seek advice from domestic violence service providers (including culturally specific (as defined in section 40002 of the Violence Against Women Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/12291">34 U.S.C. 12291</external-xref>)) organizations), social service providers, suicide prevention advocates, violence intervention specialists, law enforcement agencies, mental health disability experts, and other community groups working to reduce suicides and violence, including domestic violence, within the State or the territory under the jurisdiction of the Indian Tribe, as applicable, that enacted the legislation described in subsection (c) that enabled the grant recipient to be an eligible entity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC1897CA6F9324F5CA9048B51665CC64D"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as are necessary to carry out this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF85B654ECC724BB6B32BFC2B52053874"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligibility for extreme risk protection order grant program</header><paragraph id="HA01149984C054F22B26FB78EEE25431D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>Legislation described in this subsection is legislation that establishes requirements that are substantially similar to the following:</text><subparagraph id="H7F9125EB7FEC4DEA84D1158E06ACF80A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Petition for extreme risk protection order</header><text>A petitioner, including a law enforcement officer, may submit a petition to a State or Tribal court, on a form designed by the court or a State or Tribal agency, that—</text><clause id="HF21B401BC92A474A818767719B0E72CD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>describes the facts and circumstances justifying that an extreme risk protection order be issued against the named individual; and</text></clause><clause id="H4E95017C023D41DEA76B6E67307F9DE6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is signed by the applicant, under oath.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H10369B068E4C42AA8A9BDFC987B18AE8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Notice and due process</header><text>The individual named in a petition for an extreme risk protection order as described in subparagraph (A) shall be given written notice of the petition and an opportunity to be heard on the matter in accordance with this paragraph.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H02E18C03A38043CEA6158C45E7E66080"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Issuance of extreme risk protection orders</header><clause id="H79B6FE53A639423597C9DF536FD25CCF"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Hearing</header><subclause id="H4174C0E16FE14C23BE65A8CFB93096A8"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Upon receipt of a petition described in subparagraph (A) or request of an individual named in such a petition, the court shall order a hearing to be held within a reasonable time, and not later than 30 days after the date of the petition or request.</text></subclause><subclause id="H847B53CAEC9A4B7D8192451C31DA470D"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Determination</header><text>If the court finds at the hearing ordered under subclause (I), by a preponderance of the evidence or according to a higher evidentiary standard established by the State or Indian Tribe, that the respondent poses a danger of causing harm to self or others by having access to a firearm, the court may issue an extreme risk protection order.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H6B0DAA2188AB4B1393080FB466ADC89C"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Duration of extreme risk protection order</header><text>An extreme risk protection order shall be in effect—</text><subclause id="HED4D5E59241545C4A05B2EF8C17865AC"><enum>(I)</enum><text>until an order terminating or superseding the extreme risk protection order is issued; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H22BEA26026BB4418B56652E2090B322E"><enum>(II)</enum><text>for a set period of time.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC3C6885F3B2147BBAB25238380FA12C7"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Ex parte extreme risk protection orders</header><clause id="H4A480FD28B984137A31D19F487DD842E"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Upon receipt of a petition described in subparagraph (A), the court may issue an ex parte extreme risk protection order, if—</text><subclause id="H7E261A0A1EC24A82835F168D715D187C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the petition for an extreme risk protection order alleges that the respondent poses a danger of causing harm to self or others by having access to a firearm; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H7606607A128044AAB804A58A978FDA51"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the court finds there is probable cause to believe, or makes a finding according to a higher evidentiary standard established by the State or Indian Tribe, that the respondent poses a danger of causing harm to self or others by having access to a firearm.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HEAF6F986D57043BD872CF381D215E5F9"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Duration of ex parte extreme risk protection order</header><text>An ex parte extreme risk protection order shall remain in effect only until the hearing required under subparagraph (C)(i).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCA5E3FA085EE4865A11898BA79FA52CD"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Storage of removed firearms</header><clause id="idBD9C0BD08D8A4F45A2CFF591695E20B9"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Availability for return</header><text>All firearms removed or surrendered pursuant to an extreme risk protection order shall only be available for return to the named individual when the individual has regained eligibility under Federal and State law and, where applicable, Tribal law to possess firearms.</text></clause><clause id="id1C9979945A784817AF7D5357987E3BB3"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Consent required for disposal or destruction</header><text>Firearms owned by a named individual may not be disposed of or destroyed during the period of the extreme risk protection order without the consent of the named individual.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC236CFE411364796B188CB09C6732302"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Notification</header><clause id="H6A23D173601B4FDA957099B74D5571C2"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><subclause id="idF1220537CDB54F9CA5973F6FAACD1F54"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>A State or Tribal court that issues an extreme risk protection order shall notify the Attorney General or the comparable State or Tribal agency, as applicable, of the order as soon as practicable or within a designated period of time.</text></subclause><subclause id="idA9D72BA733754313B8D0281D4F964544"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Form and manner</header><text>A State or Tribal court shall submit a notification under subclause (I) in an electronic format, in a manner prescribed by the Attorney General or the comparable State or Tribal agency.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HAE7784E7BAD14D8C9498CE77B7C98479"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Update of databases by State or Tribal agency</header><text>As soon as practicable or within the time period designated by State or Tribal law after receiving a notification under clause (i), the comparable State or Tribal agency shall ensure that the extreme risk protection order is reflected in the National Instant Criminal Background Check System.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6729576EEEDC4F0A94F70E3BAF759A04"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additional provisions</header><text>Legislation described in this subsection may—</text><subparagraph id="H20D4605182B240979CB6066E76CB7522"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide procedures for the termination of an extreme risk protection order;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H559E606FBFD545B9A933141496E0CB80"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide procedures for the renewal of an extreme risk protection order;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4C3E1405A71B4A70B34C50A794F47140"><enum>(C)</enum><text>establish burdens and standards of proof for issuance of orders described in paragraph (1) that are substantially similar to or higher than the burdens and standards of proof set forth in that paragraph;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB108698D882844DBB56FE9C494F75458"><enum>(D)</enum><text>limit the individuals who may submit a petition described in paragraph (1), provided that, at a minimum, 1 or more law enforcement officers are authorized to do so; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC8041C535964487F9125C28DD2AE8ADD"><enum>(E)</enum><text>include any other authorizations or requirements that the State or Tribal authorities determine appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H80A3DBC49F654FE389231474DCBAC885"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Attorney General responsibilities</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id999836ce28824b2ebcf8480339011f69"><enum>(A)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Manner of submitting notification to Attorney General</header><text>The Attorney General shall prescribe the manner in which a State or Tribal court shall submit a notification to the Attorney General under a provision of State or Tribal law that is substantially similar to paragraph (1)(F)(i).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5a3ba42503c747c8a0b473757b093069"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Update of databases</header><text>As soon as practicable, and in any event not later than 30 days, after receiving a notification under a provision of State or Tribal law that is substantially similar to paragraph (1)(F)(i), the Attorney General shall ensure that the extreme risk protection order is reflected in the National Instant Criminal Background Check System.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id039407d24f9a485fadd73f905a3e118c"><enum>(4)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Annual report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date on which an eligible entity receives a grant under subsection (b), and annually thereafter for the duration of the grant period, the entity shall submit to the Attorney General a report that includes, with respect to the preceding year—</text><subparagraph id="H1EE98461E297401C90165442B3296723"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of petitions for ex parte extreme risk protection orders filed, as well as the number of such orders issued and the number denied, disaggregated by—</text><clause id="idC861BE9A3FED472EBF9516FA0E7765EE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the jurisdiction;</text></clause><clause id="id1139EDD49A80480CA5A73CB07B90A869"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the individual authorized under State or Tribal law to petition for an extreme risk protection order, including the relationship of the individual to the respondent; and</text></clause><clause id="idF314733FF01B4B4C9665B51D3FEE1367"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the alleged danger posed by the respondent, including whether the danger involved a risk of suicide, unintentional injury, domestic violence, or other interpersonal violence;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5188998EDAB749E5BE356989C213052E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of petitions for extreme risk protection orders filed, as well as the number of such orders issued and the number denied, disaggregated by—</text><clause id="idDF8C39C4CFA44B709BB27D03F68EA9E4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the jurisdiction;</text></clause><clause id="idD696B2783C434EBFAC0BD4B284181503"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the individual authorized under State or Tribal law to petition for an extreme risk protection order, including the relationship of the individual to the respondent; and</text></clause><clause id="idCE43760567A84F7A819E52957E5E43C0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the alleged danger posed by the respondent, including whether the danger involved a risk of suicide, unintentional injury, domestic violence, or other interpersonal violence;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H937B7AF8FD624E6DB69C85E2D4DA20F7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the number of petitions for renewals of extreme risk protection orders filed, as well as the number of such orders issued and the number denied;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H38874635EE7E4CFEAD7F252D1A15FFBC"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the number of cases in which a court imposed a penalty for false reporting or frivolous petitions;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6B3703F297D2475F8110928B6D3D5323"><enum>(E)</enum><text>demographic data of petitioners, including race, ethnicity, national origin, sex, gender, age, disability, and English language proficiency, if available;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HED6FC0D9AC8B44A293B17FBF9BE45441"><enum>(F)</enum><text>demographic data of respondents, including race, ethnicity, national origin, sex, gender, age, disability, and English language proficiency, if available; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA485EE620C7C46EC9F5024A74040DB4A"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the number of firearms removed, if available.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HF62CA2EAA0944BDF8DF2F4F46F242497"><enum>3.</enum><header>Federal firearms prohibition</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 922 of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="H6D117E9ADAFD42B3A5EE23D66454C1BF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (d)—</text><subparagraph id="id7E28BE67971E4279BB650A6E8890147D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (10) and (11) as paragraphs (11) and (12), respectively;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H109919F3D79E4386B0C6D357D483726C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (9) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H24AB33736AB04FB6A8DEEBDDB893BD38"><paragraph id="H975D2792E36B46BE82911F542243DAB9"><enum>(10)</enum><text>is subject to a court order that—</text><subparagraph id="id51B64237562E45DD9FF61FF34A0B08CE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>was issued after a hearing of which such person received actual notice, and at which such person had an opportunity to participate;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idA072379CAF8246FEB1F2A1E50369077B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>prevents such person from possessing or receiving firearms; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD37A115356DD49AC8E1A6C9A14B04A92"><enum>(C)</enum><text>includes a finding that such person poses a danger of harm to self or others.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2655097797EE48F693271F116FCFAE2D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (12), as so redesignated, by striking <quote>(10)</quote> and inserting <quote>(11)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD8884D035D3745EDAD2B1FCDDB8AEC1D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (g)—</text><subparagraph id="HDAD10442BCE1479A81A7ADCAC23A5D42"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (8)(C)(ii), by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8BF7DF56116B49D8B03C0C7F6A651740"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (9), by striking the comma at the end and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H85531BD524F04C64AD924C5EC87C8C00"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (9) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H97AB451E095749F3B79AAE75781C473B"><paragraph id="H17B6D004174748C49CDC68C47C1D6AF1"><enum>(10)</enum><text>is subject to a court order that—</text><subparagraph id="H325169EF327147409D32045D1870257C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>was issued after a hearing of which such person received actual notice, and at which such person had an opportunity to participate;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id21DF1AE8C68A48D98B2C1ACEE754E461"><enum>(B)</enum><text>prevents such person from possessing or receiving firearms; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE10AF50994D640EABD12A3BEC783FE43"> <enum>(C)</enum> <text>includes a finding that such person poses a danger of harm to self or others.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="HF4658E5A75C245C2B2EFA0F9D916D462"><enum>4.</enum><header>Identification records</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 534 of title 28, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="HA6FA62BF09B14DA3823BADA2AA6E3FE1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text><subparagraph id="H9432296B34EB47AAA60A2B252B4A972D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (4) and (5) as paragraphs (5) and (6), respectively; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id403DD17B52674943B7E322E5054F55CA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (3) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3D28D41949504330873549E494486175"><paragraph id="H6DB24B8E5D63429884CEF686FBE27BB7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>acquire, collect, classify, and preserve records from Federal, Tribal, and State courts and other agencies identifying individuals subject to extreme risk protection orders, as defined in section 2(a) of the <short-title>Extreme Risk Protection Order Expansion Act of 2025</short-title>;</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H531AFB814EBA413482C6FB0E16AC37A4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text><subparagraph id="id4521827D225F4F6BB8DBDB77A6694A7C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(a)(5)</quote> and inserting <quote>(a)(6)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD2CBADC88CE34555A422AA62F75DD5BC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(a)(4)</quote> and inserting <quote>(a)(5)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4551FBE45DA44EC5A8E694CDC18A61C4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HA326A96601004CB38AA95D75F29E4789"><subsection id="H33B9E719D9FA420198959BE0EB00EF36"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Extreme risk protection orders in national crime information databases</header><text>A Federal, Tribal, or State criminal justice agency or criminal or civil court may—</text><paragraph id="HE1DF3B8A22654D4E99A69E2CFFC28D8D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>include extreme risk protection orders, as defined in section 2(a) of the <short-title>Extreme Risk Protection Order Expansion Act of 2025</short-title>, in national crime information databases, as that term is defined in subsection (f)(3) of this section; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0441D6BACB1A4B7A968405E70CFB910B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>have access to information regarding extreme risk protection orders through the national crime information databases.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="HEE56C2F6F3194E92BDD58607E6EDDD09"><enum>5.</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 3(1) of the NICS Improvement Amendments Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/40903">34 U.S.C. 40903(1)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>section 922(g)(8)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraph (8) or (10) of section 922(g)</quote>.</text></section><section id="HD2C9D148667B490A9B54F29B70D26BE1"><enum>6.</enum><header>Full faith and credit</header><subsection id="id3A613655043E407C8309901B7B843D6B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the terms <term>extreme risk protection order</term>, <term>Indian Tribe</term>, and <term>State</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 2(a).</text></subsection><subsection id="H3ED6B212A7BE4376B266E9471BBC3AB3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Full faith and credit required</header><text>Any extreme risk protection order issued under a State or Tribal law enacted in accordance with this Act shall be accorded the same full faith and credit by the court of another State or Indian Tribe (referred to in this subsection as the <term>enforcing State or Indian Tribe</term>) and enforced by the court and law enforcement personnel of the other State or Tribal government as if it were the order of the enforcing State or Indian Tribe.</text></subsection><subsection id="H7F5A7B1BAE854CCF8F343936921546E7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applicability to extreme risk protection orders</header><paragraph id="idA496764483B94B508522E078F6F12740"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subsection (b) shall apply to an extreme risk protection order issued by a State or Tribal court if—</text><subparagraph id="HED34D36116AB4CA599A503C823DE58C5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the court has jurisdiction over the parties and matter under the law of the State or Indian Tribe; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD74DBA7648694A1EAEBC7893169206F5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>reasonable notice and opportunity to be heard is given to the person against whom the order is sought sufficient to protect that person’s right to due process.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id14F74CF0EBC64AD8956841AEF2830E73"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Ex parte extreme risk protection orders</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (1)(B), in the case of an ex parte extreme risk protection order, notice and opportunity to be heard shall be provided within the time required by State or Tribal law, and in any event within a reasonable time after the order is issued, sufficient to protect the due process rights of the respondent.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HABF205E031954417A24B769BADBFCE49"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Tribal court jurisdiction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, a court of an Indian Tribe shall have full civil jurisdiction to issue and enforce an extreme risk protection order involving any person, including the authority to enforce any order through civil contempt proceedings, to exclude violators from Indian land, and to use other appropriate mechanisms, in matters arising anywhere in the Indian country (as defined in section 1151 of title 18, United States Code) of the Indian Tribe or otherwise within the authority of the Indian Tribe.</text></subsection></section><section id="H1E87BF453DC74BB7A3BC6569466FAAD4"><enum>7.</enum><header>Severability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any provision of this Act or amendment made by this Act, or the application of such provision or amendment to any person or circumstance, is held to be invalid, the remaining provisions of this Act and amendments made by this Act, or the application of such provision or amendment to other persons or circumstances, shall not be affected.</text></section><section id="id981693ACAF7D40E188273E7B51245922"><enum>8.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act and the amendments made by this Act shall take effect on the date that is 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></section></legis-body></bill>

