<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H424EC46864944BD5AD3CF8EFE8C6616E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5436 IH: To amend title 38, United States Code, to prohibit an educational institution from withholding a transcript from an individual who pursued a course or program of education at such institution using Post-9/11 educational assistance.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5436</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250917">September 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001231">Mr. Mannion</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001219">Mr. Moylan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to prohibit an educational institution from withholding a transcript from an individual who pursued a course or program of education at such institution using Post-9/11 educational assistance.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H436058EBF5A0469EA75C8B9EF0B590F0" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HAD985C878956476F94C025E8BBC7C823" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Prohibition of withholding a transcript from an individual who pursued a course or program of education at an educational institution using Post-9/11 educational assistance</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subchapter III of chapter 33 of such title is amended by adding at the end the following new section (and amending the table of sections at the beginning of such chapter accordingly):</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="H8AE8D9A9D8264DA5B874DA9576625888" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <section id="H8282F05F798644488F444DCF9BA55356"><enum>3328.</enum><header>Prohibition of withholding transcripts</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">An educational institution may not withhold the transcript of an individual who attended a course or program of education at such educational institution using educational assistance under this chapter solely because such individual owes a debt to such educational institution.</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

