<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5E6CC727548A4E9FB31742B4CBA779C8" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 595 IH: Honoring the brave men and women who participated in the Afghanistan evacuation in 2021 following the United States withdrawal, for their extraordinary efforts and exceptional service in the safe evacuation of over 17,000 people from Taliban-controlled Afghanistan, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 595</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250717">July 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000190">Mr. Norman</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001211">Mrs. Miller of Illinois</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Honoring the brave men and women who participated in the Afghanistan evacuation in 2021 following the United States withdrawal, for their extraordinary efforts and exceptional service in the safe evacuation of over 17,000 people from Taliban-controlled Afghanistan, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the events of August 2021 marked a significant turning point in the history of United States engagement in Afghanistan, as the Nation underwent a process of withdrawal after over two decades of military presence;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, over the course of those 20 years, countless men and women in uniform made tremendous sacrifices to uphold the principles of democracy and freedom while also honoring the promises made to the Afghan people to build a safer and more prosperous country;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas among these exceptional individuals were the 13 individuals who participated in the Afghanistan evacuation in 2021, serving as a beacon of hope and demonstrating unwavering dedication to the ideals of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, when the final withdrawal was announced, Chad Robichaux knew he needed to act, as his combat interpreter, Azizullah Aziz, who had saved his life on countless occasions throughout his 8 deployments to Afghanistan as part of a Joint Special Operations Task Force, was now being hunted and targeted by the Taliban for helping him;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, determined to save his loyal friend, Chad embarked on a mission that would bring together 12 modern-day avengers, all Special Operations veterans, and 1 determined woman to drop everything and rescue Aziz and his family from Afghanistan, and without hesitation, each member of the team agreed to join the daring mission;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in a matter of hours, Chad Robichaux assembled a team and made a crucial call to Sarah Verardo, the wife of a catastrophically wounded soldier from his service in Afghanistan, who miraculously secured their way to Hamid Karzai International Airport (HKIA) in Kabul, Afghanistan;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the 12-man team quickly mobilized, with Chad heading to Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates, to establish a humanitarian center for evacuees, and meanwhile, Tim Kennedy, Kevin Rourke, Sean Gabler, and Dave Johnson headed for HKIA itself, setting up a command center at HKIA and nonstop rescue operations amidst Taliban-controlled territory, facing immense danger without a Quick Reaction Force (QRF), and in just 10 days, their unwavering efforts led to the successful rescue of over 12,000 lives;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, even in the face of tremendous adversity, the team’s dedication did not waver;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, despite Abbey Gate being destroyed and the gates welded shut, they refused to leave, and over the next 2 months, they continued their humanitarian efforts remotely, leading a coalition to rescue an additional 5,000 individuals through alternate routes around the region;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas their commitment and determination made a significant difference during this critical time of need;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Chad Robichaux’s mission did not end with the evacuation from HKIA, and after teaming up with Fellow Force Recon Marine and Scout Sniper, Staff Sergeant Dennis Price, he embarked on a grueling 10-day, 90-mile reconnaissance mission along the Tajikistan and Afghanistan border, swimming into Afghanistan every night past Taliban and Chinese soldiers in order to use their Special Operations experience to build evacuation routes for women and children still trapped in Afghanistan as Afghan Commandos attempted to move them to the Tajikistan border, and braving the treacherous terrain and encounters with foreign militaries, including Chinese, Russian, Tajikistan, and Taliban fighters, they successfully established routes that are still in use today, ensuring more people could find their way to safety;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the valor and courage displayed by Chad Robichaux, Dennis Price, Tim Kennedy, Kevin Rourke, Sean Gabler, Dave Johnson, Sarah Verardo, Joe Robert, Dan Stinson, Kevin Metcalf, Nick Palmisciano, Hunter Robichaux, and Sean Lee during the Afghanistan evacuation in 2021 exemplify the very essence of United States promises to the Afghan people throughout the 20 years of war;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas their actions served as a powerful testament to the unwavering loyalty and dedication of the United States Armed Forces, reinforcing the Nation’s role as a beacon of hope and justice on the global stage, and their commitment to duty and humanity will forever be etched in the Congressional Record as a shining example of United States heroism;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, under the exceptional leadership of Force Recon Marine Chad Robichaux, this remarkable team of Special Operation veterans took up the charge to protect and evacuate over 17,000 citizens and Afghan allies from Taliban-controlled Afghanistan during a time of unfathomable danger and uncertainty; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas these individuals have dedicated their lives to protecting our country, putting their own lives on the line to safeguard others, and their heroism deserves great honor: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H62A07EF154234E1CB4A743A97ADEECAB"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H9B84EA42824C4E5EAF1EA8E96FDD7778"><enum/><text>That the House of Representatives, on behalf of a grateful Nation, recognizes and thanks these courageous men and women for putting their own lives on the line and for their exemplary service in rescuing over 17,000 citizens and Afghan allies from unfathomable danger.</text></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

