<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ROS25433-50V-NW-TGT"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1339 IS: Stop Corrupt Communist Party Money Laundering Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1339</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250408">April 8, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S431">Mr. Curtis</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require a determination and report relating to money laundering and violations of export controls and sanctions in Hong Kong.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop Corrupt Communist Party Money Laundering Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Stop CCP Money Laundering Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section section-type="subsequent-section" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7742203eef84485ea30c84294df9f901"><enum>2.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Measures to address money laundering and export control and sanctions violations in Hong Kong</header><subsection id="id528862848beb4d4ba66dafe9eee56bbb"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Determination with respect to money laundering</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Treasury shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a determination, including a detailed justification, of whether reasonable grounds exist for designating the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region of the People's Republic of China as a jurisdiction of primary money laundering concern under section 5318A of title 31, United States Code.</text></subsection><subsection id="id4a462366cbb74d5db33148335f5da709"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report on role of Hong Kong in export control and sanctions violations</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide4e8d5040a6f405ca3e2722fdeb3c18f"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 360 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State, in coordination with the Secretary of the Treasury and the Secretary of Commerce, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report assessing the ability of United States and foreign financial institutions operating in Hong Kong to identify and prevent transactions that facilitate the transfer of products, technology, and money to the Russian Federation, Iran, and other countries and entities in violation of export controls and sanctions imposed by the United States. </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id39c9fc4d098443b38e4f4202ce55ee2c"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report required by paragraph (1) shall include—</text><subparagraph id="idcffd08682c9244179c790120d094745e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an evaluation of the extent of the role of Hong Kong as an international financial and trading center in facilitating, knowingly or unknowingly—</text><clause id="id7984c25ed16c454a918d414d997644ed"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the transfer of products and technologies to adversaries of the United States, including the Russian Federation, Iran, the mainland of the People’s Republic of China, and other countries in violation of export controls imposed by the United States; and</text></clause><clause id="id0252c2736efe4ac288a771fcc8b49724"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>trade and financial transactions that violate sanctions imposed by the United States on the Russian Federation, Iran, and other countries and entities;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8f04e3394ebf419ab2c087829d353dda"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an assessment of whether the People’s Republic of China’s 2020 National Security Law and the January 2024 Safeguarding National Security Ordinance of Hong Kong have limited the ability of financial institutions operating in Hong Kong to adhere to global standards for anti-money laundering and know-your-customer procedures; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id04ae6e4079c247f4b31a6bf1f1429a26"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a description of cooperation between Hong Kong and United States authorities in enforcing export control and sanctions regimes, including any challenges to such cooperation. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idff612f73d57249ff94209d10bad93105"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means— </text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2a57abcba1b445d6acc601ae9daad63d"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate; and </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idabe3da9b3260414184dd732396dad579"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives. </text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

