<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-OLL25B23-3VM-0S-N7F">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2935 IS: Sovereign Enforcement Integrity Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>II</distribution-code>
        <congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session>1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. 2935</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action>
            <action-date date="20250929">September 29, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S404">Mr. Scott of Florida</sponsor> introduced the
                following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title>To prohibit State and local law enforcement officers from arresting foreign
            nationals within the United States solely on the basis of an indictment, warrant, or
            request issued by the International Criminal Court, and for other
            purposes.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H00D4ADD1CD60462BA706B1D853E36A56">
        <section section-type="section-one" id="HAA783309E316407E915C12139EE19C82">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Sovereign Enforcement Integrity Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section id="H18E455DA91B0449A8B2BFB1686411B6E">
            <enum>2.</enum>
            <header>Findings and purpose</header>
            <subsection id="HF0772EF84A5543048EFCF667BBDC19D8">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>Findings</header>
 <text>Congress finds the following:</text> <paragraph id="HA3D3C8380B53491BB0C2339C68C4857F"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>The United States is not a party to the Rome Statute establishing the International Criminal Court (commonly known as the <quote>ICC</quote>).</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H19D6997F1FCE4AC8B3798347668A4DFC">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>The Constitution of the United States provides the Federal Government with exclusive authority over foreign relations and the treatment of foreign nationals within the territory of the United States.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H4BA38E52CAE240DFA817555098BCD605">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>The arrest or detention of foreign nationals on United States soil pursuant to an ICC request or indictment, absent Federal authorization, could jeopardize the foreign policy interests of the United States and conflict with longstanding constitutional principles.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H376AC3E1DF1B4931A94E94B367C5002F">
                    <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>Law enforcement activities implicating international law enforcement obligations must be governed by uniform national standards.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="HA6B07C2DE28F43FD903771FE1D7C8072">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Purpose</header>
 <text>The purpose of this Act is to prohibit State and local law enforcement officers from executing, honoring, or enforcing any request, warrant, or indictment issued by the International Criminal Court unless expressly authorized by Federal law.</text>
            </subsection>
        </section>
        <section id="HB03992A92DF3494999876D4B3B2760E4">
            <enum>3.</enum>
            <header>Prohibition on state or local enforcement of icc actions</header>
            <subsection id="H9D015CCC4A4540EE90FD07CA63CC4D64">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>General rule</header>
 <text>No officer, employee, or agent of a State, a territory, or the District of Columbia, or any political subdivision thereof, may—</text>
                <paragraph id="H3F8D9B5F190F43F0854AA7C3148D9E86">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>arrest, detain, or otherwise deprive a foreign national of liberty based solely on a warrant, indictment, summons, or other process issued by the International Criminal Court;</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H5388A941BCCB4121B6CBD91A79F39A75">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>cooperate with, or provide assistance to, the International Criminal Court in effectuating such an arrest or detention; or</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H11B6658F11544FF58B78DF77DF1308E6">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>use any funds, facilities, personnel, or equipment to carry out any action described in paragraph (1) or (2).</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H02C491086E334A0E9465EC6E84B691B8">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Exception</header>
 <text>The prohibitions in subsection (a) shall not apply if—</text> <paragraph id="HCF36E90CA2B34582944B6D9AF43DD440"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>Congress enacts legislation expressly authorizing cooperation with the International Criminal Court in a specific case; or</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HC9B46BA1698B4066B07247F15D3CE7B4">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the President certifies to Congress that such cooperation is essential to a declared national security interest and issues a specific written authorization.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
        </section>
        <section id="H8C2D8CC79499419190A7A01E8D5B74EB">
            <enum>4.</enum>
            <header>Preemption</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act supersedes any State or local law, policy, or regulation that permits, requires, or authorizes any action inconsistent with this Act.</text>
        </section>
        <section id="HD7EB5B9D480044F09673FE7323B32E5D">
            <enum>5.</enum>
            <header>Severability</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any provision of this Act, or the application of a provision to any person or circumstance, is held to be unconstitutional, the remainder of the Act and the application of the provisions to any other person or circumstance shall not be affected.</text>
        </section>
    </legis-body>
</bill>

