<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2C4FAEF7796F4766ABE8E01712A13D60" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5449 IH: Redistricting Reform Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5449</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250918">September 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000557">Mr. Larson of Connecticut</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000305">Ms. Ross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000371">Mr. Aguilar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001324">Mr. Bell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001287">Mr. Bera</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001112">Mr. Carbajal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001123">Mr. Cisneros</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001110">Mr. Correa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000399">Mr. Doggett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000483">Ms. Friedman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000598">Mr. Garcia of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000585">Mr. Gomez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001090">Mr. Harder of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000400">Ms. Kamlager-Dove</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000593">Mr. Levin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000607">Mr. Liccardo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Lieu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001241">Mr. Min</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001225">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000197">Ms. Pelosi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000620">Ms. Rivas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000599">Mr. Ruiz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001156">Ms. Sánchez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001231">Ms. Simon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000474">Mrs. Torres of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000491">Mr. Tran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000830">Mr. Whitesides</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000187">Ms. Waters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000305">Ms. Jacobs</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000605">Mr. Gray</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000601">Mr. Landsman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001214">Mr. Mrvan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require congressional redistricting conducted by a State to be conducted in accordance with a redistricting plan developed and enacted into law by an independent redistricting commission established by the State, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HDEEAF6AA5840495E81AB41A944F38A44" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HF6AC9A599CAD4E32BC18A6A8C96638EF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; statement of constitutional authority; table of contents</header> 
<subsection id="H343702CC7CB645E3AEF228AF7C485C6E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Redistricting Reform Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HDE0A88AED6854BDFB2E877144A4B2679"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Finding of Constitutional authority</header><text>Congress finds that it has the authority to establish the terms and conditions States must follow in carrying out congressional redistricting after an apportionment of Members of the House of Representatives because—</text> 
<paragraph id="H82F99AC06D4449DBA43C879BA21EBE9D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the authority granted to Congress under article I, section 4 of the Constitution of the United States gives Congress the power to enact laws governing the time, place, and manner of elections for Members of the House of Representatives;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3A06F48F087B47A895D08F4E739B13AA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the authority granted to Congress under section 5 of the fourteenth amendment to the Constitution gives Congress the power to enact laws to enforce section 2 of such amendment, which requires Representatives to be apportioned among the several States according to their number;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA9F59BA48C0A45C3B89C8176A4B0F938"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the authority granted to Congress under section 5 of the fourteenth amendment to the Constitution gives Congress the power to enact laws to enforce section 1 of such amendment, including protections against excessive partisan gerrymandering that Federal courts have not enforced because they understand such enforcement to be committed to Congress by the Constitution;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H776496012B80423BB0736C4B7E687CE0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>of the authority granted to Congress to enforce article IV, section 4, of the Constitution, and the guarantee of a Republican Form of Government to every State, which Federal courts have not enforced because they understand such enforcement to be committed to Congress by the Constitution; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAA8FAB3A23894970A5E1CD5C786A61DB"><enum>(5)</enum><text>requiring States to use uniform redistricting criteria is an appropriate and important exercise of such authority.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF378FF1F1EE94E9ABDBBD6A8046311C9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents of this Act is as follows:</text> 
<toc container-level="legis-body-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"> 
<toc-entry idref="HF6AC9A599CAD4E32BC18A6A8C96638EF" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; statement of constitutional authority; table of contents.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HAA88C8E855724C9DB033FA544C1D6391" level="title">Title I—Requirements for Congressional Redistricting</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HB924E2AB229C41D883B4489C6439AA80" level="section">Sec. 101. Requiring congressional redistricting to be conducted through plan of independent State commission.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H33D3B4DECC4845BB8997E5D852AECE2D" level="section">Sec. 102. Ban on mid-decade redistricting.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HDE9EF6E050474B798D67BCB3B496C781" level="section">Sec. 103. Criteria for redistricting.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HD629CA6A09454A8AB936080769EA5E39" level="title">Title II—Independent Redistricting Commissions</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H7476C866D647465A80C7831BCE3F3C1F" level="section">Sec. 201. Independent redistricting commission.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H4B336A0809A84F0EBA08F74449983F0B" level="section">Sec. 202. Establishment of selection pool of individuals eligible to serve as members of commission.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HAF234BCC22014D8A89AB7C41BDE124BF" level="section">Sec. 203. Public notice and input.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HC73A38FA1FAA4916A00A5AABBE4863F8" level="section">Sec. 204. Establishment of related entities.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H57CD8E5C153544B09E918504289881DF" level="section">Sec. 205. Report on diversity of memberships of independent redistricting commissions.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H5D016F31BB824ACEB0DF394AF8391A8E" level="title">Title III—Role of Courts in Development of Redistricting Plans</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HADFE0A7A7A4041789518C0445316BA72" level="section">Sec. 301. Failure by State to enact plan.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H78C04FBC084F43228F91FB4704CA8EF7" level="section">Sec. 302. Special rule for redistricting conducted under order of Federal court.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HD025BB3E7C1A4FEC84A906DDE2FA756E" level="title">Title IV—Administrative and Miscellaneous Provisions</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H02C012DEC90346EE9797945DE07F4AE7" level="section">Sec. 401. Payments to States for carrying out redistricting.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HAA58BC03731B4F0AB2FFDC9996D3553D" level="section">Sec. 402. Civil enforcement.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H9F26561E5DED45E392BB7AA1E6BF4617" level="section">Sec. 403. State apportionment notice defined.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HE86F3E1E3FB44E9B8B36014724E9A379" level="section">Sec. 404. No effect on elections for State and local office.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H602701E6576D4DCC8F431F13B1F4BB8B" level="section">Sec. 405. Effective date.</toc-entry> </toc> </subsection></section> 
<title id="HAA88C8E855724C9DB033FA544C1D6391"><enum>I</enum><header>Requirements for Congressional Redistricting</header> 
<section id="HB924E2AB229C41D883B4489C6439AA80"><enum>101.</enum><header>Requiring congressional redistricting to be conducted through plan of independent State commission</header> 
<subsection id="HC965E49A4763467088BCC29CDEFBEA15"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Use of Plan Required</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, and except as provided in subsection (c) and subsection (d), any congressional redistricting conducted by a State shall be conducted in accordance with—</text> <paragraph id="H41B36C8AB67442F499810D8D48DEEE4A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the redistricting plan developed and enacted into law by the independent redistricting commission established in the State, in accordance with title II; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDEFE56030D1B456FB6ADFE3C57EDE82C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>if a plan developed by such commission is not enacted into law, the redistricting plan developed and enacted into law by a 3-judge court, in accordance with section 301.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HECBFA1767E904B1898A40127CCAB0658"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Conforming amendment</header> <text>Section 22(c) of the Act entitled <quote>An Act to provide for the fifteenth and subsequent decennial censuses and to provide for an apportionment of Representatives in Congress</quote>, approved June 18, 1929 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/2a">2 U.S.C. 2a(c)</external-xref>), is amended by striking <quote>in the manner provided by the law thereof</quote> and inserting: <quote>in the manner provided by the Redistricting Reform Act of 2025</quote>.</text>
        </subsection> 
<subsection id="H0B55B2B89DE14DA98A7D34100A55F952"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Special rule for existing commissions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (a) does not apply to any State in which, under law in effect continuously on and after the date of the enactment of this Act, congressional redistricting is carried out in accordance with a plan developed and approved by an independent redistricting commission which is in compliance with each of the following requirements:</text> <paragraph id="HE28D08E13C4F438189B54468D249398B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Publicly available application process</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Membership on the commission is open to citizens of the State through a publicly available application process.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1BCF793C81A34F029CEE164E940B9A2B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Disqualifications for government service and political appointment</header><text>Individuals who, for a covered period of time as established by the State, hold or have held public office, individuals who are or have been candidates for elected public office, and individuals who serve or have served as an officer, employee, or paid consultant of a campaign committee of a candidate for public office are disqualified from serving on the commission.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H230221D5B60B41B7A930FB1CD66F66C8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Screening for conflicts</header><text>Individuals who apply to serve on the commission are screened through a process that excludes persons with conflicts of interest from the pool of potential commissioners.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCD5A53935C3D47DAA6E9542A98ECBC63"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Multi-partisan composition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Membership on the commission represents those who are affiliated with the two political parties whose candidates received the most votes in the most recent statewide election for Federal office held in the State, as well as those who are unaffiliated with any party or who are affiliated with political parties other than the two political parties whose candidates received the most votes in the most recent statewide election for Federal office held in the State.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6B18FAE07398445FA2C5E5122DF21566"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Criteria for redistricting</header><text>Members of the commission are required to meet certain criteria in the map drawing process, including minimizing the division of communities of interest and a ban on drawing maps to favor a political party.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5D19B39D73B94296BAD8098BBC26A152"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Public input</header><text>Public hearings are held and comments from the public are accepted before a final map is approved.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD0A4DA25C4A449318D5C8F1F41E3687E"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Broad-based support for approval of final plan</header><text>The approval of the final redistricting plan requires a majority vote of the members of the commission, including the support of at least one member of each of the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H0CDA694F9E7449F5A62E8B4BAE6F2263"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Members who are affiliated with the political party whose candidate received the most votes in the most recent statewide election for Federal office held in the State.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H69C9EA98F2B94C14BAFE6EA0BDB2588E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Members who are affiliated with the political party whose candidate received the second most votes in the most recent statewide election for Federal office held in the State.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H74346D45D62A43DC99863818213550EC"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Members who are not affiliated with any political party or who are affiliated with political parties other than the political parties described in subparagraphs (A) and (B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H105F8873FF5544318A8234D1DA6516EC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Treatment of State of Iowa</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (a) does not apply to the State of Iowa, so long as congressional redistricting in such State is carried out in accordance with a plan developed by the Iowa Legislative Services Agency with the assistance of a Temporary Redistricting Advisory Commission, under law which was in effect for the most recent congressional redistricting carried out in the State prior to the date of the enactment of this Act and which remains in effect continuously on and after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H33D3B4DECC4845BB8997E5D852AECE2D"><enum>102.</enum><header>Ban on mid-decade redistricting</header> 
<subsection id="H5FFC548EDB274FBCAE5A69B127AD4595">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>Ban</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State that has been redistricted in accordance with this Act and a State described in section 101(c) or section 101(d) may not be redistricted again until after the next apportionment of Representatives under section 22(a) of the Act entitled <quote>An Act to provide for the fifteenth and subsequent decennial censuses and to provide for an apportionment of Representatives in Congress</quote>, approved June 18, 1929 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/2a">2 U.S.C. 2a</external-xref>), unless a court requires the State to conduct such subsequent redistricting to comply with the Constitution of the United States, the Voting Rights Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/10301">52 U.S.C. 10301 et seq.</external-xref>), the Constitution of the State, or the terms or conditions of this Act.</text>
        </subsection> 
<subsection id="H63C1CFBDF9E14301A084CFA90C1408EF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicability of remedies for noncompliance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 402 applies with respect to a violation of subsection (a) in the same manner as such section applies with respect to a violation of any other provision of this Act, and the remedies available pursuant to such section may be applied with respect to a violation of subsection (a).</text></subsection> <subsection id="HCA0AA31B66CB4BB2A4D08287BC58214E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section shall apply with respect to redistricting carried out pursuant to the decennial census conducted during 2020 or any succeeding decennial census.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HDE9EF6E050474B798D67BCB3B496C781"><enum>103.</enum><header>Criteria for redistricting</header> 
<subsection id="H1B5F5618E4CA46689C35D78F23391AA7">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>Requiring plans To meet criteria</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State may not use a congressional redistricting plan that is not in compliance with this section.</text>
        </subsection> 
<subsection id="H0DC95221AF5C434BAFE31745B953C115"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Ranked criteria</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Under the redistricting plan of a State, there shall be established single-member congressional districts using the following criteria as set forth in the following order of priority:</text> <paragraph id="HE88941EE7411430885505EC8658C9F45"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Districts shall comply with the United States Constitution, including the requirement that they substantially equalize total population.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC78EBFCE058D4C4B80B773A0F6112F52"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Districts shall comply with the Voting Rights Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/10301">52 U.S.C. 10301 et seq.</external-xref>), including by creating any districts where, if based upon the totality of the circumstances, 2 or more politically cohesive groups protected by such Act are able to elect representatives of choice in coalition with one another, and all applicable Federal laws.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBAB2DF8EA81E4548A9867FE10CCC1231"><enum>(3)</enum> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H98F70F974F76484999B32D0AA2F080F4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Districts shall be drawn, to the extent that the totality of the circumstances warrant, to ensure the practical ability of a group protected under the Voting Rights Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/10301">52 U.S.C. 10301 et seq.</external-xref>) to participate in the political process and to nominate candidates and to elect representatives of choice is not diluted or diminished, regardless of whether or not such protected group constitutes a majority of a district’s citizen voting age population.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H11F53350B69F4AF7BD817E00A1CF3B0C" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of subparagraph (A), the assessment of whether a protected group has the practical ability to nominate candidates and to elect representatives of choice shall require the consideration of the following factors:</text> <clause id="HA6CA623E72264BE3BB0F03A0C684C833"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Whether the group is politically cohesive.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H75BC8E4E273B42079EA5488425A36C41"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Whether there is racially polarized voting in the relevant geographic region.</text></clause> <clause id="H3622A45B1095424BA3237B6F7D4BADF0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>If there is racially polarized voting in the relevant geographic region, whether the preferred candidates of the group nevertheless receive a sufficient amount of consistent crossover support from other voters such that the group is a functional majority with the ability to both nominate candidates and elect representatives of choice.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6F1F133545DD45A5847D24B4CE98343A"><enum>(4)</enum> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H6C1BB71C034C45829AE6D4ED6BC09145"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Districts shall be drawn to represent communities of interest and neighborhoods to the extent practicable after compliance with the requirements of paragraphs (1) through (3). A community of interest is defined as an area for which the record before the entity responsible for developing and adopting the redistricting plan demonstrates the existence of broadly shared interests and representational needs, including shared interests and representational needs rooted in common ethnic, racial, economic, Indian, social, cultural, geographic, or historic identities, or arising from similar socioeconomic conditions. The term communities of interest may, if the record warrants, include political subdivisions such as counties, municipalities, Indian lands, or school districts, but shall not include common relationships with political parties or political candidates.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDAD47F4D992E406D99C4BDD4B1754570" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A), in considering the needs of multiple, overlapping communities of interest, the entity responsible for developing and adopting the redistricting plan shall give greater weight to those communities of interest whose representational needs would most benefit from the community’s inclusion in a single congressional district.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB7CCEA6B361A4B12AF8AD4FAE27DA32C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>No favoring or disfavoring of political parties</header> 
<paragraph id="HE8B37258139E448F8608F0D4D30170B4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State may not use a redistricting plan to conduct an election that, when considered on a statewide basis, has been drawn with the intent or has the effect of materially favoring or disfavoring any political party.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE8CE10FB77A44A829BDF1DEBD9E93F37"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Determination of effect</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The determination of whether a redistricting plan has the effect of materially favoring or disfavoring a political party shall be based on an evaluation of the totality of circumstances which, at a minimum, shall involve consideration of each of the following factors:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H57BFD35807814C6CA20CA771A04C8689"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Computer modeling based on relevant statewide general elections for Federal office held over the 8 years preceding the adoption of the redistricting plan setting forth the probable electoral outcomes for the plan under a range of reasonably foreseeable conditions.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF98FEB8B5EF84AC38609DB9C08A3E592"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An analysis of whether the redistricting plan is statistically likely to result in partisan advantage or disadvantage on a statewide basis, the degree of any such advantage or disadvantage, and whether such advantage or disadvantage is likely to be present under a range of reasonably foreseeable electoral conditions.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H062F72EA5D5C4AC6A6FCCB8A853B7327"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A comparison of the modeled electoral outcomes for the redistricting plan to the modeled electoral outcomes for alternative plans that demonstrably comply with the requirements of paragraphs (1), (2), and (3) of subsection (b) in order to determine whether reasonable alternatives exist that would result in materially lower levels of partisan advantage or disadvantage on a statewide basis. For purposes of this subparagraph, alternative plans considered may include both actual plans proposed during the redistricting process and other plans prepared for purposes of comparison.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD0DCFE431D5D43EFB554D51127894BC6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Any other relevant information, including how broad support for the redistricting plan was among members of the entity responsible for developing and adopting the plan and whether the processes leading to the development and adoption of the plan were transparent and equally open to all members of the entity and to the public.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3F4C74F3E1D041F2841773B945FBEF58"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rebuttable presumption</header> 
<subparagraph id="HC5EE298A4FD840D3BC90370D0387785D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Trigger</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In any civil action brought under section 402 in which a party asserts a claim that a State has enacted a redistricting plan which is in violation of this subsection, a party may file a motion not later than 30 days after the enactment of the plan (or, if later, not later than 30 days after the effective date of this Act) requesting that the court determine whether a presumption of such a violation exists. If such a motion is timely filed, the court shall hold a hearing not later than 15 days after the date the motion is filed to assess whether a presumption of such a violation exists.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3EA98C4D441746DD9816BEEB8711F772"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Assessment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To conduct the assessment required under subparagraph (A), the court shall do the following:</text> 
<clause id="H6D764AE77D5D49CF8D065B22CF7A181B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Determine the number of congressional districts under the plan that would have been carried by each political party’s candidates for the office of President and the office of Senator in the 2 most recent general elections for the office of President and the 2 most recent general elections for the office of Senator (other than special general elections) immediately preceding the enactment of the plan, except that if a State conducts a primary election for the office of Senator which is open to candidates of all political parties, the primary election shall be used instead of the general election and the number of districts carried by a party’s candidates for the office of Senator shall be determined on the basis of the combined vote share of all candidates in the election who are affiliated with such party.</text></clause> <clause id="HEF28EE9FD48A43118A56BD0B655E78BC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Determine, for each of the 4 elections assessed under clause (i), whether the number of districts that would have been carried by any party’s candidate as determined under clause (i) results in partisan advantage or disadvantage in excess of 7 percent or one congressional district, whichever is greater, as determined by standard quantitative measures of partisan fairness that relate a party's share of the statewide vote to that party's share of seats.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAFBE0716CF22425CB40DDEE53D10C73F"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Presumption of violation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A plan is presumed to violate paragraph (1) if it exceeds the threshold described in clause (ii) of subparagraph (B) with respect to 2 or more of the 4 elections assessed under such subparagraph.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H235870D8080D4D7CB94DB63A419A434C"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Stay of use of plan</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this Act, in any action under this paragraph, the following rules shall apply:</text> 
<clause id="H033153FB707E4E36ACBDBDE4D1F50746"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon filing of a motion under subparagraph (A), a State’s use of the plan which is the subject of the motion shall be automatically stayed pending resolution of such motion.</text></clause> <clause id="H458A24AC7E994FDEA68EEB5795065B2E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If after considering the motion, the court rules that the plan is presumed under subparagraph (C) to violate paragraph (1), a State may not use such plan until and unless the court which is carrying out the determination of the effect of the plan under paragraph (2) determines that, notwithstanding the presumptive violation, the plan does not violate paragraph (1).</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8F3F15D7F1DE4FDFB5D6F4B44620F2A7"><enum>(E)</enum><header>No effect on other assessments</header><text>The absence of a presumption of a violation with respect to a redistricting plan as determined under this paragraph shall not affect the determination of the effect of the plan under paragraph (2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF378F95BDDEA4ADDAD7CDA36A9CDF717"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Determination of intent</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A court may rely on all available evidence when determining whether a redistricting plan was drawn with the intent to materially favor or disfavor a political party, including evidence of the partisan effects of a plan, the degree of support the plan received from members of the entity responsible for developing and adopting the plan, and whether the processes leading to development and adoption of the plan were transparent and equally open to all members of the entity and to the public.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7B518F0125274E0E9F83364996E3A473"><enum>(5)</enum><header>No violation based on certain criteria</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No redistricting plan shall be found to be in violation of paragraph (1) because of the proper application of the criteria set forth in paragraphs (1), (2), or (3) of subsection (b), unless one or more alternative plans could have complied with such paragraphs without having the effect of materially favoring or disfavoring a political party.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H798C6B5DEB424EA7BE6B413BAFAA4D1B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Factors prohibited from consideration</header><text>In developing the redistricting plan for the State, the State may not take into consideration any of the following factors, except as necessary to comply with the criteria described in paragraphs (1) through (3) of subsection (b), to achieve partisan fairness and comply with subsection (b), and to enable the redistricting plan to be measured against the external metrics described in section 203(d):</text> 
<paragraph id="H9C6382DAE74A4E3182F8C0541E4B6341"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The residence of any Member of the House of Representatives or candidate.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4F1BE96385BB4CC1BED56077B303C83A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The political party affiliation or voting history of the population of a district.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF0621220C767489E9C8BBD84D71A5CAF"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Additional criteria</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State may not rely upon criteria not set forth in this section to justify non-compliance with the requirements of this section.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H564AB4C4FCEC4901A80F9332B20EB479"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section applies to any authority, whether appointed, elected, judicial, or otherwise, responsible for enacting the congressional redistricting plan of a State.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H88E9B8C97DE94ECAA32FE8B10BE24A2C"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Severability of criteria</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If any of the criteria set forth in this section, or the application of such criteria to any person or circumstance, is held to be unconstitutional, the remaining criteria set forth in this section, and the application of such criteria to any person or circumstance, shall not be affected by the holding.</text></subsection></section></title> <title id="HD629CA6A09454A8AB936080769EA5E39"><enum>II</enum><header>Independent Redistricting Commissions</header> <section id="H7476C866D647465A80C7831BCE3F3C1F"><enum>201.</enum><header>Independent redistricting commission</header> <subsection id="HA015732E0F2041BCAE26B036BAC3132C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Appointment of members</header> <paragraph id="HB0D120ACA33543419CABB309EB434DD3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The nonpartisan agency established or designated by a State under section 204(a) shall establish an independent redistricting commission for the State, which shall consist of 15 members appointed by the agency as follows:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H36CE9DD34BC04A92BE5722673FB63BDD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Not later than October 1 of a year ending in the numeral zero, the agency shall, at a public meeting held not earlier than 15 days after notice of the meeting has been given to the public, first appoint 6 members as follows:</text> <clause id="H9A59DE2227F64A599BEB2F20ED6F6B7C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The agency shall appoint 2 members on a random basis from the majority category of the approved selection pool (as described in section 202(b)(1)(A)).</text></clause> 
<clause id="H8B040214ACC8478386E446B0BD7497D1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The agency shall appoint 2 members on a random basis from the minority category of the approved selection pool (as described in section 202(b)(1)(B)).</text></clause> <clause id="H2F36F7BF5A814175BE24EE976FD1BBE4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The agency shall appoint 2 members on a random basis from the independent category of the approved selection pool (as described in section 202(b)(1)(C)).</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA6D5A2F009CB41A08A7E992AE12ED95A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Not later than November 15 of a year ending in the numeral zero, the members appointed by the agency under subparagraph (A) shall, at a public meeting held not earlier than 15 days after notice of the meeting has been given to the public, then appoint 9 members as follows:</text> <clause id="HC2A4E71524B84BCA9C16FCFE14DB2905"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The members shall appoint 3 members from the majority category of the approved selection pool (as described in section 202(b)(1)(A)).</text></clause> 
<clause id="HC1496D103FF348DD907D6B8AB8BE7DB9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The members shall appoint 3 members from the minority category of the approved selection pool (as described in section 202(b)(1)(B)).</text></clause> <clause id="HED365B97D1E24AC0A83B52D7D18C3FC6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The members shall appoint 3 members from the independent category of the approved selection pool (as described in section 202(b)(1)(C)).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H21F76B2028264BE69802FFED0114C0B9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rules for appointment of members appointed by first members</header> 
<subparagraph id="H4AF4FA501C2E465593592B46D1614526"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Affirmative vote of at least 4 members</header><text>The appointment of any of the 9 members of the independent redistricting commission who are appointed by the first members of the commission pursuant to subparagraph (B) of paragraph (1), as well as the designation of alternates for such members pursuant to subparagraph (B) of paragraph (3) and the appointment of alternates to fill vacancies pursuant to subparagraph (B) of paragraph (4), shall require the affirmative vote of at least 4 of the members appointed by the nonpartisan agency under subparagraph (A) of paragraph (1), including at least one member from each of the categories referred to in such subparagraph.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAA7CB1430F194387901B4BBC3695AD1D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Ensuring diversity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In appointing the 9 members pursuant to subparagraph (B) of paragraph (1), as well as in designating alternates pursuant to subparagraph (B) of paragraph (3) and in appointing alternates to fill vacancies pursuant to subparagraph (B) of paragraph (4), the first members of the independent redistricting commission shall ensure that the membership is representative of the demographic groups (including racial, ethnic, economic, and gender) and geographic regions of the State, and provides racial, ethnic, and language minorities protected under the Voting Rights Act of 1965 with a meaningful opportunity to participate in the development of the State’s redistricting plan.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE832C506B02244CFA30EABAB00171CC6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Designation of alternates to serve in case of vacancies</header> 
<subparagraph id="HB50202509D0043248628A6ED0ADAF7E2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Members appointed by agency</header><text>At the time the agency appoints the members of the independent redistricting commission under subparagraph (A) of paragraph (1) from each of the categories referred to in such subparagraph, the agency shall, on a random basis, designate 2 other individuals from such category to serve as alternate members who may be appointed to fill vacancies in the commission in accordance with paragraph (4).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H214EB939ED104B1884A9280B8B8BC972"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Members appointed by first members</header><text>At the time the members appointed by the agency appoint the other members of the independent redistricting commission under subparagraph (B) of paragraph (1) from each of the categories referred to in such subparagraph, the members shall, in accordance with the special rules described in paragraph (2), designate 2 other individuals from such category to serve as alternate members who may be appointed to fill vacancies in the commission in accordance with paragraph (4).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H454CC4187A3349BDAC45E2D4845226D9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Appointment of alternates to serve in case of vacancies</header> 
<subparagraph id="H00137BF7650F4493A04E520D83CB6293"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Members appointed by agency</header><text>If a vacancy occurs in the commission with respect to a member who was appointed by the nonpartisan agency under subparagraph (A) of paragraph (1) from one of the categories referred to in such subparagraph, the agency shall fill the vacancy by appointing, on a random basis, one of the 2 alternates from such category who was designated under subparagraph (A) of paragraph (3). At the time the agency appoints an alternate to fill a vacancy under the previous sentence, the agency shall designate, on a random basis, another individual from the same category to serve as an alternate member, in accordance with subparagraph (A) of paragraph (3).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8555487AA75F47E3A149F9B07350063E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Members appointed by first members</header><text>If a vacancy occurs in the commission with respect to a member who was appointed by the first members of the commission under subparagraph (B) of paragraph (1) from one of the categories referred to in such subparagraph, the first members shall, in accordance with the special rules described in paragraph (2), fill the vacancy by appointing one of the 2 alternates from such category who was designated under subparagraph (B) of paragraph (3). At the time the first members appoint an alternate to fill a vacancy under the previous sentence, the first members shall, in accordance with the special rules described in paragraph (2), designate another individual from the same category to serve as an alternate member, in accordance with subparagraph (B) of paragraph (3).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2AB56115AD0F4F4AA17E9577172483CA"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Removal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A member of the independent redistricting commission may be removed by a majority vote of the remaining members of the commission if it is shown by a preponderance of the evidence that the member is not eligible to serve on the commission under section 202(a).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF791D0B311B34B04B1854531C25E2122"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Procedures for Conducting Commission Business</header> <paragraph id="H3699B0D2A93442AE85D287CFBB3F898D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Chair</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Members of an independent redistricting commission established under this section shall select by majority vote one member who was appointed from the independent category of the approved selection pool described in section 202(b)(1)(C) to serve as chair of the commission. The commission may not take any action to develop a redistricting plan for the State under section 203 until the appointment of the commission’s chair.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDE935005B8C44FEBA56DD66618BA3D7F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requiring majority approval for actions</header><text>The independent redistricting commission of a State may not publish and disseminate any draft or final redistricting plan, or take any other action, without the approval of at least—</text> <subparagraph id="H0FAE8DF4DF044D75BEF631CC0D1356A5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a majority of the whole membership of the commission; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEB2F14D78C3645F6BBB381DA51130B3F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>at least one member of the commission appointed from each of the categories of the approved selection pool described in section 202(b)(1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H02F82EE6BD9743B99EA97C7F770C41E0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Quorum</header><text>A majority of the members of the commission shall constitute a quorum.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HEE91B146138840A0A315B0EF0CCFCD23"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Staff; Contractors</header> 
<paragraph id="H6F632C3CDBBC45C3B25D29F1E19AB545"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Staff</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Under a public application process in which all application materials are available for public inspection, the independent redistricting commission of a State shall appoint and set the pay of technical experts, legal counsel, consultants, and such other staff as it considers appropriate, subject to State law.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFBD2CD6CEAB6492D98A6A8A8A42DF57C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contractors</header><text>The independent redistricting commission of a State may enter into such contracts with vendors as it considers appropriate, subject to State law, except that any such contract shall be valid only if approved by the vote of a majority of the members of the commission, including at least one member appointed from each of the categories of the approved selection pool described in section 202(b)(1).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA8BF3EA2F90746A18E6CE527EC04059C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Reports on expenditures for political activity</header> 
<subparagraph id="H5535CDD691EE4999A3CABDBAC51452E0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Report by applicants</header><text>Each individual who applies for a position as an employee of the independent redistricting commission and each vendor who applies for a contract with the commission shall, at the time of applying, file with the commission a report summarizing—</text> <clause id="H3C01480C757646CC9AD1A2DA05165963"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any expenditure for political activity made by such individual or vendor during the 10 most recent calendar years; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H05F1ED08D3774D65A8BFB0CF8DE56D19"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any income received by such individual or vendor during the 10 most recent calendar years which is attributable to an expenditure for political activity.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4915393EABF84324B82809519AA40D4A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Annual reports by employees and vendors</header><text>Each person who is an employee or vendor of the independent redistricting commission shall, not later than 1 year after the person is appointed as an employee or enters into a contract as a vendor (as the case may be) and annually thereafter for each year during which the person serves as an employee or a vendor, file with the commission a report summarizing the expenditures and income described in subparagraph (A) during the 10 most recent calendar years.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5995FC0B2AD14FF19C5FAC63BADEB2D5"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Expenditure for political activity defined</header><text>In this paragraph, the term <term>expenditure for political activity</term> means a disbursement for any of the following:</text> <clause id="H74D6B1B8CFD749BEBE0FE59C1876293F"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An independent expenditure, as defined in section 301(17) of the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/30101">52 U.S.C. 30101(17)</external-xref>).</text></clause> 
<clause id="H3ECDCA9E22CB40AB99D7C861CE1DB396"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>An electioneering communication, as defined in section 304(f)(3) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/30104">52 U.S.C. 30104(f)(3)</external-xref>) or any other public communication, as defined in section 301(22) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/30101">52 U.S.C. 30101(22)</external-xref>) that would be an electioneering communication if it were a broadcast, cable, or satellite communication.</text></clause> <clause id="HAABDF1AF78B048729C344FB519D4729E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Any dues or other payments to trade associations or organizations described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and exempt from tax under section 501(a) of such Code that are, or could reasonably be anticipated to be, used or transferred to another association or organization for a use described in paragraph (1), (2), or (4) of section 501(c) of such Code.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0E6C772E994244BA834DD5A96FECB5C7"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Goal of impartiality</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The commission shall take such steps as it considers appropriate to ensure that any staff appointed under this subsection, and any vendor with whom the commission enters into a contract under this subsection, will work in an impartial manner, and may require any person who applies for an appointment to a staff position or for a vendor’s contract with the commission to provide information on the person’s history of political activity beyond the information on the person’s expenditures for political activity provided in the reports required under paragraph (3) (including donations to candidates, political committees, and political parties) as a condition of the appointment or the contract.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9CAEE0E3C4FE4C3B816A915169DEE851"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Disqualification; waiver</header> <subparagraph id="HB0ED70B16E79417EB9FC0D64C866ECAB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The independent redistricting commission may not appoint an individual as an employee, and may not enter into a contract with a vendor, if the individual or vendor meets any of the criteria for the disqualification of an individual from serving as a member of the commission which are set forth in section 202(a)(2).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE3B5F67AFE1E445990ECE16C9D5493D2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>The commission may by unanimous vote of its members waive the application of subparagraph (A) to an individual or a vendor after receiving and reviewing the report filed by the individual or vendor under paragraph (3).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HEFE49CB99D24497CA11B3710F49B5203"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Termination</header> <paragraph id="H66A62C4EB822440DBD3BB079B9B1B3FF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The independent redistricting commission of a State shall terminate on the earlier of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF3B0BB7E2F3D4BADA13FFDC2D78DA721"><enum>(A)</enum><text>June 14 of the next year ending in the numeral zero; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEBBF576015854D1EB201145154B90A10"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the day on which the nonpartisan agency established or designated by a State under section 204(a) has, in accordance with section 202(b)(1), submitted a selection pool to the Select Committee on Redistricting for the State established under section 204(b).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H27CE88BCDA9A4BD38FBAE2D25A8021B0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Preservation of records</header><text>The State shall ensure that the records of the independent redistricting commission are retained in the appropriate State archive in such manner as may be necessary to enable the State to respond to any civil action brought with respect to congressional redistricting in the State.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H4B336A0809A84F0EBA08F74449983F0B"><enum>202.</enum><header>Establishment of selection pool of individuals eligible to serve as members of commission</header> <subsection id="HAE811812975647608AE13450E27A78F8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Criteria for Eligibility</header> <paragraph id="H2A9C5254EC704F569060AC40A04DC324"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An individual is eligible to serve as a member of an independent redistricting commission if the individual meets each of the following criteria:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HA0D15568F77C41B0B00C64B003D76CDE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>As of the date of appointment, the individual is registered to vote in elections for Federal office held in the State.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7DBF9E72C7044BEB981697C535108112"><enum>(B)</enum><text>During the 3-year period ending on the date of the individual’s appointment, the individual has been continuously registered to vote with the same political party, or has not been registered to vote with any political party.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H25FDDB31D910421CB747FF2945C5455E"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The individual submits to the nonpartisan agency established or designated by a State under section 204, at such time and in such form as the agency may require, an application for inclusion in the selection pool under this section, and includes with the application a written statement, with an attestation under penalty of perjury, containing the following information and assurances:</text> <clause id="H6119D4E238DB42E38FDCDFC8B10260FE"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The full current name and any former names of, and the contact information for, the individual, including an electronic mail address, the address of the individual’s residence, mailing address, and telephone numbers.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H140657B1726D45FAABD6C86F4E61F70F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The individual’s race, ethnicity, gender, age, date of birth, and household income for the most recent taxable year.</text></clause> <clause id="H868E5780AE3F4D2895D73A2A02799A2C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The political party with which the individual is affiliated, if any.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H8DC6165C63F846AF9429F1857AE70DAB"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The reason or reasons the individual desires to serve on the independent redistricting commission, the individual’s qualifications, and information relevant to the ability of the individual to be fair and impartial, including, but not limited to—</text> <subclause id="H7C3ACBF1B12A4333840F8A923AD0BE23"><enum>(I)</enum><text>any involvement with, or financial support of, professional, social, political, religious, or community organizations or causes; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HB59357D0186A4691910FDF37F8C78015"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the individual’s employment and educational history.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H314EE146A2CB48669D768BB23F081938"><enum>(v)</enum><text>An assurance that the individual shall commit to carrying out the individual’s duties under this Act in an honest, independent, and impartial fashion, and to upholding public confidence in the integrity of the redistricting process.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H8A4F3134821142BE89E98F680614C5DE"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>An assurance that, during the covered periods described in paragraph (3), the individual has not taken and will not take any action which would disqualify the individual from serving as a member of the commission under paragraph (2).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6E74878064B04D208335325EC1AD352B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Disqualifications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual is not eligible to serve as a member of the commission if any of the following applies during any of the covered periods described in paragraph (3):</text> 
<subparagraph id="HCB18A71524094368B7D167F1C1329BE1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The individual or (in the case of the covered periods described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (3)) an immediate family member of the individual holds public office or is a candidate for election for public office.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2B207CBC23D1469CB16BF6504755DE44"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The individual or (in the case of the covered periods described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (3)) an immediate family member of the individual serves as an officer of a political party or as an officer, employee, or paid consultant of a campaign committee of a candidate for public office or of any political action committee (as determined in accordance with the law of the State).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF58A3AA55D8A4AA781049A8CCEB5C601"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The individual or (in the case of the covered periods described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (3)) an immediate family member of the individual holds a position as a registered lobbyist under the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1601">2 U.S.C. 1601 et seq.</external-xref>) or an equivalent State or local law.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H32CA2ED1A10E48FEB2389FC6F8053275"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The individual or (in the case of the covered periods described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (3)) an immediate family member of the individual is an employee of an elected public official, a contractor with the government of the State, or a donor to the campaign of any candidate for public office or to any political action committee (other than a donor who, during any of such covered periods, gives an aggregate amount of $1,000 or less to the campaigns of all candidates for all public offices and to all political action committees).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H34588E576FE64F62BEC5EDF3006B6594"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The individual paid a civil money penalty or criminal fine, or was sentenced to a term of imprisonment, for violating any provision of the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/30101">52 U.S.C. 30101 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF4D997B1FC6449AC9CC108ED3358D5FA"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The individual or (in the case of the covered periods described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (3)) an immediate family member of the individual is an agent of a foreign principal under the Foreign Agents Registration Act of 1938, as amended (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/611">22 U.S.C. 611 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6AE33558BFA9412F9EB0AD067DA9992D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered periods described</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>covered period</term> means, with respect to the appointment of an individual to the commission, any of the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HD909F4DD6848410B9ED1FB77E317D395"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The 10-year period ending on the date of the individual’s appointment.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC86B43FBF5754A88887DA44AF61CC862"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The period beginning on the date of the individual’s appointment and ending on August 14 of the next year ending in the numeral one.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7C4A8CEF6D1E4B089126E9242812F255"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The 10-year period beginning on the day after the last day of the period described in subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5FD77D7250DE4A0D894613E65B72DD0C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Immediate family member defined</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>immediate family member</term> means, with respect to an individual, a father, stepfather, mother, stepmother, son, stepson, daughter, stepdaughter, brother, stepbrother, sister, stepsister, husband, wife, father-in-law, or mother-in-law.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H952AB542167743D1B836578A72F8125B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Development and Submission of Selection Pool</header> <paragraph id="HBFBB3A53A80641AFB48F7913F05156F4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than June 15 of each year ending in the numeral zero, the nonpartisan agency established or designated by a State under section 204(a) shall develop and submit to the Select Committee on Redistricting for the State established under section 204(b) a selection pool of 36 individuals who are eligible to serve as members of the independent redistricting commission of the State under this Act, consisting of individuals in the following categories:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H3AEFF8071E8E46CE847090078F49AC66"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A majority category, consisting of 12 individuals who are affiliated with the political party whose candidate received the most votes in the most recent statewide election for Federal office held in the State.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4279D0E8A3BA4A178F3218A511B5F4CC"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A minority category, consisting of 12 individuals who are affiliated with the political party whose candidate received the second most votes in the most recent statewide election for Federal office held in the State.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF7A2BD8FF40E466FAF7415AAF751198F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>An independent category, consisting of 12 individuals who are not affiliated with either of the political parties described in subparagraph (A) or subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB53A38ECE1AB4FC890D84B1C34E0F528"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Factors taken into account in developing pool</header><text>In selecting individuals for the selection pool under this subsection, the nonpartisan agency shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H3FAD41F94A4B455C81BC2F8CEEC95F5D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>ensure that the pool is representative of the demographic groups (including racial, ethnic, economic, and gender) and geographic regions of the State, and includes applicants who would allow racial, ethnic, and language minorities protected under the Voting Rights Act of 1965 a meaningful opportunity to participate in the development of the State’s redistricting plan; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H511F02D6C6A64DD2A2E99B85B92FF1F1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>take into consideration the analytical skills of the individuals selected in relevant fields (including mapping, data management, law, community outreach, demography, and the geography of the State) and their ability to work on an impartial basis.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF4354C1B714A44DF9F4A8BB7086A1A1B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Interviews of applicants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To assist the nonpartisan agency in developing the selection pool under this subsection, the nonpartisan agency shall conduct interviews of applicants under oath. If an individual is included in a selection pool developed under this section, all of the interviews of the individual shall be transcribed and the transcriptions made available on the nonpartisan agency’s website contemporaneously with release of the report under paragraph (6).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0AF6A82A3B414586BEC05ABFBAA6845B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Determination of political party affiliation of individuals in selection pool</header><text>For purposes of this section, an individual shall be considered to be affiliated with a political party only if the nonpartisan agency is able to verify (to the greatest extent possible) the information the individual provides in the application submitted under subsection (a)(1)(C), including by considering additional information provided by other persons with knowledge of the individual’s history of political activity.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF1400DB64C1340E48FD38D7A7D8E334C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Encouraging residents to apply for inclusion in pool</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The nonpartisan agency shall take such steps as may be necessary to ensure that residents of the State across various geographic regions and demographic groups are aware of the opportunity to serve on the independent redistricting commission, including publicizing the role of the panel and using newspapers, broadcast media, and online sources, including ethnic media, to encourage individuals to apply for inclusion in the selection pool developed under this subsection.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6829F44201E84027859CAAEF97783A24"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Report on establishment of selection pool</header><text>At the time the nonpartisan agency submits the selection pool to the Select Committee on Redistricting under paragraph (1), it shall publish and post on the agency’s public website a report describing the process by which the pool was developed, and shall include in the report a description of how the individuals in the pool meet the eligibility criteria of subsection (a) and of how the pool reflects the factors the agency is required to take into consideration under paragraph (2).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H56A038DB21504B738F8D3323021D968C"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Public comment on selection pool</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the 14-day period which begins on the date the nonpartisan agency publishes the report under paragraph (6), the agency shall accept comments from the public on the individuals included in the selection pool. The agency shall post all such comments contemporaneously on the nonpartisan agency’s website and shall transmit them to the Select Committee on Redistricting immediately upon the expiration of such period.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H57B50EE92D3D4EC78446734F8C45E999"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Action by Select Committee</header> <subparagraph id="H37034A2091FA4A529D54123EB9C78872"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not earlier than 15 days and not later than 21 days after receiving the selection pool from the nonpartisan agency under paragraph (1), the Select Committee on Redistricting shall, by majority vote—</text> 
<clause id="H4F3F5A89EDC5495D9B797B890021C8EC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>approve the pool as submitted by the nonpartisan agency, in which case the pool shall be considered the approved selection pool for purposes of section 201(a)(1); or</text></clause> <clause id="H3D0B5AC3DD7B4B6695B012147ABEEC13"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>reject the pool, in which case the nonpartisan agency shall develop and submit a replacement selection pool in accordance with subsection (c).</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5E3B86613F254BB586E7F349DB915890"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inaction deemed rejection</header><text>If the Select Committee on Redistricting fails to approve or reject the pool within the deadline set forth in subparagraph (A), the Select Committee shall be deemed to have rejected the pool for purposes of such subparagraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H816154CB864D4EFE9E832D768AF7B347"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Development of Replacement Selection Pool</header> <paragraph id="H0A2AD9FA7B2A4B9D8418E2E8AE3E4D7F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Select Committee on Redistricting rejects the selection pool submitted by the nonpartisan agency under subsection (b), not later than 14 days after the rejection, the nonpartisan agency shall develop and submit to the Select Committee a replacement selection pool, under the same terms and conditions that applied to the development and submission of the selection pool under paragraphs (1) through (7) of subsection (b). The replacement pool submitted under this paragraph may include individuals who were included in the rejected selection pool submitted under subsection (b), so long as at least one of the individuals in the replacement pool was not included in such rejected pool.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCD16952BC73D478092B7EEA5A1A1C1CF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Action by Select Committee</header> 
<subparagraph id="H0AFA98FDE5BB4C2286A8A7D7C39E3711"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 21 days after receiving the replacement selection pool from the nonpartisan agency under paragraph (1), the Select Committee on Redistricting shall, by majority vote—</text> <clause id="H9569C1F5F1A14F1DAF53C6992C9D09D2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>approve the pool as submitted by the nonpartisan agency, in which case the pool shall be considered the approved selection pool for purposes of section 201(a)(1); or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H0F316AF9BF64483AA09BBB08573DC90E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>reject the pool, in which case the nonpartisan agency shall develop and submit a second replacement selection pool in accordance with subsection (d).</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H42C23E86C87745D7BEC814DACEF5A220"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inaction deemed rejection</header><text>If the Select Committee on Redistricting fails to approve or reject the pool within the deadline set forth in subparagraph (A), the Select Committee shall be deemed to have rejected the pool for purposes of such subparagraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFBA401C2EB1A43C29854CF65726F52E4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Development of Second Replacement Selection Pool</header> 
<paragraph id="H0AA7A971F05142ED91F913C9158A2360"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Select Committee on Redistricting rejects the replacement selection pool submitted by the nonpartisan agency under subsection (c), not later than 14 days after the rejection, the nonpartisan agency shall develop and submit to the Select Committee a second replacement selection pool, under the same terms and conditions that applied to the development and submission of the selection pool under paragraphs (1) through (7) of subsection (b). The second replacement selection pool submitted under this paragraph may include individuals who were included in the rejected selection pool submitted under subsection (b) or the rejected replacement selection pool submitted under subsection (c), so long as at least one of the individuals in the replacement pool was not included in either such rejected pool.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H259DCFB55C474175A3FACD769C717747"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Action by Select Committee</header> <subparagraph id="H878EF88AE4CD4F1A97779217BDBA0D4A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not earlier than 15 days and not later than 14 days after receiving the second replacement selection pool from the nonpartisan agency under paragraph (1), the Select Committee on Redistricting shall, by majority vote—</text> 
<clause id="H96C1C547E856491885C0C537C1FC8233"><enum>(i)</enum><text>approve the pool as submitted by the nonpartisan agency, in which case the pool shall be considered the approved selection pool for purposes of section 201(a)(1); or</text></clause> <clause id="H6A46E462206941278BF7A9E76696AF2F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>reject the pool.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF0E98C89B60D40C9A7184B93D76E71C2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inaction deemed rejection</header><text>If the Select Committee on Redistricting fails to approve or reject the pool within the deadline set forth in subparagraph (A), the Select Committee shall be deemed to have rejected the pool for purposes of such subparagraph.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDE06E28F82DF4F1392195A6A66CF7759"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Effect of rejection</header><text>If the Select Committee on Redistricting rejects the second replacement pool from the nonpartisan agency under paragraph (1), the redistricting plan for the State shall be developed and enacted in accordance with title III.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HAF234BCC22014D8A89AB7C41BDE124BF" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>203.</enum><header>Public notice and input</header> 
<subsection id="H8688730230584FEBB362B9CB2D53C548"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Public notice and input</header> 
<paragraph id="H34FB79C3CFEA4F5B862BEEA3EADDC366"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Use of open and transparent process</header><text>The independent redistricting commission of a State shall hold each of its meetings in public, shall solicit and take into consideration comments from the public, including proposed maps, throughout the process of developing the redistricting plan for the State, and shall carry out its duties in an open and transparent manner which provides for the widest public dissemination reasonably possible of its proposed and final redistricting plans.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0452307D93F9438BB02479E514D05151"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Website</header> <subparagraph id="HD51232C383D64ADF84F3C7638ED7725E"> <enum>(A)</enum> <header>Features</header> <text>The commission shall maintain a public internet site which is not affiliated with or maintained by the office of any elected official and which includes the following features:</text>
              <clause id="HEF877E1894684C53897202DBB6EB61C7">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>General information on the commission, its role in the redistricting process, and its members, including contact information.</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="HFD94E514B9C746DB83AE68A9E22112DB">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>An updated schedule of commission hearings and activities, including deadlines for the submission of comments.</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="H11EDD6BFF2F8427392EA2E6AADF5A20F">
                <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>All draft redistricting plans developed by the commission under subsection (b) and the final redistricting plan developed under subsection (c), including the accompanying written evaluation under subsection (d).</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="H234AC24013EF409C94FB3CDB33A74DBD">
                <enum>(iv)</enum>
 <text>All comments received from the public on the commission’s activities, including any proposed maps submitted under paragraph (1).</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="H65E9CF66CD774D44A034C0DCAF504259">
                <enum>(v)</enum>
 <text>Live streaming of commission hearings and an archive of previous meetings, including any documents considered at any such meeting, which the commission shall post not later than 24 hours after the conclusion of the meeting.</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="HA568290C5A784923856657B707B07DA1">
                <enum>(vi)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Access in an easily useable format to the demographic and other data used by the commission to develop and analyze the proposed redistricting plans, together with access to any software used to draw maps of proposed districts and to any reports analyzing and evaluating any such maps.</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="H413537BDE17F4ACE888DCC291F86E0B1">
                <enum>(vii)</enum>
 <text>A method by which members of the public may submit comments and proposed maps directly to the commission.</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="H7F15B87E34C84375B60331D0D28233C0">
                <enum>(viii)</enum>
 <text>All records of the commission, including all communications to or from members, employees, and contractors regarding the work of the commission.</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="H9B4336E665C34FCF8934F9E73B0A0C62">
                <enum>(ix)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A list of all contractors receiving payment from the commission, together with the annual disclosures submitted by the contractors under section 201(c)(3).</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="HCA7549A4082F4C7C9F7EDCDD9667D024">
                <enum>(x)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A list of the names of all individuals who submitted applications to serve on the commission, together with the applications submitted by individuals included in any selection pool, except that the commission may redact from such applications any financial or other personally sensitive information.</text>
              </clause>
            </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCE50D31A499E4AF19BA7F418FCEE06CE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Searchable format</header><text>The commission shall ensure that all information posted and maintained on the site under this paragraph, including information and proposed maps submitted by the public, shall be maintained in an easily searchable format.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA53F79FD09284DD1A1569090B6A04F7C"> <enum>(C)</enum> <header>Deadline</header> <text>The commission shall ensure that the public internet site under this paragraph is operational (in at least a preliminary format) not later than January 1 of the year ending in the numeral one.</text>
            </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H495CDE56509646119FCEE93FCE5CA0DE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public comment period</header><text>The commission shall solicit, accept, and consider comments from the public with respect to its duties, activities, and procedures at any time during the period—</text> <subparagraph id="HE870F4A18837406FB9ABA684FEC7BDDE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>which begins on January 1 of the year ending in the numeral one; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC08EC6CAD803487287BBD4D7A5E69D3E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">which ends 7 days before the date of the meeting at which the commission shall vote on approving the final redistricting plan for enactment into law under subsection (c)(2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD61D2B4EB29245E8961077A3AA037489"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Meetings and hearings in various geographic locations</header><text>To the greatest extent practicable, the commission shall hold its meetings and hearings in various geographic regions and locations throughout the State.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0C773DCDD73244FC87F3287C28044DDC"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Multiple language requirements for all notices</header><text>The commission shall make each notice which is required to be posted and published under this section available in any language in which the State (or any jurisdiction in the State) is required to provide election materials under section 203 of the Voting Rights Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/10503">52 U.S.C. 10503</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H166A304282904B5298D835856B176D78" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Development and Publication of Preliminary Redistricting Plan</header> <paragraph id="H438081F2B4764A3490B3F291C68C694A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Prior to developing and publishing a final redistricting plan under subsection (c), the independent redistricting commission of a State shall develop and publish a preliminary redistricting plan.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H000A1FCC7544497884DFD19641A7D038"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Minimum public hearings and opportunity for comment prior to development</header> 
<subparagraph id="H98ED5D7B5C4F4193BB160DFB686EF7EF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>3 hearings required</header><text>Prior to developing a preliminary redistricting plan under this subsection, the commission shall hold not fewer than 3 public hearings at which members of the public may provide input and comments regarding the potential contents of redistricting plans for the State and the process by which the commission will develop the preliminary plan under this subsection.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE229414E510C46A0A723B1E92BE70429"> <enum>(B)</enum> <header>Minimum period for notice prior to hearings</header> <text>Not fewer than 14 days prior to the date of each hearing held under this paragraph, the commission shall post notices of the hearing on the website maintained under subsection (a)(2), and shall provide for the publication of such notices in newspapers of general circulation throughout the State. Each such notice shall specify the date, time, and location of the hearing.</text>
            </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2F902B7BA3564E6396BA6FA33161DF59"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Submission of plans and maps by members of the public</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any member of the public may submit maps or portions of maps for consideration by the commission. As provided under subsection (a)(2)(A), any such map shall be made publicly available on the commission’s website and open to comment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3FB6DB13A8BD4EF1BFA43A43B492700B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Publication of preliminary plan</header> <subparagraph id="H8162F724A45B44A3988B4565C7F46EAC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The commission shall post the preliminary redistricting plan developed under this subsection, together with a report that includes the commission’s responses to any public comments received under subsection (a)(3), on the website maintained under subsection (a)(2), and shall provide for the publication of each such plan in newspapers of general circulation throughout the State.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H92149988479742C1A873CB999BDD4E4E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Minimum period for notice prior to publication</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not fewer than 14 days prior to the date on which the commission posts and publishes the preliminary plan under this paragraph, the commission shall notify the public through the website maintained under subsection (a)(2), as well as through publication of notice in newspapers of general circulation throughout the State, of the pending publication of the plan.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEB65F1D22FC147D3B7C12A320BE5C6B9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Minimum post-publication period for public comment</header><text>The commission shall accept and consider comments from the public (including through the website maintained under subsection (a)(2)) with respect to the preliminary redistricting plan published under paragraph (3), including proposed revisions to maps, for not fewer than 30 days after the date on which the plan is published.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEDE4BDDF51E8436A8DE101490B66FDF9"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Post-publication hearings</header> 
<subparagraph id="HEA94EF605EBD46B997C4921AFD346321"><enum>(A)</enum><header>3 hearings required</header><text>After posting and publishing the preliminary redistricting plan under paragraph (3), the commission shall hold not fewer than 3 public hearings in different geographic areas of the State at which members of the public may provide input and comments regarding the preliminary plan.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H67F0FADDD82A4967888E7AF82B527629"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Minimum period for notice prior to hearings</header><text>Not fewer than 14 days prior to the date of each hearing held under this paragraph, the commission shall post notices of the hearing on the website maintained under subsection (a)(2), and shall provide for the publication of such notices in newspapers of general circulation throughout the State. Each such notice shall specify the date, time, and location of the hearing.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFEF12E5F736C417594DA9379066F73F0"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Permitting multiple preliminary plans</header><text>At the option of the commission, after developing and publishing the preliminary redistricting plan under this subsection, the commission may develop and publish subsequent preliminary redistricting plans, so long as the process for the development and publication of each such subsequent plan meets the requirements set forth in this subsection for the development and publication of the first preliminary redistricting plan.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF72EE22CAB3644D0BFA90FAC5C20E3A6" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Process for Enactment of Final Redistricting Plan</header> <paragraph id="HFF3BB167C4D14749B8F71EC5565B0339"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After taking into consideration comments from the public on any preliminary redistricting plan developed and published under subsection (b), the independent redistricting commission of a State shall develop and publish a final redistricting plan for the State.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H96432BA4D7824C9DB10EF7884330E2DD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Meeting; final vote</header><text>Not later than the deadline specified in subsection (e), the commission shall hold a public hearing at which the members of the commission shall vote on approving the final plan for enactment into law.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H881F6E5B6D754839B4D7964E4832047F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Publication of plan and accompanying materials</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not fewer than 14 days before the date of the meeting under paragraph (2), the commission shall provide the following information to the public through the website maintained under subsection (a)(2), as well as through newspapers of general circulation throughout the State:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB0C7F3C5A07346BD91FAA19922DAB2EF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The final redistricting plan, including all relevant maps.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC6F2D009D5F545AF91C0D1E45B844986"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A report by the commission to accompany the plan which provides the background for the plan and the commission’s reasons for selecting the plan as the final redistricting plan, including responses to the public comments received on any preliminary redistricting plan developed and published under subsection (b).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H44215F489BD548B4B7D5E0AF6AF5E3C5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Any dissenting or additional views with respect to the plan of individual members of the commission.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H248806BADD59427599E33B4EF5965E6B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Enactment</header><text>Subject to paragraph (5), the final redistricting plan developed and published under this subsection shall be deemed to be enacted into law upon the expiration of the 45-day period which begins on the date on which—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD84BA4D844D848BF986E684EF815CB4C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such final plan is approved by a majority of the whole membership of the commission; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA2DC72010EDE4867B5C87F5922618243"><enum>(B)</enum><text>at least one member of the commission appointed from each of the categories of the approved selection pool described in section 202(b)(1) approves such final plan.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H04D6820336CD445D85A9572F8F50325F"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Review by Department of Justice</header> 
<subparagraph id="H37294A19E5EB49F38A2641723A805925"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Requiring submission of plan for review</header><text>The final redistricting plan shall not be deemed to be enacted into law unless the State submits the plan to the Department of Justice for an administrative review to determine if the plan is in compliance with the criteria described in subsections (b) and (c) of section 103.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H973486AF455246EDA1C3890A78EBFF96"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Termination of review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Department of Justice shall terminate any administrative review under subparagraph (A) if, during the 45-day period which begins on the date the plan is enacted into law, an action is filed in a United States district court alleging that the plan is not in compliance with the criteria described in subsections (b) and (c) of section 103.</text></subparagraph> </paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2C677480BEF94ABB81CC01848EFECE41" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Written evaluation of plan against external metrics</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The independent redistricting commission shall include with each redistricting plan developed and published under this section a written evaluation that measures each such plan against external metrics which cover the criteria set forth in section 103(a), including the impact of the plan on the ability of communities of color to elect candidates of choice, measures of partisan fairness using multiple accepted methodologies, and the degree to which the plan preserves or divides communities of interest.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H919B6C64A6EF4019BAC73DC65FE73572"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Timing</header><text>The independent redistricting commission of a State may begin its work on the redistricting plan of the State upon receipt of relevant population information from the Bureau of the Census, and shall approve a final redistricting plan for the State in each year ending in the numeral one not later than 8 months after the date on which the State receives the State apportionment notice or October 1, whichever occurs later.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HC73A38FA1FAA4916A00A5AABBE4863F8"><enum>204.</enum><header>Establishment of related entities</header> 
<subsection id="HCDAA6A75CB8A4305A9B5CD2D3AA4DF69"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment or Designation of Nonpartisan Agency of State Legislature</header> 
<paragraph id="H2B9AACBF04434C5B899BC224FE604CC1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each State shall establish a nonpartisan agency in the legislative branch of the State government to appoint the members of the independent redistricting commission for the State in accordance with section 201.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H215A5A4D26884E97B3A373E3064346A3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Nonpartisanship described</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, an agency shall be considered to be nonpartisan if under law the agency—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H8B1C7D60856048C091AE55CD6004F37D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is required to provide services on a nonpartisan basis;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6D25E270388F404A9192C9DC1EAFCDCF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is required to maintain impartiality; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H84B21DAED3F64740A6BCEBCBC7A083BF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is prohibited from advocating for the adoption or rejection of any legislative proposal.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8681E08944294930B25115159808E027"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Training of members appointed to commission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than January 15 of a year ending in the numeral one, the nonpartisan agency established or designated under this subsection shall provide the members of the independent redistricting commission with initial training on their obligations as members of the commission, including obligations under the Voting Rights Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/10301">52 U.S.C. 10301 et seq.</external-xref>) and other applicable laws.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H358C15F82DD14EB18B12EEA3529D88CA"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The nonpartisan agency established or designated under this subsection shall adopt and publish regulations, after notice and opportunity for comment, establishing the procedures that the agency will follow in fulfilling its duties under this Act, including the procedures to be used in vetting the qualifications and political affiliation of applicants and in creating the selection pools, the randomized process to be used in selecting the initial members of the independent redistricting commission, and the rules that the agency will apply to ensure that the agency carries out its duties under this Act in a maximally transparent, publicly accessible, and impartial manner.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H237A28440C804A8DA9BA685C201FF436"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Designation of existing agency</header><text>At its option, a State may designate an existing agency in the legislative branch of its government to appoint the members of the independent redistricting commission plan for the State under this Act, so long as the agency meets the requirements for nonpartisanship under this subsection.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD6C75F0AB72E4433A3CB6FFC5F13FBD6"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Termination of agency specifically established for redistricting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a State does not designate an existing agency under paragraph (5) but instead establishes a new agency to serve as the nonpartisan agency under this section, the new agency shall terminate upon the enactment into law of the redistricting plan for the State.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3ECFFAE3572849B8B5C7713CC1E14E92"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Preservation of records</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The State shall ensure that the records of the nonpartisan agency are retained in the appropriate State archive in such manner as may be necessary to enable the State to respond to any civil action brought with respect to congressional redistricting in the State.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H55BABF202FDC4EA6B4D4A9A954BD5DAF"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Deadline</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The State shall meet the requirements of this subsection not later than each October 15 of a year ending in the numeral nine.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HBAD8809856D34D108C42BD043D26085B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment of Select Committee on Redistricting</header> <paragraph id="HC1DE87E5E1194579BD1CE49F5C199B60"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each State shall appoint a Select Committee on Redistricting to approve or disapprove a selection pool developed by the independent redistricting commission for the State under section 202.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H53CF5AAE1122411EA523AE13079DDFB6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appointment</header><text>The Select Committee on Redistricting for a State under this subsection shall consist of the following members:</text> <subparagraph id="H3F9C841EDBF44922986DD42C54D66B74"><enum>(A)</enum><text>One member of the upper house of the State legislature, who shall be appointed by the leader of the party with the greatest number of seats in the upper house.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDE22F9B769834BB09799EFD9ABC5250C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>One member of the upper house of the State legislature, who shall be appointed by the leader of the party with the second greatest number of seats in the upper house.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1CA215886C8A45CC8C4AD9BEA355ADC9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>One member of the lower house of the State legislature, who shall be appointed by the leader of the party with the greatest number of seats in the lower house.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD14CC13C7CDC49BDB31450DD1136F288"><enum>(D)</enum><text>One member of the lower house of the State legislature, who shall be appointed by the leader of the party with the second greatest number of seats in the lower house.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H552CF41EBBA04E3C8B8739D3A785AAB1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Special rule for States with unicameral legislature</header><text>In the case of a State with a unicameral legislature, the Select Committee on Redistricting for the State under this subsection shall consist of the following members:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HFDE8706814DD45BE85839E105B4E8903"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Two members of the State legislature appointed by the chair of the political party of the State whose candidate received the highest percentage of votes in the most recent statewide election for Federal office held in the State.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEB7B52DBFF91404DA87C45F6189E3A97"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Two members of the State legislature appointed by the chair of the political party whose candidate received the second highest percentage of votes in the most recent statewide election for Federal office held in the State.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4E41FD6ED0E04E93BDD02B719600E31E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Deadline</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The State shall meet the requirements of this subsection not later than each January 15 of a year ending in the numeral zero.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC353698CE9CB467A8400A33B95EF5451"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this subsection may be construed to prohibit the leader of any political party in a legislature from appointment to the Select Committee on Redistricting.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H57CD8E5C153544B09E918504289881DF"><enum>205.</enum><header>Report on diversity of memberships of independent redistricting commissions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than May 15 of a year ending in the numeral one, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report on the extent to which the memberships of independent redistricting commissions for States established under this title with respect to the immediately preceding year ending in the numeral zero meet the diversity requirements as provided for in sections 201(a)(2)(B) and 202(b)(2).</text></section></title> <title id="H5D016F31BB824ACEB0DF394AF8391A8E"><enum>III</enum><header>Role of Courts in Development of Redistricting Plans</header> <section id="HADFE0A7A7A4041789518C0445316BA72"><enum>301.</enum><header>Failure by State to enact plan</header> <subsection id="H2C3DC4FB43F043DB90A62A48288DD55A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Deadline for enactment of plan</header><text>Each State shall enact a final congressional redistricting plan following transmission of a notice of apportionment to the President by the earliest of—</text> 
<paragraph id="H3D8B99193BD442CEAC95C7F99F78C2E2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the deadline set forth in State law;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H11A76C6C7D54443691E93498BC1D5F39"><enum>(2)</enum><text>February 15 of the year in which regularly scheduled general elections for Federal office are held in the State; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7D8E4BC4AC154ED8B0527AAF3CAFA0F6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>90 days before the date of the next regularly scheduled primary election for Federal office held in the State.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD498D8F5CAEA4ECB92746AB70F338564"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Development of plan by court in case of missed deadline</header><text>If a State has not enacted a final congressional redistricting plan by the applicable deadline under subsection (a), or it appears likely that a State will fail to enact a final congressional redistricting plan by such deadline—</text> 
<paragraph id="H4F0323A81989412685DA04BB0FD770F6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any citizen of the State may file an action in the United States district court for the applicable venue asking the district court to assume jurisdiction;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE7A811819DB241ABB825F8948CBA6FBE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the United States district court for the applicable venue, acting through a 3-judge court convened pursuant to section 2284 of title 28, United States Code, shall have the exclusive authority to develop and publish the congressional redistricting plan for the State; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD6F93D7BC12449BBAF9D97CAB063485C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the final congressional redistricting plan developed and published by the court under this section shall be deemed to be enacted on the date on which the court publishes the final congressional redistricting plan, as described in subsection (e).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H32664877EB7F45E08E59F3B5CF77B911"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applicable venue</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the <quote>applicable venue</quote> with respect to a State is the District of Columbia or the judicial district in which the capital of the State is located, as selected by the first party to file with the court sufficient evidence that a State has failed to, or is reasonably likely to fail to, enact a final redistricting plan for the State prior to the expiration of the applicable deadline set forth in subsection (a).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD8986E15D5964A4B85964D7E74AACF1E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Procedures for Development of Plan</header> 
<paragraph id="HBAA4B73D6A4149919259EF39EC8A6522"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Criteria</header><text>In developing a redistricting plan for a State under this section, the court shall adhere to the same terms and conditions that applied (or that would have applied, as the case may be) to the development of a plan by the State under section 103.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9D4C6E528AC548F3A2EE8A1BA5C5847F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Access to information and records</header><text>The court shall have access to any information, data, software, or other records and material that was used (or that would have been used, as the case may be) by the State in carrying out its duties under this title.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB380F67F35954D40AB38C03516A3FFA3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Hearing; public participation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In developing a redistricting plan for a State, the court shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H7C5B5A720D3D4887ACEDB04ECB146B48"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">hold one or more evidentiary hearings at which interested members of the public may appear and be heard and present testimony, including expert testimony, in accordance with the rules of the court; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFFC4F7FF4342404D8CE9F5853CFEE6E1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>consider other submissions and comments by the public, including proposals for redistricting plans to cover the entire State or any portion of the State.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H32B10F6DF520432C8D70BC8BDDFB5DC7"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Use of special master</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To assist in the development and publication of a redistricting plan for a State under this section, the court may appoint a special master to make recommendations to the court on possible plans for the State.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB290774AADA34C9E830D18E4FC3B6A73"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Publication of plan</header> 
<paragraph id="HE6CE8F48B1AF45609A81064202CFEF7F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Public availability of initial plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon completing the development of one or more initial redistricting plans, the court shall make the plans available to the public at no cost, and shall also make available the underlying data used to develop the plans and a written evaluation of the plans against external metrics (as described in section 203(d)).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H507F02B2237842BBA034147BDDF0CB66"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Publication of final plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At any time after the expiration of the 14-day period which begins on the date the court makes the plans available to the public under paragraph (1), and taking into consideration any submissions and comments by the public which are received during such period, the court shall develop and publish the final redistricting plan for the State.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H43AD825C167D4E039B5004250DD8018C"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Use of interim plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the event that the court is not able to develop and publish a final redistricting plan for the State with sufficient time for an upcoming election to proceed, the court may develop and publish an interim redistricting plan which shall serve as the redistricting plan for the State until the court develops and publishes a final plan in accordance with this section. Nothing in this subsection may be construed to limit or otherwise affect the authority or discretion of the court to develop and publish the final redistricting plan, including the discretion to make any changes the court deems necessary to an interim redistricting plan.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HAA4365B9EE5747909C9FED33A192DC84"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Appeals</header><text>Review on appeal of any final or interim plan adopted by the court in accordance with this section shall be governed by the appellate process in section 402.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7F348C69988A4F45A894E5C7DC1CF036"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Stay of State proceedings</header><text>The filing of an action under this section shall act as a stay of any proceedings in State court with respect to the State’s congressional redistricting plan unless otherwise ordered by the court.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H78C04FBC084F43228F91FB4704CA8EF7"><enum>302.</enum><header>Special rule for redistricting conducted under order of Federal court</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If a Federal court requires a State to conduct redistricting subsequent to an apportionment of Representatives in the State in order to comply with the Constitution or to enforce the Voting Rights Act of 1965, section 203 shall apply with respect to the redistricting, except that the court may revise any of the deadlines set forth in such section if the court determines that a revision is appropriate in order to provide for a timely enactment of a new redistricting plan for the State.</text></section></title> 
<title id="HD025BB3E7C1A4FEC84A906DDE2FA756E"><enum>IV</enum><header>Administrative and Miscellaneous Provisions</header> 
<section id="H02C012DEC90346EE9797945DE07F4AE7"><enum>401.</enum><header>Payments to States for carrying out redistricting</header> 
<subsection id="H84D86408E5E640EBBACCC4400F8560B0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization of payments</header><text>Subject to subsection (d), not later than 30 days after a State receives a State apportionment notice, the Election Assistance Commission shall, subject to the availability of appropriations provided pursuant to subsection (e), make a payment to the State in an amount equal to the product of—</text> <paragraph id="HAE75A68AE6C549B798500941F53320A8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the number of Representatives to which the State is entitled, as provided under the notice; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4502FD3767E743CBBBC85AEFC3458C8B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$150,000.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H7E15418B513342BF988C13CFE12E8CDD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>A State shall use the payment made under this section to establish and operate the State’s independent redistricting commission, to implement the State redistricting plan, and to otherwise carry out congressional redistricting in the State.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7D29A90E09704F4AA33D1EB4BC2C15EB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>No payment to states with single member</header><text>The Election Assistance Commission shall not make a payment under this section to any State which is not entitled to more than one Representative under its State apportionment notice.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H0328AF91962D4F069914484358A37FAC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Requiring Submission of Selection Pool as Condition of Payment</header> <paragraph id="HC60F8108F22B4C0AAAE0F11BDE0B7A68"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2) and paragraph (3), the Election Assistance Commission may not make a payment to a State under this section until the State certifies to the Commission that the nonpartisan agency established or designated by a State under section 204(a) has, in accordance with section 202(b)(1), submitted a selection pool to the Select Committee on Redistricting for the State established under section 204(b).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H66692432330B4C3D85A6C8EECE95404B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception for States with existing commissions</header><text>In the case of a State which, pursuant to section 101(c), is exempt from the requirements of section 101(a), the Commission may not make a payment to the State under this section until the State certifies to the Commission that its redistricting commission meets the requirements of section 101(c).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0ACD645B042E4221BBD43C1598489FD6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exception for State of Iowa</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of the State of Iowa, the Commission may not make a payment to the State under this section until the State certifies to the Commission that it will carry out congressional redistricting pursuant to the State’s apportionment notice in accordance with a plan developed by the Iowa Legislative Services Agency with the assistance of a Temporary Redistricting Advisory Commission, as provided under the law described in section 101(d).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H303FA66878ED4AF3B3677CCAD07F8B78"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary for payments under this section.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HAA58BC03731B4F0AB2FFDC9996D3553D"><enum>402.</enum><header>Civil enforcement</header> <subsection id="H1C7490279639493788E552D975E649F3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Civil Enforcement</header> <paragraph id="H7F691A57785E4C6CAFC664BE9A8B45E5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Actions by Attorney General</header><text>The Attorney General may bring a civil action for such relief as may be appropriate to carry out this Act.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H27586DDFDEA94723A493F7D94AB5FA57"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Availability of private right of action</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any citizen of a State who is aggrieved by the failure of the State to meet the requirements of the Constitution or Federal law, including this Act, with respect to the State's congressional redistricting, may bring a civil action in the United States district court for the applicable venue for such relief as may be appropriate to remedy the failure.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1BAD2FFE72734695A8DE98B3E60FB35F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Delivery of complaint to House and Senate</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In any action brought under this section, a copy of the complaint shall be delivered promptly to the Clerk of the House of Representatives and the Secretary of the Senate.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H839F98C9B37F48F89033BC9373499FAB"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Exclusive jurisdiction and applicable venue</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The district courts of the United States shall have exclusive jurisdiction to hear and determine claims asserting that a congressional redistricting plan violates the requirements of the Constitution or Federal law, including this Act. The applicable venue for such an action shall be the United States District Court for the District of Columbia or for the judicial district in which the capital of the State is located, as selected by the person bringing the action, except that the applicable venue for a civil action that includes a claim that a redistricting plan is in violation of section 103(c) shall be the District of Columbia.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H08340025418F446FBD31F55EE06B5D52"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Use of 3-judge court</header><text>If an action under this section raises statewide claims under the Constitution or this Act, the action shall be heard by a 3-judge court convened pursuant to section 2284 of title 28, United States Code.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE7A35D997F0640E98689A3E2B1A4128B"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Review of final decision</header><text>A final decision in an action brought under this section shall be reviewable on appeal by the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit. There shall be no right of appeal in such proceedings to any other court of appeals. Such appeal shall be taken by the filing of a notice of appeal within 10 days of the entry of the final decision. A final decision by the Court of Appeals may be reviewed by the Supreme Court of the United States by writ of certiorari.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H958240BF0FDB427E8F053B43B4A4225C" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Expedited Consideration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In any action brought under this section, it shall be the duty of the district court, the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit, and the Supreme Court of the United States (if it chooses to hear the action) to advance on the docket and to expedite to the greatest possible extent the disposition of the action and appeal.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2DDCE0F56CFF4D2BA2EB6AAE99FD094E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Remedies</header> 
<paragraph id="H328ABE23227B4D1EBC07F62D37CCB4BD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Adoption of replacement plan</header> 
<subparagraph id="H371B67C5A29849FC932675E6A8041235"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the district court in an action under this section finds that the congressional redistricting plan of a State violates, in whole or in part, the requirements of this Act—</text> <clause id="H403ECD39F02C4F5EBDBE0558C6BD78C7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the court shall adopt a replacement congressional redistricting plan for the State in accordance with the process set forth in section 301; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="HDB155F564FBE4230AE088EE8F447A4BA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if circumstances warrant and no delay to an upcoming regularly scheduled election for the House of Representatives in the State would result, the district court, in its discretion, may allow a State to develop and propose a remedial congressional redistricting plan for review by the court to determine whether the plan is in compliance with this Act, except that—</text> <subclause id="H3098C5E62CA24AB597B957B840F582F4"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the State may not develop and propose a remedial plan under this clause if the court determines that the congressional redistricting plan of the State was enacted with discriminatory intent in violation of the Constitution or section 103(b); and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HFBC57CE7CA1B451A86E49E3DA4028712"><enum>(II)</enum><text>nothing in this clause may be construed to permit a State to use such a remedial plan which has not been approved by the court.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9EAA742A46234837B057E673FD346CE2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Prohibiting use of plans in violation of requirements</header><text>No court shall order a State to use a congressional redistricting plan which violates, in whole or in part, the requirements of this Act, or to conduct an election under terms and conditions which violate, in whole or in part, the requirements of this Act.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9E284AF5C89145CFA6FA62BAB17C8F4A"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Special rule in case final adjudication not expected within 3 months of election</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If final adjudication of an action under this section is not reasonably expected to be completed at least 3 months prior to the next regularly scheduled primary election for the House of Representatives in the State, the district court shall, as the balance of equities warrant—</text> <clause id="H70F64B07724E48ABBE8A37B6A18B9EC3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>develop, adopt, and order the use of an interim congressional redistricting plan in accordance with section 301(f) to address any claims under this Act for which a party seeking relief has demonstrated a substantial likelihood of success; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H853EF9FF318B4ECC8A1041FA47D9803C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>order adjustments to the timing of primary elections for the House of Representatives and other related deadlines, as needed, to allow sufficient opportunity for adjudication of the matter and adoption of a remedial or replacement plan for use in the next regularly scheduled general elections for the House of Representatives.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H81E4242283EE4656845750F5981ED84F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>No stay pending appeal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding the appeal of an order finding that a congressional redistricting plan of a State violates, in whole or in part, the requirements of this Act, no stay shall issue which shall bar the development or adoption of a replacement or remedial plan under this subsection, as may be directed by the district court, pending such appeal. If such a replacement or remedial plan has been adopted, no appellate court may stay or otherwise enjoin the use of such plan during the pendency of an appeal, except upon an order holding, based on the record, that adoption of such plan was an abuse of discretion.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFE934008FDEB4413A62ED5C94D70EB26"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Special authority of Court of Appeals</header> 
<subparagraph id="H64D5F5189AB74FA0B6609CD23DAF71DC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Ordering of new remedial plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If, upon consideration of an appeal under this title, the Court of Appeals determines that a plan does not comply with the requirements of this Act, it shall direct that the District Court promptly develop a new remedial plan with assistance of a special master for consideration by the Court of Appeals.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFC93257CAD1E4786A6203DC2F7309AA8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Failure of district court to take timely action</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If, at any point during the pendency of an action under this section, the District Court fails to take action necessary to permit resolution of the case prior to the next regularly scheduled election for the House of Representatives in the State or fails to grant the relief described in paragraph (1)(C), any party may seek a writ of mandamus from the Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit. The Court of Appeals shall have jurisdiction over the motion for a writ of mandamus and shall establish an expedited briefing and hearing schedule for resolution of the motion. If the Court of Appeals determines that a writ should be granted, the Court of Appeals shall take any action necessary, including developing a congressional redistricting plan with assistance of a special master to ensure that a remedial plan is adopted in time for use in the next regularly scheduled election for the House of Representatives in the State.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H09D24699DE80475DA66C002A18308F19"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Effect of enactment of replacement plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State’s enactment of a redistricting plan which replaces a plan which is the subject of an action under this section shall not be construed to limit or otherwise affect the authority of the court to adjudicate or grant relief with respect to any claims or issues not addressed by the replacement plan, including claims that the plan which is the subject of the action was enacted, in whole or in part, with discriminatory intent, or claims to consider whether relief should be granted under section 3(c) of the Voting Rights Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/10302">52 U.S.C. 10302(c)</external-xref>) based on the plan which is the subject of the action.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HEEF02A608427456EAE06CC91373D71A2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Attorney’s Fees</header><text>In a civil action under this section, the court may allow the prevailing party (other than the United States) reasonable attorney fees, including litigation expenses, and costs.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H378AB11279A74FCBBD114FBFD40C3447"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Relation to Other Laws</header> 
<paragraph id="HA411461C9E964BDDB1B060DFA0E03672"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Rights and remedies additional to other rights and remedies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The rights and remedies established by this section are in addition to all other rights and remedies provided by law, and neither the rights and remedies established by this section nor any other provision of this Act shall supersede, restrict, or limit the application of the Voting Rights Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/10301">52 U.S.C. 10301 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1247E13D9BAF40118F3595233F3FDEAB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Voting Rights Act of 1965</header><text>Nothing in this Act authorizes or requires conduct that is prohibited by the Voting Rights Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/10301">52 U.S.C. 10301 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA1AA8F1EF8614FB0AFC8BFA23800764F"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Legislative privilege</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No person, legislature, or State may claim legislative privilege under either State or Federal law in a civil action brought under this section or in any other legal challenge, under either State or Federal law, to a redistricting plan enacted under this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H1DE7FDE60B5845C5B8B5B8D8149E7BC1"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Removal</header> <paragraph id="HE70D570C455045EE8673AF715A4576DA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>At any time, a civil action brought in a State court which asserts a claim for which the district courts of the United States have exclusive jurisdiction under this title may be removed by any party in the case, including an intervenor, by filing, in the district court for an applicable venue under this section, a notice of removal signed pursuant to Rule 11 of the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure containing a short and plain statement of the grounds for removal. Consent of parties shall not be required for removal.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9C9CBE2C28FB4766ACCCA42A5BF2D463"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Claims not within the original or supplemental jurisdiction</header><text>If a civil action removed in accordance with paragraph (1) contains claims not within the original or supplemental jurisdiction of the district court, the district court shall sever all such claims and remand them to the State court from which the action was removed.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H9F26561E5DED45E392BB7AA1E6BF4617"><enum>403.</enum><header>State apportionment notice defined</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the <quote>State apportionment notice</quote> means, with respect to a State, the notice sent to the State from the Clerk of the House of Representatives under section 22(b) of the Act entitled <quote>An Act to provide for the fifteenth and subsequent decennial censuses and to provide for an apportionment of Representatives in Congress</quote>, approved June 18, 1929 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/2a">2 U.S.C. 2a</external-xref>), of the number of Representatives to which the State is entitled.</text></section> 
<section id="HE86F3E1E3FB44E9B8B36014724E9A379"><enum>404.</enum><header>No effect on elections for State and local office</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act or in any amendment made by this Act may be construed to affect the manner in which a State carries out elections for State or local office, including the process by which a State establishes the districts used in such elections.</text></section> <section id="H602701E6576D4DCC8F431F13B1F4BB8B"><enum>405.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Except as provided in section 102, this Act and the amendments made by this Act shall apply with respect to redistricting carried out pursuant to the decennial census conducted during 2030 or any succeeding decennial census.</text></section></title> 
</legis-body></bill>

