<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB18D1B73047E426196C765A301865E8E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3815 IH: True Justice Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3815</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20250606">June 6, 2025</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000602">Ms. Lee of Pennsylvania</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S001205">Ms. Scanlon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001130">Ms. Crockett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001313">Ms. Brown</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000477">Mrs. Foushee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000617">Ms. Pressley</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000631">Ms. Dean of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To authorize the Attorney General to make grants to strengthen the provision of legal representation to individuals in judicial proceedings that take place after the individual has been arrested in connection with a criminal offense, including at initial appearance.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H897854A8AF5647DDBB00364D21713E14" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H74AE265782ED48099E4F111301E4E751" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>True Justice Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H05BDB4BD6E614AF7A0D9B66F1D659CE4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Public defender grant program</header> <subsection id="HDA727C159DA84E50B0EC0191E3440988"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Public defender services grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General is authorized to make grants to States, units of local government (as such term is defined in section 901(a) of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10251">34 U.S.C. 10251(a)</external-xref>)), and public defender offices to provide legal representation to individuals in judicial proceedings that take place after the individual has been arrested in connection with a criminal offense, including at initial appearance.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H29657FA27A754678B04ECAEA8C0614BD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Public defender training grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General is authorized to make grants to States, units of local government, and non-profit organizations to provide training to public defenders, court-appointed attorneys, and contract attorneys on best practices for representing individuals in judicial proceedings described in subsection (a).</text></subsection> <subsection id="HD6696ACDA67C47F98810FD1AE047EFA2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header><text>An entity seeking a grant under this section shall submit to the Attorney General an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Attorney General may reasonably require.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H69B0D82793884819BB965C2B3C35FA21"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Amount</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In determining the amount of a grant under this section, the Attorney General shall take into account, with respect to the receiving entity—</text> <paragraph id="HEC7211A562C640379E5820555279DF0E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the cost of any technology and training that the entity will require in order to provide the services under subsection (a) or the training under subsection (b), as applicable; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2E0F023EA517446FA8BE6D2CA92537E5"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the size of the justice system that the entity administers or in which the entity participates, as applicable, relative to the size of other justice systems in—</text> <subparagraph id="H5C72B16496FC48729B7FCAB2818493F6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the United States, if the entity is a State or a public defender’s office of a State;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCEB2776E70254B5684E55ED2AD4A66AA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the State in which the entity is located, if the entity is a unit of local government (other than an Indian Tribe) or a public defender’s office of a unit of local government (other than an Indian Tribe); or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H828E4D62B60C412FBDC65EB348D6BA63"><enum>(C)</enum><text>of the Indian Tribe, if the entity is a Tribal organization or a public defender’s office of a Tribal organization.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H123A23D73F7A4847B38F45DF6DAF52E5"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Attorney General to carry out this section $50,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H3C2431A2B8C24900979C5F67BA5D5E13"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that the constitutional right to counsel established by the Supreme Court in Gideon v. Wainwright (372 U.S. 335) applies to any and all post-arrest proceedings.</text></section> 
</legis-body>
</bill> 


