<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-NEW25624-N19-PV-LN9" key="G"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 319 ATS: Recognizing and celebrating 100 years of quantum mechanics.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 319</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250710">July 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S375">Mr. Daines</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S426">Mr. Kim</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S391">Mr. Young</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing and celebrating 100 years of quantum mechanics.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, in 1925, the foundational principles of quantum mechanics were formulated by pioneering physicists and advanced by scientists in the United States, including Richard Feynman, John Archibald Wheeler, David Bohm, Bryce Dewitt, and Peter Shor, among others, laying the groundwork for a revolutionary understanding of physics that examines the behavior of matter and energy at the atomic and subatomic levels;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas quantum mechanics has led to groundbreaking scientific advancements, enabling the development of modern technologies that improve the daily lives of people, such as semiconductors, lasers, superconductive materials, magnetic resonance imaging, and the global positioning system;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the study and application of optics, photonics, cryogenics, and condensed matter physics have been instrumental in advancing quantum technologies by leveraging fundamental quantum principles such as superposition, entanglement, and interference;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas ongoing breakthroughs in quantum information science, including in quantum computing, quantum simulation, quantum communication, quantum cryptography, quantum sensing, and materials science, promise to enhance national security, drive economic growth, and advance numerous industries;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the advancement of quantum technologies creates high-quality jobs and fosters innovation across critical sectors, such as chemistry, biology, healthcare, finance, transportation, telecommunications, and advanced manufacturing;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States has been a global leader in quantum research and innovation, with significant contributions from private industry, national laboratories, universities, and government agencies; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 2025 marks the 100th anniversary of quantum mechanics, providing an opportunity to educate the public, inspire the next generation of scientists and engineers, and highlight the strategic importance of quantum science, technology, and education: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id0edc2adb2c6e4ba582bf3aa7078ba612"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognizes the 100th anniversary of quantum mechanics and its profound impact on science and technology; </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id382a2ba5d427440ea9dcffbebb7adeb7"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">celebrates the contributions of scientists, engineers, and innovators in the United States in advancing quantum science;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id445ed2676d704221b4e1a1afe7386599"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reaffirms the commitment of the United States to maintaining leadership in quantum research and development; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id962045adeccd47a885c52205755c7f2c"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supports efforts to raise public awareness of quantum science and its potential to shape the future of computing, security, healthcare, and industry.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

