<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H099C062068934BCDB3C796EA727BC400" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1844 IH: Preventing Armed Groups from Engaging in Radicalism</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1844</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250305">March 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001214">Mr. Steube</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the availability of Federal funds to support the Armed Forces of Lebanon, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC75D85BEA8704C71B9F31830F5DE2F7B" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H2D950BF810E34BDA9B9D86396CC08372" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Preventing Armed Groups from Engaging in Radicalism</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>PAGER Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section> <section id="H10867F77D9A143FDAC231BC6F675B94C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Limitations on United States support for the Lebanese armed forces</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, on and after the date that is 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, no Federal funds are authorized to be appropriated or otherwise made available to the armed forces of Lebanon until the date on which the Secretary of State certifies to the appropriate congressional committees that—</text> 
<paragraph id="H6D66D9C119314BEEA3AB4258DC554212"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Government of Lebanon, including the Chamber of Deputies, no longer recognizes the legitimacy as political parties of, nor permits its ministers or other cabinet-level officials to be from or claim alliance with—</text> <subparagraph id="H6353376821B34CFFBEAFAD738C061B3E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Hezbollah;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFCE02524EC6A493085632648A63158F3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Loyalty to the Resistance Bloc; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCEB6E8236C1F40A1AAD02EFA99539462"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Amal;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1AC2CBE7FE2A43DB9DAC6ADC66157D3F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Hezbollah no longer maintains any presence in Lebanon pursuant to action of the Lebanese Armed Forces and internal security forces to implement the clauses of United Nations Security Council Resolution 1559 (2004), which calls for the <quote>disbanding and disarmament of all Lebanese and non-Lebanese militias</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H519288460CC8476C9BF25FCF7FD1FC75"><enum>(3)</enum><text>such implementation of United Nations Security Council Resolution 1559 includes the expulsion of Hezbollah forces from known strongholds;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H89AABA2E4637485CB5FD57B3CE1B5DCC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the Lebanese Armed Forces and internal security forces have established an increased presence in areas known to be Hezbollah strongholds in order to prevent a resurgence of Hezbollah;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD743A9B82D524F2B9AFA1591EB7FBAED"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the Lebanese Armed Forces do not maintain any coordination, collaboration, or support with Hezbollah, its affiliates, or any other group designated by the United States as a foreign terrorist organization that has a presence in Lebanon as of the date of such certification;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H214D4254B1E24ABEA821DA144104788F" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">no member of the Lebanese Armed Forces maintains any coordination with or receives any support, either directly or indirectly, from any entity or organization that is an agent of, affiliated with, or owned or controlled by the Iranian Regime or Hezbollah;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H280DBAEF1C464F2589EB3DCA4DAAC526"><enum>(7)</enum><text>any military aid previously received from Iran, whether in the form of weapons, ammunition, munitions, or equipment, is destroyed or disarmed; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDE580CAF46DC48F3A6390782B7B61182" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Lebanese courts and military tribunals under the jurisdiction of the Lebanese armed forces dismiss all charges and arrest warrants against American citizens who have advocated against Hezbollah’s influence over the Government of Lebanon, including American journalists who have appeared on Israeli news media or invited Israeli guests on their media programs. </text></paragraph></section> <section id="H240B13E5D6D148AD9AB91C047193EE3E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Limitation on United States support to the United Nations Development Programme</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">On and after the date that is 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, no Federal funds authorized to be appropriated or otherwise made available to the United Nations Development Programme may be obligated or expended to support any livelihood support programs making assistance available to members of the Lebanese armed forces or the Lebanese internal security forces.</text></section> 
<section id="H1BDDC270F6E6496D89F3D3A49723136D"><enum>4.</enum><header>Designation as global terrorist</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Suhil Bahij Gharab is designated as a specially designated global terrorist organization under Executive Order 13224 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note; relating to blocking property and prohibiting transactions with persons who commit, threaten to commit, or support terrorism).</text></section> <section id="H529640C5C8BA4521BAA167C7806990A5"><enum>5.</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and every 180 days thereafter, the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense and the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the influences of Hezbollah and the Government of Iran throughout the Government of Lebanon, including the Lebanese Ministry of Defense.</text></section>
<section id="H82D543BE5EC24640AD7B5DA061496553"><enum>6.</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> <paragraph id="H634996AD30E9402E9AF9B82DE4522B39"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA71E93E030734465AA26C1E1E85201E6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate.</text> </paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

