<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDBE6A62CC2EA4980ABBA2C4F48685034" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5085 IH: To exempt Federal actions related to the construction of infill housing from the requirements of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5085</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250902">September 2, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000483">Ms. Friedman</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="E000246">Mr. Edwards</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000486">Mr. Torres of New York</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To exempt Federal actions related to the construction of infill housing from the requirements of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8F52F12F24AF474885940B53C741925C" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HB4DB6178B7B240AB9B8370D06ADB18F2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Exemption of Federal actions related to the construction of infill housing from the requirements of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969</header> 
<subsection id="HCA7BFC2195E6431184E9D56978CCDFE2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Exemption</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An action by a Federal agency related to an infill housing activity may not be considered a major Federal action under section 102(2)(C) of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4332">42 U.S.C. 4332(2)(C)</external-xref>).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H27DA44E347294DA1890BFDBF16470D79" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H4FBBCA2C0C184066815BF7A93891BCE1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Hazardous substance; pollutant or contaminant; release; remedial action</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <term>hazardous substance</term>, <term>pollutant or contaminant</term>, <term>release</term>, and <term>remedial action</term> have the meanings given such terms, respectively, in section 101 of the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9601">42 U.S.C. 9601</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFF84BF01C27248FD9BAB289F21D5E014"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Infill housing</header><text>The term <term>Infill housing</term> means residential housing—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H743918BF8D42494396FB714E765A12C9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that is located on a site—</text> <clause id="HB732DFEDDA1D43B6ABAC20D4C1C5D35A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that is vacant or underutilized;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H124C386E30BF4B29BC050D914B363B6E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that has been previously developed with an urban use;</text></clause> <clause id="HF6A599672DAF490596F79DA38DC1ADF2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that is not larger than 20 acres;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H8351E3E6BBD94F75AB9741731264642E"><enum>(iv)</enum> 
<subclause id="HD7F09BB0C719471F8236492E664335A4" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">at least 75 percent of the perimeter of which adjoins a parcel that was developed with an urban use; or</text></subclause> <subclause id="H96DE614D47E54F398C471C2593CA648E" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>at least 75 percent of the area within a 1/4-mile from the exterior boundary of which is developed with an urban use; and</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="HB91D3A90C69C434999BE231B9C6FA361" commented="no">
              <enum>(v)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that has undergone a Phase I Environmental Site Assessment in accordance with the applicable industry standards described in section 312.11 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations, (or any successor regulation) and, if the Phase I Environmental Site Assessment identified conditions indicative of a release or threatened release of a hazardous substance, a pollutant or contaminant, petroleum, or a petroleum product, the site has undergone a Phase II Environmental Site Assessment in accordance with ASTM E1903–19 (as in effect on the date of enactment of this section) that—</text>
              <subclause id="HD6BD1450FEF24B8BB31F453083608167">
                <enum>(I)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">did not show a release of a hazardous substance, a pollutant or contaminant, petroleum, or a petroleum product; or</text>
              </subclause>
              <subclause id="H6191597E97F7424BBAA9C596521CC267">
                <enum>(II)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shows a release of a hazardous substance, pollutant or contaminant, petroleum, or a petroleum product, but the site has been remediated to the standard applicable to a remedial action under the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9601">42 U.S.C. 9601 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text>
              </subclause>
            </clause> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H01993899FB844C86B2F7579DC1A87BF0" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that is not located on a site within a census tract designated as very high or relatively high risk for wildfire, coastal flooding, and riverine flooding under the National Risk Index of the Federal Emergency Management Agency pursuant to section 206 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5136">42 U.S.C. 5136</external-xref>).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7641C6B83A384208BF4F4557A9D3126D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Infill housing activity</header><text>The term <term>infill housing activity</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD54005FBD81242E9A586F1EE5E031C6E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the acquisition or disposition of land or property for the development of infill housing;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEC4AAD1E73A04464A32788E0C65CCCE9"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the demolition of property (not including a historic structure designated on a national, State, or local historic register) for the construction, reconstruction, rehabilitation, or development of infill housing;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5BF614F360C84DAE9B3E3416EC2CC2D7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the construction, reconstruction, rehabilitation, or development of infill housing; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3C3E52119D88422C9ACB2B3556B46518"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the conversion of a non-residential building into infill housing.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6AFCD844BB2E4D8AADF5F4B9E2BCC1DB" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Urban use</header><text>The term <term>urban use</term> means any residential use, commercial use, industrial use, public institutional use, transit or transportation passenger facility use, retail use, or any combination of such uses.</text></paragraph></subsection> </section> <section id="H0711E8D26675464FB09B8F61C1254424"><enum>2.</enum><header>Natural hazard risk assessment updates</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 206(d)(1) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5136">42 U.S.C. 5136(d)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>every 5 years</quote> and inserting <quote>every 3 years</quote>.</text> </section> 
</legis-body></bill>

