<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-BAG25118-2G3-NY-424"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S423 IS: Protecting Regular Order for Veterans Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 423</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250205">February 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S383">Mr. Sullivan</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S411">Mr. Marshall</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S417">Mr. Budd</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S318">Mr. Wicker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S404">Mr. Scott of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S375">Mr. Daines</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S153">Mr. Grassley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S423">Mr. Ricketts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S412">Mr. Tuberville</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S288">Ms. Murkowski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S384">Mr. Tillis</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S376">Ms. Ernst</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSVA00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To protect regular order for budgeting for the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting Regular Order for Veterans Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>PRO Veterans Act of 2025</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="HC50C2F136CE042F891DF845CBB1F52A8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Protecting regular order for veterans</header><subsection id="H5E00D26F0DC54FF3AFB3FA7EC93AD7FF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Quarterly briefings on Department of Veterans Affairs budgetary shortfalls</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H019AD6FD5FD94B9DB78A6C604DEAE7D0"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Quarterly briefings</header><subparagraph id="H794B1D214A5E431B9E772F1DA03A0961"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Quarterly briefings required</header><text>During the first quarter beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act and in each quarter thereafter until the date that is three years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall provide to the appropriate committees of Congress a quarterly briefing, in person, on the budget of the Department of Veterans Affairs and any shortfall the Department may be experiencing.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H127B26DF5C474455823A8A8B5701DFD6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Plans</header><text>In any case in which the Secretary informs Congress during a briefing under paragraph (1) that the Department is experiencing a shortfall, the Secretary shall, during such briefing, present the plans of the Secretary to address or mitigate the shortfall.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H015E0C6F37B84F2E8F59D29763EF5B8F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9FC07F6DCDD94C739DB85778FF015F62"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of Congress</header><text>The term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBFD0C9AFC76D43CBB36C2379A6A4EEBC"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Veterans' Affairs and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate; and</text></clause><clause id="HE4DF3E49AD484BA7896D7801BE04AABE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Committee on Veterans' Affairs and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7FAEFBD3A0C64834B98577D090327D9E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Shortfall</header><text>The term <term>shortfall</term>, with respect to a fiscal year, means that the amount of appropriations required by the Department of Veterans Affairs for such fiscal year to meet all of the statutory obligations of the Department during that fiscal year exceeds the amount of appropriations requested for the Department for that fiscal year in the budget of the President submitted pursuant to section 1105(a) of title 31, United States Code, for that fiscal year. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEFCB80F9968B4ED191364D3E791949DA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitations on provision of incentives for critical skills to Senior Executive Service employees of Department of Veterans Affairs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 706(d) of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HBC547F93E198455E85B12B003DC810D3" display-inline="no-display-inline" style="OLC"><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2C1604628DF041A9ADCE10F892EFF34F" indent="up1"><enum>(7)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H6911DDCD1841403FAE5B9D047C54B2D5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Subject to subparagraph (B)(ii), a critical skill incentive may not be provided under paragraph (1) to an employee of the Department employed in a Senior Executive Service position, or a position in another comparable system for senior-level Government employees, as defined by the Secretary, whose position is at the Central Office of the Department, including the Veterans Health Administration, the Veterans Benefits Administration, and the National Cemetery Administration, regardless of the actual location where the employee performs the functions of the position.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="H8919F5250F9F49D29F3649A607C3AEAC"><enum>(B)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HC1DBE2ED59974F5A8E21E4494CD26E6A"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A critical skill incentive provided under paragraph (1) to an employee of the Department employed in a Senior Executive Service position, or a position in another comparable system for senior-level Government employees, as defined by the Secretary, not described in subparagraph (A) of this paragraph may only be provided—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H47B96E02A0D947688C02DFF8D7B9B3FC" indent="up1"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">on an individual basis and may not be provided to a group of such employees; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H731902F1A06C44ACB8E2CD3FA920702E" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>upon approval of the following officers or those serving in an acting capacity:</text><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H45987266D7D9434BA8646B1FC0A6E396"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>The Under Secretary for Benefits, the Under Secretary for Health, or the Under Secretary for Memorial Affairs.</text></item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF77C511C78CF46C6B642389CFD056EA4"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Assistant Secretary for Human Resources and Administration.</text></item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3627BB68B72B4FC3ACC245E2173C5271"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>The Director of the Office of Management or the Chief Financial Officer.</text></item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H06FE443900074F49A57A370199998A18"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>The Assistant Secretary for Accountability and Whistleblower Protection.</text></item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H01B0CEB8E0E3416C960BEF8894397494"><enum>(ee)</enum><text>The General Counsel.</text></item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H20D670F898184C098DFD12310E800F6F"><enum>(ff)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such other officers as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></item></subclause></clause><clause indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9D574085CF7647BABE33F51E0E4319D0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>In the case of an employee of the Department employed in a Senior Executive Service position, or a position in another comparable system for senior-level Government employees, as defined by the Secretary, whose position is primarily at the Central Office of the Department, but who performs some portion of the employee’s job function at other facilities of the Department, as defined by the Secretary, not at Central Office—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H371D83C2627E4D588C252737F8BB63C7"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the employee shall not be considered described in subparagraph (A) with respect to the portion of the employee’s job function that is based out of non-Central Office facilities of the Department; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD3BF1B1D7AB84900BECC49811D73A042"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any critical skill incentive provided under paragraph (1) to the employee for the portion of the employee’s job function that is based out of facilities of the Department other than the Central Office shall be proportionate to the time spent at those Department facilities.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2924507B7368474BBF2C088F68DBF4A7"><enum>(C)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H22846CE910FB4ADF98836B6135594EBE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Protecting Regular Order for Veterans Act of 2025</short-title>, and not less frequently than once each year thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives an annual report on the employees of the Department employed in a Senior Executive Service position, or a position in another comparable system for senior-level Government employees, as defined by the Secretary, who were provided a critical skill incentive under paragraph (1).</text></clause><clause indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC06005CBD8EA4FE4BFAB70E051D67B36"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Reports submitted pursuant to clause (i) may be submitted by incorporating their contents into other congressionally mandated reports to the committees described in such clause.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5F91547864D441EBB094C51BC815DB4D" indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this paragraph, the term <term>Senior Executive Service position</term> has the meaning given such term in section 3132(a) of title 5.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

