<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1373FD45D5A54508B7A83779BC675B29" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 129 IH: Expressing support for the designation of February 9, 2025, as the first ever “Gulf of America Day” and celebrating the importance of changing the Gulf of Mexico to the Gulf of America.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 129</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250213">February 13, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="A000379">Mr. Alford</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of February 9, 2025, as the first ever <quote>Gulf of America Day</quote> and celebrating the importance of changing the Gulf of Mexico to the Gulf of America.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, on January 20, 2025, President Trump signed Executive Order 14172 (<quote>Restoring Names That Honor American Greatness</quote>), which required the Secretary of the Interior, acting pursuant to take all appropriate actions to rename as the <quote>Gulf of America</quote> the United States Continental Shelf area bounded on the northeast, north, and northwest by the States of Texas, Louisiana, Mississippi, Alabama, and Florida and extending to the seaward boundary with Mexico and Cuba in the area formerly named as the Gulf of Mexico;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the area formerly known as the Gulf of Mexico has long been an integral asset to the once burgeoning Nation and has remained an indelible part of America;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas February 9, 2025, marks President Trump’s first visit to the Gulf of America since its renaming; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, as President Trump restores American pride in the history of American greatness, it is fitting and appropriate for this great Nation to come together and commemorate this momentous occasion and the renaming of the Gulf of America: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H0E1EE9095D014E898BC84503732B3DA4"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H3628287619F049EBB9D8C5A88B09A649"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="H3E517161410E4639A8C3764A501FDF07"><enum>(1)</enum><text>expresses support for the designation of the first ever <quote>Gulf of America Day</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H50038BF7A73E4FCEAFF076CA22BD5E29"><enum>(2)</enum><text>celebrates the importance of changing the Gulf of Mexico to the Gulf of America.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

