<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-WIL25030-VHP-75-D7M"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S437 IS: Caring for All Families Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 437</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250205">February 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S408">Mr. Hickenlooper</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S331">Mrs. Gillibrand</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S422">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S394">Ms. Smith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S229">Mrs. Murray</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 and title 5, United States Code, to permit leave to care for a domestic partner, parent-in-law, or adult child, or another related individual, who has a serious health condition, and to allow employees to take, as additional leave, parental involvement and family wellness leave to participate in or attend their children’s and grandchildren’s educational and extracurricular activities or meet family care needs.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H763C2B6BD9A842C9B4FE5A3B8F243884"><section section-type="section-one" id="H01F452705C704D89B02532583DB4CC7C"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Caring for All Families Act</short-title></quote> .</text></section><section id="H124F63EAC7774230AB1669E75AB4D27D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Leave to care for a domestic partner, son-in-law, daughter-in-law, parent-in-law, adult child, grandparent, grandchild, or sibling of the employee, or another related individual</header><subsection id="H99867792AC054CDF917070852458E6AE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><paragraph commented="no" id="H1DA9427ADC494EEBBF4C2AEDF4764B46"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Inclusion of related individuals</header><text>Section 101 of the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/2611">29 U.S.C. 2611</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id20E1CBE61D854A1D9E75EEC9CCD88122"><paragraph id="id6D23D398BA394F8D9F54BC74C652862B"><enum>(20)</enum><header>Any other individual whose close association is the equivalent of a family relationship</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>any other individual whose close association is the equivalent of a family relationship</term>, used with respect to an employee or a covered servicemember, means any person with whom the employee or covered servicemember, as the case may be, has a significant personal bond that is or is like a family relationship, regardless of biological or legal relationship.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H2C51CC033B004924A5E563E7609D6723"><enum>(21)</enum><header>Domestic partner</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>domestic partner</term>, used with respect to an employee or a covered servicemember, means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="HF920633DAD574DD88CC82009B44A76E5"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the person recognized as the domestic partner of the employee or covered servicemember under any domestic partnership or civil union law of a State or political subdivision of a State; or </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H4A270BD8616B49FEB93C64A74BF12A45"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of an unmarried employee or covered servicemember, an unmarried adult person who is in a committed, personal relationship with the employee or covered servicemember, is not a domestic partner as described in subparagraph (A) to or in such a relationship with any other person, and who is designated to the employer by such employee or covered service member as the domestic partner of that employee or covered servicemember.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HF8F7ECEBB7684F119AA69B665F5CA68C"><enum>(22)</enum><header>Grandchild</header><text>The term <term>grandchild</term>, used with respect to an employee or a covered servicemember, means the son or daughter of a son or daughter of the employee or covered service member.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H30DCF4EBC9984E40897743E5D3696DE8"><enum>(23)</enum><header>Grandparent</header><text>The term <term>grandparent</term>, used with respect to an employee or a covered servicemember, means a parent of a parent of the employee or covered service member. </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id41E224689176435B9CCF9E20DE3046BD"><enum>(24)</enum><header>Nephew; niece</header><text>The terms <term>nephew</term> and <term>niece</term>, used with respect to an employee or a covered servicemember, mean a son or daughter of the sibling of the employee or covered service member. </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id314CA6BADF6A4D78B219B568A94264EB"><enum>(25)</enum><header>Parent-in-law</header><text> The term <term>parent-in-law</term>, used with respect to an employee or a covered servicemember, means a parent of the spouse or domestic partner of the employee or covered service member.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HD88CA0F6C498456DBF3B3033E06B4D76"><enum>(26)</enum><header>Sibling</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>sibling</term>, used with respect to an employee or a covered servicemember, means any person who is a son or daughter of parent of the employee or covered service member (other than the employee or covered servicemember).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HA56181C7148B417A9AB8B33EE46BB434"><enum>(27)</enum><header>Son-in-law; daughter-in-law</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <term>son-in-law</term> and <term>daughter-in-law</term>, used with respect to an employee or a covered servicemember, mean any person who is a spouse or domestic partner of a son or daughter, as the case may be, of the employee or covered service member. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5E4E9798D32147A783FFBB88FE4879DD"><enum>(28)</enum><header>Uncle; Aunt</header><text>The terms <term>uncle</term> and <term>aunt</term>, used with respect to an employee or a covered servicemember, mean the son or daughter, as the case may be, of the grandparent of the employee or covered servicemember (other than the parent of the employee or covered service member).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H013F4A8DBF3240BD9F123C17D9326151"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Inclusion of adult children and children of a domestic partner</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 101(12) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/2611">29 U.S.C. 2611(12)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="H8366EA5761C748C4BA8E251E65F61D3F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>a child of an individual’s domestic partner,</quote> after <quote>a legal ward,</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H238B101CF20A4C1D95DAA243DB934BA4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>who is—</quote> and all that follows and inserting <quote>and includes an adult child.</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFABC8784542E45478A04ECCA51AF30D7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Leave Requirement</header><text>Section 102 of the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/2612">29 U.S.C. 2612</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H0B69433A1DC142F48F048787D51AA221"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text><subparagraph id="id46D0D65B3E234B11A8934E9879E0F82C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text><clause id="id0D52E1E261214AC096B57232033D5654"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>spouse, or a son, daughter, or parent, of the employee, if such spouse, son, daughter, or parent</quote> and inserting <quote>spouse or domestic partner, or a son or daughter, son-in-law or daughter-in-law, parent, parent-in-law, grandparent, grandchild, sibling, uncle or aunt, or nephew or niece of the employee, or any other individual whose close association is the equivalent of a family relationship with the employee, if such spouse, domestic partner, son or daughter, son-in-law or daughter-in-law, parent, parent-in-law, grandparent, grandchild, sibling, uncle or aunt, or nephew or niece, or such other individual</quote>; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H1675BE5198F14DAFB6EAA4FA2FD4E859"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (E), by striking <quote>spouse, or a son, daughter, or parent of the employee</quote> and inserting <quote>spouse or domestic partner, or a son or daughter, son-in-law or daughter-in-law, parent, parent-in-law, grandchild, sibling, uncle or aunt, or nephew or niece of the employee, or any other individual whose close association is the equivalent of a family relationship with the employee</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H6C514E9E5B514DAD8BA1FC113FEE7B27"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>spouse, son, daughter, parent, or next of kin of a covered servicemember</quote> and inserting <quote>spouse or domestic partner, son or daughter, son-in-law or daughter-in-law, parent, parent-in-law, grandparent, sibling, uncle or aunt, nephew or niece, or next of kin of a covered servicemember, or any other individual whose close association is the equivalent of a family relationship with the covered servicemember</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5FAF4D40B5454F1ABD22FA8766BCBECF"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (e)—</text><subparagraph id="idE58C33818993414CA2BA2225E3131D48"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (2)(A), by striking <quote>son, daughter, spouse, parent, or covered servicemember of the employee, as appropriate</quote> and inserting <quote>son or daughter, son-in-law or daughter-in-law, spouse or domestic partner, parent, parent-in-law, grandparent, grandchild, sibling, uncle or aunt, nephew or niece, or covered servicemember of the employee, or any other individual whose close association is the equivalent of a family relationship with the employee, as appropriate</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H15C645CFD8AB49CE95C5E53FAA7EB494"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>spouse, or a son, daughter, or parent, of the employee</quote> and inserting <quote>spouse or domestic partner, or a son or daughter, son-in-law or daughter-in-law, parent, parent-in-law, grandchild, sibling, uncle or aunt, or nephew or niece of the employee, or any other individual whose close association is the equivalent of a family relationship with the employee, as appropriate,</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB67E7F67C49A4DE89B300FA58D8868C7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (f)—</text><subparagraph id="id8225BF3AB8CD44E495E9C0DD24E93A69"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text><clause id="HFB5F42B42FBE4A9EA58D699658370954"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by inserting <quote>, or domestic partners,</quote> after <quote>husband and wife</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="H8E99A406A9DE4D6F83D019B150A4F1FB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by inserting <quote>or parent-in-law</quote> after <quote>parent</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idDA52E329565341B9B40FB9A23401A3CC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by inserting <quote>, or those domestic partners,</quote> after <quote>husband and wife</quote> each place it appears.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H08EF39614C9443D4BC2A06279D147A6E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Certification</header><text>Section 103 of the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/2613">29 U.S.C. 2613</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HB233678A298D4580A57B08A3BE293450"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>son, daughter, spouse, or parent of the employee, or of the next of kin of an individual in the case of leave taken under such paragraph (3), as appropriate</quote> and inserting <quote>son or daughter, son-in-law or daughter-in-law, spouse or domestic partner, parent, parent-in-law, grandparent, grandchild, sibling, uncle or aunt, or nephew or niece of the employee, or the next of kin of an individual, or any other individual whose close association is the equivalent of a family relationship with the employee, as appropriate</quote>; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9328B1C6CCE24BC3ABB26BA5E84D9C78"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text><subparagraph id="HB5CF8627AC0543D1A848208B2806F428"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)(A), by striking <quote>son, daughter, spouse, or parent and an estimate of the amount of time that such employee is needed to care for the son, daughter, spouse, or parent</quote> and inserting <quote>son or daughter, son-in-law or daughter-in-law, spouse or domestic partner, parent, parent-in-law, grandparent, grandchild, sibling, uncle or aunt, or nephew or niece of the employee, or any other individual whose close association is the equivalent of a family relationship with the employee, as appropriate, and an estimate of the amount of time that such employee is needed to care for such son or daughter, son-in-law or daughter-in-law, spouse or domestic partner, parent, parent-in-law, grandparent, grandchild, sibling, uncle or aunt, or nephew or niece, or such other individual</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H50C3D578CA8E45F5830946EBB2AEE2A0"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (7), by striking <quote>son, daughter, parent, or spouse who has a serious health condition, or will assist in their recovery,</quote> and inserting <quote>son or daughter, son-in-law or daughter-in-law, spouse or domestic partner, parent, parent-in-law, grandparent, grandchild, sibling, uncle or aunt, or nephew or niece, with a serious health condition, of the employee, or an individual, with a serious health condition, who is any other individual whose close association is the equivalent of a family relationship with the employee, as appropriate, or will assist in the recovery,</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC6DC61A4B68D4E6AA4E1C0762D2D4656"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Employment and Benefits Protection</header><text>Section 104(c)(3) of the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/2614">29 U.S.C. 2614(c)(3)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H2826727402384C6CAE279EB8BA9827EB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)(i), by striking <quote>son, daughter, spouse, or parent of the employee, as appropriate,</quote> and inserting <quote>son or daughter, son-in-law or daughter-in-law, spouse or domestic partner, parent, parent-in-law, grandparent, grandchild, sibling, uncle or aunt, or nephew or niece of the employee, or any other individual whose close association is the equivalent of a family relationship with the employee, as appropriate,</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H153D82AAF39D4F8795678C5A61A87BDB"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (C)(ii), by striking <quote>son, daughter, spouse, or parent</quote> and inserting <quote>employee's son or daughter, son-in-law or daughter-in-law, spouse or domestic partner, parent, parent-in-law, grandparent, grandchild, sibling, uncle or aunt, or nephew or niece, or (with relation to the employee) any other individual whose close association is the equivalent of a family relationship, as appropriate,</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HE087E05361454500ABA1956A14A39BA2"><enum>3.</enum><header>Leave to care for a domestic partner, son-in-law, daughter-in-law, parent-in-law, adult child, grandparent, grandchild, or sibling of the employee, or another related individual for Federal employees</header><subsection id="H3FEF93A5270640BF8CF0E4E0E7E5431B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><paragraph id="H16EB5C9A7D9A42798A9FA929B5619263"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Inclusion of a domestic partner, son-in-law, daughter-in-law, parent-in-law, adult child, grandparent, grandchild, or sibling of the employee, or another individual whose close association is the equivalent of a family relationship</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 6381 of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text><subparagraph id="H871FDFF451424D3893EAC3FF30D91E4B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (11) by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H694D321F93EA4273904C9BEAA2A133D5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (12), by striking the period and inserting a semicolon; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HD8A850F950DC496BA1F7C8032E4CF342"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H374429B8BA074761B35B95CE9163B3FC"><paragraph id="idCCE15A1473BA4E6AA8E261CF8D3623D2"><enum>(13)</enum><text>the term <term>any other individual whose close association is the equivalent of a family relationship</term>, used with respect to an employee or a covered servicemember, means any person with whom the employee or covered servicemember, as the case may be, has a significant personal bond that is or is like a family relationship, regardless of biological or legal relationship;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HAD8902CD81E94FEF921D12A840E0881E"><enum>(14)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>domestic partner</term>, used with respect to an employee or a covered servicemember, means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="id91DDE34963F0489BA7B23E069F0439B5"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the person recognized as the domestic partner of the employee or covered servicemember under any domestic partnership or civil union law of a State or political subdivision of a State; or </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id8E9AA8108D524822960E9147669E8A5F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of an unmarried employee or covered servicemember, an unmarried adult person who is in a committed, personal relationship with the employee or covered servicemember, is not a domestic partner as described in subparagraph (A) to or in such a relationship with any other person, and who is designated to the employing agency by such employee or covered service member as the domestic partner of that employee or covered servicemember;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HC6D1D9E33D774033BD56E07C648B8EF5"><enum>(15)</enum><text>the term <term>grandchild</term>, used with respect to an employee or a covered servicemember, means the son or daughter of a son or daughter of the employee or covered service member;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HB647B9FBC4314BDD8891501108333FED"><enum>(16)</enum><text>the term <term>grandparent</term>, used with respect to an employee or a covered servicemember, means a parent of a parent of the employee or covered service member; </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id37F352B5C9094DA98CFE2CCD63630D68"><enum>(17)</enum><text>the terms <term>nephew</term> and <term>niece</term>, used with respect to an employee or a covered servicemember, mean a son or daughter of the sibling of the employee or covered service member; </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HEBD5E12F283F49DCA4E5897F921781BA"><enum>(18)</enum><text>the term <term>parent-in-law</term>, used with respect to an employee or a covered servicemember, means a parent of the spouse or domestic partner of the employee or covered service member;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H71EB2313E7D843A58F9482353B44FE2E"><enum>(19)</enum><text>the term <term>sibling</term>, used with respect to an employee or a covered servicemember, means any person who is a son or daughter of parent of the employee or covered service member (other than the employee or covered servicemember);</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HCD0769022C4041008AAD271A1CDADE71"><enum>(20)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the terms <term>son-in-law</term> and <term>daughter-in-law</term>, used with respect to an employee or a covered servicemember, mean any person who is a spouse or domestic partner of a son or daughter, as the case may be, of the employee or covered service member; </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idF88E6E11B0564C51B35991D306BA23A3"><enum>(21)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>State</term> has the same meaning given the term in section 3 of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/203">29 U.S.C. 203</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H49A8C23680CD4BC9B6DCD8345C3ADBF3"><enum>(22)</enum><text>terms <term>uncle</term> and <term>aunt</term>, used with respect to an employee or a covered servicemember, mean the son or daughter, as the case may be, of the grandparent of the employee or covered servicemember (other than the parent of the employee or covered service member). </text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA03D2E9ABF3A4407BD38384D739F8835"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Inclusion of adult children and children of a domestic partner</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 6381(6) of such title is amended—</text><subparagraph id="H468E80EE2A794776A522035F9E08FCA4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>a child of an individual’s domestic partner,</quote> after <quote>a legal ward,</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H29DCAE325D934ED69F7BE85F5DD66BD5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>who is—</quote> and all that follows and inserting <quote>and includes an adult child</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFD72F35BBBB24595BF66673CAE0D8A0F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Leave Requirement</header><text>Section 6382 of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="idA0F74D367FA542FBABF3BD22E36F94E0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text><subparagraph id="idEFACC5EA08124C41BEDD446D6E6560A3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text><clause id="HEEDA5F53FE8D4FFD8F435BE1260E5C2E"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>spouse, or a son, daughter, or parent, of the employee, if such spouse, son, daughter, or parent</quote> and inserting <quote>spouse or domestic partner, or a son or daughter, son-in-law or daughter-in-law, parent, parent-in-law, grandparent, grandchild, sibling, uncle or aunt, or nephew or niece of the employee, or any other individual whose close association with the employee is the equivalent of a family relationship, if such spouse, domestic partner, son or daughter, son-in-law or daughter-in-law, parent, parent-in-law, grandparent, grandchild, sibling, uncle or aunt, or nephew or niece, or such other individual</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="H7AEE152FB84246DB855752ADCADD41F3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (E), by striking <quote>spouse, or a son, daughter, or parent of the employee</quote> and inserting <quote>spouse or domestic partner, or a son or daughter, son-in-law or daughter-in-law, parent, parent-in-law, grandchild, sibling, uncle or aunt, or nephew or niece of the employee, or any other individual whose close association is the equivalent of a family relationship with the employee</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HF5E6F1276B614B06A17CC36E6311E851"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>spouse, son, daughter, parent, or next of kin of a covered servicemember</quote> and inserting <quote>spouse or domestic partner, son or daughter, son-in-law or daughter-in-law, parent, parent-in-law, grandparent, sibling, uncle or aunt, nephew or niece, or next of kin of a covered servicemember, or any other individual whose close association is the equivalent of a family relationship with the covered servicemember</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H972A2EB79CC0426EBA2B73740F009FDC"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (e)—</text><subparagraph id="id632F4C286D3C459497CE616CEDE93A55"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (2)(A), by striking <quote>son, daughter, spouse, parent, or covered servicemember of the employee, as appropriate</quote> and inserting <quote>son or daughter, son-in-law or daughter-in-law, spouse or domestic partner, parent, parent-in-law, grandparent, grandchild, sibling, uncle or aunt, nephew or niece, or covered servicemember of the employee, or any other individual whose close association is the equivalent of a family relationship with the employee, as appropriate</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H4C03ABD683764CC795512AC70714217B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>spouse, or a son, daughter, or parent, of the employee</quote> and inserting <quote>spouse or domestic partner, or a son or daughter, son-in-law or daughter-in-law, parent, parent-in-law, grandchild, sibling, uncle or aunt, or nephew or niece of the employee, or any other individual whose close association is the equivalent of a family relationship with the employee, as appropriate,</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H04991B2E06E1414E97CF1AD1BEACBDF4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Certification</header><text>Section 6383 of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="H0F09208E3671448A86B155533317C7DA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (a), by striking <quote>son, daughter, spouse, or parent of the employee, as appropriate</quote> and inserting <quote>son or daughter, son-in-law or daughter-in-law, spouse or domestic partner, parent, parent-in-law, grandparent, grandchild, sibling, uncle or aunt, or nephew or niece of the employee, or any other individual whose close association is the equivalent of a family relationship with the employee, as appropriate</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC2E9F2BF102C4F87A06E58E0961852D7"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (b)(4)(A), by striking <quote>son, daughter, spouse, or parent, and an estimate of the amount of time that such employee is needed to care for such son, daughter, spouse, or parent</quote> and inserting <quote>son or daughter, son-in-law or daughter-in-law, spouse or domestic partner, parent, parent-in-law, grandparent, grandchild, sibling, uncle or aunt, or nephew or niece of the employee, or any other individual whose close association is the equivalent of a family relationship with the employee, as appropriate, and an estimate of the amount of time that such employee is needed to care for such son or daughter, son-in-law or daughter-in-law, spouse or domestic partner, parent, parent-in-law, grandparent, grandchild, sibling, uncle or aunt, or nephew or niece, or such other individual</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HF8A151541C0C4A319A16728C5B5E5130"><enum>4.</enum><header>Entitlement to additional leave under the FMLA for parental involvement and family wellness</header><subsection id="H1C4BE587E1594F2AA4447781CFD69819"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Leave requirement</header><text>Section 102(a) of the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/2612">29 U.S.C. 2612(a)</external-xref>), as amended by section 2(b), is further amended—</text><paragraph id="idBE0057D8B5F24119A353F26A035B44E3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (5) as paragraph (6); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4077E6D4CC9C4789B6A056CBED19FBE8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (4) the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block id="HDE36BB4C6098458BB1D20D63619D7561"><paragraph id="HC65410AFE6E2437587C247ADF4706270"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Entitlement to additional leave for parental involvement and family wellness</header><subparagraph id="H194C76D2B80F47D8A406CB6F91F236DD"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (B) and section 103(g), an eligible employee shall be entitled to leave under this paragraph to—</text><clause id="HAE6886D366904D82A35886C68E634ADE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>participate in or attend an activity that is sponsored by a school or community organization and relates to a program of the school or organization that is attended by a son or daughter or a grandchild of the employee; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H058E648E20CB40A69A6810AF666AE387"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">meet routine family medical care needs (including by attending medical and dental appointments of the employee or a son or daughter, spouse or domestic partner, or grandchild of the employee) or attend to the care needs of an elderly individual who is any other individual whose close association is the equivalent of a family relationship with the employee (including by making visits to nursing homes or group homes). </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0928EA66242E4994BFDE284914F9C8E1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitations</header><clause id="H0CA435D9328649288B442BDB223C0EA5"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible employee shall be entitled to—</text><subclause id="HDE67C31DFFEF40B38C4049149376177B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>not to exceed 4 hours of leave under this paragraph during any 30-day period; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H5078C40D7BCD4D4CAA28048E49DE9B34"><enum>(II)</enum><text>not to exceed 24 hours of leave under this paragraph during any 12-month period described in paragraph (4). </text></subclause></clause><clause id="H7FB18ED038AE4B50990A13373E7BAA37"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Coordination rule</header><text>Leave under this paragraph shall be in addition to any leave provided under any other paragraph of this subsection.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3F9A286A20E34FD487DBAEC6094784F0"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>As used in this paragraph:</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idFE21584F42AD4FAFA0E447BDD3E5D021"><enum>(i)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Community organization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>community organization</term> means a private nonprofit organization that is representative of a community or a significant segment of a community and provides activities for individuals described in section 101(12), such as a scouting or sports organization.</text></clause><clause id="HD3CF068795094FEFB7181D1573C72EF7"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>School</header><text>The term <term>school</term> means an elementary school or secondary school (as such terms are defined in section 8101 of the <act-name parsable-cite="ESEA">Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>)), a Head Start program assisted under the <act-name parsable-cite="HSA">Head Start Act</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9831">42 U.S.C. 9831 et seq.</external-xref>), and a child care facility licensed under State law.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA98B18758B6D42B7A7586A5DF80A2C6F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Schedule</header><text>Section 102(b)(1) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/2612">29 U.S.C. 2612(b)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after the third sentence the following new sentence: <quote>Subject to subsection (e)(4) and section 103(g), leave under subsection (a)(5) may be taken intermittently or on a reduced leave schedule.</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H239A1653AA5C4D7387628D488B72D4B6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Substitution of paid leave</header><text>Section 102(d)(2) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/2612">29 U.S.C. 2612(d)(2)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H56D88CEDD8E2406EBF5351E8ACD54E5D"><subparagraph id="H474C53F6AD8246808BE037EEABC65203"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Parental involvement leave and family wellness leave</header><clause id="id8D96E5A47AEF43B68760050D5BE173E3"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Vacation leave; personal leave; family leave</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible employee may elect, or an employer may require the employee, to substitute any of the accrued paid vacation leave, personal leave, or family leave of the employee for any part of the period of leave under subsection (a)(5).</text></clause><clause id="id5B33462245364809B8FF79746D649514"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Medical or sick leave</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible employee may elect, or an employer may require the employee, to substitute any of the accrued paid medical or sick leave of the employee for any part of the period of leave provided under clause (ii) of subsection (a)(5)(A), except that nothing in this title shall require an employer to provide paid sick leave or paid medical leave in any situation in which such employer would not normally provide any such paid leave.</text></clause><clause id="id6E6027537F1840A695B1AADE182BFE62"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Prohibition on restrictions and limitations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the employee elects or the employer requires the substitution of accrued paid leave for leave under subsection (a)(5), the employer shall not restrict or limit the leave that may be substituted or impose any additional terms and conditions on the substitution of such leave that are more stringent for the employee than the terms and conditions set forth in this Act.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HA9AFCE59E685473387DE18115C8E343D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>Section 102(e) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/2612">29 U.S.C. 2612(e)</external-xref>), as amended by section 2(b), is further amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF7E624CB3DE14F20BF6CB30A876F6AF9"><paragraph id="H5B2E05D01BE44C0782367DA0BE5BAFEB"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Notice relating to parental involvement and family wellness leave</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In any case in which an employee requests leave under paragraph (5) of subsection (a), the employee shall—</text><subparagraph id="H7837BAFF7A35426C983292B01AAC8338"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide the employer with not less than 7 days’ notice, or (if such notice is impracticable) such notice as is practicable, before the date the leave is to begin, of the employee’s intention to take leave under such paragraph; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7711F077C0CB4427B673CAB9576207B8"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of leave to be taken under subsection (a)(5)(A)(ii), make a reasonable effort to schedule the activity or care involved so as not to disrupt unduly the operations of the employer, subject to the approval of the health care provider involved (if any).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H416BFB139C61474CB5F5CA72FE297576"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Certification</header><text>Section 103 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/2613">29 U.S.C. 2613</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block id="H4D8CC301456D4BE1909814B6C1AB7884"><subsection id="H559C39598D824410AF08A6F9997F5758"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Certification related to parental involvement and family wellness leave</header><text>An employer may require that a request for leave under section 102(a)(5) be supported by a certification issued at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may by regulation prescribe.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section commented="no" id="HA7A85F8C3D694B79850767376C072361"><enum>5.</enum><header>Entitlement of Federal employees to leave for parental involvement and family wellness</header><subsection commented="no" id="H9D65C7D334B346D1BAF3B9067E4AAC75"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Leave requirement</header><text>Section 6382(a) of title 5, United States Code, as amended by section 3(b), is further amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block id="H139F497C083943F59E5FE5CFA1AD1B15"><paragraph commented="no" id="H269384197C4A491EAC173F692336DFC2" indent="up1"><enum>(5)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H60C7B5B2DD964DC1AC79955CD31F6837"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Subject to subparagraph (B) and section 6383(f), an employee shall be entitled to leave under this paragraph to—</text><clause commented="no" id="H4676648A0CE340E78796B92581D6DFD8" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>participate in or attend an activity that is sponsored by a school or community organization and relates to a program of the school or organization that is attended by a son or daughter or a grandchild of the employee; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H44F7A2E6522246F2AE36A759CFA9977F" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>meet routine family medical care needs (including by attending medical and dental appointments of the employee or a son or daughter, spouse or domestic partner, or grandchild of the employee) or to attend to the care needs of an elderly individual who is any other individual whose close association is the equivalent of a family relationship with the employee (including by making visits to nursing homes and group homes). </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H0267F2DAFE3B49CA845FBD34FEBD9D10" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HA3BAB25E1E224FD0BF17CD1CFD6469E0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>An employee is entitled to—</text><subclause commented="no" id="HA9924710C6B94B38A0A332C231325702" indent="up1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>not to exceed 4 hours of leave under this paragraph during any 30-day period; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HF6171C5ACE3C4F56A013440E1177F582" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>not to exceed 24 hours of leave under this paragraph during any 12-month period described in paragraph (4). </text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" id="H2C62E21169B04F06A21E338BACF12284" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Leave under this paragraph shall be in addition to any leave provided under any other paragraph of this subsection.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H8B36D51A210740A4BFA01F96906B99D4" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>For the purpose of this paragraph—</text><clause commented="no" id="id2AECB8424559451699C36A2A6B669D83"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the term <term>community organization</term> means a private nonprofit organization that is representative of a community or a significant segment of a community and provides activities for individuals described in section 6381(6), such as a scouting or sports organization; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="HA84BBD5635814093A9FC415222180B4B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the term <term>school</term> means an elementary school or secondary school (as such terms are defined in section 8101 of the <act-name parsable-cite="ESEA">Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>)), a Head Start program assisted under the <act-name parsable-cite="HSA">Head Start Act</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9831">42 U.S.C. 9831 et seq.</external-xref>), and a child care facility licensed under State law.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H2075E9342EFE4710AE133FBC2B1746A6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Schedule</header><text>Section 6382(b)(1) of such title is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" id="HD1E16F627DCB40A89F0E30098785AAB2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by inserting after the third sentence the following new sentence: <quote>Subject to subsection (e)(4) and section 6383(f), leave under subsection (a)(5) may be taken intermittently or on a reduced leave schedule.</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HE448102C12A047B8AF987C2D4556A459"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the last sentence, by striking <quote>involved,</quote> and inserting <quote>involved (or, in the case of leave under subsection (a)(5), for purposes of the 30-day or 12-month period involved),</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H6EDBDE140CD0437BAD59DC35ED6EE10D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Substitution of paid leave</header><text>Section 6382(d) of such title is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF4F3726BCD394AF8B42E1CE2A95E472A"><paragraph id="H213746AB77EA4B1CAAE836FA3DBBCBF8" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An employee may elect to substitute for any part of the period of leave under subsection (a)(5), any of the employee’s accrued or accumulated annual or sick leave. If the employee elects the substitution of that accrued or accumulated annual or sick leave for leave under subsection (a)(5), the employing agency shall not restrict or limit the leave that may be substituted or impose any additional terms and conditions on the substitution of such leave that are more stringent for the employee than the terms and conditions set forth in this subchapter.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H72C0BA6DA4D94A8DBFD542BA361F9DFE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>Section 6382(e) of such title, as amended by section 3(b)(2), is further amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7ABF564B14CE4E65A6B12A53A5DDD346"><paragraph commented="no" id="H6348720292724590849E025F68390432" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In any case in which an employee requests leave under paragraph (5) of subsection (a), the employee shall—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="HE3FE934D302E4BC0A8086A03C3135BD8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide the employing agency with not less than 7 days’ notice, or (if such notice is impracticable) such notice as is practicable, before the date the leave is to begin, of the employee’s intention to take leave under such paragraph; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H8E2264C771F743B28EC0E4C629317BB7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of leave to be taken under subsection (a)(5)(A)(ii), make a reasonable effort to schedule the activity or care involved so as not to disrupt unduly the operations of the employing agency, subject to the approval of the health care provider involved (if any).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H8AB65000B7FB42B28EBD2F12B4028704"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Certification</header><text>Section 6383(f) of such title is amended by striking <quote>paragraph (1)(E) or (3) of</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraph (1)(E), (3) or (5) of </quote>.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

