<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" dms-id="H12749B0BCB9C4BAFA2A08407A17FD140" public-private="public" key="G" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 586 : Vietnam Veterans Liver Fluke Cancer Study Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 586</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250408">April 8, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSVA00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to study and report on the prevalence of cholangiocarcinoma in veterans who served in the Vietnam theater of operations during the Vietnam era, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0606F36E7BF04677AEA52C5FF0738FED" style="OLC"><pagebreak></pagebreak><section id="H5A485AD9FA6C43ECB0AC587E21163063" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Vietnam Veterans Liver Fluke Cancer Study Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H534440B840124488804E18CECACD50A4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Study on the prevalence of cholangiocarcinoma in veterans who served in the Vietnam theater of operations during the Vietnam era</header><subsection id="H3158948F5F4A4EA5A7868684A155EEC5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Epidemiological study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, in consultation with the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention of the Department of Health and Human Services, shall commence an epidemiological study on the prevalence of cholangiocarcinoma in covered veterans of the Vietnam era, using data from the Veterans Affairs Central Cancer Registry and the National Program of Cancer Registries. The study shall include—</text><paragraph id="H9A8A22345E354808866A7F140318F03C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an identification of the rate of incidence of cholangiocarcinoma in covered veterans of the Vietnam era and in residents of the United States, from the beginning of the Vietnam era to the date of enactment of this Act; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD4988ED509AC4003B7F78C780A6BFD82"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for each of the groups specified in paragraph (1), an identification of the percentage of individuals with cholangiocarcinoma by various demographic characteristics, including by age, gender, race, ethnicity, and the geographic location of the patient at the time of diagnosis.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8E4C147CDAB0435E995DD68C2AED3783"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header><paragraph id="HB6DA29ADA9A7447D83A1C70EB7360428"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial report</header><text>Not later than one year after the completion of the study under subsection (a), the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report containing—</text><subparagraph id="H833513DC9901492697072CF21F2F35A1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the results of the study under subsection (a); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H79F366C7850145C8A5FFB6074F65B8FC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>recommendations for administrative or legislative actions required to address issues identified in the study under subsection (a).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H847CFC88C2CF4C96A43F7085E058C58B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Follow-Up reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall periodically submit to the Congress a follow-up reports, as determined by the Secretary, to provide updates to the information included in the initial report under paragraph (1) and information collected pursuant to subsection (c).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEB25D0BC89074ABD8EC904DEE024FBB2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Continued tracking of cholangiocarcinoma in covered veterans of the Vietnam era</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall track the prevalence of cholangiocarcinoma in covered veterans of the Vietnam era using the Veterans Affairs Central Cancer Registry, and provide such information to Congress in follow-up reports submitted under subsection (b)(2).</text></subsection><subsection id="HA8425E55B07F4F9C9CE1F1C72A27CB00"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H744929A3B3AE4A88830E19B2681B3E0B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>Vietnam era</term> has the meaning given such term in section 101 of title 38, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7EBEB469480043BBB05DB57334213A68"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered veterans of the Vietnam era</term> means veterans who served in the Vietnam theater of operations during the Vietnam era.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H0717026AEC434AAAAF12C76A1BD44467"><enum>3.</enum><header>Extension of certain limitation of pension payments</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 5503(d)(7) of title 38, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>November 30, 2031</quote> and inserting <quote>December 31, 2031</quote>.</text></section></legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20250407" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives April 7, 2025.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Kevin F. McCumber,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation></bill> 

