<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-FLO25294-YRJ-JJ-5YJ"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>95 S888 IS: Oregon Recreation Enhancement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 888</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250306">March 6, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To designate certain land administered by the Bureau of Land Management and the Forest Service in the State of Oregon as wilderness and national recreation areas, to withdraw certain land located in Curry County and Josephine County, Oregon, from all forms of entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws, location, entry, and patent under the mining laws, and operation under the mineral leasing and geothermal leasing laws, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="idcbc583ca48ed47698e4962ac434fd951"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Oregon Recreation Enhancement Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="ida4e18eeb53ca4c19ab4791182b812102"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="id269777485ff042f19717c50d1f3eb730"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="id53f5390f4fdb4e8389db595841ea061c"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary of the Interior, with respect to public land administered by the Secretary of the Interior; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida0bc3b698522425ba41607be848c9abf"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary of Agriculture, with respect to National Forest System land.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5e5d97a38a3142c9beb498839ef9da4d"><enum>(2)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means the State of Oregon.</text></paragraph></section><section id="id46de6fc6e884434ea145634135761b6b"><enum>3.</enum><header>Rogue Canyon and Molalla Recreation Areas, Oregon</header><subsection id="id48ab3ba08b8a49d1a7f26c0140586866"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation of rogue canyon and molalla recreation areas</header><text>For the purposes of protecting, conserving, and enhancing the unique and nationally important recreational, ecological, scenic, cultural, watershed, and fish and wildlife values of the areas, the following areas in the State are designated as recreation areas for management by the Secretary in accordance with subsection (c):</text><paragraph id="idd953a3672b594b9d887e82031992bfa9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Rogue canyon recreation area</header><text>The approximately 98,150 acres of Bureau of Land Management land within the boundary generally depicted as the <quote>Rogue Canyon Recreation Area</quote> on the map entitled <quote>Rogue Canyon Recreation Area Wild Rogue Wilderness Additions</quote> and dated November 19, 2019, which is designated as the <quote>Rogue Canyon Recreation Area</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id40c162e902fb4e0e9234d92426c3ec34"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Molalla recreation area</header><text>The approximately 29,884 acres of Bureau of Land Management land within the boundary generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Molalla Recreation Area</quote> and dated September 26, 2018, which is designated as the <quote>Molalla Recreation Area</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0d885acefdf249f09b9fcdec8faa42bd"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Maps and legal descriptions</header><paragraph id="idf716b6151d774bde8d730af61bb31a72"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>As soon as practicable after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall prepare a map and legal description of each recreation area designated by subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddd7bfd52ecd3470eb09a533257798b3d"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effect</header><text>The maps and legal descriptions prepared under paragraph (1) shall have the same force and effect as if included in this Act, except that the Secretary may correct any minor errors in the maps and legal descriptions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc445829e07364d45aa72c15ffb90eba3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The maps and legal descriptions prepared under paragraph (1) shall be available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of the Bureau of Land Management.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id60a9d9e719fc406b9a0aea6c5ad54084"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Administration</header><paragraph id="id5363c497a97b4553a794671e45371686"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Applicable law</header><text>The Secretary shall administer each recreation area designated by subsection (a)—</text><subparagraph id="id13ab568186264f2e93d6553db940b887"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in a manner that conserves, protects, and enhances the purposes for which the recreation area is established; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1379748ffdaa49ebb458d3d34e8af0c3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in accordance with—</text><clause id="id42D8EFC6AFE64B819BBD4C283726E390"><enum>(i)</enum><text>this section;</text></clause><clause id="idBF24E3550A9A419F850F802F46B86FF9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1701">43 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></clause><clause id="idB4AB37E632604331BABE960A9DBBC695"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>other applicable laws.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id8d3ca730941a407a88c84badb7ecdd35"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Uses</header><text>The Secretary shall only allow those uses of a recreation area designated by subsection (a) that are consistent with the purposes for which the recreation area is established.</text></paragraph><paragraph changed="not-changed" id="idfecd173656944e1396616baf2b87f8c6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Wildfire risk assessment</header><text>Not later than 280 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary, in consultation with the Oregon Governor’s Council on Wildfire Response, shall conduct a wildfire risk assessment that covers—</text><subparagraph id="id97fc804b14ad4dc88111e9fdd347d53e" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the recreation areas designated by subsection (a);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9e1cce72c0604b1dacb8a1319b426646" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Wild Rogue Wilderness; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd54105be42ff44369a2e3ffc43ae6958" changed="not-changed"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any Federal land adjacent to an area described in subparagraph (A) or (B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph changed="not-changed" id="idc4ac048e03414213a8ef8f8b03e6a329"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Wildfire mitigation plan</header><subparagraph id="ida76ef7b4763e43dd97413ee68ac9d18b" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date on which the wildfire risk assessment is conducted under paragraph (3), the Secretary shall develop a wildfire mitigation plan, based on the wildfire risk assessment, that identifies, evaluates, and prioritizes treatments and other management activities that can be implemented on the Federal land covered by the wildfire risk assessment (other than Federal land designated as a unit of the National Wilderness Preservation System) to mitigate wildfire risk to communities located near the applicable Federal land.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2470006899f54efebb70acd979768ab5" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Plan components</header><text>The wildfire mitigation plan developed under subparagraph (A) shall include—</text><clause id="idedf8498cb0f04df2bd55adad36e088e2" changed="not-changed"><enum>(i)</enum><text>vegetation management projects (including mechanical treatments to reduce hazardous fuels and improve forest health and resiliency);</text></clause><clause id="id542dd1fef28b4fd782970d2010b49f32" changed="not-changed"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>evacuation routes for communities located near the applicable Federal land, which shall be developed in consultation with State and local fire agencies; and</text></clause><clause id="id0ccd94527dbb4d4cb7871afad8166ebc" changed="not-changed"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>strategies for public dissemination of emergency evacuation plans and routes.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7422b03365b645ca983d2445ebed05ce" changed="not-changed"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Applicable law</header><text>The wildfire mitigation plan under subparagraph (A) shall be developed in accordance with—</text><clause id="id3fe89a828ab74e8cb6154c97c672be21" changed="not-changed"><enum>(i)</enum><text>this section; and</text></clause><clause id="idd1c637ec8b8f4cd6ade7603d6b723a1f" changed="not-changed"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any other applicable law.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph changed="not-changed" id="id5eaa73a273bc4f17aabea67de7c280a4"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Road construction</header><subparagraph id="iddf43ffe3f7ae458ab29b05002d030420" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B) or as the Secretary determines necessary for public safety, no new permanent or temporary roads shall be constructed (other than the repair and maintenance of existing roads) within a recreation area designated by subsection (a).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id51dae0f33ac84e058234b28328a057df" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Temporary roads</header><text>Consistent with the purposes of this Act, the Secretary may construct temporary roads within a recreation area designated by subsection (a) to implement the wildfire mitigation plan developed under paragraph (4), unless the temporary road would be within an area designated as a unit of the National Wilderness Preservation System.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id80e655745e544b55986a510630e4cc2f" changed="not-changed"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Effect</header><text>Nothing in this paragraph affects the administration by the Secretary of the Molalla Forest Road in accordance with applicable resource management plans.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph changed="not-changed" id="id7B4A32FE0490446E94A8EA6EEDC2E3DC"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Effect on wildfire management</header><text>Nothing in this section alters the authority of the Secretary (in cooperation with other Federal, State, and local agencies, as appropriate) to conduct wildland fire operations within a recreation area designated by subsection (a), consistent with the purposes of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph changed="not-changed" id="idE7D73B0A222241FEB1A5CFDFCA320006"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Withdrawal</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, all Federal surface and subsurface land within a recreation area designated by subsection (a) is withdrawn from all forms of—</text><subparagraph id="id01A6935A51BB485F8927978DA9C37D01" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id23DB2B7058A54492B2408BD5D43FCC7A" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8191A3AB65F94C86B82777C7953A48D0" changed="not-changed"><enum>(C)</enum><text>disposition under all laws pertaining to mineral leasing, geothermal leasing, or mineral materials.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph changed="not-changed" id="id60443c402def4b0fbe0e773bf3b2e305"><enum>(8)</enum><header>No effect on wilderness areas</header><text>Any wilderness area located within a recreation area designated by subsection (a) shall be administered in accordance with the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idb67f9c2cef774db2a35049e2f441878a"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Adjacent management</header><text>Nothing in this section creates any protective perimeter or buffer zone around a recreation area designated by subsection (a).</text></subsection></section><section id="idf02a832f37b641109c5db5f4eb1e80a0"><enum>4.</enum><header>Expansion of Wild Rogue Wilderness Area</header><subsection id="id964fdbc3d3bc4558a882e0e124b41759"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="id637d43e2fcbc4fe18ba6e8eab57ede2a"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Map</header><text>The term <term>map</term> means the map entitled <quote>Rogue Canyon Recreation Area Wild Rogue Wilderness Additions</quote> and dated November 19, 2019.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id52a5b456f0594d5680a963272bebea23"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Wilderness additions</header><text>The term <term>Wilderness additions</term> means the land added to the Wild Rogue Wilderness under subsection (b)(1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id270283a550394c999883b232aafffebf"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Expansion of wild rogue wilderness area</header><paragraph id="id4afab6fcdbdd4b87bb9b4e935d8de793"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Expansion</header><text>The approximately 59,512 acres of Federal land in the State generally depicted on the map as <quote>Proposed Wilderness</quote> shall be added to and administered as part of the Wild Rogue Wilderness in accordance with the Endangered American Wilderness Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1132">16 U.S.C. 1132</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/95/237">Public Law 95–237</external-xref>), except that—</text><subparagraph id="id49f29fb1feee4ee3b7c21b7a142aed2f"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture shall administer the Federal land under their respective jurisdiction; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id42b0465a7e694ed4bd3b227926ec40a0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any reference in that Act to the Secretary of Agriculture shall be considered to be a reference to the Secretary of Agriculture or the Secretary of the Interior, as applicable.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id8dab3a446a5c4de384f55677e4747b8d"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Map; legal description</header><subparagraph id="id88387950ae4541f38d377ec4acc2d307"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>As soon as practicable after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall prepare a map and legal description of the wilderness area designated by paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbffd7a73120e4d4cbee23972741b2f42"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Force of law</header><text>The map and legal description filed under subparagraph (A) shall have the same force and effect as if included in this section, except that the Secretary may correct typographical errors in the map and legal description.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id27ff633f14a446dfb7e8935eddce2c6b"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The map and legal description filed under subparagraph (A) shall be on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of the Bureau of Land Management and Forest Service.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id59bd97d121ec47ce8f7c9cf99e6151c3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Fire, insects, and disease</header><text>The Secretary may take such measures within the Wilderness additions as the Secretary determines to be necessary for the control of fire, insects, and disease, in accordance with section 4(d)(1) of the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1133">16 U.S.C. 1133(d)(1)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2ecadd1290f44fe6a14ab56ce1990f73"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Withdrawal</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, the Wilderness additions are withdrawn from all forms of—</text><subparagraph id="id4c004804f6584aa6956bfebfa57f94aa"><enum>(A)</enum><text>entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id518c649db47a416d87b7591d242fab42"><enum>(B)</enum><text>location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf4df88eea57d47578bba11571872f27c"><enum>(C)</enum><text>disposition under all laws pertaining to mineral leasing, geothermal leasing, or mineral materials.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id49ce9e6f46c44a4c970bc9d64dfa10b3"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Tribal rights</header><text>Nothing in this subsection alters, modifies, enlarges, diminishes, or abrogates the treaty rights of any Indian Tribe.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idB2C7B94F41644532AB5B6CCFBEEABFFF"><enum>5.</enum><header>Withdrawal of Federal land, Curry County and Josephine County, Oregon</header><subsection id="H1E3B240D8D6946FA9EDE11C1F9E2DBE5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph id="H096BC0FC300441349DCEE3658C495691"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible Federal land</header><text>The term <term>eligible Federal land</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H6C22AFDFDA7D42CDBD53D1B677675C9F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any federally owned land or interest in land depicted on the Maps as within the Hunter Creek and Pistol River Headwaters Withdrawal Proposal or the Rough and Ready and Baldface Creeks Mineral Withdrawal Proposal; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H84E34F83D5BE48B2B4DF82BCED3E0C9B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any land or interest in land located within such withdrawal proposals that is acquired by the Federal Government after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1E901419E7BF4220A0DE64AC3922C356"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Maps</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Maps</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H409455E65F134A1EA2B75B26537344C1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Bureau of Land Management map entitled <quote>Hunter Creek and Pistol River Headwaters Withdrawal Proposal</quote> and dated January 12, 2015; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H29E54BE1849E4930B9285D1FB3A89C6F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Bureau of Land Management map entitled <quote>Rough and Ready and Baldface Creeks Mineral Withdrawal Proposal</quote> and dated January 12, 2015.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2800CD9562744CE59804408F8456A101"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Withdrawal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to valid existing rights, the eligible Federal land is withdrawn from all forms of—</text><paragraph id="H9256E5C9B30A4A6A85AED164C4B86413"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAD28945667E245619E4E8412D455F992"><enum>(2)</enum><text>location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8585AF8404A748DEBAC988AB697CCAA6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>operation under the mineral leasing and geothermal leasing laws.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0887CA3047DA422B9DA6A44BBB85D7E4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Availability of maps</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Maps shall be made available to the public at each appropriate office of the Bureau of Land Management.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA7D00CF4AB9B4082BC301089EE892EDA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Existing uses not affected</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except with respect to the withdrawal under subsection (b), nothing in this section restricts recreational uses, hunting, fishing, forest management activities, or other authorized uses allowed on the date of enactment of this Act on the eligible Federal land in accordance with applicable law.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

