<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD4BDA3C0D76449DD9237605C62AA246E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3687 IH: To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to renew and enhance opportunity zones, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3687</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250603">June 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000376">Mr. Kelly of Pennsylvania</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to renew and enhance opportunity zones, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA4D056A278894EF294CEE49027112247" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H248564FA39F740D89BDEC40BFB5F37B9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Renewal and enhancement of opportunity zones</header> 
<subsection id="H01BCDB622BA946E4AC573F27AFA8DEBF">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Modification of low-Income community definition</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/1400Z">Section 1400Z–1(c)(1)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended—</text>
        <paragraph id="HA94C336A2B6B4E2CBDE16AC2C72478A3">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>by striking <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC" >communities.</header-in-text>—The term</quote> and inserting the following:</text>
          <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="yes-display-inline"
            id="HEE7356BFEF1340F9A7F13CF470F2A3C3">
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC" >communities.</header-in-text>—</text>
            <subparagraph id="H623E5879D5FC4825BFA32CC9E404B057">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <header>In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term</text> </subparagraph> <after-quoted-block>, and</after-quoted-block> </quoted-block> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HCF528523C8644DA590EDD8D2DBE1BEBE"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
          <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline"
            id="H317AFEB432F74E32AA2CC60BE1C14EFB">
            <subparagraph id="HA1041E48A55242318FD873CB992968F3">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <header>Modifications</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of subparagraph (A), section 45D(e)(1) shall be applied in subparagraph (B) thereof, by substituting <quote>70 percent</quote> for <quote>80 percent</quote> each place it appears.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HCF264D5D25AC4BB1BE908CACBA96FC7A">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <header>Certain census tracts disallowed</header>
 <text>The term <quote>low-income community</quote> shall not include any population census tract if—</text>
              <clause id="H3D487A617B884EBC9183503C355A685B">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>in the case of a tract not located within a metropolitan area, the median family income for such tract is at least 125 percent of statewide median family income, or</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="H1F011332D2FF4441A7B5AF13554AF4F2">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>in the case of a tract located within a metropolitan area, the median family income for such tract is at least 125 percent of the metropolitan area median family income.</text>
              </clause>
            </subparagraph>
            <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
          </quoted-block>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H9BD1D9E89DC2462C962ECBE522FD21EB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>New round of qualified opportunity zone designations</header> 
<paragraph id="H9F7711D1A4704664A4C56103C0AB1459"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1400Z–1 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8684BAA17E864E828A2F31DA2B851936"> <subsection id="H3CF26FDB15554FED9E86BF7CF8F8A09E"><enum>(g)</enum><header>New round of qualified opportunity zone designations</header> <paragraph id="H24D57E9DF38E48E39453368C12AABCF9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to designations under subsection (b), and under rules similar to the rules of such subsection, the Secretary shall designate tracts nominated by the chief executive officers of States for purposes of this section.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC8640576DFF94274A9B297DA5B8F1A46"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Number of designations; proportion of rural areas designated</header> 
<subparagraph id="H11B3571F66564CE6A0DBE3CF14F72AC5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Of the low-income communities within a State, the Secretary may designate under this subsection not more than 25 percent as qualified opportunity zones, of which at least the lesser of the following shall be qualified opportunity zones which are comprised entirely of a rural area:</text> <clause id="HAC759E9810DC45ED943FD2329995D635"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The applicable percentage of the total number of qualified opportunity zone designations which may be made within the State under this subsection.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H2A53A24FCA474FF7BBCA3EFAE0E06182"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">All low-income communities within the State which are comprised entirely of a rural area.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2DBF5AA79FC14A268F45F928A73154C1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Applicable percentage</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the applicable percentage shall be, for any calendar year during which a designation is made, the greater of—</text> 
<clause id="HA572C10258EC4CE094250EE4664C8B3D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>33 percent, or</text></clause> <clause id="H14015B2BBD7D44509985E0400B483A16"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the percentage of the United States population living within a rural area for the preceding calendar year.</text></clause></subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H69B3B8D0CED046C2AA7B4DB675B589F9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rural area</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether a low-income community is comprised entirely of a rural area shall be determined by the Secretary in consultation with the Secretary of Agriculture. For purposes of this subsection, the term <quote>rural area</quote> has the meaning given such term by section 343(a)(13)(A) of the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE7E855FD31274ADFA34308940AB07187"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Period for which designation is in effect</header><text>A designation as a qualified opportunity zone under this subsection shall remain in effect for the period beginning on January 1, 2027, and ending on December 31, 2033.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE70B16B9676E49599C753CD439EBF886"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Contiguous tracts not eligible</header><text>Subsection (e) shall not apply to designations made under this subsection.</text></paragraph> </subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA6ACF075D64D4FACB4B46E8E27AB7F30"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Election with respect to new round of zones</header><text>Section 1400Z–2(a)(2)(B) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>December 31, 2026</quote> and inserting <quote>December 31, 2033</quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA5E0798590E1467BBC9609CCE28005F1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Year of inclusion</header><text>Section 1400Z–2(b)(1)(B) of such Code is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H238F9B176C7F46318D058E3B18577647"> <subparagraph id="H3040EE331CA04E17830AE1931BEE950D"><enum>(B)</enum> <clause id="H6A4F89F612B0464C9AADEC9DD1B8DA34" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(i)</enum><text>December 31, 2026, in the case of an amount invested before January 1, 2027, and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H55F56C468A0F44CE90D70EC5A547CCB8" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>December 31, 2033, in the case of an amount invested after December 31, 2026, and before January 1, 2034.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="H208CD5409BBF4A14AAE8145B7407298E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Winding down initial zone designations</header><text>Section 1400Z–1(f) of such Code is amended—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE7FE887B1A75442F9FDE076693A6C2B3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and ending</quote> and all that follows and inserting the following: <quote>and ending on December 31, 2026.</quote>, and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H41504F848C71439B82040965BB463481"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>A designation</quote> and inserting <quote>Except as provided in subsection (g)(4), a designation</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD3F779F04DBD4F9094DB048126A47D4D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Modification of opportunity zone investment incentives</header> 
<paragraph id="H541F6930E26444BC9DE551B9323E4B5C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Consolidated basis increases; rural zone basis increase</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1400Z–2(b)(2)(B) of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new clauses:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H46FAE8F129B747F39D3A2FF2DED48131"> <clause id="HAA031709982D467E93B419B13A533476"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Consolidated basis increase for investments after <enum-in-header>2026</enum-in-header></header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of investments made after December 31, 2026—</text> 
<subclause id="H2C092E11C2B84DD5B21E9180F57064C3"><enum>(I)</enum><text>clauses (iii) and (iv) shall not apply, and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H43285E614703450A999B193F24CE5A39"><enum>(II)</enum><text>for any such investment held by the taxpayer for at least 5 years, the basis of such adjustment shall be increased by an amount equal to 10 percent of the amount of gain deferred by reason of subsection (a)(1)(A).</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="HBE750E1F66484A53B71F7973DD0A9C7C"><enum>(vi)</enum><header>Special rule for rural opportunity funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Clause (v) shall be applied by substituting <quote>30 percent</quote> for <quote>10 percent</quote> in the case of an investment in a qualified rural opportunity fund.</text></clause> <clause id="H1B82564BFE2845FCB820EF8C316BA1DF"><enum>(vii)</enum><header>Qualified rural opportunity fund</header><text>For purposes of clause (vi), a <quote>qualified rural opportunity fund</quote> means a qualified opportunity fund that holds at least 90 percent of its assets in qualified opportunity zone property which—</text> 
<subclause id="H599566239F4143D79E5695F0B852F731"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is qualified opportunity zone business property substantially all of the use of which, during substantially all of the fund’s holding period for such property, was in a qualified opportunity zone comprised entirely of a rural area, or</text></subclause> <subclause id="H503A33EB27254A1FA61987543908EBB7"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is qualified opportunity zone stock, or a qualified opportunity zone partnership interest, in a qualified opportunity zone business in which substantially all of the tangible property owned or leased is qualified opportunity zone business property described in subsection (d)(3)(A)(i) and substantially all the use of which is in a qualified opportunity zone comprised entirely of a rural area.</text></subclause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="clause">For purposes of the preceding sentence, property held in the fund shall be measured under rules similar to the rules of subsection (d)(1).</continuation-text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBA8AA073B1E04F06927D61082FC909B3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limited treatment of ordinary income</header><text>Section 1400Z–2(a) of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1DBBBEC9D0154E6EA7FEC47F8929A0C1"> <paragraph id="H4A2ABE9CC56745BC9D8A6ADF0C180494"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Special rule for ordinary income</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any ordinary income of the taxpayer for the taxable year—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H282CB1673D1341EF83DAF637ACD61DED"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the taxpayer may elect the application of paragraph (1) with respect to so much of ordinary income as does not exceed $10,000 (reduced by the amount of any income with respect to which an election pursuant to this paragraph has previously been made), and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4B264BB44F7741C39BE93EFB39BD9A58"><enum>(B)</enum><text>subsection (b)(2)(B) shall not apply to the investment with respect to such election.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF4D24C47A1F44CC6923C6E375912ED4C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Special rule for improvement of existing structures in rural areas, including for data centers</header><text>Section 1400Z–2(d)(2)(D)(ii) of such Code is amended by inserting <quote>(50 percent of such adjusted basis in the case of property in a qualified opportunity zone comprised entirely of a rural area)</quote> after <quote>the adjusted basis of such property</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H44912CEEF7E74162915D6F4A134379BA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Information reporting on qualified opportunity funds and qualified rural opportunity funds</header> <paragraph id="H0ED71E75A0FE4AE0A51F6A2FE579BE48"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Filing requirements for funds and investors</header><text>Subpart A of part III of subchapter A of chapter 61 of such Code is amended by inserting after section 6039J the following new sections:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HBF5652993B19483D8D72F1ABC982CC3D"> 
<section id="H7886CBDC68DA4E7E98208347DFB1AD9D"><enum>6039K.</enum><header>Returns with respect to qualified opportunity funds and qualified rural opportunity funds</header> 
<subsection id="HE74D8693834E41A79B0A5085EA9E5E63"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Every qualified opportunity fund shall file an annual return (at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may prescribe) containing the information described in subsection (b).</text></subsection> <subsection id="HBACF0537F03B4E09BB6B29E156B81782"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Information from qualified opportunity funds</header><text>The information described in this subsection is—</text> 
<paragraph id="H179A5B5EA0E54FEBAEAD4EFADCED2CCC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the name, address, and taxpayer identification number of the qualified opportunity fund,</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H81DF97F36DCB44C0997FCFFEEAC5C634"><enum>(2)</enum><text>whether the qualified opportunity fund is organized as a corporation or a partnership,</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H89BB760E423943F9A507380FE5C11675"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the value of the total assets held by the qualified opportunity fund as of each date described in section 1400Z–2(d)(1),</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0DB103E668E84E47B3E1173ABA3CC6F4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the value of all qualified opportunity zone property held by the qualified opportunity fund on each such date,</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9542B423195E4B0F889181C7C66B3903"><enum>(5)</enum><text>with respect to each investment held by the qualified opportunity fund in qualified opportunity zone stock or a qualified opportunity zone partnership interest—</text> <subparagraph id="H61755363DD75419FAB5319FBD20C967F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the name, address, and taxpayer identification number of the corporation in which such stock is held or the partnership in which such interest is held, as the case may be,</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA2A473BA78514F7B89D11AE5CE6ACA73"><enum>(B)</enum><text>each North American Industry Classification System (NAICS) code that applies to the trades or businesses conducted by such corporation or partnership,</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCA378BAC65A64C049142E644B5E06D57"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the population census tracts in which the qualified opportunity zone business property of such corporation or partnership is located,</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H678F3ADDB46C40289835B4080D890714"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the amount of the investment in such stock or partnership interest as of each date described in section 1400Z–2(d)(1),</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H41FEDD5A015540C3963ACCE5B9F1756C"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the value of tangible property held by such corporation or partnership on each such date which is owned by such corporation or partnership,</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9AFD8E5CA5EE48409020B7E3F3ACD2C6"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the value of tangible property held by such corporation or partnership on each such date which is leased by such corporation or partnership,</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF1092BA1FE964B36BD0D641C6313F6BA"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the approximate number of residential units (if any) for any real property held by such corporation or partnership, and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5C16D96EFE4C43E4ADC961FF4BF7F5AA"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the approximate average monthly number of full-time equivalent employees of such corporation or partnership for the year (within numerical ranges identified by the Secretary) or such other indication of the employment impact of such corporation or partnership as determined appropriate by the Secretary,</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H61580A927D44463EAD98390447FEE48B"><enum>(6)</enum><text>with respect to the items of qualified opportunity zone business property held by the qualified opportunity fund—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H82AC9F6066F8436D926EB13A04D35777"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the North American Industry Classification System (NAICS) code that applies to the trades or businesses in which such property is held,</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE6105EA0F16C493185642C40B72352AD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the population census tract in which the property is located,</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8F7CA44BC025487C9DDEAED239E69C96"><enum>(C)</enum><text>whether the property is owned or leased,</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H96BA0761501D470F90EE4E3A9C77B8DF"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the aggregate value of the items of qualified opportunity zone property held by the qualified opportunity fund as of each date described in section 1400Z–2(d)(1), and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7FEB53836768475FBD693A6AB5C789D6"><enum>(E)</enum><text>in the case of real property, number of residential units (if any),</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE521D326C8894BD992C1403DE7F945C0"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the approximate average monthly number of full-time equivalent employees for the year of the trades or businesses of the qualified opportunity fund in which qualified opportunity zone business property is held (within numerical ranges identified by the Secretary) or such other indication of the employment impact of such trades or businesses as determined appropriate by the Secretary,</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6CDC3640A0994538A4741152DD055E85"><enum>(8)</enum><text>with respect to each person who disposed of an investment in the qualified opportunity fund during the year—</text> <subparagraph id="H5A9FBD42E6934FDFB2C56FBAA662F2F6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the name and taxpayer identification number of such person,</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB2A0832B5A034E0CAE060C2EF2BEA990"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the date or dates on which the investment disposed was acquired, and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H84EA4743C8F74F1881C9AB90A53F2EDF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the date or dates on which any such investment was disposed and the amount of the investment disposed, and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H100A2D6520114D6E8CDE74D9D269F47B"><enum>(9)</enum><text>such other information as the Secretary may require.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HAE34E6F3E01B47EBB0CB9A09F837E8F1"> <enum>(c)</enum> <header>Statement required To be furnished to investors</header> <text>Every person required to make a return under subsection (a) shall furnish to each person whose name is required to be set forth in such return by reason of subsection (b)(8) a written statement showing—</text>
                <paragraph id="H6A7890A5123A4E74AA45EEF2A6220F8C">
                  <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>the name, address and phone number of the information contact of the person required to make such return, and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HD1DA8D3D5445450C859AD7611BD94181">
                  <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>the information required to be shown on such return by reason of subsection (b)(8) with respect to the person whose name is required to be so set forth.</text>
                </paragraph>
              </subsection> 
<subsection id="HCE4C34AAFB9C46F0A23750AA6AC5926F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text> <paragraph id="H56937C2DF3E84FE6975885B2680987F1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any term used in this section which is also used in subchapter Z of chapter 1 shall have the meaning given such term under such subchapter.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3852FB0BF8AA4EC1A583506FE3304DC7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Full-time equivalent employees</header><text>The term <quote>full-time equivalent employees</quote> means, with respect to any month, the sum of—</text> <subparagraph id="HB08701BA9D3E463D9F60E557856551DC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of full-time employees (as defined in section 4980H(c)(4)) for the month, plus</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2E6E539BA4E944689EEE0AC013C9AABD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of employees determined (under rules similar to the rules of section 4980H(c)(2)(E)) by dividing the aggregate number of hours of service of employees who are not full-time employees for the month by 120.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H5F6B988171904562850E516998E9D5DC" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Application to qualified rural opportunity funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Every qualified rural opportunity fund (as defined in section 1400Z–2(b)(2)(B)(vii)) shall file the annual return required under subsection (a), and the statements required under subsection (c), applied—</text> 
<paragraph id="HB72E80A9CE8043E0B71AEABF28C0295F" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by substituting <quote>qualified rural opportunity</quote> for <quote>qualified opportunity</quote> each place it appears,</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBB8C015A7FE04D0F91C407A30C6F3363" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by substituting <quote>section 1400Z–2(b)(2)(B)(vii)</quote> for <quote>section 1400Z–2(d)(1)</quote> each place it appears, and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB6ECCAE5520F4FDB88C278785C29C247"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by treating any reference (after the application of paragraph (1)) to qualified rural opportunity zone stock, a qualified rural opportunity zone partnership interest, a qualified rural opportunity zone business, or qualified opportunity zone business property as stock, an interest, a business, or property, respectively, described in (I) or (II), as the case may be, of section 1400Z–2(b)(2)(B)(vii).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HD33A9CBC49684582894518036009613A"><enum>6039L.</enum><header>Information required from qualified opportunity zone businesses and qualified rural opportunity zone businesses</header> <subsection id="H75AFC3582FBD4ED19B1779F8CA3873D1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Every applicable qualified opportunity zone business shall furnish to the qualified opportunity fund described in subsection (b) a written statement in such manner and setting forth such information as the Secretary may by regulations prescribe for purposes of enabling such qualified opportunity fund to meet the requirements of section 6039K(b)(5).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9916B5BEE0BB4B01A4E43DC5523F9302"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicable qualified opportunity zone business</header><text>For purposes of subsection (a), the term <quote>applicable qualified opportunity zone business</quote> means any qualified opportunity zone business—</text> <paragraph id="H371848DAF90A49F6A39AC3AAA08A7BB2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>which is a trade or business of a qualified opportunity fund,</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0AF727612FDA4B5AA4F12FB3A3221220"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in which a qualified opportunity fund holds qualified opportunity zone stock, or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9E3B74F7BD1F4636B6BC3F60DE428C27"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in which a qualified opportunity fund holds a qualified opportunity zone partnership interest.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H96F96DAD5091447EA42C5DB97F1E9788"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Other terms</header><text>Any term used in this section which is also used in subchapter Z of chapter 1 shall have the meaning given such term under such subchapter.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H6D2E9E5D854C41FABECBB8AF2C70B112" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Application to qualified rural opportunity businesses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Every applicable qualified rural opportunity zone business (as defined in subsection (b) determined after application of the substitutions described in this sentence) shall furnish the written statement required under subsection (a), applied—</text> 
<paragraph id="H0F755EA8BF7C4DEB97EE40D27D78BB27" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by substituting <quote>qualified rural opportunity</quote> for <quote>qualified opportunity</quote> each place it appears, and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H36D1DAE765E84E90B2268F6169F1443B" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by treating any reference (after the application of paragraph (1)) to qualified rural opportunity zone stock, a qualified rural opportunity zone partnership interest, or a qualified rural opportunity zone business as stock, an interest, or a business, respectively, described in (I) or (II), as the case may be, of section 1400Z–2(b)(2)(B)(vii).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2837321F97A2493EA915E7E55FB2FA71"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Penalties</header> 
<subparagraph id="H2FBA3DEF5A0747CEAA2FE59FE38E4F5B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Part II of subchapter B of chapter 68 of such Code is amended by inserting after section 6725 the following new section:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HAFAADA804A8C46C0BC78C7891D9C7AE3"> <section id="H66EBB4BDED29416FB5EE93A3C77B205A"><enum>6726.</enum><header>Failure to comply with information reporting requirements relating to qualified opportunity funds and qualified rural opportunity funds</header> <subsection id="HAEE741CD305548F2BEB0CF7184D98CF1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of any person required to file a return under section 6039K fails to file a complete and correct return under such section in the time and in the manner prescribed therefor, such person shall pay a penalty of $500 for each day during which such failure continues.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HADC0816AA7E04D5F80E3699B10E50D19"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitation</header> 
<paragraph id="H10FD5185F3B542B2849FA0DFDFA022A2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The maximum penalty under this section on failures with respect to any 1 return shall not exceed $10,000.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8C717CDB86E048C0B83F166F88CAE967"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Large qualified opportunity funds</header><text>In the case of any failure described in subsection (a) with respect to a fund the gross assets of which (determined on the last day of the taxable year) are in excess of $10,000,000, paragraph (1) shall be applied by substituting <quote>$50,000</quote> for <quote>$10,000</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9208346614064696B55CFF76AAA19BBB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Penalty in cases of intentional disregard</header><text>If a failure described in subsection (a) is due to intentional disregard, then—</text> <paragraph id="HCCCF58E692CA44A091354C24796A2B7A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>subsection (a) shall be applied by substituting <quote>$2,500</quote> for <quote>$500</quote>,</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1C466C5C75764BB8A1C978D31C963CC7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>subsection (b)(1) shall be applied by substituting <quote>$50,000</quote> for <quote>$10,000</quote>, and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7BF693ADBBD54222ACE43804E5C00B57"><enum>(3)</enum><text>subsection (b)(2) shall be applied by substituting <quote>$250,000</quote> for <quote>$50,000</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H186891D7B0F648E296A2D66157AD6AA1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Inflation adjustment</header> 
<paragraph id="H23B1848817F2437AA04C051EC2956D5C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of any failure relating to a return required to be filed in a calendar year beginning after 2025, each of the dollar amounts in subsections (a), (b), and (c) shall be increased by an amount equal to such dollar amount multiplied by the cost-of-living adjustment determined under section 1(f)(3) for the calendar year determined by substituting <quote>calendar year 2024</quote> for <quote>calendar year 2016</quote> in subparagraph (A)(ii) thereof.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H90F08B8956DF41D5984E4B4F0C449FCC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rounding</header> <subparagraph id="H3347B8B3630E4BD9BBA06594D8D978E1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the $500 dollar amount in subsection (a) and (c)(1) or the $2,500 amount in subsection (c)(1), after being increased under paragraph (1), is not a multiple of $10, such dollar amount shall be rounded to the next lowest multiple of $10.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB93273B50433466D9F9627A40A58BCDF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Asset threshold</header><text>If the $10,000,000 dollar amount in subsection (b)(2), after being increased under paragraph (1), is not a multiple of $10,000, such dollar amount shall be rounded to the next lowest multiple of $10,000.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5E6028BF0CA54C78A9DF2A20465137E4"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Other dollar amounts</header><text>If any dollar amount in subsection (b) or (c) (other than any amount to which subparagraph (A) or (B) applies), after being increased under paragraph (1), is not a multiple of $1,000, such dollar amount shall be rounded to the next lowest multiple of $1,000.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2F8B470C91214623A6FC2077D779CC87"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Information required to be sent to other taxpayers</header><text>Section 6724(d)(2) of such Code is amended—</text> <clause id="H6A389A0161884A5789FE10885DE685D3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end of subparagraph (KK),</text></clause> 
<clause id="H6F9CD63A2FC54C3E85E24DB244B96063"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end of the subparagraph (LL) and inserting a comma, and</text></clause> <clause id="HF6377965F70943798254CFED5CBCF4F8"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (LL) the following new subparagraphs:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HAB601B72963C47B99A63795FC90F80D0"> 
<subparagraph id="H3736D28DBCB64E25BD17DCF9BFBE4A96"><enum>(MM)</enum><text>section 6039K(c) (relating to disposition of qualified opportunity fund investments), or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3E8E7F6F48BD47779044C0066D173B21"><enum>(NN)</enum><text>section 6039L (relating to information required from certain qualified opportunity zone businesses and qualified rural opportunity zone businesses).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2D31280951CE48749C94216B07D2D936"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Electronic filing</header><text>Section 6011(e) of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H1BBC326ADA2D46DEB9926DC183B06301"> <paragraph id="H215469F3715747BB99555A5198421127"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Qualified opportunity funds and qualified rural opportunity funds</header><text>Notwithstanding paragraphs (1) and (2), any return filed by a qualified opportunity fund or qualified rural opportunity fund shall be filed on magnetic media or other machine-readable form.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE7C9C90E451F4757AB9F461D98C85D1B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Clerical amendments</header> 
<subparagraph id="H09C1990ABCE442598B7452D3E36B03A9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The table of sections for subpart A of part III of subchapter A of chapter 61 of such Code is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 6039J the following new items:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HDDA495CA22B247BA8E6E769D66967B6E"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 6039K. Returns with respect to qualified opportunity funds and qualified rural opportunity funds.</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 6039L. Information required from qualified opportunity zone businesses and qualified rural opportunity zone businesses.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H77F32CB085EE403CB8D5625365053354"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The table of sections for part II of subchapter B of chapter 68 of such Code is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 6725 the following new item:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HA7C8F0D7CFBD470C9443C288AF0057BD"> 
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 6726. Failure to comply with information reporting requirements relating to qualified opportunity funds and qualified rural opportunity funds.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H413B0C871D3D4743A61E2E2E0BB4F7B2"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this subsection shall apply to taxable years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="H635901E1583C44BBACAB50E6BD7BC741"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Secretary reporting of data on opportunity zone and rural opportunity zone tax incentives</header> <paragraph id="HF24E48E40556445A862A2627687A3779"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>As soon as practical after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Secretary of the Treasury, or the Secretary’s delegate (referred to in this section as the <quote>Secretary</quote>), in consultation with the Director of the Bureau of the Census and such other agencies as the Secretary determines appropriate, shall make publicly available a report on qualified opportunity funds.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEBB44EA336F54B639156B3ABF0E20A5C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Information included</header><text>The report required under paragraph (1) shall include, to the extent available, the following information:</text> <subparagraph id="HB9D9C01E2D2D4315B490393B5570B69C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The number of qualified opportunity funds.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDD0EA19ACC4449ADB74A8583C0F53C34"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The aggregate dollar amount of assets held in qualified opportunity funds.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFD34EFED051C4184BBD07E69D9ED846E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The aggregate dollar amount of investments made by qualified opportunity funds in qualified opportunity fund property, stated separately for each North American Industry Classification System (NAICS) code.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H433F1089D473486EAE4965A86B18EC24"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The percentage of population census tracts designated as qualified opportunity zones that have received qualified opportunity fund investments.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA5F40926D57F402A9477E99FA42DFAB7"><enum>(E)</enum><text>For each population census tract designated as a qualified opportunity zone, the approximate average monthly number of full-time equivalent employees of the qualified opportunity zone businesses in such qualified opportunity zone for the preceding 12-month period (within numerical ranges identified by the Secretary) or such other indication of the employment impact of such qualified opportunity fund businesses as determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE017DF5A940D464E8807539339BAC5E0"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The percentage of the total amount of investments made by qualified opportunity funds in—</text> <clause id="H6DDE4A1E76134CA2A4C65156AEF13945"><enum>(i)</enum><text>qualified opportunity zone property which is real property; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H0AD22DCFDE814A8BAC906BD0DC570DDB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>other qualified opportunity zone property.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5FBFEF54279349D2B1EAD5688B961B8B"><enum>(G)</enum><text>For each population census tract, the aggregate approximate number of residential units resulting from investments made by qualified opportunity funds in real property.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H89D1CB3D268740299019BB90E677B30F"><enum>(H)</enum><text>The aggregate dollar amount of investments made by qualified opportunity funds in each population census tract.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9594B3A041B3476A8B9CAD332FCAC06C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Additional information</header> <subparagraph id="HC4DB8B585CCD47A28874D27EA180EE56"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Beginning with the report submitted under paragraph (1) for the 6th year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall include in such report the impacts and outcomes of a designation of a population census tract as a qualified opportunity zone as measured by economic indicators, such as job creation, poverty reduction, new business starts, and other metrics as determined by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8AE9977618F84572B93AA9D7B7B26E09"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Semi-decennial information</header> 
<clause id="H5B91CAC2A351449C9B85A6EEB0F59F6C"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of any report submitted under paragraph (1) in the 6th year or the 11th year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall include the following information:</text> <subclause id="H1E6161FCA0EC4933A3C00902A56073AD"><enum>(I)</enum><text>For population census tracts designated as a qualified opportunity zone, a comparison (based on aggregate information) of the factors listed in clause (iii) between the 5-year period ending on the date of the enactment of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/97">Public Law 115–97</external-xref> and the most recent 5-year period for which data is available.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HB88611B4E130490684881076DE97CF05"><enum>(II)</enum><text>For population census tracts designated as a qualified opportunity zone, a comparison (based on aggregate information) of the factors listed in clause (iii) for the most recent 5-year period for which data is available between such population census tracts and a similar population census tracts that were not designated as a qualified opportunity zone.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H9A35FF367F0347929F3D7A9EE42BC4A6"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Control groups</header><text>For purposes of clause (i), the Secretary may combine population census tracts into such groups as the Secretary determines appropriate for purposes of making comparisons.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HF8729A8D97C54FC29C2399A649154F7F"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Factors listed</header><text>The factors listed in this clause are the following:</text> <subclause id="HCBBD34844A6745CBB1250E7634BACA28"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The unemployment rate.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H05AEB4D4210F423FA0BE931615265234"><enum>(II)</enum><text>The number of persons working in the population census tract, including the percentage of such persons who were not residents in the population census tract in the preceding year.</text></subclause> <subclause id="H4B30757D5D174165A7DF425469D95DBA"><enum>(III)</enum><text>Individual, family, and household poverty rates.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H1EBBC488020B49F28F2BE527D328AFCA"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>Median family income of residents of the population census tract.</text></subclause> <subclause id="H76F3D22963784C4DB4C432DFDEF56820"><enum>(V)</enum><text>Demographic information on residents of the population census tract, including age, income, education, race, and employment.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H22248E0EEB5A4D03A421912A259A175F"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>The average percentage of income of residents of the population census tract spent on rent annually.</text></subclause> <subclause id="HF5A27C70AA9B437394075D83D5F1D5E6"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>The number of residences in the population census tract.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H10E3113AD93847D2A2C8C45C4D3DFBF0"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text>The rate of home ownership in the population census tract.</text></subclause> <subclause id="HB6B87EA3FCC34F31B59EE7F05FD49C0E"><enum>(IX)</enum><text>The average value of residential property in the population census tract.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H5DBCADBD93D9480F9A1C3246A6AB0E90"><enum>(X)</enum><text>The number of affordable housing units in the population census tract.</text></subclause> <subclause id="HCE01772567CA497AAC5188622CCAABDF"><enum>(XI)</enum><text>The number and percentage of residents in the population census tract that were not employed for the preceding year.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H2E13219AFB884ED19E52AB995C97C367"><enum>(XII)</enum><text>The number of new business starts in the population census tract.</text></subclause> <subclause id="H7298765386E64F0D9D0425C938085D73"><enum>(XIII)</enum><text>The distribution of employees in the population census tract by North American Industry Classification System (NAICS) code.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H14442961BFC344488665BB68D71F3042"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Protection of identifiable return information</header><text>In making reports required under this subsection, the Secretary—</text> <subparagraph id="H6732DD57D5B74146AFA9923CB179CF1E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall establish appropriate procedures to ensure that any amounts reported do not disclose taxpayer return information that can be associated with any particular taxpayer or competitive or proprietary information, and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3633655900F4408E903085069ED4480A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if necessary to protect taxpayer return information, may combine information required with respect to individual population census tracts into larger geographic areas.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3FFFB6E4CB0B486A89DF64A2D2AB4D8C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>Any term used in this subsection which is also used in subchapter Z of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 shall have the meaning given such term under such subchapter.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD02EB90FD4E941CEB1FA7E29BB0419ED" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Reports on qualified rural opportunity funds</header><text>The Secretary shall make publicly available, with respect to qualified rural opportunity funds, separate reports as required under this subsection, applied—</text> <subparagraph id="H82F0C45D994547D7A3FA6F6BBA1E99B1" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by substituting <quote>qualified rural opportunity</quote> for <quote>qualified opportunity</quote> each place it appears,</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0852B66A58B34FB8BC6D23D89F13FEC6" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by substituting a reference to this Act for <quote>Public Law 115–97</quote>, and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC37A11FF5CC14D37B466B6E934A0686C" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by treating any reference (after the application of subparagraph (A)) to qualified rural opportunity zone stock, qualified rural opportunity zone partnership interest, qualified rural opportunity zone business, or qualified opportunity zone business property as stock, interest, business, or property, respectively, described in subclause (I) or (II), as the case may be, of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/1400Z">section 1400Z–2(b)(2)(B)(vii)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

