<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB93811552C9F4DC8ADF388770E3D4B11" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 610 IH: Expressing the approval of Congress for the 72d anniversary celebration of the Small Business Administration and in recognition of America’s entrepreneurs and job creators for their important contributions to the United States economy.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 610</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250723">July 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000816">Mr. Williams of Texas</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="O000176">Mr. Olszewski</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSM00">Committee on Small Business</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing the approval of Congress for the 72d anniversary celebration of the Small Business Administration and in recognition of America&#8217;s entrepreneurs and job creators for their important contributions to the United States economy.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas President Dwight D. Eisenhower signed the Small Business Act on July 30, 1953, to create an independent agency to aid, counsel, assist, and protect the interests of small businesses;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas there are more than 33,000,000 small businesses in the United States;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the men and women who own and operate the Nation’s small businesses make a vital contribution to the Nation’s prosperity through their ongoing work to create new technologies, products, and services;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas small businesses are a driving force of the United States economy, driving innovation and competitiveness in the private sector;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas 99.9 percent of businesses across the United States are small businesses;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas nearly half of all United States employees are employed by a small business;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas small businesses ensure a resilient and dominant industrial base critical to the defense of the United States;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Small Business Administration helps small businesses access capital through private sector lending intermediaries;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Small Business Administration supports entrepreneurial development with free and low-cost counseling and training in partnership with resource providers;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Small Business Administration advocates on behalf of small businesses including reducing regulatory burdens, workforce development, and other issues; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Small Business Administration advocates for and supports access to capital and business assistance to help Americans reach the dream of entrepreneurship: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H3A9D76BF78804BA68393D8BE6C2A65C8"> <section id="H3DC4A4D51A43407B8AC65BEBFA824B1E" section-type="undesignated-section" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text> 
<paragraph id="H7184EDA06EC640F7B5D58CA2D61B79A4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>expresses approval of the 72d anniversary celebration of the Small Business Administration; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9C11435089F54217AE406AF3854F2A4E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes American entrepreneurs and job creators for their important contributions to the United States economy.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

