<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1BA4FAB35014498793852EB87F7DAFFE" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 428 IH: Expressing support for the designation of May 2025 as “Moving Month”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 428</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250519">May 19, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001233">Mr. Messmer</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of May 2025 as <quote>Moving Month</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas more than 15,000,000 households move annually for career relocation, educational pursuits, and other personal reasons;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas more than 1 in 10 households move annually;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas moving and storage companies range from small, family-run operations to global corporations transporting the United States most valuable and sentimental possessions with care;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas moving and storage companies come in many different forms, from national van lines and their network of agents to independent movers operating at the national, regional, and local levels;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas moving and storage companies invest in more than just trucks, they rely on a skilled workforce, procure and deploy packing materials, maintain and secure warehouse space, and use state-of-the-art technology and logistics systems and a fleet of trucks and vans;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the moving and storage industry relies on drivers, packers, estimators, warehouse managers, fleet maintenance, a sales team, marketers, software engineers, insurance, and additional third-party specialists;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, in 2024, there were nearly 8,000 interstate household goods carriers in the United States, employing 200,000 men and women, with payrolls totaling more than $13,000,000,000 annually;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the moving and storage industry executes the relocation of residential homes, offices, and industrial and institutional facilities, and provides essential relocation services to Government agencies;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the moving and storage industry plays a vital role in national defense and global mobility through its support of the United States Armed Forces, coordinating and executing close to 300,000 military household goods shipments each year through the Defense Personal Property Program of the Department of Defense;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas more than 70 percent of United States citizens move between the period of May to September, as families aim to finish and begin the school year with minimal disruption; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the purpose of <quote>Moving Month</quote> is to—</text> <paragraph id="H633230E5ADCD47E1A38ADDFB0F1C0B23"><enum>(1)</enum><text>raise public awareness about the invaluable contributions of moving and storage companies who represent an irreplaceable supply chain created through generations of movers’ investment in buildings, people, and equipment; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H071F76F55D10402599E3AE36CDC248DA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>promote respect and understanding of the essential work that moving and storage companies do to carefully and safely transport our essential household goods from one home to another: Now, therefore, be it</text></paragraph></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HC923962C03CF440AA8F9CBC4F80D22D5"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H09CBABB668BB41E2A6BA45E342527DA4"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> 
<paragraph id="HA16E710BC9E5408B97305C5E93D11B7D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">thanks the moving and storage industry of the United States; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H58BB295C4ED642B79A15525477303487"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">promotes the professional services of moving and storage companies by encouraging the public to recognize <quote>Moving Month</quote>.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

