<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MDM25363-9HV-J9-3JD"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1128 IS: Stop Taxpayer Funding of Hamas Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1128</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250325">March 25, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S404">Mr. Scott of Florida</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S374">Mr. Cotton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S355">Mr. Cruz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S429">Mr. Banks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S417">Mr. Budd</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S372">Mrs. Capito</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To prohibit any direct or indirect United States funding for the territory of Gaza unless certain conditions are met.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop Taxpayer Funding of Hamas Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idAC1E4EAE62FE479AAF8656E4AD21CAB0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Restriction on the expenditure for Federal funds in Gaza</header><subsection id="id5288e1ea99ff412ea8aef767749bd48a"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>No United States Government funds may be obligated or expended in the territory of Gaza until after the President certifies to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate</committee-name> and the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives</committee-name> that such funds will be expended without benefitting any organization or persons that is—</text><paragraph id="id654525E852164301889C08C04B824F93"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a member of Hamas, Palestinian Islamic Jihad, or any other organization designated by the Secretary of State as a foreign terrorist organization under section 219 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1189">8 U.S.C. 1189</external-xref>); or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0F42219EE8F94C7CB3FADB6D346BDA41"><enum>(2)</enum><text>controlled or influenced by Hamas, Palestinian Islamic Jihad, or any such foreign terrorist organization.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4c6ff6c5755b497a8f7bebe2c9e9f939"><enum>(b)</enum><header>United Nations entities</header><text>No United States Government funds may be obligated or expended in the territory of Gaza through any United Nations entity or office unless the President certifies to the congressional committees referred to in subsection (a) that such entity or office is not encouraging or teaching anti-Israel or anti-Semitic ideas or propaganda. </text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

