<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD5A950D20848490EA4F3D74C3565D0C2" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5017 IH: Greyhound Protection Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5017</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250822">August 22, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001112">Mr. Carbajal</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="F000484">Mr. Fine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000230">Mr. Davis of North Carolina</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="N000193">Mr. Nunn of Iowa</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Animal Welfare Act to prohibit commercial greyhound racing, live lure training, and open field coursing, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HEEDA0E699E4A48399AEC45C4590E49F7" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H31E7F657BC854428ABA33E5BF0D00F23" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Greyhound Protection Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H773D5BCA75424378831B2C8A706827BA"><enum>2.</enum><header>Congressional findings and policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H2D5A7A679AF64220BCCE161F396D6059"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Greyhounds have existed for thousands of years and are the only canines mentioned by name in the Bible.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC7E72E467AB447A8AA91C3CEB70D8D0D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Commercial greyhound racing was first legalized in Florida in 1931.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6166486F472D4A3CBCD6486E7AB270A7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Modern racetracks require internet-based wire communications to process bets and wagers, calculate odds, broadcast races, announce results, and pay winnings to gamblers. The majority of gambling on dog racing now occurs via simulcast and online.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H396FD8EE327D45148F2472445BB21AA5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Public records reveal that some greyhounds used for live commercial racing suffer serious injuries including broken backs, broken necks, head trauma, paralysis, seizures, and electrocution.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H45E1CA51AFED4E2694CE870C6CF3CD98"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Regulatory records show that some racing greyhounds test positive for drugs including cocaine, amphetamines, barbituates, opiods, and steroids.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7D0E96B8C68540B58644F39ED00AD997"><enum>(6)</enum><text>State investigatory files document that racing greyhounds are kept confined for 20 to 23 hours a day in stacked, metal cages, typically with little opportunity to socialize with other dogs.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9E8202534A8F44B4881A9EA57B0B0902"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Many small animals, including jack rabbits and hares, are bought, sold, delivered, transported, and received in interstate and foreign commerce for use as live bait in the training of racing greyhounds and in open field coursing.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD1DA54A2B99B4B6F8CC7005E3839CA10"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Typically, animals used in live lure training of greyhounds may be dragged on ropes, hung from a horizontal pole which rotates around a training track, or simply set loose to be chased and mauled. Alive or dead, helpless bait animals may be used repeatedly until they are torn apart.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6B4FD6E519DC4773AD09D8081818AD89"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Live lure training is prohibited in more than a dozen States, but there is no Federal statute prohibiting such practice. In the late 1970s, the National Greyhound Association, a membership organization representing breeders, trainers, and other industry participants, announced a policy against live lure training in order to convince the late Senators Birch Bayh and Robert Dole to withdraw their proposed legislation.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H30B2CF077FB743EDB00C2C22ABF9145E"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Open field coursing preceded commercial dog racing and is an activity in which greyhounds or other sighthounds are released to pursue and kill bait animals, including jack rabbits and hares, often in a fenced area. Greyhounds may collide and suffer injuries in the chase.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3D1DAF33CA8443D9A3DF6E8606A8F361"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Dog owners travel from multiple States and countries to compete and win prizes and sometimes gamble on open field coursing events.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDFD0E55D0B054ACB9B09AD67B4719EFD"><enum>(12)</enum><text>As with commercial greyhound racing, internet sites are used to promote coursing tournaments and post results to a worldwide audience.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9585BA66F73343089E64B7FB06DFD48F"><enum>(13)</enum><text>The National Field Coursing Association is the umbrella group for coursing clubs nationwide and maintained 12 clubs in California as of 2006.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6A83BCE46F244FF5AC50D387DB51861E"><enum>(14)</enum><text>Open field coursing is illegal in as many as 12 States.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H52C1465366924A789E3AE534F78D9D9A"><enum>(15)</enum><text>Open field coursing was prohibited as a blood sport in Scotland in 2002, and in the United Kingdom in 2004.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5BAD1B74FB60489FBDB15BA2A11B2C5F"><enum>(16)</enum><text>25 years ago, there were 60 greyhound tracks in the United States. With the voter-mandated closure of 12 dog tracks in Florida and the voluntary shut down of Southland Park in Arkansas and Iowa Greyhound Park in 2022, only 2 tracks, both in West Virginia, will remain nationwide.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8CCDC4F9DD9A40B08AC3DB92FC4A28EA"><enum>(17)</enum><text>According to the State of Florida, track owners had been collectively losing more than $30,000,000 annually because of sagging attendance and decreased wagering. According to a State-commissioned report, the State spent more money regulating the industry in its national hub than it generated in tax revenue. Similarly, nearly $20,000,000 is diverted annually to subsidize the 2 West Virginia tracks.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA6D53E9D97054DA4BB6BCA12ACE72398"><enum>(18)</enum><text>According to State records, more than 10,000 greyhound injuries have been reported at West Virginia racetracks since 2008. More than 3,500 dogs suffered broken bones during this period, and at least 437 dogs died after suffering serious injuries.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H493DFA2623FD4168AAD3AE577DC1CE47"><enum>(19)</enum><text>Live commercial dog racing is illegal in 42 States. As of December 2022, this dying industry will remain legal and operational in no more than 1 State.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H13217E713557408D97890E06972C64B9"><enum>3.</enum><header>Protection of greyhounds</header> <subsection id="HA56545C043A649FDB0BFF99BFE8D76F9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Animal Welfare Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2131">7 U.S.C. 2131 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H473B1618C9644CE3BBDF082F90B1629C" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="H595670D2255B4B76A2C7ADBD6A158676"><enum>30.</enum><header>Protection of greyhounds</header> 
<subsection id="H1681CA6746B940BEAF727F1C75E97E76"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It shall be unlawful—</text> <paragraph id="H8B254CB4D43E463593E7EFFA982DCCB5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>for any person to knowingly engage in commercial greyhound racing, live lure training, or open field coursing events in which any greyhound is moved in interstate or foreign commerce;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6BD96B94A11748E899382255691154A7"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to conduct commercial greyhound racing or racing meeting where any form of betting or wagering on the speed or ability of greyhounds occurs;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9E784269FE3F48F78A613E27CBC8BDE1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to conduct open field coursing or live lure training with the use of any bait that is not an inanimate object;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBDEB8D5074D34A51898A0979AC46259C"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to engage in or facilitate simulcast betting or wagering on greyhound races in interstate or foreign commerce; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H19F48DE73EC74BBC94669A0594B2914F"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for any person to knowingly sell, buy, possess, train, transport, deliver, or receive any greyhound for purposes of having the greyhound participate in commercial greyhound racing, live lure training, or open field coursing events.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HEB9C4814998B4FC5BA6B342F9B1B9C04">
                            <enum>(b)</enum>
                            <header>Investigations</header>
 <text>The Secretary, or any other person authorized by the Secretary, shall make such investigations as the Secretary determines necessary to determine whether any person has violated or is violating any provision of this section. The Secretary may obtain the assistance of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, the Department of the Treasury, or other law enforcement agencies of the United States, and State and local governmental agencies, in the conduct of such investigations, under cooperative agreements with such agencies.</text>
                        </subsection> 
<subsection id="HF100A142927942CAB17E1AA3BBBEF3AA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text>Any person who violates any of paragraphs (1) through (5) of subsection (a) shall be fined under this Act, imprisoned for not more than 7 years, or both, for each such violation. Each instance of a violation of any such paragraph shall be considered a single violation.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H341A0CAB49B54E5B8E6D840C50B29332"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H6143073B53EA45F68FB655293E447647"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Commercial greyhound racing</header><text>The term <term>commercial greyhound racing</term> means any event involving the participation of greyhounds in which betting or wagering on the speed or ability of such greyhounds occurs.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC77BEFD34958472A8069CFDDF48DA7ED"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Simulcast</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>simulcast</term> means the simultaneous audio or visual transmission from one location of foreign or domestic greyhound races taking place at a different location and gambling on the results of such races.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H449087DFFDFD4C029B5FF93CC7421C5B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definition of animal</header><text>Section 2(g) of the Animal Welfare Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2132">7 U.S.C. 2132(g)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>hare,</quote> after <quote>rabbit,</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H16904220AFE540E7B450314D5DD86220"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply with respect to conduct occurring on or after October 1, 2027.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H95D697209D0046DE8DBB5CA0A3543F96"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section, or the amendments made by this section, shall be construed—</text> <paragraph id="HBC11433B8DEC471B847DB5367D13A545"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to preempt any State law prohibiting gambling or protecting the welfare of animals, including greyhounds, jackrabbits, and hares; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H82A152C311F941D192FCF876C7940A2E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to alter, limit, or extend the relationship between the Interstate Horseracing Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/3001">15 U.S.C. 3001 et seq.</external-xref>) as it relates to horse racing and other Federal laws in effect on the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

