<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" slc-id="S1-NEW25442-2S0-M7-019"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 184 ATS: Expressing support for the designation of April 2025 as “National Child Abuse Prevention Month”, and the goals and ideals of National Child Abuse Prevention Month.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 184</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250429">April 29, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S287">Mr. Cornyn</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S430">Ms. Blunt Rochester</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S388">Ms. Hassan</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S408">Mr. Hickenlooper</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of April 2025 as <quote>National Child Abuse Prevention Month</quote>, and the goals and ideals of National Child Abuse Prevention Month.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas children are fundamental to the success of the United States and will shape the future of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas elected representatives and leaders in the communities of the United States must be ever vigilant and proactive in support of evidence-based means to prevent child abuse and neglect, and to support families;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas adverse childhood experiences (referred to in this preamble as <quote>ACEs</quote>) are traumatic experiences that occur during childhood with lasting effects and include experiences of violence, abuse, or neglect;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas at least 5 of the top 10 leading causes of death are associated with ACEs;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas preventing ACEs could reduce many health conditions and long-term negative effects on life, opportunity, and well-being, including—</text><paragraph id="id22f13d189023404b882bcfcb8be02a15"><enum>(1)</enum><text>up to 21,000,000 cases of depression; </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id96acf766952141cab024f73d335c5e39"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">up to 1,900,000 cases of heart disease; and </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf4c3d95c746b4e7dbb04c4b421a3bd7a"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">up to 2,500,000 cases of overweight and obesity;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas every child is filled with tremendous promise, and we all have a collective responsibility to prevent ACEs, foster the potential of every child, and promote positive childhood experiences;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas preventing child abuse and neglect can reduce the costly lifetime economic burden associated with child maltreatment;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2023, an estimated 7,782,000 children were referred to child protective services agencies, alleging maltreatment;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas each year approximately 1 in 7 children in the United States experiences child abuse, neglect, or both;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas reports indicate that 1 in 4 girls and 1 in 13 boys will become victims of child sexual abuse before their 18th birthday;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas 93 percent of child sexual abuse victims are abused by a person they know and trust;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas children who are sexually abused, especially when not provided appropriate treatment and support, often suffer lifelong consequences, such as physical and mental health challenges and higher risk of drug and alcohol misuse and suicide;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas, in 2023, the National Center for Missing and Exploited Children’s CyberTipline received nearly 36,200,000 reports of suspected online child sexual exploitation, a 12-percent increase from 2022, the highest number of reports ever received in 1 year;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas education and awareness of possible signs of child abuse and neglect should be prioritized for purposes of prevention; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, by intervening to prevent adversity and build resilience during the most critical years of development of a child, voluntary, evidence-based, home-visiting programs have shown positive impact on—</text><paragraph id="id051d6a021c334d6eb3db1f4d56d47918"><enum>(1)</enum><text>reducing the recurrence of child abuse and neglect; </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc5f3fb73feb54ae8b0bff1ac5717a34b"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">decreasing the incidence of low-birthweight babies;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id501a37dfd1f446a6bfa63386a382205b"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">improved school readiness for children; and </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb34fd4b99467416395ab515e7a2852c8"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">increased high school graduation rates: Now, therefore, be it</text></paragraph></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="OLC" id="H84DC890CAE184BA98D112AC9E19B3127"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H515B0ABF103A42B79ADD47F40CA1EF24"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="H5278B126D5994FDE827143085E133EED"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the designation of April 2025 as <quote>National Child Abuse Prevention Month</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id96f81316ae20448db95457dd24bbf1a7"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">expresses support for the goals and ideals of National Child Abuse Prevention Month;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5AACC30E9EC043CF81FA3F65294BC6D1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recognizes that child abuse and neglect and child sexual abuse are preventable, and that a healthy and prosperous society depends on strong families and communities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD8BC020BC108455EABC4228C202C1575"><enum>(4)</enum><text>supports efforts to increase the awareness of, and provide education for, the general public of the United States, with respect to preventing child abuse and neglect and building protective factors for families;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA2708BDAAEF149878307A77510F500D5"><enum>(5)</enum><text>supports the efforts to help survivors of childhood sexual abuse heal;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H938137E889CC4058BFEBFD211FAFBE8F"><enum>(6)</enum><text>supports justice for victims of childhood sexual abuse; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H31CF78E319DD44AD8773E3A7842F2CDD"><enum>(7)</enum><text>recognizes the need for prevention, healing, and justice efforts related to childhood abuse, neglect, and sexual abuse.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

