<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-SIL25A13-J5F-23-8JS">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2799 IS: Forced Arbitration Injustice Repeal Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>II</distribution-code>
        <congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session>1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. 2799</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action>
            <action-date date="20250915">September 15, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S354">Ms. Baldwin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S330">Mr.
                    Bennet</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S430">Ms. Blunt Rochester</cosponsor>,
                    <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S275">Ms.
                    Cantwell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</cosponsor>,
                    <cosponsor name-id="S385">Ms. Cortez Masto</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr.
                    Durbin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S331">Mrs. Gillibrand</cosponsor>,
                    <cosponsor name-id="S388">Ms. Hassan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S359">Mr.
                    Heinrich</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>,
                    <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms.
                    Klobuchar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S409">Mr. Luján</cosponsor>,
                    <cosponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S364">Mr.
                    Murphy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S229">Mrs. Murray</cosponsor>,
                    <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S380">Mr.
                    Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S259">Mr. Reed</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S402">Ms. Rosen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S313">Mr.
                    Sanders</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S353">Mr. Schatz</cosponsor>,
                    <cosponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs.
                    Shaheen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S394">Ms. Smith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S415">Mr.
                    Warnock</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S366">Ms. Warren</cosponsor>,
                    <cosponsor name-id="S422">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S316">Mr.
                    Whitehouse</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</cosponsor>)
                introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the
                    <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the
                    Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title>To amend title 9 of the United States Code with respect to
            arbitration.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HACC6172C8655400C98292239985C3577">
        <section section-type="section-one" id="H744FA7221F2C451DB0AE67297C3A822A">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Forced Arbitration Injustice Repeal Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section id="HA78B87BC017847949F5CFFC10AEDFEAB">
            <enum>2.</enum>
            <header>Purposes</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purposes of this Act are to—</text> <paragraph id="HE67E4B5053D34FE7BB378EFEB62F8B5F"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>prohibit predispute arbitration agreements that force arbitration of future employment, consumer, antitrust, or civil rights disputes; and</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HA5AB9ECC209540A094F4AE379EDD6A13">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>prohibit agreements and practices that interfere with the right of individuals, workers, and small businesses to participate in a joint, class, or collective action related to an employment, consumer, antitrust, or civil rights dispute.</text>
            </paragraph>
        </section>
        <section id="HF2D8A32365ED4106A75B0D6161CFBD33">
            <enum>3.</enum>
            <header>Arbitration of employment, consumer, antitrust, and civil rights
                disputes</header>
            <subsection id="H8E8AF6B616D64602B4972DC503FC3C28">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
 <text>Title 9 of the United States Code is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
                <quoted-block style="USC" id="H5EAD47C160F04340A452B4C7EFDAE03F">
                    <chapter id="HBE4FADFACCA141B1B49BE54CFA7127DE">
                        <enum>5</enum>
                        <header>Arbitration of Employment, Consumer, Antitrust, and Civil Rights
                            Disputes</header>
                        <toc>
                            <toc-entry level="section">Sec. </toc-entry>
                            <toc-entry idref="H2DC34A8E2A4F4837B11546BE567CCA4A" level="section">501. Definitions.</toc-entry>
                            <toc-entry idref="H2861C7A34B3D46D98546D31485F52CEB" level="section">502. No validity or enforceability.</toc-entry>
                        </toc>
                        <section id="H2DC34A8E2A4F4837B11546BE567CCA4A">
                            <enum>501.</enum>
                            <header>Definitions</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this chapter—</text> <paragraph id="H2D9A66715F394CBA929DB14FD063DBD0"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>the term <quote>antitrust dispute</quote> means a dispute—</text>
                                <subparagraph id="H37F46275470749049B74BC9994E2888A">
                                    <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>arising from an alleged violation of the antitrust laws (as defined in subsection (a) of the first section of the Clayton Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/12">15 U.S.C. 12(a)</external-xref>)) or State antitrust laws; and</text>
                                </subparagraph>
                                <subparagraph id="H47FC498F14A7481388CADE229F699F0D">
                                    <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>in which the plaintiffs seek certification as a class under rule 23 of the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure or a comparable rule or provision of State law;</text>
                                </subparagraph>
                            </paragraph>
                            <paragraph id="H26739682399C44508C98196C5F2CBF33">
                                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>the term <quote>civil rights dispute</quote> means a dispute—</text>
                                <subparagraph id="H1AC2D720ACBB4DF1B9DED4462F4B008E">
                                    <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>arising from an alleged violation of—</text> <clause id="HAFB035C92B054CF9904E6BA195F5D4C7"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>the Constitution of the United States or the constitution of a State; or</text>
                                    </clause>
                                    <clause id="H06339A96F79E4E3EA399E56A030116B5">
                                        <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>any Federal, State, or local law that prohibits discrimination on the basis of race, sex, age, gender identity, sexual orientation, disability, religion, national origin, or any legally protected status in education, employment, credit, housing, public accommodations and facilities, voting, veterans or servicemembers, health care, or a program funded or conducted by the Federal Government or a State government, including any law referred to or described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/62">section 62(e)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, including parts of such law not explicitly referenced in such section but that relate to protecting individuals on any such basis; and</text>
                                    </clause>
                                </subparagraph>
                                <subparagraph id="H48793F1A96334BAB832D9FF31F60E1EF">
                                    <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>in which at least 1 party alleging a violation described in subparagraph (A) is an individual (or an authorized representative of an individual), including an individual seeking certification as a class under rule 23 of the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure or a comparable rule or provision of State law;</text>
                                </subparagraph>
                            </paragraph>
                            <paragraph id="H7C9B76E8C6C646739D3E1CFBD58D6871">
                                <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>the term <quote>consumer dispute</quote> means a dispute between—</text>
                                <subparagraph id="H287C279925D34D2093582029E744C852">
                                    <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>1 or more individuals, including an individual who seeks certification as a class under rule 23 of the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure or a comparable rule or provision of State law, who seek or acquire real or personal property, services (including services related to digital technology), securities or other investments, money, or credit for personal, family, or household purposes; and</text>
                                </subparagraph>
                                <subparagraph id="H7F2AAC235C4C499E9898A43189A98C76">
                                    <enum>(B)</enum>
                                    <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H65660FD8CC9F4ACFADF8EC56F6E48177">
                                        <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>the seller or provider of such property, services, securities or other investments, money, or credit; or</text>
                                    </clause>
                                    <clause id="HB4EAAED965EC488987EBA6DFAEACC4B4" indent="up1">
                                        <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>a third party involved in the selling, providing of, payment for, receipt or use of information about, or other relationship to any such property, services, securities or other investments, money, or credit;</text>
                                    </clause>
                                </subparagraph>
                            </paragraph>
                            <paragraph id="HB8D1F6E9639A460ABB10560A02B2C891">
                                <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>the term <quote>employment dispute</quote>—</text> <subparagraph id="id64951D6AC8C54102BD3D71B106BC79B7"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>means a dispute between 1 or more individuals (or their authorized representative) and a person arising out of or related to the work relationship or prospective work relationship between them, including a dispute regarding the terms of or payment for, advertising of, recruiting for, referring of, arranging for, or discipline or discharge in connection with, such work, regardless of whether the individual is or would be classified as an employee or an independent contractor with respect to such work; and</text>
                                </subparagraph>
                                <subparagraph id="id42F13E5E16D74DD7A741E6CE7C411E34">
                                    <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>includes—</text> <clause id="idF69D1E0B42D845449CDFB10F5E1468C1"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>a dispute arising under any law referred to or described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/62">section 62(e)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, including parts of such law not explicitly referenced in such section but that relate to protecting individuals on any such basis; and</text>
                                    </clause>
                                    <clause id="id3FB5CD43B3E849989203278964407E19">
                                        <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>a dispute in which an individual seeks certification as a class under rule 23 of the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure or as a collective action under section 16(b) of the Fair Labor Standards Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/216">29 U.S.C. 216(b)</external-xref>), or a comparable rule or provision of State law;</text>
                                    </clause>
                                </subparagraph>
                            </paragraph>
                            <paragraph id="HC8C3A1FBE15A4A9D8046E431C7E3F539">
                                <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text>the term <quote>predispute arbitration agreement</quote> means an agreement to arbitrate a dispute that has not yet arisen at the time of the making of the agreement; and</text>
                            </paragraph>
                            <paragraph id="HD64289E09EC7421985FB1A13DFFF6A52">
                                <enum>(6)</enum>
 <text>the term <quote>predispute joint-action waiver</quote> means an agreement, whether or not part of a predispute arbitration agreement, that would prohibit, or waive the right of, one of the parties to the agreement to participate in a joint, class, or collective action in a judicial, arbitral, administrative, or other forum, concerning a dispute that has not yet arisen at the time of the making of the agreement.</text>
                            </paragraph>
                        </section>
                        <section id="H2861C7A34B3D46D98546D31485F52CEB">
                            <enum>502.</enum>
                            <header>No validity or enforceability</header>
                            <subsection id="HD460930E545F41CAA80F07EA99FC3F53">
                                <enum>(a)</enum>
                                <header>In general</header>
 <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this title, no predispute arbitration agreement or predispute joint-action waiver shall be valid or enforceable with respect to an employment dispute, consumer dispute, antitrust dispute, or civil rights dispute.</text>
                            </subsection>
                            <subsection id="HE3ED3BBB4F114028AE48D939E4442786">
                                <enum>(b)</enum>
                                <header>Applicability</header>
                                <paragraph id="HB04A8ED906224DCFB082D93E5C8FE6E4">
                                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                                    <header>In general</header>
 <text>An issue as to whether this chapter applies with respect to a dispute shall be determined under Federal law. The applicability of this chapter to an agreement to arbitrate and the validity and enforceability of an agreement to which this chapter applies shall be determined by a court, rather than an arbitrator, irrespective of whether the party resisting arbitration challenges the arbitration agreement specifically or in conjunction with other terms of the contract containing such agreement, and irrespective of whether the agreement purports to delegate such determinations to an arbitrator.</text>
                                </paragraph>
                                <paragraph id="H5E6D55120BD54A13BB0AF736968C6114">
                                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                                    <header>Collective bargaining agreements</header>
 <text>Nothing in this chapter shall apply to any arbitration provision in a contract between an employer and a labor organization or between labor organizations, except that no such arbitration provision shall have the effect of waiving the right of a worker to seek judicial enforcement of a right arising under a provision of the Constitution of the United States, a State constitution, or a Federal or State statute, or public policy arising therefrom.</text>
                                </paragraph>
                            </subsection>
                        </section>
                    </chapter>
                    <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
                </quoted-block>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id25ade7c705e94890b6b1286dd22bcf42">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Technical and conforming amendments</header>
                <paragraph id="id7644bb225f74442a9973fe3787bdd171">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                    <header>In general</header>
 <text>Title 9 of the United States Code is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="idc7e86d5003e5490eb2f20c0640e329ee"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>in section 1, by striking <quote>of seamen,</quote> and all that follows through <quote>interstate commerce</quote> and inserting <quote>of individuals, regardless of whether the individuals are designated as employees or independent contractors for other purposes</quote>;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="ide94e68c414e54b14a912875ed2c4c6a7">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>in section 2, by inserting <quote>or 5</quote> before the period at the end;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id367df404fc45400fbca89c3a1f6918cc">
                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>in section 208, in the second sentence, by inserting <quote>or 5</quote> before the period at the end; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="idedc4d43b29b94eec84dd7f8580bb4930">
                        <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>in section 307, in the second sentence, by inserting <quote>or 5</quote> before the period at the end.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="idc56ebcfa8c134ed99a8c5a84aa9206a1">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Table of chapters</header>
 <text>The table of chapters of title 9, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
                    <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idBAF842E9C16C44EE85D079391C8E1327">
                        <toc>
                            <multi-column-toc-entry bold="on" level="chapter">
                                <toc-enum>5. </toc-enum>
                                <level-header level="chapter">Arbitration of employment, consumer,
                                    antitrust, and civil rights disputes</level-header>
                                <target>501</target>
                            </multi-column-toc-entry>
                        </toc>
                        <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
                    </quoted-block>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
        </section>
        <section id="H30EACBBA21734AC7817DB1505E093253">
            <enum>4.</enum>
            <header>Effective date</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act, and the amendments made by this Act, shall take effect on the date of enactment of this Act and shall apply with respect to any dispute or claim that arises or accrues on or after such date.</text>
        </section>
    </legis-body>
</bill>

