<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" slc-id="S1-HLA25002-138-6T-WWG"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 18 IS: Providing for sufficient time for legislation to be read.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 18</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250109">January 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S348">Mr. Paul</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSRA00">Committee on Rules and Administration</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Providing for sufficient time for legislation to be read.</official-title></form><resolution-body style="OLC" id="H50598B92AEF741A199DE1756DA1B6EEF"><section section-type="section-one" id="idC0D5C3E06D9A4B2B85181BDF846E4189"><enum>1.</enum><header>Time for reading of legislation</header><subsection id="id92B9EE8F5C5D4CFAAFE03B8F96298FE9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>It shall not be in order for the Senate to consider any bill, resolution, message, conference report, amendment between the Houses, amendment, treaty, or other measure or matter until 1 session day has passed since introduction for every 20 pages included in the measure or matter in the usual form plus 1 session day for any number of remaining pages less than 20 in the usual form.</text></subsection><subsection id="IDc87f6291fd024bbd90c33c1227c4088c"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Point of order</header><paragraph id="idDA5317C2C714465796C8660E9263F583"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any Senator may raise a point of order that consideration of any bill, resolution, message, conference report, amendment, treaty, or other measure or matter is not in order under subsection (a). A motion to table the point of order shall not be in order.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3CF819025F5D4DEFBF6E896F533AB294"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>Paragraph (1) may be waived or suspended only by an affirmative vote of three-fifths of the Members, duly chosen and sworn. All motions to waive under this paragraph shall be debatable collectively for not to exceed 3 hours equally divided between the Senator raising the point of order and the Senator moving to waive the point of order or their designees. A motion to waive the point of order shall not be amendable.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idF9ACC2CE9DC347A4809293E083F2FE8A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Constitutional authority</header><text>This resolution is adopted pursuant to the power granted to each House of Congress to determine the Rules of its Proceedings in article I, section 5, clause 2 of the Constitution of the United States.</text></subsection></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

