<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-KEL25324-K6N-2N-VR6">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1936 IS: Improving Access to Transfusion Care for Hospice Patients Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>II</distribution-code>
        <congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session>1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. 1936</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action>
            <action-date date="20250603">June 3, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S402">Ms. Rosen</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S317">Mr. Barrasso</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S354">Ms.
                    Baldwin</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and
                referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on
                    Finance</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title>To require the Center for Medicare and Medicaid Innovation to test allowing
            blood transfusions to be paid separately from the Medicare hospice all-inclusive per
            diem payment.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause">
        <section section-type="section-one" id="S1">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Improving Access to Transfusion Care for Hospice Patients Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section id="id963b2d6487304b62a307fcd7c3b0fd81">
            <enum>2.</enum>
            <header>Center for Medicare and Medicaid Innovation testing of allowing blood
                transfusions to be paid separately from the Medicare hospice all-inclusive per diem
                payment</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1115A of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1315a">42 U.S.C. 1315a</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
            <paragraph id="id3850987BB4864FD8A586839B6F656CB5">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>in subsection (b)(2)(A), by adding at the end the following new sentence: “The models selected under this subparagraph shall include the testing of the model described in subsection (h).”; and</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="id1F5C38D06B86424188F187FFCB8843BB">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idC5C70895691449D095A2FDDB020318C4"> <subsection id="id57836F70CBAF482F81938E73F29954A0"> <enum>(h)</enum> <header>Testing of allowing blood transfusions To be paid separately from the Medicare hospice all-Inclusive per diem payment</header> <paragraph id="id4253921B22FD464981A3C40AFA3586BB"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this subsection, the CMI shall establish and implement a model under which blood transfusions furnished to an individual receiving hospice care are paid separately from the hospice all-inclusive per diem payment under section 1814(i). The separate payment amount for such blood transfusion shall be the amount that would otherwise apply under title XVIII if the transfusion was not furnished as part of hospice care.</text>
                        </paragraph>
                        <paragraph id="idC20E6D62B168477CAA84F0646C3D5451">
                            <enum>(2)</enum>
                            <header>Requirements for evaluation</header>
 <text>In conducting any evaluation of the model described in paragraph (1) pursuant to subsection (b)(4), the CMI shall ensure it compares participants under the model with similar patients outside of the model with respect to the following metrics:</text>
                            <subparagraph id="id7d67a2c3b2694fe1b1d17f1ff63c53c7">
                                <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>The number of chemotherapy services furnished in the last 14 days of life.</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <subparagraph id="idcda363c20b294dc59f72e3286067cfb5">
                                <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>Hospital utilization in the last 30 days of life, including emergency department visits, in-patient and observation status stays (including the length of the stays), and intensive care unit (ICU) days.</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <subparagraph id="id656338aa191c45f5b1f5abe15eb5b36d">
                                <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>How many days receiving hospice care before the end of life.</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <subparagraph id="idd1bc7251f4d74f709bb75901ab1c85c8">
                                <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>The number of patients receiving hospice care who received a transfusion compared to patients with similar diagnoses not receiving hospice care.</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <subparagraph id="id28e097c86fe5488a8618133adce263dc">
                                <enum>(E)</enum>
 <text>The average frequency of transfusion for patients receiving hospice care compared to patients not receiving hospice care.</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <subparagraph id="ide6b0094f04594c3c9c7d056a56acc204">
                                <enum>(F)</enum>
 <text>The number of transfusions for patients receiving hospice care compared to patients not receiving hospice care.</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <subparagraph id="idB8CB7CB717434FBFBA82EEF1A9254CF3">
                                <enum>(G)</enum>
 <text> Other areas determined appropriate by the CMI.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> </subsection> <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block> </quoted-block> </paragraph> </section> </legis-body> </bill>

