<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6DAC5023D0B1448DA792ED187919BA51" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5123 IH: Indoor Air Quality and Healthy Schools Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5123</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250903">September 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize a national program to reduce the threat to human health posed by exposure to indoor air contaminants, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6CAE30BB8FBA4DF5B3FE555F70998129" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HBF3DE7BF140941099AF8E05CEE9B4BE0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Indoor Air Quality and Healthy Schools Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H44DC1787FDF34387BE518EE4E66C677A" commented="no"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="H22E38A05A3014962A9AA4D68A42A86D8" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8181FA43928A4A83A4C2864760E5EF76" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered childcare facility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered childcare facility</term> means a facility used by an early childhood education program.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF6B456B08EA0472DAF0664B91B243680" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Early childhood education program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>early childhood education program</term> has the meaning given to that term in section 103 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1003">20 U.S.C. 1003</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD6B8F2C6D0D147B8912AF98AE201C17F" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Indoor</header><text>The term <term>indoor</term> means the enclosed portions of buildings, including nonindustrial workplaces, public buildings, Federal buildings, schools, childcare facilities, commercial buildings, and residences.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB72EAA1688324332BEE0ACE9CDB7BC61" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Indoor air contaminant</header><text>The term <term>indoor air contaminant</term> means any solid, liquid, semisolid, dissolved solid, biogenic agent, aerosol, or gaseous material, including combinations or mixtures of substances, in indoor air which may reasonably be anticipated to have an adverse effect on human health.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H907B829F428D4BEF899546CDB5740134" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Indoor contaminant of concern</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>indoor contaminant of concern</term> means an indoor air contaminant that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD92961A60B1F403C8CCB856BA6CCB36B" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is among the most commonly occurring and poses a risk to human health; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8B052A482C964277A45472F4E8800E04" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is less commonly occurring and poses a significant risk to human health.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFB42CEA06AA4472DBDB2F468523D6D6D" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Local educational agency</header><text>The term <term>local educational agency</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H8C32EAD12AE84B01AA4FDE60148B26AF" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a local educational agency (as defined in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>)); or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H085CA225912D4AA594A90BC0926B105E" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a Tribal education agency (as the term <term>tribal education agency</term> is defined in section 3 of the National Environmental Education Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/5502">20 U.S.C. 5502</external-xref>)).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H21E18F5BB7174932919F04AFADAC7E0C" commented="no"><enum>(8)</enum><header>State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>State</term> includes each of the several States, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HDF4A46F1FF274EBE81D87636CBA046B1" commented="no"><enum>3.</enum><header>Indoor Air Quality Program</header> 
<subsection id="H349E29234BF1466E91142A6F38D3E2D8" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall carry out a program to support the assessment, reduction, and avoidance of exposure to indoor air contaminants to reduce risks to human health.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H68C771BE09954A268AB9FA066E942F43" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the program under subsection (a), the Administrator shall support the assessment, reduction, and avoidance of exposure to indoor air contaminants to reduce risks to human health, including by—</text> 
<paragraph id="H0042EECD0AEB493CB09BE509001D66EA" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">carrying out research, development, and demonstration activities pursuant to the Radon Gas and Indoor Air Quality Research Act of 1986 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7401">42 U.S.C. 7401</external-xref> note);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H81CDBECDC54043678FAD16A62D1A12C4" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">listing indoor contaminants of concern, and publishing guidelines for such indoor contaminants of concern, under section 4;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9316D0F2124947338406557D5540AB90" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">providing training, education, outreach, and technical assistance to identify, eliminate, or reduce indoor air contaminants, including by effective monitoring, source control, ventilation, and filtration practices;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA07EFD65CEBB4613A4384742309E946B" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">providing training, education, outreach, and technical assistance to support the monitoring of humidity levels and the inspection, testing, prevention, and remediation of mold;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HED0BC4E065424CDC919CF39D53B4B8C3" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>carrying out or recognizing voluntary certifications to identify and promote buildings that are most effective at preventing or minimizing risks to health from indoor air contaminants under section 7;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H19F86A2FBABB4B13BCFB71253FEF5F7A" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text>supporting efforts to improve indoor air quality in buildings used by local educational agencies and covered childcare facilities under section 9;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H323839C745A04575AC56D46FA1198782" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensuring effective consultation and coordination among Federal agencies in carrying out programs related to indoor air quality, including the Department of Labor, the Department of Energy, the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, the Occupational Safety and Health Administration, the National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health, the Department of Housing and Urban Development, the Department of Health and Human Services, the Department of Education, the Department of Defense, the Federal Emergency Management Agency, the Consumer Product Safety Commission, and other appropriate agencies carrying out programs related to indoor air quality;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9830AF6F093549CCA82461658F790CAF" commented="no"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supporting State, local, and Tribal governments, local educational agencies, housing authorities, and other entities to develop and implement indoor air quality management strategies, educational campaigns, assessments, guidelines, standards, and response programs;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFF5278D813EE43639A3066C00B6049AD" commented="no"><enum>(9)</enum><text>providing information, guidance, and assistance to the public, including building owners and occupants, on—</text> <subparagraph id="HD5B6B1F54F2844368935C2807E60758E" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>health-related risks of exposure to indoor air contaminants; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5651D23CA0CC42B48F382E1FC3B508F2" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>effective measures and programs for reducing or avoiding exposure to indoor air contaminants;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBF2B5C08FCAA4C7395FFD4DFF1F60547" commented="no"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supporting development and adoption of standardized methods, techniques, minimum product requirements, and protocols for assessing, measuring, and sampling indoor air to determine the presence and concentrations of indoor air contaminants;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8D550E9125C84FDEBDA1AA9C1E80D279" commented="no"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supporting development and adoption of control technologies, building design criteria, and management practices to prevent the entrance of contaminants into buildings and to reduce or mitigate emissions from indoor sources;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HACC85B03CE74433DAC90C594E75E6B66" commented="no"><enum>(12)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assessing the effectiveness of methods, techniques, protocols, response plans, products, and technologies to reduce or avoid exposure to indoor air contaminants;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H23F6DBA9BA084939A08CE71AFA8B408F" commented="no"><enum>(13)</enum><text>supporting the development and adoption of model provisions, to be incorporated into building codes for various types of buildings, designed to improve indoor air quality while taking into account comfort, safety, and energy conservation goals;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCA579DD68E574E469C74C66C576ADC27" commented="no"><enum>(14)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supporting development and adoption of control technologies, building design criteria, and management practices to improve indoor air quality and building resilience against the impacts of more frequent extreme weather events and other consequences of climate change; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7D1B9F1E23F24CD9A625527E5337D5C0" commented="no"><enum>(15)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensuring consideration of disadvantaged communities and individuals in carrying out such program, including by providing access to financial assistance, technical assistance, and other offerings developed pursuant to this Act for all people regardless of income, race, color, gender, national origin, Tribal affiliation, or disability.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H5EDAB5E512C6499E8E7CB1BB2FED5B43" commented="no"><enum>4.</enum><header>Guidelines for indoor contaminants of concern</header> <subsection id="HD3941BFC81914BB7A286BA71201BAF48" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>List</header> <paragraph id="HA9EB6BB289BE4F8E86925C5F1AB2CE2C" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall establish and maintain a list of indoor contaminants of concern.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H407DCA4548024E7C8127AA8C789447D7" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The list under paragraph (1) may—</text> <subparagraph id="H60CC57629212413CB79E103BAFD239AF" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>include combinations or mixtures of contaminants; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC3E0DAF94DD34D01AC77DA065471FF30" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>refer to such combinations or mixtures by a common name.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H20BC77A787E145EFB476D94E0964A479" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Initial list</header><text>Not later than 5 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall establish the initial list under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3B63A229E6D047F1B001FFB0C9A39CE0" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Minimum contaminants on initial list</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At a minimum, the initial list established under subsection (a) shall include—</text> <paragraph id="H86F54088BC804EC884E3C634690BE8DE" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">particulate matter;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H59E8580DAE8C4AD390CE9A4E91D51937" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>carbon monoxide;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H19D231F17BD74BCFB535904F598F904D" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>nitrogen dioxide;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H00DED5FAF1E54C4D88B24915FED13209" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>ozone;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB8B6595280FC47BF82CB97384883C145" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>formaldehyde; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H16FB9D025FA5416A836FB94AE88EFAA6" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text>radon.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H837E3BF6858F4DA88FFBF2CC340EFB92" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Indoor air quality guidelines</header> <paragraph id="H9C3EFBB6F8404FD7979B93EA8A1EBEE4" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator shall publish science-based, voluntary guidelines for each indoor contaminant of concern listed under subsection (a).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H318A081A1F61439F9D049979B3BA17BD" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Guideline components</header><text>A guideline published under this subsection shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HB1ED54C2FB2940B4AB0A1C06B52D66A2" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include information and a range of recommendations for operation and maintenance of existing buildings, the design and construction of new buildings, building renovation, and such other activities as are necessary to identify, and reduce or prevent exposure to, the indoor contaminant of concern listed under subsection (a);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H941F1EEEF2B0410B8C36BD8A646ECDCC" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be designed to achieve significant risk reduction;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8C2E9963CF1A4BAABB804135AAE448C4" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>be technologically achievable and readily implementable;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCAC0119493C14D498A2A8C368DEDFC19" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>take into consideration safety, energy, and other relevant factors;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDC122C018D434E479C5EF86C9F3304C0" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>include an assessment of effectiveness and cost; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9762915069B44149AE2D9AFF0C56F83D" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text>be based on available research and expertise.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H280984B9FC8A450AA43426561554F520" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Concentration limits</header> <subparagraph id="H325A904BF9B24E4FAEBFD50FF9BE8EA2" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each guideline published under this subsection shall, upon the Administrator making a determination that sufficient scientific evidence exists, include a recommended health-based limit on concentration levels of indoor contaminants of concern.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD0861162A28E4B5790F2A23AD3A8E97C" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Best available science; lowest level of exposure</header><text>A limit under subparagraph (A)—</text> <clause id="HAF2927F374944D57BF0E7645697589F3" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall be based on the best available science; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H57C0694DBD9C4019A4564DC286211C36" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may include a range that includes—</text> <subclause id="H46A98193547443E5B0C2B5BBB8D7A82F" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a concentration level at which a healthy adult should take action to reduce exposure; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HF0B29248B41C470CA07B15E66CF55F09" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a concentration level at which there is evidence of adverse human health effects in susceptible subpopulations, such as infants, children, pregnant women, workers, and the elderly.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF3E1EA3FE3764A8490BFB8189F890A39" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Insufficient evidence</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Administrator determines insufficient evidence exists to set a health-based concentration limit for an indoor contaminant of concern listed under subsection (a), the Administrator shall publish a report not later than 1 year after making such determination, which shall identify—</text> 
<clause id="H0111EDE5AC0242A581BD3F1C29D83E0A" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>studies and other activities to be taken to develop the evidence necessary to set a health-based concentration limit; and</text></clause> <clause id="H5F96062B1B464C95BF5DF4CEC1839CC6" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>resources necessary to carry out activities under clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD9B46B2E241643A1A1BB100AF65C3C19" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Interim guidelines</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">While the Administrator develops sufficient scientific evidence to set a recommended health-based concentration limit for an indoor contaminant of concern under subparagraph (A), the Administrator shall publish interim guidelines, which shall include best practices to reduce exposure to such indoor contaminant of concern.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H4DE2EF50426544C29C0B4B534BA94115" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Review and revision</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not less than every five years, the Administrator shall review and, as necessary, revise—</text> 
<paragraph id="H40D75450CE7E4DF3A896D68483D25E56" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the list of indoor contaminants of concern under subsection (a); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4953611763C745A9BF676D7DBC4A04F4" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the guidelines published under subsection (c).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H14749CADAFAD48F2903F9D82EE74D2D9" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In developing, reviewing, and revising the guidelines published under subsection (c), the Administrator shall consult with representatives from non-profit, professional, private sector, governmental, and labor organizations, and individuals, having demonstrated expertise in indoor air quality, public health, building systems, industrial hygiene, environmental engineering, toxicology, and environmental health and safety.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HBE3098745D964DA58D3AA4C7EF8B808F" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Consistency with indoor air regulations of other Federal agencies</header> <paragraph id="H32508B0D1A1C4BB286CEBC15E8547747" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Labor</header> <subparagraph id="HE240B68505A6479097FFE92BCC8E2550" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Consistency with certain regulations</header><text>The Administrator shall, after consultation with the Secretary of Labor, ensure that the guidelines published under subsection (c) are consistent with any Federal workplace regulations addressing indoor air quality risks.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA69DEB1DE0A14E54906EFFC4B0582BC2" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Additional voluntary actions</header><text>Notwithstanding subparagraph (A), the guidelines published under subsection (c) may recommend additional voluntary actions to protect persons other than workers covered by such guidelines from indoor contaminants of concern listed under subsection (a).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA4331038D7A94F599E9D32ED0B0DBF2C" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Energy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall, after consultation with the Secretary of Energy, ensure that the guidelines published under subsection (c) are consistent with applicable energy conservation and efficiency statutes and regulations administered by the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H35A0D5C7257849B9ABCD13299D432627" commented="no"><enum>5.</enum><header>Indoor air quality index</header> 
<subsection id="HE5D2EC81092449D497DC61CF76D49F88" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator shall seek to enter, not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, into an agreement with the National Academy of Sciences under which the Academy agrees to conduct a study to assess the feasibility of developing a science-based indoor air quality index aimed at informing action for the protection of public health.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HF89A80B4633B4239938D2710D415EB10" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 2 years after entering into an agreement with the Administrator under subsection (a), the Academy shall submit to the Congress and the Administrator a report, which shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H1FD6EFFAD9964E0583111F75D678345A" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>make recommendations to support the development of an indoor air quality index while ensuring that such proposed index—</text> <subparagraph id="H4DEE36B11D254D22B72401B70E61F661" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>communicates to the public in clear and simple terms the level of concern and description of indoor air quality;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8C4E73A39AC74564BEA59C47107E04F3" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>considers health risks for certain sensitive groups of people;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2CB30820219B495E997CDEFF26CF8977" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>addresses the feasibility of assessing indoor air quality through low-cost, real-time sensors and monitoring equipment; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCDE6BEE95CCB4445928795EDEADAFA40" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>allows for updates to account for developments in science and harmonization with indoor air quality guidelines developed under section 4;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6EE082B86A5D440484A88F5D0111A6D2" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>proposes methodologies, inputs, measurements, techniques, and equations to calculate a science-based assessment of indoor air quality; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1EEC9CC55FD54FDA91E11EABC103FFC8" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>identifies limitations and challenges to the development of an indoor air quality index.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H2914FA527650409699E3030EC3628CF0" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated $1,000,000, to remain available until expended, to carry out this section.</text> </subsection></section> 
<section id="H3A81DE31E1A1490F9B271D1D77BC49A6" commented="no"><enum>6.</enum><header>Indoor air quality assistance</header> 
<subsection id="H130E1644618B446085CF48335BF420C7" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator may provide technical assistance and financial assistance, which may include grants, to State, local, and Tribal governments, local educational agencies, housing authorities, nonprofit organizations, labor organizations, and other persons to develop and implement programs to assess and improve indoor air quality.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HCC51BD8DF82C42C9ADCD771BEA352422" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Financial assistance awarded under this section shall be used to support one or more of the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HAB16B12980B348A0B5D1A2364BFC625D" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The development and implementation of educational programs, training and technical assistance programs, assessment and monitoring programs, benchmarking programs, response programs, and other activities designed to reduce human exposure to indoor air contaminants.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4BD280ED3AAE4EDC9C60F9CFBB6AE522" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Mitigation of health risks from indoor air contaminants due to more frequent extreme weather events and other consequences of climate change.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC84A0A3A8507433E9C5283DDD9F12236" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Adoption or adaptation by State, local, and Tribal governments of indoor air quality guidelines published pursuant to section 4, or development and adoption of indoor air quality standards based on such guidelines, including development of assessment and compliance programs needed to implement such standards.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H1801744E8AF54DCCB027979C39BD17C3" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Matching requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal share of the cost of the activities for which financial assistance is awarded under this section shall not exceed 75 percent of the total cost of such activities.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H5F0B675413C44389B466C8218B631AF9" commented="no"><enum>7.</enum><header>Healthy building certifications</header> 
<subsection id="H790F8B87CF104EB1A9F4B4C928B0C8B2" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall provide for one or more types of voluntary certifications of buildings that are built, operated, and maintained to prevent or minimize risks to health from indoor air contaminants in an exemplary manner.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H719A35D1E83642AC8A7418ED40E3FB0C" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For a building to be certified under this section, the owner or operator of the building—</text> 
<paragraph id="H89E2123DC1B5443AB79CB036F9A43A95" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall adhere to applicable guidelines published by the Administrator pursuant to section 4; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H51C7AA54194D46C4BFFA40CCBB1AE2A1" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall develop and maintain an indoor air quality management plan in accordance with best practices developed or approved by the Administrator.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H95A3B8866A9D4AE094BA832AC34B1F32" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consideration</header><text>A certification process under subsection (a) may recognize actions taken by the owners and operators of existing buildings to improve indoor air quality using the most effective source control, air filtration, ventilation, and other best practices, techniques, and products.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HE882E53A16494E599DBD03438E35426D" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Option for third-Party administration</header><text>The Administrator may—</text> 
<paragraph id="HD94BD3886AF84D6EA3C3C00B74C199BD" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">carry out a certification process under subsection (a) directly; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCD00537F6F2A400E828A45FEB189D83F" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recognize one or more certification processes under subsection (a) that are developed and administered through a third party.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H8D7E4A4FDA8A4ACAB2038850644AE961" commented="no"><enum>8.</enum><header>Model provisions for building design, operation, and maintenance</header> 
<subsection id="HD179FF2BC51D499A876DEF900472EE6E" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Model provisions for authorities having jurisdiction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall recommend one or more model provisions for building design, operation, and maintenance for use by States and local jurisdictions in establishing and implementing building codes.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H0A34DB49DFAE44B98970D23FF8AF4CE9" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Components of model provisions</header><text>The model provisions recommended under this section shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="HAF6A90BF32C7472995875B412E19AE15" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establish minimum requirements that address ventilation, filtration, air cleaning, and design, operation, and maintenance of relevant building systems (including equipment, filtration, and controls); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD741BD0F436A452AA569844ABD464401" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>address acceptable indoor air quality and may include control of infectious aerosols and indoor contaminants of concern.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE9C47018231541C6866232D99BB6DB3B" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consideration of model provisions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In accordance with section 12(d) of the National Technology Transfer and Advancement Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/272">15 U.S.C. 272</external-xref> note), the Administrator shall consider technical standards that are developed or adopted by voluntary consensus standards bodies in the development of recommendations under this section.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H6C44FB0ED9EE4D2B9CE4A24D2E14C20A" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In recommending model provisions under this section, the Administrator shall consult with organizations, including non-profit, professional, private sector, governmental, and labor organizations, having demonstrated expertise in building systems and indoor air quality, public health, indoor chemistry, building codes and standards, and above-code building programs.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2309844923B044C09F5DCE5AAFEF9472" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>No conflict with model energy code or standard</header><text>The Administrator shall consult with the Secretary of Energy to ensure that model provisions recommended under this section do not conflict with a model energy code or standard for which the Secretary has made an affirmative determination under section 304 of the Energy Conservation and Production Act, provided that such recommended model provisions may be additive and more stringent than related provisions of the model energy code or standard.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H448874C058D1443A9A31A2E88C6BF711" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Review and revision</header><text>The Administrator shall, not less than once every three years, review and revise (as necessary), in accordance with this section, the recommendations for model provisions developed under this section.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF82F11F0C0224C4197C953094C058728" commented="no"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Cost and benefit</header><text>Not less than 12 months following a recommendation for model provisions under this section, the Administrator shall determine the incremental costs and the 30-year health benefits associated with compliance with the model provisions for new single-family homes, multifamily dwelling units, and a representative set of commercial building prototypes.</text> </subsection></section> <section id="HF7DD8052790547CB8FE1D196391888BD" commented="no"><enum>9.</enum><header>Healthy schools</header> <subsection id="H2952B715C67846C58528392F8C2F2C6A" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Assessment of schools and covered childcare facilities</header> <paragraph id="H864571A9DBC04DD4AED79EFC4F3D80B6" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall conduct a national assessment of indoor air quality in buildings used by local educational agencies and covered childcare facilities.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H256F50815A13454499866239AA118B75" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Assessment contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The national assessment under this section, including updates thereto—</text> <subparagraph id="H6194DD09D9154562817A52B0A45F939F" commented="no"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall include data and metrics, as determined appropriate by the Administrator, to track progress in, and challenges to, improving the indoor air quality in buildings used by local educational agencies and covered child care facilities;</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H04CBD6AF8DDC42B49CE494A23E924151" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall assess whether buildings used by local educational agencies and covered childcare facilities achieve acceptable indoor air quality by meeting minimum ventilation rate requirements and other factors as set forth by widely recognized best practices and standards, as determined appropriate by the Administrator, such as ANSI/ASHRAE Standard 62.1–2022, Ventilation and Acceptable Indoor Air Quality; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC401C263B93A470CB53D644C04EFEF4C" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may be conducted through a survey, an onsite representative sampling of buildings (accounting for geography and building size, type, and age), or other methods or combination of methods determined appropriate by the Administrator to accurately assess the condition of buildings used by local educational agencies and covered childcare facilities throughout the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2A9C3D0F8B9B42E6800C948F32614EF1" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Advisory group</header> 
<subparagraph id="H91D2560030C94F39B00567BBB11583DC" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall establish an advisory group to provide guidance and direction in the development of the initial national assessment under this subsection.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBC1DD466A8BB45BFA2FDEEEFD1E5EFEC" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Members</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The advisory group under subparagraph (A) shall include representatives of—</text> 
<clause id="H7A9E06BE65164C3EABC713D847CB08FC" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>school administrators, teachers, maintenance staff, and other people working in buildings described in paragraph (1), labor organizations, childcare providers, and parents and caregivers; and</text></clause> <clause id="H542F75AB3AB249629AEFD204AE685786" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>other interested parties, including scientific and technical experts familiar with indoor air contaminant exposures, effects, and controls.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9B0FA7D25A00414FAA8A8E13C7D938D5" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Initial assessment; updates</header> 
<subparagraph id="H2040C7AD6FFE457D860231E12954CF30" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Initial assessment</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall conduct the initial national assessment under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD63B6F4C9C514749A5AF879D3F3885F8" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Updates</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not less than five years following the completion of the initial national assessment under subparagraph (A), and each five years thereafter, the Administrator shall carry out an update of the previous national assessment under this subsection, accounting for—</text> 
<clause id="H93F795161F7F4E8680B95BB66F700798" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the number of schools certified pursuant to subsection (c); and</text></clause> <clause id="H8ED2B98EC6AC4F55920E559B9082D894" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>changes in the guidelines, best practices, and other support published by the Administrator to improve indoor air quality.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4DFFA355C3BC4994A30F4594BFD91006" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header><text>Upon completing each national assessment under this subsection, the Administrator shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H98577656C1B04A3AB860D265BA0BB2AE" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>submit to the Congress a report on the results of such assessment; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1E1B78B0C6A047B391AE0B907DA4FC5E" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include in each such report such recommendations as the Administrator determines to be appropriate for activities or programs to reduce and avoid indoor air contaminants in buildings used by local educational agencies and covered childcare facilities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H2398BAA319D84B8791CECEE18402A512" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical assistance and other support</header> <paragraph id="H776BBB8D4FD8425EBEAC116543D6D633" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall develop and promote guidance, best practices, technical assistance, training, outreach, and other support to improve indoor air quality in buildings used by a local educational agency or a covered childcare facility.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H66E407822A114FA080707B528EFA00E0" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall tailor guidance, best practices, technical assistance, training, outreach, and other support under paragraph (1) to the needs of—</text> <subparagraph id="HF3B9C74406F84CCDB28AD0F700477B55" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>students;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAA13362A62514F008BA24A80F7FCEBCA" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>parents and caregivers;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9B12EE3D1F004B3CA417A9035053943F" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">educators;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H741A764C72C240B9814465D58557882E" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>childcare providers;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0CDA0D81EF9F4A9CB7DCE6F579EB0358" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">maintenance staff and other employees responsible for operating and maintaining buildings referred to in paragraph (1);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8D1955EABF4B44E6837121684410C66B" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Indian Tribes; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H84756EB28A2C4791BEA357E247408EA0" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><text>low-income and disadvantaged communities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE28872A4915C4254BCC05E92DE7747F4" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Healthy school certification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall ensure that at least one type of certification carried out or recognized pursuant to section 7 is applicable to buildings used by local educational agencies and covered childcare facilities.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H41659CC5DBF1448B99D7F5FD33C0AB0C" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Interagency coordination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall coordinate with the Secretary of Education, the Secretary of Energy, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Secretary of Labor, and the heads of other relevant Federal agencies, to ensure that any Federal assistance made available to local educational agencies or covered childcare facilities for building construction, alteration, repair, and maintenance is consistent with any guidance and best practices developed by the Administrator under this Act.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H6FB5727C25EA48A8BBEEBD03DB001E55" commented="no"><enum>10.</enum><header>Relation to other law</header> 
<subsection id="H249F62449AA848DE8A0B31AEAE99CB94" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>General authority</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed, interpreted, or applied to preempt, displace, or supplant any other State or Federal law, whether statutory or common, or any local ordinance.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H8161A586A73B4DAD86201F14B99093E3" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Occupational safety and health</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In exercising any authority under this Act, the Administrator shall not, for purposes of section 4(b)(1) of the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/653">29 U.S.C. 653(b)(1)</external-xref>), be considered to be exercising statutory authority to prescribe or enforce standards or regulations affecting occupational safety or health.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H93B3A8E806B04B3EAAF1A5A9C2FD43CA" commented="no"><enum>11.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated $100,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030 to carry out this Act (other than section 5).</text></section> </legis-body></bill>

