<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC97AB88598F14DF3BE9AD98252758EF0" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 118 IH: Calling on Federal law enforcement, led by the Federal Bureau of Investigation, the Department of Homeland Security, and the Federal Aviation Administration, to provide an immediate briefing to the public regarding the recent drone activity in New Jersey and New York.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 118</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250206">February 6, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Calling on Federal law enforcement, led by the Federal Bureau of Investigation, the Department of Homeland Security, and the Federal Aviation Administration, to provide an immediate briefing to the public regarding the recent drone activity in New Jersey and New York.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, in the weeks leading up to Thanksgiving 2024, residents of New Jersey began reporting sightings of unidentified drones flying in the sky;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas residents in at least 10 counties across New Jersey have reported sightings of unmanned aircraft systems (UAS) and other drone-like objects;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas some witness reports suggest that certain drones were as large as small cars or planes;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on December 8, 2024, there were 49 reported drone sightings in a single night in New Jersey;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, as of September 2020, the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) had registered approximately 1.7 million unmanned aircraft systems, more than 70 percent of which are reportedly used for recreational purposes;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas while drones and advancing technology provide significant benefits to businesses and the economy, they may also be exploited for nefarious purposes, including criminal and terrorist activities;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on November 26, 2024, drones flying near a designated landing zone prevented a medical helicopter from responding to a car crash victim in Somerset County, New Jersey;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas drones and other UAS have been spotted near sensitive sites such as Picatinny Arsenal and Round Valley Reservoir, a critical component of New Jersey’s water supply;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on December 13, 2024, Stewart Airport in Orange County, New York—operated by the Port Authority of New York and New Jersey—was forced to close its runways for approximately one hour due to drone activity in the airspace;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas drones and other unidentified aerial objects have also been reported in multiple States in addition to New Jersey and New York;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on January 28, 2025, White House Press Secretary Karoline Leavitt stated that many of these drones were authorized and known to the government; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Press Secretary Leavitt further stated: <quote>After research and study, the drones flying over New Jersey in large numbers were authorized to be flown by the FAA for research and various other reasons.</quote>: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HA5D1D33364F14049B841E0FF145A9AEA"><section id="H8DDA7543DA1E4B1D9F2FEE80ADA54BFD" section-type="undesignated-section" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="H62C2F5994AA04D6D81FA4AA023F2DF38"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognizes the efforts and dedication of State and local law enforcement in addressing public concerns regarding drone activity;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC506D67FB0E1441F830A44F23FD49879"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">calls on the Federal Bureau of Investigation, the Department of Homeland Security, and the Federal Aviation Administration to provide transparency and release information to the public regarding recent drone activity where possible;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H96A71559193E4798A508606FFE47330A"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">urges the Federal Bureau of Investigation, the Department of Homeland Security, and the Federal Aviation Administration to conduct an immediate briefing to inform the public about the current drone situation in New Jersey;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1561B9A257274086B2A88461978F1F45"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">calls on Federal law enforcement agencies, led by the Federal Bureau of Investigation and the Department of Homeland Security, to collaborate with State and local law enforcement in deploying resources to mitigate unauthorized drone activity; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9B5049FCA1264A1BA8FADE4DE29F5D78"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">requests that the Federal Bureau of Investigation, the Department of Homeland Security, and the Federal Aviation Administration assess whether additional security measures are necessary to protect critical infrastructure and public safety from potential drone-related threats.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

