<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2971A74D1BB946A88268B39DF543FEFF" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 194 IH: Expressing support for the designation of March 6, 2025, as “Great Lakes Day”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 194</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250305">March 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000307">Mr. James</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001301">Mr. Bergman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001194">Mr. Moolenaar</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001221">Ms. Scholten</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Natural Resources</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of March 6, 2025, as <quote>Great Lakes Day</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the Great Lakes consist of Lake Michigan, Lake Huron, Lake Erie, Lake Ontario, and Lake Superior, and border the States of Michigan, Wisconsin, Minnesota, Ohio, Indiana, Illinois, Pennsylvania, and New York;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Great Lakes watershed provides habitats for numerous fascinating species of wildlife, including moose, Canada lynx, river otter, bald eagle, herring gull, northern harrier, common loon, Kirtland’s warbler, ring-necked duck, piping plover, whitefish, walleye, yellow perch, muskellunge, and brook trout;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Great Lakes have exceptional surrounding parks, forests, shorelines, and islands, which are a source of enjoyment and wonder, and attract tourism through recreational opportunities, including swimming, hiking, picnics, boating, fishing, hunting, and wildlife watching;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the States bordering the Great Lakes are currently home to 35 million people and have been the ancestral home for Native American Tribes for millennia;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Great Lakes are the largest surface freshwater system on Earth, with over 90 percent of the United States freshwater supply and over 20 percent of the world’s freshwater supply, providing drinking water for over 40 million people;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Great Lakes are vital for the region’s economy, providing transportation for goods and contributing $3.1 trillion in gross domestic product;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Great Lakes region employs over 25 million people and supports $1.3 trillion in wages;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Great Lakes region’s environment and economy depend on the health and well-being of the Great Lakes;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Great Lakes are an essential part of the heritage of the United States; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Lake St. Clair is the <quote>Heart of the Great Lakes</quote> because of its location and size, and its contribution to drinking water, recreation, and commerce: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H5852277475AA4E5FB4A5641393A7D91C"><section id="HA49E52D6EBAB4AE59989BC8859F84B3F" section-type="undesignated-section" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="H9073FF074B08417D8A69B91F751E2E19"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the designation of <quote>Great Lakes Day</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0A65EC4020454E2DADA0E2B72AEC4736"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the contribution of the Great Lakes to the way of life of people in the United States; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H53A261D507FD4BD098D12FC2813E77DC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>commits to ensuring that the Great Lakes are preserved and protected, through programs such as the Great Lakes Restoration Initiative, for this generation and generations to come; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H24881ED7867547A7BB47ABD56745F1B1"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">calls on all Americans and all levels of government in the United States to take additional actions and accelerate existing efforts to preserve and protect Lake St. Clair as a vital natural resource.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

