<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCBD3BB78ABDC404EA4BCF810A9B8B1CB" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4020 IH: To authorize the Secretary of Defense to enter into arrangements with institutions of higher education to provide dual or concurrent enrollment programs for students enrolled in schools operated by the Department of Defense Education Activity, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4020</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250617">June 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="A000055">Mr. Aderholt</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and Workforce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the Secretary of Defense to enter into arrangements with institutions of higher education to provide dual or concurrent enrollment programs for students enrolled in schools operated by the Department of Defense Education Activity, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HAEC871768880423EB82D35327D06DEAD" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H6440F4835B864B3689DB062AD299675F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Authorization of dual or concurrent enrollment programs for students of DODEA schools</header> 
<subsection id="H7BFC8BE4EB594204A6E10165A10C94B7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense, acting through the Director of the Department of Defense Education Activity, may—</text> <paragraph id="H02821D5AA3644250AFC953F06CA4BE50"><enum>(1)</enum><text>enter into arrangements with institutions of higher education to provide students of DODEA schools with access to postsecondary course credit through dual or concurrent enrollment programs; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0EDC8666D3FA47D095F2EC635FD3E977"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide financial assistance to students to cover the costs associated with such programs.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H69195C30E96B40128AE52D90800C2925"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="HF277DE041D38490796B2CE470808C52B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>DODEA school</term> means a school operated by the Department of Defense Education Activity within or outside the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9FAC0086FEC240BEA18D895EA50BB846"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>dual or concurrent enrollment program</term> means a program offered by an arrangement between the Department of Defense Education Activity and an institution of higher education and through which a student enrolled in a DODEA school who has not graduated from high school with a regular high school diploma is able to enroll in one or more postsecondary courses and earn credit that applies—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HEEA9505819E942ED849C57F3779FA5EF"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">toward completion of a postsecondary degree or recognized educational credential as described in the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD99D4EA446CE44DC99180454A84CE695"><enum>(B)</enum><text>toward completion of high school.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H025AD77EEC7041748EE992A9AE04648B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given that term in section 102 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1002">20 U.S.C. 1002</external-xref>).</text> </paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

