<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H78D57E4CC13544C0AF96B66F9C1F1B9F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1390 IH: Ocean Pollution Reduction Act II</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1390</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250214">February 14, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000593">Mr. Levin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="I000056">Mr. Issa</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="J000305">Ms. Jacobs</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To modify permitting requirements with respect to the discharge of any pollutant from the Point Loma Wastewater Treatment Plant in certain circumstances, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H53B0A90CF42F4577B71D328735DC6A87" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HFFDDB1FE44D248CFA9827157DD796B50" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Ocean Pollution Reduction Act II</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H6E59038CFEA341E28262A8900FD735AC"><enum>2.</enum><header>San Diego Point Loma permitting requirements</header> <subsection id="HD3711F819D2F48EFAF09CD59E300669B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any provision of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1251">33 U.S.C. 1251 et seq.</external-xref>), the Administrator may issue a permit under section 402 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1342">33 U.S.C. 1342</external-xref>) for a discharge from the Point Loma Plant into marine waters that requires compliance with the requirements described in subsection (b).</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H15A2EA60E1C64EF7A7A5AEF94798EE85"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conditions</header><text>A permit issued under this section shall require—</text> <paragraph id="HD241A670FF91419383123F603A9A1279"><enum>(1)</enum><text>maintenance of the currently designed deep ocean outfall from the Point Loma Plant with a discharge depth of not less than 300 feet and distance from the shore of not less than 4 miles;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2D1F481AB365442FADA76145B23C03EB"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">as applicable to the term of the permit, discharge of not more than 12,000 metric tons of total suspended solids per year commencing on the date of enactment of this section, not more than 11,500 metric tons of total suspended solids per year commencing on December 31, 2029, and not more than 9,942 metric tons of total suspended solids per year commencing on December 31, 2031;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA0C9D47A3AF84463BFC2255542573BFD"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">discharge of not more than 60 milligrams per liter of total suspended solids, calculated as a 30-day average;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF71841FDC25C4200B88708C771E68FE2"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">removal of not less than 80 percent of total suspended solids on a monthly average and not less than 58 percent of biochemical oxygen demand on an annual average, taking into account removal occurring at all treatment processes for wastewater upstream from and at the Point Loma Plant;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD473ADADFA484C99ABEECCFF7C09ACCC"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">attainment of all other effluent limitations of secondary treatment as determined by the Administrator pursuant to section 304(d)(1) of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1314">33 U.S.C. 1314(d)(1)</external-xref>), other than any requirements otherwise applicable to the discharge of biochemical oxygen demand and total suspended solids;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H421A1A3C7E944CA588B0913CC76787A8" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">compliance with the requirements applicable to Federal issuance of a permit under section 402 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act, including State concurrence consistent with section 401 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1341">33 U.S.C. 1341</external-xref>) and ocean discharge criteria evaluation pursuant to section 403 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1343">33 U.S.C. 1343</external-xref>);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFD974DD5731743EB926FE21BA2095B6B"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">implementation of the pretreatment program requirements of paragraphs (5) and (6) of section 301(h) of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1311">33 U.S.C. 1311(h)</external-xref>) in addition to the requirements of section 402(b)(8) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1342">33 U.S.C. 1342(b)(8)</external-xref>);</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HCF990A29C13E49419FC3B4F785C9E5EA"><enum>(8)</enum><text>that the applicant provide 10 consecutive years of ocean monitoring data and analysis for the period immediately preceding the date of each application for a permit under this section sufficient to demonstrate to the satisfaction of the Administrator that the discharge of pollutants pursuant to a permit issued under this section will meet the requirements of section 301(h)(2) of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1311">33 U.S.C. 1311(h)(2)</external-xref>) and that the applicant has established and will maintain throughout the permit term an ocean monitoring program that meets or exceeds the requirements of section 301(h)(3) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1311">33 U.S.C. 1311(h)(3)</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD3D36FCEEF304C7CAB3AE408B187B989"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to the extent potable reuse is permitted by Federal and State regulatory agencies, that the applicant demonstrate that at least 83,000,000 gallons per day on an annual average of water suitable for potable reuse will be produced by December 31, 2039, taking into account production of water suitable for potable reuse occurring at all treatment processes for wastewater upstream from and at the Point Loma Plant.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HFB4E11B6F41D4F3DB2B0888616A83AE0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Milestones</header><text>The Administrator shall determine development milestones necessary to ensure compliance with this section and include such milestones as conditions in each permit issued under this section before December 31, 2039.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HA6813E1E6DE84A2EBFF6C1A596F420D3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Secondary treatment</header><text>Nothing in this section prevents the applicant from alternatively submitting an application for the Point Loma Plant that complies with secondary treatment pursuant to section 301(b)(1)(B) and section 402 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1311">33 U.S.C. 1311(b)(1)(B)</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1342">33 U.S.C. 1342</external-xref>).</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H341E430738B647A8BE3C015DC22EA591"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HC3CE07510A44422481EC1BE5BA517B76"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8818F094C13448F28803ABB2307F87A6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Biochemical oxygen demand</header><text>The term <term>biochemical oxygen demand</term> means biological oxygen demand, as such term is used in the Federal Water Pollution Control Act. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HED46D632A15742508577C962E8D7D7EE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Point Loma Plant</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Point Loma Plant</term> means the Point Loma Wastewater Treatment Plant owned by the City of San Diego on the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4D09FA438B364E71BE9F4DE3EC86B0F4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means the State of California. </text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

