<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6EBDF4868C864A2A8403E650CDCE81A3" public-private="private" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5293 IH: To authorize the President to award the Medal of Honor to Ret. Col. Robert J. Graham for acts of valor while as a member of the Air Force during the Vietnam War.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">V</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5293</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250910">September 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001327">Mr. Bresnahan</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the President to award the Medal of Honor to Ret. Col. Robert J. Graham for acts of valor while as a member of the Air Force during the Vietnam War.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H2ACA8A6736F144C59A6349192F2128E3" style="OLC"><section id="H176A8153B1CF48F1BB5E756CBB2D1422" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H077DE6D05B184DC888AF231BFFAB5D64"><enum>(1)</enum><text>On May 1, 1966, during Operation Birmingham in the Vietnam War, then-Captain Robert J. Graham launched his F–100 Super Sabre from an alert pad at Bien Hoa Air Base, despite being grounded due to driving monsoon conditions. Alongside his flight leader, he provided close air support to an Army fire base which was under heavy attack by enemy forces.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8DEFAEE26F1A47F087353294A395EDFA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>During the first strike pass, Capt. Graham’s plane sustained severe damage from enemy anti-aircraft artillery (AAA) to the fuel boost pumps. Despite the loss, he skillfully kept his engine running by relying solely on gravity fuel flow, forcing him to fly barely above stall speed in hazardous weather.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H25C27F194C254886BA8F239EF7625DB4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>As Capt. Graham attempted to return to base with his crippled plane, an urgent request came in for support at another army base, which was being attacked by over 4,000 North Vietnamese troops, with the enemy about to breach the concertina wire perimeter.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC2B42D2D0EE34D3A95E83D4B0F186CDC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Despite his battle-damaged plane and his own survival highly unlikely, Captain Graham carried on and executed strikes against enemy forces under the guns of friendly Army defenders, a feat never attempted in combat.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB73468607EAD428497D825F27E41F101"><enum>(5)</enum><text>With complete disregard for his own safety, Capt. Graham made more than 15 passes, destroying all eight North Vietnamese AAA gun positions, neutralizing over 1,500 enemy troops, and saving hundreds of American lives.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDF4FE09C40684BA89FAAC032DA41165F"><enum>(6)</enum><text>His actions turned the tide of the battle and remain a testament to the highest ideals of service and sacrifice.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6CD30DD3034B4C6F810801185C3CA56E"><enum>(7)</enum><text>For his actions in Operation Birmingham on May 1, 1966, Capt. Graham was awarded the Silver Star.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1D154DBDA33843B59A2A30C887556D96"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Ret. Col. Graham served four tours in Vietnam and flew more than 500 combat missions. He enlisted in the United States Air Force in 1953 and after completing basic training and flight school, he continued to serve 26 years as a fighter pilot.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H172538E6E4A64AE3B841A4C37EC259D2"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Ret. Col. Robert J. Graham deserves the Congressional Medal of Honor for his heroic actions on May 1, 1966, going above and beyond the call of duty, where his undaunted courage in the face of danger saved the lives of hundreds of his fellow Americans.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HABDF4EA4B87F47A18CC9E56DD685C727"><enum>2.</enum><header>Authorization for award of medal of honor to Ret. Col. Robert J. Graham for acts of valor during the Vietnam War</header><subsection id="HF3650CD8ABC0408E85438EC6A2BCE1AC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Waiver of time limitations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding the time limitations specified in section 8298 of title 10, United States Code, or any other time limitation with respect to the awarding of certain medals to persons who served in the Armed Forces, the President may award the Medal of Honor under section 8291 of such title to Robert J. Graham for the acts of valor described in subsection (b).</text></subsection><subsection id="H789048402E0949A3BF31B4A08C33A012"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Acts of valor described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The acts of valor described in this subsection are the actions of Robert J. Graham, as a captain in the Air Force, on May 1, 1966.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

