<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7DCF6EE77FF5410ABE944D45FD9F4F14" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3461 IH: Confronting CCP Human Rights Abusers Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3461</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250515">May 15, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="O000175">Mr. Ogles</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001194">Mr. Moolenaar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001196">Ms. Stefanik</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001212">Mr. Moore of Alabama</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the inclusion of the Ministry of Public Security’s Institute of Forensic Science of China on the entity list maintained by the Bureau of Industry and Security of the Department of Commerce, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H4BE1BFE7194E484B8B1AD19DEDF1BFB0" style="OLC"><section id="H5C9D7DB0DDE947F9875624A03A28E1F5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Confronting CCP Human Rights Abusers Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HF4B8653C68E9411BB3AD18542EADEBC2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Inclusion of Ministry of Public Security’s Institute of Forensic Science of China on entity list</header><subsection id="H70CC018A75A94E5F9D1C7BB2BDB69B15"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Under Secretary of Commerce for Industry and Security shall include on the entity list the Ministry of Public Security’s Institute of Forensic Science of China, including the aliases—</text><paragraph id="H587F4529CB6C4398819F49736B3592CD"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Forensic Identification Center of the Ministry of Public Security of the People’s Republic of China; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3DB0982C63B74C09B5B813F20BD80D54"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Material Identification Center of the Ministry of Public Security of the People’s Republic of China.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8F276F6CFA904CEB862736675CA5A0A2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President, acting through the Secretary of Commerce, may waive the application of subsection (a) if, not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President submits to the<committee-name committee-id="HIF00"> Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name> of the House of Representatives and the<committee-name committee-id=""> Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name> of the Senate a certification that the Ministry of Public Security’s Institute of Forensic Science of China is not—</text><paragraph id="H58DD6C12842E4F2B939CE2B4A19B2AD1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>engaging in an activity contrary to the foreign policy interests of the United States; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE3D0C6AF926042E0B9F66510A92E2902"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">implicated in or contributing to abuse or a violation of human rights with respect to the campaign of the People’s Republic of China of repression, mass arbitrary detention, forced labor, and high-technology surveillance against Uyghurs, Kazakhs, and other members of Muslim minority groups in the Xinjiang Uyghur Autonomous Region.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD6A663809EA14FF2A9A9AB5DE2FBB440"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Entity list defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>entity list</term> means the list maintained by the Bureau of Industry and Security of the Department of Commerce and set forth in Supplement No. 4 to part 744 of the Export Administration Regulations, or successor regulations.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

