<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MIR25102-HFV-GG-273"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S861 IS: Disaster Assistance Simplification Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 861</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250305">March 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S380">Mr. Peters</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S378">Mr. Lankford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S348">Mr. Paul</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S384">Mr. Tillis</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To streamline the sharing of information among Federal disaster assistance agencies, to expedite the delivery of life-saving assistance to disaster survivors, to speed the recovery of communities from disasters, to protect the security and privacy of information provided by disaster survivors, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="idaa7b553d-cb9a-4f9e-8221-c434fbbb25b4" changed="not-changed"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Disaster Assistance Simplification Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id972ec777-53da-416a-8274-61297e9b1cfa" changed="not-changed"><enum>2.</enum><header>Establishment of a unified disaster assistance intake process and system</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5121">42 U.S.C. 5121 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6a20d53f-18ee-4d93-a3b8-478fdbb2dc69" changed="not-changed"><section id="id60d799a4-f2c6-4215-a09a-8fbcb6e66c9f" changed="not-changed"><enum>707.</enum><header>Establishment of a unified disaster assistance intake process and system</header><subsection id="id0fe4b70b-431f-4524-a3f0-98df55d96938" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="idbebaf788-36db-421e-b8c7-7ae2e74bb0e2" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide83733b5-ecdb-4d1f-855e-99e94be2d628" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applicant</header><text>The term <term>applicant</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="idd950ec5b-1983-4d85-aab9-e04332c5ce1b" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an individual, business, or organization that applies for disaster assistance from a disaster assistance program; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id85b2dd31-fa13-4cd4-a160-5d32051ac4e8" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an individual, business, or organization on behalf of which an individual described in subparagraph (A) applies for disaster assistance from a disaster assistance program; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph changed="not-changed" id="id83004D48F4014A249EFE80DDBF31528F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an individual, business, or organization that seeks assistance as a beneficiary of a State, local government, or Indian tribal government that received assistance under a disaster assistance program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idcf366a9c-931c-4843-8159-176cd8c9d732" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Disaster assistance agency</header><text>The term <term>disaster assistance agency</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="id63bd22a8-050f-46bf-8d3a-9134b3e69dfb" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Federal Emergency Management Agency; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id800a4895-fe57-48e6-8a62-de8ea01bee12" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any Federal agency that provides disaster assistance to individuals, businesses, organizations, States, local governments, Indian tribal governments, communities, or organizations that the Administrator certifies as a disaster assistance agency in accordance with subsection (f) to carry out the purposes of a disaster assistance program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id518b15b4-80f8-4de2-8e34-7223c0028d75" changed="not-changed"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Disaster assistance information</header><text>The term <term>disaster assistance information</term> includes any personal, biographical, demographic, geographical, financial, application decision, or other information that a disaster assistance agency, or a recipient of a Federal block grant from a disaster assistance agency, is authorized to collect, maintain, disclose, or use to—</text><subparagraph id="id2f3742fa-0c5c-4f01-8830-9316544d7b89" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>process an application for disaster assistance from a disaster assistance program; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idde272d09-f4c2-4f5c-b439-602f4fa97c29" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>otherwise carry out the purpose of a disaster assistance program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id7553bd10-cf8f-4449-ae35-84333279cb67" changed="not-changed"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Disaster assistance program</header><text>The term <term>disaster assistance program</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="idaab5bc52-ca66-4908-8724-c81c53ea48fa" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a program that provides disaster assistance to individuals and households under title IV or V in accordance with sections 408 and 502; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id23a23691-86ed-4c56-a641-fa0c50cb346c" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other assistance program authorized by a Federal statute or funded with Federal appropriations under which a disaster assistance agency awards or distributes disaster assistance to an individual, household, or organization, or provides a Federal block grant for these purposes, that arises from a major disaster or emergency declared under section 401 or 501, respectively, including—</text><clause id="idfc853274-e20c-4163-9a00-8b2fd1c4f999" changed="not-changed"><enum>(i)</enum><text>disaster assistance;</text></clause><clause id="id593f90b2-b0a1-453b-98db-c489a20d38e3" changed="not-changed"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>long-term disaster recovery assistance;</text></clause><clause id="id991ae465-01b0-4214-9739-8ebbc4176436" changed="not-changed"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the post-disaster restoration of infrastructure and housing;</text></clause><clause id="id3066dc06-767f-482f-9417-9ecb7f27ecea" changed="not-changed"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>post-disaster economic revitalization;</text></clause><clause id="idee36b39b-1803-4e16-8878-9794d63ee2b8" changed="not-changed"><enum>(v)</enum><text>a loan authorized under section 7(b) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/636">15 U.S.C. 636(b)</external-xref>); and</text></clause><clause id="idb1ac8368-6e3e-4cd6-b267-67df7a66c4a9" changed="not-changed"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>food benefit allotments under section 412 of this Act and section 5(h) of the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2014">7 U.S.C. 2014(h)</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide0882fa4-afd0-4a00-beb4-ba273852c5c9" changed="not-changed"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Record</header><text>The term <term>record</term> has the meaning given the term in section 552a of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id5480f001-effe-400d-9be2-3f8ec301729c" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Unified disaster assistance intake process and system</header><paragraph id="id58e4272a-bdc4-4260-a4f2-a896a2c3dc12" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 360 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Disaster Assistance Simplification Act</short-title>, the Administrator shall, in consultation with appropriate Federal, State, local, and Indian tribal governments and entities, develop and establish a unified intake process and system for applicants for disaster assistance provided by a disaster assistance agency to—</text><subparagraph id="idfb84ab33-c51b-4a15-afd1-6d9641e441d2" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>facilitate a consolidated application for any form of disaster assistance provided by a disaster assistance agency when appropriate to support the nature and purposes of the assistance;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5101dca5-ac2a-4cf7-a277-89cecb95a6a4" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>carry out the purposes of disaster assistance programs swiftly, efficiently, fairly, and in accordance with applicable laws and privacy and data protections; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9a17b733-dc16-4205-afdb-838a5c30c854" changed="not-changed"><enum>(C)</enum><text>support the detection, prevention, and investigation of waste, fraud, abuse, or discrimination in the administration of disaster assistance programs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idf9a15dd6-ae38-41c5-b08b-fe8867c30de6" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Capabilities of the consolidated application system</header><text>The unified intake process and system established under paragraph (1) shall—</text><subparagraph id="id42ae0dad-439c-42a9-92e7-2c791f8f8bcf" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>accept applications for disaster assistance programs;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="not-changed" id="id5c0c8e43d15f44f994717746441d7124"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">allow for applicants to receive status updates on applications for disaster assistance programs;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id78bb1491-0070-4e97-b7a3-33be2c78f793" changed="not-changed"><enum>(C)</enum><text>allow for applicants to update disaster assistance information throughout the recovery journeys of those applicants;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbc960d2d-e99d-47bd-ba6a-51b6eea180fa" changed="not-changed"><enum>(D)</enum><text>allow for the distribution of information on additional recovery resources to disaster survivors that may be available in a disaster-stricken jurisdiction, in coordination with appropriate Federal, State, local, and Tribal partners;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8bbedd49-f497-411e-b974-1c281b943186" changed="not-changed"><enum>(E)</enum><text>provide disaster survivors with information and documentation on the applications of those disaster survivors for a disaster assistance program; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph changed="not-changed" id="id46B3740B81464417A90AD4C2B68898D3"><enum>(F)</enum><text>allow for the distribution of application data to support faster and more effective distribution of Federal disaster assistance, including block grant assistance, for disaster recovery; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="not-changed" id="id24b0ed9c871740e3be707f443102447b"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">allow for disaster assistance agencies to communicate directly with disaster survivors; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id66594c48-244a-445b-beec-cdf83ef5b336" changed="not-changed"><enum>(H)</enum><text>contain other capabilities determined necessary by the heads of disaster assistance agencies. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="not-changed" id="ided131105f5914e50ba816c0870c3713b"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Updates</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date on which the Administrator receives a request from a disaster assistance agency to update questions in the consolidated application described in paragraph (1) needed to administer the disaster assistance programs of the disaster assistance agency, the Administrator shall make those updates.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4b7aebfd-3d83-432f-8f3c-d6ab31d78290" changed="not-changed"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorities of Administrator</header><text>The Administrator may—</text><paragraph id="id1c267d7b-e6af-4737-9a8e-7e1f3fdaf9f3" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>collect, maintain, disclose, and use disaster assistance information, including such information received from any disaster assistance agency, with any other disaster assistance agency for purposes of subsection (b)(1); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfb6abf21-cd34-4794-a5ee-4475694a7d03" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>subject to subsection (d), authorize the collection, maintenance, disclosure, and use of disaster assistance information collected on or after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Disaster Assistance Simplification Act</short-title> by publishing a notice on a public website that—</text><subparagraph id="id8c56c286-2866-4cb5-86ce-e04c0da5bf9e" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>includes a detailed description of—</text><clause id="idbb76280a-1d6d-4e6b-8437-12165b3e8be5" changed="not-changed"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the specific disaster assistance information authorized to be collected, maintained, disclosed, and used;</text></clause><clause id="idd49b0076-2186-4847-843b-e576912fec73" changed="not-changed"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>why the collection, maintenance, disclosure, or use of the disaster assistance information is necessary to carry out the purpose of a disaster assistance program;</text></clause><clause id="id2333bed7-4390-4a39-82db-3d7bfa2ef4fd" changed="not-changed"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>how the collection, maintenance, disclosure, and use of disaster assistance information incorporates fair information practices; and</text></clause><clause id="idaa406857-446b-4e42-ac31-4e5a53198f0e" changed="not-changed"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the disaster assistance agencies that will be granted access to the disaster assistance information to carry out the purpose of any disaster assistance program; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id04a8fe91-9de6-441e-a80b-467eb191115d" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provides that the submission of an application through a unified disaster application constitutes prior written consent to disclose disaster assistance information to disaster assistance agencies for the purpose of section 552a(b) of title 5, United States Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idd148e2ff-adbe-48aa-8eaa-038c87336c8b" changed="not-changed"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Collection and sharing of records and information</header><paragraph id="id052134c0-8789-4b75-aaf9-4fd743cc2170" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Effect of publication of notice on public website</header><text>The publication of a notice by the Administrator on a public website of a revision to the system of records of the unified intake process and system established under subsection (b)(1) prior to any new collection, maintenance, disclosure, or use of records to carry out the purposes of a disaster assistance program with respect to a major disaster or emergency declared by the President under section 401 or 501, respectively, of this Act shall be deemed to satisfy the notice and publication requirements of section 552a(e)(4) of title 5, United States Code, for the entire period of performance for any assistance provided under a disaster assistance program. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4eff3d11-880f-46ec-9cbb-f962d3a87f91" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Paperwork Reduction Act waiver</header><subparagraph id="id24d49d10-c316-429a-b799-9bd07c792b02" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Upon the declaration of a major disaster or emergency pursuant to section 401 or 501, respectively, of this Act, the Administrator may waive the requirements of subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/44/35">chapter 35</external-xref> of title 44, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Paperwork Reduction Act</quote>), with respect to the voluntary collection of information specific to the declared major disaster or emergency needed to carry out the purposes of a disaster assistance program.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc22e5674-e98b-481a-b23d-a606e9f3f8ef" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>A waiver described in subparagraph (A) shall be in effect for the entire period of performance for any assistance provided under a disaster assistance program with respect to a declared major disaster or emergency.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfc8940b7-e12b-4cc8-a580-c35c989ff8a7" changed="not-changed"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Transparency</header><text>If the Administrator waives the requirements described in subparagraph (A), the Administrator shall—</text><clause id="id337e8180-f912-4507-81af-77b668eb6444" changed="not-changed"><enum>(i)</enum><text>promptly post on a public website—</text><subclause id="idbdb02f27-6922-4a91-a539-480763a11fdb" changed="not-changed"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a brief justification for the waiver; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id0814968c-ee88-48a2-a7d2-570a26f6756c" changed="not-changed"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the agencies and offices to which the waiver shall apply;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id7adfd6de-e030-4748-b755-f1d8c9b5f19b" changed="not-changed"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>update the information posted under clause (i), as applicable; and</text></clause><clause changed="not-changed" id="idF799318A14DA48BA9A3CFDB6ECEF9DCD"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>comply with the requirements of subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/44/35">chapter 35</external-xref> of title 44, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Paperwork Reduction Act</quote>) upon the expiration of the period of performance of any assistance provided under a disaster assistance program if the collection of information may be utilized for the purposes of supporting the disaster assistance program in future major disaster or emergency declarations.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idecc5843a-8deb-48db-b85a-2fd17d46f528" changed="not-changed"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Effectiveness of waiver</header><text>Any waiver under subparagraph (A) shall take effect on the date on which the Administrator posts information on the internet website as provided for under subparagraph (C).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id7d48405b-2556-4349-a194-26e0a927c05b" changed="not-changed"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Data security</header><text>The Administrator shall facilitate the collection of disaster assistance information into a unified application only after—</text><paragraph id="id43d726bf-39a0-4d0c-9c20-27022b5697e7" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Administrator certifies that the unified application substantially complies with the data security standards established pursuant to subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/44/35">chapter 35</external-xref> of title 44, United States Code, and any other applicable Federal information security policy; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6274ebbe-b64e-410e-b491-5dab57d9b756" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Secretary of Homeland Security publishes a privacy impact assessment for the unified application that is similar to the privacy assessment conducted under section 208(b)(1)(B) of the E-Government Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/44/3501">44 U.S.C. 3501</external-xref> note); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida2b3234d-ebaa-4687-bd27-97aee210681f" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Administrator, in consultation with disaster assistance agencies, publishes standard rules of behavior for disaster assistance agencies and personnel granted access to disaster assistance information to protect such information from improper disclosure.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id939295c2-74e0-4429-b273-18485eae61fb" changed="not-changed"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Certification of disaster assistance agencies</header><paragraph id="id7dc3cf91-78c2-43e3-afe0-d5ae8a705cef" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator may certify a Federal agency as a disaster assistance agency after posting an agreement between the Administrator and the Federal agency on a public website that contains the detailed terms of the agreement.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id49af74af-26b5-423a-8c38-5632210d7e35" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents of agreement</header><text>An agreement between the Administrator and a Federal agency described in paragraph (1) shall state that the Federal Emergency Management Agency and the Federal agency will—</text><subparagraph id="id19c2ec55-60d5-4d25-afe9-668bec77d0a6" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>collect, disclose, maintain, and use disaster assistance information in accordance with—</text><clause id="idE0F563E69C1D4A09A57C8C20756EC85A" changed="not-changed"><enum>(i)</enum><text>this section; and</text></clause><clause id="idE74A3B66D91F42359AC1BAB2AB279BAE" changed="not-changed"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>subject to subsection (i)(2), any existing policies of the Federal Emergency Management Agency and the Federal agency for information protection and use;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6c5a7e9f-8a52-4ea8-83a6-c60e365766f4" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>train any personnel granted access to disaster assistance information on the rules of behavior established by the Administrator under subsection (e)(3);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idda2a478a-ff53-4d95-92d7-1754a141f848" changed="not-changed"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in the event of any unauthorized disclosure of disaster assistance information—</text><clause id="id4f28ac22-4baf-452c-b354-bce88764c8fa" changed="not-changed"><enum>(i)</enum><text>not later than 24 hours after discovering the unauthorized disclosure—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="not-changed" id="id1c17f28bcca64d01a2891c51bfe88287"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of an unauthorized disclosure by the Federal agency, notify the Administrator of the disclosure; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="not-changed" id="id3b993be33e2e45018b9e42f2f8debf77"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in the case of an unauthorized disclosure by the Federal Emergency Management Agency, notify disaster assistance agencies of the disclosure;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id85701645-d0c5-44a2-9b26-108c24222dbf" changed="not-changed"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>cooperate fully with the Administrator and disaster assistance agencies in the investigation and remediation of the disclosure; and</text></clause><clause id="id6ecc0d4a-93af-4ea8-b62b-b9e0952175ba" changed="not-changed"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>cooperate fully in the prosecution of a person responsible for the disclosure; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6ed16d6a-7623-47ce-8677-9c1608628773" changed="not-changed"><enum>(D)</enum><text>assume responsibility for any compensation, civil liability, or other remediation measure awarded by a judgment of a court or agreed upon as a compromise of any potential claim by or on behalf of an applicant, including by obtaining credit monitoring and remediation services, for an improper disclosure of disaster assistance information that is—</text><clause id="id5defb16a-5762-498e-a8c3-b9b658af2803" changed="not-changed"><enum>(i)</enum><text>caused, directly or indirectly, by the acts or omissions of an officer, employee, or contractor of the Federal agency; or</text></clause><clause id="idd281563f-94b9-46be-947f-fa5bf061a437" changed="not-changed"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>from any electronic system of records that was created or maintained by the Federal agency pursuant to section 552a(e) of title 5, United States Code.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="not-changed" id="idd6edfdf4154549c58258d3bdda94060a"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Reports</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="not-changed" id="ida2f1f8e0193c4bed9152c0a00078c8fb"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">FEMA</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section, and every year thereafter for 2 years, the Administrator, in coordination with the heads of disaster assistance agencies, shall submit to Congress a report on the implementation of this section, including—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="not-changed" id="idf754a75146e24f6f84460c85628a275c"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how disaster assistance agencies are working together to implement the requirements under this section;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="not-changed" id="idbce6dec157504c36b80ecf206ca3de39"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the effect of this section on disaster survivor burden and the speed and efficiency of delivering disaster assistance; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="not-changed" id="idf56d9c73af094d648ce41c0ee65b7917"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a description of any other challenges that require further legislative action.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="not-changed" id="idf0834bf8f9564933b0a4afcc9c369255"><enum>(2)</enum><header>GAO</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this section, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report on how the implementation of this section has affected the disaster survivor experience, and any recommendations for improvements to the requirements under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="not-changed" id="id4578ebb1c3e847e0aa821557e51b5f83"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Briefings</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this section, and again not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this section, the Administrator shall brief Congress on—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="not-changed" id="idfa751077799a4a76bc9974a1090228ab"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the status of the implementation of the requirements under this section; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="not-changed" id="idbd45b20b522b44d4866fd84d8abfb739"><enum>(2)</enum><text>how disaster assistance agencies are working together to implement the requirements under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0bc03045-77f9-4c47-8f8a-c803c9489646" changed="not-changed"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Rules of construction</header><paragraph id="id0fe519f5-e52a-472c-b7df-dfe190268cd2" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Inapplicability of matching program provisions</header><text>The disclosure and use of disaster assistance information subject to the requirements of section 552a of title 5, United States Code, among disaster assistance agencies or with State, local, or Tribal governments carrying out disaster assistance programs shall not—</text><subparagraph id="id688db2c9-441e-4438-8910-386207f787c9" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be construed as a matching program for the purpose of section 552a(a)(8) of title 5, United States Code; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2681ba86-5d7b-4484-902a-9e6a614a7c14" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>be subject to subsection (e)(12), (o), (p)(1)(A)(ii), (q), (r), or (u) of section 552a of title 5, United States Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9e699987-5fec-43b5-8c89-b2daa001e5d1" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authorities in other laws</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to affect the authority of an entity to share disaster assistance information regarding programs funded or facilitated by the entity in accordance with any other law or agency policy.</text></paragraph><paragraph changed="not-changed" id="idE49D76F150B24864A16FEE5C33E9FCD0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Applying to multiple programs</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to require an applicant to apply to more than 1 disaster assistance program.</text></paragraph><paragraph changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idda1ff3ff27c14d20ad13ae5a8c1115c6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Program authorization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall be construed to authorize a program that is not authorized by law as of the date of enactment of this section.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

