<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA59C56FE74CA415CAC93E9D8C9AABF48" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4567 IH: Supporting Military Voters Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4567</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250721">July 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000597">Ms. Lee of Florida</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="N000191">Mr. Neguse</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B000740">Mrs. Bice</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Comptroller General of the United States to conduct a study of the effectiveness of the Federal Government in carrying out its responsibilities under the Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act to promote access to voting for absent uniformed services voters and an analysis of means for improving access to voter registration information and assistance for members of the Armed Forces and their family members, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H85688702474040288372C1442D5AEF5A" style="OLC"><section id="HB452C620DEA847ADBFEDC6638AF253A4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Supporting Military Voters Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HF80344450D524AC88F009449AE590BB3" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Government Accountability Office report on implementation of Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act and improving access to voter registration information and assistance for absent uniformed services voters</header><subsection id="HABC79B0DB10D47F3B781044248B08F51"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct—</text><paragraph id="H3A41E815734741359542BD7A5F761D51"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an analysis of the effectiveness of the Federal Government in carrying out its responsibilities under the Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/20301">52 U.S.C. 20301 et seq.</external-xref>) to promote access to voting for absent uniformed services voters; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H85851B1AB9F64255A382D71C27AA1A81"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a study on means for improving access to voter registration information and assistance for members of the Armed Forces and their family members.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD9D6BA81F2DF4C94A11749E5C022526E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><paragraph id="H85BF2C057C314192B8C0DF79C5171913"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Analysis</header><text>The analysis required by subsection (a)(1) shall include analysis of the following:</text><subparagraph id="H53EF8F912DB141008EDA268B7C8009E1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Data and information pertaining to the transmission of ballots to absent uniformed services voters.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD894023AA86E49CF9145B2B0412B2DE7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Data and information pertaining to the methods of transmission of voted ballots from absent uniformed services voters, including the efficacy and security of such methods.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H46BD20F5A9BC49E085A4048B1D426FD2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Data and information pertaining to the treatment by election officials of voted ballots transmitted by absent uniformed services voters, including—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H96FA143BCEBC48FCA86FEBBD49C5CBC8"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the rate at which such ballots are counted in elections;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1197838CAE694E278172701A3420024D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the rate at which such ballots are rejected in elections; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2B140EDA5ACE495399B3450C97D5BC7A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the reasons for such rejections.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2C62E7A7BAD24EB78B99DC8C25FD81BC"><enum>(D)</enum><text>An analysis of the effectiveness of the assistance provided to absent uniformed services voters by Voting Assistance Officers of the Federal Voting Assistance Program of the Department of Defense.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H21B56EED5CEF4FDC98515767C33D2C18"><enum>(E)</enum><text>A review of the extent of coordination between Voting Assistance Officers and State and local election officials.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2CFCF0BC71BE45F89E9C2DFE76B6ADE1"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Information regarding such other issues relating to the ability of absent uniformed services voters to register to vote, vote, and have their ballots counted in elections for Federal office.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H26129A9B63FB461B887ED605D8DD29EC"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Data and information pertaining to—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H32ED9825DA0D42B2992D00C90BA1CCAB"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the awareness of members of the Armed Forces and their family members of the requirement under section 1566a of title 10, United States Code, that the Secretaries of the military departments provide voter registration information and assistance; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1EDF9324DC5F4EDD9656F7AFCBFCD873"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether members of the Armed Forces and their family members received such information and assistance at the times required by subsection (c) of that section.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2894F05CC9D3414095BF4C4797AFE9AD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Study</header><text>The study required by subsection (a)(2) shall include the following:</text><subparagraph id="HE4FB297192FA41579DD7D599293CBFE6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An assessment of potential actions to be undertaken by the Secretary of each military department to increase access to voter registration information and assistance for members of the Armed Forces and their family members.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6A884039E1BD4D33911F5A71A5760321"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An estimate of the costs and requirements to fully meet the needs of members of the Armed Forces for access to voter registration information and assistance.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5934BD4FA83948F08662F02079FD3758"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Methods</header><text>In conducting the analysis and study required by subsection (a), the Comptroller General shall, in cooperation and consultation with the Secretaries of the military departments—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H32AE999A93944D9786DFB2163D9D0C09"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">use existing information from available government and other public sources; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3248DEB2D2F84C8FAD3D5BC96905A201"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">acquire, through the Comptroller General’s own investigations, interviews, and analysis, such other information as the Comptroller General requires to conduct the analysis and study.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H40584D80CB4E4C32B78168FECFCCA46E" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report required</header><text>Not later than September 30, 2027, the Comptroller General shall submit to the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate and the Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives a report on the analysis and study required by subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="HE442B7A101ED45DDB70C6C3F73CDA435"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H99F50F5782AF4BC4B99164670299B212"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Absent uniformed services voter</header><text>The term <term>absent uniformed services voter</term> has the meaning given that term in section 107 of the Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/20310">52 U.S.C. 20310</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H80977A91276944468D241445A7CCFB0E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Family member</header><text>The term <term>family member</term>, with respect to a member of the Armed Forces, means a spouse and other dependent (as defined in section 1072 of title 10, United States Code) of the member.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

