<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H87EC112942884724A95F146522D5C0D7" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1746 IH: Standardizing Accreditation information for Veteran Ease Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1746</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250227">February 27, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001211">Mr. Stanton</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="H001098">Mr. Hamadeh of Arizona</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to make certain improvements to the laws relating to the recognition of agents, attorneys, organizations and their representatives, and other individuals for the purposes of assisting in the preparation, presentation, and prosecution of claims for benefits under the laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H55899E868CD741FBB3EE977CD6B4F14A" style="OLC"><section id="HF13CA03A61544605A210AF4E7B4F3E4E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Standardizing Accreditation information for Veteran Ease Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SAVE Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H966C02902BFD42028386263C7947EA73"><enum>2.</enum><header>Annual report</header><subsection id="H162C606341F34F259D2645AF204ED899"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/59">Chapter 59</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new sections:</text><quoted-block id="HE6E2563FAB5A46D8ABD1330E82515218" style="USC"><section id="HAB4077B51369423999E276B4475C7A1E"><enum>5907.</enum><header>Annual submission of information on recognition of agents, attorneys, organizations and their representatives, and other individuals</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary shall include in the annual report required to be submitted to Congress under section 529 of this title information on agents, attorneys, organizations and their representatives, and any other individuals recognized under this chapter. Such information shall include, for the year covered by the report, the following:</text><paragraph id="H72B4809768D84FED9D15A535E7FB8B68"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A description of the type and frequency of training that is required to be recognized, or to continue to be recognized, under this chapter and of any review or audit conducted of such training.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDD79D93F2B514C6595A006CBC5BE04E9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A description of the type of information the Secretary collects from individuals who request to be recognized, or to continue to be recognized, under this chapter.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6A1DBC5366D54DD3BFC6245032161614"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A description of the method the Secretary uses to gather personal and qualifying information from individuals and organizations recognized or seeking recognition under this chapter.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H56AF0C72D8B541A395DC6A84FBAD0D48"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An identification of the frequency with which the Secretary receives updated personal and qualifying information from individuals and organizations recognized under this chapter.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB5E3A0E81BD54A72BD6AC879F302B99D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A description of the method the Secretary uses to verify personal and qualifying information received from individuals and organizations recognized or seeking recognition under this chapter.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6CEB2A7ADB754092A434E79FB9BBC509"><enum>(6)</enum><text>An identification of the frequency with which individuals and organizations recognized under this chapter are required to comply with ongoing reporting requirements.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H20E227184119493A8DB09E16AD5BDF79"><enum>(7)</enum><text>An identification of the number of Department employees responsible for the administration of this chapter.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H836FBB9FD4564453900C915009386A7E"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An identification of the frequency with which the VA Accreditation Search database, or any successor to such database, is—</text><subparagraph id="H73276C3E340C45DFADDA81518C697399"><enum>(A)</enum><text>updated; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC2F1943D910544BFA9DF6AD4463DF7E8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>checked for accuracy, including with respect to the accuracy of contact information and the removal of individuals and organizations no longer recognized to assist veterans in the preparation, presentation, or prosecution of claims under laws administered by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7E88E1B0063B474B929B771B86082D1D"><enum>(9)</enum><text>A description of the steps the Secretary has taken to ensure such database is updated.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7F83411FED3742E1992694CE9583AFBB"><enum>(10)</enum><text>An identification of any additional resources the Department may need to ensure that—</text><subparagraph id="H0BF87EEE0AA94E6293F4EECEADC2E95D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any published information regarding individuals and organizations recognized under this chapter is accurate and up-to date; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H59AF00C477364CD584D2616D5699FAE3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>individuals who are recognized under this chapter are of good moral character and in good repute, are qualified to render claimants valuable service, and are otherwise competent to assist claimants in presenting claims under laws administered by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9AD1777EFBBB4F249FDED51BAC3D6BCB"><enum>(11)</enum><text>An identification of the costs of processing applications for recognition under this chapter.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H17E359EB5AA842999CF9E104A4DD265F"><enum>(12)</enum><text>A description of the timeline for processing applications for recognition under this chapter.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0A528C63F4E94B348C70000E9F486C13"><enum>(13)</enum><text>An identification of how frequently individuals seeking recognition under this chapter are denied such recognition and for what reasons.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAFF131920C9049A7996B161909583198"><enum>(14)</enum><text>An identification of how frequently recognition is rescinded from individuals recognized under this chapter and for what reasons.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HBAF5D895A0384A5F9A871B176642B70F"><enum>5908.</enum><header>Certification mark for identification of recognized individuals</header><subsection id="H4B16681902E84D9E9AA8C15551F3A895"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall establish and maintain a certification mark, which may be used to identify individuals who are recognized under this chapter for the purposes of assisting in the preparation, presentation, and prosecution of claims for benefits under the laws administered by the Secretary. Such certification mark shall be registered with the United States Patent and Trademark Office.</text></subsection><subsection id="H8B0FDC831C234AA78305668DBF6CF9AF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Civil penalty for violation</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H5FDC8E529EEF4010B9C082A6A000E92C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A person who displays or otherwise uses the certification mark established under subsection (a) for the fraudulent purpose of inducing the belief that the person is recognized under this chapter for the purposes of assisting in the preparation, presentation, and prosecution of claims for benefits under the laws administered by the Secretary shall be fined in accordance with title 18, imprisoned, or both.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCB0B640462344F01AA0FA756E12BD668" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This subsection shall not make unlawful the use of any such emblem, sign, insignia or words which was lawful on the date of enactment of this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0771EB594DDF4CE7ACE05C48AE7DE157" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Amounts collected as civil penalties pursuant to this subsection shall remain available for the Department of Veterans Affairs, without fiscal year limitation, for the purpose of enforcing paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HFDAA0C73CA6C4AF19E85226410DB2F6F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of such chapter is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 5906 the following new items:</text><quoted-block id="HD5E55686289A4041AF6379A9546A50FB" style="USC"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">5907. Annual submission of information on recognition of agents, attorneys, organizations and their representatives, and other individuals.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section">5908. Certification mark for identification of recognized individuals.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="H59EC3A19824D4991AF1B36CCDCA1A9AC"><enum>3.</enum><header>Biannual database accuracy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date on which the Secretary submits the first report under section 529 of title 38, United States Code, that includes the information required to be submitted under section 5907 of title 38, United States Code, as added by section 2, and annually thereafter, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall—</text><paragraph id="HEBE49CAE7D4340F895AC668FBA53497A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide to each individual recognized under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/59">chapter 59</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, a notice that includes a request to update the contact information of the individual provided to the Department of Veterans Affairs;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H31547AA8ED0848488474F3FD4A675288"><enum>(2)</enum><text>make publicly available instructions such individuals may use to update such contact information; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF9D9CFF471534A0F8DFF8DD507DC9879"><enum>(3)</enum><text>ensure the VA Accreditation Search Database is updated to include updated contact information.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

