<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0AD6F3FF14B844ACBA0F706FDF2FF4A1" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3310 IH: Venezuela TPS Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3310</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250508">May 8, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001200">Mr. Soto</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S000168">Ms. Salazar</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000797">Ms.
                    Wasserman Schultz</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred
                to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the
                    Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HBU00">the Budget</committee-name>, for a period to be
                subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
                provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To designate Venezuela under section 244 of the Immigration and Nationality Act to permit nationals of Venezuela to be eligible for temporary protected status under such section, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6A28127F17864BF29DB5088DB7681624" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H442BA42941FD42F9B3E042A036B022B2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Venezuela TPS Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H1079ED212FB141BCBE73D59D7CA3C75B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Designation for purposes of granting temporary protected status</header> <subsection id="H33AB4B0CA88146B3A6E4D82B6059CEF1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation</header> <paragraph id="HB4E616096E4B4A08A8DED0368D2A92E1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of section 244 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1254a">8 U.S.C. 1254a</external-xref>), Venezuela shall be treated as if it had been designated under subsection (b)(1)(C) of that section, subject to the provisions of this section.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1E4FFD29C475446EA363A946EB799BBF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Period of designation</header><text>The initial period of the designation referred to in paragraph (1) shall be for the 18-month period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H0364BAE6979B435EA185C7DAB42B6555"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Aliens eligible</header><text>As a result of the designation made under subsection (a), an alien who is a national of Venezuela is deemed to satisfy the requirements under paragraph (1) of section 244(c) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1254a">8 U.S.C. 1254a(c)</external-xref>), subject to paragraph (3) of such section, if the alien—</text> 
<paragraph id="H44025E8028694FF583D1835F66448F26"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has been continuously physically present in the United States since the date of the enactment of this Act;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB51BAE83F47D4E7D876A8A915E92ECCF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is admissible as an immigrant, except as otherwise provided in paragraph (2)(A) of such section, and is not ineligible for temporary protected status under paragraph (2)(B) of such section; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE38879C8E5914089A9B15D9885945224"><enum>(3)</enum><text>registers for temporary protected status in a manner established by the Secretary of Homeland Security.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H74305EC59D8C4813812B32412F18C5B3"> <enum>(c)</enum> <header>Consent To travel abroad</header> <paragraph id="H67123B1C9D4746CD87B1D389CEA951EA"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall give prior consent to travel abroad, in accordance with section 244(f)(3) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1254a">8 U.S.C. 1254a(f)(3)</external-xref>), to an alien who is granted temporary protected status pursuant to the designation made under subsection (a) if the alien establishes to the satisfaction of the Secretary of Homeland Security that emergency and extenuating circumstances beyond the control of the alien require the alien to depart for a brief, temporary trip abroad.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H3507B741CDBE4DA495E893EFAE674CE6">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Treatment upon return</header>
 <text>An alien returning to the United States in accordance with an authorization described in paragraph (1) shall be treated as any other returning alien provided temporary protected status under section 244 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1254a">8 U.S.C. 1254a</external-xref>).</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="H6C157A8BAB7F424EAD85F54C319AFCF2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Fee</header> 
<paragraph id="HA4CE3B4344F2448AB581D4DB172E5E5E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to any other fee authorized by law, the Secretary of Homeland Security is authorized to charge and collect a fee of $360 for each application for temporary protected status under section 244 of the Immigration and Nationality Act by a person who is only eligible for such status by reason of subsection (a).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFBF66F1146124E269E2F675F2507C47C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security shall permit aliens to apply for a waiver of any fees associated with filing an application referred to in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H2F0DAE357AB94E7DAC8BF3F505A72FEE"><enum>3.</enum><header>Determination of budgetary effects</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The budgetary effects of this Act, for the purpose of complying with the Statutory Pay-As-You-Go Act of 2010, shall be determined by reference to the latest statement titled “Budgetary Effects of PAYGO Legislation” for this Act, submitted for printing in the Congressional Record by the Chairman of the House Budget Committee, provided that such statement has been submitted prior to the vote on passage.</text></section> </legis-body></bill>

