<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-REI25176-C16-4Y-29X"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 345 ATS: Congratulating the Oklahoma City Thunder on winning the 2025 National Basketball Association Finals.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 345</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250729">July 29, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S378">Mr. Lankford</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S419">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Congratulating the Oklahoma City Thunder on winning the 2025 National Basketball Association Finals.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, on Sunday, June 22, 2025, the Oklahoma City Thunder (referred to in this preamble as the <term>Thunder</term>) won the 2025 National Basketball Association (referred to in this preamble as the <term>NBA</term>) Finals, defeating the Indiana Pacers in Game 7 with a final score of 103-91 to win the series 4-3;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas, in 2008, the Seattle SuperSonics relocated to Oklahoma City, changing the name of the franchise to the Thunder on arrival;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas the 2008-2009 NBA season was the inaugural season of the Thunder in Oklahoma City;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas the Thunder defeated the Memphis Grizzles, Denver Nuggets, and Minnesota Timberwolves en route to the 2025 NBA Finals;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas, on winning the 2025 NBA Finals, the Thunder secured the first NBA championship for the franchise since relocating to Oklahoma City;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas the Thunder finished the 2024-2025 NBA regular season with 68 wins and 14 losses, a winning percentage of .829;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas the 2025 NBA Finals was the first NBA Finals since 2016 to reach a Game 7;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas, in Game 7 of the 2025 NBA Finals, the Thunder—</text><paragraph id="id1cafbbdae0d14d70a329807eb4634a41"><enum>(1)</enum><text>trailed the Indiana Pacers 48-47 at halftime, making an incredible comeback in the second half to secure the win and championship; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida68d9a368d3a46d18f19e8af57e2b72c"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shut down the Pacers offense, causing the Pacers to score its fewest points of any postseason game;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas Shai Gilgeous-Alexander was named the Most Valuable Player of the NBA for the 2024-2025 regular season and the 2025 NBA Finals, scoring 29 points and 12 assists in Game 7 of the 2025 NBA Finals;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas, during the 2024-2025 NBA season, the Thunder averaged 120.5 points per game, ranking fourth in the NBA, and only allowed their opponents to score an average of 107.6 points per game, outscoring their opponents by an average of 12.8 points per game, the best margin in the NBA during that season;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Thunder victory parade passed in front of the Oklahoma City National Memorial, with 2025 marking the 30-year anniversary of the tragic 1995 Oklahoma City bombing;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas an estimated 500,000 Thunder fans descended on Oklahoma City to attend the victory parade; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the entire State of Oklahoma rallied behind the Thunder to celebrate the historic win of the Thunder in the 2025 NBA Finals: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id22ed4782d0fa4573900301c33ec67f70"><enum>(1)</enum><text>congratulates the Oklahoma City Thunder (referred to in this resolution as the <term>Thunder</term>) on winning the 2025 National Basketball Association Finals; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8529c5f84f264efc80c206e11419c2ea"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the Thunder for—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3d3616fd36ac4f86916b3dc32ddcacac"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">its hard work and dedication to basketball; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide563d3eed45448b89e1d30a6bd9b81db"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the excitement the Thunder bring to the State of Oklahoma and fans everywhere.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

