<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="H97C97818DA30404FAE57269C48D04B69"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4317 IH: Pharmacy Benefit Manager Reform Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4317</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250710">July 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</sponsor> (for himself,
                    <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001210">Mr. Murphy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000305">Ms.
                    Ross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000375">Mr. Arrington</cosponsor>,
                    <cosponsor name-id="H001086">Mrs. Harshbarger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000581">Mr. Vicente Gonzalez of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000372">Mr. Allen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr.
                    Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000612">Mr. Rose</cosponsor>,
                    <cosponsor name-id="T000491">Mr. Tran</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M000317">Ms. Malliotakis</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill;
                which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy
                    and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on
                    <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and Workforce</committee-name>,
                and <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a
                period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration
                of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee
                concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To assure pharmacy access and choice for Medicare
 beneficiaries, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB69E8CFD56394FB9A793225E42AC879B"><section id="HDCA0275CBB754D70AB8014DC0868670D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Pharmacy Benefit Manager Reform Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>PBM Reform Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HE53F583A3B5C485CA4602734EBF4CA0C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Assuring pharmacy access and choice for medicare beneficiaries</header><subsection id="H28449A2F653D4F4784BD509A4582FE16"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1860D–4(b)(1) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-104">42 U.S.C. 1395w–104(b)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by striking subparagraph (A) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H77CB3E6F48884B08B576F78F9DF143D5" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="HC2720724168C4C0DBB4761683E28B80B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><clause id="H072DD9BF0AE84C9DB0A8F60026BC0819"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Participation of any willing pharmacy</header><text>A PDP sponsor offering a prescription drug plan shall permit any pharmacy that meets the standard contract terms and conditions under such plan to participate as a network pharmacy of such plan.</text></clause><clause id="H6D28F9323A0B43B6A27EFEF8FE90BD04"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Contract terms and conditions</header><subclause id="H5536EA1422014F368840953F00D0EFC8"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, for plan years beginning on or after January 1, 2029, in accordance with clause (i), contract terms and conditions offered by such PDP sponsor shall be reasonable and relevant according to standards established by the Secretary under subclause (II).</text></subclause><subclause id="H39ADF40531C94CE597E060BCAB52B0BF"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Standards</header><text>Not later than the first Monday in April of 2028, the Secretary shall establish standards for reasonable and relevant contract terms and conditions for purposes of this clause.</text></subclause><subclause id="H83F3F74DF7794C3C9AB103C3465DF672"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Request for information</header><text>Not later than April 1, 2027, for purposes of establishing the standards under subclause (II), the Secretary shall issue a request for information to seek input on trends in prescription drug plan and network pharmacy contract terms and conditions, current prescription drug plan and network pharmacy contracting practices, whether pharmacy reimbursement and dispensing fees paid by PDP sponsors to network pharmacies sufficiently cover the ingredient and operational costs of such pharmacies, the use and application of pharmacy quality measures by PDP sponsors for network pharmacies, PDP sponsor restrictions or limitations on the dispensing of covered part D drugs by network pharmacies (or any subsets of such pharmacies), PDP sponsor auditing practices for network pharmacies, areas in current regulations or program guidance related to contracting between prescription drug plans and network pharmacies requiring clarification or additional specificity, factors for consideration in determining the reasonableness and relevance of contract terms and conditions between prescription drug plans and network pharmacies, and other issues as determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HB0A75E0157CA4F2D8AB59E9DC4114408"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Essential retail pharmacies</header><text>Section 1860D–42 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-152">42 U.S.C. 1395w–152</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HECB9322BC17F4BD4AAA5EF946D34D040" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="HE7249CBA0ED34638A840D974C0E3465A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Essential retail pharmacies</header><paragraph id="HAAA0DF93C9F8445E98380745D5BAE3A0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>With respect to plan years beginning on or after January 1, 2028, the Secretary shall publish reports, at least once every 2 years until 2034, and periodically thereafter, that provide information, to the extent feasible, on—</text><subparagraph id="H9BCC673ADBF740218EB5AF7E83DF98DA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>trends in ingredient cost reimbursement, dispensing fees, incentive payments and other fees paid by PDP sponsors offering prescription drug plans and MA organizations offering MA–PD plans under this part to essential retail pharmacies (as defined in paragraph (2)) with respect to the dispensing of covered part D drugs, including a comparison of such trends between essential retail pharmacies and pharmacies that are not essential retail pharmacies;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2D7E964147E04E92AA616D69B291DADE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>trends in amounts paid to PDP sponsors offering prescription drug plans and MA organizations offering MA–PD plans under this part by essential retail pharmacies with respect to the dispensing of covered part D drugs, including a comparison of such trends between essential retail pharmacies and pharmacies that are not essential retail pharmacies;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF1D270A33DB94298A3BACE8058952B1E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>trends in essential retail pharmacy participation in pharmacy networks and preferred pharmacy networks for prescription drug plans offered by PDP sponsors and MA–PD plans offered by MA organizations under this part, including a comparison of such trends between essential retail pharmacies and pharmacies that are not essential retail pharmacies;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEC1500E945CC4F67A4ADA4E15BAD9D26"><enum>(D)</enum><text>trends in the number of essential retail pharmacies, including variation in such trends by geographic region or other factors;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5B1DFB559662483D8E4329690647C2CF"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a comparison of cost-sharing for covered part D drugs dispensed by essential retail pharmacies that are network pharmacies for prescription drug plans offered by PDP sponsors and MA–PD plans offered by MA organizations under this part and cost-sharing for covered part D drugs dispensed by other network pharmacies for such plans located in similar geographic areas that are not essential retail pharmacies;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFE5C7D3F864948B6A268B438792D51A0"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a comparison of the volume of covered part D drugs dispensed by essential retail pharmacies that are network pharmacies for prescription drug plans offered by PDP sponsors and MA–PD plans offered by MA organizations under this part and such volume of dispensing by network pharmacies for such plans located in similar geographic areas that are not essential retail pharmacies, including information on any patterns or trends in such comparison specific to certain types of covered part D drugs, such as generic drugs or drugs specified as specialty drugs by a PDP sponsor under a prescription drug plan or an MA organization under an MA–PD plan; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5FF01DDFF79F41568CEBCF3AB18EDDA9"><enum>(G)</enum><text>a comparison of the information described in subparagraphs (A) through (F) between essential retail pharmacies that are network pharmacies for prescription drug plans offered by PDP sponsors under this part and essential retail pharmacies that are network pharmacies for MA–PD plans offered by MA organizations under this part.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4375E36B66824DAF95AAF72F55733DC0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Definition of essential retail pharmacy</header><text>In this subsection, the term <quote>essential retail pharmacy</quote> means, with respect to a plan year, a retail pharmacy that—</text><subparagraph id="HB9444B439D14407A8E24ABA1CDBFD76E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is not a pharmacy that is an affiliate as defined in paragraph (4); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC1ABED5B7DFD44FCBBCC6D490BFEF304"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is located in—</text><clause id="H14E63204844B44BA8A23E206BC30D2D1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a medically underserved area (as designated pursuant to section 330(b)(3)(A) of the Public Health Service Act);</text></clause><clause id="HA0A518DB5B8744A69A789C3B25B85623"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a rural area in which there is no other retail pharmacy within 10 miles, as determined by the Secretary;</text></clause><clause id="HEE8B9FA7DD684B128CD7A3F6D5000D2A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a suburban area in which there is no other retail pharmacy within 2 miles, as determined by the Secretary; or</text></clause><clause id="HF73AB941BD524B89A0883C23BA1E85AC"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>an urban area in which there is no other retail pharmacy within 1 mile, as determined by the Secretary.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB8FA3FCAE3374B84BFFBD23179C02D1A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>List of essential retail pharmacies</header><subparagraph id="H50FEFF7DEDA243D6B486C02FDCB5AD82"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Publication of list of essential retail pharmacies</header><text>For each plan year (beginning with plan year 2028), the Secretary shall publish, on a publicly available internet website of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services, a list of pharmacies that meet the criteria described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (2) to be considered an essential retail pharmacy.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H244925DAA9B34FA7AD3CE6EC22FCA818"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Required submissions from pdp sponsors</header><text>For each plan year (beginning with plan year 2028), each PDP sponsor offering a prescription drug plan and each MA organization offering an MA–PD plan shall submit to the Secretary, for the purposes of determining retail pharmacies that meet the criterion specified in subparagraph (A) of paragraph (2), a list of retail pharmacies that are affiliates of such sponsor or organization, or are affiliates of a pharmacy benefit manager acting on behalf of such sponsor or organization, at a time, and in a form and manner, specified by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8773FA0F76D4444AB75C406C482997BD"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Reporting by pdp sponsors and ma organizations</header><text>For each plan year beginning with plan year 2027, each PDP sponsor offering a prescription drug plan and each MA organization offering an MA–PD plan under this part shall submit to the Secretary information on incentive payments and other fees paid by such sponsor or organization to pharmacies, insofar as any such payments or fees are not otherwise reported, at a time, and in a form and manner, specified by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC4623C7D8C0342CD9583703CD5B1E62E"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary may implement this paragraph by program instruction or otherwise.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDE2C65B85C02498F8D5FD006F8ECA046"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Nonapplication of paperwork reduction act</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/44/35">Chapter 35</external-xref> of title 44, United States Code, shall not apply to the implementation of this paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFD8B3284D5DF4221AFAB1F18DAA4959E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Definition of affiliate; pharmacy benefit manager</header><text>In this subsection, the terms <quote>affiliate</quote> and <quote>pharmacy benefit manager</quote> have the meaning given those terms in section 1860D–12(h)(7).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H94F69147BC8D4F8BAB7550866082F942"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><paragraph id="H46CEE0923FB44F5CBE1F2340B0A2FCFF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1860D–4(b)(1) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-104">42 U.S.C. 1395w–104(b)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HA40AB91B14B64698BDCCFA6EC5CBCD21" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="H2507E02D80514684A67629C5CD155A56"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Enforcement of standards for reasonable and relevant contract
 terms and conditions</header><clause id="HF9294766DC564DCBBC3713D2B6E45C0F"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Allegation submission process</header><subclause id="H223A616C6726419684BEF1FEDB9AA815"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than January 1, 2028, the Secretary shall establish a process through which a pharmacy may submit to the Secretary an allegation of a violation by a PDP sponsor offering a prescription drug plan of the standards for reasonable and relevant contract terms and conditions under subparagraph (A)(ii), or of subclause (VIII) of this clause.</text></subclause><subclause id="H1B923C7465664F3EB34F755466C208BD"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Frequency of submission</header><item id="H472644F2BCF54F319ACCFD5BD963FE0A"><enum>(aa)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in item (bb), the allegation submission process under this clause shall allow pharmacies to submit any allegations of violations described in subclause (I) not more frequently than once per plan year per contract between a pharmacy and a PDP sponsor.</text></item><item id="H53CF5DC6693F4B83A4681014101EA7DD"><enum>(bb)</enum><header>Allegations relating to contract
 modifications</header><text>In the case where a contract between a pharmacy and a PDP sponsor is modified following the submission of allegations by a pharmacy with respect to such contract and plan year, the allegation submission process under this clause shall allow such pharmacy to submit an additional allegation related to those modifications with respect to such contract and plan year.</text></item></subclause><subclause id="HC5682710899A4DA88EA9FF45691ED694"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Access to relevant documents and materials</header><text>A PDP sponsor subject to an allegation under this clause—</text><item id="HDCDEA3B731DC48BC9BCE8222CF79A944"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>shall provide documents or materials, as specified by the Secretary, including contract offers made by such sponsor to such pharmacy or correspondence related to such offers, to the Secretary at a time, and in a form and manner, specified by the Secretary; and</text></item><item id="HECAD4D0D178C4173A3408DE1DAAE580F"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>shall not prohibit or otherwise limit the ability of a pharmacy to submit such documents or materials to the Secretary for the purpose of submitting an allegation or providing evidence for such an allegation under this clause.</text></item></subclause><subclause id="H78CC7A2B49BD40CBAE030BC3240A49C6"><enum>(IV)</enum><header>Standardized template</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a standardized template for pharmacies to use for the submission of allegations described in subclause (I). Such template shall require that the submission include a certification by the pharmacy that the information included is accurate, complete, and true to the best of the knowledge, information, and belief of such pharmacy.</text></subclause><subclause id="H6DC5624738B74EC292F2387E9EB71BA9"><enum>(V)</enum><header>Preventing frivolous allegations</header><text>In the case where the Secretary determines that a pharmacy has submitted frivolous allegations under this clause on a routine basis, the Secretary may temporarily prohibit such pharmacy from using the allegation submission process under this clause, as determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text></subclause><subclause id="H5BA8D07BD91B405C851BEFC87B799240"><enum>(VI)</enum><header>Exemption from freedom of information act</header><text>Allegations submitted under this clause shall be exempt from disclosure under section 552 of title 5, United States Code.</text></subclause><subclause id="H38448640F0DE4A0A88C37103F5EA63DB"><enum>(VII)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this clause shall be construed as limiting the ability of a pharmacy to pursue other legal actions or remedies, consistent with applicable Federal or State law, with respect to a potential violation of a requirement described in this subparagraph.</text></subclause><subclause id="H37D2A9B56A53419BA6B62E4325E5443A"><enum>(VIII)</enum><header>Anti-retaliation and anti-coercion</header><text>Consistent with applicable Federal or State law, a PDP sponsor shall not—</text><item id="H1CE7FF63635F48C58921507E12C8191F"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>retaliate against a pharmacy for submitting any allegations under this clause; or</text></item><item id="H3DD20EAF08C245DC8BBEEFA61E54B06D"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>coerce, intimidate, threaten, or interfere with the ability of a pharmacy to submit any such allegations.</text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="H03B090C9B0EA4939B6D3E9A26ECD6A36"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Investigation</header><text>The Secretary shall investigate, as determined appropriate by the Secretary, allegations submitted pursuant to clause (i).</text></clause><clause id="H3821A397EF194FA4809396C0D61C313F"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><subclause id="H81D84C8A866245AF8EA37CC98EFF9C90"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case where the Secretary determines that a PDP sponsor offering a prescription drug plan has violated the standards for reasonable and relevant contract terms and conditions under subparagraph (A)(ii), the Secretary may use authorities under sections 1857(g) and 1860D–12(b)(3)(E) to impose civil monetary penalties or other intermediate sanctions.</text></subclause><subclause id="HD8A7AB18514D46F58A4C207A3F749088"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Application of civil monetary penalties</header><text>The provisions of section 1128A (other than subsections (a) and (b)) shall apply to a civil monetary penalty under this clause in the same manner as such provisions apply to a penalty or proceeding under section 1128A(a).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H6CC7AF300FFA4DF7A4040B284FD5C952"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 1857(g)(1) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-27">42 U.S.C. 1395w–27(g)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="H5C4DC49E1C214140B8B13A64C95FED0E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (J), by striking <quote>or</quote> after the semicolon;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H940F2AFA12E44E58B18B9129BA9DD0B5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (K) as subparagraph (L);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6E75E91D27F1473CB64FF8516EA414C4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (J), the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block id="H48C57C0FF11C493488E74C23954FDFB9" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="H33B8EA1FD3B745D9AA30F107750AA1F3"><enum>(K)</enum><text>fails to comply with the standards for reasonable and relevant contract terms and conditions under subparagraph (A)(ii) of section 1860D–4(b)(1); or</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0CF2878937334671B652807DF36B87B0"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in subparagraph (L), as redesignated by subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>through (J)</quote> and inserting <quote>through (K)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB3029C8FA77445D88EF6D31E8BF74F75"><enum>(E)</enum><text>in the flush matter following subparagraph (L), as so redesignated, by striking <quote>subparagraphs (A) through (K)</quote> and inserting <quote>subparagraphs (A) through (L)</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4E767D59CAA843568C985CA10CEEE5A9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Accountability of pharmacy benefit managers for violations of reasonable and
 relevant contract terms and conditions</header><paragraph id="HFE5A87AB05404F3DB2D592DC4465FE12"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1860D–12(b) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-112">42 U.S.C. 1395w–112</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block id="H153E97444BB740BCA50150CFF2C1AE76" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H0C0AAC222219469CA5406D8452488ADB"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Accountability of pharmacy benefit managers for violations of
 reasonable and relevant contract terms and conditions</header><text>For plan years beginning on or after January 1, 2028, each contract entered into with a PDP sponsor under this part with respect to a prescription drug plan offered by such sponsor shall provide that any pharmacy benefit manager acting on behalf of such sponsor has a written agreement with the PDP sponsor under which the pharmacy benefit manager agrees to reimburse the PDP sponsor for any amounts paid by such sponsor under section 1860D–4(b)(1)(F)(iii)(I) to the Secretary as a result of a violation described in such section if such violation is related to a responsibility delegated to the pharmacy benefit manager by such PDP sponsor.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H8F6F20618C31457390AAE7B83B9AA1A8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>M<enum-in-header>A</enum-in-header>–<enum-in-header>PD</enum-in-header> plans</header><text>Section 1857(f)(3) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-27">42 U.S.C. 1395w–27(f)(3)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block id="HE418A27F7F36433AB1E13BB59E66EBA0" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="H3EBDEEC543A1401F9CCF316BB4259806"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Accountability of pharmacy benefit managers for violations of
 reasonable and relevant contract terms</header><text>For plan years beginning on or after January 1, 2028, section 1860D–12(b)(9).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFDF2E4EFCB624B0F8958C2C12C339F71"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Biennial report on enforcement and oversight of pharmacy access
 requirements</header><text>Section 1860D–42 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-152">42 U.S.C. 1395w–152</external-xref>), as amended by subsection (b), is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block id="H88ADFFDB0A564FA1BB76BDCBA1AE85B1" style="OLC"><subsection id="HD2AB91BA6C054ED085A4BCBB75502341"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Biennial report on enforcement and oversight of pharmacy access
 requirements</header><paragraph id="H4C966B4C6D204A5BA54659B5EF7FC0FF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this subsection, and at least once every 2 years thereafter, the Secretary shall publish a report on enforcement and oversight actions and activities undertaken by the Secretary with respect to the requirements under section 1860D–4(b)(1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H09CF905F17434DA8BB8AA313CDA5D63E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>A report under paragraph (1) shall not disclose—</text><subparagraph id="H111F476118434D6488AEA411DFC27C15"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identifiable information about individuals or entities unless such information is otherwise publicly available; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H38EF3B05383A4EBBA7AE79565F677172"><enum>(B)</enum><text>trade secrets with respect to any entities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H65197D18C7C94004B00BE5D46CDDF855"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>In addition to amounts otherwise available, there is appropriated to the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services Program Management Account, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, $188,000,000 for fiscal year 2025, to remain available until expended, to carry out this section.</text></subsection></section><section id="H7965257A50E344C9848B0B4709C39604"><enum>3.</enum><header>Modernizing and ensuring pbm accountability</header><subsection id="H091EAF2FA71D40A68F8BC81C48938DB9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><paragraph id="HCAE1D8C120104615ACD5A299A818F16C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Prescription drug plans</header><text>Section 1860D–12 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-112">42 U.S.C. 1395w–112</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block id="H51753FCE7BCC40EE84F399ADFE8791F4" style="OLC"><subsection id="H32C517836AE348FBAF0455FDB6481710"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Requirements relating to pharmacy benefit managers</header><text>For plan years beginning on or after January 1, 2028:</text><paragraph id="H8BFD1F2DB55346BEA6082EB7B8B6AEA2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agreements with pharmacy benefit managers</header><text>Each contract entered into with a PDP sponsor under this part with respect to a prescription drug plan offered by such sponsor shall provide that any pharmacy benefit manager acting on behalf of such sponsor has a written agreement with the PDP sponsor under which the pharmacy benefit manager, and any affiliates of such pharmacy benefit manager, as applicable, agree to meet the following requirements:</text><subparagraph id="HE70E16C4EDD747128717A4508D131921"><enum>(A)</enum><header>No income other than bona fide service fees</header><clause id="HDA15D7C836F444DF98D70AC9B87CEA59"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The pharmacy benefit manager and any affiliate of such pharmacy benefit manager shall not derive any remuneration with respect to any services provided on behalf of any entity or individual, in connection with the utilization of covered part D drugs, from any such entity or individual other than bona fide service fees, subject to clauses (ii) and (iii).</text></clause><clause id="H5203A0A5D1D74A1EACD1CB827F7F0193"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Incentive payments</header><text>For the purposes of this subsection, an incentive payment (as determined by the Secretary) paid by a PDP sponsor to a pharmacy benefit manager that is performing services on behalf of such sponsor shall be deemed a <quote>bona fide service fee</quote> (even if such payment does not otherwise meet the definition of such term under paragraph (7)(B)) if such payment is a flat dollar amount, is consistent with fair market value (as specified by the Secretary), is related to services actually performed by the pharmacy benefit manager or affiliate of such pharmacy benefit manager, on behalf of the PDP sponsor making such payment, in connection with the utilization of covered part D drugs, and meets additional requirements, if any, as determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text></clause><clause id="HE46726DF2238498F80C1FE33C42A7AEC"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Clarification on rebates and discounts used to lower
 costs for covered part d drugs</header><text>Rebates, discounts, and other price concessions received by a pharmacy benefit manager or an affiliate of a pharmacy benefit manager from manufacturers, even if such price concessions are calculated as a percentage of a drug’s price, shall not be considered a violation of the requirements of clause (i) if they are fully passed through to a PDP sponsor and are compliant with all regulatory and subregulatory requirements related to direct and indirect remuneration for manufacturer rebates under this part, including in cases where a PDP sponsor is acting as a pharmacy benefit manager on behalf of a prescription drug plan offered by such PDP sponsor.</text></clause><clause id="H042C61B4900A4A4386D925F1284A30EB"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Evaluation of remuneration arrangements</header><text>Components of subsets of remuneration arrangements (such as fees or other forms of compensation paid to or retained by the pharmacy benefit manager or affiliate of such pharmacy benefit manager), as determined appropriate by the Secretary, between pharmacy benefit managers or affiliates of such pharmacy benefit managers, as applicable, and other entities involved in the dispensing or utilization of covered part D drugs (including PDP sponsors, manufacturers, and pharmacies) shall be subject to review by the Secretary, in consultation with the Office of the Inspector General of the Department of Health and Human Services, as determined appropriate by the Secretary. The Secretary, in consultation with the Office of the Inspector General, shall review whether remuneration under such arrangements is consistent with fair market value (as specified by the Secretary) through reviews and assessments of such remuneration, as determined appropriate.</text></clause><clause id="H6B1D144D3561409E802450E8115058E2"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Disgorgement</header><text>The pharmacy benefit manager shall disgorge any remuneration paid to such pharmacy benefit manager or an affiliate of such pharmacy benefit manager in violation of this subparagraph to the PDP sponsor.</text></clause><clause id="H5EDE01FC7A2E4D5EB0C4845BF10265C0"><enum>(vi)</enum><header>Additional requirements</header><text>The pharmacy benefit manager shall—</text><subclause id="HEAFBA74A2AA74D24A0FAF2960D01F7CD"><enum>(I)</enum><text>enter into a written agreement with any affiliate of such pharmacy benefit manager, under which the affiliate shall identify and disgorge any remuneration described in clause (v) to the pharmacy benefit manager; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HCE808E3228E142DBB59E36FFE59542A0"><enum>(II)</enum><text>attest, subject to any requirements determined appropriate by the Secretary, that the pharmacy benefit manager has entered into a written agreement described in subclause (I) with any relevant affiliate of the pharmacy benefit manager.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE787D8646816468C85FCEB9FA2E7F004"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Transparency regarding guarantees and cost performance
 evaluations</header><text>The pharmacy benefit manager shall—</text><clause id="HE22E64A2C92B47B3A161CA72F06C225A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>define, interpret, and apply, in a fully transparent and consistent manner for purposes of calculating or otherwise evaluating pharmacy benefit manager performance against pricing guarantees or similar cost performance measurements related to rebates, discounts, price concessions, or net costs, terms such as—</text><subclause id="H51945B7D30A24AAE81D337272F90D208"><enum>(I)</enum><text><quote>generic drug</quote>, in a manner consistent with the definition of the term under section 423.4 of title 42, Code of Federal Regulations, or a successor regulation;</text></subclause><subclause id="H0BBC206F92004F3491E5924A4586B3C4"><enum>(II)</enum><text><quote>brand name drug</quote>, in a manner consistent with the definition of the term under section 423.4 of title 42, Code of Federal Regulations, or a successor regulation;</text></subclause><subclause id="H5A2070C343BE4168A801A11B722A466F"><enum>(III)</enum><text><quote>specialty drug</quote>;</text></subclause><subclause id="H132B2908F094430286643012E0DB1963"><enum>(IV)</enum><text><quote>rebate</quote>; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HDB779644181244CA836C594CB1C69495"><enum>(V)</enum><text>‘discount’;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H742FD762F20843B3B60A74CA18241D98"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>identify any drugs, claims, or price concessions excluded from any pricing guarantee or other cost performance measure in a clear and consistent manner; and</text></clause><clause id="HADFE8F9E7D5A4C7FA53A61E2A99CEE8C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>where a pricing guarantee or other cost performance measure is based on a pricing benchmark other than the wholesale acquisition cost (as defined in section 1847A(c)(6)(B)) of a drug, calculate and provide a wholesale acquisition cost-based equivalent to the pricing guarantee or other cost performance measure.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H97564D6B03874DF588EA3E4C0F49979E"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Provision of information</header><clause id="HEC01F227A99340F79FFB139AAC0BB30C"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than July 1 of each year, beginning in 2028, the pharmacy benefit manager shall submit to the PDP sponsor, and to the Secretary, a report, in accordance with this subparagraph, and shall make such report available to such sponsor at no cost to such sponsor in a format specified by the Secretary under paragraph (5). Each such report shall include, with respect to such PDP sponsor and each plan offered by such sponsor, the following information with respect to the previous plan year:</text><subclause id="H72F2C6CEED0E4A4392BA6F8D0A0452FA"><enum>(I)</enum><text>A list of all drugs covered by the plan that were dispensed including, with respect to each such drug—</text><item id="H5A437B1A989C4A3EB4E8251316D0631F"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the brand name, generic or non-proprietary name, and National Drug Code;</text></item><item id="HB9F177D64EC94544871CF8F601B892BE"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the number of plan enrollees for whom the drug was dispensed, the total number of prescription claims for the drug (including original prescriptions and refills, counted as separate claims), and the total number of dosage units of the drug dispensed;</text></item><item id="HE87CF104B0D6433E9DD4FB02126E2081"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>the number of prescription claims described in item (bb) by each type of dispensing channel through which the drug was dispensed, including retail, mail order, specialty pharmacy, long-term care pharmacy, home infusion pharmacy, or other types of pharmacies or providers;</text></item><item id="H0D8683D3907343E5BFEDBA771D1D437C"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>the average wholesale acquisition cost, listed as cost per day’s supply, cost per dosage unit, and cost per typical course of treatment (as applicable);</text></item><item id="HD1D422BC62F948D7A5F45BD54AC97E1F"><enum>(ee)</enum><text>the average wholesale price for the drug, listed as price per day’s supply, price per dosage unit, and price per typical course of treatment (as applicable);</text></item><item id="HAD46AF0D9AEF4BD2A0C8CD3A08770787"><enum>(ff)</enum><text>the total out-of-pocket spending by plan enrollees on such drug after application of any benefits under the plan, including plan enrollee spending through copayments, coinsurance, and deductibles;</text></item><item id="H423653A29ED94E32BC635D3A8AB7F1CF"><enum>(gg)</enum><text>total rebates paid by the manufacturer on the drug as reported under the Detailed DIR Report (or any successor report) submitted by such sponsor to the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services;</text></item><item id="H601EB2ABC80C4E80A982E74115B12EA7"><enum>(hh)</enum><text>all other direct or indirect remuneration on the drug as reported under the Detailed DIR Report (or any successor report) submitted by such sponsor to the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services;</text></item><item id="H413E3955ED624D1884DB10AFFBAA46F6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the average pharmacy reimbursement amount paid by the plan for the drug in the aggregate and disaggregated by dispensing channel identified in item (cc);</text></item><item id="H0EFBD94DE81D41DEB2CE617AA587D033"><enum>(jj)</enum><text>the average National Average Drug Acquisition Cost (NADAC); and</text></item><item id="H50F4905F86444AB1995FBF9D84E844FF"><enum>(kk)</enum><text>total manufacturer-derived revenue, inclusive of bona fide service fees, attributable to the drug and retained by the pharmacy benefit manager and any affiliate of such pharmacy benefit manager.</text></item></subclause><subclause id="HB09EA3D5A96A491086986DAF8E1FB6C3"><enum>(II)</enum><text>In the case of a pharmacy benefit manager that has an affiliate that is a retail, mail order, or specialty pharmacy, with respect to drugs covered by such plan that were dispensed, the following information:</text><item id="H3EF0F72E0CE8465E85F05B03CA1F291B"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>The percentage of total prescriptions that were dispensed by pharmacies that are an affiliate of the pharmacy benefit manager for each drug.</text></item><item id="HBB69B81E384D41638E682DA5A229578F"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>The interquartile range of the total combined costs paid by the plan and plan enrollees, per dosage unit, per course of treatment, per 30-day supply, and per 90-day supply for each drug dispensed by pharmacies that are not an affiliate of the pharmacy benefit manager and that are included in the pharmacy network of such plan.</text></item><item id="HE898654154484222B65C515D4E1A5213"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>The interquartile range of the total combined costs paid by the plan and plan enrollees, per dosage unit, per course of treatment, per 30-day supply, and per 90-day supply for each drug dispensed by pharmacies that are an affiliate of the pharmacy benefit manager and that are included in the pharmacy network of such plan.</text></item><item id="H998E2AD0029447F694FC741CF0CE9994"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>The lowest total combined cost paid by the plan and plan enrollees, per dosage unit, per course of treatment, per 30-day supply, and per 90-day supply, for each drug that is available from any pharmacy included in the pharmacy network of such plan.</text></item><item id="H4DD2EC7F373742C3B2B2460E2295BBB9"><enum>(ee)</enum><text>The difference between the average acquisition cost of the affiliate, such as a pharmacy or other entity that acquires prescription drugs, that initially acquires the drug and the amount reported under subclause (I)(jj) for each drug.</text></item><item id="H098088BC1FCF453C8C0490D9339AD555"><enum>(ff)</enum><text>A list inclusive of the brand name, generic or non-proprietary name, and National Drug Code of covered part D drugs subject to an agreement with a covered entity under section 340B of the Public Health Service Act for which the pharmacy benefit manager or an affiliate of the pharmacy benefit manager had a contract or other arrangement with such a covered entity in the service area of such plan.</text></item></subclause><subclause id="HE6F41D79E26E4D4FBBB81796C236E5E1"><enum>(III)</enum><text>Where a drug approved under section 505(c) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (referred to in this subclause as the <quote>listed drug</quote>) is covered by the plan, the following information:</text><item id="H12B7E4DE9AAA4C0BA06FECAC22F276FE"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>A list of currently marketed generic drugs approved under section 505(j) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act pursuant to an application that references such listed drug that are not covered by the plan, are covered on the same formulary tier or a formulary tier typically associated with higher cost-sharing than the listed drug, or are subject to utilization management that the listed drug is not subject to.</text></item><item id="H312EE4AEED39478980641007AEB8A165"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>The estimated average beneficiary cost-sharing under the plan for a 30-day supply of the listed drug.</text></item><item id="HE7FBAA07CD49474AA7E649E507E2D8A4"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>Where a generic drug listed under item (aa) is on a formulary tier typically associated with higher cost-sharing than the listed drug, the estimated average cost-sharing that a beneficiary would have paid for a 30-day supply of each of the generic drugs described in item (aa), had the plan provided coverage for such drugs on the same formulary tier as the listed drug.</text></item><item id="H8B64EC24CFD747A5947234EA088984E0"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>A written justification for providing more favorable coverage of the listed drug than the generic drugs described in item (aa).</text></item><item id="H080521CE3C8E4B8F9305AC3258B42C26"><enum>(ee)</enum><text>The number of currently marketed generic drugs approved under section 505(j) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act pursuant to an application that references such listed drug.</text></item></subclause><subclause id="HCD7E2C4A6D5A41899726519B2D70967A"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>Where a reference product (as defined in section 351(i) of the Public Health Service Act) is covered by the plan, the following information:</text><item id="H4954AF6EC99745308610BC9E3DD05BB1"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>A list of currently marketed biosimilar biological products licensed under section 351(k) of the Public Health Service Act pursuant to an application that refers to such reference product that are not covered by the plan, are covered on the same formulary tier or a formulary tier typically associated with higher cost-sharing than the reference product, or are subject to utilization management that the reference product is not subject to.</text></item><item id="H900BB8CC84BC409F855451D41E45E876"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>The estimated average beneficiary cost-sharing under the plan for a 30-day supply of the reference product.</text></item><item id="H332E55B00A744F85B3B234A8B6A0ED6D"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>Where a biosimilar biological product listed under item (aa) is on a formulary tier typically associated with higher cost- sharing than the reference product, the estimated average cost-sharing that a beneficiary would have paid for a 30-day supply of each of the biosimilar biological products described in item (aa), had the plan provided coverage for such products on the same formulary tier as the reference product.</text></item><item id="H5960FA2F2C9842CCB5CADB7EFE90D7EF"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>A written justification for providing more favorable coverage of the reference product than the biosimilar biological product described in item (aa).</text></item><item id="H17900D2879C545F88D5750FC4764AEB6"><enum>(ee)</enum><text>The number of currently marketed biosimilar biological products licensed under section 351(k) of the Public Health Service Act, pursuant to an application that refers to such reference product.</text></item></subclause><subclause id="HF4023416D2974EE499E7B5493FB35306"><enum>(V)</enum><text>Total gross spending on covered part D drugs by the plan, not net of rebates, fees, discounts, or other direct or indirect remuneration.</text></subclause><subclause id="H907C50CDD1FB477C8EF44AF0BEAEAD14"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>The total amount retained by the pharmacy benefit manager or an affiliate of such pharmacy benefit manager in revenue related to utilization of covered part D drugs under that plan, inclusive of bona fide service fees.</text></subclause><subclause id="HA0FA35A2E303483DA41A4694E57A7E4E"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>The total spending on covered part D drugs net of rebates, fees, discounts, or other direct and indirect remuneration by the plan.</text></subclause><subclause id="H77233D2F32A44AC2A02D57B9188595DA"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text>An explanation of any benefit design parameters under such plan that encourage plan enrollees to fill prescriptions at pharmacies that are an affiliate of such pharmacy benefit manager, such as mail and specialty home delivery programs, and retail and mail auto-refill programs.</text></subclause><subclause id="H1290B471616E43CBA18160FE8403450F"><enum>(IX)</enum><text>The following information:</text><item id="H420399000FB84CD8AB0264B6E2CCBD2F"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>A list of all brokers, consultants, advisors, and auditors that receive compensation from the pharmacy benefit manager or an affiliate of such pharmacy benefit manager for referrals, consulting, auditing, or other services offered to PDP sponsors related to pharmacy benefit management services.</text></item><item id="H5515CC0800364A68B3C1B567475868BE"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>The amount of compensation provided by such pharmacy benefit manager or affiliate to each such broker, consultant, advisor, and auditor.</text></item><item id="HD029EAA131584F86A1C522CA067A5E25"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>The methodology for calculating the amount of compensation provided by such pharmacy benefit manager or affiliate, for each such broker, consultant, advisor, and auditor.</text></item></subclause><subclause id="HC300167B8E13435DB2EA59A794A30AB7"><enum>(X)</enum><text>A list of all affiliates of the pharmacy benefit manager.</text></subclause><subclause id="HA4F7C1CC61874DA690839E91BE54AFA1"><enum>(XI)</enum><text>A summary document submitted in a standardized template developed by the Secretary that includes such information described in subclauses (I) through (X).</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H2A9491B9AC5D4FD2920DD329750329F8"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Written explanation of contracts or agreements with
 drug manufacturers</header><subclause id="H756FF5A7DC95459EAFD3DEF7F3145247"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The pharmacy benefit manager shall, not later than 30 days after the finalization of any contract or agreement between such pharmacy benefit manager or an affiliate of such pharmacy benefit manager and a drug manufacturer (or subsidiary, agent, or entity affiliated with such drug manufacturer) that makes rebates, discounts, payments, or other financial incentives related to one or more covered part D drugs or other prescription drugs, as applicable, of the manufacturer directly or indirectly contingent upon coverage, formulary placement, or utilization management conditions on any other covered part D drugs or other prescription drugs, as applicable, submit to the PDP sponsor a written explanation of such contract or agreement.</text></subclause><subclause id="H1F71927F947C4A27A2CC87E59814EF29"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>A written explanation under subclause (I) shall—</text><item id="H59B88F161B834D88A206810962587770"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>include the manufacturer subject to the contract or agreement, all covered part D drugs and other prescription drugs, as applicable, subject to the contract or agreement and the manufacturers of such drugs, and a high-level description of the terms of such contract or agreement and how such terms apply to such drugs; and</text></item><item id="H95F048868238446C9753EA06B9414C93"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>be certified by the Chief Executive Officer, Chief Financial Officer, or General Counsel of such pharmacy benefit manager, or affiliate of such pharmacy benefit manager, as applicable, or an individual delegated with the authority to sign on behalf of one of these officers, who reports directly to the officer.</text></item></subclause><subclause id="H657785C78F08440DADFDEA3D40AE1D68"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Definition of other prescription drugs</header><text>For purposes of this clause, the term <quote>other prescription drugs</quote> means prescription drugs covered as supplemental benefits under this part or prescription drugs paid outside of this part.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H14E3049DE14B4151B684863951FD527E"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Audit rights</header><clause id="HECE727E023F745E79AF3D7E69070CB02"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not less than once a year, at the request of the PDP sponsor, the pharmacy benefit manager shall allow for an audit of the pharmacy benefit manager to ensure compliance with all terms and conditions under the written agreement described in this paragraph and the accuracy of information reported under subparagraph (C).</text></clause><clause id="H269469890EF248289023065545224EFB"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Auditor</header><text>The PDP sponsor shall have the right to select an auditor. The pharmacy benefit manager shall not impose any limitations on the selection of such auditor.</text></clause><clause id="H707B3870A9144F9093EDE206D4CDD3A7"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Provision of information</header><text>The pharmacy benefit manager shall make available to such auditor all records, data, contracts, and other information necessary to confirm the accuracy of information provided under subparagraph (C), subject to reasonable restrictions on how such information must be reported to prevent redisclosure of such information.</text></clause><clause id="HD223951B7C16445F8DF5B8C937C1686C"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Timing</header><text>The pharmacy benefit manager must provide information under clause (iii) and other information, data, and records relevant to the audit to such auditor within 6 months of the initiation of the audit and respond to requests for additional information from such auditor within 30 days after the request for additional information.</text></clause><clause id="HF44C05E0DCE64B7CAE925AF7F359BA3E"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Information from affiliates</header><text>The pharmacy benefit manager shall be responsible for providing to such auditor information required to be reported under subparagraph (C) or under clause (iii) of this subparagraph that is owned or held by an affiliate of such pharmacy benefit manager.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA6AA82C22F8740B7B35C810FF2425B3D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><subparagraph id="H70EFC9E5146D455BB6F601C818F58849"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each PDP sponsor shall—</text><clause id="H7E13CDF96D944347975FBC77ACC9CAEA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>disgorge to the Secretary any amounts disgorged to the PDP sponsor by a pharmacy benefit manager under paragraph (1)(A)(v);</text></clause><clause id="H6D8B90BB4BE74B23BDD4AA175D21FAA5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>require, in a written agreement with any pharmacy benefit manager acting on behalf of such sponsor or affiliate of such pharmacy benefit manager, that such pharmacy benefit manager or affiliate reimburse the PDP sponsor for any civil money penalty imposed on the PDP sponsor as a result of the failure of the pharmacy benefit manager or affiliate to meet the requirements of paragraph (1) that are applicable to the pharmacy benefit manager or affiliate under the agreement; and</text></clause><clause id="H242AF4DBC1BA468A8DD01A196FA170CF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>require, in a written agreement with any such pharmacy benefit manager acting on behalf of such sponsor or affiliate of such pharmacy benefit manager, that such pharmacy benefit manager or affiliate be subject to punitive remedies for breach of contract for failure to comply with the requirements applicable under paragraph (1).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H349023C6F3EE4D95B2F80E8DEAFAD8AB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Reporting of alleged violations</header><text>The Secretary shall make available and maintain a mechanism for manufacturers, PDP sponsors, pharmacies, and other entities that have contractual relationships with pharmacy benefit managers or affiliates of such pharmacy benefit managers to report, on a confidential basis, alleged violations of paragraph (1)(A) or subparagraph (C).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBC5AF372C1F647569BD5FA7422FB7434"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Anti-retaliation and anti-coercion</header><text>Consistent with applicable Federal or State law, a PDP sponsor shall not—</text><clause id="H9F90E84B98CF4C1EA9CA7B829D6574F0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>retaliate against an individual or entity for reporting an alleged violation under subparagraph (B); or</text></clause><clause id="H6EABC44C99DA4465B74721A0E9C50B3E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>coerce, intimidate, threaten, or interfere with the ability of an individual or entity to report any such alleged violations.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDF4EAC2C965C4DFD9E2F50C61994307C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Certification of compliance</header><subparagraph id="H4DE6F02C35A446B9BF8C556F64EB20CE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each PDP sponsor shall furnish to the Secretary (at a time and in a manner specified by the Secretary) an annual certification of compliance with this subsection, as well as such information as the Secretary determines necessary to carry out this subsection.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD2F786EA162644D3B292A6CC8FF6089E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>The Secretary may implement this paragraph by program instruction or otherwise.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2941FFE009714069BC073646019B01F4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed as—</text><subparagraph id="H50905712D6AB48CF99B46F3D4F3EDCB8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>prohibiting flat dispensing fees or reimbursement or payment for ingredient costs (including customary, industry-standard discounts directly related to drug acquisition that are retained by pharmacies or wholesalers) to entities that acquire or dispense prescription drugs; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBE23F9FE2AEA49DBAB025FA6CEF8E43F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>modifying regulatory requirements or sub-regulatory program instruction or guidance related to pharmacy payment, reimbursement, or dispensing fees.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC24BB6C00ACE48069DE7943A859B04D0"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Standard formats</header><subparagraph id="H5BD3E6BB59DF4CB9A5906C8A92214646"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than June 1, 2027, the Secretary shall specify standard, machine-readable formats for pharmacy benefit managers to submit annual reports required under paragraph (1)(C)(i).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC952BBE552EF4D1E9876E1539BDE41E4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>The Secretary may implement this paragraph by program instruction or otherwise.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3E8BEC5C34CE45E6B737226C337E9E9F"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Confidentiality</header><subparagraph id="H6E10341756B34DBD95E261AD1CE4BE2E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Information disclosed by a pharmacy benefit manager, an affiliate of a pharmacy benefit manager, a PDP sponsor, or a pharmacy under this subsection that is not otherwise publicly available or available for purchase shall not be disclosed by the Secretary or a PDP sponsor receiving the information, except that the Secretary may disclose the information for the following purposes:</text><clause id="HC298381218714E5F8B0CE6464EA052BB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>As the Secretary determines necessary to carry out this part.</text></clause><clause id="H33160FB1303548A2BFB5E60A1AC185DA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>To permit the Comptroller General to review the information provided.</text></clause><clause id="H807F32BAE64542D8A76A09E2D5F9FBC6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>To permit the Director of the Congressional Budget Office to review the information provided.</text></clause><clause id="HB8A67DF1080C4B22AA1EC6034806FA14"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>To permit the Executive Director of the Medicare Payment Advisory Commission to review the information provided.</text></clause><clause id="H8BA9B4BDFD0D489D8D86A6C3DE39D7A9"><enum>(v)</enum><text>To the Attorney General for the purposes of conducting oversight and enforcement under this title.</text></clause><clause id="H78B888646F114F1E87B015250D548B0B"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>To the Inspector General of the Department of Health and Human Services in accordance with its authorities under the Inspector General Act of 1978 (section 406 of title 5, United States Code), and other applicable statutes.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H871B7BFD8E564C97BE5C33946244576B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Restriction on use of information</header><text>The Secretary, the Comptroller General, the Director of the Congressional Budget Office, and the Executive Director of the Medicare Payment Advisory Commission shall not report on or disclose information disclosed pursuant to subparagraph (A) to the public in a manner that would identify—</text><clause id="HEB9E4AAFB5974F7BB670BFBE4252957F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a specific pharmacy benefit manager, affiliate, pharmacy, manufacturer, wholesaler, PDP sponsor, or plan; or</text></clause><clause id="HB74392EE85D54452A517E2F6A9117586"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>contract prices, rebates, discounts, or other remuneration for specific drugs in a manner that may allow the identification of specific contracting parties or of such specific drugs.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAB920BEF435C431C82CFB6C7138AAC1C"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this subsection:</text><subparagraph id="H91D45BB804CB4C4C9933671089E2957D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Affiliate</header><text>The term <quote>affiliate</quote> means, with respect to any pharmacy benefit manager or PDP sponsor, any entity that, directly or indirectly—</text><clause id="H1E5854DE339245D8A1AE2C708781D01C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>owns or is owned by, controls or is controlled by, or is otherwise related in any ownership structure to such pharmacy benefit manager or PDP sponsor; or</text></clause><clause id="HDAB89D5DCC00484FB36EED82B322234B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>acts as a contractor, principal, or agent to such pharmacy benefit manager or PDP sponsor, insofar as such contractor, principal, or agent performs any of the functions described under subparagraph (C).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H297CE0A47C374E1FAA0FDC8012A24554"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Bona fide service fee</header><text>The term <quote>bona fide service fee</quote> means a fee that is reflective of the fair market value (as specified by the Secretary, through notice and comment rulemaking) for a bona fide, itemized service actually performed on behalf of an entity, that the entity would otherwise perform (or contract for) in the absence of the service arrangement and that is not passed on in whole or in part to a client or customer, whether or not the entity takes title to the drug. Such fee must be a flat dollar amount and shall not be directly or indirectly based on, or contingent upon—</text><clause id="H87BAAF412F6345B1BDD5F9B0939C975D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>drug price, such as wholesale acquisition cost or drug benchmark price (such as average wholesale price);</text></clause><clause id="HB6CBA7E640CD4C419DA012F76A6F5C1E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the amount of discounts, rebates, fees, or other direct or indirect remuneration with respect to covered part D drugs dispensed to enrollees in a prescription drug plan, except as permitted pursuant to paragraph (1)(A)(ii);</text></clause><clause id="HEDC109CC26484F36AAB9FEAB12949DE9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>coverage or formulary placement decisions or the volume or value of any referrals or business generated between the parties to the arrangement; or</text></clause><clause id="H3E396047E2AB43139D250DA002150AF5"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>any other amounts or methodologies prohibited by the Secretary.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFB4347FFE8B84942B754B2B8786ED5F3"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Pharmacy benefit manager</header><text>The term <quote>pharmacy benefit manager</quote> means any person or entity that, either directly or through an intermediary, acts as a price negotiator or group purchaser on behalf of a PDP sponsor or prescription drug plan, or manages the prescription drug benefits provided by such sponsor or plan, including the processing and payment of claims for prescription drugs, the performance of drug utilization review, the processing of drug prior authorization requests, the adjudication of appeals or grievances related to the prescription drug benefit, contracting with network pharmacies, controlling the cost of covered part D drugs, or the provision of related services. Such term includes any person or entity that carries out one or more of the activities described in the preceding sentence, irrespective of whether such person or entity calls itself a <quote>pharmacy benefit manager</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="HE7F0650FB43B44DB8C2BD1977C046B4B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>M<enum-in-header>A</enum-in-header>–<enum-in-header>PD</enum-in-header> plans</header><text>Section 1857(f)(3) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-27">42 U.S.C. 1395w–27(f)(3)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HEF06DC40AC034E0BA46D928EBF28BEF7" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="H74E6F6D69B3F4321ABD207D9DF376DC6"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Requirements relating to pharmacy benefit managers</header><text>For plan years beginning on or after January 1, 2028, section 1860D–12(h).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="HB05EDC1DEED341ECAA5E22F33BB3207C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Nonapplication of paperwork reduction act</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/44/35">Chapter 35</external-xref> of title 44, United States Code, shall not apply to the implementation of this subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H638FB3924A7643AAB556D737356FE824"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Funding</header><subparagraph id="H6467A5415C8F45E192CF251D694EAA65"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>In addition to amounts otherwise available, there is appropriated to the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services Program Management Account, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, $113,000,000 for fiscal year 2025, to remain available until expended, to carry out this subsection.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6EA32CEAF92740878F14EB0487EBE760"><enum>(B)</enum><header>O<enum-in-header>IG</enum-in-header></header><text>In addition to amounts otherwise available, there is appropriated to the Inspector General of the Department of Health and Human Services, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, $20,000,000 for fiscal year 2025, to remain available until expended, to carry out this subsection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA822AA7DD819473BAF1584C09DEEA4F6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Gao study and report on price-Related compensation across the supply
 chain</header><paragraph id="HA455A8B32F494037A68BE561D8521CB5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Study</header><text>The Comptroller General of the United States (in this subsection referred to as the <quote>Comptroller General</quote>) shall conduct a study describing the use of compensation and payment structures related to a prescription drug’s price within the retail prescription drug supply chain in part D of title XVIII of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-101">42 U.S.C. 1395w–101 et seq.</external-xref>). Such study shall summarize information from Federal agencies and industry experts, to the extent available, with respect to the following:</text><subparagraph id="HFB04EA7803434B27B32BCD29BE39F1DD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The type, magnitude, other features (such as the pricing benchmarks used), and prevalence of compensation and payment structures related to a prescription drug’s price, such as calculating fee amounts as a percentage of a prescription drug’s price, between intermediaries in the prescription drug supply chain, including—</text><clause id="H0EB36ED7C93946339A27622877936389"><enum>(i)</enum><text>pharmacy benefit managers;</text></clause><clause id="HDC70B3E1C1524695AFE43AE0DEDB9982"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>PDP sponsors offering prescription drug plans and Medicare Advantage organizations offering MA–PD plans;</text></clause><clause id="H0B0DF0FD5BA7437EA052425B30F13210"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>drug wholesalers;</text></clause><clause id="H9B723A1FC359468DA8C3FEFE87BEB6A6"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>pharmacies;</text></clause><clause id="H08A95099589D46E792047D7A45BF6448"><enum>(v)</enum><text>manufacturers;</text></clause><clause id="HFC8F4DB90A544FC291C846EC07E7E75A"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>pharmacy services administrative organizations;</text></clause><clause id="H8FC74771744543A8A50B186F1E15A62E"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>brokers, auditors, consultants, and other entities that—</text><subclause id="HC4985ECDE53247B58D2F91CF6C29D518"><enum>(I)</enum><text>advise PDP sponsors offering prescription drug plans and Medicare Advantage organizations offering MA–PD plans regarding pharmacy benefits; or</text></subclause><subclause id="HC16CD28463394E228989765B6C643061"><enum>(II)</enum><text>review PDP sponsor and Medicare Advantage organization contracts with pharmacy benefit managers; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HDB3728CB16FC4DEA88B2CB2BECE8C730"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>other service providers that contract with any of the entities described in clauses (i) through (vii) that may use price-related compensation and payment structures, such as rebate aggregators (or other entities that negotiate or process price concessions on behalf of pharmacy benefit managers, plan sponsors, or pharmacies).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H826E2730FA1647738991CD583E2DF630"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The primary business models and compensation structures for each category of intermediary described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H38128ADCF11D42D381BAAAAC9502725F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Variation in price-related compensation structures between affiliated entities (such as entities with common ownership, either full or partial, and subsidiary relationships) and unaffiliated entities.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBC877706FD0A4C9F891AA5D7CD9402D5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Potential conflicts of interest among contracting entities related to the use of prescription drug price-related compensation structures, such as the potential for fees or other payments set as a percentage of a prescription drug’s price to advantage formulary selection, distribution, or purchasing of prescription drugs with higher prices.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H79CE6839F2D1417298180CF65039F5E9"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Notable differences, if any, in the use and level of price-based compensation structures over time and between different market segments, such as under part D of title XVIII of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-101">42 U.S.C. 1395w–101 et seq.</external-xref>) and the Medicaid program under title XIX of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396">42 U.S.C. 1396 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8091F4C813F342A9A1B4324FD2308FC5"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The effects of drug price-related compensation structures and alternative compensation structures on Federal health care programs and program beneficiaries, including with respect to cost-sharing, premiums, Federal outlays, biosimilar and generic drug adoption and utilization, drug shortage risks, and the potential for fees set as a percentage of a drug’s price to advantage the formulary selection, distribution, or purchasing of drugs with higher prices.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H17252D323D1C40A499DD6C1657A3F768"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Other issues determined to be relevant and appropriate by the Comptroller General.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7DEB0DBC5CDD4197891BEBB72E054DFC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this section, the Comptroller General shall submit to Congress a report containing the results of the study conducted under paragraph (1), together with recommendations for such legislation and administrative action as the Comptroller General determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H721B22868FC54C828CF1089E1D240247"><enum>(c)</enum><header>MedPAC reports on agreements with pharmacy benefit managers with respect to
 prescription drug plans and MA–PD plans</header><paragraph id="HF82621BF3AAC4F9F8E45B45DD3A6DEFD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Medicare Payment Advisory Commission shall submit to Congress the following reports:</text><subparagraph id="H0B6AF4C95FFA4679890D9CE440B1FFE0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Initial report</header><text>Not later than the first March 15 occurring after the date that is 2 years after the date on which the Secretary makes the data available to the Commission, a report regarding agreements with pharmacy benefit managers with respect to prescription drug plans and MA–PD plans. Such report shall include, to the extent practicable—</text><clause id="H070F32D6A1DD4F9F97F9DBC3F7BE1612"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a description of trends and patterns, including relevant averages, totals, and other figures for the types of information submitted;</text></clause><clause id="H02270A6CFDF94D3EAEB847B8AE6AB0B1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an analysis of any differences in agreements and their effects on plan enrollee out-of-pocket spending and average pharmacy reimbursement, and other impacts; and</text></clause><clause id="HCE307D2F74CB486E840DFCD391A12437"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any recommendations the Commission determines appropriate.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1505C854049849A5A43556D002DC87FF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Final report</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date on which the Commission submits the initial report under subparagraph (A), a report describing any changes with respect to the information described in subparagraph (A) over time, together with any recommendations the Commission determines appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3D3A459B33A546C48145136EA196B53B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>In addition to amounts otherwise available, there is appropriated to the Medicare Payment Advisory Commission, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, $1,000,000 for fiscal year 2025, to remain available until expended, to carry out this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H4DFB120B3BBB4B5CB9DEF192CD338F0C"><enum>4.</enum><header>Oversight of pharmacy benefit management services</header><subsection id="H7828427C723A4328B168E2BF0D2E7F95"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Public health service act</header><text>Title XXVII of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg">42 U.S.C. 300gg et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H780585337E81443CB024202A81A766D9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in part D (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg-111">42 U.S.C. 300gg–111 et seq.</external-xref>), by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block id="H7946BB65F0A54157AFC1C2D4AEA9D30F" style="OLC"><section id="HEB0F5543B67245CBB807AF50B9F70B4F"><enum>2799A–11.</enum><header>Oversight of entities that provide pharmacy benefit management
 services</header><subsection id="HBC5B32FFEB7F445188C99669227611E3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For plan years beginning on or after the date that is 30 months after the date of enactment of this section (referred to in this subsection and subsection (b) as the <quote>effective date</quote>), a group health plan or a health insurance issuer offering group health insurance coverage, or an entity providing pharmacy benefit management services on behalf of such a plan or issuer, shall not enter into a contract, including an extension or renewal of a contract, entered into on or after the effective date, with an applicable entity unless such applicable entity agrees to—</text><paragraph id="H9F5089A6842F44709BB4FACB3F7B2656"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not limit or delay the disclosure of information to the group health plan (including such a plan offered through a health insurance issuer) in such a manner that prevents an entity providing pharmacy benefit management services on behalf of a group health plan or health insurance issuer offering group health insurance coverage from making the reports described in subsection (b); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD037A72C21D449BCACF7ABD1DB0D54D2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide the entity providing pharmacy benefit management services on behalf of a group health plan or health insurance issuer relevant information necessary to make the reports described in subsection (b).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDCFE43736AE345BAB17E1F69A3D79D6B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reports</header><paragraph id="H3C6BB7D55B0641B1A06B9D0D2C6ADD69"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For plan years beginning on or after the effective date, in the case of any contract between a group health plan or a health insurance issuer offering group health insurance coverage offered in connection with such a plan and an entity providing pharmacy benefit management services on behalf of such plan or issuer, including an extension or renewal of such a contract, entered into on or after the effective date, the entity providing pharmacy benefit management services on behalf of such a group health plan or health insurance issuer, not less frequently than every 6 months (or, at the request of a group health plan, not less frequently than quarterly, and under the same conditions, terms, and cost of the semiannual report under this subsection), shall submit to the group health plan a report in accordance with this section. Each such report shall be made available to such group health plan in plain language, in a machine-readable format, and as the Secretary may determine, other formats. Each such report shall include the information described in paragraph (2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC4EDA9EB7756444FA3AB9C3BCAA2D552"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Information described</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (1), the information described in this paragraph is, with respect to drugs covered by a group health plan or group health insurance coverage offered by a health insurance issuer in connection with a group health plan during each reporting period—</text><subparagraph id="HEB7CB2B3C519458285EE09BBE4D7B6A5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case of a group health plan that is offered by a specified large employer or that is a specified large plan, and is not offered as health insurance coverage, or in the case of health insurance coverage for which the election under paragraph (3) is made for the applicable reporting period—</text><clause id="H4FAED886D56845B2B64E123CF0A0755B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a list of drugs for which a claim was filed and, with respect to each such drug on such list—</text><subclause id="H6D06AAA8A9B64755A75348C2A2062571"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the contracted compensation paid by the group health plan or health insurance issuer for each covered drug (identified by the National Drug Code) to the entity providing pharmacy benefit management services or other applicable entity on behalf of the group health plan or health insurance issuer;</text></subclause><subclause id="H81A20B3092BC4FA689256BC462CFC04C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the contracted compensation paid to the pharmacy, by any entity providing pharmacy benefit management services or other applicable entity on behalf of the group health plan or health insurance issuer, for each covered drug (identified by the National Drug Code);</text></subclause><subclause id="HA91F9A1C882D4E97888DD6A973646F9D"><enum>(III)</enum><text>for each such claim, the difference between the amount paid under subclause (I) and the amount paid under subclause (II);</text></subclause><subclause id="H9A82877CE72F4CC68629F8186340D780"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the proprietary name, established name or proper name, and National Drug Code;</text></subclause><subclause id="H621F3A342B264B5EBAB68682F2927CFC"><enum>(V)</enum><text>for each claim for the drug (including original prescriptions and refills) and for each dosage unit of the drug for which a claim was filed, the type of dispensing channel used to furnish the drug, including retail, mail order, or specialty pharmacy;</text></subclause><subclause id="H67A651704CC84E01B7360DA72B737115"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>with respect to each drug dispensed, for each type of dispensing channel (including retail, mail order, or specialty pharmacy)—</text><item id="HB3681B8EB82D46B3BDBA35EF8BDA6F92"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>whether such drug is a brand name drug or a generic drug, and—</text><subitem id="H81DF5D48AAD04AE9B20E4347911EA5CF"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>in the case of a brand name drug, the wholesale acquisition cost, listed as cost per days supply and cost per dosage unit, on the date such drug was dispensed; and</text></subitem><subitem id="HA978497B44DF42EE86CE655A1B1B15BF"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>in the case of a generic drug, the average wholesale price, listed as cost per days supply and cost per dosage unit, on the date such drug was dispensed; and</text></subitem></item><item id="H562AE0E217EA4C82826C94F9C441546D"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the total number of—</text><subitem id="H0986F5D4FCC64E47A989C5390669B1C2"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>prescription claims (including original prescriptions and refills);</text></subitem><subitem id="HB2ADC00ED2B149D791F3440FC3C0FCA3"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>participants and beneficiaries for whom a claim for such drug was filed through the applicable dispensing channel;</text></subitem><subitem id="H09E90B6A0E774F28ADD8A80D6CEE3528"><enum>(CC)</enum><text>dosage units and dosage units per fill of such drug; and</text></subitem><subitem id="H25383D8B837E4491A874BF0C572E47B5"><enum>(DD)</enum><text>days supply of such drug per fill;</text></subitem></item></subclause><subclause id="HB6BDEAD4B1A246EA8137B554D0E98EBD"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>the net price per course of treatment or single fill, such as a 30-day supply or 90-day supply to the plan or coverage after rebates, fees, alternative discounts, or other remuneration received from applicable entities;</text></subclause><subclause id="H96DACABBB34241FB85F587C5336190B4"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text>the total amount of out-of-pocket spending by participants and beneficiaries on such drug, including spending through copayments, coinsurance, and deductibles, but not including any amounts spent by participants and beneficiaries on drugs not covered under the plan or coverage, or for which no claim is submitted under the plan or coverage;</text></subclause><subclause id="HEAC5574D0B96444B9EFFB450D4D81E5F"><enum>(IX)</enum><text>the total net spending on the drug;</text></subclause><subclause id="HD82A14B9FFF346B6A6F46A0B47EFE85C"><enum>(X)</enum><text>the total amount received, or expected to be received, by the plan or issuer from any applicable entity in rebates, fees, alternative discounts, or other remuneration;</text></subclause><subclause id="H91699C9BE4824D6A98199A17B567E2B3"><enum>(XI)</enum><text>the total amount received, or expected to be received, by the entity providing pharmacy benefit management services, from applicable entities, in rebates, fees, alternative discounts, or other remuneration from such entities—</text><item id="H2FA77E44819846EFB8E6A086E090A4AD"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>for claims incurred during the reporting period; and</text></item><item id="H77F6F6EC2B40441EB4CE9B63693E353E"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>that is related to utilization of such drug or spending on such drug; and</text></item></subclause><subclause id="HAC53A3C74AC14FC38D08FAA312AD47FA"><enum>(XII)</enum><text>to the extent feasible, information on the total amount of remuneration for such drug, including copayment assistance dollars paid, copayment cards applied, or other discounts provided by each drug manufacturer (or entity administering copayment assistance on behalf of such drug manufacturer), to the participants and beneficiaries enrolled in such plan or coverage;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H98075DE131894345B5670DDAA83A13CB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a list of each therapeutic class (as defined by the Secretary) for which a claim was filed under the group health plan or health insurance coverage during the reporting period, and, with respect to each such therapeutic class—</text><subclause id="H42ABE96E68BB415E8BF82EA8BE667A18"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the total gross spending on drugs in such class before rebates, price concessions, alternative discounts, or other remuneration from applicable entities;</text></subclause><subclause id="H6BDCABED72944767AA6C6DDD118832E7"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the net spending in such class after such rebates, price concessions, alternative discounts, or other remuneration from applicable entities;</text></subclause><subclause id="H2E4E09B90870409491D80BD496830F55"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the total amount received, or expected to be received, by the entity providing pharmacy benefit management services, from applicable entities, in rebates, fees, alternative discounts, or other remuneration from such entities—</text><item id="H693B53D17B3C43898753AE0A2E413E55"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>for claims incurred during the reporting period; and</text></item><item id="H6D9A9C0C527A4E39A782B2A1B7930459"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>that is related to utilization of drugs or drug spending;</text></item></subclause><subclause id="H89FD68C6DCF24836940D0BC04A6544B3"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the average net spending per 30-day supply and per 90-day supply by the plan or by the issuer with respect to such coverage and its participants and beneficiaries, among all drugs within the therapeutic class for which a claim was filed during the reporting period;</text></subclause><subclause id="HCF3F28CE311C490FAB7CBEA199B2E5DB"><enum>(V)</enum><text>the number of participants and beneficiaries who filled a prescription for a drug in such class, including the National Drug Code for each such drug;</text></subclause><subclause id="H931FED80A89C4B5BBC63AFD0C97CEEE8"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>if applicable, a description of the formulary tiers and utilization mechanisms (such as prior authorization or step therapy) employed for drugs in that class; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H15A4BE49EC2B4C569F2ED8EE6CD8F416"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>the total out-of-pocket spending under the plan or coverage by participants and beneficiaries, including spending through copayments, coinsurance, and deductibles, but not including any amounts spent by participants and beneficiaries on drugs not covered under the plan or coverage or for which no claim is submitted under the plan or coverage;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HEDDBF7BCA16644A6BB9ED0486517DAB8"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>with respect to any drug for which gross spending under the group health plan or health insurance coverage exceeded $10,000 during the reporting period or, in the case that gross spending under the group health plan or coverage exceeded $10,000 during the reporting period with respect to fewer than 50 drugs, with respect to the 50 prescription drugs with the highest spending during the reporting period—</text><subclause id="H85DBDE61AA054381A1F80989DF94BAA8"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a list of all other drugs in the same therapeutic class as such drug;</text></subclause><subclause id="HBDFF99C120AF4FD79EA9D5F1E47CC6E6"><enum>(II)</enum><text>if applicable, the rationale for the formulary placement of such drug in that therapeutic category or class, selected from a list of standard rationales established by the Secretary, in consultation with stakeholders; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H54340CEA125E4E6095294DD1BFF02D19"><enum>(III)</enum><text>any change in formulary placement compared to the prior plan year; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H0A9383C0FA734019A18F8E2A33837015"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>in the case that such plan or issuer (or an entity providing pharmacy benefit management services on behalf of such plan or issuer) has an affiliated pharmacy or pharmacy under common ownership, including mandatory mail and specialty home delivery programs, retail and mail auto-refill programs, and cost-sharing assistance incentives funded by an entity providing pharmacy benefit services—</text><subclause id="H4A6A370DE1844DC9917769EACC3C5469"><enum>(I)</enum><text>an explanation of any benefit design parameters that encourage or require participants and beneficiaries in the plan or coverage to fill prescriptions at mail order, specialty, or retail pharmacies;</text></subclause><subclause id="H97E379612B9240E3922A0754F70B3EBA"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the percentage of total prescriptions dispensed by such pharmacies to participants or beneficiaries in such plan or coverage; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H315389DAE0B84A7BBC42876278D344C9"><enum>(III)</enum><text>a list of all drugs dispensed by such pharmacies to participants or beneficiaries enrolled in such plan or coverage, and, with respect to each drug dispensed—</text><item id="HEB117AC2C90E48479B13281F4CBE928B"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the amount charged, per dosage unit, per 30-day supply, or per 90-day supply (as applicable) to the plan or issuer, and to participants and beneficiaries;</text></item><item id="H85FC3048704B4826BA6F47D8CF46090D"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the median amount charged to such plan or issuer, and the interquartile range of the costs, per dosage unit, per 30-day supply, and per 90-day supply, including amounts paid by the participants and beneficiaries, when the same drug is dispensed by other pharmacies that are not affiliated with or under common ownership with the entity and that are included in the pharmacy network of such plan or coverage;</text></item><item id="HA751538A5CE342319D1C90C0CC783B57"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>the lowest cost per dosage unit, per 30-day supply and per 90-day supply, for each such drug, including amounts charged to the plan or coverage and to participants and beneficiaries, that is available from any pharmacy included in the network of such plan or coverage; and</text></item><item id="H0135FAA9D7044933BCD8D83E4706C97A"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>the net acquisition cost per dosage unit, per 30-day supply, and per 90-day supply, if such drug is subject to a maximum price discount; and</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H06642BA12058499185B9E3FC617CE336"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to any group health plan, including group health insurance coverage offered in connection with such a plan, regardless of whether the plan or coverage is offered by a specified large employer or whether it is a specified large plan—</text><clause id="H48252402FBA246EC9A6AE3C190FED864"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a summary document for the group health plan that includes such information described in clauses (i) through (iv) of subparagraph (A), as specified by the Secretary through guidance, program instruction, or otherwise (with no requirement of notice and comment rulemaking), that the Secretary determines useful to group health plans for purposes of selecting pharmacy benefit management services, such as an estimated net price to group health plan and participant or beneficiary, a cost per claim, the fee structure or reimbursement model, and estimated cost per participant or beneficiary;</text></clause><clause id="HB42E6424D8E0461BA03C48CD6DE15276"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a summary document for plans and issuers to provide to participants and beneficiaries, which shall be made available to participants or beneficiaries upon request to their group health plan (including in the case of group health insurance coverage offered in connection with such a plan), that—</text><subclause id="HD8D2AC926D4B4AD7B5E0CF05E8A07C53"><enum>(I)</enum><text>contains such information described in clauses (iii), (iv), (v), and (vi), as applicable, as specified by the Secretary through guidance, program instruction, or otherwise (with no requirement of notice and comment rulemaking) that the Secretary determines useful to participants or beneficiaries in better understanding the plan or coverage or benefits under such plan or coverage;</text></subclause><subclause id="H879E0077485449ADBCF391E40779B229"><enum>(II)</enum><text>contains only aggregate information; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HEF23995CD27143AB964F10A8D991730C"><enum>(III)</enum><text>states that participants and beneficiaries may request specific, claims-level information required to be furnished under subsection (c) from the group health plan or health insurance issuer; </text></subclause></clause><clause id="HCD5888B9241C4A38A74033636F92CC9D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>with respect to drugs covered by such plan or coverage during such reporting period—</text><subclause id="H71630C4DC7364EE8897E655AEFCD4F39"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the total net spending by the plan or coverage for all such drugs;</text></subclause><subclause id="HCCC2FCF4A255463380FEDDB84E0F60C5"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the total amount received, or expected to be received, by the plan or issuer from any applicable entity in rebates, fees, alternative discounts, or other remuneration; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H901DCF6A285E4401AB9C7597B68F73C7"><enum>(III)</enum><text>to the extent feasible, information on the total amount of remuneration for such drugs, including copayment assistance dollars paid, copayment cards applied, or other discounts provided by each drug manufacturer (or entity administering copayment assistance on behalf of such drug manufacturer) to participants and beneficiaries;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HA44BFFE299FF42EBB303509B35DC81F0"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>amounts paid directly or indirectly in rebates, fees, or any other type of compensation (as defined in section 408(b)(2)(B)(ii)(dd)(AA) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act) to brokerage firms, brokers, consultants, advisors, or any other individual or firm, for—</text><subclause id="H844E53BECAF4457BBBC75AEDAC114530"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the referral of the group health plan’s or health insurance issuer’s business to an entity providing pharmacy benefit management services, including the identity of the recipient of such amounts;</text></subclause><subclause id="H5393E82A4A15402ABD64FD1DBCB26024"><enum>(II)</enum><text>consideration of the entity providing pharmacy benefit management services by the group health plan or health insurance issuer; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H5198EF27934E41CD94F4DB7E7325508C"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the retention of the entity by the group health plan or health insurance issuer;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H5239213D2CEA44118B6C527134B80872"><enum>(v)</enum><text>an explanation of any benefit design parameters that encourage or require participants and beneficiaries in such plan or coverage to fill prescriptions at mail order, specialty, or retail pharmacies that are affiliated with or under common ownership with the entity providing pharmacy benefit management services under such plan or coverage, including mandatory mail and specialty home delivery programs, retail and mail auto-refill programs, and cost-sharing assistance incentives directly or indirectly funded by such entity; and</text></clause><clause id="H3737EBC69D36456EBC86C715E8A52149"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>total gross spending on all drugs under the plan or coverage during the reporting period.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2748E737F2DD400F8C405C7095000C08"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Opt-in for group health insurance coverage offered by a
                                        specified large employer or that is a specified large
 plan</header><text>In the case of group health insurance coverage offered in connection with a group health plan that is offered by a specified large employer or is a specified large plan, such group health plan may, on an annual basis, for plan years beginning on or after the date that is 30 months after the date of enactment of this section, elect to require an entity providing pharmacy benefit management services on behalf of the health insurance issuer to submit to such group health plan a report that includes all of the information described in paragraph (2)(A), in addition to the information described in paragraph (2)(B).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAC2832C1470040CF8A99FEDA642A5607"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Privacy requirements</header><subparagraph id="H510BBCAEA6484A9DA9009D46BD98197E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An entity providing pharmacy benefit management services on behalf of a group health plan or a health insurance issuer offering group health insurance coverage shall report information under paragraph (1) in a manner consistent with the privacy regulations promulgated under section 13402(a) of the Health Information Technology for Economic and Clinical Health Act and consistent with the privacy regulations promulgated under the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 in part 160 and subparts A and E of part 164 of title 45, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations) (referred to in this paragraph as the <quote>HIPAA privacy regulations</quote>) and shall restrict the use and disclosure of such information according to such privacy regulations and such HIPAA privacy regulations.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9E56D2497A4C42B7BCF1BAC99919E8D9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Additional requirements</header><clause id="H1A9DC7FD9F7E439398A1D8E5B14CBA8E"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An entity providing pharmacy benefit management services on behalf of a group health plan or health insurance issuer offering group health insurance coverage that submits a report under paragraph (1) shall ensure that such report contains only summary health information, as defined in section 164.504(a) of title 45, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).</text></clause><clause id="HE62531A0DA91435E9B5F6B1741FEEBF0"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Restrictions</header><text>In carrying out this subsection, a group health plan shall comply with section 164.504(f) of title 45, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation), and a plan sponsor shall act in accordance with the terms of the agreement described in such section.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7F6C3F7591704547B63DB762DD7D2F9E"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><clause id="H7CF5505059E94A02BDF88F96C613250B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to modify the requirements for the creation, receipt, maintenance, or transmission of protected health information under the HIPAA privacy regulations.</text></clause><clause id="idA2539C11733742508845A3048085DF4C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to affect the application of any Federal or State privacy or civil rights law, including the HIPAA privacy regulations, the Genetic Information Nondiscrimination Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/233">Public Law 110–233</external-xref>) (including the amendments made by such Act), the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12101">42 U.S.C. 12101 et seq.</external-xref>), section 504 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/794">29 U.S.C. 794</external-xref>), section 1557 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18116">42 U.S.C. 18116</external-xref>), title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d">42 U.S.C. 2000d</external-xref>), and title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000e">42 U.S.C. 2000e</external-xref>). </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8B93B22B103044F0B23D6B0E8EA01744"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Written notice</header><text>Each plan year, group health plans, including with respect to group health insurance coverage offered in connection with a group health plan, shall provide to each participant or beneficiary written notice informing the participant or beneficiary of the requirement for entities providing pharmacy benefit management services on behalf of the group health plan or health insurance issuer offering group health insurance coverage to submit reports to group health plans under paragraph (1), as applicable, which may include incorporating such notification in plan documents provided to the participant or beneficiary, or providing individual notification.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H14BEC2F4A78A400D9D546C7033FB164D"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Limitation to business associates</header><text>A group health plan receiving a report under paragraph (1) may disclose such information only to the entity from which the report was received or to that entity’s business associates as defined in section 160.103 of title 45, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations) or as permitted by the HIPAA privacy regulations.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7A8575CC97E24266B3F5C8BE40AEF0A9"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Clarification regarding public disclosure of
 information</header><text>Nothing in this section shall prevent an entity providing pharmacy benefit management services on behalf of a group health plan or health insurance issuer offering group health insurance coverage, from placing reasonable restrictions on the public disclosure of the information contained in a report described in paragraph (1), except that such plan, issuer, or entity may not—</text><clause id="HBB12898B51F94E3CBE0061A3B50D0A41"><enum>(i)</enum><text>restrict disclosure of such report to the Department of Health and Human Services, the Department of Labor, or the Department of the Treasury; or</text></clause><clause id="H1247249112704AD482CD15EB6F7F1450"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>prevent disclosure for the purposes of subsection (c), or any other public disclosure requirement under this section.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H242C584359A741A9B2068A48205BA4E2"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Limited form of report</header><text>The Secretary shall define through rulemaking a limited form of the report under paragraph (1) required with respect to any group health plan established by a plan sponsor that is, or is affiliated with, a drug manufacturer, drug wholesaler, or other direct participant in the drug supply chain, in order to prevent anti-competitive behavior.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFC2EA366ED67486DA39D4B647175F1D2"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Standard format and regulations</header><subparagraph id="HCDDF23C1ECEA46658F737012A05EB9BF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary shall specify through rulemaking a standard format for entities providing pharmacy benefit management services on behalf of group health plans and health insurance issuers offering group health insurance coverage, to submit reports required under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF67AB1CB1B994684B616BDA1259FADBA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Additional regulations</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary shall, through rulemaking, promulgate any other final regulations necessary to implement the requirements of this section. In promulgating such regulations, the Secretary shall, to the extent practicable, align the reporting requirements under this section with the reporting requirements under section 2799A–10.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1FBB792B6DB047CD9E2C45C9386545F6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Requirement To provide information to participants or
 beneficiaries</header><text>A group health plan, including with respect to group health insurance coverage offered in connection with a group health plan, upon request of a participant or beneficiary, shall provide to such participant or beneficiary—</text><paragraph id="H7CBB29BD86184A968ABDCD0C12691731"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the summary document described in subsection (b)(2)(B)(ii); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H146CD9D619964EC59CF79AD2CFE6893C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the information described in subsection (b)(2)(A)(i)(III) with respect to a claim made by or on behalf of such participant or beneficiary.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFB5F40D9EDD84655AAD14BF7176A81C4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><paragraph id="H76BE921A77944DDBB07CC8F5CD01721E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall enforce this section. The enforcement authority under this subsection shall apply only with respect to group health plans (including group health insurance coverage offered in connection with such a plan) to which the requirements of subparts I and II of part A and part D apply in accordance with section 2722, and with respect to entities providing pharmacy benefit management services on behalf of such plans and applicable entities providing services on behalf of such plans.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE66FBF6D16304E2A8807A717478A707D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Failure to provide information</header><text>A group health plan, a health insurance issuer offering group health insurance coverage, an entity providing pharmacy benefit management services on behalf of such a plan or issuer, or an applicable entity providing services on behalf of such a plan or issuer that violates subsection (a); an entity providing pharmacy benefit management services on behalf of such a plan or issuer that fails to provide the information required under subsection (b); or a group health plan that fails to provide the information required under subsection (c), shall be subject to a civil monetary penalty in the amount of $10,000 for each day during which such violation continues or such information is not disclosed or reported.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3411C81CFE984738BE0DF2D6698E3A59"><enum>(3)</enum><header>False information</header><text>A health insurance issuer, an entity providing pharmacy benefit management services, or a third party administrator providing services on behalf of such issuer offered by a health insurance issuer that knowingly provides false information under this section shall be subject to a civil monetary penalty in an amount not to exceed $100,000 for each item of false information. Such civil monetary penalty shall be in addition to other penalties as may be prescribed by law.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0D766CEACA2E4384BDEC7E5D0B759681"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Procedure</header><text>The provisions of section 1128A of the Social Security Act, other than subsections (a) and (b) and the first sentence of subsection (c)(1) of such section shall apply to civil monetary penalties under this subsection in the same manner as such provisions apply to a penalty or proceeding under such section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5E1DC8334B5A4CA2ACC58B1CED789A11"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Waivers</header><text>The Secretary may waive penalties under paragraph (2), or extend the period of time for compliance with a requirement of this section, for an entity in violation of this section that has made a good-faith effort to comply with the requirements in this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2E133CC142364EC78EF66F088B05E188"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to permit a health insurance issuer, group health plan, entity providing pharmacy benefit management services on behalf of a group health plan or health insurance issuer, or other entity to restrict disclosure to, or otherwise limit the access of, the Secretary to a report described in subsection (b)(1) or information related to compliance with subsections (a), (b), (c), or (d) by such issuer, plan, or entity.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF8FA06F7C8EA4BD2BE1C023E80E9F392"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H94F3B35497DF4E4D9F32F5D889411FC1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Applicable entity</header><text>The term <quote>applicable entity</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="HDD2CFBABB3634542BFC602BD394C002F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an applicable group purchasing organization, drug manufacturer, distributor, wholesaler, rebate aggregator (or other purchasing entity designed to aggregate rebates), or associated third party;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2F3863FCA25F413D894527F79C6A173B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any subsidiary, parent, affiliate, or subcontractor of a group health plan, health insurance issuer, entity that provides pharmacy benefit management services on behalf of such a plan or issuer, or any entity described in subparagraph (A); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA1CB3C92D43B4B8BA137B2975ED60760"><enum>(C)</enum><text>such other entity as the Secretary may specify through rulemaking.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H909699FAAA3C462D89C0393523C24C51"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applicable group purchasing organization</header><text>The term <quote>applicable group purchasing organization</quote> means a group purchasing organization that is affiliated with or under common ownership with an entity providing pharmacy benefit management services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE3B6A3EBF47643008988982D962FCE2E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Contracted compensation</header><text>The term <quote>contracted compensation</quote> means the sum of any ingredient cost and dispensing fee for a drug (inclusive of the out-of-pocket costs to the participant or beneficiary), or another analogous compensation structure that the Secretary may specify through regulations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9CE51B5EB7B840B7BC36D97B7B3269F9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Gross spending</header><text>The term <quote>gross spending</quote>, with respect to prescription drug benefits under a group health plan or health insurance coverage, means the amount spent by a group health plan or health insurance issuer on prescription drug benefits, calculated before the application of rebates, fees, alternative discounts, or other remuneration.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H229B0F20D23E46B293F4743E04999C9A"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Net spending</header><text>The term <quote>net spending</quote>, with respect to prescription drug benefits under a group health plan or health insurance coverage, means the amount spent by a group health plan or health insurance issuer on prescription drug benefits, calculated after the application of rebates, fees, alternative discounts, or other remuneration.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB669E6D8692B404C941B2266C4AD4EE9"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Plan sponsor</header><text>The term <quote>plan sponsor</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 3(16)(B) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFE61A99719D7404F82EACEDF00424256"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Remuneration</header><text>The term <quote>remuneration</quote> has the meaning given such term by the Secretary through rulemaking, which shall be reevaluated by the Secretary every 5 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0967D8C2A1614AC8B405434317575186"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Specified large employer</header><text>The term <quote>specified large employer</quote> means, in connection with a group health plan (including group health insurance coverage offered in connection with such a plan) established or maintained by a single employer, with respect to a calendar year or a plan year, as applicable, an employer who employed an average of at least 100 employees on business days during the preceding calendar year or plan year and who employs at least 1 employee on the first day of the calendar year or plan year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1A79006CFFB9421A9B48CA7927B88149"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Specified large plan</header><text>The term <quote>specified large plan</quote> means a group health plan (including group health insurance coverage offered in connection with such a plan) established or maintained by a plan sponsor described in clause (ii) or (iii) of section 3(16)(B) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 that had an average of at least 100 participants on business days during the preceding calendar year or plan year, as applicable.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2AB9A49EA20142A38CBCBFE65D1D478F"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Wholesale acquisition cost</header><text>The term <quote>wholesale acquisition cost</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 1847A(c)(6)(B) of the Social Security Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H311B0486A3734AA1A067F5CD2FAE784F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 2723 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg-22">42 U.S.C. 300gg–22</external-xref>)—</text><subparagraph id="H44232170769B47D8A6D581CA38ECADD9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text><clause id="HA248D43CEBB34F49918B7F235CDB2019"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by inserting <quote>(other than section 2799A–11)</quote> after <quote>part D</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="HCB9FF703011F4C1F80F33A9149EB4025"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by inserting <quote>(other than section 2799A–11)</quote> after <quote>part D</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE9F59CD238BA463294C2D67DB192B778"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text><clause id="H9772ABEDBAF04839B1356598A1642912"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by inserting <quote>(other than section 2799A–11)</quote> after <quote>part D</quote>;</text></clause><clause id="H75D8391A18B14670A01FCB31D14E9CFA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)(A), by inserting <quote>(other than section 2799A–11)</quote> after <quote>part D</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="HB54D313BC1044C8BB2452073717568BF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)(C)(ii), by inserting <quote>(other than section 2799A–11)</quote> after <quote>part D</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H61BDF08B346042F995FB18E34A68E527"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Employee retirement income security act of 1974</header><paragraph id="HC74B8FFF2E74457484F616A432E4CE1B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subtitle B of title I of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1021">29 U.S.C. 1021 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="HE431BFF4E3C4414F8B6BA8AD2315D88F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subpart B of part 7 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1185">29 U.S.C. 1185 et seq.</external-xref>), by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H7F70A0B12E49467D977A64D47CAB3A66" style="OLC"><section id="H4E1DBCAB524343E599CCADBFDEAB1146"><enum>726.</enum><header>Oversight of entities that provide pharmacy benefit
 management services</header><subsection id="HF2AD618870DC4330A6D43753C8C44D80"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For plan years beginning on or after the date that is 30 months after the date of enactment of this section (referred to in this subsection and subsection (b) as the <quote>effective date</quote>), a group health plan or a health insurance issuer offering group health insurance coverage, or an entity providing pharmacy benefit management services on behalf of such a plan or issuer, shall not enter into a contract, including an extension or renewal of a contract, entered into on or after the effective date, with an applicable entity unless such applicable entity agrees to—</text><paragraph id="H63EB30A3C9604EEF8DD1D2588C90F2B0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not limit or delay the disclosure of information to the group health plan (including such a plan offered through a health insurance issuer) in such a manner that prevents an entity providing pharmacy benefit management services on behalf of a group health plan or health insurance issuer offering group health insurance coverage from making the reports described in subsection (b); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF205881A73654AFBB0252C432FE5F74C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide the entity providing pharmacy benefit management services on behalf of a group health plan or health insurance issuer relevant information necessary to make the reports described in subsection (b).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5FC8BE669866418C98B30EF453607BC0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reports</header><paragraph id="H85E089415F5B41BB9AD7BBD8EB7929E7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For plan years beginning on or after the effective date, in the case of any contract between a group health plan or a health insurance issuer offering group health insurance coverage offered in connection with such a plan and an entity providing pharmacy benefit management services on behalf of such plan or issuer, including an extension or renewal of such a contract, entered into on or after the effective date, the entity providing pharmacy benefit management services on behalf of such a group health plan or health insurance issuer, not less frequently than every 6 months (or, at the request of a group health plan, not less frequently than quarterly, and under the same conditions, terms, and cost of the semiannual report under this subsection), shall submit to the group health plan a report in accordance with this section. Each such report shall be made available to such group health plan in plain language, in a machine-readable format, and as the Secretary may determine, other formats. Each such report shall include the information described in paragraph (2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4CFEBE9D23314A6EBD41BD5CFEE8F69A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Information described</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (1), the information described in this paragraph is, with respect to drugs covered by a group health plan or group health insurance coverage offered by a health insurance issuer in connection with a group health plan during each reporting period—</text><subparagraph id="H97C6514728074C788EEE43A3067ABE62"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case of a group health plan that is offered by a specified large employer or that is a specified large plan, and is not offered as health insurance coverage, or in the case of health insurance coverage for which the election under paragraph (3) is made for the applicable reporting period—</text><clause id="HBC6C4BA822BA4A8AB30494DFA89607E4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a list of drugs for which a claim was filed and, with respect to each such drug on such list—</text><subclause id="H6D735F4822984697AE85F9B8031291C5"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the contracted compensation paid by the group health plan or health insurance issuer for each covered drug (identified by the National Drug Code) to the entity providing pharmacy benefit management services or other applicable entity on behalf of the group health plan or health insurance issuer;</text></subclause><subclause id="H511B67528E704CF98BC5AC00A34C571E"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the contracted compensation paid to the pharmacy, by any entity providing pharmacy benefit management services or other applicable entity on behalf of the group health plan or health insurance issuer, for each covered drug (identified by the National Drug Code);</text></subclause><subclause id="H732030EC39ED44BEBED01A7FFC303251"><enum>(III)</enum><text>for each such claim, the difference between the amount paid under subclause (I) and the amount paid under subclause (II);</text></subclause><subclause id="H7E067A5144AD4505A84EB4229FBD3412"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the proprietary name, established name or proper name, and National Drug Code;</text></subclause><subclause id="H248FDAC5EBD847BCA2446891C4099885"><enum>(V)</enum><text>for each claim for the drug (including original prescriptions and refills) and for each dosage unit of the drug for which a claim was filed, the type of dispensing channel used to furnish the drug, including retail, mail order, or specialty pharmacy;</text></subclause><subclause id="HD49A52CB696449A584DD849A8670A07B"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>with respect to each drug dispensed, for each type of dispensing channel (including retail, mail order, or specialty pharmacy)—</text><item id="H13CFABCDDE2341E2963DAF74B786280D"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>whether such drug is a brand name drug or a generic drug, and—</text><subitem id="HBFD80CEED2F4432598349355F17A96D2"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>in the case of a brand name drug, the wholesale acquisition cost, listed as cost per days supply and cost per dosage unit, on the date such drug was dispensed; and</text></subitem><subitem id="H9C78673FFFB34CA58424683E8F9EE0CD"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>in the case of a generic drug, the average wholesale price, listed as cost per days supply and cost per dosage unit, on the date such drug was dispensed; and</text></subitem></item><item id="H816090258D1949DD9D5BBA0085558FF2"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the total number of—</text><subitem id="H246666FABCEB4EEA8C87ED0225EA05BC"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>prescription claims (including original prescriptions and refills);</text></subitem><subitem id="H78803AE30CE349B3B549A71BDD215A74"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>participants and beneficiaries for whom a claim for such drug was filed through the applicable dispensing channel;</text></subitem><subitem id="H28204CCA627542E7B20219DFE9B2C33B"><enum>(CC)</enum><text>dosage units and dosage units per fill of such drug; and</text></subitem><subitem id="HE55286AC562A405486ADDEA05E094208"><enum>(DD)</enum><text>days supply of such drug per fill;</text></subitem></item></subclause><subclause id="idA1A796CD814D41EE8A6AF8BDD29007D0"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>the net price per course of treatment or single fill, such as a 30-day supply or 90-day supply to the plan or coverage after rebates, fees, alternative discounts, or other remuneration received from applicable entities; </text></subclause><subclause id="H04DD423F156247DC908499E01D1FF68A"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text>the total amount of out-of-pocket spending by participants and beneficiaries on such drug, including spending through copayments, coinsurance, and deductibles, but not including any amounts spent by participants and beneficiaries on drugs not covered under the plan or coverage, or for which no claim is submitted under the plan or coverage;</text></subclause><subclause id="H4912101924D546FB9444181ECCF0D1E6"><enum>(IX)</enum><text>the total net spending on the drug;</text></subclause><subclause id="H967C75E1A3844BAF9A2B4C3274853BB3"><enum>(X)</enum><text>the total amount received, or expected to be received, by the plan or issuer from any applicable entity in rebates, fees, alternative discounts, or other remuneration;</text></subclause><subclause id="H6B66F7988AD6456D9081685F9BA1A9E8"><enum>(XI)</enum><text>the total amount received, or expected to be received, by the entity providing pharmacy benefit management services, from applicable entities, in rebates, fees, alternative discounts, or other remuneration from such entities—</text><item id="H9B99909086B34CC29D70DF11B4C9B184"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>for claims incurred during the reporting period; and</text></item><item id="H7504933B869D4F22A5676A405FCB6D6C"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>that is related to utilization of such drug or spending on such drug; and</text></item></subclause><subclause id="H7BD5F7CDAAF343CAAAB550C769898093"><enum>(XII)</enum><text>to the extent feasible, information on the total amount of remuneration for such drug, including copayment assistance dollars paid, copayment cards applied, or other discounts provided by each drug manufacturer (or entity administering copayment assistance on behalf of such drug manufacturer), to the participants and beneficiaries enrolled in such plan or coverage;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H99DE3C4B9320457C82D8DA2CBF730441"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a list of each therapeutic class (as defined by the Secretary) for which a claim was filed under the group health plan or health insurance coverage during the reporting period, and, with respect to each such therapeutic class—</text><subclause id="HD17F69FC1F0E49F3B6129F4660F29F21"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the total gross spending on drugs in such class before rebates, price concessions, alternative discounts, or other remuneration from applicable entities;</text></subclause><subclause id="H3F9F5BA35920431392AA5EDCDFA4C1CE"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the net spending in such class after such rebates, price concessions, alternative discounts, or other remuneration from applicable entities;</text></subclause><subclause id="HD11364D6094F4A0C897F870C6057FF16"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the total amount received, or expected to be received, by the entity providing pharmacy benefit management services, from applicable entities, in rebates, fees, alternative discounts, or other remuneration from such entities—</text><item id="H3A0BC6CE488445ABADC2FEE87D57A330"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>for claims incurred during the reporting period; and</text></item><item id="HDFB2812FB15245EFAE30C98E8F9ECB8C"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>that is related to utilization of drugs or drug spending;</text></item></subclause><subclause id="HC21EF5D1957A4E58884D32EB381C06AE"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the average net spending per 30-day supply and per 90-day supply by the plan or by the issuer with respect to such coverage and its participants and beneficiaries, among all drugs within the therapeutic class for which a claim was filed during the reporting period;</text></subclause><subclause id="H9D5496F748604C119975030BC52A000D"><enum>(V)</enum><text>the number of participants and beneficiaries who filled a prescription for a drug in such class, including the National Drug Code for each such drug;</text></subclause><subclause id="H1C40358B8F9A41B09FECFA56869055D0"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>if applicable, a description of the formulary tiers and utilization mechanisms (such as prior authorization or step therapy) employed for drugs in that class; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HBC4790ED7AAD4A23BD6B512B4AA2A2BB"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>the total out-of-pocket spending under the plan or coverage by participants and beneficiaries, including spending through copayments, coinsurance, and deductibles, but not including any amounts spent by participants and beneficiaries on drugs not covered under the plan or coverage or for which no claim is submitted under the plan or coverage;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H0DDDD3888F4E42D7A292FAB389ECA755"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>with respect to any drug for which gross spending under the group health plan or health insurance coverage exceeded $10,000 during the reporting period or, in the case that gross spending under the group health plan or coverage exceeded $10,000 during the reporting period with respect to fewer than 50 drugs, with respect to the 50 prescription drugs with the highest spending during the reporting period—</text><subclause id="HF34670EDAB05486B9C6076B063CE86BE"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a list of all other drugs in the same therapeutic class as such drug;</text></subclause><subclause id="H691AC9EA522E4B0497C48F50069807C6"><enum>(II)</enum><text>if applicable, the rationale for the formulary placement of such drug in that therapeutic category or class, selected from a list of standard rationales established by the Secretary, in consultation with stakeholders; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H6D62157754E348B0BE45B1727B0A37FB"><enum>(III)</enum><text>any change in formulary placement compared to the prior plan year; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HA80C2CF35CED48C198382A73F20D5C0C"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>in the case that such plan or issuer (or an entity providing pharmacy benefit management services on behalf of such plan or issuer) has an affiliated pharmacy or pharmacy under common ownership, including mandatory mail and specialty home delivery programs, retail and mail auto-refill programs, and cost sharing assistance incentives funded by an entity providing pharmacy benefit services—</text><subclause id="H7CEF6D00B90A4DC89044CDB803AE32BE"><enum>(I)</enum><text>an explanation of any benefit design parameters that encourage or require participants and beneficiaries in the plan or coverage to fill prescriptions at mail order, specialty, or retail pharmacies;</text></subclause><subclause id="HEB68AAC846234533B710905C07F69A3F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the percentage of total prescriptions dispensed by such pharmacies to participants or beneficiaries in such plan or coverage; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HAFC912E7EF0047F3BF8D5BBC7AF3883D"><enum>(III)</enum><text>a list of all drugs dispensed by such pharmacies to participants or beneficiaries enrolled in such plan or coverage, and, with respect to each drug dispensed—</text><item id="HE76FC24B3A9041B5B259F93F031C3B8F"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the amount charged, per dosage unit, per 30-day supply, or per 90-day supply (as applicable) to the plan or issuer, and to participants and beneficiaries;</text></item><item id="H6BF3B6AF3D70485E97463BD074B398F5"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the median amount charged to such plan or issuer, and the interquartile range of the costs, per dosage unit, per 30-day supply, and per 90-day supply, including amounts paid by the participants and beneficiaries, when the same drug is dispensed by other pharmacies that are not affiliated with or under common ownership with the entity and that are included in the pharmacy network of such plan or coverage;</text></item><item id="HE8EAE930C63F412E961661FC5C19F2F7"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>the lowest cost per dosage unit, per 30-day supply and per 90-day supply, for each such drug, including amounts charged to the plan or coverage and to participants and beneficiaries, that is available from any pharmacy included in the network of such plan or coverage; and</text></item><item id="H62875C7031A1410F8E905C198D8F6295"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>the net acquisition cost per dosage unit, per 30-day supply, and per 90-day supply, if such drug is subject to a maximum price discount; and</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC187FAE9D21344D5908A43A785AC28C1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to any group health plan, including group health insurance coverage offered in connection with such a plan, regardless of whether the plan or coverage is offered by a specified large employer or whether it is a specified large plan—</text><clause id="H741566F0632340269E24E5E67D74BA1F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a summary document for the group health plan that includes such information described in clauses (i) through (iv) of subparagraph (A), as specified by the Secretary through guidance, program instruction, or otherwise (with no requirement of notice and comment rulemaking), that the Secretary determines useful to group health plans for purposes of selecting pharmacy benefit management services, such as an estimated net price to group health plan and participant or beneficiary, a cost per claim, the fee structure or reimbursement model, and estimated cost per participant or beneficiary;</text></clause><clause id="H3B80A33B7D3B4D57965E8F883519AC98"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a summary document for plans and issuers to provide to participants and beneficiaries, which shall be made available to participants or beneficiaries upon request to their group health plan (including in the case of group health insurance coverage offered in connection with such a plan), that—</text><subclause id="H7DCB7CD028104AC4B5E6BBF317592D95"><enum>(I)</enum><text>contains such information described in clauses (iii), (iv), (v), and (vi), as applicable, as specified by the Secretary through guidance, program instruction, or otherwise (with no requirement of notice and comment rulemaking) that the Secretary determines useful to participants or beneficiaries in better understanding the plan or coverage or benefits under such plan or coverage;</text></subclause><subclause id="H01C378ED2BE642919B0442006728F749"><enum>(II)</enum><text>contains only aggregate information; and </text></subclause><subclause id="idA81DEA756A184D3EAD85F72BB6DC24D6"><enum>(III)</enum><text> states that participants and beneficiaries may request specific, claims-level information required to be furnished under subsection (c) from the group health plan or health insurance issuer; </text></subclause></clause><clause id="HDED311B0DFB44A50A6476522522A5AE2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>with respect to drugs covered by such plan or coverage during such reporting period—</text><subclause id="H3E82A98FF0F1417FA4C96E40E98DF513"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the total net spending by the plan or coverage for all such drugs;</text></subclause><subclause id="H303AC14BA11A45F59BEDF8543D1A5EA1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the total amount received, or expected to be received, by the plan or issuer from any applicable entity in rebates, fees, alternative discounts, or other remuneration; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HDF62E2BC43814E8F9B9B39B139D68F76"><enum>(III)</enum><text>to the extent feasible, information on the total amount of remuneration for such drugs, including copayment assistance dollars paid, copayment cards applied, or other discounts provided by each drug manufacturer (or entity administering copayment assistance on behalf of such drug manufacturer) to participants and beneficiaries;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H60A68664BE0247019B0165B528CB2672"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>amounts paid directly or indirectly in rebates, fees, or any other type of compensation (as defined in section 408(b)(2)(B)(ii)(dd)(AA)) to brokerage firms, brokers, consultants, advisors, or any other individual or firm, for—</text><subclause id="H4B841B94972A4C8884B52FBC43E2609D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the referral of the group health plan’s or health insurance issuer’s business to an entity providing pharmacy benefit management services, including the identity of the recipient of such amounts;</text></subclause><subclause id="H3CEA04B988AC45EC983FE4752C16E851"><enum>(II)</enum><text>consideration of the entity providing pharmacy benefit management services by the group health plan or health insurance issuer; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H3A1405869DFE495CB551E64657E1AAB6"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the retention of the entity by the group health plan or health insurance issuer;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H25704326FEDD4E79B8B6C4F2C7CC253E"><enum>(v)</enum><text>an explanation of any benefit design parameters that encourage or require participants and beneficiaries in such plan or coverage to fill prescriptions at mail order, specialty, or retail pharmacies that are affiliated with or under common ownership with the entity providing pharmacy benefit management services under such plan or coverage, including mandatory mail and specialty home delivery programs, retail and mail auto-refill programs, and cost-sharing assistance incentives directly or indirectly funded by such entity; and</text></clause><clause id="HF720AE6B4F9C4641B513EDE752F9605B"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>total gross spending on all drugs under the plan or coverage during the reporting period.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7141572D9BAD424781EB9A1910147CBC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Opt-in for group health insurance coverage offered
                                            by a specified large employer or that is a specified
 large plan</header><text>In the case of group health insurance coverage offered in connection with a group health plan that is offered by a specified large employer or is a specified large plan, such group health plan may, on an annual basis, for plan years beginning on or after the date that is 30 months after the date of enactment of this section, elect to require an entity providing pharmacy benefit management services on behalf of the health insurance issuer to submit to such group health plan a report that includes all of the information described in paragraph (2)(A), in addition to the information described in paragraph (2)(B).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4E2B115729E14DBDB314B28F160271C7"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Privacy requirements</header><subparagraph id="HB850428293E849DBB5B73A698ACECC5C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An entity providing pharmacy benefit management services on behalf of a group health plan or a health insurance issuer offering group health insurance coverage shall report information under paragraph (1) in a manner consistent with the privacy regulations promulgated under section 13402(a) of the Health Information Technology for Economic and Clinical Health Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/17932">42 U.S.C. 17932(a)</external-xref>) and consistent with the privacy regulations promulgated under the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 in part 160 and subparts A and E of part 164 of title 45, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations) (referred to in this paragraph as the <quote>HIPAA privacy regulations</quote>) and shall restrict the use and disclosure of such information according to such privacy regulations and such HIPAA privacy regulations.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6FC6EC60D30E46D2ACAE9001B3CC11FF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Additional requirements</header><clause id="H242119AE01E24DA9A318603AF748CCA4"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An entity providing pharmacy benefit management services on behalf of a group health plan or health insurance issuer offering group health insurance coverage that submits a report under paragraph (1) shall ensure that such report contains only summary health information, as defined in section 164.504(a) of title 45, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).</text></clause><clause id="HB4C3FB19B4BB4C09A6D8470D68126FFE"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Restrictions</header><text>In carrying out this subsection, a group health plan shall comply with section 164.504(f) of title 45, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation), and a plan sponsor shall act in accordance with the terms of the agreement described in such section.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H38B1518D9DFD42D8A4525C081D7D67D4"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><clause id="H2F69D0B3738D48EB9F24FD5BC0B725B4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to modify the requirements for the creation, receipt, maintenance, or transmission of protected health information under the HIPAA privacy regulations.</text></clause><clause id="H432317768AD045B180E88DD4BED56F3B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to affect the application of any Federal or State privacy or civil rights law, including the HIPAA privacy regulations, the Genetic Information Nondiscrimination Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/233">Public Law 110–233</external-xref>) (including the amendments made by such Act), the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12101">42 U.S.C. 12101 et seq.</external-xref>), section 504 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/794">29 U.S.C. 794</external-xref>), section 1557 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18116">42 U.S.C. 18116</external-xref>), title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d">42 U.S.C. 2000d</external-xref>), and title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000e">42 U.S.C. 2000e</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0DEEE52243094F158C70F8F6E75944AC"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Written notice</header><text>Each plan year, group health plans, including with respect to group health insurance coverage offered in connection with a group health plan, shall provide to each participant or beneficiary written notice informing the participant or beneficiary of the requirement for entities providing pharmacy benefit management services on behalf of the group health plan or health insurance issuer offering group health insurance coverage to submit reports to group health plans under paragraph (1), as applicable, which may include incorporating such notification in plan documents provided to the participant or beneficiary, or providing individual notification.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB5F14A8FFA7A4E8E990BC441A55DC003"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Limitation to business associates</header><text>A group health plan receiving a report under paragraph (1) may disclose such information only to the entity from which the report was received or to that entity’s business associates as defined in section 160.103 of title 45, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations) or as permitted by the HIPAA privacy regulations.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBB0BAD3BAB154151B52A4DA985C7280D"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Clarification regarding public disclosure of
 information</header><text>Nothing in this section shall prevent an entity providing pharmacy benefit management services on behalf of a group health plan or health insurance issuer offering group health insurance coverage, from placing reasonable restrictions on the public disclosure of the information contained in a report described in paragraph (1), except that such plan, issuer, or entity may not—</text><clause id="HD9B4646520F34EBBB8AC65A58DA304E5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>restrict disclosure of such report to the Department of Health and Human Services, the Department of Labor, or the Department of the Treasury; or</text></clause><clause id="H7DEF27612DE04D0983C51595E198E90D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>prevent disclosure for the purposes of subsection (c), or any other public disclosure requirement under this section.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2256B29154FE4A8DB2ED4BBBA504C8D6"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Limited form of report</header><text>The Secretary shall define through rulemaking a limited form of the report under paragraph (1) required with respect to any group health plan established by a plan sponsor that is, or is affiliated with, a drug manufacturer, drug wholesaler, or other direct participant in the drug supply chain, in order to prevent anti-competitive behavior.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5E492621C6BA4BD9BE9562AA7FD693FA"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Standard format and regulations</header><subparagraph id="H585B5C0AA3074AF0B7A9E4044DF55F58"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary shall specify through rulemaking a standard format for entities providing pharmacy benefit management services on behalf of group health plans and health insurance issuers offering group health insurance coverage, to submit reports required under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H471FFF7ED91A4D7E8D11E4C59AB4D396"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Additional regulations</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary shall, through rulemaking, promulgate any other final regulations necessary to implement the requirements of this section. In promulgating such regulations, the Secretary shall, to the extent practicable, align the reporting requirements under this section with the reporting requirements under section 725.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE08CB405CF4C499293E56874F53FC40F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Requirement To provide information to participants or
 beneficiaries</header><text>A group health plan, including with respect to group health insurance coverage offered in connection with a group health plan, upon request of a participant or beneficiary, shall provide to such participant or beneficiary—</text><paragraph id="H0557696571844CB8BDFEA935B8D22C7F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the summary document described in subsection (b)(2)(B)(ii); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H416A117C35E04165A64C9C9FF12696CD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the information described in subsection (b)(2)(A)(i)(III) with respect to a claim made by or on behalf of such participant or beneficiary.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H67034051B4D64661810485909CA3892B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to permit a health insurance issuer, group health plan, entity providing pharmacy benefit management services on behalf of a group health plan or health insurance issuer, or other entity to restrict disclosure to, or otherwise limit the access of, the Secretary to a report described in subsection (b)(1) or information related to compliance with subsections (a), (b), or (c) of this section or section 502(c)(13) by such issuer, plan, or entity.</text></subsection><subsection id="HCF7E7CD041E541CE9F189E10FC0B14C5"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HF2FA7F818A5B4776B6F91BA9EE113D62"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Applicable entity</header><text>The term <quote>applicable entity</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="H64007FAD77AF4F7DAFD5DAFFF493D3FB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an applicable group purchasing organization, drug manufacturer, distributor, wholesaler, rebate aggregator (or other purchasing entity designed to aggregate rebates), or associated third party;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H863C88480BE345EFA1051B3C2592A039"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any subsidiary, parent, affiliate, or subcontractor of a group health plan, health insurance issuer, entity that provides pharmacy benefit management services on behalf of such a plan or issuer, or any entity described in subparagraph (A); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H091B27645F5C477184840E85EDA02306"><enum>(C)</enum><text>such other entity as the Secretary may specify through rulemaking.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H276735A1520543498FF06E0E9DB40233"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applicable group purchasing organization</header><text>The term <quote>applicable group purchasing organization</quote> means a group purchasing organization that is affiliated with or under common ownership with an entity providing pharmacy benefit management services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF0BAC1F146224ADC9C40E322B7819CB9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Contracted compensation</header><text>The term <quote>contracted compensation</quote> means the sum of any ingredient cost and dispensing fee for a drug (inclusive of the out-of-pocket costs to the participant or beneficiary), or another analogous compensation structure that the Secretary may specify through regulations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC68BB69BDBFC435A956D36717C9836B2"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Gross spending</header><text>The term <quote>gross spending</quote>, with respect to prescription drug benefits under a group health plan or health insurance coverage, means the amount spent by a group health plan or health insurance issuer on prescription drug benefits, calculated before the application of rebates, fees, alternative discounts, or other remuneration.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8392F80D6505418AB50493EFCA79597B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Net spending</header><text>The term <quote>net spending</quote>, with respect to prescription drug benefits under a group health plan or health insurance coverage, means the amount spent by a group health plan or health insurance issuer on prescription drug benefits, calculated after the application of rebates, fees, alternative discounts, or other remuneration.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8A74650F259C42E2BE3CA198E913F6DA"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Plan sponsor</header><text>The term <quote>plan sponsor</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 3(16)(B).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBA435466DF3248FEAC04A0FB9C2740E7"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Remuneration</header><text>The term <quote>remuneration</quote> has the meaning given such term by the Secretary through rulemaking, which shall be reevaluated by the Secretary every 5 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H52BBBE6EB127489D8A2211EF357A4591"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Specified large employer</header><text>The term ‘specified large employer’ means, in connection with a group health plan (including group health insurance coverage offered in connection with such a plan) established or maintained by a single employer, with respect to a calendar year or a plan year, as applicable, an employer who employed an average of at least 100 employees on business days during the preceding calendar year or plan year and who employs at least 1 employee on the first day of the calendar year or plan year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H137578987749430599F5211D5F4D602F"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Specified large plan</header><text>The term <quote>specified large plan</quote> means a group health plan (including group health insurance coverage offered in connection with such a plan) established or maintained by a plan sponsor described in clause (ii) or (iii) of section 3(16)(B) that had an average of at least 100 participants on business days during the preceding calendar year or plan year, as applicable.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5776D0ABBE2445D3A98513F3BE6207AA"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Wholesale acquisition cost</header><text>The term <quote>wholesale acquisition cost</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 1847A(c)(6)(B) of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 1395w–3a(c)(6)(B)).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA7E7733A6ADB491A86F0AE8870E2FE25"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in section 502 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1132">29 U.S.C. 1132</external-xref>)—</text><clause id="H38ADD8A0F2B34F54A1B25071FF9D0681"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(6), by striking <quote>or (9)</quote> and inserting <quote>(9), or (13)</quote>;</text></clause><clause id="HF82C9F5451EB4ED8A380DE402A87ACBC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(3), by striking <quote>under subsection (c)(9)</quote> and inserting <quote>under paragraphs (9) and (13) of subsection (c)</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="HE1C3BB97CC9746DDAA33FFE20E2089CD"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in subsection (c), by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H75C7764152BB423389E8BA8AD8E393A1" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H7C9FF81DEE814351901B179A73875EC7"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Secretarial enforcement authority relating to oversight of pharmacy benefit management services</header><subparagraph id="H1848B9F86A8241649450A065BDA5F521"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Failure to provide information</header><text>The Secretary may impose a penalty against a plan administrator of a group health plan, a health insurance issuer offering group health insurance coverage, or an entity providing pharmacy benefit management services on behalf of such a plan or issuer, or an applicable entity (as defined in section 726(f)) that violates section 726(a); an entity providing pharmacy benefit management services on behalf of such a plan or issuer that fails to provide the information required under section 726(b); or any person who causes a group health plan to fail to provide the information required under section 726(c), in the amount of $10,000 for each day during which such violation continues or such information is not disclosed or reported.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H74A7BFACEB3444B6AE29E3924308949F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>False information</header><text>The Secretary may impose a penalty against a plan administrator of a group health plan, a health insurance issuer offering group health insurance coverage, an entity providing pharmacy benefit management services, or an applicable entity (as defined in section 726(f)) that knowingly provides false information under section 726, in an amount not to exceed $100,000 for each item of false information. Such penalty shall be in addition to other penalties as may be prescribed by law.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6CE0571F141947DE90E783FDA02901E6"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Waivers</header><text>The Secretary may waive penalties under subparagraph (A), or extend the period of time for compliance with a requirement of this section, for an entity in violation of section 726 that has made a good-faith effort to comply with the requirements of section 726.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H72742B59C6154D068B4B12681442EA9C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in section 732(a) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1191a">29 U.S.C. 1191a(a)</external-xref>), by striking <quote>section 711</quote> and inserting <quote>sections 711 and 726</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H318D65939207469C8009A25CA6ACAF27"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents in section 1 of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1001">29 U.S.C. 1001 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 725 the following new item:</text><quoted-block id="H7807D89A19D44BFBA73D4FED8685D4E1" style="OLC"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 726. Oversight of entities that provide
 pharmacy benefit management services.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA93CF046AFF94059937DBD86BC6D3984"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Internal revenue code of 1986</header><paragraph id="H8AD14FF5570A49908424207CA9207A54"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/100">Chapter 100</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended—</text><subparagraph id="HCBB3264BEDE04931A7C152103065963D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by adding at the end of subchapter B the following:</text><quoted-block id="H4AA6B7B0180E4924B73C9D9D5BE165FE" style="OLC"><section id="HFA978C239D724AAA94FDB860274A1D80"><enum>9826.</enum><header>Oversight of entities that provide pharmacy benefit management services</header><subsection id="H3A94A24B0C3B41BCB4FED15D6CDC24D7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For plan years beginning on or after the date that is 30 months after the date of enactment of this section (referred to in this subsection and subsection (b) as the <quote>effective date</quote>), a group health plan, or an entity providing pharmacy benefit management services on behalf of such a plan, shall not enter into a contract, including an extension or renewal of a contract, entered into on or after the effective date, with an applicable entity unless such applicable entity agrees to—</text><paragraph id="HB503515D35B44458AE158E023448C9BA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not limit or delay the disclosure of information to the group health plan in such a manner that prevents an entity providing pharmacy benefit management services on behalf of a group health plan from making the reports described in subsection (b); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA44BBF99E9A540CEB45AEEF2AA4919FB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide the entity providing pharmacy benefit management services on behalf of a group health plan relevant information necessary to make the reports described in subsection (b).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF2EB26F91D7345D5B00C30E50ECFAF5E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reports</header><paragraph id="HEB9B024FF8D34FC9AABD5212CD0F1D7A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For plan years beginning on or after the effective date, in the case of any contract between a group health plan and an entity providing pharmacy benefit management services on behalf of such plan, including an extension or renewal of such a contract, entered into on or after the effective date, the entity providing pharmacy benefit management services on behalf of such a group health plan, not less frequently than every 6 months (or, at the request of a group health plan, not less frequently than quarterly, and under the same conditions, terms, and cost of the semiannual report under this subsection), shall submit to the group health plan a report in accordance with this section. Each such report shall be made available to such group health plan in plain language, in a machine-readable format, and as the Secretary may determine, other formats. Each such report shall include the information described in paragraph (2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF8694D9AFF9A46FD902C8CA5832F6ACD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Information described</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (1), the information described in this paragraph is, with respect to drugs covered by a group health plan during each reporting period—</text><subparagraph id="HD6A8440AC7804751B1A61B8F86676F6C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case of a group health plan that is offered by a specified large employer or that is a specified large plan, and is not offered as health insurance coverage, or in the case of health insurance coverage for which the election under paragraph (3) is made for the applicable reporting period—</text><clause id="HD9BE7CB197BC4BD6B79B7B183AD28FEE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a list of drugs for which a claim was filed and, with respect to each such drug on such list—</text><subclause id="H2E09C0904C3340C482E06FA3DD944EA8"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the contracted compensation paid by the group health plan for each covered drug (identified by the National Drug Code) to the entity providing pharmacy benefit management services or other applicable entity on behalf of the group health plan;</text></subclause><subclause id="H7E0DED023BDD46EEBE9F9386791D68BD"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the contracted compensation paid to the pharmacy, by any entity providing pharmacy benefit management services or other applicable entity on behalf of the group health plan, for each covered drug (identified by the National Drug Code);</text></subclause><subclause id="H450ECA0D0BB448BA9ED43B55D603694F"><enum>(III)</enum><text>for each such claim, the difference between the amount paid under subclause (I) and the amount paid under subclause (II);</text></subclause><subclause id="H8FC641FC32B7478FA6EC4E865940A93D"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the proprietary name, established name or proper name, and National Drug Code;</text></subclause><subclause id="H25B548E1BDB449FFB36EA27D3841EFA8"><enum>(V)</enum><text>for each claim for the drug (including original prescriptions and refills) and for each dosage unit of the drug for which a claim was filed, the type of dispensing channel used to furnish the drug, including retail, mail order, or specialty pharmacy;</text></subclause><subclause id="HB43070CCDF7348E48E3B04908C177F76"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>with respect to each drug dispensed, for each type of dispensing channel (including retail, mail order, or specialty pharmacy)—</text><item id="H285928CDC78B474BACE934C01BC67E1C"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>whether such drug is a brand name drug or a generic drug, and—</text><subitem id="H7EC7606D31B34A9E9DE6B3FBD512F0F9"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>in the case of a brand name drug, the wholesale acquisition cost, listed as cost per days supply and cost per dosage unit, on the date such drug was dispensed; and</text></subitem><subitem id="subitem_d4k_gvg_1gc"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>in the case of a generic drug, the average wholesale price, listed as cost per days supply and cost per dosage unit, on the date such drug was dispensed; and</text></subitem></item><item id="H084F3E658C324E77ACF6C9B3364AF213"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the total number of—</text><subitem id="H8C4C3B8491CF4ED29510C1C041FC0431"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>prescription claims (including original prescriptions and refills);</text></subitem><subitem id="H21E9F2160F0F44ACB8D032DF5CED4914"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>participants and beneficiaries for whom a claim for such drug was filed through the applicable dispensing channel;</text></subitem><subitem id="H70EE9625F0D04FF7867E821F644E3641"><enum>(CC)</enum><text>dosage units and dosage units per fill of such drug; and</text></subitem><subitem id="H3DD183F7C4744C3DBE61014C32689D15"><enum>(DD)</enum><text>days supply of such drug per fill;</text></subitem></item></subclause><subclause id="H307273BFB1A745E98EB24247C42B6073"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>the net price per course of treatment or single fill, such as a 30-day supply or 90-day supply to the plan after rebates, fees, alternative discounts, or other remuneration received from applicable entities;</text></subclause><subclause id="H2E6D6E4CD6E14A7283A24CC1B18A4076"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text>the total amount of out-of-pocket spending by participants and beneficiaries on such drug, including spending through copayments, coinsurance, and deductibles, but not including any amounts spent by participants and beneficiaries on drugs not covered under the plan, or for which no claim is submitted under the plan;</text></subclause><subclause id="H422A70C0047B42D9AC17B43BA4571083"><enum>(IX)</enum><text>the total net spending on the drug;</text></subclause><subclause id="HFBB2D7F362BA40CE8536152131D36805"><enum>(X)</enum><text>the total amount received, or expected to be received, by the plan from any applicable entity in rebates, fees, alternative discounts, or other remuneration;</text></subclause><subclause id="H6BF30E26028F4A58B033760F94A302EE"><enum>(XI)</enum><text>the total amount received, or expected to be received, by the entity providing pharmacy benefit management services, from applicable entities, in rebates, fees, alternative discounts, or other remuneration from such entities—</text><item id="H1B3FCB3A83164C21ACF45834A7684006"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>for claims incurred during the reporting period; and</text></item><item id="H44C05CC9BF86498A8FDD29C197732E99"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>that is related to utilization of such drug or spending on such drug; and</text></item></subclause><subclause id="HB7B73BC31F51421E9C21C3AE65CD9D33"><enum>(XII)</enum><text>to the extent feasible, information on the total amount of remuneration for such drug, including copayment assistance dollars paid, copayment cards applied, or other discounts provided by each drug manufacturer (or entity administering copayment assistance on behalf of such drug manufacturer), to the participants and beneficiaries enrolled in such plan;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H6DCF46E72E704FEA87CCCECF1CC92714"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a list of each therapeutic class (as defined by the Secretary) for which a claim was filed under the group health plan during the reporting period, and, with respect to each such therapeutic class—</text><subclause id="H896F16FC2D314F408CFEDA055F3525E6"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the total gross spending on drugs in such class before rebates, price concessions, alternative discounts, or other remuneration from applicable entities;</text></subclause><subclause id="H66219AA5184242249CEC272A4F2C6098"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the net spending in such class after such rebates, price concessions, alternative discounts, or other remuneration from applicable entities;</text></subclause><subclause id="HF8A69357639A4470A617B69FA6871296"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the total amount received, or expected to be received, by the entity providing pharmacy benefit management services, from applicable entities, in rebates, fees, alternative discounts, or other remuneration from such entities—</text><item id="HC9D5A29045F94607BCF83E078B27A672"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>for claims incurred during the reporting period; and</text></item><item id="HA27069EBE55041C6B94A227DC61EDCA0"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>that is related to utilization of drugs or drug spending;</text></item></subclause><subclause id="HA458493E50764E80AB274C4742CEE13C"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the average net spending per 30-day supply and per 90-day supply by the plan and its participants and beneficiaries, among all drugs within the therapeutic class for which a claim was filed during the reporting period;</text></subclause><subclause id="HEB50D906E49C4C16A3E6E714D37D3E88"><enum>(V)</enum><text>the number of participants and beneficiaries who filled a prescription for a drug in such class, including the National Drug Code for each such drug;</text></subclause><subclause id="HFBD2658B35B541509B29DEF875C4F328"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>if applicable, a description of the formulary tiers and utilization mechanisms (such as prior authorization or step therapy) employed for drugs in that class; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H8AF77C259618408DB3AD8742C9984B65"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>the total out-of-pocket spending under the plan by participants and beneficiaries, including spending through copayments, coinsurance, and deductibles, but not including any amounts spent by participants and beneficiaries on drugs not covered under the plan or for which no claim is submitted under the plan;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H1E4217125FD74418A9E25802AA0741CB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>with respect to any drug for which gross spending under the group health plan exceeded $10,000 during the reporting period or, in the case that gross spending under the group health plan exceeded $10,000 during the reporting period with respect to fewer than 50 drugs, with respect to the 50 prescription drugs with the highest spending during the reporting period—</text><subclause id="H9EB3A2CE12C241CB979DE7456875F135"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a list of all other drugs in the same therapeutic class as such drug;</text></subclause><subclause id="H664D0903CF2C464EACCF5BC036820DA8"><enum>(II)</enum><text>if applicable, the rationale for the formulary placement of such drug in that therapeutic category or class, selected from a list of standard rationales established by the Secretary, in consultation with stakeholders; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HFCC4468ACB8E4132A460CF7285606B37"><enum>(III)</enum><text>any change in formulary placement compared to the prior plan year; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HD8872AF0EC314C01828490F4DF94A4CC"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>in the case that such plan (or an entity providing pharmacy benefit management services on behalf of such plan) has an affiliated pharmacy or pharmacy under common ownership, including mandatory mail and specialty home delivery programs, retail and mail auto-refill programs, and cost sharing assistance incentives funded by an entity providing pharmacy benefit services—</text><subclause id="HD1920715BE084E7C8D212C64F5D647DB"><enum>(I)</enum><text>an explanation of any benefit design parameters that encourage or require participants and beneficiaries in the plan to fill prescriptions at mail order, specialty, or retail pharmacies;</text></subclause><subclause id="HB3CFE72FE8A14DA88BEA9A1CE5C79B4F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the percentage of total prescriptions dispensed by such pharmacies to participants or beneficiaries in such plan; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H72ADCA6C0EDE4A47A990D8DA70F4F9E5"><enum>(III)</enum><text>a list of all drugs dispensed by such pharmacies to participants or beneficiaries enrolled in such plan, and, with respect to each drug dispensed—</text><item id="HFD5D32BE0CA04823BDC329174E9488A6"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the amount charged, per dosage unit, per 30-day supply, or per 90-day supply (as applicable) to the plan, and to participants and beneficiaries;</text></item><item id="HC99CC3A38C5D4B70887E523C52EE191C"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the median amount charged to such plan, and the interquartile range of the costs, per dosage unit, per 30-day supply, and per 90- day supply, including amounts paid by the participants and beneficiaries, when the same drug is dispensed by other pharmacies that are not affiliated with or under common ownership with the entity and that are included in the pharmacy network of such plan;</text></item><item id="H64C3128CD2C04B2DAEE6341B36899FC7"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>the lowest cost per dosage unit, per 30-day supply and per 90-day supply, for each such drug, including amounts charged to the plan and to participants and beneficiaries, that is available from any pharmacy included in the network of such plan; and</text></item><item id="H42506CCBF74C4D74832C5A7F52374953"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>the net acquisition cost per dosage unit, per 30-day supply, and per 90-day supply, if such drug is subject to a maximum price discount; and</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8C081E1D33674183BDFD634E777E5555"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to any group health plan, regardless of whether the plan is offered by a specified large employer or whether it is a specified large plan—</text><clause id="H9EB8CE96798A432DAD5175EAC12841F1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a summary document for the group health plan that includes such information described in clauses (i) through (iv) of subparagraph (A), as specified by the Secretary through guidance, program instruction, or otherwise (with no requirement of notice and comment rulemaking), that the Secretary determines useful to group health plans for purposes of selecting pharmacy benefit management services, such as an estimated net price to group health plan and participant or beneficiary, a cost per claim, the fee structure or reimbursement model, and estimated cost per participant or beneficiary;</text></clause><clause id="HB1B711FA7430472CB17BFD2F0AFB5D18"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a summary document for plans to provide to participants and beneficiaries, which shall be made available to participants or beneficiaries upon request to their group health plan, that—</text><subclause id="H36DA417F676D435AB0ADA090870CFF4E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>contains such information described in clauses (iii), (iv), (v), and (vi), as applicable, as specified by the Secretary through guidance, program instruction, or otherwise (with no requirement of notice and comment rulemaking) that the Secretary determines useful to participants or beneficiaries in better understanding the plan or benefits under such plan;</text></subclause><subclause id="HFC6D6BABA1534F4E8C1EAED043F77A1E"><enum>(II)</enum><text>contains only aggregate information; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H3BE2FA8CD71C46B8BA655D960E89EC2D"><enum>(III)</enum><text>states that participants and beneficiaries may request specific, claims-level information required to be furnished under subsection (c) from the group health plan; </text></subclause></clause><clause id="H9F75AC658AAF4D8BBF029A6898F40983"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>with respect to drugs covered by such plan during such reporting period—</text><subclause id="H9C09CF88085043939E210DFD29EFBF30"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the total net spending by the plan for all such drugs;</text></subclause><subclause id="H73764671EABE409593BC9EAA708D01ED"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the total amount received, or expected to be received, by the plan from any applicable entity in rebates, fees, alternative discounts, or other remuneration; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HC6D6DF34EE0644908DA2A0EE31FDCD54"><enum>(III)</enum><text>to the extent feasible, information on the total amount of remuneration for such drugs, including copayment assistance dollars paid, copayment cards applied, or other discounts provided by each drug manufacturer (or entity administering copayment assistance on behalf of such drug manufacturer) to participants and beneficiaries;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H33C97A05112C435A9B5C787467BAB112"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>amounts paid directly or indirectly in rebates, fees, or any other type of compensation (as defined in section 408(b)(2)(B)(ii)(dd)(AA) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act (29 U.S.C. 1108(b)(2)(B)(ii)(dd)(AA))) to brokerage firms, brokers, consultants, advisors, or any other individual or firm, for—</text><subclause id="HEF3E247F2AAD49C795CACF8F5BA880D5"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the referral of the group health plan’s business to an entity providing pharmacy benefit management services, including the identity of the recipient of such amounts;</text></subclause><subclause id="HD496ACE99FD54AEF9C16664CAE579585"><enum>(II)</enum><text>consideration of the entity providing pharmacy benefit management services by the group health plan; or</text></subclause><subclause id="HB9B53A1FBC624957AAC1C59E124B6C9D"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the retention of the entity by the group health plan;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H0B9F6972AC594B20BA1CB09CC5F37987"><enum>(v)</enum><text>an explanation of any benefit design parameters that encourage or require participants and beneficiaries in such plan to fill prescriptions at mail order, specialty, or retail pharmacies that are affiliated with or under common ownership with the entity providing pharmacy benefit management services under such plan, including mandatory mail and specialty home delivery programs, retail and mail auto-refill programs, and cost-sharing assistance incentives directly or indirectly funded by such entity; and</text></clause><clause id="H322A2299A9384C80A414B484295558F4"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>total gross spending on all drugs under the plan during the reporting period.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDFE8DE58E33645E89D4B1797B033C29F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Opt-in for group health insurance coverage offered
                                            by a specified large employer or that is a specified
 large plan</header><text>In the case of group health insurance coverage offered in connection with a group health plan that is offered by a specified large employer or is a specified large plan, such group health plan may, on an annual basis, for plan years beginning on or after the date that is 30 months after the date of enactment of this section, elect to require an entity providing pharmacy benefit management services on behalf of the health insurance issuer to submit to such group health plan a report that includes all of the information described in paragraph (2)(A), in addition to the information described in paragraph (2)(B).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF2C9EAD9D7E34CA3BF1F1FF8CCA9BFB8"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Privacy requirements</header><subparagraph id="H7AC31B2A04CC4802AEEAF2F2710C70CC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An entity providing pharmacy benefit management services on behalf of a group health plan shall report information under paragraph (1) in a manner consistent with the privacy regulations promulgated under section 13402(a) of the Health Information Technology for Economic and Clinical Health Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/17932">42 U.S.C. 17932(a)</external-xref>) and consistent with the privacy regulations promulgated under the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 in part 160 and subparts A and E of part 164 of title 45, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations) (referred to in this paragraph as the <quote>HIPAA privacy regulations</quote>) and shall restrict the use and disclosure of such information according to such privacy regulations and such HIPAA privacy regulations.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H57E83A4F71BA4464BD8B5C9F4001F5DB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Additional requirements</header><clause id="HB64F7A22CB684B13929725B913B3F601"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An entity providing pharmacy benefit management services on behalf of a group health plan that submits a report under paragraph (1) shall ensure that such report contains only summary health information, as defined in section 164.504(a) of title 45, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).</text></clause><clause id="H50639BD04EE4466284D555A0678464B8"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Restrictions</header><text>In carrying out this subsection, a group health plan shall comply with section 164.504(f) of title 45, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation), and a plan sponsor shall act in accordance with the terms of the agreement described in such section.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4B2FF2FD22B949F48D7BF61B840EF3D7"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><clause id="H8FBED5C0BA994F0D8E6008B2055F6544"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to modify the requirements for the creation, receipt, maintenance, or transmission of protected health information under the HIPAA privacy regulations.</text></clause><clause id="H96F66491468F4FA59F0BD45B599E739A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to affect the application of any Federal or State privacy or civil rights law, including the HIPAA privacy regulations, the Genetic Information Nondiscrimination Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/233">Public Law 110–233</external-xref>) (including the amendments made by such Act), the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12101">42 U.S.C. 12101 et seq.</external-xref>), section 504 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/794">29 U.S.C. 794</external-xref>), section 1557 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18116">42 U.S.C. 18116</external-xref>), title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d">42 U.S.C. 2000d</external-xref>), and title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000e">42 U.S.C. 2000e</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H007EA114D2B0486F96A210A32B9E95F6"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Written notice</header><text>Each plan year, group health plans shall provide to each participant or beneficiary written notice informing the participant or beneficiary of the requirement for entities providing pharmacy benefit management services on behalf of the group health plan to submit reports to group health plans under paragraph (1), as applicable, which may include incorporating such notification in plan documents provided to the participant or beneficiary, or providing individual notification.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H49FAF8D92E264F2595D20D0950A9875A"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Limitation to business associates</header><text>A group health plan receiving a report under paragraph (1) may disclose such information only to the entity from which the report was received or to that entity’s business associates as defined in section 160.103 of title 45, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations) or as permitted by the HIPAA privacy regulations.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC18D45F04FE84D628FDFE993103EF0F4"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Clarification regarding public disclosure of
 information</header><text>Nothing in this section shall prevent an entity providing pharmacy benefit management services on behalf of a group health plan, from placing reasonable restrictions on the public disclosure of the information contained in a report described in paragraph (1), except that such plan or entity may not—</text><clause id="HC196FD070212402DA6230BD927729ADC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>restrict disclosure of such report to the Department of Health and Human Services, the Department of Labor, or the Department of the Treasury; or</text></clause><clause id="H455FF9461F1E47978C4D5EF1AF54A253"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>prevent disclosure for the purposes of subsection (c), or any other public disclosure requirement under this section.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAC82472279754EEFB0BAFC44C41DB657"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Limited form of report</header><text>The Secretary shall define through rulemaking a limited form of the report under paragraph (1) required with respect to any group health plan established by a plan sponsor that is, or is affiliated with, a drug manufacturer, drug wholesaler, or other direct participant in the drug supply chain, in order to prevent anti-competitive behavior.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9FCD25AA99D444A9B3A04E9E75FD7316"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Standard format and regulations</header><subparagraph id="H7B1E06E3EC7F4DC9871C44543BB64B6C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary shall specify through rulemaking a standard format for entities providing pharmacy benefit management services on behalf of group health plans, to submit reports required under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFA9413590397497EBA7076A593584526"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Additional regulations</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary shall, through rulemaking, promulgate any other final regulations necessary to implement the requirements of this section. In promulgating such regulations, the Secretary shall, to the extent practicable, align the reporting requirements under this section with the reporting requirements under section 9825.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H292AF1DAF5114E099DF23FAE2B238607"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Requirement To provide information to participants or
 beneficiaries</header><text>A group health plan, upon request of a participant or beneficiary, shall provide to such participant or beneficiary—</text><paragraph id="HCF3AB729DC95455E86BA342EEA7B1393"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the summary document described in subsection (b)(2)(B)(ii); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2B0EF25D8FB74E45A3368DC71C2CC8EB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the information described in subsection (b)(2)(A)(i)(III) with respect to a claim made by or on behalf of such participant or beneficiary.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H28310155F16441A19ED575CB573DB15C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to permit a health insurance issuer, group health plan, entity providing pharmacy benefit management services on behalf of a group health plan or health insurance issuer, or other entity to restrict disclosure to, or otherwise limit the access of, the Secretary to a report described in subsection (b)(1) or information related to compliance with subsections (a), (b), or (c) of this section or section 4980D(g) by such issuer, plan, or entity.</text></subsection><subsection id="H6DD0546967E34E6F80C74BA193D1C09A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HF7EC7CD217D04C1AA8A260A701E7BB01"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Applicable entity</header><text>The term <quote>applicable entity</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="HA3A031A27B164F878C9D78DB3FD7E3AC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an applicable group purchasing organization, drug manufacturer, distributor, wholesaler, rebate aggregator (or other purchasing entity designed to aggregate rebates), or associated third party;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDFE1D0C68435480EBCCD72D3593F860A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any subsidiary, parent, affiliate, or subcontractor of a group health plan, health insurance issuer, entity that provides pharmacy benefit management services on behalf of such a plan or issuer, or any entity described in subparagraph (A); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFC288F3E15BF41B4B69135582E68FBB2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>such other entity as the Secretary may specify through rulemaking.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4C49690189B34BD396EFC6120E9AD45E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applicable group purchasing organization</header><text>The term <quote>applicable group purchasing organization</quote> means a group purchasing organization that is affiliated with or under common ownership with an entity providing pharmacy benefit management services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDC97F4AC220E4439A8C86A7281DD42BC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Contracted compensation</header><text>The term <quote>contracted compensation</quote> means the sum of any ingredient cost and dispensing fee for a drug (inclusive of the out-of-pocket costs to the participant or beneficiary), or another analogous compensation structure that the Secretary may specify through regulations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H117A89ADC90D41E7866D583C99AEB574"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Gross spending</header><text>The term <quote>gross spending</quote>, with respect to prescription drug benefits under a group health plan, means the amount spent by a group health plan on prescription drug benefits, calculated before the application of rebates, fees, alternative discounts, or other remuneration.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9D44653653984A65AB6CC98992C60E04"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Net spending</header><text>The term <quote>net spending</quote>, with respect to prescription drug benefits under a group health plan, means the amount spent by a group health plan on prescription drug benefits, calculated after the application of rebates, fees, alternative discounts, or other remuneration.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H44D99D461F74421DBEDC38D74CBA4DC1"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Plan sponsor</header><text>The term <quote>plan sponsor</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 3(16)(B) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1002">29 U.S.C. 1002(16)(B)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H99D5EB89052847188091E77E47E26936"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Remuneration</header><text>The term <quote>remuneration</quote> has the meaning given such term by the Secretary, through rulemaking, which shall be reevaluated by the Secretary every 5 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD5E90117EE9B4CFFB3E1FC9E63CDC4A4"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Specified large employer</header><text>The term <quote>specified large employer</quote> means, in connection with a group health plan established or maintained by a single employer, with respect to a calendar year or a plan year, as applicable, an employer who employed an average of at least 100 employees on business days during the preceding calendar year or plan year and who employs at least 1 employee on the first day of the calendar year or plan year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0577467595E441DEAD68E01603E9B610"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Specified large plan</header><text>The term <quote>specified large plan</quote> means a group health plan established or maintained by a plan sponsor described in clause (ii) or (iii) of section 3(16)(B) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1002">29 U.S.C. 1002(16)(B)</external-xref>) that had an average of at least 100 participants on business days during the preceding calendar year or plan year, as applicable.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6746C942AA8A402E90F9FE083B1382D6"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Wholesale acquisition cost</header><text>The term <quote>wholesale acquisition cost</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 1847A(c)(6)(B) of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 1395w–3a(c)(6)(B)).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H846822BA6FA14382B201A40FD95C2504"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception for certain group health plans</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/9831">Section 9831(a)(2)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting <quote>other than with respect to section 9826,</quote> before <quote>any group health plan</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB2E0E5FD820841EEAC3448702BFDF7DD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/4980D">Section 4980D</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block id="H7AA99B1A901E4317A54ACAD386507911" style="OLC"><subsection id="H7101B6799E7B43C7B2CEF124C9F84B70"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Application to requirements imposed on certain entities
 providing pharmacy benefit management services</header><text>In the case of any requirement under section 9826 that applies with respect to an entity providing pharmacy benefit management services on behalf of a group health plan, any reference in this section to such group health plan (and the reference in subsection (e)(1) to the employer) shall be treated as including a reference to such entity.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H140E579EB455415AB3A3BBB1A9D1B512"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for subchapter B of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/100">chapter 100</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text><quoted-block id="H61118488896545F5B861ACC9BBD2D7B6" style="OLC"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 9826. Oversight of entities that provide
 pharmacy benefit management services.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H49F6174B9C604354AA24B3887F311066"><enum>5.</enum><header>Ensuring accurate payments to pharmacies under medicaid</header><subsection id="H07A3AE11174148C79992A32FC3F31088"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1927(f) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396r-8">42 U.S.C. 1396r–8(f)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H5C408A00B7224EEE83B72A61A8196F1C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)(A)—</text><subparagraph id="HED38CE816C0D4904A47AB2D0F0D1FDE7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating clause (ii) as clause (iii); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1968DB1880CE4AE693F714B3480EE425"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon at the end of clause (i) and all that precedes it through <quote>(1)</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block id="HADB30A261B054CCA99DBBDA3C8F7C603" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H74C752B94D2C4E74BDDD780CCCD42AE7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Determining pharmacy actual acquisition costs</header><text>The Secretary shall conduct a survey of retail community pharmacy drug prices and applicable non-retail pharmacy drug prices to determine national average drug acquisition cost benchmarks (as such term is defined by the Secretary) as follows:</text><subparagraph id="HF50C5F3D5AD9438A82884620B5CD7B60"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Use of vendor</header><text>The Secretary may contract services for—</text><clause id="HB08DD2721BE241AD8AB240D4A3FC13C0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>with respect to retail community pharmacies, the determination of retail survey prices of the national average drug acquisition cost for covered outpatient drugs that represent a nationwide average of consumer purchase prices for such drugs, net of all discounts, rebates, and other price concessions (to the extent any information with respect to such discounts, rebates, and other price concessions is available) based on a monthly survey of such pharmacies;</text></clause><clause id="HF135386A21F84525BAFCF86669B5A803"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>with respect to applicable non-retail pharmacies—</text><subclause id="H9B816FDC03AD4695A5D0B590C36C74F3"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the determination of survey prices, separate from the survey prices described in clause (i), of the non-retail national average drug acquisition cost for covered outpatient drugs that represent a nationwide average of consumer purchase prices for such drugs, net of all discounts, rebates, and other price concessions (to the extent any information with respect to such discounts, rebates, and other price concessions is available) based on a monthly survey of such pharmacies; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H6A54B2B6663B49E493D57CE118F07527"><enum>(II)</enum><text>at the discretion of the Secretary, for each type of applicable non-retail pharmacy, the determination of survey prices, separate from the survey prices described in clause (i) or subclause (I) of this clause, of the national average drug acquisition cost for such type of pharmacy for covered outpatient drugs that represent a nationwide average of consumer purchase prices for such drugs, net of all discounts, rebates, and other price concessions (to the extent any information with respect to such discounts, rebates, and other price concessions is available) based on a monthly survey of such pharmacies; and</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H77A3913F1A1C4FF9AE624C79DD4A57C9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B) of paragraph (1), by striking <quote>subparagraph (A)(ii)</quote> and inserting <quote>subparagraph (A)(iii)</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H145647E923514B91AA8C20F2842D5A07"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D) of paragraph (1), by striking clauses (ii) and (iii) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block id="HB9C94495FF5B4C61937DBEDB4EB841D2" style="OLC"><clause id="HBF6DB9AE317D4BCBB27543F69A0D558B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The vendor must update the Secretary no less often than monthly on the survey prices for covered outpatient drugs.</text></clause><clause id="HCA836DE10FA8468F998AC9C82326D363"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The vendor must differentiate, in collecting and reporting survey data, for all cost information collected, whether a pharmacy is a retail community pharmacy or an applicable non-retail pharmacy, including whether such pharmacy is an affiliate (as defined in subsection (k)(14)), and, in the case of an applicable non-retail pharmacy, which type of applicable non-retail pharmacy it is using the relevant pharmacy type indicators included in the guidance required by subsection (d)(2) of section 44123 of the Act titled ‘An Act to provide for reconciliation pursuant to title II of H. Con. Res. 14.’</text></clause><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H491F2689A500426BB4D97A1D025FCDB3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by adding at the end of paragraph (1) the following:</text><quoted-block id="HCD795C975A9A4B4BA46453989FC76216" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="H9D2E47AF631247028D78D71BAE68A247"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Survey reporting</header><text>In order to meet the requirement of section 1902(a)(54), a State shall require that any retail community pharmacy or applicable non-retail pharmacy in the State that receives any payment, reimbursement, administrative fee, discount, rebate, or other price concession related to the dispensing of covered outpatient drugs to individuals receiving benefits under this title, regardless of whether such payment, reimbursement, administrative fee, discount, rebate, or other price concession is received from the State or a managed care entity or other specified entity (as such terms are defined in section 1903(m)(9)(D)) directly or from a pharmacy benefit manager or another entity that has a contract with the State or a managed care entity or other specified entity (as so defined), shall respond to surveys conducted under this paragraph.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6D4A55C2544C448F908565C2ED6EE103"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Survey information</header><text>Information on national drug acquisition prices obtained under this paragraph shall be made publicly available in a form and manner to be determined by the Secretary and shall include at least the following:</text><clause id="H64FFB149D3ED4D868FC9A300C39FEAA7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The monthly response rate to the survey including a list of pharmacies not in compliance with subparagraph (F).</text></clause><clause id="HE9463333D702450887CC0F1137B43E67"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The sampling methodology and number of pharmacies sampled monthly.</text></clause><clause id="H922DB2CE6F7D4767AA565C7A9EBDE216"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Information on price concessions to pharmacies, including discounts, rebates, and other price concessions, to the extent that such information may be publicly released and has been collected by the Secretary as part of the survey.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA32F3CD122684D27B15EA1F56A8F407F"><enum>(H)</enum><header>Penalties</header><clause id="H9800AD53A8D047A388B8EEEA193BF56B"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to clauses (ii), (iii), and (iv), the Secretary shall enforce the provisions of this paragraph with respect to a pharmacy through the establishment of civil money penalties applicable to a retail community pharmacy or an applicable non-retail pharmacy.</text></clause><clause id="H5CD13DDCD29F44DFB4CED7A62265E9F5"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Basis for penalties</header><text>The Secretary shall impose a civil money penalty established under this subparagraph on a retail community pharmacy or applicable non-retail pharmacy if—</text><subclause id="HB40516EF5E0C423A953E8AF7D3FEE2D5"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the retail pharmacy or applicable non-retail pharmacy refuses or otherwise fails to respond to a request for information about prices in connection with a survey under this subsection;</text></subclause><subclause id="H492344C11F8943D7A777EE9CB6272343"><enum>(II)</enum><text>knowingly provides false information in response to such a survey; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H1F09D0183F884DD0850128031F9C22C4"><enum>(III)</enum><text>otherwise fails to comply with the requirements established under this paragraph.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H8C7E0C8AE6B64DB19FB726E75E093F9C"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Parameters for penalties</header><subclause id="H26DBD9B9FEE84A2CBB8D826FAD940998"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A civil money penalty established under this subparagraph may be assessed with respect to each violation, and with respect to each non-compliant retail community pharmacy (including a pharmacy that is part of a chain) or non-compliant applicable non-retail pharmacy (including a pharmacy that is part of a chain), in an amount not to exceed $100,000 for each such violation.</text></subclause><subclause id="H8961EB2D74794D2D9EBD779E1386D7FB"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In determining the amount of a civil money penalty imposed under this subparagraph, the Secretary may consider the size, business structure, and type of pharmacy involved, as well as the type of violation and other relevant factors, as determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H10DAE32017A04187BC6FAC46C9F64124"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Rule of application</header><text>The provisions of section 1128A (other than subsections (a) and (b)) shall apply to a civil money penalty under this subparagraph in the same manner as such provisions apply to a civil money penalty or proceeding under section 1128A(a).</text><subclause id="HD6671C8296004B1480A840D4F61DAB10"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Limitation on use of applicable non-retail pharmacy
 pricing information</header><text>No State shall use pricing information reported by applicable non-retail pharmacies under subparagraph (A)(ii) to develop or inform payment methodologies for retail community pharmacies.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="HA5A2A7BE31824AB5BD3E128B1DB2E40C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text><subparagraph id="HD2CCAD0092D44D74B7FBC1A86A169CF3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by inserting <quote>, including payment rates and methodologies for determining ingredient cost reimbursement under managed care entities or other specified entities (as such terms are defined in section 1903(m)(9)(D)),</quote> after <quote>under this title</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H93358FE7B4564A41BC406AFD68B08EC7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by inserting <quote>and the basis for such dispensing fees</quote> before the semicolon;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9B0617E34DB74CC49DDA56FFDCA1DD64"><enum>(6)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (4) as paragraph (5);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF94C32DE54DF4992BE939007D0592461"><enum>(7)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (3) the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block id="H2BA83FB8F1D34CEB8C3110286C4413E3" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H21026845E42148DEA53D1FE78CE61368"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Oversight</header><subparagraph id="H0C9CD3B7AEAE4C268C2DF4FD6F44DDD5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Inspector General of the Department of Health and Human Services shall conduct periodic studies of the survey data reported under this subsection, as appropriate, including with respect to substantial variations in acquisition costs or other applicable costs, as well as with respect to how internal transfer prices and related party transactions may influence the costs reported by pharmacies that are affiliates (as defined in subsection (k)(14)) or are owned by, controlled by, or related under a common ownership structure with a wholesaler, distributor, or other entity that acquires covered outpatient drugs relative to costs reported by pharmacies not affiliated with such entities. The Inspector General shall provide periodic updates to Congress on the results of such studies, as appropriate, in a manner that does not disclose trade secrets or other proprietary information.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE0ACFC21EAC24B1F902D6B1E8CD093C0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Appropriation</header><text>There is appropriated to the Inspector General of the Department of Health and Human Services, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, $5,000,000 for fiscal year 2025, to remain available until expended, to carry out this paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="HC846FC97D4E849D4B4730C336F23D569"><enum>(8)</enum><text>in paragraph (5), as so redesignated—</text><subparagraph id="H4F44ADDB44B543BC974A4B279E24F10D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, and $9,000,000 for fiscal year 2025 and each fiscal year thereafter,</quote> after <quote>2010</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4B3FD9481C5A4D4E82E7149465043BAD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>Funds appropriated under this paragraph for fiscal year 2025 and any subsequent fiscal year shall remain available until expended.</quote> after the period.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA55CBD883EBC4C799A822EAB29CEDA6A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>Section 1927(k) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396r-8">42 U.S.C. 1396r–8(k)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HCBA1094C407A4864ACD62534DE14CC9F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by striking <quote>In the section</quote> and inserting <quote>In this section</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCE0177C69370447EAE0A11F83A301597"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraphs:</text><quoted-block id="H8BED6E86913D45EAA1EE26F0FB5680E8" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H4F9D2E6247274B0F9012D907528A7BF1"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Applicable non-retail pharmacy</header><text>The term <quote>applicable non-retail pharmacy</quote> means a pharmacy that is licensed as a pharmacy by the State and that is not a retail community pharmacy, including a pharmacy that dispenses prescription medications to patients primarily through mail and specialty pharmacies. Such term does not include nursing home pharmacies, long-term care facility pharmacies, hospital pharmacies, clinics, charitable or not-for-profit pharmacies, government pharmacies, or low dispensing pharmacies (as defined by the Secretary).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0B3F699FC7384DAEA8B391ACAD0C2472"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Affiliate</header><text>The term <quote>affiliate</quote> means any entity that is owned by, controlled by, or related under a common ownership structure with a pharmacy benefit manager or a managed care entity or other specified entity (as such terms are defined in section 1903(m)(9)(D)).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB5A25E151ED04BD0A00818C64533E488"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><paragraph id="HC5D916E90EAE4D21AD031FA49DEDFADD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2), the amendments made by this section shall take effect on the first day of the first quarter that begins on or after the date that is 6 months after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2C29EF1C7F594C86A33075AD22FF9A23"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Delayed application to applicable non-retail pharmacies</header><text>The pharmacy survey requirements established by the amendments to section 1927(f) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396r-8">42 U.S.C. 1396r–8(f)</external-xref>) made by this section shall apply to retail community pharmacies beginning on the effective date described in paragraph (1), but shall not apply to applicable non-retail pharmacies until the first day of the first quarter that begins on or after the date that is 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4E5D7CC8D69D43269C29A308697C5DF2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Identification of applicable non-Retail pharmacies</header><paragraph id="HECCF73A3513A462F86B561226E72A58C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than January 1, 2027, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall publish guidance specifying pharmacies that meet the definition of applicable non-retail pharmacies (as such term is defined in subsection (k)(12) of section 1927 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396r-8">42 U.S.C. 1396r–8</external-xref>), as added by subsection (b)), and that will be subject to the survey requirements under subsection (f)(1) of such section, as amended by subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H38E2484F75EA49DB86D648BA016EEE11"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Inclusion of pharmacy type indicators</header><text>The guidance published under paragraph (1) shall include pharmacy type indicators to distinguish between different types of applicable non-retail pharmacies, such as pharmacies that dispense prescriptions primarily through the mail and pharmacies that dispense prescriptions that require special handling or distribution. An applicable non-retail pharmacy may be identified through multiple pharmacy type indicators.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF46AF8C6D69143FBA9B4EF24EF91983F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Implementation</header><paragraph id="HB64D47DBB9664FA7A22DE72CB4F51CF7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Implementation of the amendments made by this section shall be exempt from the requirements of section 553 of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD6A22380C04C4571BBD0499A2E311548"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Nonapplication of paperwork reduction act</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/44/35">Chapter 35</external-xref> of title 44, United States Code, shall not apply to any data collection undertaken by the Secretary of Health and Human Services under section 1927(f) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396r-8">42 U.S.C. 1396r–8(f)</external-xref>), as amended by this section.</text></subsection></section><section id="H0E0B4286D51B4F729EFDB416A2305412"><enum>6.</enum><header>Preventing the use of abusive spread pricing in medicaid</header><subsection id="H890D47511A7A4ADA848608BBC4ABE656"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1927 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396r-8">42 U.S.C. 1396r–8</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H2C776CD2011D473D9E74EDA5E172813D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (e), by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block id="H72D9CFA6DE16432F8D8E76016A91339F" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H0193DB13E1534FF08A2A3C48EE07FDCE"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Transparent prescription drug pass- through pricing
 required</header><subparagraph id="HDF8B776E18114DFB91C763E305B9AD75"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A contract between the State and a pharmacy benefit manager (referred to in this paragraph as a <quote>PBM</quote>), or a contract between the State and a managed care entity or other specified entity (as such terms are defined in section 1903(m)(9)(D) and collectively referred to in this paragraph as the <quote>entity</quote>) that includes provisions making the entity responsible for coverage of covered outpatient drugs dispensed to individuals enrolled with the entity, shall require that payment for such drugs and related administrative services (as applicable), including payments made by a PBM on behalf of the State or entity, is based on a transparent prescription drug pass-through pricing model under which—</text><clause id="H93516DC053E546AF997E334FCE0DA661"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any payment made by the entity or the PBM (as applicable) for such a drug—</text><subclause id="H63D5DEAC96364BEFB73F0D8335CC5FF3"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is limited to—</text><item id="H1549F608355F4601A5C2286F9CF43A20"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>ingredient cost; and</text></item><item id="H7B0DA739923E4150A2116C028D4FE3A1"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>a professional dispensing fee that is not less than the professional dispensing fee that the State would pay if the State were making the payment directly in accordance with the State plan;</text></item></subclause><subclause id="H952848CCB42E4048A57C7DF30DB5BBE8"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is passed through in its entirety (except as reduced under Federal or State laws and regulations in response to instances of waste, fraud, or abuse) by the entity or PBM to the pharmacy or provider that dispenses the drug; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H9C3B0A36FCDA454199A9D59CF3DCFFC6"><enum>(III)</enum><text>is made in a manner that is consistent with sections 447.502, 447.512, 447.514, and 447.518 of title 42, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation) as if such requirements applied directly to the entity or the PBM, except that any payment by the entity or the PBM for the ingredient cost of such drug purchased by a covered entity (as defined in subsection (a)(5)(B)) may exceed the actual acquisition cost (as defined in 447.502 of title 42, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor regulation) for such drug if—</text><item id="HB5DBF08EF21E4320B0DDC5FD4252446A"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>such drug was subject to an agreement under section 340B of the Public Health Service Act;</text></item><item id="H4A176F9097B742D388A509267363ED68"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>such payment for the ingredient cost of such drug does not exceed the maximum payment that would have been made by the entity or the PBM for the ingredient cost of such drug if such drug had not been purchased by such covered entity; and</text></item><item id="HAF0E1918434047DE86C5BEA156B94AD7"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>such covered entity reports to the Secretary (in a form and manner specified by the Secretary), on an annual basis and with respect to payments for the ingredient costs of such drugs so purchased by such covered entity that are in excess of the actual acquisition costs for such drugs, the aggregate amount of such excess;</text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="HA4F3A95B71D1418DB8DF4BE9142C02A4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>payment to the entity or the PBM (as applicable) for administrative services performed by the entity or PBM is limited to an administrative fee that reflects the fair market value (as defined by the Secretary) of such services;</text></clause><clause id="H2EA58AF659C6486B8ECC8A722511A2B4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the entity or the PBM (as applicable) makes available to the State, and the Secretary upon request in a form and manner specified by the Secretary, all costs and payments related to covered outpatient drugs and accompanying administrative services (as described in clause (ii)) incurred, received, or made by the entity or the PBM, broken down (as specified by the Secretary), to the extent such costs and payments are attributable to an individual covered outpatient drug, by each such drug, including any ingredient costs, professional dispensing fees, administrative fees (as described in clause (ii)), post-sale and post-invoice fees, discounts, or related adjustments such as direct and indirect remuneration fees, and any and all other remuneration, as defined by the Secretary; and</text></clause><clause id="H7B133E7215494B149026A591B89EE42C"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>any form of spread pricing whereby any amount charged or claimed by the entity or the PBM (as applicable) that exceeds the amount paid to the pharmacies or providers on behalf of the State or entity, including any post-sale or post-invoice fees, discounts, or related adjustments such as direct and indirect remuneration fees or assessments, as defined by the Secretary, (after allowing for an administrative fee as described in clause (ii)) is not allowable for purposes of claiming Federal matching payments under this title.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF65E758F01904BC8AA3447C1E633EDCD"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Publication of information</header><text>The Secretary shall publish, not less frequently than on an annual basis and in a manner that does not disclose the identity of a particular covered entity or organization, information received by the Secretary pursuant to subparagraph (A)(iii)(III) that is broken out by State and by each of the following categories of covered entity within each such State:</text><clause id="H34196D8300964D3E857B12D4419D2D2F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Covered entities described in subparagraph (A) of section 340B(a)(4) of the Public Health Service Act.</text></clause><clause id="H8E9D00E58542463299A15CAFF2E8B2C7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Covered entities described in subparagraphs (B) through (K) of such section.</text></clause><clause id="H1ADA0A7BACD049EAB6A5B8CD7492F367"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Covered entities described in subparagraph (L) of such section.</text></clause><clause id="H99D9BD61489B4063B08ADA2E2906269B"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Covered entities described in subparagraph (M) of such section.</text></clause><clause id="H706D15D888654902BD419F6E02EC1411"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Covered entities described in subparagraph (N) of such section.</text></clause><clause id="HB6FF930881F9499683484C59115636AB"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Covered entities described in subparagraph (O) of such section.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block> ; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H4F346A1E2DC5442D917DE6705F2F2DDA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (k), as previously amended by this title, by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block id="HE262E7A13BF645DEA66214F4AA6FE948" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H7F641FBCE0324F41BB3AAB808DAD338B"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Pharmacy benefit manager</header><text>The term <quote>pharmacy benefit manager</quote> means any person or entity that, either directly or through an intermediary, acts as a price negotiator or group purchaser on behalf of a State, managed care entity (as defined in section 1903(m)(9)(D)), or other specified entity (as so defined), or manages the prescription drug benefits provided by a State, managed care entity, or other specified entity, including the processing and payment of claims for prescription drugs, the performance of drug utilization review, the processing of drug prior authorization requests, the managing of appeals or grievances related to the prescription drug benefits, contracting with pharmacies, controlling the cost of covered outpatient drugs, or the provision of services related thereto. Such term includes any person or entity that acts as a price negotiator (with regard to payment amounts to pharmacies and providers for a covered outpatient drug or the net cost of the drug) or group purchaser on behalf of a State, managed care entity, or other specified entity or that carries out 1 or more of the other activities described in the preceding sentence, irrespective of whether such person or entity calls itself a pharmacy benefit manager.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD669871D78984FAD89905AEBC31435E0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text>Section 1903(m) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396b">42 U.S.C. 1396b(m)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HAF31CA9C93A44378AC0914D590D46ECB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)(A)(xiii)—</text><subparagraph id="HA16F791438EE4DC2B02A29F91897E128"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and (III)</quote> and inserting <quote>(III)</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA56F58A149644D1EB2A7912094A3F28E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting before the period at the end the following: <quote>, and (IV) if the contract includes provisions making the entity responsible for coverage of covered outpatient drugs, the entity shall comply with the requirements of section 1927(e)(6)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA595671549BA494F8E7E81CD18C82D39"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by moving the margin 2 ems to the left; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H40A6A75E94E843BF8A372A0EF4E8C66C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block id="HE262E7A13BF645DEA66214F4AA6FE958" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="HF8C03675A841412EB47770CAFD9D150E"><enum>(10)</enum><text>No payment shall be made under this title to a State with respect to expenditures incurred by the State for payment for services provided by an other specified entity (as defined in paragraph (9)(D)(iii)) unless such services are provided in accordance with a contract between the State and such entity which satisfies the requirements of paragraph (2)(A)(xiii).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HED4EBBBA32BA4A2C86F80CAFA7E3A967"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to contracts between States and managed care entities, other specified entities, or pharmacy benefit managers that have an effective date beginning on or after the date that is 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H04F13D36E68649E884410872FCEFD1A4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Implementation</header><paragraph id="H06FD2B4AF4C84144A925A68326FE8F71"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Implementation of the amendments made by this section shall be exempt from the requirements of section 553 of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H467F9564833A4396B389E84451B74479"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Nonapplication of paperwork reduction act</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/44/35">Chapter 35</external-xref> of title 44, United States Code, shall not apply to any data collection undertaken by the Secretary of Health and Human Services under section 1927(e) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396r-8">42 U.S.C. 1396r–8(e)</external-xref>), as amended by this section.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


