<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-PAT25792-DF5-8W-H9K"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2980 IS: Innovative and Safe Hydrogen Transportation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2980</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251007">October 7, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S347">Mr. Moran</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To direct the Secretary of Transportation to study certain composite material pipelines, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H43AEA55C02694A739EBBC44B793C2992"><section section-type="section-one" id="H91CDB842A20E495BABA921F28E412B04"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Innovative and Safe Hydrogen Transportation Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section section-type="subsequent-section" id="HD6F89A8D929545219C61B1117E750BB9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Study on composite materials</header><subsection id="H1BC42E481A7849228C4B67B949DDD363"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Transportation (referred to in this section as the <term>Secretary</term>) shall complete a study assessing the potential and existing use of pipelines constructed with composite materials to safely transport hydrogen and hydrogen blended with natural gas.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2B1A77570DD84B1396F59C76F3F803B4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Study considerations</header><text>In completing the study under subsection (a), the Secretary shall consider—</text><paragraph id="HFF060E134B144646B4E2C7A1486B1A5E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any commercially available composite pipeline materials;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4AE7291FDF3B4CE2B1C581625F4B921A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any completed or ongoing tests and data available to the Secretary or other Federal agencies; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H613E001FEB7B4D58A2650E589E12C593"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any recommended standards, including consensus standards, and Federal agency authorizations relating to use of the composite pipeline materials.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7D632233C00D46C68753342F8F18492D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Public participation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To ensure adequate public participation in completing the study under subsection (a), the Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="H3F88281E5CD34D7E9F20872C67FA8650"><enum>(1)</enum><text>hold a pre-completion public meeting with interested stakeholders, including affected industries, interest groups, and other individuals with relevant expertise;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC8F1837275B548D18DA076CF6D77E701"><enum>(2)</enum><text>release a draft version of the study for public comment for a period of not less than 60 days; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H13DEB60D481844DDA558F795FA05A24E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>address any substantive comments submitted by the public during the public comment period under paragraph (2) in preparing the final study.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H58B608B0E260448983D592418D737BD0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Public meeting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after the closing of the public comment period under subsection (c)(2), the Secretary shall hold a post-completion public meeting to present the findings of the study under subsection (a) and any responses to public comments received under subsection (c)(2).</text></subsection><subsection id="H7C76C5D4301B46518EBFACD05327872A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the public meeting described in subsection (d), the Secretary shall initiate a rulemaking that includes a notice of proposed rulemaking to allow for the use of composite materials for pipeline transportation of hydrogen and hydrogen blended with natural gas.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

