<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" slc-id="S1-NEW25018-S6K-L5-CXW"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 56 ATS: Congratulating the University of Vermont men's soccer team on winning the 2024 National Collegiate Athletic Association Division I men’s soccer national championship. </dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 56</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250204">February 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S422">Mr. Welch</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S313">Mr. Sanders</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Congratulating the University of Vermont men's soccer team on winning the 2024 National Collegiate Athletic Association Division I men’s soccer national championship. </official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, on December 16th, 2024, the University of Vermont men's soccer team (referred to in this preamble as the <quote>Catamounts</quote>), after a golden goal with 5 minutes and 6 seconds left in overtime, pulled off an historic comeback against Marshall University to win the 2024 National Collegiate Athletic Association (referred to in this preamble as <quote>NCAA</quote>) Division I men’s soccer national championship, with a final score of 2 goals to 1;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the 2024 NCAA Division I men's soccer national championship victory for the Catamounts is the first-ever NCAA Division I national championship in the history of the Catamounts;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the 2024 NCAA Division I men's soccer national championship game was a game for the record books, with many notable moments including—</text><paragraph id="id559174155bfd45da91652d6de8e4ade4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a perfectly timed goal by Marcell Papp, which gave the Catamounts a golden opportunity in overtime; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6b66417032e643b8b682a269fc88596c"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the game winning goal by Maximilian Kissel, his 11th goal of the season, which will be remembered by the Catamounts for all time;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the coaching staff of the Catamounts led the team with grit and determination;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the support staff of the Catamounts played critical roles in supporting the Catamounts throughout the 2024 season;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas, to the casual observer, the Catamounts may have been the underdogs or the <quote>Cinderella story</quote> of the entire 2024 NCAA Division I men's soccer national championship tournament;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, during the 2024 season, the Catamounts scored 22 goals in the 76th minute or later, including the championship equalizing goal, earning the Catamounts the nickname <quote>Cardiac Cats</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas last-minute victories were a habit for the Catamounts during the 2024 NCAA Division I men's soccer national championship tournament, including—</text><paragraph id="idc4579fa3080447e78dca44306e96f7e1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>beating San Diego University in overtime in the third round match; and </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8626f01f3eaf4919bb2396491320bce4"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">tying the University of Denver in the final minutes of the semifinal match to push the game into penalty kicks, where a save from Catamounts goalkeeper Niklas Herceg ended up securing the Catamounts a ticket to the championship match;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Vermonters and fans of the Catamounts congratulate the Catamounts for their well-deserved 2024 NCAA Division I men's soccer national championship win;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Catamounts are champions, not underdogs; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Catamounts made the people and State of Vermont very proud and showed the United States that the State of Vermont is, in fact, a soccer State: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="S1"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id6b06598b986048f9962e3f05796b1852"><enum>(1)</enum><text>congratulates the University of Vermont men's soccer team on winning the 2024 National Collegiate Athletic Association Division I men's soccer national championship; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idafc302b0d95e44cdae3b9354249e06b0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>respectfully requests that the Secretary of the Senate transmit an enrolled copy of this resolution to—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5c292175c907433988b6dd9ec098e703"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the interim president of the University of Vermont, Patricia A. Prelock;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id05ef7e600c7b4e1abb933a1fdbb19f97"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the director of athletics of the University of Vermont, Jeff Schulman; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id87dd7271a42d4ddea269a72a2db49c9b"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the head coach of the University of Vermont Catamounts men's soccer team, Rob Dow.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

