<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0760119E1B174DB6824C5CEB3BBD71B4" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1359 IH: Black History Matters Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1359</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250213">February 13, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="M001229">Mrs. McIver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000309">Mr. Jackson of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001127">Mrs. Cherfilus-McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000788">Ms. Williams of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001081">Mrs. Hayes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000187">Ms. Waters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000489">Mr. Turner of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001313">Ms. Brown</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000617">Ms. Pressley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001226">Mr. Menendez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000617">Mrs. Ramirez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000610">Ms. Plaskett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000602">Ms. Lee of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Director of the National Museum of African American History and Culture to conduct a study on Black history education efforts in public elementary and secondary schools, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9EC1367D9C024510964F0B50C60D3D2F" style="OLC"><section id="H37F1A296F2A84318BB0FA359801BDDEB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Black History Matters Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HA283EE97903E4B789B9EBDFEEF2AAF6C" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Study and report on Black history education</header><subsection id="H0727FD5ADCC440A8ABDB025DE3ECAF93"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><paragraph id="H1A2CA95EE7E84EC3AE29192458E2B20E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>During the period described in paragraph (2), the Director of the National Museum of African American History and Culture (referred to in this Act as the <quote>Director</quote>) shall conduct a study on Black history education efforts in public elementary and secondary schools.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H99CF21FE0CB94255B2150E242BC6552B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Period</header><text>The Director shall, with respect to the study required under paragraph (1)—</text><subparagraph id="HF7228590396448A48926222188B0C4A9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>begin such study not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE2041D09E4054AF2988695E260141770"><enum>(B)</enum><text>complete such study not later than 3 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4320E1511AD348D9A42D8F19EF664CDA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>In conducting the study under subsection (a), the Director shall—</text><paragraph id="H80E864C4F59F4764AB49629AA0AC4904"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identify States and local educational agencies that require Black history education as part of the curriculum taught in public elementary and secondary schools;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H06CCAA2A58B6463B8FB2ABBC353BA807"><enum>(2)</enum><text>identify States and local educational agencies that do not require Black history education as part of the curriculum taught in public elementary and secondary schools;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2DA74A0A3FAC489CAA31D748DC939C29"><enum>(3)</enum><text>assess the quality of Black history education provided by public elementary and secondary schools, including through the qualitative and quantitative analysis of such indicators as—</text><subparagraph id="H5D206E9711F640BC9E4DA090277F54BA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in-class discussion;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H06D1F3FA9FB34FA78AA5032BA71DC3D9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>educational activities conducted outside the classroom, including homework assignments; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC781B0F7ADA645D6BA12D858D17A5AA3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>project based learning;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H861599112A5F4DB09F9C9783575150A4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>assess the types and quality of instructional materials used to teach students about Black history;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2EAB89077E3D4FBCAE7D0A2590F50CC9"><enum>(5)</enum><text>examine the duration and comprehensiveness of any Black history-related courses or lessons provided by public elementary and secondary schools; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7BFDCB192CC749FFB42F09E9ED7F6073"><enum>(6)</enum><text>analyze the approaches used by such schools to assess students’ knowledge of Black history, including the use of traditional and nontraditional assessments.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1EBC0DFE3D2945F7AAF97917228A0C04"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><paragraph id="H341B230DB9AC4A2D991B86C0969F316B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Following the completion of the study under subsection (a), the Director shall prepare and submit to Congress a report on the results of the study.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H09D2F1A561E347168A5BAE73CDEE4172"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Deadline for submittal</header><text>The report required under paragraph (1) shall be submitted not later than 180 days after the completion of the study under subsection (a)(2)(B).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H606D214F19694A90AC972147ECCC4A0E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H588377DCFB874356B163489D113939E1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>ESEA terms</header><text>The terms <term>elementary school</term>, <term>local educational agency</term>, <term>secondary school</term>, and <term>State</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H65B7CFDC2E894A3BBC45957D61BBD81F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Black history</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Black history</term> means the study and stories of Black life in the United States and around the world, with a specific focus on the triumphs and struggles (including political, social, and cultural achievements) of African Americans throughout the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0136B02289CD4716BC984CAF418E9AA7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Black history education</header><text>The term <term>Black history education</term> means educational activities that are specifically intended—</text><subparagraph id="HE3902D61DC35431B86F2A1800E058DFE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to improve students’ awareness and understanding of the history of people of African descent, especially as it relates to United States history;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC71E6A46194046B694E73AA9A21379DD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to educate students on the lessons of chattel slavery, Reconstruction, Jim Crow laws, and the Civil Rights movement as a means to raise awareness about the importance of preventing genocide, hate, and bigotry against any group of people; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H18A7C0EA9D2345B592467A50C0057BE1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to study the history of racism, its deep historical roots, the use of discrimination and propaganda that target the Black people, and the evolving nature of white supremacy over time.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H39C44672BEDA474EA6B32CABAEDA22F6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Project based learning</header><text>The term <term>project based learning</term> means a teaching method through which students learn by actively engaging in real-world and personally meaningful projects.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

