<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ERN25094-MP0-2X-JH3"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1250 IS: Stopping Harmful Incidents to Enforce Lawful Drone Use Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1250</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250402">April 2, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S346">Mr. Lee</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To authorize Counter-UAS activities on and off commercial service airport property, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stopping Harmful Incidents to Enforce Lawful Drone Use Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SHIELD U Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idF0B47F8ADD1F4E1282BA9055FBF7B214"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph commented="no" id="id933B7F766D9A4597AE5AA7EFC8C14428"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Commercial service airport</header><text>The term <term>commercial service airport</term> has the meaning given that term in paragraph (7) of section 47102 of title 49, United States Code, and includes the area of navigable airspace necessary to ensure safety in the takeoff and landing of aircraft at the airport.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idd49365e05c1a4b92b079fe1aa9167872"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered air carrier</header><text>The term <term>covered air carrier</term> means an air carrier or a foreign air carrier as those terms are defined in section 40102 of title 49, United States Code. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id13FB2CFEB93546AE976A282B3944A0F6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Counter-UAS activities</header><text>The term <term>Counter-UAS activities</term> means the following:</text><subparagraph id="id93774b799e6b42b9a9bf86d78ea7a7c1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Detecting, identifying, monitoring, and tracking an unmanned aircraft or unmanned aircraft system, without prior consent, including by means of intercept or other access of a wire communication, an oral communication, or an electronic communication used to control the unmanned aircraft or unmanned aircraft system.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9c1e7cda71a348f58f90b8ee15ab4e0f"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Warning an operator of an unmanned aircraft or unmanned aircraft system, including by passive or active, and direct or indirect physical, electronic, radio, and electromagnetic means.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc6df49ec0dce408980d6a83fb5c1e184"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Disrupting control of an unmanned aircraft or unmanned aircraft system, without prior consent, including by disabling the unmanned aircraft or unmanned aircraft system by intercepting, interfering, or causing interference with wire, oral, electronic, or radio communications used to control the unmanned aircraft or unmanned aircraft system.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2801f0a3d66746b88e625e694987a578"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Seizing or exercising control of an unmanned aircraft or unmanned aircraft system.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida15f173035c344ed86361dc0b75d119c"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Seizing or otherwise confiscating an unmanned aircraft or unmanned aircraft system.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8d57b005535040219fa460affc8b99e6"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Using reasonable force to disable, damage, or destroy an unmanned aircraft or unmanned aircraft system. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id2FCAB93F24384C6FBEC84A6D4C7B7444"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Navigable airspace</header><text>The term <term>navigable airspace</term> has the meaning given that term in paragraph (32) of section 40102 of title 49, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id86ed78232370447382e5f046491c85c6"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Non-kinetic equipment</header><text>The term <term>non-kinetic equipment</term> means equipment that is used to—</text><subparagraph id="id4A7FC39F109F47339BD444399C3CD4A7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>intercept or otherwise access a wire communication, an oral communication, an electronic communication, or a radio communication used to control an unmanned aircraft or unmanned aircraft system; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2B885659AD8C46A89823E8056E9641BD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>disrupt control of the unmanned aircraft or unmanned aircraft system, without prior consent, including by disabling the unmanned aircraft or unmanned aircraft system by intercepting, interfering, or causing interference with wire, oral, electronic, or radio communications that are used to control the unmanned aircraft or unmanned aircraft system.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idBAA743BAAD9A4A83BA91D4FE64A0C159"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Threats posed by an unmanned aircraft or unmanned aircraft system</header><text>The term <term>threats posed by an unmanned aircraft or unmanned aircraft system</term> means an unauthorized activity of an unmanned aircraft or unmanned aircraft system that is reasonably believed to—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="idF8094F6B26D648209D2E50060B390739"><enum>(A)</enum><text>create the potential for bodily harm to, or loss of human life of, a person within property under the jurisdiction of—</text><clause commented="no" id="id6B367B7AC473415080A3E348C94640D5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a commercial service airport; or </text></clause><clause commented="no" id="idBE24BE6BA07A4420BF7A83F172B7F95B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a State or locality; or </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id42F1F479E3424F44AC600437E7C31FDD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>have the potential to cause severe economic damage to—</text><clause commented="no" id="idC51941E4232149A496A73B98A3565B5A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>property of a commercial service airport; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id876B8790B5474CC19FD2DBE0051516AF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>property under the jurisdiction of a State or locality. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id74171629C32844079D91968468D95B61"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Unmanned aircraft, unmanned aircraft system</header><text>The terms <term>unmanned aircraft</term> and <term>unmanned aircraft system</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 44801 of title 49, United States Code.</text></paragraph></section><section id="id61F432AAA19D4E4A8826A231D0EA68BB"><enum>3.</enum><header>Counter-UAS activities on commercial service airport property</header><subsection id="idA585F67A256F413FA437487CB4FADFB3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Counter-UAS activities</header><paragraph id="idB63F27AA6505408F85AC015F8BF16BFA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law and subject to paragraph (3), with respect to a commercial service airport, the following departments and agencies may, in a manner consistent with the Fourth Amendment to the Constitution of the United States, carry out Counter-UAS activities for purposes of detecting, identifying, and mitigating the threats posed by an unmanned aircraft or unmanned aircraft system to the safety or security of the airport: </text><subparagraph id="idab07ed71eeb54e48b866591bbd7e1288"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Department of Homeland Security.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1c434c92feb241adbfb4228d433f91c1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The State and local law enforcement agencies in the State in which the airport is located.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3af789452d9f4e80aedd5aefb1b689d9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The law enforcement agency of the airport.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id58464ec44bcb467fb6b7caa619c653e6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Testing authority</header><text>Subject to paragraphs (3) and (4), the Secretary of Homeland Security, the heads of the State or local law enforcement agencies of the State in which a commercial service airport is located, or the law enforcement agency of the commercial service airport, may research, test, provide training on, and evaluate any equipment, including any electronic equipment, to determine the capability and utility of the equipment to carry out Counter-UAS activities to detect, identify, and mitigate the threats posed by an unmanned aircraft or unmanned aircraft system to the safety or security of the airport. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="idBCDD47688754437A90EA5C7E86865BE4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Airport operator consent required</header><text>Activities permitted under paragraph (1) or (2) shall only be carried out with the consent of, in consultation with, and with the participation of, the airport operator. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="idD585674DB1E7409595AB76CE368258EE"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Consultation requirement for testing of non-kinetic equipment</header><text>Any testing of non-kinetic equipment carried out under the authority of this subsection shall be done in consultation with the Federal Communications Commission and the National Telecommunications and Information Administration. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idBE5C650921D141BF92DA538AD7FDA831"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Non-Kinetic equipment</header><paragraph id="idDE266C20A7E14DE5B1302EA1AA21834A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Before adopting any standard operating procedures within a tactical response plan for use of non-kinetic equipment to carry out a Counter-UAS activity under the authority of this section, the Secretary of Homeland Security and the heads of the State, local, or airport law enforcement agencies of the State in which a commercial service airport is located, shall do the following: </text><subparagraph id="id0CA2CA434ACF4F588BD97748DBD1FC5B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Consult with the Federal Communications Commission and the National Telecommunications and Information Administration about the use of non-kinetic equipment to carry out a Counter-UAS activity consistent with the tactical response plan updates required under subsection (c). </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1EF15D849FEE453D850B414B2A7487EA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Jointly, with the Federal Communications Commission and the National Telecommunications and Information Administration, create a process for an authorized designee of the commercial service airport to, consistent with procedures outlined in the tactical response plan (as updated under subsection (c)), notify the Commission when non-kinetic equipment has been used to carry out a Counter-UAS activity. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idF02DD8EDB53E4948A658B0AC97F1AEB9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>FCC and NTIA duties</header><text>The Federal Communications Commission and the National Telecommunications and Information Administration shall— </text><subparagraph id="id80988d053660414cb8a2e9c29881d15e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, assign to an office of the Commission and to an office of the Administration, respectively, responsibility for carrying out the consultation regarding the use of non-kinetic equipment to carry out Counter-UAS activities required by paragraph (1)(A) and the consultation regarding the testing of non-kinetic equipment required by subsection (a)(4); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7512b9f8f52e4580bc2a739b54af0ea9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not later than 180 days after the responsibility described in subparagraph (A) is assigned to each such office—</text><clause id="id64700C2DE2334A17A044158B03DE8ED1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>publicly designate an office of the Commission and an office of the Administration, respectively, to receive the notifications from commercial service airports required under paragraph (1)(B); and</text></clause><clause id="idE22E59B5B20242349489323B4D46C7B2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>make publicly available the process for the Commission and the Administration to carry out any follow-up consultation, if necessary. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id235126b840574ad6b4e1a7166517871c"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Nonduplication</header><text>To the greatest extent practicable, the Federal Communications Commission and the National Telecommunications and Information Administration shall coordinate with respect to the consultations, process creation, follow-up consultations, and other requirements of this subsection and subsection (a)(4) so as to minimize duplication of requirements, efforts, and expenditures. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id421FE0E80CA64A878D7D760089EA414F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Tactical response plan updates</header><paragraph id="id64B807ADE0574D4395F01AF15DAD945B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Task force</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the airport director of each commercial service airport shall convene a task force for purposes of establishing or modifying the emergency action preparedness plan for the airport to include a tactical response plan for the detection, identification, and mitigation of threats posed by an unmanned aircraft or unmanned aircraft system. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4E4AB3313B2C494EA335D305E0E6B391"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Required coordination</header><text>Each task force convened under paragraph (1) shall coordinate the establishing or modifying of the airport's emergency action preparedness plan with representatives of the following:</text><subparagraph id="id493f3766e83d4169bab8acf5360f310b"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Department of Transportation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idA06107719F724B678F18133B7198F725"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Federal Aviation Administration.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idcf2909e0ba354a37832e187785b11211"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Department of Homeland Security. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id345a4d7bc9154932a7ded777ecb06907"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The State and local law enforcement agencies in the State in which the airport is located.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="idB9EF16DA12964338AD7037910771A8DD"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The law enforcement agency of the airport. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc4bdcca5d7bf4ebb87956e38b1a1214a"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The covered air carriers operating at the airport. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id65c4cad5f6ee463eab4d5648efea06fb"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Representatives of general aviation operators at the airport.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9E06849A192040449B8660644D872D4D"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Representatives of providers of telecommunications and broadband service with a service area that covers the airport property or the navigable airspace necessary to ensure safety in the takeoff and landing of aircraft at such airport. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id15BCB26A46584277BBF5F877FF3BD7C6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>As part of the inclusion of a tactical response plan in the emergency action preparedness plan for a commercial service airport, each task force convened under paragraph (1) shall do the following:</text><subparagraph id="id9fd08d0d5e9c4d159f1b9fcf83cf5f0a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Create and define the various threat levels posed by an unmanned aircraft or unmanned aircraft system to the airport.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idcd756f070ba44bd5a390088dc0f065b1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Create the standard operating procedures for responding to each threat level defined under subparagraph (A) that include a requirement to minimize collateral damage. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4127cfe521324f508fc1ea16072ec6b6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Define and assign to each entity specified in paragraph (2), the role and responsibilities of the entity in carrying out the standard operating procedures for responding to a specified threat posed by an unmanned aircraft or unmanned aircraft system to the airport.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idFAD847D9CBF7427CA138B25D10D4A84E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Designate the applicable State and local law enforcement agencies, or the law enforcement agency of the airport, in coordination with the Department of Homeland Security, as the first responders to any specified threat posed by an unmanned aircraft or unmanned aircraft system to the airport. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id332833A851604AD994BEE5184396DC79"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Narrowly tailor the use of non-kinetic Counter-UAS equipment (if applicable under the standard operating procedures) to only temporary activities necessary to mitigate an immediate threat posed by an unmanned aircraft or unmanned aircraft system to the airport. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1FF5B11BC56042D59FAD7399F53225D1"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Incorporate any existing Federal guidance for updating airport emergency plans for responding to unauthorized unmanned aircraft system operations into 1 tactical response plan for addressing threats posed by an unmanned aircraft or unmanned aircraft system. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idFEB7B3BDE78D48B5B22488FCCF88F480"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to require multiple tactical response plans or emergency action preparedness plans for addressing the threats posed by an unmanned aircraft, an unmanned aircraft system, or unauthorized unmanned aircraft system operations. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id13072e49fc644b63a8dd15e502d66f90"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Airport improvement program eligibility</header><text>Notwithstanding section 47102 of title 49, United States Code, the definition of the term <term>airport development</term> under that section shall include the purchase of equipment necessary to carry out Counter-UAS activities at commercial service airports. </text></subsection><subsection id="id9BA15B7EB5D444848B3128448E5CAB01"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Best practices</header><paragraph id="id18CD8CA9E826422E8DAEF05F46532049"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration and the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration acting jointly and in collaboration with airport directors of commercial service airports, shall—</text><subparagraph id="id16E5661F53094D7BA551CA5D9BB4B74B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>publish guidance regarding best practices for use of Counter-UAS Activities at commercial service airports; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB8E2D5B395E049AC86E0B207AEA71D59"><enum>(B)</enum><text>make such guidance available to the airport director for each commercial service airport in the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idB36492B5B2DF45A7BD11D2193BF2BA08"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Annual updates</header><text>The guidance issued under this subsection shall be annually updated to incorporate the most recent results and conclusions regarding best practices for the use of Counter-UAS activities at commercial service airports. </text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idFC1E50514B5D418C83CBD9AA6D714415"><enum>4.</enum><header>Counter-UAS activities off commercial service airport property</header><subsection id="idCAC5C15A625B4CE79C4AD90D37C8EACC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, with respect to a State, the State and local law enforcement agencies in the State may, in a manner consistent with the Fourth Amendment to the Constitution of the United States, carry out Counter-UAS activities for purposes of detecting, identifying, and mitigating the threats posed by an unmanned aircraft or unmanned aircraft system within the jurisdiction of the State or locality. </text></subsection><subsection id="idF4A943405FCE4D28B1EF57E95224FE86"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Testing authority</header><paragraph id="idEC2347DAC3A4468C99B90D30FDFF67D4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><subparagraph id="id5F37FFAB379A4B75973B1E1701D923B1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>States and localities</header><text>Subject to paragraphs (2) and (3), any State or locality of a State may establish testing areas for purposes of researching, testing, providing training on, and evaluating of any equipment, including any electronic equipment, to determine the capability and utility of the equipment to carry out Counter-UAS activities to detect, identify, and mitigate the threats posed by an unmanned aircraft or unmanned aircraft system within the jurisdiction of the State or locality.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD9C5A18BFC0D41A1948630BF6F4AE432"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Private sector entities</header><text>Subject to paragraphs (2) and (3), any private sector entity may establish testing areas for purposes of researching, testing, providing training on, and evaluating of any equipment, including any electronic equipment, to determine the capability and utility of the equipment to carry out Counter-UAS activities to detect, identify, and mitigate the threats posed by an unmanned aircraft or unmanned aircraft system, so long as such activities are carried out in accordance with applicable State and local laws.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idA79B6227C768446C827406DC6413516F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>FAA cooperation</header><text>The Federal Aviation Administration shall cooperate with any action by a State, a locality of a State, or a private sector entity to designate airspace to be used for testing under paragraph (1) unless the State, locality, or entity designates an area of airspace that would create a significant safety hazard to airport operations, air navigation facilities, air traffic control systems, or other components of the national airspace system that facilitate the safe and efficient operation of manned civil, commercial, or military aircraft within the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id415F5B2E7EA1486F9890AE7EFBCB54C5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Consultation requirement for testing of non-kinetic equipment</header><text>Any testing of non-kinetic equipment carried out under the authority of this subsection shall be done in consultation with the Federal Communications Commission and the National Telecommunications and Information Administration. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id91E3514EAC304F448AED5118545EC859"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Non-Kinetic equipment</header><paragraph id="id5304EFAC5A97468AB574B3EEFBFBE51F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Before adopting any standard operating procedures for using any non-kinetic equipment to carry out a Counter-UAS activity under the authority of this section, a State or local law enforcement agency shall do the following:</text><subparagraph id="id5D87C7EBF1874C959561AC76A27B0F01"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Consult with the Federal Communications Commission and the National Telecommunications and Information Administration about the use of non-kinetic equipment to carry out a Counter-UAS activity and the standard operating procedures that the State or local law enforcement agency will follow for use of such equipment. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id23F057BFF11D4E079EF08E94B3124773"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Jointly, with the Federal Communications Commission and the National Telecommunications and Information Administration create a process for an authorized designee of the State or local law enforcement agency to notify the Commission when non-kinetic equipment has been used to carry out a Counter-UAS activity. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idF0EE8D577B874373BDFD2C07FE6999D3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>FCC and NTIA duties</header><text>The Federal Communications Commission shall—</text><subparagraph id="idC0891493BC8B44548BC404E0E853F470"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, assign to an office of the Commission and to an office of the Administration, respectively, responsibility for carrying out the consultation regarding the use of non-kinetic equipment to carry out Counter-UAS activities required under paragraph (1)(A) and the consultation regarding the testing of non-kinetic equipment required by subsection (b)(3); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5516583E21DE4019B47B39902996415D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not later than 180 days after the responsibility described in subparagraph (A) is assigned to each such office—</text><clause id="id4BA8270967BA4801ABCEB588498A3D31"><enum>(i)</enum><text>publicly designate an office of the Commission and an office of the Administration, respectively, to receive the notifications from State or local law enforcement agencies required under paragraph (1)(B); and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2BE5799D6F2146CCB957F1324D857003"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>make publicly available the process for the Commission and the Administration to carry out any follow-up consultation, if necessary. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7E3007B0EA59475F8A15C601B7039B57"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Nonduplication</header><text>To the greatest extent practicable, the Federal Communications Commission and the National Telecommunications and Information Administration shall coordinate with respect to the consultations, process creation, follow-up consultations, and other requirements of this subsection and subsection (a)(4) so as to minimize duplication of requirements, efforts, and expenditures. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0EDA443BAA314ECF800641DA9B09047F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Coordination with the FAA</header><text>Section 376 of the FAA Reauthorization Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/44802">49 U.S.C. 44802</external-xref> note) is amended—</text><paragraph id="idE1D7391CC3974F87B7644300ACED452C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b), by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idCD7AAAA6FB824547BAA0083D3500AC7C"><paragraph id="id2D8F41D8321A46628CC59142133C0D46"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Permit a process for an applicable State or local law enforcement agency to notify and coordinate with the Federal Aviation Administration on actions being taken by the State or local law enforcement agency to exercise the Counter-UAS activities authority established under section 4(a) of the <short-title>SHIELD U Act</short-title>.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="id865AEDD7D3F549C1B3DA0B6B5FEDF915"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text><subparagraph id="idD9132FB303464F8E90A425941B7E4ABF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)(G), by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idBE345EC700ED4E8B84994AA7AB8989E4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3359D1BAE559427C849A2BE125051513"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idA880C547E2914F658F406841DA15D435"><paragraph id="id614D505343424E849A93F2EA11496D02"><enum>(5)</enum><text>establish a process that allows for collaboration and coordination between the Federal Aviation Administration and the law enforcement of a State or local government with respect to the use of the Counter-UAS activities authority established under section 4(a) of the <short-title>SHIELD U Act</short-title>.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id5C8DB8E8EB44400FA3DA56E8AE73D947"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Interim notification plan</header><paragraph id="id600098E12C2140DA8DA06EDC86599220"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall establish a process under which—</text><subparagraph id="id73ABE6617C4C4EC98DD9C87FD3657FCF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the law enforcement agency of a State or local government may notify the Administrator of an active threat posed by an unmanned aircraft or unmanned aircraft system within the jurisdiction of the State or local law enforcement agency and the intent of the agency to facilitate Counter-UAS activities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idee1bb7fc46984ddf8024b4c14e6e5caf"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Administrator, based on notice made pursuant to subparagraph (A), shall issue immediate warnings to operators of both manned and unmanned aircraft operating within the area of airspace where the law enforcement agency’s Counter-UAS activities are taking place; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida65b6a2cd7034543a32596a3e8d8952d"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Administrator and the State and local law enforcement agency notify UAS operators and manned operators in the area that an area of airspace is clear once the State and local law enforcement have concluded the Counter-UAS activities to mitigate the threat. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id0E9070A47158454383C156757035F5AE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>The process established under paragraph (1) shall terminate on the date on which the unmanned aircraft systems traffic management system required under section 376 of the FAA Reauthorization Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/44802">49 U.S.C. 44802</external-xref> note) is fully implemented.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id38263599B7024ECDACA43C777FED0773"><enum>5.</enum><header>Authority to enter into contracts to protect facilities from unmanned aircraft</header><subsection id="idD040CFABD6D4415EAD403E269BC1E4FC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority</header><text>The following Federal departments are authorized to enter into contracts to carry out the following authorities:</text><paragraph id="id2CD6189C05A2423C838E91A37A9D903A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Department of Defense for the purpose of carrying out activities under section 130i of title 10, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idF7DD251D848E427BAE3F32EA9FF73237"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Department of Homeland Security for the purpose of carrying out activities under section 210G of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/124n">6 U.S.C. 124n</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idE162B45E3E3C4C8DB59E86ED39C6A33C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Department of Justice for the purpose of carrying out activities under section 210G of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/124n">6 U.S.C. 124n</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idE46FD2272B4E4A30A68D6452A800693D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Department of Energy for the purpose of carrying out activities under section 4510 of the Atomic Energy Defense Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/2661">50 U.S.C. 2661</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id557AF6F6BFAE4D62AB9BC223EC2377B3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Federal Acquisition Regulation</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Federal Acquisition Regulatory Council shall amend the Federal Acquisition Regulation to implement the authority provided under subsection (a). </text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id384A88A0BAF14AD9B77728FA29916119"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Annual publication of recommended vendors and equipment</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6A004E9885C14A38A78EA5C55B89F011"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Attorney General, the Secretary of Energy, the Secretary of Transportation, and the heads of such other Federal departments or agencies as determined appropriate by the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, shall publish and make available to State and local governments the following:</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id103434FFFA874194A33CF49E885983F6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A list of vendors that are eligible under the Federal Acquisition Regulation to enter into contracts with the Federal Government to carry out Counter-UAS activities.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6118aacd757a47a4a9dc87b0c4f190f3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A list of Counter-UAS equipment that is recommended by the Federal Government to carry out Counter-UAS activities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id3d787269448e47e6b6aaed21b3b0aa87"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Annual risk assessment</header><text>The Director of the Office of Management and Budget, in consultation with the heads of the applicable Federal departments and agencies, shall review and reassess the vendors and equipment specified on the lists required to be published and made available under paragraph (1) based on a risk assessment that is jointly considered by the applicable agencies as part of each annual update of such lists. </text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id4E24B0BA22564716A04806559AA7CE69"><enum>6.</enum><header>Federal law enforcement training</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 884(c) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/464">6 U.S.C. 464(c)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="idCBA8604D9D5E4239A03F866906D3B717"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (9), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6F2F752A01994376A470C12AF157E68D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (10) as paragraph (11); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id13A01BE0ED8847BE9D599A0BAAB27866"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (9) the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id44B1181716F644CE801EA32323B75A6A"><paragraph id="id24BB8AE71E904B359CE7AE93CE2FA909"><enum>(10)</enum><text>develop and implement homeland security and law enforcement training curricula related to the use of Counter-UAS activities (as defined in section 2 of the <short-title>SHIELD U Act</short-title>) to protect against a threat from an unmanned aircraft or unmanned aircraft system (as such terms are defined in section 210G), which shall—</text><subparagraph id="id2E1E6082BF304861B6BFE65144AE43CE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>include—</text><clause id="id2C5024B38FEB4FC9BB3A88360787A757"><enum>(i)</enum><text>training on the use of both kinetic and non-kinetic equipment; </text></clause><clause id="idFB00D3E62CC94E0F9F88B3C2027E6952"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>training on the tactics used to detect, identify, and mitigate a threat from an unmanned aircraft or unmanned aircraft system; and</text></clause><clause id="id5596C737547044CAA55586E6F1BB51A0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>such other curricula or training the Director believes necessary; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4B261181390D4A0A99A3BE68D30146FE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>be made available to Federal, State, local, Tribal, and territorial law enforcement and security agencies and private sector security agencies; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="id3AA56CC9893341B5A041F68C2E1FA373"><enum>7.</enum><header>Authorized use of jamming technology</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title III of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/301">47 U.S.C. 301 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="id6F6E9302999F44D1A92F8726530D3A86"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 301 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/301">47 U.S.C. 301</external-xref>)—</text><subparagraph id="id6AC4335D8F4D4477B5E37DF67AA57AD1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>It is</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1E453F3CC57B408581FB9ACF63B4CCF6"><subsection id="idE9EB46E82637421E91CA7F7CB3A1B97F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>It is</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id792167C38E8C42FE992EBDD5D21B8805"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7F5FB1203101442480B04E4EA13A6B42"><subsection id="idAC7BE633487A4C1D9C7258B9832B2029"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exception for an unmanned aircraft and unmanned aircraft system</header><paragraph id="idF161BBB880B3415E8E6352252B71B49E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection—</text><subparagraph id="idFC286598C7B24781A66E2772F9F5B8F4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the term <term>covered equipment</term> means equipment that is used to—</text><clause id="idDE50961351E2499EB3C4B700B67FF311"><enum>(i)</enum><text>intercept or otherwise access a wire communication, an oral communication, an electronic communication, or a radio communication used to control an unmanned aircraft or unmanned aircraft system; and</text></clause><clause id="id4D0B501D665243E28BE4D414C77FDDD9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>disrupt control of an unmanned aircraft or unmanned aircraft system, without prior consent, including by disabling the unmanned aircraft or unmanned aircraft system by intercepting, interfering, or causing interference with wire, oral, electronic, or radio communications that are used to control the unmanned aircraft or unmanned aircraft system; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6C3C4E528E194EB9A7209085A94006A8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the terms <term>unmanned aircraft</term> and <term>unmanned aircraft system</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 44801 of title 49, United States Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id349E92748956465A8BC2D0CFE26493AC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Subsection (a) shall not apply with respect to actions taken by State or local law enforcement or the law enforcement agency of a commercial service airport using covered equipment in consultation with the Commission to detect, identify, or mitigate a threat posed by an unmanned aircraft or unmanned aircraft system.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id35DA803E2D7543C2B6BA0FDD806C940B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 302 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/302a">47 U.S.C. 302a</external-xref>), by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id09361E7EEAB7413DB65012E6370734DE"><subsection id="idFF37ADE979654279B4A49105016350A4"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Exception for an unmanned aircraft and unmanned aircraft system</header><paragraph id="idD9ADA663FE1E41B08BD3DCBFFB2FF0B8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection, the terms <term>covered equipment</term>, <term>unmanned aircraft</term>, and <term>unmanned aircraft system</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 301.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id524F5A6243DA48D3B894B12AAB2BD6C7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The provisions of this section shall not apply with respect to actions taken by State or local law enforcement or the law enforcement agency of a commercial service airport using covered equipment in consultation with the Commission to detect, identify, or mitigate a threat posed by an unmanned aircraft or unmanned aircraft system.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="idCE935268843D4B5588A0C2E5E4DB2E0B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in section 333 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/333">47 U.S.C. 333</external-xref>)—</text><subparagraph id="id074037911EEF4DE9A476545796C8DB7B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>No person</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id027551283C0F499ABA76DA7651EE2742"><subsection id="idD6EE6A621CC147A38CDCAC31824E6CF6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>No person</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC0F8A54982724401A0A3A4896516E60B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6360CA542BF74930AE83EB8881277CD0"><subsection id="id060AAE00B9114F8697EDC995B774408D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exception for an unmanned aircraft and unmanned aircraft system</header><paragraph id="idC2F9D6E4A107430DAAC92C3190014205"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection, the terms <term>covered equipment</term>, <term>unmanned aircraft</term>, and <term>unmanned aircraft system</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 301(b).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9DC4A67A14974E36A54ACC2296208A5A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Subsection (a) shall not apply with respect to actions taken by State or local law enforcement or the law enforcement agency of a commercial service airport using covered equipment in consultation with the Commission to detect, identify, or mitigate a threat posed by an unmanned aircraft or unmanned aircraft system.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="idcd332f9a1a4c4d55a653ec9c54fbe7fd"><enum>8.</enum><header>No abrogation of traditional police powers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act or the amendments made by this Act shall be construed to abrogate the inherent authority of a State government or subdivision thereof from using their traditional police powers, including (but not limited to) the authority to counter an imminent threat to public health or safety. </text></section></legis-body></bill> 

