<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC801E61D926A4F85AD4C8F34D983CFC5" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 289 IH: Expressing support for the designation of April 2025 as “Second Chance Month”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 289</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250401">April 1, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000821">Mr. Westerman</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001212">Mr. Moore of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001205">Mrs. Miller of West Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001208">Mrs. McBath</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of April 2025 as <quote>Second Chance Month</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas every individual is endowed with human dignity and value;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas redemption and second chances are values of the United States;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas millions of citizens of the United States have a criminal record;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas hundreds of thousands of individuals return to their communities from Federal and State prisons every year;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas individuals returning from Federal and State prisons have paid their debt for committing crimes but still face significant legal and societal barriers (referred to in this preamble as <quote>collateral consequences</quote>);</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas collateral consequences for an individual returning from a Federal or State prison are mandatory and take effect automatically, regardless of—</text> 
<paragraph id="H270139460CE74AA4B5A5F5BE44BF1BAA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>whether there is a nexus between the crime and public safety;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC91DF5A422504664BBD4D9640B9179E5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the seriousness of the crime;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H74F492BEC907456D85A4495C8BB60C3D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the time that has passed since the individual committed the crime; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB90CB167721042C9BF59266E20C98E1B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the efforts of the individual to make amends or earn back the trust of the public;</text></paragraph></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, for individuals returning to their communities from Federal and State prisons, gaining meaningful employment is one of the most significant predictors of successful reentry and has been shown to reduce future criminal activity;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas many individuals who have been incarcerated struggle to find employment and access capital to start a small business because of collateral consequences, which are sometimes not directly related to the offenses the individuals committed or any proven public safety benefit;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas many States have laws that prohibit an individual with a criminal record from working in certain industries or obtaining professional licenses;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, in addition to employment, education has also been shown to be a significant predictor of successful reentry for individuals returning from Federal and State prisons;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas an individual with a criminal record often has a lower level of educational attainment than the general population and has significant difficulty acquiring admission to, and funding for, educational programs;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas an individual who has been convicted of certain crimes is often barred from receiving the financial aid necessary to acquire additional skills and knowledge through certain formal educational programs;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas an individual with a criminal record—</text> <paragraph id="HD101AB80E63145D9A114852B2FFE9193"><enum>(1)</enum><text>faces collateral consequences in securing a place to live; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6942E9EC98AE4C3BB89414B92930E711"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is often barred from seeking access to public housing;</text></paragraph></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas collateral consequences can prevent millions of individuals in the United States from contributing fully to their families and communities;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas collateral consequences can have an impact on public safety by contributing to recidivism;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas collateral consequences have particularly impacted underserved communities of color and community rates of employment, housing stability, and recidivism;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the inability to find gainful employment and other collateral consequences inhibit the economic mobility of an individual with a criminal record, which can negatively impact the well-being of the children and families of the individual for generations;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the bipartisan First Step Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/391">Public Law 115–391</external-xref>; 132 Stat. 5194) was signed into law on December 21, 2018, to increase opportunities for individuals incarcerated in Federal prisons to participate in meaningful recidivism reduction programs and prepare for their second chances;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the programs authorized by the Second Chance Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/199">Public Law 110–199</external-xref>; 122 Stat. 657)—</text> <paragraph id="H0F9B12602C0A4F3EAA2F5BA031A8C904"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have provided reentry services to more than 442,000 individuals in 49 States and the District of Columbia since the date of the enactment of such Act; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAF8E7297877B4C6EA31E9FF4046EADD8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>were reauthorized by the First Step Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/391">Public Law 115–391</external-xref>; 132 Stat. 5194);</text></paragraph></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the anniversary of the death of Charles Colson, who used his second chance following his incarceration for a Watergate-related crime to found Prison Fellowship, the largest program in the United States that provides outreach to prisoners, former prisoners, and their families, falls on April 21; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the designation of April as <quote>Second Chance Month</quote> may contribute to—</text> <paragraph id="H8AF0488E9D9B4D45BAC6B57594665F05"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">increased public awareness about—</text>
<subparagraph id="HB250E3D1E831464090CFF2437D9100B4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the impact of collateral consequences; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1F1F48DB11164449AD312C177CB8F46E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the need for closure for individuals with a criminal record who have paid their debt; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H89B53E5FA8F24B56B0AD787883EF44C8"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">opportunities for individuals, employers, congregations, and communities to extend second chances to those individuals: Now, therefore, be it</text></paragraph></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HB1065290B564452F9CC6565CEB36318F"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H57A8B1EDAA274C37954AC4DD8046B40B"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> 
<paragraph id="H781C5B23503B4AFEB39E0640F0E385E2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the designation of <quote>Second Chance Month</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7BEE9FFB29A9478088C83802C5B1261B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>honors the work of communities, governmental institutions, nonprofit organizations, congregations, employers, and individuals to remove unnecessary legal and societal barriers that prevent individuals with criminal records from becoming productive members of society; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H39E512FAB2BF4A3DB4D5295AC0D0AC18"><enum>(3)</enum><text>calls upon the people of the United States to observe <quote>Second Chance Month</quote> through actions and programs that—</text> <subparagraph id="H8300CBEC5941424A8A219FEBBFFAB645"><enum>(A)</enum><text>promote awareness of those unnecessary legal and social barriers; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H11F0E9C0069847DAA6541DA753578C48"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide closure for individuals with a criminal record who have paid their debt.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

