<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCC42A8FE80CF4F68B16437743FFC7ED2" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 33 IH: Supporting the goals and ideals of Korean American Day.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 33</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250113">January 13, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000585">Mr. Gomez</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="K000397">Mrs. Kim</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001287">Mr. Bera</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001296">Mr. Boyle of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001055">Mr. Case</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000491">Mr. Tran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001156">Ms. Sánchez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001159">Ms. Strickland</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000510">Mr. Smith of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000788">Ms. Williams of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001241">Mr. Min</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Lieu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000400">Ms. Kamlager-Dove</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000474">Mrs. Torres of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001205">Ms. Scanlon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000795">Mr. Wilson of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001230">Mr. Subramanyam</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001229">Mrs. McIver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000483">Ms. Friedman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001225">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000590">Ms. Lee of Nevada</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001215">Ms. Stevens</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001207">Ms. Sherrill</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001208">Mrs. McBath</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001218">Ms. Stansbury</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000468">Mrs. Fletcher</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001201">Mr. Suozzi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000185">Mr. Scott of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001123">Mr. Cisneros</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001112">Mr. Carbajal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001226">Mr. Menendez</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Supporting the goals and ideals of Korean American Day.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the influence of Korean Americans may be observed in all facets of American life, from politics to industry, entrepreneurship to volunteerism, the arts, and education;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on January 13, 1903, 102 courageous Korean immigrants arrived in the United States initiating the first large wave of Korean immigration to America;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas these pioneer Korean immigrants faced tremendous social and economic obstacles as well as language barriers in America, the land of opportunity;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in pursuit of the American dream, Korean immigrants initially served as farmworkers, wage laborers, and section hands throughout the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas first generation Korean immigrants established a new home in a new land through resilience, tenacious effort, and immense sacrifice, which became the bedrock for their children and future generations of Korean Americans;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the centennial year of 2003 marked an important milestone in the history of Korean immigration;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the House passed House Resolution 487 to commemorate Korean American Day in the 109th Congress;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Senate passed Senate Resolution 283 to commemorate Korean American Day in the 109th Congress;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Korean Americans, like other groups of immigrants that came to the United States before them, seeking a better life and opportunity, have thrived in their new homeland due to a strong work ethic, family bonds, and community spirit;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Korean Americans have made significant contributions to the economic vitality of the United States and the global marketplace;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Korean Americans have made history by winning elections throughout the country in local, State, and Federal levels of political office;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Korean Americans have invigorated businesses, not-for-profit and other nongovernmental organizations, government, technology, medicine, athletics, arts and entertainment, journalism, churches, academic communities, and countless facets of American life;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Korean Americans have built and strengthened the alliance between the United States and the Republic of Korea, fostering peace on the Korean Peninsula;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Korean Americans have made enormous contributions to the military strength of the United States and served with distinction in the Armed Forces during World War I, World War II, the Vietnam war, the conflict in Korea, and subsequent military conflicts across the globe; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Centennial Committees of Korean Immigration and Korean Americans have designated January 13 of each year as <quote>Korean American Day</quote> to commemorate the first step of the long and prosperous journey of Korean Americans in the United States: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HB78CDF0B36D04681A93D301F4722FA8E"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H17B8A8D117144F0B800FD7376F6CB636"><enum/><text>That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="HB91E7DCDD5B649238B88060099AD5448"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the goals and ideals of Korean American Day;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEED4FF79713044C6843487E82F4913DB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>urges all Americans to observe Korean American Day so as to have a greater appreciation of the invaluable contributions Korean Americans have made to the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC99955EC4723488EA2B37F76AC201475"><enum>(3)</enum><text>honors and recognizes the 122nd anniversary of the arrival of the first Korean immigrants to the United States.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

