<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5679F8D85A624B24A5213C4486CF2050" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2538 IH: Comprehensive Alternative Response for Emergencies Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2538</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250401">April 1, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001126">Mr. Carey</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="D000399">Mr. Doggett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001205">Mrs. Miller of West Virginia</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000579">Mr. Ryan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XI of the Social Security Act to require the Center for Medicare and Medicaid Innovation to test a comprehensive alternative response for emergencies model under the Medicare program.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF28CD5251F134D61A9971C67C6831F7B" style="OLC"><section id="H36CE4E4CB747446B86F5DF8CF632605F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Comprehensive Alternative Response for Emergencies Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>CARE Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HCB8125A2A91349DE88CFC5A3195E769C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Requiring the Center for Medicare and Medicaid Innovation to test a comprehensive alternative response for emergencies model under the Medicare program</header><subsection id="HA5C807D02E9F47AF9414C34D3E2EB44D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1115A of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1315a">42 U.S.C. 1315a</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H9089F80F0FD241B78622D00A11EE9014"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text><subparagraph id="H13CAA7BC564F462A866A71D69DCB8773"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)(A), in the third sentence, by inserting <quote>, and, beginning not later than the date that is 2 years after the date of the enactment of the CARE Act of 2025, shall include the Comprehensive Alternative Response for Emergencies Model described in subsection (h)</quote> before the period at the end; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB92B6DBC69B049538394ABE6A75D74A6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraphs (3)(B), by striking <quote>The Secretary</quote> and inserting <quote>Except in the case of the model described in subsection (h), the Secretary</quote>; and </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H47E11A88AB0C467989BD8F25890E025E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H98E89AE3B1C4496AB7E78713E1D53500" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="HD905F85892714AE881238443F4424879"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Comprehensive alternative response for emergencies model</header><paragraph id="H4146C5299B6E475FBA76F2910410A141"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of subsection (b)(2)(A), the Comprehensive Alternative Response for Emergencies Model described in this subsection is a model under which payment is made under part B of title XVIII for treatment services furnished to an individual enrolled under such part by a provider or supplier of ground ambulance services (as described in section 1834(l)), or by an entity under arrangement with such a provider, when such services—</text><subparagraph id="HC71FE6F8285944A38A5810B0555E53EF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>include the dispatch of a ground ambulance vehicle but do not include a corresponding transport payable under such section; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB0E8745388F64CB2930ADE31CBFCC81D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>are so furnished in response to an emergency medical call (as specified by the Secretary) made with respect to such individual; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H479FE117E45C4BC693B6EC90DE5E58CA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>are so furnished in accordance with State and local licensure requirements and protocols (which may include online medical direction through the use of audiovisual telecommunications technology).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFE83033DB6F34FDD9959D66A2FFDD8E2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Payment</header><subparagraph id="HE2F07B9EE87040AF992B051D2957FC90"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall set payment rates for services furnished under the model described in paragraph (1) in a manner that generally aligns such payments with the payments that would have been made for such services had such services resulted in a transport payable under section 1834(l).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H81237085313E480DB830897B23507EBD"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Originating site fee</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a telehealth service payable under section 1834(m) that is furnished in conjunction with treatment services furnished under the model described in paragraph (1), the site where the individual receiving such telehealth service is located shall be treated as an originating site that is described in paragraph (4)(C)(ii)(V) of such section for purposes of applying paragraph (2)(B) of such section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD0D87772A93C45B4BF2C6470F83EAEC9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>The model described in paragraph (1) shall be carried out for a period of 5 years.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H056C18AE62164F11B0C1DD12D93C96A5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 4 years after the date on which the Comprehensive Alternative Response for Emergencies Model (as described in section 1115A(h) of the Social Security Act, as added by subsection (a)) is implemented, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate a report that, taking into account stakeholder input and to the extent data is available—</text><paragraph id="HA2E93767568A4EDBB0972CB43BCD5FF3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>analyzes various aspects of Medicare beneficiaries’ access to emergency medical services, including an evaluation of the impact of such model on beneficiary outcomes and resource utilization;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H32691C96B5424E62AE4957375E102568"><enum>(2)</enum><text>compares beneficiary outcomes under such model with beneficiary outcomes using traditional emergency transportation;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H374FF42FFFD24C3D9C4C811D6062BB62"><enum>(3)</enum><text>assesses the impact of regional variations and demographics on the availability of emergency medical services;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H85DA194212F54AF9A654B28A3361AF2F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>identifies best practices and potential challenges in implementing such model; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFE22A353EDCD4DB19D819F0BF0B82630"><enum>(5)</enum><text>includes recommendations for improving emergency medical services.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

