<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H54EC49FC597C409AAED256DB04F47FB7" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4971 IH: Terrorist Watchlist Data Accuracy and Transparency Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4971</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250815">August 15, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to improve the accuracy of the Department of Homeland Security’s terrorism screening information, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H4C6D007CD6E746E3865648F6750DFFE2" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H5DFE8ACA503545F7B10D20E3D18F61DE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Terrorist Watchlist Data Accuracy and Transparency Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HDEFEF6C9CFD74A80975C4B2DE747A444"><enum>2.</enum><header>Quality assurance reviews of Department of Homeland Security nominations to the terrorist watchlist and other terrorism databases</header> <subsection id="H08F0B84901774ECB8E9AEE7AE2B6C33C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subtitle A of title II of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/121">6 U.S.C. 121 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H99689D4589AD43E5AA22E76E4E621443" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H44D4F149C4FF43709D4FDDABCAF01E9D"><enum>210H.</enum><header>Quality assurance reviews of departmental nominations to the terrorist watchlist and other terrorism databases</header> 
<subsection id="H7D31FCFDA57D49DC859FEE891E0F0F24"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Quality assurance reviews</header> 
<paragraph id="H25C9A2A0133A44CCA7B2951105788E04" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Prior to submission to the Federal Bureau of Investigation’s Terrorist Screening Center and the National Counterterrorism Center of an initial Department nomination of an individual for inclusion in the terrorist watchlist, including subsets of such watchlist, such as the No Fly List, the Selectee List, and watchlist exceptions, or other terrorism databases, or successors of such watchlist or other terrorism databases, the Secretary shall conduct a quality assurance review of such initial nomination to determine if all information contained in such initial Department nomination is free from error.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H96E6E1AE41BF43B296EFE4E70343A98A" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Submission of review and determination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall ensure that reviews and determinations under paragraph (1) are included in each initial Department nomination submitted to the Federal Bureau of Investigation’s Terrorist Screening Center and the National Counterterrorism Center.</text></paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H279F754B1229496AAF99CE761F5D95C3" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Annual audits of United States persons nominations</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this section and annually thereafter, the Secretary, acting through the Under Secretary for Intelligence and Analysis, shall review, as of the date of each such review, all Department nominations of United States persons for inclusion in the terrorist watchlist, including subsets of such watchlist, such as the No Fly List, the Selectee List, and watchlist exceptions, or other terrorism databases, or successors of such watchlist or other terrorism databases, and determine the following for each such nomination:</text> <paragraph id="H941A022B087A4F0583D4D08B9B6EC5AB" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>If all information contained in each such Department nomination is free from error.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H015758C9394742AB88799F21717BFC33" commented="no">
                                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If each such Department nomination continues to satisfy the criteria specified in the Watchlisting Advisory Council’s Watchlisting Guidance for such inclusion.</text>
                            </paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8D052CB5A332470EB159D756199192DE" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Random audits</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this section and monthly thereafter, the Secretary, acting through the Under Secretary for Intelligence and Analysis, shall establish a random audit program to periodically review, as of the date of each such review, all Department nominations of individuals for inclusion in the terrorist watchlist, including subsets of such watchlist, such as the No Fly List, the Selectee List, and watchlist exceptions, or other terrorism databases, or successors of such watchlist or other terrorism databases, and determine the following for each such Department nomination:</text> <paragraph id="H122AB9E0BE234F79A3E37EFC755221F2" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>If all information contained in each such Department nomination is free from error.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H568ABBC4EED948129BF336CADB6529B0" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>If each such Department nomination continues to satisfy the criteria referred to in subsection (b)(2) for such inclusions.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HB4C85A656B944927AC19D1713C2CB586" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Correcting or retracting records</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, acting through the Under Secretary for Intelligence and Analysis, shall notify the Federal Bureau of Investigation’s Terrorist Screening Center and the National Counterterrorism Center not later than 24 hours after making a determination in the negative pursuant to subsection (b) or (c), as the case may be, with respect to a Department nomination of an individual for inclusion in the terrorist watchlist, including subsets of such watchlist, such as the No Fly List, the Selectee List, and watchlist exceptions, or other terrorism databases, or successors of such watchlist or other terrorism databases, and include in any such notification a request, if appropriate, for an associated correction or retraction with respect to such inclusion.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="HB8793AC354544A57B7B6E7BC5D5F26E9" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Consultation with FBI and NCTC</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary determines a correction or retraction, as appropriate and as the case may be, under subsection (d) with respect to the inclusion of an individual in the terrorist watchlist, including subsets of such watchlist, such as the No Fly List, the Selectee List, and watchlist exceptions, or other terrorism databases, or successors of such watchlist or other terrorism databases has not been effectuated by the date that is 30 days after a request relating thereto was made pursuant to such subsection, the Secretary shall promptly consult with the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation or the Director of the National Counterterrorism Center, as appropriate, regarding any decision or justification by either such Director, as appropriate, relating to such correction or retraction, as the case may be.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H5A90959039D34297B76596185554CCEB"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall annually submit to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a report containing information relating to the number of identities, disaggregated by United States person identities and non-United States person identities, referred for corrections or retractions pursuant to this section, and the number of nominations recalled or reissued as a result of such referrals.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HDEEFFCD27E684430AFD50EFE813344A4"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H0C9B682A62C44506986F14D854126050"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Terrorist watchlist</header><text>The term <quote>terrorist watchlist</quote> has the meaning given the term <quote>terrorist screening database</quote> in section 2101.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H70B91AFB31894FA0A017496CF87CAB52"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Other terrorism databases</header><text>The term <quote>other terrorism databases</quote> means the Terrorist Identities Datamart Environment or any other database maintained by the National Counterterrorism Center pursuant to section 119(d)(6) of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3056">50 U.S.C. 3056(d)(6)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDF48B7BF82D14DFDA9C5C5EF45EE256C" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>United States person</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>United States person</quote> means any United States citizen or alien admitted for permanent residence in the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H84E0ECB98ABD4F8B9D66E3EE4622FC92"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents in section 1(b) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 210G the following new item:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H6DA9FDED2A174B1EB77E35F0B874D8EE" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 210G. Quality assurance reviews of departmental nominations to the terrorist watchlist and other terrorism databases.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

