<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA607092F8DD442748027E32CC30D8468" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2319 IH: Women and Lung Cancer Research and Preventive Services Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2319</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250325">March 25, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001296">Mr. Boyle of Pennsylvania</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to conduct a review to evaluate the status of research on lung cancer in women and underserved populations, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD13DF92EAFBF432E9547A46D4011B9EE" style="OLC"><section id="HF83745C18E6B4189B11E5A7E11482FAF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Women and Lung Cancer Research and Preventive Services Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HBAA39A82B3F04EDBB3B4B427859809C1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Interagency review to evaluate and identify opportunities for the acceleration of research on lung cancer in women and underserved populations, greater access to preventive services, and strategic public awareness and education campaigns</header><subsection id="H503E271CF9A84D5888D755600DDC087D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, shall conduct an interagency review to evaluate the status of, and identify opportunities for the acceleration of research related to—</text><paragraph id="H4DD7C2F3867649039654935635E8B334"><enum>(1)</enum><text>research on lung cancer in women;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB810622392C24BD59C5AFDD537672471"><enum>(2)</enum><text>research on lung cancer in underserved populations that meet the eligibility criteria for lung cancer screening as recommended by the United States Preventive Services Task Force;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4EF6A24C5C5E4C14BB3C9D5D375718D0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>access to lung cancer preventive services; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCD0ED47EFF34409994F4526A6AB98BA1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>strategic public awareness and education campaigns on lung cancer.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD08F9DE9C28D4B58A933DFFE69DDBAE8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Content</header><text>The review and recommendations under subsection (a) shall include—</text><paragraph id="H952147D427C241049FE3DDA03DB56101"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a review and comprehensive report on the outcomes of previous research, the status of existing research activities, and knowledge gaps related to lung cancer in women and underserved populations in all agencies of the Federal Government;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H78688D0F7E0143E7BCFC931DA9484776"><enum>(2)</enum><text>opportunities for collaborative, interagency, multidisciplinary, and innovative research, that would—</text><subparagraph id="HB9DFC27E64344578BA783D2D6CF0628E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>encourage innovative approaches to eliminate knowledge gaps in research on lung cancer in women;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE65BDDEAFD224110B4DC8C14FBA226D4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>evaluate environmental and genomic factors that may be related to the etiology of lung cancer in women; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9AD42076E30F449296FCB79D89E9DDC0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>foster advances in imaging technology and techniques to improve risk assessment, diagnosis, treatment, and the simultaneous utilization of other preventive services and activities;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H00B9BBB4A1C74B20B055283D9942ADA7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>opportunities regarding the development of a national lung cancer screening strategy to expand access to such screenings, particularly among women and underserved populations; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3EB005F42C504373AE4AC7EB5B46AA58"><enum>(4)</enum><text>opportunities regarding the development of a national public education and awareness campaign on—</text><subparagraph id="HD4EDFEB73702433895A634E41B40B2F8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>lung cancer in women and underserved populations; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H06EEDCF20C654FE98586C31E48581566"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the importance of early detection of lung cancer.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA37402FB5BC942CE84FFD6387C5887FC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than two years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall submit to Congress a report on the review conducted under subsection (a).</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

