<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H73901E0437404E318B19AE9427AB02A5" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3374 IH: Pink Tax Repeal Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3374</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250513">May 13, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000474">Mrs. Torres of California</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="C001066">Ms. Castor of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001127">Mrs. Cherfilus-McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000462">Ms. Lois Frankel of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000631">Ms. Dean of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="O000173">Ms. Omar</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the pricing of consumer products and services that are substantially similar if such products or services are priced differently based on the gender of the individuals for whose use the products are intended or marketed or for whom the services are performed or offered.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD8593E8195F847B5ADDE17872A29F549" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H900A78F83427419488A7EF5A8B984456" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Pink Tax Repeal Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HE7EC98FA41BB4DEE957A0C443DDEAB06"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on gender-based pricing of consumer products and services</header> <subsection id="HBBA6262B7BDE4155845B389CD7BDE5BF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibited practices</header> <paragraph id="HBE5F6D4E90BC44CBAC13CEEBE34909A4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Consumer products</header><text>It shall be unlawful for any person to sell or offer for sale in interstate commerce any two consumer products from the same manufacturer that are substantially similar if such products are priced differently based on the gender of the individuals for whose use the products are intended or marketed.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0F41200776C44ABCB74A344DA91CCCAB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Services</header><text>It shall be unlawful for any person to sell or offer for sale any services that are substantially similar if such services are priced differently based on the gender of the individuals for which the services are performed, offered, or marketed.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H0AF8953936074EA08A0FBE8BED22DCEA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Enforcement by the Commission</header> <paragraph id="HBFD45BC055EB4A8E800DB160B9F3FAC0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Unfair and deceptive act or practice</header><text>A violation of subsection (a) shall be treated as a violation of a rule prescribed under section 18(a)(1)(B) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/57a">15 U.S.C. 57a(a)(1)(B)</external-xref>) defining an unfair or deceptive act or practice in or affecting interstate commerce.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD9D30C926ACD447ABE6DCAD748C1A1FE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Powers of the commission</header><text>The Federal Trade Commission shall enforce this section in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though all applicable terms and provisions of the Federal Trade Commission Act were incorporated into and made a part of this Act.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H698D81AC0783436DAABDA87810B38204"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Privileges and immunities</header><text>Any person who violates subsection (a) shall be subject to the penalties and entitled to the privileges and immunities provided in the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H705C8E3FF64D4EFD9A3B7F1CC8641C8A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Authority preserved</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit the authority of the Commission under any other provision of law.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H68691C9AECAB43E29C86BBF1079C8D37"><enum>(c)</enum><header>State attorneys general</header> <paragraph id="H91B9B58CFB4041338CF55FC79923DAE6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Civil action</header><text>In any case in which the attorney general of a State has reason to believe that an interest of the residents of the State has been or is adversely affected by a violation of subsection (a), the attorney general may, as parens patriae, bring a civil action on behalf of the residents of the State in an appropriate district court of the United States—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H3488A8489B584C158935529B332F8DA8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to enjoin further violation of such subsection by the defendant;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H970A87A6F7D14ED1A07FE6ABF109F624"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to compel compliance with such subsection; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6091900401BE496DB2C80B20C33D8AB4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>obtain damages, restitution, or other compensation on behalf of residents of the State.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H080EE4699A72487FBD16D5BD82EF0DF6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notice to the Commission</header> <subparagraph id="H5444A8F86B054184B005FB0B1DCD70CC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (C), the attorney general of a State shall notify the Commission in writing that the attorney general intends to bring a civil action under paragraph (1) not later than 10 days before initiating the civil action.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA86706E77BEC45699B2AEDC815790449"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The notice required by subparagraph (A) shall include a copy of the complaint to be filed to initiate such civil action.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBCE51958D19B4F399DDA234DA1444D9B"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>If it is not feasible for the attorney general of a State to provide the notice required by subparagraph (A), the attorney general shall notify the Commission immediately upon instituting a civil action under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H79978092231C48C5B8FE541386992B84"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Intervention by the Commission</header><text>The Commission may—</text> <subparagraph id="H86009CE20EB14019AB72B5045CF47E0A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>intervene in any civil action brought by the attorney general of a State under this subsection; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H485E037CA9184DB1AFC49C51084685AF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>upon intervening, be heard on all matters arising in such civil action and file petitions for appeal of a decision in such action.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H97CCB1F521C84397B5983CCA2D81260E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Investigatory powers</header><text>Nothing in this subsection may be construed to prevent the attorney general of a State from exercising the powers conferred on the attorney general by the laws of the State to conduct investigations, to administer oaths or affirmations, or to compel the attendance of witnesses or the production of documentary or other evidence.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3324C77AEF8C4117860A05A4A1C013A5"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Preemptive action by the Commission</header><text>If the Commission institutes a civil action or an administrative action for a violation of this section, the attorney general of a State may not, during the pendency of such action, bring a civil action under this subsection against any defendant named in the complaint of the Commission for the violation with respect to which the Commission instituted such action.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H09EBCC936C1549CC978B74B867D626EA"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Actions by other state officials</header> <subparagraph id="H149061C00A374046A4F1935697AAB221"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In addition to any civil action brought by an attorney general under paragraph (1), any other consumer protection officer of a State who is authorized by the State to do so may bring a civil action under paragraph (1), subject to the same requirements and limitations that apply under this subsection to civil actions brought by an attorney general.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD98A2EDF64AF450A9135F9D39D150D89"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Savings provision</header><text>Nothing in this subsection may be construed to prohibit an authorized official of a State from initiating or continuing any proceeding in a court of the State for a violation of any civil or criminal law of the State.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H9D10A0C8CAF84FF79B71F101BBF2FED7"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rules of construction</header> <paragraph id="H347B9CF58B7D4F21B7C23105968832FE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Substantially similar products</header><text>For purposes of this section, two consumer products are substantially similar if there are no substantial differences in the materials used in the product, the intended use of the product, and the functional design and features of the product. A difference in coloring among any consumer products shall not be construed as a substantial difference for purposes of this paragraph.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB116EDFFAA9D485DA14D62256156C30C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Substantially similar services</header><text>For purposes of this section, two services are substantially similar if there is no substantial difference in the amount of time to provide the services, the difficulty in providing the services, or the cost of providing the services.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H6F40A803EBAD443389B557937D6F85B9"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H2CECAF021DAC4CAA8E709EFD76B2C02B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Federal Trade Commission.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3C793C92980C475487A1167045DF06D8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consumer product</header><text>The term <term>consumer product</term>—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HC9EAF96EFAA14BEFA48B809621868FA2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has the meaning given such term in section 3 of the Consumer Product Safety Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/2052">15 U.S.C. 2052</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0C019FA165DD4B79B03DB987BC2733CF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes a device or cosmetics, as such terms are defined in section 201 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/321">21 U.S.C. 321</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB0B6DF3493CB4C6D87781370A33E02F3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>includes a child restraint system, as such term is defined in section 571.213 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

