<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" dms-id="H0AF835A1228347D880FBAAB3693342E6" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1479 EH: Hotel Fees Transparency Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">IB</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1479</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To prohibit unfair and deceptive advertising of prices for hotel rooms and other places of short-term lodging, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HD9F66B7A0825405FB4D7145C4F4FB7C4" style="OLC"><pagebreak/> 
<section id="H90EDFFEA04E74913A5CEBB5CF15138EC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Hotel Fees Transparency Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="HEBFA2F27E4164BF8820C40EBB60ABF56"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on unfair and deceptive advertising of hotel rooms and other short-term rental prices</header> <subsection id="H748A4CB474554755AECC72F10B1C6D69"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H76FC4A8250DF48DE83969FDBC1B08219"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It shall be unlawful for a covered entity to display, advertise, market, or offer in interstate commerce, including through direct offerings, third-party distribution, or metasearch referrals, a price for covered services that does not clearly, conspicuously, and prominently—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB1F40855935842DFB92E399AAEB19B91"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">display the total services price, if a price is displayed, in any advertisement, marketing, or price list wherever the covered services are displayed, advertised, marketed, or offered for sale; </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9F92459193DC40298C0988883BE4AF08"><enum>(B)</enum><text>disclose to any individual who seeks to purchase covered services the total services price at the time the covered services are first displayed to the individual and anytime thereafter throughout the covered services purchasing process; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8CA4D91DEDE1465797AF02D3348D8379"><enum>(C)</enum><text>disclose, prior to the final purchase, any tax, fee, or assessment imposed by any government entity, quasi-government entity, or government-created special district or program on the sale of covered services.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA1EF172355C44AEEA98DC78A2E0CB135"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Individual components</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Provided that such displays are less prominent than the total service price required in paragraph (1), nothing in this Act shall be construed to prohibit the display of— </text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF56B429F7A3446DC8968AD3B53CADC86"><enum>(A)</enum><text>individual components of the total price; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H91C964ACBB19409992CD8FE9E118A6BC"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">details of other items not required by paragraph (1). </text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2F2940289D554663A362774B73F5DA9F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Indemnification provisions</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to prohibit any covered entity from entering into a contract with any other covered entity that contains an indemnification provision with respect to price or fee information disclosed, exchanged, or shared between the covered entities that are parties to the contract.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H6E1E377B4C6A4EBBBE9DB7A3C0DFE98E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Enforcement</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFBBFAA547DBC43868B5B2247AFC15A0B"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Enforcement by the Commission</header> <subparagraph id="HEF0D24E21CC5496BA359EF5DFC261E4E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Unfair or deceptive acts or practices</header><text>A violation of subsection (a) shall be treated as a violation of a rule defining an unfair or deceptive act or practice prescribed under section 18(a)(1)(B) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/57a">15 U.S.C. 57a(a)(1)(B)</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE4AD054F9B9443F3864D45DC5DFF69DB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Powers of the Commission</header> 
<clause id="H5806A4C7820B4579949609B129C80BFE"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission shall enforce this section in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though all applicable terms and provisions of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>) were incorporated into and made a part of this Act. </text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H16C7E9EB0084475680E48767860BB903"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Privileges and immunities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any person who violates this section shall be subject to the penalties and entitled to the privileges and immunities provided in the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H182164F637694A46A4EED1EA939A08F8"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Authority preserved</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit the authority of the Commission under any other provision of law.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H76B1A608BA614571AB8E500BC3634D03"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Enforcement by States</header> <subparagraph id="HACCBD259EB0B4E81A62F179FEB3562E4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the attorney general of a State has reason to believe that an interest of the residents of the State has been or is being threatened or adversely affected by a practice that violates subsection (a), the attorney general of the State may, as parens patriae, bring a civil action on behalf of the residents of the State in an appropriate district court of the United States to obtain appropriate relief. </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC7500ED674E34E0985B144998DED5998"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Rights of the Commission</header> 
<clause id="H14CC4C04B0A94929A7CA9622D215C247"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Notice to the Commission</header> 
<subclause id="HC20C9B2086064CA698528F998F24E696"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subclause (III), the attorney general of a State, before initiating a civil action under subparagraph (A) shall notify the Commission in writing that the attorney general intends to bring such civil action.</text></subclause> <subclause id="H8B64CFAC893A43CBB156394EFDCE0D4B"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The notification required by subclause (I) shall include a copy of the complaint to be filed to initiate the civil action.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H6DED86768D994A6FA4FE79148BD4B722"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>If it is not feasible for the attorney general of a State to provide the notification required by subclause (I) before initiating a civil action under subparagraph (A), the attorney general shall notify the Commission immediately upon instituting the civil action.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HCABE27570BC94FFC899412DB05DF882B"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Intervention by the Commission</header><text>The Commission may—</text> 
<subclause id="HB4F8606E1110456080C04648576F31D8"><enum>(I)</enum><text>intervene in any civil action brought by the attorney general of a State under subparagraph (A); and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H28B0CB4410764560A3C2C212A3416481"><enum>(II)</enum><text>upon intervening—</text> 
<item id="HAA5F7AE51C0D422C9316B158D7C19C4D"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>be heard on all matters arising in the civil action; and</text></item> <item id="H48FFB19802554204BCAF6398830C0B88"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>file petitions for appeal.</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3DFA22020B2E47D6B78889C91043B678"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Investigatory powers</header><text>Nothing in this paragraph may be construed to prevent the attorney general of a State from exercising the powers conferred on the attorney general by the laws of the State to conduct investigations, to administer oaths or affirmations, or to compel the attendance of witnesses or the production of documentary or other evidence.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H91AD65987BF644118AADFC309190198A"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Action by the Commission</header><text>Whenever a civil action has been instituted by or on behalf of the Commission for violation of subsection (a), no attorney general of a State may, during the pendency of that action, institute an action under subparagraph (A) against any defendant named in the complaint in that action for a violation of subsection (a) alleged in such complaint.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB25B86555AFB4AB1B0154E8438AB8223"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Venue; service of process</header> 
<clause id="HA8FD98BEAF41427E94E1A55F375CCE07"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Venue</header><text>Any action brought under subparagraph (A) may be brought in—</text> <subclause id="HE99C2CB34A6C49A9B82A6C2EA0FF0831"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the district court of the United States that meets applicable requirements relating to venue under section 1391 of title 28, United States Code; or</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HBB566B5638294017BD366BF3AEF84E87"><enum>(II)</enum><text>another court of competent jurisdiction.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H727CC8A0A06A4D02B7C60FC44315E0A7" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Service of process</header><text>In an action brought under subparagraph (A), process may be served in any district in which—</text> 
<subclause id="HF70BAE85BD474807BD52DB3396DAFFB7" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the defendant is an inhabitant, may be found, or transacts business; or</text></subclause> <subclause id="H4BC2174F83D347528E3F20F28916FBE3" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>venue is proper under section 1391 of title 28, United States Code.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5C05AFC5619C482094BEF0B6D149E511"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Actions by other State officials</header> 
<clause id="HDC0CA424CE1747EAA8BAF76CCC5D7386"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In addition to civil actions brought by an attorney general under subparagraph (A), any other officer of a State who is authorized by the State to do so may bring a civil action under subparagraph (A), subject to the same requirements and limitations that apply under this paragraph to civil actions brought by attorneys general.</text></clause> <clause id="HF7E9129510414E4FA6F9F3F7D0294F18" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Savings provision</header><text>Nothing in this paragraph may be construed to prohibit an authorized official of a State from initiating or continuing any proceeding in a court of the State for a violation of any civil or criminal law of the State.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H49CF764F67824E92BE10DC1196900345"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Affirmative defense</header><text>In any action pursuant to paragraph (1) or (2), an intermediary or third-party online seller may assert an affirmative defense if such intermediary or third-party online seller— </text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB88767EC68E54F34B6D7D259C6A2BF65"><enum>(A)</enum><text>established procedures to receive up-to-date price information from hotels or short-term rentals, or agents acting on behalf of a hotel or short-term rental;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDAE363450F834BB6BBBFB2AB9AE92E34"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">relied in good faith on information provided to the intermediary or third-party online seller by a hotel or short-term rental, or agent acting on behalf of such hotel or short-term rental, and such information was inaccurate at the time it was provided to the intermediary or third-party online seller; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H067AB63A6609462C9EEB6BC87B66B282"><enum>(C)</enum><text>took prompt action to remove or correct any false or inaccurate information about the total services price after receiving notice that such information was false or inaccurate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H624AD38D2AB44F3D89E476937B25A693"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Preemption</header> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2D90B22531E54DC8B28D68E51AA516A5"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State, or political subdivision of a State, may not maintain, enforce, prescribe, or continue in effect any law, rule, regulation, requirement, standard, or other provision having the force and effect of law of the State, or political subdivision of the State, that prohibits a covered entity from advertising, displaying, marketing, or otherwise offering, or otherwise affects the manner in which a covered entity may advertise, display, market, or otherwise offer, for sale in interstate commerce, including through a direct offering, third-party distribution, or metasearch referral, a price of a reservation for a covered service, and that requires fee disclosure, unless such provision requires the total services price to include each service fee in accordance with subsection (a)(1). </text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8C7D2A7010C84958BF1B4DB9C613F122"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rule of Construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section may not be construed to—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB724BF1C57BF4B959E88CD54947B484D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">preempt any law of a State or political subdivision of a State relating to contracts or torts; or </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0DA4817A7F9C4701A1A296001FE14641"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">preempt any law of a State or political subdivision of a State to the extent that such law relates to an act of fraud, unauthorized access to personal information, or notification of unauthorized access to personal information.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0BA6E61C81B14BA499360DB5E0572AAC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this Act:</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBACC900E9DF0441492A20C02742A2669"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Base services price</header><text>The term <term>base services price</term>—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H50C584C69A32417C919EA5F658C8180E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means, with respect to the covered services provided by a hotel or short-term rental, the price in order to obtain the covered services of the hotel or short-term rental; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7C1C66002BD5490CA213CCCD06800180"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not include— </text> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8A3A5B37964C4816ADA92F78AF703FF0"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any service fee;</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB0081B2C1A7044649545C5E38FF3EA8E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any taxes or fees imposed by a government or quasi-government entity;</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3C06A48CB316460290F428038423569F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>assessment fees of a government-created special district or program; or</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H418664C7266A43C3977660AA75AA6E08"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any charges or fees for an optional product or service associated with the covered services that may be selected by a purchaser of covered services.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDCC3CFC6B39B4F998DC6C221D7AAFA3E"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Commission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Commission</term> means the Federal Trade Commission.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD09B183503484ACB8507A8260202FFFB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered entity</header><text>The term <term>covered entity</term> means a person, partnership, or corporation with respect to whom the Commission has jurisdiction under section 5(a)(2) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/45">15 U.S.C. 45(a)(2)</external-xref>), including—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE76AD6DA58DA4827B3B8F64E68CD6728"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a hotel or short-term rental;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H125AA4349EFA48A0B63525C2A712E606"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a third-party online seller; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF095615035D64D9A834C0C9EABE34633"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an intermediary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3672413B6FB74D83B525CFF9EE63CF65"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Covered services</header><text>The term <term>covered services</term>—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2A07824FE90A4A70A39B0A9FB2592A30"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means the temporary provision of a room, building, or other lodging facility; and </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD049E366622F41E6B3B1631F7D4CE3A1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not include the provision of a meeting room, banquet services, or catering services.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H42E176EF151444A29E7CA1E46117A16E"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Hotel</header><text>The term <term>hotel</term> means an establishment that is—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H453C05871B664079B5577C71925B1938"><enum>(A)</enum><text>primarily engaged in providing a covered service to the general public; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H180D039BB777466DB47AF686B312BE9E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>promoted, advertised, or marketed in interstate commerce or for which such establishment's services are sold in interstate commerce.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H75294B721C784E3FA6E220EB5F342AC8"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Intermediary</header><text>The term <term>intermediary</term> means an entity that operates either as a business-to-business platform, consumer-facing platform, or both, that displays, including through direct offerings, third-party distribution, or metasearch referral, a price for covered services or price comparison tools for consumers seeking covered services. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF6AA42B51AFA4836AB7145D4B9205EA2"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Optional product or service</header><text>The term <term>optional product or service</term> means a product or service that an individual does not need to purchase to use or obtain covered services.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7511F0C7191740FC83B06DE2403F3F5D"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Service fee</header><text>The term <term>service fee</term>—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HABBE6FCA3B134C4C8BFBF402101EEBCB"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means a charge imposed by a covered entity that must be paid in order to obtain covered services; and </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF6FA3A2E247D4F81B4D4F60D862C2B92"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not include— </text> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H59AF67A6DFF144068CC27D5734E12FDC"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any taxes or fees imposed by a government or quasi-government entity;</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFC6663D4038D4D5B907EC28F51C51D2F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any assessment fees of a government-created special district or program; or </text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H03D22147978B49FC9F24837223B27B04"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any charges or fees for an optional product or service associated with the covered services that may be selected by a purchaser of covered services.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0FF307CC00BD4126BE5CC51E6C499D8C"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Short-term rental</header><text>The term <term>short-term rental</term> means a property, including a single-family dwelling or a unit in a condominium, cooperative, or time-share, that provides covered services (either with respect to the entire property or a part of the property) to the general public—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE6482646937740B4B7FB48FDAABC7A70"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in exchange for a fee;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBD7079B1AFBD4978A783440DAF88A457"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for periods shorter than 30 consecutive days; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE797D823C58F47CC9D03A7EC7577DF5C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is promoted, advertised, or marketed in interstate commerce or for which such property’s services are sold in interstate commerce.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD29588F0B2AE4B45B4E4D4F49FC08E81" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(10)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means each of the 50 States, the District of Columbia, and any territory or possession of the United States.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H575DCCFECA2F4C1BAC66CAE3C655DF1C"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Third-party online seller</header><text>The term <term>third-party online seller</term> means any person other than a hotel or short-term rental that sells covered services or offers for sale covered services with respect to a hotel or short-term rental in a transaction facilitated on the internet. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCD2BC273D4E54B11AECC7CAFB798E311"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Total services price</header><text>The term <term>total services</term>—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA86D753737704699BC7249C3973939D0"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means, with respect to covered services, the total cost of the covered services, including the base services price and any service fees; and </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF3944FC4361E459794EC12B4671F5AFC"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not include— </text> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFBA105412C51440DAAB988CF8D5BCA7D"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any taxes or fees imposed by a government or quasi-government entity;</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H84A68D72560C45DF9EEE92BCD50B9CC0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any assessment fees of a government-created special district or program; or</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF9E91EA7A74B4B12B9ACB6B47A18235F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any charges or fees for an optional product or service associated with the covered services that may be selected by a purchaser of covered services.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC564D7A53810468CAE1FA24ECC4F6823" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The prohibition under subsection (a) shall take effect 450 days after the date of the enactment of this Act and shall apply to advertisements, displays, marketing, and offers of covered services of a covered entity made on or after such date.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20250428" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives April 28, 2025.</attestation-date><attestor display="no">Kevin F. McCumber,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation> 
<endorsement display="yes"></endorsement> 
</bill> 


