<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCA4B041F80C74666AAC3FA497EC0B07E" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 663 IH: Celebrating 100 years of The American Legion Baseball program and honoring its legacy of mentoring young Americans.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 663</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250826">August 26, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001309">Mr. Burchett</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Celebrating 100 years of The American Legion Baseball program and honoring its legacy of mentoring young Americans.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, on July 17, 1925, The American Legion in Milbank, South Dakota was asked to develop a youth fitness program centered on the principles of citizenship, discipline, and sportsmanship imparted through mentorship from veterans;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas The American Legion Baseball program was born of the First World War, the experiences of those who served overseas, and who hoped to instill wisdom into the next generation of young Americans;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas The American Legion passed a national resolution in October 1925 officially creating The American Legion Junior Baseball program, known today as American Legion Baseball;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas The American Legion Baseball program has since been a source of mentorship, physical fitness, athletic excellence, and sportsmanship for over 10,000,000 participants around the country and beyond;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the program now has over 50,000 athletes with more than 3,500 teams in all 50 States, Canada, and Puerto Rico;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas The American Legion Baseball program formally adopted the following Code of Sportsmanship in 1928: <quote>I will keep the rules, keep faith with my teammates, keep my temper, keep myself fit, keep a stout heart in defeat, keep pride under control in victory, keep a sound soul, a clean mind, and a healthy body.</quote>;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas The American Legion Baseball program has produced some of our country’s greatest athletes, public servants, celebrities, and citizens including Bob Feller, Yogi Berra, Bob Lemon, Bob Gibson, Gil Hodges, Dave Winfield, Reggie Jackson, Joe Torre, Wade Boggs, Mike Piazza, C.C. Sabathia, Dick Cheney, Tom Vilsack, Steve Young, Tom Brokaw, Charlie Day, and Darrell Hammond;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas world famous baseball legend Babe Ruth dedicated the final years of his life traveling around the country promoting the American Legion Baseball program; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the program continues to serve the American public by providing unique character building and athletic opportunities to young Americans across the country, including the annual American Legion World Series in Shelby, North Carolina: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H24383E8F60DF4CD0A2F1C85AA289240B"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HCC0B4595729841C5AFB8F7727DCCC268"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> 
<paragraph id="H77F7A4136F374E00878DB7728CD0777C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognizes and honors the accomplishments of The American Legion Baseball program in mentoring young Americans; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC2768A31C4064FA8A4720F580F55D760"><enum>(2)</enum><text>celebrates the program’s 100th anniversary.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

