<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB230EB87962242E1B46957DD6FD54484" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2829 IH: Strengthening Efforts for Relief and Vital Incentives for Community Service and Engagement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2829</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250410">April 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001069">Mr. Courtney</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to improve the Public Service Loan Forgiveness program and reduce interest rates.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB42DCB07DFA448E9A37F96F46907C664" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H9CF5004EB4EC40D1A444EBEC8EDE2B11" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Strengthening Efforts for Relief and Vital Incentives for Community Service and Engagement Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SERVICE Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H5B09628D5F314D48979A2DEEEB313E41"><enum>2.</enum><header>Amendments to terms and conditions of public service loan forgiveness</header> <subsection id="H074946F71584401F910CAF2613F7D2A7" display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Number of monthly payments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (1) of section 455(m) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087e">20 U.S.C. 1087e(m)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H1FC0A0ECAEAC4051BD2481BE5931DE1D" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>a borrower who</quote> and inserting <quote>a borrower</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7587105F6C1F4D55B44504971A0FA0B1" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by amending subparagraph (A) to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H895AEEFFEEE94A678249B52491E68A10" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subparagraph id="H93BB7361BD2A4C5AAEB682747107D11E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">who—</text> <clause id="H32765E56764F45718F41D924E8B9AA3E"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has made 96 qualifying monthly payments on the eligible Federal Direct Loan after October 1, 2007; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H2052AA1F68EB42068E8C906A680A0C6C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has been employed in a public service job during the period in which the borrower makes each of the 96 qualifying monthly payments; and</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFB9F17C4975F419FAD0F9912AB39E058"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by amending subparagraph (B) to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H575B6D76EE0140B99F0B9483FA624E0C" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subparagraph id="HF60BB81938ED4A5488DA1B087A4031E8"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">without regard to the employment status of the borrower at the time of such cancellation.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="H76A9E15F2A70445DA5792FCA9585C682" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Redesignations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 455(m) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087e">20 U.S.C. 1087e(m)</external-xref>) is further amended by redesignating paragraphs (2), (3), and (4), as paragraphs (3), (6), and (7), respectively; </text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0D6B2351C3DC4180A998CD8EFC1EC851" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Monthly payments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 455(m) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087e">20 U.S.C. 1087e(m)</external-xref>) is further amended—</text> <paragraph id="H5772CDBF592443E39093D82D6233B234"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (1), as so amended, the following: </text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HEE5AA9023454465F867EF6B4E870EBC0" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="H071D6798295E43629C9EBC3FCB6C3B5B" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Monthly payments</header> 
<subparagraph id="H5D280868300A4AEEBA821F28B187801D" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Qualifying monthly payments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purpose of determining under paragraph (1) the number of qualifying monthly payments made by a borrower on an eligible Federal Direct Loan, the Secretary shall consider the borrower to have made a qualifying monthly payment for each month that—</text> <clause id="H7B1D799428454765A06511FDF0F81DCE"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the borrower pays (as a lump sum or in multiple installments) an amount that is not less than the monthly payment amount due on the eligible Federal Direct Loan pursuant to any one or a combination of the following—</text> 
<subclause id="HB8887800469E491CBE3FE68C05578DBE" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(I)</enum><text>payments under an income-based repayment plan under section 493C;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H9F370A7CF6CA47C5BC6356E462BA72B3"><enum>(II)</enum><text>payments under a standard repayment plan under subsection (d)(1)(A), based on a 10-year repayment period;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H602FE482578E48B5815541BCD62DC768"><enum>(III)</enum><text>monthly payments under a repayment plan under subsection (d)(1) or (g) of not less than the monthly amount calculated under subsection (d)(1)(A), based on a 10-year repayment period; or</text></subclause> <subclause id="H433E6F6892AD43F297F11A6B985CB84D"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>payments under an income contingent repayment plan under subsection (d)(1)(D); or</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H2C768B5B06AB40B9A72CCA75452C0F4B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in lieu of a payment described in clause (i), the borrower is in one of the following periods of deferment or forbearance—</text> <subclause id="H064DF444E52D4F2E808944CED90BCB93"><enum>(I)</enum><text>cancer treatment deferment under section 427(a)(2)(C)(iv), 428(b)(1)(M)(v), or 455(f)(3);</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H38B20FB582104C0499927BAC78BC75CA"><enum>(II)</enum><text>rehabilitation training program deferment under section 427(a)(2)(C)(i)(II), 428(b)(1)(M)(i)(II), or 455(f)(2)(A)(ii);</text></subclause> <subclause id="H719BD1E8271049A0B2E2D4AD1D18B2B3"><enum>(III)</enum><text>military service deferment under section 428(b)(1)(M)(iii) or 455(f)(2)(C);</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HE31C3A84069E4D289145B0620C635090"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>unemployment deferment under section 427(a)(2)(C)(ii), 428(b)(1)(M)(ii), 428B(d)(1)(A)(i), or 455(f)(2)(B);</text></subclause> <subclause id="HA78127C628C442C4A537561A3B2E6F1D"><enum>(V)</enum><text>deferment due to an economic hardship described in section 427(a)(2)(C)(iii), section 428(b)(1)(M)(iv), section 428B(d)(1)(A)(i), section 435(o), or section 455(f)(2)(D);</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HD800E3F6E53443FFB07774CFA1DC6FBE"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>Peace Corps service deferment under section 682.210(b)(2)(ii) or 682.210(k) of title 34, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations), as made applicable to Direct Loan borrowers under section 685.204(j) of such title 34;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H9609523EECF34595998EAFF89C8AC814"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>post-active-duty student deferment under section 493D;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HE9124389AAD046309183B1E443D49F2C"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text>AmeriCorps forbearance under section 428(c)(3)(A)(i)(III);</text></subclause> <subclause id="HE96FE80A64C64A9C97AFA9F086A2B6A8"><enum>(IX)</enum><text>National Guard Duty forbearance under section 682.211(h)(2)(iii) or 685.205(a)(7) of title 34, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations);</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H1C58D30272BE414098F5DB7020A565A7"><enum>(X)</enum><text>Department of Defense student loan repayment program forbearance under section 428(c)(3)(A)(i)(IV);</text></subclause> <subclause id="H81CF4107902047329BE15F5D09854148"><enum>(XI)</enum><text>administrative forbearance or mandatory administrative forbearance under section 428(c)(3)(D) or 428H(e)(7); or</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HCDC2FB99A46D455DB4DD22215799C808"><enum>(XII)</enum><text>student loan debt burden forbearance under section 428(c)(3)(A)(i)(II).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6867187A4F774D39AE585203F144D2A2" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Prepayments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"></text> 
<clause id="HB8E3BB8C634E48EB96E8E725A6A44A2C" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to clause (ii), if, for any month, a borrower makes a qualifying monthly payment on an eligible Federal Direct Loan in an amount that exceeds the monthly payment amount due on such loan for such month, the Secretary shall—</text> <subclause id="H9997DC9C259346FA803B5F6BF0B1C5D6" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the excess amount is less than the monthly payment amount due for the subsequent month on such loan, apply the excess amount toward the monthly payment amount due for such subsequent month;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H84DE3DD8CAA6419C947CB035222712B6" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the excess amount is equal to the monthly payment amount due for the subsequent month on such loan, treat the excess amount as the monthly payment for such subsequent month; </text></subclause> <subclause id="HECFC8F3DB6BB4EAAA2FED4844EFF9028" commented="no"><enum>(III)</enum><text>if the excess amount is greater than the monthly payment amount due for the subsequent month on such loan, but less than the total monthly payment amounts due for the 2 subsequent months on such loan—</text> 
<item id="H415357CE0E114288A311CC95DECC1C74" commented="no"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">treat the portion of the excess amount that covers the monthly payment amount due for the subsequent month as the monthly payment for such subsequent month; and</text></item> <item id="HC63D87F3961E4A109CAB4C2F40751DDD" commented="no"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>apply the remainder of the excess amount toward the monthly payment amount due for the second subsequent month;</text></item></subclause> 
<subclause id="H9ED4D3CBE61F4F35AC1A8CF6B2F0DD10" commented="no"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>if the excess amount is equal to or greater than the monthly payment amount due for the 2 subsequent months on such loan, but less than the total monthly payment amounts due for the 3 subsequent months on such loan—</text> <item id="H73440254EB6A46C0A033271E67D85C2E" commented="no"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">treat the portion of the excess amount that covers the monthly payment amounts due for the subsequent month and the second subsequent month as the monthly payments for such months; and</text></item> 
<item id="H21F17A00DF1849E3A184F96DF81F0CE9" commented="no"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>apply any remainder of such excess amount toward the monthly payment amount due for the third subsequent month;</text></item></subclause> <subclause id="HDFA43DB0C00147D8A7B5A4A771A21F27" commented="no"><enum>(V)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the excess amount is equal to the monthly payment amounts due for the 3 subsequent months on such loan, treat the excess amount as the monthly payments for such months;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H989D7F6AA68F42B5844864FBB410C84C" commented="no"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>if the excess amount is greater than the monthly payment amounts due for the 3 subsequent months on such loan—</text> <item id="H5941EEB53D90433896B6DD6601EFD50C" commented="no"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>treat the portion of the excess amount that covers the monthly payment amounts due for the 3 subsequent months as the monthly payments for such months; and</text></item> 
<item id="HDE2FBE0851664A2BBA556996887807D0"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>apply any remainder of such excess amount to the principal balance of the eligible Federal Direct loan; and</text></item></subclause> <subclause id="H702DF8EA630E41929D564870B704E089" commented="no"><enum>(VII)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">notwithstanding subclauses (I) through (VI), if the borrower has a monthly payment amount due on such loan for such month that is equal to $0, apply any excess amount for such month to the principal balance of the eligible Federal Direct loan.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="HADCC74CD167D4213A7AA2A988F91FFC2" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Alternative application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Prior to or at the time of making a payment that exceeds the monthly payment amount due on an eligible Federal Direct Loan for such month, a borrower may request that any excess amount for such month be applied to the principal balance of an eligible Federal Direct loan in lieu of such excess amount being applied in accordance with clause (i).<italic></italic></text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5FAE0102FEA04036BD85ED5D9618B9CC" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Buyback payment process</header> <clause id="HAD5AB6FC2E88400A85A3CD6A9C99E3E5" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish a buyback payment process under which a qualified borrower of an eligible Federal Direct Loan may make a buyback payment in order to have eligible months of the borrower’s public service employment period during which the borrower did not make a qualifying monthly payment on such loan be treated as if the borrower had made a qualifying monthly payment on such loan.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H010F41279E7B4E7BA83C0BF19F690B44"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Qualified borrower</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A borrower is a qualified borrower for the purposes of making a buyback payment in accordance with this subparagraph if the borrower—</text> <subclause id="HCA09E78FBBC043D889860A2FA7D99D2F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>has an eligible Federal Direct Loan that is not in default; </text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H8AB4AAE76DBE43E8B0807F29A94F2260"><enum>(II)</enum><text>has been employed in a public service job for not less than a 96 month employment period, but during such employment period has made fewer than 96 qualifying monthly payments on an eligible Federal Direct Loan; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H1179D3627F5B4868A5B8B9A49891BC05"><enum>(III)</enum><text>requests to make a buyback payment in accordance with this subparagraph.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H51F74CD3D6FA4BC495B3ACA8F9D9AFC3" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Eligible month</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purposes of this subparagraph, an eligible month means a month during which a qualified borrower was employed in a public service job, was not in an in-school deferment or grace period, and did not make a qualifying monthly payment on an eligible Federal Direct Loan for such month—</text> <subclause id="H3D5D219B1AA04324BF5F5D49588AE47C" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">because the borrower made a monthly payment on such eligible Federal Direct Loan pursuant to a repayment plan that is not a qualifying repayment plan; </text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H064E05E2D9A84F0693EBE26198A79499"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">because the borrower was in a period of deferment or forbearance other than a period described in clause (ii) of subparagraph (A); or</text></subclause> <subclause id="H6ADA1CB0A7D4439F8ABB77008E2503FF"><enum>(III)</enum><text>for another reason determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H64985A4C17D940A58DC3C629B760A498"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Buyback payment requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A buyback payment made in accordance with this subparagraph—</text> <subclause id="H60E19F1CCE1A42FB9CB0631C09A9E31A"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall be made by a qualified borrower as a lump sum payment amount, and in an amount that equals the total amount the borrower would have paid in qualifying monthly payments on the eligible Federal Direct Loan for all eligible months the borrower is requesting to buyback, pursuant to a qualifying repayment plan applicable to the borrower, in accordance with section 685.219(g)(6) of title 34, Code of Federal Regulations (as such section is in effect on the date of enactment of this paragraph) or any other relevant regulations in effect on such date; </text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H0DD0C8ED736041F7AF8473C83D285D86"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may not be made with respect to an eligible Federal Direct Loan that has been paid off, discharged, or cancelled; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HB17BBDC9FD334AE6AA1C20A3C33E431D"><enum>(III)</enum><text>with respect to an eligible Federal Direct Loan that is a consolidation loan, may not be used to buyback eligible months that occurred before the date of the consolidation of such loan.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE30B104D73674913BDC829AC6CAC23B7"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Hold harmless against retroactive determinations</header><text>For purposes of determining under paragraph (1) the number of qualifying monthly payments made by a borrower, any payment or period of deferment or forbearance that is determined to be a qualifying monthly payment may not, at a later time, be determined not to be a qualifying monthly payment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD6CA52E75BE9460A827A02109283B639"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (6), as redesignated by section 2(b), by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HBEA7D60D56B54894BF15C5CE797422E2" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subparagraph id="H9B56A755C87C4D1B92FCCFD082827874"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Qualifying repayment plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>qualifying repayment plan</term> means any of the repayment plans listed in clause (i) of paragraph (2)(A). </text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H0771DB0E997543C2A29F6F63021966EC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Loan cancellation</header><text>Paragraph (3) of section 455(m) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087e">20 U.S.C. 1087e(m)</external-xref>), as redesignated by subsection (b), is amended to read as follows: </text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H7975FBDF6643493DB9724F13C036E292" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="H7DF6D61E6B60423E98D0395F02B0D951"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Loan cancellation amount</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon certification by a borrower of completion of 96 qualifying monthly payments by the borrower, the Secretary shall determine whether the borrower meets each of the requirements of paragraph (1), and—</text> <subparagraph id="H8DC45E6521A345DFAFE439F49B20BD00"><enum>(A)</enum><text>if the Secretary determines that the borrower does meet such requirements, cancel the obligation to repay the balance of principal and interest due as of the time of such cancellation on the eligible Federal Direct Loans made to the borrower under this part, without further action by the borrower; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1420A97C516B4D5D97F1399A5168C3DD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if the Secretary determines that the borrower does not meet such requirements, notify the borrower of such determination in accordance with paragraph (4).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HD2CEBEA51C0D4F1488B01ECDFDDF8733"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reconsideration process</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 455(m) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087e">20 U.S.C. 1087e(m)</external-xref>), as redesignated by subsection (b), is further amended by inserting after paragraph (3), as so amended, the following: </text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H8A306F0D4E714B888AFDCED937D189DF" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="H68F8BD275EE54DF295D811CA442941F1" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Initial determination of ineligibility for loan cancellation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In a case in which the Secretary determines that a borrower has not met the requirements of paragraph (1), the Secretary shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H7F314AC8C1E9450DBC390C26BD730100"><enum>(A)</enum><text>notify the borrower that—</text> 
<clause id="HAF6EAD7DC653490DB7E19B23FF0F8691" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the borrower’s application has been denied, including the basis for such denial;</text></clause> <clause id="H645ABB44384B4BF08B0CAB7E05E425AC" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the borrower is in a 90-day forbearance period described in subparagraph (B); and </text></clause> 
<clause id="H8CC47C5C49024446BA6BFEC2A1F414BE" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary will resume collection of the eligible Federal Direct Loans for which the borrower was seeking loan cancellation under this subsection after such 90-day forbearance period, unless the borrower opts to extend such forbearance period under paragraph (5)(A)(ii); and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H88C5B4BC6D044D7D816A0536A5EEC7A6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>grant the borrower a 90-day forbearance period, beginning on the date of the notice described in subparagraph (A) provided to the borrower, and during which—</text> 
<clause id="H333773C60C7E498298727984098C8F90"><enum>(i)</enum><text>payments of principal and interest need not be made on the eligible Federal Direct Loans for which the borrower was seeking loan cancellation under this subsection; and</text></clause> <clause id="H37DE91144D264036898900FCCFA6762D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any interest accrued and not paid may not be capitalized.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDDD9108CC47043029846198C69D95207"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Reconsideration process</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"></text> <subparagraph id="HD5195260D85943C8B94D10F3A4987BC2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Request for reconsideration</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the notice described in paragraph (4)(A) provided to the borrower—</text> 
<clause id="H2FC94A3D6150473CA4BE57B78746B60C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the borrower may request, on a form approved by the Secretary, that the Secretary reconsider the basis for the Secretary’s denial under paragraph (4)(A)(i); and</text></clause> <clause id="H97EE6F5825724D6989EC12732E07BFC4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if the Secretary grants the borrower’s reconsideration request, offer the borrower an extension of the 90-day forbearance period described in paragraph (4)(B), which shall—</text> 
<subclause id="HB77FB2C303AD4741BBBBCD9418D99352"><enum>(I)</enum><text>begin on the date of the borrower’s reconsideration request under this subparagraph; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H437477073ACD4BC0A9148CC6CFE2BE15"><enum>(II)</enum><text>end on the date of the notice provided to the borrower under subparagraph (C)(i)(I) of the Secretary’s reconsideration decision.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9E8F1F2639404D3ABA2DBD558CDBD08A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Consideration of reconsideration request</header><text>In evaluating a reconsideration request from a borrower, the Secretary shall consider any relevant evidence or supporting documentation that may assist the Secretary in determining whether the borrower meets each of the requirements of paragraph (1) to qualify for loan cancellation under this subsection.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H056199FBA6A041F5B48D607E63589AD9"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Decision by the Secretary</header> <clause id="HA5D3B045A582472DB41C40EE21A62F1D" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 6 months after receipt of a borrower’s reconsideration request, the Secretary shall—</text> 
<subclause id="HFF29334B5304425A8A133ADDFCD628DB" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>notify the borrower of the reconsideration decision and the reason for the Secretary’s determination; </text></subclause> <subclause id="H402C1C342DFA4767AC587907B73BDB9F" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in a case in which the reconsideration request is granted, adjust the borrower’s number of qualifying monthly payments under paragraph (1) or cancel the loan under paragraph (3); and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HA0577D42A506417C80EC6394A72D6D3A" commented="no"><enum>(III)</enum><text>in a case in which the Secretary denies the reconsideration request, with respect to a borrower who agrees to the forbearance extension described in subparagraph (A)(ii), include in the notice provided to the borrower under subclause (I), a reminder that the Secretary will resume collection of the eligible Federal Direct Loans for which the borrower was seeking loan cancellation under this subsection as of the date of such notice.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H9D5EFE787FFB4A2BAFF8930AA4992F99"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Final decision</header><text>After the Secretary makes a decision on the borrower’s reconsideration request, the Secretary’s decision is final, and the borrower will not receive additional reconsideration.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> 
<section id="H3B6DAB6B5ED447219AA23D65C78B7340"><enum>3.</enum><header>Terms and conditions of employment</header> 
<subsection id="H76D0A8BE048442BDBEA83BE7AF8DB5ED"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Independent contractors</header><text>Section 455(m) is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HAD836D48344248CB996B1381EC53535B" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="HE13120117A424B57AAC0691FDEC8D9D6"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Treatment of independent contractors</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection, each reference to <quote>employment</quote> and <quote>employed</quote> shall be treated as including work as an independent contractor. </text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE48FE396F5184FACBDF58994CBD6D6BC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (6) of section 455(m) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087e">20 U.S.C. 1087e(m)</external-xref>), as redesignated by section 2(b), is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H76D8B0CE8F08457C89C7FA4934BCCB50"> <subparagraph id="H14698F6508F64ACE9CAC876A370E4992"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Full-time</header><text>The term <term>full-time</term> means, with respect to a public service job, working 1 or more such jobs—</text> 
<clause id="H759AE5014BC34F5BA75E6EEE806952BF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a minimum average of 30 hours per week during the period being certified;</text></clause> <clause id="H6E7C9DC3C7BF4DFBA19A33600E78AB22"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a minimum of 30 hours per week throughout a contractual or employment period of at least 8 months in a 12-month period; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H4EFD11DE163240FC80533BFD16984793"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>with respect to an individual who is in nontenure track employment at an institution of higher education, the equivalent of 30 hours per week as determined by multiplying each credit or contact hour taught by such individual per week by a number to be determined by the Secretary.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H63F401635EAD42AA810E0CF598891A82"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Independent contractor</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>independent contractor</term> means an individual who is not an employee and who is working in a public service job in a position or providing services which, under applicable State law, cannot be filled or provided by an employee of the public service job.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> 
<section id="HC7DED8D9D13F4BC0B0173DD5F7E6EFE4" commented="no"><enum>4.</enum><header>Online portal and database of public service jobs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 455(m) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H9ACF41860A54401AB462441E67C785E2"> <paragraph id="H9CABC49D8C7245198BFD5DD825BBCF46" commented="no"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Online portal and database of public service jobs</header> <subparagraph id="HBAC84EAD96244134AFC52F813C113E00" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Online portal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"></text> 
<clause id="HFE30C77FF8254D78A41DD62F040D88DF" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Borrowers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish an online portal that provides to borrowers of eligible Federal Direct Loans the following information: </text> <subclause id="H651444F5EEBD476982142162D072C2A9" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Instructions on how to access the database established under subparagraph (B) so that the borrower can determine whether the borrower is employed in a public service job.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HCDEBCB2066134E6DA49A41DA99529FAE" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>An identification of the loans of the borrower that are eligible Federal Direct Loans, and an identification of the qualifying repayment plans for which such eligible Federal Direct Loans qualify. </text></subclause> <subclause id="H4131CB7238314F6EA276CD89E5C225DE" commented="no"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to each such eligible Federal Direct Loan—</text> 
<item id="H6D29018C36CD4196BB1B4CFA4054AA47"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the number of qualifying monthly payments the borrower has made in accordance with paragraph (1); and</text></item> <item id="HAE2D3AC795BA4B1496E19C1E1AF2CE0E"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the estimated number of qualifying monthly payments under such paragraph remaining on such loan before the borrower may be eligible for loan cancellation under this subsection.</text></item></subclause> 
<subclause id="H967E046C6BEC411F9CD947B37AF8C4CC" commented="no"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to each loan of the borrower that is not eligible for loan cancellation under paragraph (3) of this subsection, an explanation of why the loan is not so eligible and instructions on how what, if anything, the borrower may do to make the loan so eligible.</text></subclause> <subclause id="HE0B2B9367A934BC88D4D6BD8A52EAFA9" commented="no"><enum>(V)</enum><text>Instructions for the submission of any forms associated with such loan cancellation, and an ability for the borrower to use the portal to electronically sign and submit such forms.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HF53546C882B94F4D9C7B5244A90095AA" commented="no"><enum>(VI)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In a case in which a borrower submits to the Secretary an application for loan cancellation under this subsection that is denied by the Secretary—</text> <item id="HDFA556CA08BA435997C20D40C17BF11E" commented="no"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a notice of such denial that meets each of the requirements of paragraph (4)(A), including an explanation of the 90-day forbearance period; </text></item> 
<item id="HD61A3DD403EC4996BB195F5B9E4FC60A" commented="no"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>a form that meets each of the requirements of paragraph (5)(A), which the borrower may use to request reconsideration of such denial, including accepting an extension of the 90-day forbearance period; and</text></item> <item id="H99016DB7416F42288611301B0D2719E9" commented="no"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>a notice of the Secretary’s reconsideration decision, which meets each of the requirements of paragraph (5)(C).</text></item></subclause> 
<subclause id="HFF0A3194A06E4839A9CB43D17856A68A"><enum>(VII)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An explanation of the buyback payment process described in paragraph (2)(C), and a form to request such a buyback, including the eligible months for which the borrower may request a buyback, and the amount that the borrower would be required to pay for such buyback.</text></subclause> <subclause id="H880FC502124149C5939B50467A058F19"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An explanation of how consolidating one or more Direct Loans into a Direct Consolidation Loan, including a Direct PLUS Loan made to a parent borrower, will affect the number of qualifying monthly payments attributed to the borrower.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H314CA61699924DF2BC802CBE0C7EE029" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Appropriate contacts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall ensure that an appropriate contact for a public service job of a borrower has the option to electronically sign and submit any forms associated with loan cancellation under paragraph (3) of this subsection.</text></clause> <clause id="H78CA82CF98AB46FE92B8371975C16836" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Information</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that any information provided through the online portal described in this subparagraph contains up-to-date information.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H942CA56BE6164816B14D1D64B85AF777" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Database of public service jobs</header> 
<clause id="HBA46519029924982A7650A7995A72C8A" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Labor, shall establish and regularly update a database that lists public service jobs.</text></clause> <clause id="HF70CAA7F10A14227957B9A4EADC9B958" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The database established under clause (i) shall be made available on a publicly accessible website of the Department of Education in an easily searchable format.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
<section id="H1BC6BBF5868C48C5AEB5CE35DA8AB7D0"><enum>5.</enum><header>Treatment of periods of deferment and forbearance</header> 
<subsection id="HEACCA2EF2BA74D1184988CAC28930B99"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 455(f) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087e">20 U.S.C. 1087e(f)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H2D9C154DD65F42889C6A47861A640419"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the subsection heading, by inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">and forbearance</header-in-text></quote> at the end;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6F66842E46C9437B801045ABEAFE99D0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)(B), by striking <quote>capitalized or</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7302DDCB5ACC4F3489B03B8CBA04FEFF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HD7620415B6EB4CA3B5AF915DDFB9F8E2"> 
<paragraph id="HEA8A88B3F9BB47BEA7466A409F750911"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Forbearance</header><text>With respect to a loan that is in a period of forbearance, interest on such loan may not be capitalized after the conclusion of such period.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD46ED98F2C2E48449373E19262463ADE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application of amendment</header><text>The amendments made by subsection (a) shall apply to any period of deferment or forbearance in effect as of the date of the enactment of this Act, and any period of deferment or forbearance beginning on or after such date of enactment.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HA0F38CF6AC09456CBE22832BDD479332"><enum>6.</enum><header>Treatment of consolidated and refinanced loans</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 455(m)(2) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087e">20 U.S.C. 1087e(m)(2)</external-xref>, as amended by the preceding provisions of this Act, is further amended by inserting after subparagraph (D) the following: </text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H7C964768038645F08CB3A6FE0FB20679" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subparagraph id="HC950A02D2103462E93D8C56A7885B938"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Determination of number of qualifying monthly payments for consolidation loans</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to determining the number of qualifying monthly payments for a borrower seeking loan forgiveness under this subsection who consolidates one or more Direct Loans into a Direct Consolidation Loan, including a Direct PLUS Loan made to a parent borrower, the Secretary shall use the weighted average of the payments the borrower made on the Direct Loans prior to consolidating that met the criteria under this subsection.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
<section id="H3F8A43F7AAEB4CE7A867A1B87CB1BAD4"><enum>7.</enum><header>Loan forgiveness for teachers</header> 
<subsection id="HBFB66D307E334ADEA525805133EF651E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001 et seq.</external-xref>) is further amended—</text> <paragraph id="H6BFEC793B6A345D7B453B84A796515E4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 428J(g)(2) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1078-10">20 U.S.C. 1078–10(g)(2)</external-xref>)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HA896DD4285224D8FA850116078D0D3BF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by inserting <quote>or</quote> after the semicolon at the end;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0296A7FDD0A84AEBAC421549F55155B3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (B); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0A79429FC68A4DA9A71F040346FDF54F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (C) as subparagraph (B); and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD334DDF04B6349A5B56224577D6A9400"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 460(g)(2) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087j">20 U.S.C. 1087j(g)(2)</external-xref>)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H2AAE4B0001F24350926E8C4E1B200991"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by inserting <quote>or</quote> after the semicolon at the end;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0B3C543320444EE7A3C5E444CE96C28D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (B); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD3A9D483E86F47B69E277F5214DC1985"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (C) as subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H9A9CE54373124C60B40411B48EEF4AC5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 455(m)(7) of the Higher Education Act of 1965, as redesignated by section 2(b) of this Act, is amended by striking <quote>section 428J, 428K, 428L, or 460</quote> and inserting <quote>section 428K or 428L</quote>.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H3CC8F3E95AE64F5FA7C1B2FC98244B1C" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>8.</enum><header>GAO study on data matching agreements for public service loan forgiveness</header> 
<subsection id="H549BC74A3E244DB99D53200EDE1AF432" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a study on the feasibility of establishing data matching agreements for public service loan forgiveness under section 455(m) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087e">20 U.S.C. 1087e(m)</external-xref>) that would allow a borrower to forego requesting certification of employment from the appropriate contact for the public service job of the borrower. The study shall include an examination of the Department of Education and the Department of Defense’s progress towards automatic data matching for military and veteran borrowers.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H67B4922BA8EF4FA9BEED78F5CDE4EC68"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General shall submit a report to the Committee on Education and Workforce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate containing the findings and recommendations resulting from the study required under subsection (a).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3CFCBD7F36844947A80FFF307F89FD11" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Cooperation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The head of each relevant Federal agency, including the Secretary of Education, Secretary of Defense, and Commissioner of Internal Revenue, shall cooperate with the Comptroller General to facilitate the completion of the study required under subsection (a).</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

