<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE2FB5B9E71C144DBACAD19241E255D14" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 477 IH: Establishing the Select Committee on President Biden’s Cognitive Decline.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 477</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250604">June 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000622">Mr. Patronis</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Committee on Rules</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Establishing the Select Committee on President Biden’s Cognitive Decline.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas overwhelming evidence shows President Biden and his staff covered up the extent of his cognitive decline;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas additional information has come to light following his departure from the White House showing the full extent of his cognitive infirmaries;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the 25th Amendment establishes a process whereby the President or the Vice President and a majority of either the principal officers of the executive departments or such other body as Congress may by law provide may report to Congress that the President is unable to discharge the powers and duties of the office;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the American people deserve to have a President who is engaged and understands the nature and consequences of his actions; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Congress has an institutional interest in understanding whether the President is capable of discharging these powers and duties: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="OLC" id="H8438FA431CF84A3BBA38CFD7F8126D2D"> <section id="HCC8500F1A0A74DE4ACC7686CB79D60A5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is hereby established in the House of Representatives a Select Committee on President Biden’s Cognitive Decline (hereafter in this resolution referred to as the <quote>Select Committee</quote>).</text></section> 
<section id="H8FECCA90E3AD4A4BA6B4FA8D2E35E560"><enum>2.</enum><header>Composition</header> 
<subsection id="HF1E787CFB94E4589B156D3AC9B3691E2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Appointment of members</header><text>The Speaker shall appoint 13 Members to the Select Committee, 5 of whom shall be appointed after consultation with the minority leader.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H27D75130162640708BD546F55A92603C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Designation of chair</header><text>The Speaker shall designate one Member to serve as chair of the Select Committee.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC6DD75F559E64D76AC6DCB205BA75C1A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Vacancies</header><text>Any vacancy in the Select Committee shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HC01C2645451D4F98B4A40A6B077E4581"><enum>3.</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Consistent with the functions described in section 4, the purposes of the Select Committee are the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HB701A7B197C344568DCE7EDA0C792D0C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>To investigate and to report upon the facts, circumstances, and causes related to the coverup of President Biden’s cognitive decline (hereafter referred to as <quote>the coverup</quote>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H72F733D8421C48CD82D878B3D7334535"><enum>(2)</enum><text>To determine who was executing the powers and duties of the President given the coverup.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H37B0C31A502A4ADE922B67867AEF81CF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>To examine and evaluate evidence developed by relevant Federal, State, and local governmental offices regarding the facts and circumstances surrounding the coverup.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H54CA77663B2A4EB98372AACEA977CB78"><enum>(4)</enum><text>To build upon the investigations of other entities and avoid unnecessary duplication of efforts by reviewing the investigations, findings, conclusions, and recommendations of other executive branch, congressional, or independent bipartisan or nonpartisan investigations into the coverup.</text></paragraph> </section> 
<section id="H10A834A23A7947ED8BDB11B1197E8277"><enum>4.</enum><header>Functions</header> 
<subsection id="H144D1F2DB88F45B78BBA45A162DB0CA2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Functions</header><text>The functions of the Select Committee are to—</text> <paragraph id="H5EFC717CEB494F70B9B7EE79ED662E8C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>investigate the facts, circumstances, and causes relating to the coverup, including facts and circumstances relating to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE390BCBC263D4837B85FF380ABD2D7EB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>activities of intelligence agencies, law enforcement agencies, and the Armed Forces, including with respect to intelligence collection, analysis, and dissemination and information sharing among the branches and other instrumentalities of government;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC662B336A03C4537B7972873F064B598"><enum>(B)</enum><text>influencing factors that contributed to the coverup and how technology, including online platforms, financing, and malign foreign influence operations and campaigns may have factored into the motivation, organization, and execution of the coverup; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H70E464BABD15466DA6E56995518D6568"><enum>(C)</enum><text>other entities of the public and private sector as determined relevant by the Select Committee for such investigation;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H917C915A1AC446A7B397C96803B4236C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>identify, review, and evaluate the causes of and the lessons learned from the coverup regarding—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H7898684B284442ED8D0EE91DA3DF92CD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the command, control, and communications of the Federal Government;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H60F29E17E22F4F21B7E782ABA6995423"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the structure, coordination, operational plans, policies, and procedures of the Federal Government;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H34F47542567F4E909945DDF0E0A6019A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the structure, authorities, training, manpower utilization, equipment, and operational planning of the Federal Government; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H73D0238BF58544AF9208F644F63BC3E0"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the policies, protocols, processes, procedures, and systems of the Federal Government;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA508EB856E79479D9555FC39B9D11CD9"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submit all legislative proposals to the House or any committee of the House; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEC2DB5AC93E0446DBAB5B3792C290A80"><enum>(4)</enum><text>not later than September 25, 2026, issue a final report to the House containing such findings, conclusions, and recommendations for corrective measures described in subsection (c) as it may deem necessary.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA9B0566836FD48E18B9776AED9F99FBA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reports</header> 
<paragraph id="H140B7F88EBE44C69B00D958FB357D7B2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Interim reports</header><text>In addition to the final report required under subsection (a)(4), the Select Committee may report to the House or any committee of the House from time to time the results of its investigations, together with such detailed findings and legislative proposals as it may deem advisable.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5B29597FFBBB4BDABB28AA1418DCC083"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Treatment of classified or law enforcement-sensitive matter</header><text>Any report issued by the Select Committee shall be issued in unclassified form but may include a classified annex, a law enforcement-sensitive annex, or both.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6BC8F60BE5B2459EA730D77EE0AC4BF1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Corrective measures described</header><text>The corrective measures described in this subsection may include changes in law, policy, procedures, rules, or regulations that could be taken—</text> <paragraph id="HDADAFF9EB8454F79B590579AD13905DB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to prevent future acts covering up the President’s cognitive decline;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H13A342B09CE54459851A3FA1414AF272"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to improve the public’s understanding of the President’s cognitive health; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA906C6FFF2F949D2BB26016955FEB372"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to strengthen the domestic institutions of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H910E367525BC411FA2782038E8D89B9E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>No legislative jurisdiction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Select Committee shall not have legislative jurisdiction and shall have no authority to take legislative action on any bill or resolution.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H42B79C120274469D96227D6FDDF1DBA7"><enum>5.</enum><header>Procedure</header> <subsection id="H0C817B32C63148BFB75B575A0382C5F3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Access to information from Intelligence Community</header><text>Notwithstanding clause 3(m) of rule X of the Rules of the House of Representatives, the Select Committee is authorized to study the sources and methods of entities described in clause 11(b)(1)(A) of rule X insofar as such study is related to the matters described in sections 3 and 4.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF30A1B8C670243FBBB452E0F98D68531"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Treatment of classified information</header><text>Clause 11(b)(4), clause 11(e), and the first sentence of clause 11(f) of rule X of the Rules of the House of Representatives shall apply to the Select Committee.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H779CA514AB9B493CB4A719B43B214287"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applicability of rules governing procedures of committees</header><text>Rule XI of the Rules of the House of Representatives shall apply to the Select Committee except as follows:</text> 
<paragraph id="H7167526A22C0496389140CEED5896DF7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Clause 2(a) of rule XI shall not apply to the Select Committee.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD75C5D0427CF43E89718452DA0C60BC9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Clause 2(g)(2)(D) of rule XI shall apply to the Select Committee in the same manner as it applies to the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8D81DE7D0DB54AE2902BADEEA9011595"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Pursuant to clause 2(h) of rule XI, two Members of the Select Committee shall constitute a quorum for taking testimony or receiving evidence and one-third of the Members of the Select Committee shall constitute a quorum for taking any action other than one for which the presence of a majority of the Select Committee is required.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBB007C7616354FCF822B1B9EC5FDE700"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The chair of the Select Committee may authorize and issue subpoenas pursuant to clause 2(m) of rule XI in the investigation and study conducted pursuant to sections 3 and 4 of this resolution, including for the purpose of taking depositions.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H73FC3AC46E214C8E9209FFA002BA8715"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The chair of the Select Committee is authorized to compel by subpoena the furnishing of information by interrogatory.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4CC191039FB04FFB93879BEF5F7627C6"><enum>(6)</enum> <subparagraph id="HAD6E5C4C48F84C9C93316C582DF9510C" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The chair of the Select Committee, upon consultation with the ranking minority member, may order the taking of depositions, including pursuant to subpoena, by a Member or counsel of the Select Committee, in the same manner as a standing committee pursuant to section 3(t) of House Resolution 5, One Hundred Nineteenth Congress.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H91088C7ACC1649EFBA00AA07023ED31F" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Depositions taken under the authority prescribed in this paragraph shall be governed by the most recent procedures submitted by the chair of the Committee on Rules for printing in the Congressional Record.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC4E8C9475839423C8DFAEAE6CB2FAF0A"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Subpoenas authorized pursuant to this resolution may be signed by the chair of the Select Committee or a designee.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H17A2A0F717144377BBC6C5518C914422"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The chair of the Select Committee may, after consultation with the ranking minority member, recognize—</text> <subparagraph id="H0589B5ADFAC148D9AF6A26065BEE8059"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Members of the Select Committee to question a witness for periods longer than five minutes as though pursuant to clause 2(j)(2)(B) of rule XI; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9A17075AE66B4CE0B6052D76DC0E2771"><enum>(B)</enum><text>staff of the Select Committee to question a witness as though pursuant to clause 2(j)(2)(C) of rule XI.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H02DB643E31604A05AFFF9CE159F5A1AA"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The chair of the Select Committee may postpone further proceedings when a record vote is ordered on questions referenced in clause 2(h)(4) of rule XI, and may resume proceedings on such postponed questions at any time after reasonable notice. Notwithstanding any intervening order for the previous question, an underlying proposition shall remain subject to further debate or amendment to the same extent as when the question was postponed.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9106F1458978406089B15818D6AE6B85"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The provisions of paragraphs (f)(1) through (f)(12) of clause 4 of rule XI shall apply to the Select Committee.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H764FF7AEF8C548FBB0543079FA7C7FFF"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>The Select Committee shall ensure that reports and proposals prepared under this resolution shall, upon completion, be made available to the general public in widely accessible formats not later than 10 calendar days after the submission of the final report under section 4(a)(4).</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H84BF8AF1DBB44A0EB389FCCC8D5489FD"><enum>6.</enum><header>Records; staff; travel; funding</header> 
<subsection id="H5C720A4B69C04B089C3CEA8A6BEE8500"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Access to records of committees</header><text>A committee of the House shall cooperate with the Select Committee in providing access to records of the committee which will support the Select Committee in carrying out its purposes and functions.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HAA557AE25D024BD69DF55C445EC20B31"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Staff</header><text>The appointment and the compensation of staff for the Select Committee shall be subject to regulations issued by the Committee on House Administration.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFB94FD342126426DAADBF0955B2055E0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Detail of staff from the legislative and executive branches</header> 
<paragraph id="HBA7A60EE09324075B60464FA84DF4A65"><enum>(1)</enum><header>House staff</header><text>Staff of employing entities of the House or a joint committee may be detailed to the Select Committee to carry out this resolution and shall be deemed to be staff of the Select Committee.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFC528100A5DE46569C037D35FFAFD3CB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Executive branch staff</header><text>The Select Committee may request the head of any Federal agency to detail, on a nonreimbursable basis, any of the personnel of the agency to the Select Committee.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD9B7453BA086471CA2CB0FCDA8428052"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Use of consultants permitted</header><text>Section 202(i) of the Legislative Reorganization Act of 1946 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/4301">2 U.S.C. 4301(i)</external-xref>) shall apply with respect to the Select Committee in the same manner as such section applies with respect to a standing committee of the House of Representatives.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H41E71B5410B940F297993703A7A1FD20"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Travel</header><text>Clauses 8(a), (b), and (c) of rule X of the Rules of the House of Representatives shall apply to the Select Committee.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H068C85A5A87F47C886F8284CD90EB48B"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Funding; payments</header><text>There shall be paid out of the applicable accounts of the House of Representatives such sums as may be necessary for the expenses of the Select Committee. Such payments shall be made on vouchers signed by the chair of the Select Committee and approved in the manner directed by the Committee on House Administration. Amounts made available under this subsection shall be expended in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Committee on House Administration.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H1CCC536D21B2476098250D05CEE5869C"><enum>7.</enum><header>Termination and disposition of records</header> <subsection id="HBE9C5F008D1B43C5A970AE5927BAF80B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The Select Committee shall terminate 30 days after filing the final report under section 4.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA10ABF233C3C429E8DF1FCA246C70732"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Disposition of records</header><text>Upon termination of the Select Committee—</text> <paragraph id="H5F876B0F8DF1425BA0CD859C0C6C276B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the records of the Select Committee shall become the records of such committee or committees designated by the Speaker; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC24DE238991D4A96B948EC056127649C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the copies of records provided to the Select Committee by a committee of the House under section 6(a) shall be returned to the committee.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

