<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H68AE654718624053AB47FC93E33B731F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1664 IH: Deploying American Blockchains Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1664</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250227">February 27, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001039">Mrs. Cammack</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S001200">Mr. Soto</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Commerce to take actions necessary and appropriate to promote the competitiveness of the United States related to the deployment, use, application, and competitiveness of blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC16FDB00C94F43F694D0F3EF68359AD7" style="OLC"><section id="HC63BF2BA3286494B9AF05E95C730DBA7" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Deploying American Blockchains Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H84E1BE7ED24145489C815459ACF751DC"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="HD57F4B8781144E3A83A96537FAA05091"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology</header><text>The term <quote>blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology</quote> means a distributed digital database where data is—</text><subparagraph id="H8F7D4335F15249F295FF19A25F79C1FC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shared across a network of computers to create a ledger of verified information among network participants;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE21FCF17D93F4BA98EBD8103769F6707"><enum>(B)</enum><text>linked using cryptography to maintain the integrity of the ledger and to execute other functions; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA9EA22F44901493281715737B7FD14FC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>distributed among network participants in an automated fashion to concurrently update network participants on the state of the ledger and other functions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H022A416BDFCB4DD3A9E26F797F9CA5CC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered nongovernmental representatives</header><text>The term <quote>covered nongovernmental representatives</quote> means representatives as specified in the second sentence of section 135(b)(1) of the Trade Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/2155">19 U.S.C. 2155(b)(1)</external-xref>), except that such term does not include representatives of non-Federal Governments.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H38C7CA2071674FB0AA80CC0DAE614FB5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of Commerce.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H414538BC61D14CB5B41843B8BDA04E8B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <quote>State</quote> means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, each commonwealth, territory, or possession of the United States, and each federally recognized Indian Tribe.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7E24BA1977324319BFB3107B99F003FE"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Token</header><text>The term <quote>token</quote> means a transferable, digital representation of information recorded on blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3943164B073C4466BE67EE3B06831CB5"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Tokenization</header><text>The term <quote>tokenization</quote> means the process of creating a token.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H1883C27BF66F46BBB854C9E3D6B4B4AD"><enum>3.</enum><header>Department of commerce leadership on blockchain</header><subsection id="HE1D44F591F264FD186942592B454B0D6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Function of secretary</header><text>The Secretary shall serve as the principal advisor to the President for policy pertaining to the deployment, use, application, and competitiveness of blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, applications built on blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, tokens, and tokenization.</text></subsection><subsection id="H38432E0A411F4078A35EDB32EF901A17"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Activities</header><text>The Secretary shall take actions necessary and appropriate to support the leadership of the United States with respect to the deployment, use, application, and competitiveness of blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, applications built on blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, tokens, and tokenization, including by—</text><paragraph id="H56626D445E514FC4B4636DFE6D172E54"><enum>(1)</enum><text>developing policies and recommendations on issues and risks related to the deployment, use, application, and competitiveness of blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, applications built on blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, tokens, and tokenization, including the issues of decentralized identity, cybersecurity, key storage and security systems, artificial intelligence, fraud reduction, regulatory compliance, e-commerce, health care applications, and supply chain resiliency;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H96C8576C95B147FE80B438CBA3713A2A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>supporting and promoting the stability, maintenance, improvement, and security of blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, applications built on blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, tokens, and tokenization;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H643526129D554143AFEDEB963966CD63"><enum>(3)</enum><text>helping to promote the leadership of the United States with respect to the deployment, use, application, and competitiveness of blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, applications built on blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, tokens, and tokenization through the establishment of a Blockchain Deployment Program in the Department of Commerce;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H539A02A965334244B8D67110CB5BDAD1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>promoting the national security and economic security of the United States with respect to blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, applications built on blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, tokens, and tokenization;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HED94443BE7FC4DFA86B497393C3D6788"><enum>(5)</enum><text>supporting engagement with the public to promote the best practices described in subsection (c);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H710394CF63884C3E80FE150E77AB39AB"><enum>(6)</enum><text>considering policies and programs to encourage and improve coordination among Federal agencies with respect to the deployment of blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, applications built on blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, tokens, and tokenization;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE2E0708E2DB24A07B2FC3725C41E7CE3"><enum>(7)</enum><text>examining—</text><subparagraph id="H92C9646857CE457AAECD09589B3D30E3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>how Federal agencies can benefit from utilizing blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, applications built on blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, tokens, and tokenization;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H43820FEF7B3A454B9871B9D9D7F07562"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the current use by Federal agencies of blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, applications built on blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, tokens, and tokenization;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8E86610E76984572BB0E3A5462827D8A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the current and future preparedness and ability of Federal agencies to adopt blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, applications built on blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, tokens, and tokenization; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H455D81A68B8744629F4853D0A4829071"><enum>(D)</enum><text>additional security measures Federal agencies may need to take to—</text><clause id="H98E2B9F3545C4F919C99FF3D9974C06D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>safely and securely use blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, applications built on blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, tokens, and tokenization, including to ensure the security of critical infrastructure; and</text></clause><clause id="H687EC4F208AD415F997AE6D5757EB423"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>enhance the resiliency of Federal systems against cyber threats to blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, applications built on blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, tokens, and tokenization;</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H71562239C7C64279B181FD77DA5363C4"><enum>(8)</enum><text>supporting coordination of the activities of the Federal Government related to the security of blockchain technology and other distributed ledger technology, applications built on blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, tokens, and tokenization; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H378A1F8BB95C4696A9137A027795EDC3"><enum>(9)</enum><text>not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, establishing advisory committees to support the adoption of blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, applications built on blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, tokens, and tokenization, the membership of which shall include—</text><subparagraph id="HEF2F9FABEC954ACEA69FEB2291CB9D0D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6DA0FA6A37AA4A929BA695271859486B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>representatives of Federal agencies (as determined necessary by the Secretary); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0B7BBBA92BBA43D58C39645D1489BA92"><enum>(C)</enum><text>nongovernmental stakeholders with expertise related to blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, including—</text><clause id="HDA076DF3CEA3472C954A528BDA25EB46"><enum>(i)</enum><text>blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology infrastructure operators, suppliers, service providers, and vendors;</text></clause><clause id="H61946058374E499B82C8D262C5173BAF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>application developers building on blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology;</text></clause><clause id="HE03A4391CD8F40A8B9A8E08BE422CF9C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>developers and organizations supporting the advancement and deployment of public blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology;</text></clause><clause id="H78C43B2B954D45EEA6512C1BB6201B3E"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>subject matter experts representing industrial sectors that can benefit from blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology;</text></clause><clause id="H4C21340C7330454EB45C084E349F6F8D"><enum>(v)</enum><text>small, medium, and large businesses;</text></clause><clause id="H80AF345866E84463A159FA0536143782"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>think tanks and academia;</text></clause><clause id="HC7E00761E8D4419089F0A50250F0E48F"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>nonprofit organizations and consumer groups;</text></clause><clause id="H2F869A261C5546C3A093F6EF61B09AE8"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>cybersecurity experts;</text></clause><clause id="H71A7368C976D4508BF7482B0DB9DEAEC"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>rural stakeholders;</text></clause><clause id="H5B88CE2360FB4A31882C6F5B4B8DC8B4"><enum>(x)</enum><text>covered nongovernmental representatives;</text></clause><clause id="HE5B52BC8F44B49F99E30F9AEFB3E7368"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>artists and the content creator community; and</text></clause><clause id="H236EABA6F52E4F249A871BD9F59F1C26"><enum>(xii)</enum><text>other stakeholders with relevant expertise (as determined necessary by the Secretary).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC356E38C4A5748E89DA18A0E212B40F7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Best practices</header><text>The Secretary shall, on an ongoing basis, facilitate and support the development and dissemination of best practices with respect to blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, applications built on blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, tokens, and tokenization that—</text><paragraph id="H8AFEF198D7F44E0BBFC843B81A143D8C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>support the private sector, the public sector, and public-private partnerships in the deployment of technologies needed to advance the capabilities of blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, applications built on blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, tokens, and tokenization;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5CE764F8F3CB4266AFAE9F7E455EB405"><enum>(2)</enum><text>support the interoperability of blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, applications built on blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, tokens, and tokenization;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H457642198F50433A9722208BAC5599B8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>support operations, including hashing and key storage and security systems, that form the foundation of blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, applications built on blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, tokens, and tokenization;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2C12F093B091478E895800F9AAEFE1C6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>reduce cybersecurity and other risks that may compromise blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, applications built on blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, tokens, and tokenization;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H59DE44C500BE4982B534444405748F3D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>reduce uncertainty and risks in the use of blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, applications built on blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, tokens, and tokenization; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC657508629164A51B4225F002E77A22E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>quantify the value and potential cost savings associated with adoption of blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, applications built on blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, tokens, and tokenization, including through comparative analyses of competing and existing technologies within specific industry applications.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9791A563ABBA4C53AA5BB9769CC21586"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Additional requirements</header><text>In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="HCA90D1C9FA2A4AD1916335917DB634EE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>consult closely and regularly with stakeholders, including private sector individuals and entities, and incorporate industry expertise;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFFC9931620C24C59809A8CCCF0D53BAC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>collaborate with private sector stakeholders to identify prioritized, flexible, repeatable, performance-based, and cost-effective approaches to the deployment of blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, applications built on blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, tokens, and tokenization;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF3E84B21718044339D3A8669CE9591DA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>disseminate research and information pertaining to the use of, and marketplace for, blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, applications built on blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, tokens, and tokenization;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF571DBA325BB421CB47985981B4A3804"><enum>(4)</enum><text>develop standardized terminology for, and promote common understanding of, blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, applications built on blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, tokens, and tokenization;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB48CBCFA769F4CE3BB3A403856699521"><enum>(5)</enum><text>ensure the best practices described in subsection (c) facilitate the ease of use of blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, applications built on blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, tokens, and tokenization;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA0B42E9D93964051808E4F05A1D1D888"><enum>(6)</enum><text>support open-source infrastructure, data management, and authentication activities with respect to blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, applications built on blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, tokens, and tokenization; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6AEAADCD47944EA18A23D878E6279DC5"><enum>(7)</enum><text>consider the needs and interests of both the private and public sector, including small businesses and Federal, State, and local governments.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H456E664AA9064B0D9747DBD3899148E1"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Rules of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to—</text><paragraph id="HC45EF924C78B4E4492C6BCB07BA38092"><enum>(1)</enum><text>require a private entity to share information with the Secretary;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA4D3EA362786423A8AB41C8125643796"><enum>(2)</enum><text>require a private entity to request assistance from the Secretary;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAC0B78987AAE40388422EB76DAB8AC3E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>require a private entity to implement any measure or recommendation suggested by the Secretary in response to a request by the private entity; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6D8AF5145D2C416497D8B1BF683DC6B3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>require the adoption of the best practices described in subsection (c).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7004AFFC2FFB494EA6179C5F7C3A22C4"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In implementing this section, the Secretary may, as appropriate, consult with the heads of relevant Federal agencies.</text></subsection><subsection id="HFFC824E7F8884570AAEEAA1EDAA7B36D"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Termination of program</header><text>The Blockchain Deployment Program established pursuant to subsection (b)(3) shall terminate on the date that is 7 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="H19ABAC357399449E9E0731B37CA44CB7"><enum>4.</enum><header>Report to congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall make public on the website of the Department of Commerce and submit to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a report that includes—</text><paragraph id="HFC8A224696264B458B310F28C31F0CDC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a description of the activities of the Secretary under this Act during the preceding year;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H90929EF227B2473D9009883BF24661F3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any recommendations by the Secretary for additional legislation to strengthen the competitiveness of the United States with respect to blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, applications built on blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, tokens, and tokenization; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2962050EACAF4325931BAA23A991DD54"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a description of any emerging risks and long-term trends with respect to blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, applications built on blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, tokens, and tokenization.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

