<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H75A6B04ACCA34C51A68FD9AB8268A9F0" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1449 IH: Energy Resilient Communities Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1449</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250221">February 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barrag&#225;n</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001225">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001218">Ms. Stansbury</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001205">Ms. Scanlon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001055">Mr. Case</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001217">Mr. Moskowitz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000172">Ms. Ocasio-Cortez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001226">Ms. Salinas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000176">Mr. Olszewski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001066">Ms. Castor of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Energy to carry out a grant program to improve the energy resilience, energy democracy, and security of communities, prioritizing environmental justice communities, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD92E943E7383493D8BF872D18383C14E" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H8A932CD930E74DF78D9B24C2BF04168C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Energy Resilient Communities Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section> <section id="HB02E98B7AD5040EEB028A7BA26D61D4D" commented="no"><enum>2.</enum><header>Clean energy microgrid grant program</header> <subsection id="H275801D4CE2A4EBEAB939D0D0F53EC97" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Energy shall establish and carry out a program to provide grants to eligible entities.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HA50E8D1394A7496BB68D6373C5AC00B2" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>An eligible entity may use a grant provided under the program established pursuant to subsection (a) to—</text> <paragraph id="HA89AF494988945239A63D369818AFB17" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>obtain technical assistance to—</text>
<subparagraph id="H7C91973FB2574557866F5D110F93E126" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">upgrade building codes and standards for resiliency to climate change hazards (including wildfires, flooding, sea level rise, landslides, drought, storms, temperature extremes, and other extreme weather events);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H067CD69F1E1E41A28CDD1899BC5F46F7" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>develop a FEMA Hazard Mitigation Plan to identify and overcome known climate change hazards to critical community infrastructure; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HAC91692F7F92438B9F20547F3A21C975" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>conduct a needs assessment of prospective clean energy microgrid projects and, as applicable, design prospective clean energy microgrids, including assistance to address permitting and siting challenges, understand and facilitate financing options, and understand the technical characteristics of clean energy microgrids; </text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7D93F6DBF49941ADB6EBB11BE8648E6F" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide community outreach and collaborative planning with respect to a prospective project described in paragraph (3); or </text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HDF82ED15073A4DA2990EF73A1490F95E" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>carry out a project to develop and construct—</text> <subparagraph id="H4D4784AAE06D4A2C915D3C7117F8A87E" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a clean energy microgrid that supports critical community infrastructure; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H4442C10F735B4002A0946EFE112FB126" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a clean energy microgrid for residences of medical baseline customers.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H8FB153CB20F14D7BBD68B92F8EBBA570" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Priority</header> <paragraph id="HF01DA8013EA6471AAF9A072BDDFB7002" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In providing grants under the program established pursuant to subsection (a), the Secretary of Energy shall give priority to an eligible entity that proposes to use a grant to obtain technical assistance described in subsection (b)(1), provide outreach described in subsection (b)(2), or carry out a project described in subsection (b)(3), that will benefit an environmental justice community.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7933BCE98DC248EA8B8F2092A8F89695" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Technical assistance and community outreach grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After priority given under paragraph (1), in providing grants to obtain technical assistance described in subsection (b)(1) or provide outreach described in subsection (b)(2), the Secretary of Energy shall give priority to an eligible entity proposing to obtain technical assistance or provide outreach that the Secretary of Energy determines will further the development of clean energy microgrids that are community-owned energy systems. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H74A5993C00004B839D89DF5B9A6F29D8" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Clean energy microgrid grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After priority given under paragraph (1), in providing grants under the program established pursuant to subsection (a) for projects described in subsection (b)(3), the Secretary of Energy shall give priority to an eligible entity that—</text>
<subparagraph id="HD1410DE48C9645C5A23F602B8BCAB657" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>proposes to develop and construct a clean energy microgrid that, in comparison to other clean energy microgrids for which grants are sought under such program, will result in the greatest reduction—</text> <clause id="HCFB0130574C14E9C8B771359BAD4DB10" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>of greenhouse gas emissions;</text></clause>
<clause id="H2F71A1C6BF51459288C3D8279AE2BDB6" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>of emissions of criteria air pollutants; </text></clause> <clause id="H892DA6331A6B497D978A6F14D3FF6B10" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in public health disparities in communities experiencing a disproportionate level of air pollution; or</text></clause>
<clause id="H8895C0463CA84FDCA82410D49038F98C"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the energy cost burden for communities;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB0FEBAD4B84E4E7489CA42A1C0C51F78" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>proposes to develop and construct a clean energy microgrid that is a community-owned energy system;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HDE07C2BDF11A4890972475DA70F8CABF" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">proposes to develop and construct a clean energy microgrid that, in comparison to other clean energy microgrids for which grants are sought under such program, will provide the greatest amount of resiliency benefits to a jurisdiction in which the microgrid is located;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2B10146870B4426CB19827DAEE100F2A" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>proposes to develop and construct a clean energy microgrid that minimizes land use impacts by—</text>
<clause id="H5B4454F005B3457F8E154E200DF0BCCC" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">siting sources of clean energy within the already-built environment, including over rooftops and parking lots;</text></clause> <clause id="H014B6EECE09347E79A897F33F52C5530" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">siting sources of clean energy on existing brownfield sites or contaminated sites;</text></clause>
<clause id="HFE350292963E40B6B1178754E07C81F9" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">co-locating sources of clean energy on agricultural lands or over reservoirs; or</text></clause> <clause id="HA41E360284E343E39CCEEDDD4AFC626F" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">siting sources of clean energy on compatible lands;</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H97C972A93F904FAD890164FC9CBCF509" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">proposes to, in developing and constructing a clean energy microgrid, utilize or involve small businesses or nonprofits that primarily operate or are located within environmental justice communities, particularly those that are women-owned and operated or minority-owned and operated;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE9D5F78FC3CB4FEDB281334F931C106C" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text>has previously received a grant to obtain technical assistance under such program;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H98043D9EBBC4467193D30D0B8BB8D88E" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><text>imposes registered apprentice utilization requirements on projects, provided that such requirements comply with the apprentice to journey worker ratios established by the Department of Labor or the applicable State Apprenticeship Agency; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H21C376F6588E4080A17FA5589EDE4936"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">proposes to develop and construct a clean energy microgrid in an area designated nonattainment and classified as an Extreme Area or Severe Area for one or more criteria air pollutants.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H9EBB092D7F0748E9B4E6875D801835AC" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Educational outreach program</header>
<paragraph id="HE14CAD8787AE4652A62D919D6EBDECA2" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after funds are made available to carry out this section, the Secretary of Energy shall develop and carry out an educational outreach program to inform eligible entities about the program established pursuant to subsection (a).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1C33B26D30C04291B20F756A1449FB17" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contracts</header><text>The Secretary of Energy may enter into third-party contracts to implement the educational outreach program under paragraph (1). In entering into contracts pursuant to this paragraph, the Secretary shall prioritize entering into contracts with women-owned and operated or minority-owned and operated entities. </text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HAAF1E464E32A4E2BBB05615022A4EF77" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>The educational outreach program under paragraph (1) shall prioritize—</text> <subparagraph id="HC8783900A0364F08BAB6AC3E1AA5F5BA" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>providing information on the program established pursuant to subsection (a) to eligible entities that serve an environmental justice community and to environmental justice communities; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HEFD31BBA2CB64980916C6E62350B49D5" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>promoting public understanding of the community benefits of clean energy microgrids for critical community infrastructure.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H0AB8BD3501B54C9088D60CD06C071D0E" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Cost share</header> <paragraph id="H68BBE3998D824F27B91FD0C2CA53139A" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the Federal share of the cost of technical assistance, outreach, or a project for which a grant is provided pursuant to the program established pursuant to subsection (a) shall not exceed 60 percent of such cost. </text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD566C8F621CA423F9A04F00EE64E7A0A" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Environmental justice community</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal share of the cost of technical assistance that is obtained for, outreach that is provided to, or a project that is carried out in, an environmental justice community, and for which a grant is provided pursuant to the program established pursuant to subsection (a) shall not exceed 90 percent of such cost.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H92D6C720807A4CAF9DACE7389ED536B8" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Limitation on amount</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount of a grant provided to an eligible entity under this section to carry out a project described in subsection (b)(3) may not exceed $10,000,000.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H571861C9A7AF4EEE893454D6F6CC31B0" commented="no"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Use of American iron, steel, and manufactured goods</header>
<paragraph id="HE6EB69F30CDD4298834FA05FAEE6A1EE" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>No funds authorized under this section shall be made available with respect to a project unless all of the iron, steel, and manufactured goods used in the project are produced in the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1E18E18A6D1643F6AA6EDFFAB7CA4A36" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Paragraph (1) shall not apply in any case or category of cases in which the Secretary of Energy finds that—</text>
<subparagraph id="H74538F9478344E68B0259510CE532F28" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>applying paragraph (1) would be inconsistent with the public interest;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCDA4F70D180E4F0082FFB1ECE54812FB" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>iron, steel, and the relevant manufactured goods are not produced in the United States in sufficient and reasonably available quantities and of a satisfactory quality; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HFF71D61E4BB7467AA00E478EFF6B5292" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>inclusion of iron, steel, and manufactured goods produced in the United States will increase the cost of the overall project by more than 25 percent.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE3D3E4B4D0B84185B3B3FC2F06663382" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>If the Secretary of Energy receives a request for a waiver under this subsection, the Secretary shall make available to the public on an informal basis a copy of the request and information available to the Secretary concerning the request, and shall allow for informal public input on the request for at least 15 days prior to making a finding based on the request. The Secretary shall make the request and accompanying information available by electronic means, including on the official public website of the Department of Energy.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H925C29EF4A544EE5B988718E755EAF10" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>This subsection shall be applied in a manner consistent with the United States obligations under international agreements.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H6F617E980AEE4BA98E010D940CDF0044" commented="no"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Prevailing wages</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">All laborers and mechanics employed by contractors or subcontractors in the performance of construction, alteration, or repair work assisted, in whole or in part, by a grant under this section shall be paid wages at rates not less than those prevailing on similar construction in the locality as determined by the Secretary of Labor in accordance with subchapter IV of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/40/31">chapter 31</external-xref> of title 40, United States Code. With respect to the labor standards in this subsection, the Secretary of Labor shall have the authority and functions set forth in Reorganization Plan Numbered 14 of 1950 (64 Stat. 1267; 5 U.S.C. App.) and section 3145 of title 40, United States Code.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H99D4C443ED314AC9A91C97ED2F7ACE70" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Project labor</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity that uses a grant provided under this section to construct a clean energy microgrid shall ensure, to the greatest extent practicable, that any subgrantee of such eligible entity, and any subgrantee thereof, that carries out such construction employs at least 40 percent of laborers or mechanics for such construction that are individuals who—</text> <paragraph id="HE7F4DD6579944D61969EE2748C9B03CB" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>are domiciled, if the applicable construction area is—</text>
<subparagraph id="H0BF47F21EB754ED2AE353BF7EACF7A41" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a major urban area, not further than 15 miles from such construction area; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6BA7678A0F4F4383AD7872CAEB3D4412" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not a major urban area, not further than 50 miles from such construction area;</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0B978C4B688F4FE49B376B359AB5BA42" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>are displaced and unemployed energy workers;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H841BC1AA8E42488EA7A609580B293EDE" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>are members of the Armed Forces serving on active duty, separated from active duty, or retired from active duty;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5B6D990E53B94B6C9EC112AF32F5F923" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have been incarcerated or served time in a juvenile or adult detention or correctional facility, or been placed on probation, community supervision, or in a diversion scheme;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H232C8CDE8C994A0B8AEFA4092F34E7CF" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>have a disability;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1EA58B93A8A942F2B7CB8F0F31C24898" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are homeless;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBFB6E6CB92BE40B5906235813884922C" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><text>are receiving public assistance;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9D9C4AEFE53E4C22A6AF7DF31098399E" commented="no"><enum>(8)</enum><text>lack a general education diploma or high school diploma;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5091D25ED0504299A07BDE7DC6CFEE8A" commented="no"><enum>(9)</enum><text>are emancipated from the foster care system;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H64510EC37E7B4B30A1669FC56328349B" commented="no"><enum>(10)</enum><text>reside or work in an environmental justice community; or </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H262E70C46E8B428D99E0F4252BEC6CBF" commented="no"><enum>(11)</enum><text>are registered apprentices with fewer than 15 percent of the required graduating apprentice hours in a program.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H7DC107777A75472481D196476816D1D1" commented="no"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Energy shall submit to Congress, and make available on the public website of the Department of Energy, an annual report on the program established pursuant to subsection (a) that includes, with respect to the previous year—</text> <paragraph id="HC20D969271FF4AD18E78E3BDD8568B02" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the number of grants provided;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD4B27DDE5F7748829A4BE819CB265B83" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the total dollar amount of all grants provided; </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7041EE51E5F34F91A9218E9981337F5F" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a list of grant disbursements by State; </text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7D2A8247F5B64F64ABC87BD7E7A7D11F" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>for each grant provided—</text> <subparagraph id="H829CEF217D4249338C0468AA6B310D54" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of the technical assistance obtained, outreach provided, or project carried out with grants funds; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD5779DEFB92041F2B8BA50E259CB2C84" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether the grant is provided to obtain technical assistance, provide outreach, or carry out a project with respect to an environmental justice community; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H19AA01BA4CA54D35B20849C0D13C406E" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>for each grant provided to carry out a clean energy microgrid project—</text>
<subparagraph id="HAF3A52C64C494331BF3E518FE2DA34B7" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">employment data for such project, including the number of jobs created and what percent of laborers and mechanics hired for such project meet the criteria under subsection (i); </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1CA9E8F784C24D37848155F8ABD53D32" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the greenhouse gas and criteria air pollutant reduction impacts for such project; </text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HAE19CBB4548B4872A2F47118D180B36A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the public health benefits from such project; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H08459EEAB1C843ADB634BD72F2F25735"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the reduced energy cost burden from such project.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H001EC619B2D44F51A79DA9CD0AD8634C" commented="no"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Funding</header>
<paragraph id="H802FD909257E41F79010628F06C2E5B1" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>For each of fiscal years 2025 through 2034, there is authorized to be appropriated—</text> <subparagraph id="HC0726A7B0403456B9F1C76A957DFAC5A" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$50,000,000 for grants for technical assistance described in subsection (b)(1) and outreach described in subsection (b)(2); and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HC75CA9707CC04CFC82EEA23236B50AE8" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$1,500,000,000 for grants for projects described in subsection (b)(3).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1BED5CEDEFE540A28332C302E71AFD39" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Community-owned energy systems</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To the maximum extent practicable, not less than 10 percent of the amount appropriated under paragraph (1)(B) for any fiscal year shall be used to provide grants for projects to develop and construct clean energy microgrids that are community-owned energy systems.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA98A0C819A0043E2BE1C542BC9FD6AC3" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Administrative expenses</header>
<subparagraph id="HFBB89C175D6C4025BE31609E4B509672" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Technical assistance and outreach</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may use not more than 2 percent of the amount appropriated for any fiscal year under paragraph (1)(A) for administrative expenses. </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0EFEB6E8AF2E4884A942D63DBBB58E67" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Clean energy microgrid projects</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may use not more than 2 percent of the amount appropriated for any fiscal year under paragraph (1)(B) for administrative expenses, including expenses for carrying out the educational outreach program under subsection (d).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H2B04A0EAFDFD4568A85D09B05A9745BC" commented="no"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H07B487A155054FA6A55CF94EDD5D15AD" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Clean energy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>clean energy</term> means electric energy generated from solar, wind, geothermal, existing hydropower, micro-hydropower, hydrokinetic, or hydrogen fuel cells.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HBD7FC4CD97C54B8599071CFA873F2A8B" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Community of color</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>community of color</term> means a geographically distinct area in which the population of any of the following categories of individuals is higher than the average populations of that category for the State in which the community is located:</text> <subparagraph id="H0D2B9ECC2EFD4FB7886CB8D4E9C4D3CE" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Black.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD0965522667F4E47A28BD88C55A9CA03" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>African American.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD66A8DB55B504C9998995853671794E3" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Asian. </text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HBA1E30CB0DDF4BBA83240EE1E62F43F8" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Pacific Islander.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCBDBFBAC92D644FC9AFB52E6986DF6BD" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Other non-White race.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H7DE736BCA787491CB4B880BFE188AD64" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Non-White Hispanic. </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H01C864D1B181440DBC24FDDCCCF81377" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Latino. </text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H0A01952232D5466D81088EDB8D2A0E45" commented="no"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Linguistically isolated.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDDDBEA36E95A469F86AF0E9614D936CC" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Community-owned energy system</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>community-owned energy system</term> means an energy system owned—</text>
<subparagraph id="H0E6F780CDE0E46799AB5C3958C2664DD" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by the local government where the system is located;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA843C417A30749D399E76426E7F5B4AF" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by a nonprofit organization that is based in the local jurisdiction where the energy system is located;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HEE6D888E650749959C00689B1DA8B9B1" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">collectively, by community members; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC22F4308EF6E44C585F649DD59085C04" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by a worker-owned or community-owned for-profit entity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H80DCEA56D5DB40CFBE88B368EB82732F" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Compatible land</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>compatible land</term> means land that is at least 5 miles away from existing protected areas and within 3 miles of existing transmission infrastructure.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD8EBE4A007AB4B1E8B97FA37909315AF" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Critical community infrastructure</header><text>The term <term>critical community infrastructure</term> means infrastructure that is necessary to providing vital community and individual functions, including—</text>
<subparagraph id="HE37FDBD58F664123A8CBC00BC43E4A1C" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>schools;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEDFE3006F3D54DD5B3B6535475D65717" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>town halls;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H6D662EAC21CA4BDA985A50A49A7538B9" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>public safety facilities;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE3AD2F0DB0C04E348BFCB8856E1221D0" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>hospitals;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H3255ACDBB3B6418BAC17EB4D1EB75F2E" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>health clinics;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H380EFF77DCA344629448B7E89A250D1B" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text>community centers;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H60B8DE48D66541CE84746B7D50C53257" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><text>community nonprofit facilities providing essential services; </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H897223CFC00F495BA02E707887BF4949" commented="no"><enum>(H)</enum><text>libraries;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HF8D018C4A832498391B20D78B9B58C1A" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>grocery stores;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC9B58E6335254877B9D81C6FC8212E93" commented="no"><enum>(J)</enum><text>emergency management facilities;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H3CA52AB1629A45C6812A15306EF4B7C8" commented="no"><enum>(K)</enum><text>water systems;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF998336478154FDDA5FC109B36E519AE" commented="no"><enum>(L)</enum><text>homeless shelters; </text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H46403CAE731A4AC39FE678F887724827" commented="no"><enum>(M)</enum><text>senior housing; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC6EBE7D7224442B984386B8D994BC6A9" commented="no"><enum>(N)</enum><text>public or affordable housing.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H63E976874AC9487CBB5429B7D9FB33A0" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H5CF29F9198854A54B07273C02AD22C70" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a State, territory of the United States, or Tribal agency;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA87360C820BE45CEBC1761418DBBF995" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a local government or political subdivision of a State, including a municipally owned electric utility and an agency, authority, corporation, or instrumentality of a State or Indian Tribe;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC7446648AE9E432A8F8A14A917341337" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an electric utility;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H0ACDA21DD9FD4CA3919E532F5CC5D0E5" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a nonprofit organization; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H109D8827D89C4186B668E0D45F8FE068" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a partnership between—</text>
<clause id="H0C473B33EABD4ED69892C4C572551A38" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a private entity, or a nonprofit organization, that owns critical community infrastructure; and</text></clause> <clause id="HDD4CEE57D6934FCE977F27909CC9404F" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a State, territory of the United States, Tribal agency, or local government.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6CEFE83D6C954AA2A991658E69432396" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Environmental justice community</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>environmental justice community</term> means a community with significant representation of communities of color, low-income communities, or Tribal and indigenous communities, that experiences, or is at risk of experiencing, higher or more adverse human health or environmental effects.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H047D3AC60B354AC98E3DBC78AE47E506" commented="no"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Low-income community</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>low-income community</term> means any census block group in which 30 percent or more of the population are individuals with an annual household income equal to, or less than, the greater of—</text>
<subparagraph id="H97CC56C075624CC0805506F884407C76" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an amount equal to 80 percent of the median income of the area in which the household is located, as reported by the Department of Housing and Urban Development; and </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF33B6C95822C4C97BE1ED15D708D2BC2" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>200 percent of the Federal poverty line.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H69B13A4F34A24B5083EA36A557552DE2" commented="no"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Major urban area</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>major urban area</term> means a metropolitan statistical area within the United States with an estimated population that is greater than or equal to 1,500,000.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1E7955D965E44B4FB0130FE0D134D4B6" commented="no"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Medical baseline customer</header><text>The term <term>medical baseline customer</term> means a customer of an electric utility with special energy needs due to a medical condition, including energy needs for—</text>
<subparagraph id="H87B68E1F25D04E169EAC9146C5C1F552" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a motorized wheelchair;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE9AFE3B7283C44B69BB882E5C62A4AD7" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a ventilator;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HEE5F9305DA064EE6B44015856141034C" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a dialysis machine;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H79620416D48F4AF0934A6619A44094B5" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an apnea monitor;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HF3F2B3036C34440CA4BCC6ABDC686A55" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>an electrostatic nebulizer;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H52A70A1B76D54E029D952417A2AFB994" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a respirator;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H5BA3A411442B438CBDEE27C1A13BEBA7" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><text>medication requiring refrigeration; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H78D38F6630EF407E879D8A9A254CFAF3" commented="no"><enum>(H)</enum><text>for a customer with a vulnerable respiratory system, an air cleaning system.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H05C5508F1769404894EB49562A932641" commented="no"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Microgrid</header><text>The term <term>microgrid</term> means an interconnected system of loads and clean energy resources (including distributed energy resources, energy storage, demand response tools, and other management, forecasting, and analytical tools) which—</text> <subparagraph id="H2D7D2D6BDF604E5F83B103EF1240CCB8" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is appropriately sized to meet the critical needs of its customers;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H1B9BA13A8D544FE6BB034CB08FC3D12C" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is contained within a clearly defined electrical boundary and has the ability to operate as a single and controllable entity;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3697B6DB2E7B443E9FBD00317C930C9F" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>has the ability to—</text>
<clause id="HB1BFF2FCEE6B4DD1B5EDC59070117109" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>connect to, disconnect from, or run in parallel with the applicable grid region; or</text></clause> <clause id="H0024F706750A488CAE546379314CC945" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>be managed and isolated from the applicable grid region in order to withstand larger disturbances and maintain the supply of electricity to a connected location; </text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H56021E1B2D3540239E45F72B90062E62" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>has no point of interconnection to the applicable grid region with a throughput capacity in excess of 20 megawatts; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H169516615C2440D187EA901511654D97" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>can connect to one building or multiple interconnected buildings.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H3991EAE55E664CD8AD883D65BECD5F8A" commented="no"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Micro-hydropower</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>micro-hydropower</term> means hydropower that produces no more than 100 kilowatts of electricity using the natural flow of water.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H091091DDADD64F55AB89B4B11961AF9D" commented="no"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Produced in the United States</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>produced in the United States</term> means, in the case of iron or steel, that all manufacturing processes, including the application of a coating, occur in the United States.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HBD601BAC6BC34407BA2ECA6BB7895712" commented="no"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Registered apprentice</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>registered apprentice</term> means a person in an apprenticeship program that is registered with, and approved by, the United States Department of Labor or a State Apprenticeship Agency in accordance with parts 29 and 30 of title 29, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on January 1, 2020).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H156FEB089F73401784D4B790424D8446" commented="no"><enum>(15)</enum><header>Small business</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>small business</term> has the meaning given the term <term>small business concern</term> under section 3 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/632">15 U.S.C. 632</external-xref>). </text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF9EDEAC5C97B402E991BAFA31F0E8C29" commented="no"><enum>(16)</enum><header>Tribal and indigenous community</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Tribal and indigenous community</term> means a population of people who are members of—</text> <subparagraph id="H5F3F94CF32204A54982EB8FC7A75A080" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a federally recognized Indian Tribe; </text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H74965CF5BB724E858F490FE46B5EF8D6" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a State-recognized Indian Tribe; </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2FC62269C71C45A3863028471B9ADF9F" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an Alaska Native or Native Hawaiian community or organization; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H03F68308639342BB912053536014F910" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any other community of indigenous people located in a State.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

