<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA7CFF5EB279A4BA5888BC3EA98551EE4" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1290 IH: Veterans Mental Health Crisis Referral Enhancement Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1290</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250213">February 13, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001260">Mr. Buchanan</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001210">Mr. Murphy</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to carry out a pilot program under which the Department of Veterans Affairs refers veterans experiencing mental health crises to approved non-Department mental health care providers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H5714CCDEC47443C799B6E385301A956E" style="OLC"><section id="H61292569564C4F4984D7E6EC7D95EE0B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Veterans Mental Health Crisis Referral Enhancement Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HEAF1B98B1E404EC492B622F4AD2575E3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Department of Veterans Affairs pilot program on mental health referrals</header><subsection id="H13FE91DB7A034DE49DCE90FDF37FC38F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Pilot program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall carry out a three-year pilot program under which Vet Centers and medical facilities of the Department provide veterans experiencing mental health crises with referrals to non-Department mental health care providers approved by the Secretary.</text></subsection><subsection id="H568906638B6846D89EA94B83BC681C9A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Locations</header><text>The Secretary shall select at least three geographic locations at which to carry out the pilot program required under subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="H4FFFF4FF72CC49EF94D5C000278B5C86"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>In carrying out the pilot program under subsection (a), the Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="HD7E2481D324A432CBCB1E545D30E1E1B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>develop and maintain a referral system to connect veterans experiencing mental health crises with non-Department mental health care providers within one week;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1AFE48432C2644C393B7310D11CF01AF"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop criteria for the approval of non-Department mental health care providers for purposes of referrals under the program;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6C2841D7060043A5BA620C50C67E58EB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>hire any additional employees required to facilitate referrals under the system; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H005764F80FA645FBAA096AD05F4B0DD7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>provide appropriate training to employees of Vet Centers and medical facilities of the Department on the referral system.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H36CB5235DEE34A7B853A97E45EC900B8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reports</header><paragraph id="H391CBCFE7E0B4754B08B1A53D9F1DEF9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Annual reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than six months after the last day of each year during which the Secretary carries out the pilot program under subsection (a), the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the implementation and outcomes of the pilot program. Each such report shall include the following for the year covered by the report:</text><subparagraph id="H73DFD3C858FE4432AB2A2B5754599906"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The number of veterans referred to non-Department mental health care providers under the pilot program.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC31401B1BFF7478E96B524BBBE6D0A57"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The average wait time for a veteran to receive mental health care after receiving a referral under the pilot program.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC3C3671B5981487283B3DFB1F8DD0741"><enum>(C)</enum><text>An evaluation of veteran satisfaction with the mental health care received through the referral system.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE6136AFB7F8E49668E249D5B2C53C0A8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Final report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the conclusion of the pilot program, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a final report containing an evaluation of the effectiveness of the program and the recommendations of the Secretary with respect to expanding or modifying the referral system developed under the program.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD8FE585BBE464C7E8B67FDBF3F0E3DC3"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out the pilot program required under subsection (a) $3,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2025 through 2027.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

