<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ELT25036-Y08-82-4T8"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S228 IS: Acequia Communities Empowered by Qualifying Upgrades for Infrastructure Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 228</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250123">January 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S409">Mr. Luján</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S287">Mr. Cornyn</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAF00">Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Federal Agriculture Improvement and Reform Act of 1996 to ensure that producers who rely on acequia systems have access to drought protections, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Acequia Communities Empowered by Qualifying Upgrades for Infrastructure Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H4F75795F76F84718BB3A0FBB3039764F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph commented="no" id="HABBA433D919840AFA5ABE1972ED74BA1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Water delivery systems known as acequias, or community ditches, are a centuries-old system used for water distribution.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id43cbda0070fd4560b1da7ccfa8ea0c85"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A combination of Spanish and Indigenous irrigation methods, acequias were expanded in New Mexico during the 16th century to allow for farming to sustain the needs of the community. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4D51312EE3894F2A952911058960D3AD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Acequias are a vital component of the economy of the State of New Mexico (referred to in this section as the <term>State</term>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4f23e77b73fa400bbbf1e8d83b855bdd"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Acequias are a centuries-old form of water governance and are recognized as political subdivisions of the State. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf4dd648785074a4f9170845db33568ee"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Acequias consist of water rights holders, often called parciantes, who are responsible for the upkeep and maintenance of the acequias and who internally elect a board to monitor and administer surface water rights.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H44C2F6D588CF4A68A1B726702E2B1DE9"><enum>(6)</enum><text>In the State, acequias have created a cultural landscape and way of life centered around local agriculture, water governance, and a custom of sharing scarce water. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd66e6481df5a41a9a7c42139da23defc"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Acequias—</text><subparagraph id="idA39E84F5EDA8476BA1E9314425FF8C3D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>play an integral role in maintaining forest and watershed health;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id498F23F8CFE14F4390D87316FA0B3887"><enum>(B)</enum><text>serve as examples of responsible land and water stewardship by providing benefits such as groundwater recharge, flood attenuation, and groundwater contaminants filtration; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7112784572DA48DFB24B4C13045EBD84"><enum>(C)</enum><text>support native vegetation and provide habitat for wildlife species.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ida7e5f7a7f9a245e9b00c22aabb6058ef"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Despite their contribution to local food production and watershed stewardship, acequias are managing already limited water resources under conditions of aridification, changing irrigation and growing seasons, and encroachment of invasive species. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id85CFF6DD4CC6448E938C04F87A872CCB"><enum>(9)</enum><text>To address crop loss, planting challenges, and yield reductions, parciantes rely on direct financial assistance from Department of Agriculture programs, including the noninsured crop disaster assistance program established by section 196 of the Federal Agriculture Improvement and Reform Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/7333">7 U.S.C. 7333</external-xref>). </text></paragraph></section><section id="id558B070381344F43A279A1162583ED4D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Ensuring farmers and ranchers have access to drought and disaster protections</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 196(c)(2) of the Federal Agriculture Improvement and Reform Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/7333">7 U.S.C. 7333(c)(2)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id455C5A12BB594D6992D2D044707EC560"><subparagraph commented="no" id="id7c08e3add19b420cacf8706dc5f2e52b"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Acequia systems</header><text>On making a determination described in subsection (a)(3) for producers who rely on acequia systems, the Secretary shall provide assistance under this section to those producers from all losses suffered as a result of the cause described in subsection (a)(3).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H6A9D48B671D7483EA829321FDB2C5814"><enum>4.</enum><header>Special use permits not required for routine maintenance and minor improvements of acequias</header><subsection id="HA18E036E01834255B3F9DFB305A88682"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph id="H1850560D5FDD449EB109000854ABA143"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Acequia</header><text>The term <term>acequia</term> has the meaning of the term <term>community ditch</term> as that term is construed under New Mexico Stat. 73–2–27. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id020136359e314952885aa7b6a7c7686c"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Community user</header><text>The term <term>community user</term> means an employee, contractor, delegate, representative, volunteer, or other authorized personnel of the governing body of an acequia. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2BF52C94AEBB443997383F7D782BE171"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary concerned</header><text>The term <term>Secretary concerned</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="id2DBC607261914FFF9EF3846CE7D1FBCD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary of Agriculture, with respect to land under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of Agriculture; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id302852A8721A45DEA05A0FB45252A8EA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary of the Interior, with respect to land under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Interior.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H663CCA034CF346D7A4953689290FD6E1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A special use permit shall not be required for—</text><paragraph id="idA3AA6657CF784AAD9F4962ADD8FD9300"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the presence or use of an acequia on Federal land or the use of the water therein; or </text></paragraph><paragraph id="idF7CFB6EDD7624BED858E8682FDF522D2"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">routine maintenance and minor improvements described in subsection (c) conducted by a community user or governing body of an acequia on an acequia on Federal land.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5494DF2EE302479A9B3B70B2555D1415"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Routine maintenance and minor improvements described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Routine maintenance and minor improvements referred to in subsection (b)(2) are—</text><paragraph commented="no" id="H9EBA8EFE85774B26AA5778D8E7944DC7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">cleaning, maintenance, repair, or replacement-in-kind of infrastructure;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H656D4E9940E34A2ABB3744E69E90513A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">annual ditch cleaning, including removal of silt; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H94E0ACAB14DC48BBA1F736DABF4B2D5A"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other traditional activity that preserves the state of the acequia, as agreed to in writing by the Secretary concerned and the governing body of the acequia. </text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id676799b997dc4e889dba91f1dd704bf5"><enum>5.</enum><header>Department of Agriculture reporting</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Agriculture shall submit to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate and the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives a report that includes the following information:</text><paragraph id="idd286f23f22a74102a92a059c12eca6dd"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The number of agricultural producers in the most recent calendar year who rely on acequia systems or other traditional infrastructure that is vulnerable to drought conditions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id23aa47d5767b46e88583b77cb58ffdf5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The amount of assistance provided under the noninsured crop disaster assistance program established by section 196 of the Federal Agriculture Improvement and Reform Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/7333">7 U.S.C. 7333</external-xref>) to producers described in subsection (c)(2)(C) of that section, in each county, during the most recent calendar year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6f497621ec9e4b43bad88f4d1d94d5ad"><enum>(3)</enum><text>An analysis of the ability of agricultural producers who rely on acequia systems or other traditional infrastructure that is vulnerable to drought conditions to access all programs administered by the Farm Service Agency and the Natural Resources Conservation Service.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0a6b3174327d4c50bf23a5b312c8916e"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A summary of any Department of Agriculture programs or initiatives in the most recent calendar year that provide technical or financial assistance targeted to agricultural producers who rely on acequia systems or other traditional infrastructure that is vulnerable to drought conditions. </text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

