<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H88EBBB55F0F640828FFCD2D7B400D749" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 666 IH: Supporting the goals of Overdose Awareness Day and strengthening efforts to combat the opioid crisis in the United States.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 666</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250829">August 29, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000482">Mrs. Trahan</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="P000620">Ms. Pettersen</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Supporting the goals of Overdose Awareness Day and strengthening efforts to combat the opioid crisis in the United States.</official-title></form><preamble>
<whereas><text>Whereas provisional data from the Center for Disease Control and Prevention’s National Center for Health Statistics indicate there were an estimated 80,391 drug overdose deaths in the United States during 2024;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas over 90 percent of drug overdose opioid deaths involved illicitly manufactured fentanyl;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas substance use disorder and drug overdose affect all socioeconomic groups, racial and ethnic groups, geographical regions, and ages;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Black and American Indian or Alaskan Native populations are more likely to die from a drug overdose than their White counterparts;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas substance use disorder is a chronic disease, and recognizing it as such decreases stigma and acknowledges that substance use is a health issue;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas overdose deaths are preventable, and countless lives can be saved through increased awareness, effective prevention strategies, timely intervention, comprehensive treatment, and robust recovery support; and</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas Congress and the executive branch must continue to work together to pass and implement policy solutions that accelerate and strengthen the United States ability to treat and prevent substance use disorders: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H235D8C43AC324AEAB1E33D1D88D5EE83"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HA2E452C9761F4D36960CE539DAA00634"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text>
<paragraph id="HE84D33F7FF70437FAC14BFEC10C423CE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognizes Overdose Awareness Day in the United States;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H64BF33694DDA498B9BC38F35114362ED"><enum>(2)</enum><text>commits to advancing and passing bipartisan policies that reduce the stigma surrounding substance use disorders and overdoses; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD9809C82E90F46719C4B3DE5F029965D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>is dedicated to collaborating with States, localities, businesses, nongovernmental organizations, health care providers, patients, and families to support a comprehensive system that promotes prevention, treatment, harm reduction, and recovery from opioid use disorder.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

