<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ROS25D48-G88-20-CJR">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2725 IS: STOP Act 2.0</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>II</distribution-code>
        <congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session>1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. 2725</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action>
            <action-date date="20250904">September 4, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S372">Mrs. Capito</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was
                read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on
                    Finance</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title>To increase the criminal penalty for mail fraud involving misrepresentation
            of the country of origin, to terminate the authority to exclude countries from the
            requirement to transmit advance electronic information for 100 percent of mail shipments
            under the STOP Act of 2018, and for other purposes.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause">
        <section section-type="section-one" id="S1">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>STOP Act 2.0</short-title></quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section commented="no" id="idfac9d526b87f4a46a50710fdb49504aa">
            <enum>2.</enum>
            <header>Criminal penalty for mail fraud involving misrepresentation of country of
                origin</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1341 of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text>
            <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc761b231f068421294e16d3b7f665884">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>Whoever</quote> and inserting the following:</text>
                <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id46B42C7AB4974754921E1783F95226A2">
                    <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb72b8b2c93d74a40a8b7429fa2f36811">
                        <enum>(a)</enum>
                        <header>In general</header>
 <text>Whoever</text> </subsection> <after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block> </quoted-block> </paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="id062a638c0eec49f0800648efaa292cc8"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
                <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idE3358B4C0C944EF7BEE8633694D3F2DF">
                    <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc432977d17dc41e4aa0a4e7119b3a769">
                        <enum>(b)</enum>
                        <header>Misrepresentation of country of origin of international mail
                            shipments</header>
                        <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida2c3a4d1cc49417893c1dfe1e1751815">
                            <enum>(1)</enum>
                            <header>In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person that, in violating subsection (a) or conspiring under section 371 or 1349 to violate subsection (a), knowingly misrepresents the country of origin of an international mail shipment in information required to be submitted under section 343(a) of the Trade Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1415">19 U.S.C. 1415(a)</external-xref>), shall in addition to any other penalty for the offense, be fined under this title, imprisoned not more than 5 years, or both.</text>
                        </paragraph>
                        <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id694b13a856de4c0cae12c71c88f2ea9c">
                            <enum>(2)</enum>
                            <header>Seizure and forfeiture</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The authority of the Department of Homeland Security under subsection (c)(14) of section 592 of the Tariff Act of 1930 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1592">19 U.S.C. 1592</external-xref>) with respect to seizure and forfeiture shall apply with respect to international mail shipments described in paragraph (1) to the same extent that such authority applies with respect to merchandise entered or attempted to be entered in violation of subsection (a) of such section 592.</text>
                        </paragraph>
                    </subsection>
                    <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
                </quoted-block>
            </paragraph>
        </section>
        <section id="idebe31b3be77444939de48322275b9473">
            <enum>3.</enum>
            <header>Termination of authority to exclude countries from requirement to transmit
                advance electronic information for 100 percent of mail shipments</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 343(a)(3)(K)(vi) of the Trade Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1415">19 U.S.C. 1415(a)(3)(K)(vi)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
            <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2D05CB7A419B42F59878FAE6C5E9EB10">
                <subclause id="id7146b228782a473d9c8fd4c30671bdcd" indent="up2">
                    <enum>(V)</enum>
 <text>The authority provided by subclause (II) to exclude a country from the requirement described in subclause (I) shall terminate on the date that is 5 years after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>STOP Act 2.0</short-title>.</text>
                </subclause>
                <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
            </quoted-block>
        </section>
        <section id="id582e4d7ebf884426be6c9538d2fe9d0b">
            <enum>4.</enum>
            <header>Annual report on compliance with advance electronic information
                requirements</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 8003 of the STOP Act of 2018 (subtitle A of title VIII of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/271">Public Law 115–271</external-xref>; 132 Stat. 4077) is amended by striking subsections (c) through (f) and inserting the following:</text>
            <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id64CAA71592F946478F27841A030F32CC">
                <subsection id="idaf4453e78dbb4402bad14e718ba09afd">
                    <enum>(c)</enum>
                    <header>Annual report on compliance</header>
                    <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0f8cb505e63245c7b34130f41a99b6b0">
                        <enum>(1)</enum>
                        <header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>STOP Act 2.0</short-title>, and annually thereafter, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on compliance with the requirements of section 343(a) of the Trade Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1415">19 U.S.C. 1415(a)</external-xref>) that includes the following:</text>
                        <subparagraph id="id44f19b8917bb47a7b9b8c8fe01552e77">
                            <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>An update regarding new and existing agreements reached with foreign postal operators for the transmission of the information required by paragraph (3)(K) of that section.</text>
                        </subparagraph>
                        <subparagraph id="id6be9c8977b844359ad1f18027674d173">
                            <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>A summary of deliberations between the United States Postal Service and foreign postal operators with respect to issues relating to the transmission of that information.</text>
                        </subparagraph>
                        <subparagraph id="id0998b78abf9049b18917a7dddcd00094">
                            <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>A summary of the progress made in achieving the transmission of that information for the percentage of shipments required by that paragraph, including the results of random checks and information disaggregated by postal and nonpostal data.</text>
                        </subparagraph>
                        <subparagraph id="id9b715a340f574863bc0d07fdbaffbe30">
                            <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>An assessment of the quality of that information being received by foreign postal operators, as determined by the Secretary, and actions taken to improve the quality of that information, including estimates of—</text>
                            <clause id="id7bb1671982774d4194f8c7d5e662f01c">
                                <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>the amount of information required by section 343(a) of the Trade Act of 2002 that is missing elements, incomplete, inaccurate, or apparently false;</text>
                            </clause>
                            <clause id="idf8d5ddf697724760b715efc998a7cf56">
                                <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>the number of shipments that U.S. Customs and Border Protection requested to be searched as a result of information required by that section;</text>
                            </clause>
                            <clause id="id7c2daef4bd6245d5836159feae1cf1af">
                                <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>how many shipments were actually searched pursuant to such a request; and</text>
                            </clause>
                            <clause id="id7fe8c2ef4e3f4c45b1ea6d823d0d5c04">
                                <enum>(iv)</enum>
 <text>the results of such searches, including the number of illicit narcotics and counterfeit goods identified during such searches.</text>
                            </clause>
                        </subparagraph>
                        <subparagraph id="ide542187c0c054503a49f4071d4321226">
                            <enum>(E)</enum>
 <text>A description of the results of randomized tests of packages entering the United States to assess the rate of compliance with the requirements of section 343(a) of the Trade Act of 2002—</text>
                            <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9571c6926a5045efaa45383b28b5037c">
                                <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">disaggregated by packages transported by the United States Postal Service and packages transported by private carriers; and</text>
                            </clause>
                            <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1141fd0bcddc441fa88918fc9b252b3d">
                                <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that takes into account, as relevant, the way that the factors set forth in paragraph (3) of that section may affect any differences identified between packages transported by the United States Postal Service and packages transported by private carriers.</text>
                            </clause>
                        </subparagraph>
                        <subparagraph id="idf5f1ab46ed4e4f4090b9c82f306e906b">
                            <enum>(F)</enum>
 <text>For each report submitted during the 5-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of the <short-title>STOP Act 2.0</short-title>—</text>
                            <clause id="idabe4124baa98482fa6cf03f303cf9c42">
                                <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>a list of the countries that, during the year preceding submission of the report, were excluded from the requirement under subclause (I) of section 343(a)(3)(K)(vi) of the Trade Act of 2002 that advance information be provided for 100 percent of international mail shipments pursuant to subclause (II) of that section; and</text>
                            </clause>
                            <clause id="id34cde7efa06041a59b7f7225c67d83cc">
                                <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>for any country on the list required by clause (i) that has been excluded from the requirement described in that clause for each of the preceding 3 years—</text>
                                <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id138d5d25acf14977a8c7e948356b540a">
                                    <enum>(I)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an identification of the reasons why the country remains on the list; and</text>
                                </subclause>
                                <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf57cb006bba44710b2b536481d5401f1">
                                    <enum>(II)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of steps that are being taken to ensure that the country is prepared for the termination of the authority to exclude countries from that requirement terminates under subclause (V) of that section (as added by section 3 of the <short-title>STOP Act 2.0</short-title>).</text>
                                </subclause>
                            </clause>
                        </subparagraph>
                        <subparagraph id="id1ca00e8a0c384e86a9303042f597fdf6">
                            <enum>(G)</enum>
 <text>A summary of policies established by the Universal Postal Union that may affect the ability of the Postmaster General to obtain the transmission of the information required by section 343(a) of the Trade Act of 2002.</text>
                        </subparagraph>
                        <subparagraph id="idb475ba5c84574d4c81a57457758db66e">
                            <enum>(H)</enum>
 <text>A summary of the use of technology to detect illicit synthetic opioids and other illegal substances in international mail parcels and planned acquisitions and advancements in such technology.</text>
                        </subparagraph>
                        <subparagraph id="id29328fabbb3a493bab39cd87d5c1abf5">
                            <enum>(I)</enum>
 <text>Such other information as the Secretary of Homeland Security and the Postmaster General consider appropriate with respect to obtaining the transmission of information required by section 343(a)(3)(K) of the Trade Act of 2002.</text>
                        </subparagraph>
                    </paragraph>
                    <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id69fb2244c10f433e83789510b31862c3">
                        <enum>(2)</enum>
                        <header>Form of report</header>
                        <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb449ff728ef643fd80f24649cc60a57b">
                            <enum>(A)</enum>
                            <header>In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each report required by paragraph (1) shall be submitted in unclassified form but may include a classified annex.</text>
                        </subparagraph>
                        <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd0d7b262186e4b3eacdc6799d8e95301">
                            <enum>(B)</enum>
                            <header>Public availability</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The unclassified portion of the report required by paragraph (1) may be made available on a publicly accessible internet website of the United States Postal Service.</text>
                        </subparagraph>
                    </paragraph>
                    <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3c3e9879c6804869b6ecb020f7ea2b1f">
                        <enum>(3)</enum>
                        <header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text>
                        <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf47e0acd391546ffadb45301b60035ae">
                            <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on the Judiciary and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate; and</text>
                        </subparagraph>
                        <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id33ffdd2dba9d40038fb4a9e92765f6c7">
                            <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>the Committee on the Judiciary and the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives.</text>
                        </subparagraph>
                    </paragraph>
                </subsection>
                <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
            </quoted-block>
        </section>
        <section id="idb86eb9dbbd164d0db8c67c92e9bc1321">
            <enum>5.</enum>
            <header>Public-Private partnerships</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security, the Attorney General, and the Postmaster General may enter into a public-private partnership with private parcel services or other private information technology entities to develop technology and processes for identifying information that could be used to identify the origin of fentanyl, other synthetic opioids, and other narcotics and psychoactive substances, and precursors to such substances, including information on the origin of parcels and shipping information.</text>
        </section>
        <section id="id52b2441073764e4a85ae0c496b18309b">
            <enum>6.</enum>
            <header>International collaboration and information sharing</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security, in consultation with Secretary of State, may, as appropriate, share with and receive from the governments of foreign countries that are allies of the United States, consistent with existing law (including contractual obligations), information with respect to—</text>
            <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf707ea2fdc1e4a419f32af2ac9bc2e80">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shippers with a history of transporting illicit fentanyl, other synthetic opioids, and other narcotics and psychoactive substances, and precursors to such substances; and</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7dd01cc724cf40a3bb8990d7a7f2b309">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">best practices regarding the detection of such substances, including such substances moving through the mail.</text>
            </paragraph>
        </section>
        <section id="ided66d75789904d42b35eba2b66cdc475">
            <enum>7.</enum>
            <header>Training of U.S. Customs and Border Protection officers with respect to
                detecting synthetic opioids</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection shall provide to officers of U.S. Customs and Border Protection training in detecting illicit fentanyl, other synthetic opioids, and other narcotics and psychoactive substances, and precursors to such substances, entering the United States, including training with respect to the use of detection equipment and trends in the transportation of such substances.</text>
        </section>
        <section id="id1B97D5433BEC43CCA1FAAA20BC1C06DE">
            <enum>8.</enum>
            <header>Evaluation of implementation of STOP Act of 2018</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report evaluating the implementation of the provisions of and amendments made by the STOP Act of 2018 (subtitle A of title VIII of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/271">Public Law 115–271</external-xref>; 132 Stat. 4073) that includes—</text>
            <paragraph id="id24eeff145c5149ea8d995a13bf486efd">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>identification of potential areas of risk with respect to the entry of illicit fentanyl, other synthetic opioids, and other narcotics and psychoactive substances into the United States by mail, including any gaps that drug traffickers have found in the system established under the STOP Act of 2018, that takes into account, as relevant, the factors set forth in section 343(a)(3) of the Trade Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1415">19 U.S.C. 1415(a)(3)</external-xref>);</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="id50b6a2897e8747b9b6d6e946039a01be">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id1ae412053f0945ff8d822ff87b2a43ec">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>a description—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idce8a3878019b43f8bcbf5ecf0ab0dc0e" indent="up1"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">of any significant differences in rates of compliance with that section between packages transported by the United States Postal Service and packages transported by private carriers; and</text>
                    </clause>
                    <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0EA0CF1404AE44DABC80D56AD6BBFAE9" indent="up1">
                        <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that takes into account, as relevant, the way that the factors set forth in paragraph (3) of that section may affect any such differences; and</text>
                    </clause>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="id2905a35b75964991b3f10c240212d6c5" indent="up1">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>an analysis of how, if at all, those differences may contribute to the risks identified in paragraph (1); and</text>
                </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph commented="no" id="id4E43964620B248DCBD5590E1B43FF7BC">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>an assessment of—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="id76FE266992654EEDA2DE7EAFD0404351"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>the use of the authority provided under subclause (II) of section 343(a)(3)(K)(vi) of the Trade Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1415">19 U.S.C. 1415(a)(3)(K)(vi)</external-xref>) to exclude countries from the requirement under subclause (I) of that section that advance information be provided for 100 percent of international mail shipments; and</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph commented="no" id="idD4EB493AAD8A48C7A54281D22E48CBC3">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>whether the use of that authority should be decreased during the period before that authority terminates under subclause (V) of that section (as added by section 3).</text>
                </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
        </section>
        <section id="idaf9d32267d66494e899178bd6a0d399c">
            <enum>9.</enum>
            <header>Severability</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any provision of or amendment made by this Act, or the application of such provision or amendment to any person or circumstance, is held to be unconstitutional, the remainder of the provisions of and amendments made by this Act, and the application of such provisions and amendments to any person or circumstance, shall not be affected.</text>
        </section>
    </legis-body>
</bill>

