<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-BOM25048-4M8-01-FHY"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S163 IS: Protecting Students on Campus Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 163</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250121">January 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S373">Mr. Cassidy</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S418">Mr. Fetterman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require institutions of higher education participating in Federal student aid programs to share information about title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964, including a link to the webpage of the Office for Civil Rights where an individual can submit a complaint regarding discrimination in violation of such title, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting Students on Campus Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3d831be3fbe042fa93d8afb3614ff212"><enum>2.</enum><header>Title VI awareness campaign</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id75281387aa964e2a9319f4752945df33"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Title VI awareness campaign</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd227dbfdc0a448ef9ececcf294e82cfb"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Education, acting through the Assistant Secretary for Civil Rights of the Department of Education, shall carry out a public awareness campaign regarding the availability of rights provided to individuals under title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d">42 U.S.C. 2000d et seq.</external-xref>). </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id656bc91cf7b3464faafeecc3c0ad80c2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Awareness campaign</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The public awareness campaign shall include appealing visual and auditory elements and shall be updated annually and distributed to institutions of higher education for physical posting in 1 or more high traffic public places, such as student centers, and digital posting on 1 or more high traffic institution web pages, such as student services. The campaign shall utilize such methods and materials as necessary to maximize student accessibility.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb9017a290db54e8399132483946959d8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Ability to contract</header><text>The Secretary may carry out this subsection directly or through a contract with a nonprofit organization that specializes in public awareness communications.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd005da63f6c24fe09470e5464fe1e912"><enum>(b)</enum><header>HEA Amendments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 487(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1094">20 U.S.C. 1094(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idE92A582CB85B4362B64EA75239166909"><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3048136c2c0c41daa4451e78119bd027"><enum>(30)</enum><text>The institution—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id30864ff60acb4310ab4d02b0ccc482a2"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has prominently displayed on the homepage of the institution a link to the webpage of the Office for Civil Rights of the Department of Education where an individual can submit a complaint regarding discrimination on the basis of race, color, or national origin in violation of title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d">42 U.S.C. 2000d et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idef858cef66f54c3aa50297797e195e5b"><enum>(B)</enum><text>will annually display and post the public awareness campaign materials created and distributed under section 2(a) of the <short-title>Protecting Students on Campus Act of 2025</short-title> in high traffic public places on campus, such as student centers, and high traffic institution web pages, such as student services.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="idcafac886fa294c469e7c725206944228"><enum>3.</enum><header>Congressional briefings</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4b62a8269de74121bd1f7633785b4941"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act and ending 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Assistant Secretary for Civil Rights of the Department of Education shall give a monthly briefing to Congress—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaa291cf184c44553a08ea22f7bee5506"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">explaining the number of complaints that the Office for Civil Rights of the Department of Education (referred to in this Act as the <quote>Office</quote>) has received in the previous month regarding discrimination on the basis of race, color, or national origin in violation of title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d">42 U.S.C. 2000d et seq.</external-xref>), disaggregated by the basis of discrimination; </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide1a90749942045f29bef102b8402f4d3"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">describing how the Office plans to address those complaints and the investigations opened in response to those complaints; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id32bcc4c1e5914618951b71e0b9fd4812"><enum>(3)</enum><text>providing data about the length of time that those complaints remain open after being received by the Office. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaa01d83a7cf54b29ba7797e62d950c6d"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 48 hours prior to each briefing described in subsection (a), the Assistant Secretary for Civil Rights of the Department of Education shall provide a written report to Congress that contains the information that will be presented at the next briefing, in a manner that protects personally identifiable information in accordance with applicable privacy laws.</text></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id290a1d39136e4281bf585bde0a5f2414"><enum>4.</enum><header>Audit and study</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id29ef4cfc37da46d9a32d1ee18cf23d8d"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement To submit data</header><text>Each institution of higher education receiving Federal funds shall submit an annual report to the Inspector General of the Department of Education that includes—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0499bb417b9c4b1192b45b1c13e1f821"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of complaints regarding discrimination on the basis of race, color, or national origin in violation of title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d">42 U.S.C. 2000d et seq.</external-xref>) that were submitted to the institution in the previous year; </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb71b45d69d6741da9bdc63f46f51b20b"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an analysis of the number of such complaints and their substance; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4768b8baa30240c78733621337d9565b"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a narrative of the action the institution took with respect to such complaints.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5cbb48e9845f4e40b96d71733b02823f"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Audit</header><text>The Inspector General of the Department of Education shall complete an annual audit of the institutions of higher education that are in the top 5 percent of institutions based on the per capita number of complaints described in subsection (a) received by the institutions, controlling for student population, to examine the process for addressing such complaints and the need for any referrals to the Office for Civil Rights of the Department of Education. </text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2204600c63574d0996f2f434454c6d47"><enum>(c)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Inspector General of the Department of Education shall conduct a study—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd9113d79af834656b66d09d911757f8b"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">regarding why there is a disparity between the complaints regarding discrimination on the basis of race, color, or national origin in violation of title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d">42 U.S.C. 2000d et seq.</external-xref>) that are submitted to institutions of higher education and such complaints that are submitted to the Office; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id11490c7b5e384f6a8f5e29be6492c9f8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>quantifying the distinction described in paragraph (1). </text></paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaa66cad8606b49ae83e0191cd4303532"><enum>5.</enum><header>OCR process reforms</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Office for Civil Rights of the Department of Education shall not close or dismiss any complaint due to resolution by another Federal, State, or local civil rights enforcement agency or through a recipient’s internal grievance procedures. </text></section></legis-body></bill> 

