<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDC82DD5B124047539C7702A546D5D46A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5755 IH: No Budget, No Pay Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5755</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251014">October 14, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="H001058">Mr. Huizenga</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide that Members of Congress may not receive pay after October 1 of any fiscal year in which Congress has not approved a concurrent resolution on the budget and passed the regular appropriations bills.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H7D61E66A8BC347588876657BC6B02065" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H85484D4B555340539393F58A5A522FDA" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No Budget, No Pay Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HB35CE095FEDD48CF88A4F86B78861E56"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>Member of Congress</term>—</text> 
<paragraph id="HE18D0DE80DA44F7C949EF265E95C37CC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>has the meaning given under section 2106 of title 5, United States Code; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H764579D0E69745AB84FC0514FB7F4890"><enum>(2)</enum><text>does not include the Vice President.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HC8554190747144F3AA79DFAB62205F4B"><enum>3.</enum><header>Timely approval of concurrent resolution on the budget and the appropriations bills</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If both Houses of Congress have not approved a concurrent resolution on the budget as described under section 301 of the Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/632">2 U.S.C. 632</external-xref>) for a fiscal year before October 1 of that fiscal year and have not passed all the regular appropriations bills for the next fiscal year before October 1 of that fiscal year, the pay of each Member of Congress may not be paid for each day following that October 1 until the date on which both Houses of Congress approve a concurrent resolution on the budget for that fiscal year and all the regular appropriations bills.</text></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H388E6C44A58F4B65B9EEBB7F43AD91A0"><enum>4.</enum><header>No pay without concurrent resolution on the budget and the appropriations bills</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7611E275885C492EBB0D1C52949DCD1A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no funds may be appropriated or otherwise be made available from the United States Treasury for the pay of any Member of Congress during any period determined by the Chairpersons of the Committee on the Budget and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate or the Chairpersons of the Committee on the Budget and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives under section 5.</text></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF5B5A6326C3C48649A65C40C7392936D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>No retroactive pay</header><text>A Member of Congress may not receive pay for any period determined by the Chairpersons of the Committee on the Budget and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate or the Chairpersons of the Committee on the Budget and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives under section 5, at any time after the end of that period.</text></subsection></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE2EA02B237F945EF9913A68923A0FF68"><enum>5.</enum><header>Determinations</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H30C339C352A140D6AEEA66E9DEA4CBDE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Senate</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5FE1B84B7DE54515B561AAC4DD2E0F82"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Request for certifications</header><text>On October 1 of each year, the Secretary of the Senate shall submit a request to the Chairpersons of the Committee on the Budget and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate for certification of determinations made under paragraphs (2) (A) and (B).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H23EA5A37A5704E67BE16A26320BFA295"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Determinations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Chairpersons of the Committee on the Budget and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate shall—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9C2BD599C6D34D56BC397001D5824F88"><enum>(A)</enum><text>on October 1 of each year, make a determination of whether Congress is in compliance with section 3 and whether Senators may not be paid under that section;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC9FAC31CF282432FA0AAD7CD0A82BB7A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>determine the period of days following each October 1 that Senators may not be paid under section 3; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H12F97EA64082469DBAEC9FCD3C12C0A8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>provide timely certification of the determinations under subparagraphs (A) and (B) upon the request of the Secretary of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H330EC230CF744CE4A3EC662F964AA4FC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>House of Representatives</header> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H04BD13E9854D45489F6F49EBEAF3D63A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Request for certifications</header><text>On October 1 of each year, the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives shall submit a request to the Chairpersons of the Committee on the Budget and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives for certification of determinations made under paragraphs (2) (A) and (B).</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE1FB253DDC3842E793B6726748372EDD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Determinations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Chairpersons of the Committee on the Budget and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives shall—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6965582B106F4F5CA0659E911A87F384"><enum>(A)</enum><text>on October 1 of each year, make a determination of whether Congress is in compliance with section 3 and whether Members of the House of Representatives may not be paid under that section;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3051C0A58E244B178D3481D8026BCE10"><enum>(B)</enum><text>determine the period of days following each October 1 that Members of the House of Representatives may not be paid under section 3; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB57257BEB9E94EF790116DD9326F126E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>provide timely certification of the determinations under subparagraphs (A) and (B) upon the request of the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H456135B43FC54C41AB4D6986CB2AA5DD"><enum>6.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This section shall take effect on February 1, 2027.</text></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

