<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB41D48E4A4714E34B62F4ECF6D303734" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4582 IH: To amend the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 and title 5, United States Code, to clarify that organ donation surgery qualifies as a serious health condition.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4582</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250722">July 22, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">House Administration</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 and title 5, United States Code, to clarify that organ donation surgery qualifies as a serious health condition.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE52D7B9AD985470C9611F05C76D8C581" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H8198515F8C5249DC9199998EACD13C33" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Clarification of organ donation surgery as qualifying as a serious health condition under FMLA</header> 
<subsection id="HFB90F19BF0F24E8093751461742DE552"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Private sector employees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 101(11) of the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/2611">29 U.S.C. 2611(11)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>(including recovery from surgery related to organ donation)</quote> after <quote>physical or mental condition</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H3961DA56C9724A549DB61E885FE3772E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Federal civil service employees</header> <paragraph id="H6901C26E6C9843689DF9DED6E97858CA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 6381(5) of title 5, United States Code, is amended by inserting <quote>(including recovery from surgery related to organ donation)</quote> after <quote>physical or mental condition</quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEB581E7F15D24F3E9EBAA27151DE4656" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Relationship to organ donor leave</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 6382(d)(1) of title 5, United States Code is amended by adding at the end the following: <quote>An employee who takes any part of the 12-week period of leave under subsection (a)(1) to serve as an organ donor (including recovery from surgery related to organ donation) shall substitute, for as much of that part as possible, any leave available to the employee under section 6327.</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

