<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H32EC31551C76448B9EDBD42720D11759" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3757 IH: Pride In Mental Health Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3757</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250605">June 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000629">Ms. Davids of Kansas</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S001225">Mr. Sorensen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000486">Mr. Torres of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001318">Ms. Balint</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000310">Ms. Johnson of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001119">Ms. Craig</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000598">Mr. Garcia of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001226">Ms. Salinas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001238">Ms. McBride</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001227">Ms. McClellan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title V of the Public Health Service Act to ensure protections for lesbian, gay, bisexual, and transgender youth and their families.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HCAE4C32E3E9F4266B638006C6AD10258" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HF06080699A7747FE8C3A01B4E905C177" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Pride In Mental Health Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H94CFA07A1438416A80783AB661F2F531"><enum>2.</enum><header>Grants for mental health services for LGBTQ+ youth</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subpart 3 of part B of title V of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/290bb-31">42 U.S.C. 290bb–31 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HF16A12B1EEC54FA798AF5C3BA39602F8" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="H16F568A0485A4406870F5D1A44FC2A5E"><enum>520O.</enum><header>Grants for mental health services for LGBTQ+ youth</header> 
<subsection id="H81AAC6C6B8EA443CA19CD56E827311C0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, acting through the Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use (referred to in this section as the <quote>Secretary</quote>), shall establish a program under which the Secretary will award grants to eligible entities to assess and improve lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, queer or questioning, nonbinary, intersex, and Two Spirit youth mental health and substance abuse outcomes.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H14EC9725EF324CF19359E6C5BE34A94A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>An eligible entity receiving a grant under this section shall use funds received through such grant—</text> 
<paragraph id="HD70858767495485085848108D78F648A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to provide mental and behavioral health and crisis intervention resources for lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, queer or questioning, nonbinary, intersex, and Two Spirit youth, including trauma-informed care;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA9AD5926507844CDA60B6B92E3B8714F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to provide cultural competency training for caregivers;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H54F4CD11F82F482FBF488DD0EBFC1AE7"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to develop and disseminate mental and behavioral health and crisis intervention resources for lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, queer or questioning, nonbinary, intersex, and Two Spirit youth, and their families and caregivers;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8821995DFC99410487DA75B2C44D3528"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to develop and disseminate evidence-based practices to be added to the Evidence-Based Practices Resource Center of the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Administration;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4EB00468A87245E0B823B4E828719654"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to collect data with respect to the mental and behavioral health of lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, queer or questioning, nonbinary, intersex, and Two Spirit youth;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC81F995911E24C5FB56802D329F08B4B"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to issue school bullying prevention guidelines with respect to lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, queer or questioning, nonbinary, intersex, and Two Spirit youth;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H844E96669CE648B1B8E3AC0F4EC3428E"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to provide for the integration within school systems of mental and behavioral health services for lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, queer or questioning, nonbinary, intersex, and Two Spirit youth;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA712C299E3E24FE9BB77BDB3C878B9C7"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to establish and implement mental and behavioral patient navigator programs for lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, queer or questioning, nonbinary, intersex, and Two Spirit youth, and their families; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0CCB7A544C3C42AE9FFE42ED1875AEBC"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to create and disseminate family acceptance and support models for lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, queer or questioning, nonbinary, intersex, and Two Spirit youth, and their families and caregivers.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HB984D083583D486583D1D48B0BBA3A88"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Limitation</header> <paragraph id="H1769CCBCFE7F47C384E894FC7844B088"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An eligible entity selected to receive a grant under this section shall agree, as a condition on receiving the grant, that such funds shall not be used—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HDE65BCBAA0F246F0BF02E4A0A26B7138"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to provide conversion therapy to any individual;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H23A1299D9018438795092134E970948C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to advertise for the provision of conversion therapy and claim in such advertising—</text> 
<clause id="H667CCF62DC364F548DE482C5D3ACA846"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to change another individual’s sexual orientation or gender identity;</text></clause> <clause id="H5542AC144B364356B5FFB5336C4CF554"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to eliminate or reduce sexual or romantic attractions or feelings toward individuals of the same gender; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="HC10373CD173E4E98B2EEC1ECBDF3661E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>that such efforts are harmless or without risk to individuals receiving such therapy;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HABEC7F88AF934418B6A4C9E2ABE80BD9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to knowingly assist or facilitate the provision of conversion therapy to an individual if such person receives compensation from any source in connection with providing conversion therapy; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5FA76ADAE43145ADA8AE3668465CEBAD"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to promote or direct an individual to conversion therapy resources or providers.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB3DB98B4DF374718B7C01CC9C6CF60B0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conversion therapy defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, the term <term>conversion therapy</term>—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HBB70715F610C47F8B1046068CDF3C405"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means any practice or treatment by any person that seeks to change another individual’s sexual orientation or gender identity, including efforts to change behaviors or gender expressions, or to eliminate or reduce sexual or romantic attractions or feelings toward individuals of the same gender, if such person—</text> <clause id="H2C518EC03730438BA962FFDCC8CDB493"><enum>(i)</enum><text>receives monetary compensation in exchange for such practice or treatment; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="HDD19BB4679CE464C8BAFB20B8C501FB3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>instead of, or in addition to, receiving monetary compensation in exchange for such practice or treatment directly, receives monetary compensation in exchange for a product or service that is integral to the provision of such practice or treatment by such person, unless such product or service is protected by the First Amendment to the Constitution; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA8CD662DAFD544BF94AEA4B88BB70FD5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include any practice or treatment, which does not seek to change sexual orientation or gender identity, that—</text> 
<clause id="H6FA5AE0D016040CD912255B55A4EE252"><enum>(i)</enum><text>provides assistance to an individual undergoing a gender transition; or</text></clause> <clause id="HA300E27DAAB04F55815A8E334040C58E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provides acceptance, support, and understanding of a client or facilitation of a client’s coping, social support, and identity exploration and development, including sexual orientation-neutral interventions to prevent or address unlawful conduct or unsafe sexual practices.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HED1B798C36A34433A46F3BB0D2BABF37"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Review of reports</header> 
<paragraph id="H379BABCA808C4D619F8C87EF78B26F06"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary shall restore, review, and update as necessary, the reports and publications that were listed on the internet website of the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Administration on January 19, 2025, and that were focused on lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, queer or questioning, non-binary, intersex, and Two Spirit individuals.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H31DCF7EF43574180AA3C230AA1C04F1C" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>No promotion of conversion therapy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In updating the reports and publications under paragraph (1), the Secretary may not include reports or publications that promote the provision of conversion therapy, as defined in subsection (c)(2).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8BFDA20506FB4AB4B10056D1B9041617"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Priority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In reviewing reports and publications under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall prioritize updating older reports and commissioning new reports that fill information gaps with respect to the mental and behavioral health of lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, queer or questioning, nonbinary, intersex, and Two Spirit individuals.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H93686C80B2544A17A8D0CF8698E46B17"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Federal survey</header> <paragraph id="HA0EE186E59FB445DAE34A0E0667C7C65"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall develop and conduct a Federal survey measuring serious psychological distress, mental illness, mental health, and mental health care among lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, queer or questioning, nonbinary, intersex, and Two Spirit youth. In developing such survey, the Secretary may consider integrating such survey as an enhanced feature of the National Survey on Drug Use and Health.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2146744FB4854E85BA322ADEEA307D40"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Privacy a<editorial/>nd confidentiality</header> 
<subparagraph id="H2D2F81A44FD94C9FBEA192E6D86A5E4D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Confidentiality of Information</header><text>All data or information collected in identifiable form pursuant to this subsection shall be treated as confidential and shall be used only by officers, employees, or agents of the Department of Health and Human Services, and exclusively for statistical purposes.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1E3B53809B344D139221AAC5F40B62DC"><enum>(B)</enum><header>No Other Use Permitted</header><text>Data or information acquired by the Secretary pursuant to this subsection shall not be disclosed by an agency or its officers, employees, or agents in identifiable form, or for any use other than an exclusively statistical purpose. In no case shall information furnished under this subsection be used to the detriment of any respondent or other person to whom such information relates. A disclosure pursuant to this subsection is authorized only when the Secretary or the Secretary’s designee approves such disclosure, and the disclosure is not prohibited by any other law.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H02AE677CD26F47DEBEB69BF211A09D69"><enum>(C)</enum><header>No Other Rights Diminished</header><text>This subsection does not restrict or diminish any confidentiality protections or remedies in law that otherwise apply to information acquired by the Secretary under this subsection.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDBCCE88C8A8D4F40B5BE2B54ADFCFC18"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Cause of Action</header><text>Whoever, being an officer, employee, or agent of an agency acquiring information for exclusively statistical purposes, having taken and subscribed the oath of office, or having sworn to observe the limitations imposed by this subsection, comes into possession of such information by reason of being an officer, employee, or agent and knowing that the disclosure of the specific information is prohibited under the provisions of this subsection, willfully discloses the information in any manner to a person or agency not authorized under this subsection to receive it, may be subject to a civil action against the individual in a court of competent jurisdiction for declaratory or injunctive relief, compensatory damages for any harms reasonably related to the disclosure, statutory damages up to $500 per violation, punitive damages, and attorney’s fees. Such action may be brought against such individual by any party whose identifiable data or information is disclosed or used in violation of this subsection. A claim of sovereign immunity is not a defense to an action brought under this subparagraph.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD335776D971741D9970F7BFBD6F431A1"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Notification of Rights</header><text>The Secretary shall require that respondents to the Federal survey described in paragraph (1) are notified, prior to participation, of their right to confidentiality and the availability of remedy in the occasion of a violation of this subsection.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA687142F44DB49E29560CCAD506A8A47"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Statistical purpose defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this paragraph, the term <quote>statistical purpose</quote> has the same meaning and application given the term in section 3561 of title 44, United States Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H28838420D54C41DE9AE65A365B30E388"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Report</header> 
<paragraph id="HA88472AFA55640E7BFAB843BCB98C3E1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary shall, in consultation with the Director of the National Institute of Mental Health and the Assistant Secretary for the Administration for Children and Families, commence a report on mental health, mental health care, and cultural competency in mental health care for lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, queer or questioning, nonbinary, intersex, and Two Spirit youth in foster care and who are beneficiaries of other social services programs subject to Federal oversight.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6B416F20C0BC483F82BD27C557A05615"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Submission to Congress</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary shall submit the report required under paragraph (1) to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HEDCF139542464E41969379A1B51A0830" commented="no"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriation</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $20,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> </legis-body></bill>

