<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCF1D0897259C492DB35B0CC71C940386" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2728 IH: Growing Regional Entrepreneurship and Access To Economic Resilience Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2728</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250408">April 8, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000595">Ms. Letlow</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="D000530">Mr. Deluzio</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HSM00">Small Business</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Small Business Administration, the Appalachian Regional Commission, and the Delta Regional Authority to enter into an agreement to carry out activities to expand rural entrepreneurship, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H4014D21A592A46A89285DC1EE9C52C96" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H04DAAE6EAD444F6988705EC5A106C761" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Growing Regional Entrepreneurship and Access To Economic Resilience Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>GREATER Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section> <section id="H911AE08B895E427FBAD30F876CAD0992" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Memorandum of understanding to expand rural entrepreneurship and support to small business concerns within Appalachian region and the Delta region</header> <subsection id="HC31589FC2B15484AB516D0E97C4320D1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Small Business Administration, the appropriate head of the Appalachian Regional Commission, and the appropriate head of the Delta Regional Authority (in this section referred to as the <quote>covered officials</quote>) shall enter into a memorandum of understanding or other appropriate agreement to carry out activities within the Appalachian region and the Delta region, as applicable, to expand rural entrepreneurship and to support covered small business concerns.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2CD2E293E6674A8B95425E6D0E45E206"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Memorandum of understanding or agreement</header><text>The covered officials shall carry out and coordinate the activities described in subsection (a) by entering into one or more memoranda of understanding or other appropriate agreements, as jointly determined by the covered officials.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HA2F2ECCC62DD438AAEECBF0A210476F3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Inclusion of covered small business concerns</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the activities described in subsection (a), the covered officials shall ensure the inclusion of covered small business concerns in such activities, as appropriate.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6186BB6A0D464060ACA26402D872AAEE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Other Requirements</header><text>In carrying out the activities described in subsection (a), the covered officials may—</text> <paragraph id="HD0D0227DB7164C67B41AB796B423A82D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>carry out reimbursable agreements between the Appalachian Regional Commission, Delta Regional Authority, the Small Business Administration, and other appropriate entities in order to maximize the effectiveness of activities carried out pursuant to a memorandum or agreement described in subsection (b); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBE982BFEDC354729A99E561133947546"><enum>(2)</enum><text>collaborate with other Federal agencies as appropriate to carry out such activities.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H0A4738ED1309422C9D97543015FA2676"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than two years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the covered officials shall jointly submit to Congress a report on activities carried out pursuant to a memorandum or agreement described in subsection (b) that includes the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H7548B1EC92164B278E8A81320E757B9C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Coordination between the covered officials involved in such activities.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF524B4780B8D4215985E175F3609E4FB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Potential opportunities to expand the ability of the Appalachian Regional Commission, Delta Regional Authority, and the Small Business Administration to provide assistance to rural entrepreneurs or covered small business concerns, as applicable. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8C3CCEF5750445DC82836C79BB787B30"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number of rural entrepreneurs or covered small business concerns assisted through activities carried out pursuant to such memorandum or agreement.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H87D8885D4FAD4D26ABDA3AC4B5C2764F"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Areas of future collaboration among the covered officials for the benefit of rural entrepreneurs or covered small business concerns located within the Appalachian region or Delta region, as applicable.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H22EB6BE068C349DCAD60B31E10978DF9"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Plans of the covered officials to continue coordination on activities described in subsection (a). </text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H640A8843DC7D486798F03C69F1A92815"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="HDFBBCAC3CF544F63ACCEF02329FCBC26"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered small business concern</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered small business concern</term> means a small business concern (as defined under section 3 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/632">15 U.S.C. 632</external-xref>)) located within the Appalachian region or Delta region.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFA8CFCC3754E4BD396A3E5091CE5EE05"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appalachian Regional Commission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Appalachian Regional Commission</term> means the commission established by section 14301(a) of title 40, United States Code.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6941B59202D44721875D67079C3A9CEF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Delta region</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Delta region</term> has the meaning given the term <term>region</term> in section 382A of the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2009aa">7 U.S.C. 2009aa</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0274D658362E41BB8E120BDD62978BCF"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Delta Regional Authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Delta Regional Authority</term> means the entity established under subtitle F of the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2009aa">7 U.S.C. 2009aa et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

