<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H22FF461BBE1648B7A053967D10D9341A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3395 IH: Middle Market IPO Cost Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3395</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250514">May 14, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001047">Mr. Himes</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Comptroller General of the United States to carry out a study of the costs associated with small- and medium-sized companies to undertake initial public offerings.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HAC416BA70F4349728A88D03308533670" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HA654BF92771141CDB2CB9DAAFA9D2505" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Middle Market IPO Cost Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H5C02258D359546E2B096EDA322E0E144"><enum>2.</enum><header>Study on IPO fees</header> <subsection id="HF7A5FDED0597448D9950BBDF7411DD6C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Comptroller General of the United States, in consultation with the Securities and Exchange Commission and the Financial Industry Regulatory Authority, shall carry out a study of the costs associated with small- and medium-sized companies to undertake initial public offerings (<quote>IPOs</quote>). In carrying out such study, the Comptroller General shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H2CCABE7BFA48418F8BEA6C94F25993C0"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consider the direct and indirect costs of an IPO, including—</text> <subparagraph id="H755DA866C47A46D18F74CD7CDCD12E81" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">fees of accountants, underwriters, and any other outside advisors with respect to the IPO;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1D2013C88D984BD68D99AD5C9856C1A4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>compliance with Federal and State securities laws at the time of the IPO; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEB3DFCEEAFA042309CE5FBE208C891C5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>such other IPO-related costs as the Comptroller General may consider;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE6EAA60F80614176AFDBFA66BDA9D0F6"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">compare and analyze the costs of an IPO with the costs of obtaining alternative sources of financing and of liquidity;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6630F436B5274A8993F4D31ADCBA7E09"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consider the impact of such costs on capital formation;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7912D6D073B94B2FB9A8F3F176E2D967"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">analyze the impact of these costs on the availability of public securities of small- and medium-sized companies to retail investors; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H089C4E69CA9043DB87890A7FA82BB9F6"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">analyze trends in IPOs over a time period the Comptroller General determines is appropriate to analyze IPO pricing practices, considering—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H79A1A9422E9A47C493D3B12151B4C23B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of IPOs;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA1C4546D775243D9863F2DF002F32E3D"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how costs for IPOs have evolved over time for underwriters, investment advisory firms, and other professions for services in connection with an IPO;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBEC9618F1EDC4B8F876270FC34E97C4B"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of brokers and dealers active in underwriting IPOs;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H81E7472321D54A9CA1D33D4B32D255D4"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the different types of services that underwriters and related persons provide before and after a small- or medium-sized company IPO and the factors impacting IPOs costs;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H32040CF6823A456CA1A03CED1A14A73C"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">changes in the costs and availability of investment research for small- and medium-sized companies; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8C21144D66944BCE87668FEC6FE4CF5D"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the impacts of litigation and its costs on being a public company.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9066034377024B0AAE8BF8D86405926F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than the end of the 360-day period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General shall issue a report to the Congress containing all findings and determinations made in carrying out the study required under subsection (a) and any administrative or legislative recommendations the Comptroller General may have.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

