<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9B2F5EDCD6264EAE9302E34C34DC465D" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 767 IH: Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that violent attacks against United States Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) facilities and officers are unacceptable, must be fully condemned, and that Congress stands in support of ICE’s mission to protect national security, public safety, and the enforcement of immigration laws.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 767</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250926">September 26, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000478">Mr. Fry</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000048">Mr. Pfluger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000816">Mr. Williams of Texas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S000250">Mr. Sessions</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that violent attacks against United States Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) facilities and officers are unacceptable, must be fully condemned, and that Congress stands in support of ICE’s mission to protect national security, public safety, and the enforcement of immigration laws.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, since President Trump took office, there has been a rise in hostile rhetoric and violence directed against ICE facilities and officers;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on September 24, 2025, a shooter opened fire from a rooftop at an ICE field office in Dallas, Texas, striking detainees in transit, killing one and critically injuring two before taking his own life;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas investigators during the September 24, 2025, shooting found the words <quote>ANTI-ICE</quote> written on shell casings discovered at the scene and a note saying <quote>give ICE agents real terror</quote>, according to the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI);</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on September 19, 2025, violent rioters stormed the ICE processing center in Broadview, Illinois, assaulting officers, vandalizing vehicles, hurling tear gas canisters, blocking entrances, and trespassing on restricted property;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on September 1, 2025, radical demonstrators in Portland, Oregon, staged violent riots outside an ICE facility, brandishing a guillotine and threatening Federal officers;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on August 25, 2025, an individual entered the reporting entrance of a Dallas, Texas ICE field office and claimed to be carrying a bomb in his backpack;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on August 2, 2025, a rock was thrown and broke a window at an ICE facility in Yakima, Washington;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on July 8, 2025, a gunman opened fire at the entrance of a Border Patrol station in McAllen, Texas, wounding 3 officers;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on July 4, 2025, armed assailants wearing tactical gear carried out an attack on the ICE detention center in Alvarado, Texas, during which a local law enforcement officer was shot;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on June 7, 2025, more than 1,000 rioters besieged a Federal law enforcement facility in Los Angeles, California, assaulting ICE officers, slashing vehicle tires, and defacing Federal property;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas these acts reflect an escalation of attacks against ICE and Federal immigration enforcement operations, including a 1,000 percent increase in assaults on ICE officers;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas ICE officers and supporting staff carry out vital functions in the protection of national security, public safety, and the enforcement of United States immigration laws;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas ICE’s work frequently involves high-risk operations that protect communities from criminal organizations and disrupt transnational criminal networks;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas ICE is working to locate and protect unaccompanied alien children, with more than 465,000 having entered the border during the Biden Administration;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, under President Trump, ICE has located at least 22,638 unaccompanied alien children, with more than 400 sponsors arrested, and 27 minors tragically found dead as a result of murder, suicide, or drug overdose;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, since the Trump Administration took office, roughly 70 percent of ICE arrests have been of individuals unlawfully present in the United States who were convicted of or charged with criminal offenses;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas violent, ideologically motivated attacks on ICE not only endanger life, but undermine public trust in the rule of law and impair the capacity of ICE to carry out lawful missions; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Members of Congress and public officials have a duty to condemn all such violence, ensure accountability for perpetrators, and enact measures to protect ICE agents, personnel, and facilities: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HAF65B12E8AA94AE9907005288F800236"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H8FC9877301AA482D86098A0FC0E597DC"><enum/><text>That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="H4DB636322C554CD28C438D120CE4B143"><enum>(1)</enum><text>unequivocally condemns the recent escalation of violent attacks and threats against ICE facilities, personnel, and detainees under ICE custody and expresses profound sorrow for the lives lost and the injuries sustained;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H816F7E7C969F41A088C0DAC3E61A04E2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>reaffirms its full support for ICE agents, officers, and staff performing their law enforcement duties under the Department of Homeland Security, and acknowledges the difficult, dangerous, and essential tasks they carry out daily in service of public safety;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB3CEBDC93F0D4F908BC32EB5A804F7DF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>calls on the Department of Homeland Security, ICE, the Department of Justice, the Department of State, and Federal, State, and local law enforcement partners to investigate attacks, strengthen coordination to prevent violence, improve training and equipment, and counter digital threats such as tracking technologies and doxxing platforms used against personnel, facilities, and detainees; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4002EEF223FD4E4FB5F6595C35C4D1A5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>encourages all public officials and media entities to reject rhetoric that incites hostility toward ICE or law enforcement personnel, and instead to speak responsibly about those charged with enforcing the laws of the United States.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

