<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-LIP25157-TSH-F1-JR9"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S734 IS: Edward J. Dwight, Jr. Congressional Gold Medal Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 734</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250225">February 25, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S330">Mr. Bennet</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S287">Mr. Cornyn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S408">Mr. Hickenlooper</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S363">Mr. King</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To award a Congressional Gold Medal to Edward J. Dwight, Jr., the first African American astronaut candidate in the United States.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Edward J. Dwight, Jr. Congressional Gold Medal Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idbe4b7c88a64b41eb846958aea5808708"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="id866e9081aad441ba8472bbf6986613db"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Edward Joseph Dwight, Jr., was born on September 9, 1933, to Georgia Baker Dwight and Edward Dwight, Sr., in Kansas City, Kansas. Ed Senior had been a second baseman and center fielder for the Kansas City Monarchs and played on other all-Black teams from 1924 to 1937. Georgia was a devoted mother who enrolled her son in a Head Start type program at the age of 2 and made sure to expose her children to as much culture as she could.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0be4c0535fde4e35a75676b85078f414"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Edward Joseph Dwight, Jr., grew up with a passion for art and airplanes.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id578b4ffec1974047b6856c0cb70446aa"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Edward became the first African American male to graduate from Bishop Ward Catholic High School in 1951. He then earned an associate degree in engineering in 1953 from Kansas City Junior College. That same year he left to join the Air Force and began flight training.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1929446d162e4d4d94bc20be06706796"><enum>(4)</enum><text>After completing flight training, he served as a military pilot and obtained a degree in aeronautical engineering from Arizona State University. During his career as an officer in the Air Force, Edward served at bases in Texas, Missouri, and Arizona, developing technical manuals and training fellow pilots on various instruments, as he accumulated flight hours.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id926c20d47d6f48d49f7e4a0db4f329ea"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Edward recalled, <quote>I was the only Black officer pilot just about every base I was stationed</quote> and that even at 5’4”, he <quote>got award after award</quote>. While in the Air Force, Edward earned his Bachelor of Science in aeronautical engineering from Arizona State University in 1957.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2ce6e6524c314d1196aea204576fcb03"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Edward flew some of the most advanced aircraft of the era and ultimately accumulated over 9,000 hours of flight time, 2,000 in high-performance jets. His engineering background and extensive training opened the door for him to enter the test pilot school where the most successful trainees become astronauts.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id011309b1d9d643d7b132a9fdd6d901ec"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Edward was chosen by President John F. Kennedy to enter training as an experimental test pilot. The Kennedy administration knew that a Black astronaut would be an inspiring display of opportunity for African Americans across the country.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id04c04ae17b8b4b019b95f26946a5a5f3"><enum>(8)</enum><text>On November 4, 1961, Edward received a letter inviting him to join the astronaut training program. He followed the advice of his mother and accepted the invitation to take the first steps toward improving diversity and talent in the United States space program by becoming the first African American astronaut candidate in the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id51096aa5cca34c03a2799cbc1baea561"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Edward went to the Aerospace Research Pilot School at Edwards Air Force Base in California to begin training.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd12641e4ca3542d2887df6d96f0da103"><enum>(10)</enum><text>This was a time of uncertainty where the color of a person’s skin mattered more than his or her skill.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9c37248793d445309d13c782b3adee50"><enum>(11)</enum><text>The astronaut candidacy of Edwards became cover news on Black magazines such as Jet, Ebony, and Sepia.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb76121f5141d4421be553186bee07617"><enum>(12)</enum><text>At Edwards Air Force Base, however, Edward experienced prejudice and scorn, as he recounted in his autobiography <quote>Soaring on the Wings of a Dream: The Untold Story of America's First Black Astronaut Candidate</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddc523d84747b48f082ac9f9a87d45e60"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Edward completed the experimental test pilot course and entered aerospace research pilot training in preparation for astronaut duties. He successfully completed the course and continued to perform duties as a fully qualified aerospace research pilot.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id467ca086fae94491943e947705ff8745"><enum>(14)</enum><text>On October 18, 1963, the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (referred to in this section as <quote>NASA</quote>) announced 14 astronauts for Group 3, but Edward did not make the list.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id56e8bc3824ce4777936fd710061cad5e"><enum>(15)</enum><text>While in training, Edward faced obstacles due to his race, which derailed his chance to be the first African American in space. His fight for equality was one of many trailblazing battles happening during the Civil Rights Era.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id520e69084e114fefbcc562e19606a096"><enum>(16)</enum><text>The assassination of President Kennedy, the main sponsor in the White House of Edward and the space journey, led to his voluntary separation from the Air Force.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd4ddb107788e4c2a8924cd7a360f695c"><enum>(17)</enum><text>In 1966, Edward resigned from the Air Force as a captain and moved to Denver, Colorado.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide3c8a31a9a1c45a8a7ebddd7defed120"><enum>(18)</enum><text>After the Kennedy assassination, pressure on NASA to fly a Black astronaut waned, and the first African American would not fly in space until Guion Bluford flew with the crew of NASA’s eighth space flight on the Space Shuttle orbiter Challenger in 1983.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2c1fbdb74ace41eea8f338ec1065a5ce"><enum>(19)</enum><text>After successful careers in the Air Force, and as an IBM systems engineer, restauranteur, aviation consultant, real estate, and construction entrepreneur, Edward dedicated 43 years solely to his artistic endeavors.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id735eb9b0279a4e8f9a7c4fa8ef73e3a0"><enum>(20)</enum><text>In 1974, George Brown, the first African American lieutenant governor of Colorado and a member of the Tuskegee Airmen in World War II, chose Edward to create a bronze bust of him to display in the Colorado State Capitol.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7965d552001143249d38c472ece22f95"><enum>(21)</enum><text>Being a neophyte to bronze sculpting, and at the age of 42, Edward enrolled at the University of Denver in the Masters of Fine Arts program. While at the University of Denver, he became proficient in metal casting and managed the foundry at the school while also teaching other students. He received his Master of Fine Arts in 1977.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id81242d04fc1d459282e77e6ee586df73"><enum>(22)</enum><text>In 1975, while at the University of Denver, Edward received a commission from the Colorado Centennial Commission to create a series of bronzes depicting the contribution of Blacks to the American Frontier West. The series exhibited for several years throughout the United States, gaining widespread acceptance and critical acclaim.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf357eb8588204109979d4eee6bdca0f9"><enum>(23)</enum><text>In 1979, the National Park Service encouraged Edward to create a bronze series portraying the history and historical roots of jazz. The series was created and entitled <quote>Jazz: An American Art Form</quote>, which consisted of over 70 bronzes depicting the evolution of jazz from its African origins to the fusion of contemporary music.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide20582915a334337aec7b9bc51802443"><enum>(24)</enum><text>Since his art career began in 1976, Edward has become one of most prolific and insightful sculptors in the United States. As of the date of enactment of this Act, Edward has completed more than 115 large-scale commissioned sculpture installations. His pieces are collected by museums, institutions and art enthusiasts around the world, including the Smithsonian. Ed Dwight Studios, Inc., in Denver, is now one of the largest privately owned production facilities in the western United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbc961375f4b8487f9abcd2f59b8960a5"><enum>(25)</enum><text>Edward is the recipient of numerable living legends awards from around the country for his achievements in space activities and contributions in art and Black history.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id952756c340994120a8585cd5f2572cc0"><enum>(26)</enum><text>On August 5, 2020, in recognition of his accomplishments as a scientist, test pilot, and sculptor, the Space Force inducted him as an honorary member. A permanent display is installed at the Pentagon in honor of these achievements.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2b08a86a7db44f1a82c086ce190dee9a"><enum>(27)</enum><text>In a ceremony at the Pentagon, General Jay Raymond, Chief of Space Operations of the Space Force, presented Edward with the Commander’s Public Service Award and inducted him as an honorary member of the Space Force, for his contributions to the United States, space, and history during times of overt racism in the field of science. Astronaut Victor Glover honored Edward by carrying this award with him to the International Space Station during his Crew-1 mission. Despite all that he had to overcome, Edward was an example of excellence, embarking on a nationwide speaking tour encouraging young people to study science, engineering, and math. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id12b5bea9dd1c4edb9a7beab574b3f0c1"><enum>(28)</enum><text>In 2021, the Minor Planet Center, an organization affiliated with the International Astronomical Union, named an asteroid after Edward. NASA has honored him by sending his sculpture <quote>Pioneer Woman</quote> to space on Exploration Flight Test-1 in 2014.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf291230883ce4dceba86587db467a3cf"><enum>(29)</enum><text>On November 3, 2022, Denver International Airport opened an exhibit titled <quote>Soaring on the Wings of a Dream,</quote> the title of Edward's book. The exhibit is on the life of Edward, beginning with childhood and ending with adulthood. It will be on display for 5 months.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0663c72ae5854d82bcae6df40788814c"><enum>(30)</enum><text>The National Geographic documentary, <quote>The Space Race</quote>, weaves together the stories of Black astronauts seeking to break the bonds of social injustice to reach for the stars, including Edward, Guion Bluford, Charles Bolden, Mae C. Jemison, Victor Glover, among many others, including Leland Melvin, one of the producers of the film.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id759abbec5f1142658cb8a97314aba46c"><enum>(31)</enum><text>On May 19, 2024, Edward, sponsored by Space for Humanity, finally traveled to space as 1 of 6 individuals aboard the Blue Origin New Shepard rocket, which launched from a private site near Van Horn, Texas. At 90 years old, Edward became the oldest person to go to space. </text></paragraph></section><section id="id302da1a86f83466292ef5171986b6d05"><enum>3.</enum><header>Congressional Gold Medal</header><subsection id="idb37153a50f5d413c823002116eb1129d"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Presentation authorized</header><text>The Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President pro tempore of the Senate shall make appropriate arrangements for the presentation, on behalf of Congress, of a single gold medal of appropriate design to Edward J. Dwight, the first African-American astronaut candidate in the United States, in recognition of—</text><paragraph id="id64ef963d87c942e7b1ab010e7c28a38f"><enum>(1)</enum><text>his historic service to the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0729dff350374d1cbfae6ab2a9880692"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the example of excellence during times of struggle and overt racism; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idcc41265a75294dda8415753b06573b12"><enum>(3)</enum><text>his contributions in art and Black history.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id7252eed349e846b0b6c54f6edbbfaa31"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Design and striking</header><text>For purposes of the presentation described in subsection (a), the Secretary of the Treasury (referred to in this Act as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall strike a gold medal with suitable emblems, devices, and inscriptions, to be determined by the Secretary. The design shall bear an image of, and an inscription of the name of, Edward J. Dwight, Jr. </text></subsection><subsection id="idda25918ce0f24e64a71966abf9ae4bf2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Disposition of medal</header><text>Following the presentation described in subsection (a), the gold medal shall be given to Edward J. Dwight, Jr., or, if unavailable, to Curtis Christopher Dwight. </text></subsection></section><section id="id8606d8457f334256b23e6002e842999d"><enum>4.</enum><header>Duplicate medals</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary may strike and sell duplicates in bronze of the gold medal struck under section 3, at a price sufficient to cover the costs thereof, including labor, materials, dies, use of machinery, and overhead expenses.</text></section><section id="id78fbab169e0c42c488a0c3f8ee665249"><enum>5.</enum><header>Status of medals</header><subsection id="id6567ce944c94458a9ec0e768bde2e0d2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>National medals</header><text>Medals struck under this Act are national medals for purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/51">chapter 51</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code.</text></subsection><subsection id="id9ffaebd7eacf4f5f8d5f5bb19df83ac5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Numismatic items</header><text>For purposes of sections 5134 and 5136 of title 31, United States Code, all medals struck under this Act shall be considered to be numismatic items.</text></subsection></section><section id="id5be7ab8466714bf2bd7ff684f0f711a4"><enum>6.</enum><header>Authority to use fund amounts; proceeds of sale</header><subsection id="idd1809b5577ee4626aaffc2bffcd37ff7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority To use fund amounts</header><text>There is authorized to be charged against the United States Mint Public Enterprise Fund such amounts as may be necessary to pay for the costs of the medals struck under this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="idf91f584ecac44876ab4378fc0c1b95d0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Proceeds of sale</header><text>Amounts received from the sale of duplicate bronze medals authorized under section 4 shall be deposited into the United States Mint Public Enterprise Fund. </text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

