<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H88345C1DB8E24B3097C310021B5B2EF1" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4888 IH: Reproductive Rights are Human Rights Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4888</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250805">August 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000310">Ms. Johnson of Texas</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="J000305">Ms. Jacobs</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000399">Mr. Doggett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000148">Mr. Auchincloss</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000486">Mr. Torres of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001315">Ms. Budzinski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000301">Ms. Elfreth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000474">Mrs. Torres of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000305">Ms. Ross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001127">Mrs. Cherfilus-McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000830">Mr. Whitesides</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001119">Ms. Craig</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000197">Ms. DeGette</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001218">Ms. Stansbury</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000468">Mrs. Fletcher</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001130">Ms. Crockett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000188">Mr. Norcross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001231">Ms. Simon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001200">Mr. Soto</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001318">Ms. Balint</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000788">Ms. Williams of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000629">Ms. Davids of Kansas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001232">Mrs. McClain Delaney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000380">Mr. Amo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001238">Ms. McBride</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000586">Mr. García of Illinois</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to require a section on reproductive rights in the Annual Country Reports on Human Rights Practices, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF3F46D29D4E94BC3935B42E461F51330" style="OLC"><section id="HF8D4C66919F04EAFA31C141F775D55BC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Reproductive Rights are Human Rights Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HBCFC77B8531E4C09A968AC117C150884"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H22BEC64C88E043C6AB080253EF6DC4A8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The United States has joined the international community in identifying reproductive rights as human rights, including in connection with the 1994 International Conference on Population and Development, the 1995 Beijing World Conference on Women, and through its ratification of the International Covenant on Civil and Political Rights, done at New York December 19, 1966 (referred to in this Act as <quote>ICCPR</quote>), the International Convention on the Elimination of All Forms of Racial Discrimination, done at New York December 21, 1965, and the Convention against Torture and Other Cruel, Inhuman or Degrading Treatment or Punishment, done at New York December 10, 1984.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H487010897FD34ED385AD38B648B172C3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>General comment No. 36 (2018) on article 6 of the ICCPR, which was adopted by the Human Rights Committee on October 30, 2018, asserts that States parties—</text><subparagraph id="H153418921DC34F1ABC37714026E1DB69"><enum>(A)</enum><text>should ensure access for all persons to quality and evidence-based information and education about sexual and reproductive health and to a wide range of affordable contraceptive methods;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAC9C2E89B2D94963BF5B23AC551CD9E5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>must provide safe, legal, and effective access to abortion where the life and health of the pregnant woman or girl is at risk, or where carrying a pregnancy to term would cause the pregnant woman or girl substantial pain or suffering, most notably where pregnancy is the result of rape or incest or is not viable;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H16AD22BDF4604F3CBDF2489E56E1F057"><enum>(C)</enum><text>ensure the availability of, and effective access to, quality prenatal and post-abortion health care for women and girls; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC91F1DE7E3FF4136836C36FE0DE1CCA0"><enum>(D)</enum><text>must not impose restrictions on the ability of women or girls to seek abortion in a manner that jeopardizes their lives, subjects them to physical or mental pain or suffering, discriminates against them, arbitrarily interferes with their privacy, or places them at risk of undertaking unsafe abortions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6F05E74AFDC040B4A81705F09AA4C1F8" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The World Health Organization (WHO) Abortion Care Guidelines (2022) asserts comprehensive abortion care includes the provision of information, abortion management (including induced abortion), and care related to pregnancy loss/spontaneous abortion and post-abortion care, and requires supportive law and policy including—</text><subparagraph id="HBE210E3910364D719BA895DC5707E9B8" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>full decriminalization of abortion;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8085EF77B05D4F7FB82AFC95B7CF4305" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>repeal of laws and regulations that restrict abortion by reasons, prohibit abortion based on gestational limits, and require mandatory waiting periods;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF81AA5C9E1C24253B103EFFFCF9A148B" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>availability of abortion on the request of the woman, girl or other pregnant person and without the need for authorization from any other person, body, or institution;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8F84087863EB4E4D9C9410E8FC0A7634" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>ending regulations that limit who can provide and manage abortion care that are inconsistent with WHO guidance; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H340C0516FC8844EBA1013DDE501E99FC" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>protection of abortion access from barriers created by conscientious refusal.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2EBD145BE04C449D941DD24A7F969517"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Reproductive coercion, which is any behavior that interferes with autonomous decision making about reproductive health outcomes, is a violation of human rights.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF897CFDB36C2415B92116A99DA2C5C24"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, queer, and intersex persons (LGBTQI+) face stigma and discrimination in accessing reproductive health services, and barriers, including anti-LGBTQI+ laws, policies, and gender norms in countries. The denial of access to sexual and reproductive health care and associated human rights violations due to these barriers should be reported in relevant Department of State Annual Country Reports on Human Rights Practices.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H054DF09ECA0C4C0FBF85671D4F257684" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">People with disabilities have historically been subjected to forced sterilization and coercive abortion practices, eugenics, institutionalization or guardianship practices that stripped them of their right to autonomy, and barriers to comprehensive reproductive care, including denial of fertility care, access to comprehensive sex education, contraception, and abortion care, and often face disrespect during pregnancy and birth. The denial of access to sexual and reproductive health care and associated human rights violations due to these barriers should be reported in relevant Department of State Annual Country Reports on Human Rights Practices.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1073F49057EF45BB95C4D139D10C081E"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Human rights are grounded in international standards. The Department of State’s deletion of the reproductive rights subsection from its 2017, 2018, 2019, and 2024 Country Reports on Human Rights Practices inappropriately politicized human rights of people around the world.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3D681D75A46943A7BCD303207E0048D6" commented="no"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The dismantling of the United States Agency for International Development (USAID) will severely undermine global reproductive health outcomes by disrupting funding for contraception, maternal healthcare, and safe childbirth services. USAID’s programs are critical in reducing maternal and infant mortality, preventing unintended pregnancies, and ensuring access to care for marginalized communities worldwide.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H87C3C128C2E54BFEB200E155E990566D"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Limiting reproductive rights also limits pathways to economic, social, and political empowerment. Sexual and reproductive health and rights are essential for sustainable economic development, are intrinsically linked to gender equality and women’s well-being, and are critical to community health.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H486325569BE94D289A8593C69497388C"><enum>3.</enum><header>Annual country reports on human rights practices</header><subsection id="HE3152ED159A545D496A16FA87B11DC1F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2151">22 U.S.C. 2151 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HCCC2568EA4444433AB821D54878D4BC2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 116(d) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2151n">22 U.S.C. 2151n(d)</external-xref>), by amending paragraph (2) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H89F6BC73496D4D7DA6432E696F164452"><paragraph id="HC3E72A1B18CF408B9FBF3058E344D12C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the status of reproductive rights in each country, including—</text><subparagraph id="H91496C5F7ADA47959845CDB09E9AB64B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>whether such country has adopted and enforced policies—</text><clause id="H2D9D4315F1D8485FA4A5E55E57CE7F92"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to promote access to safe, effective, and affordable methods of contraception and comprehensive, accurate, nondiscriminatory family planning and sexual health information;</text></clause><clause id="H02EB1BE2FE1C45B59F0B6CB019AC7CF8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to promote access to a full range of quality health care services to ensure safe and healthy pregnancy and childbirth free from violence and discrimination;</text></clause><clause id="H59C0AF4813D94208908CF694E073EA01"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to promote the equitable prevention, detection, and treatment of sexually transmitted infections, including HIV and HPV, and of reproductive tract infections and reproductive cancers; and</text></clause><clause id="HDA0A62FC436547CE8A0D193ED9FD73D6"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>to expand or restrict access to safe abortion services or post-abortion care, or to criminalize pregnancy-related outcomes, including spontaneous miscarriages or pregnancies outside of marriage;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7AB73E9BCA724B85ACD6B6A738EE27C3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of the rates and causes of pregnancy-related injuries and deaths, including deaths due to unsafe abortions;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1DB13A75935A4DC087E4D43A09A4B467"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a description of—</text><clause id="H6F6D668875FE4C0B98EC540D3F86416D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the nature and extent of instances of discrimination, coercion, and violence against women, girls, and LGBTQI+ individuals in all settings where health care is provided, including in detention;</text></clause><clause id="H1E028A1915E44AB29B15B5FA235839AE" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the nature and extent of instances of discrimination, coercion, and violence against people with disabilities in all settings where reproductive health care is provided, including in institutions and detention settings;</text></clause><clause id="HAF4C0C11B55D411F9B9DEAC1C785ED03"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>instances of obstetric violence, involuntary or coerced abortion, involuntary or coerced pregnancy, coerced sterilization, use of incentives or disincentives to lower or raise fertility, withholding of information on reproductive health options, and other forms of reproductive and sexual coercion; and </text></clause><clause id="H9C27D9C78C6C4D8AA68F86D670B620F0"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the actions, if any, taken by the government of such country to respond to such discrimination, coercion, and violence, if applicable;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H589A453AF5DC43A1B597D48D4DF84D93"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a description of—</text><clause id="HF3C495A0DCB24EF4A1A1EC8FD9A947B0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the proportion of individuals of reproductive age (15 through 49 years of age) whose need for family planning is satisfied with modern methods;</text></clause><clause id="HE040E9A5DCF048719455B21E0DFEA225"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the barriers such individuals face in accessing such services;</text></clause><clause id="H0CBC574386DC47E48982C4C93F8609B8"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the nature and extent of instances of denial of comprehensive and accurate family planning information and services in such country; and </text></clause><clause id="HA6FD6979D64741B3A0B1FF647522C9FD"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the actions, if any, taken by the government of such country to address such denials; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAFE72904CC204859B767DAAB09195ED7"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a description of—</text><clause id="HAC6DAD98FD0D453CB7A7524E3D53DD30"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">disparities in access to family planning and reproductive health services and pregnancy-related health outcomes, including pregnancy-related injuries and deaths, based on race, ethnicity, indigenous status, language, religious affiliation, age, marital status, disability, sexual orientation and gender identity, or other marginalized identity; and </text></clause><clause id="HCDD847FEF1524C5DAF3CC9AC899B3ECC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any measures taken by the government of such country to hold health systems accountable for addressing such disparities;</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H83B0F240C0FD463FB97423B852911448"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 502B (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2304">22 U.S.C. 2304</external-xref>)—</text><subparagraph id="H8868E651238840D692AB02F942209B09"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating the second subsection (i) (relating to child marriage status) as subsection (j); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE06C7EC324D7419FA2D00D7D6B52750F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H57C9CDD4F3C740B69E45ED0DE4372699"><subsection id="H5FDB87DBABAE427EA8846C7D2ADADE6B"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Inclusion of status of reproductive rights in Annual Country Reports on Human Rights Practices</header><text>The report required under subsection (b) shall include a description of the status of reproductive rights in each country, including—</text><paragraph id="HDD0032A061F946478C431A3BB2B855C9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>whether such country has adopted and enforced policies—</text><subparagraph id="H4DB0AE6B14C443B48A0F4853F2F6BC60"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to promote access to safe, effective, and affordable methods of contraception and comprehensive, accurate, non-discriminatory family planning and sexual health information;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H271A338B007B4F4CA82E42EEE72EC5E5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to promote access to a full range of quality health care services to ensure safe and healthy pregnancy and childbirth, free from violence and discrimination;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H68655943FD274746B8E7070C783C6939"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to promote the equitable prevention, detection, and treatment of sexually transmitted infections, including HIV and HPV, and of reproductive tract infections and reproductive cancers; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0AB668BD8DAD477F9D69920D86A97452"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to expand or restrict access to safe abortion services or post-abortion care, or criminalize pregnancy-related outcomes, including spontaneous miscarriages and pregnancies outside of marriage;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H26295B57E9614F02BED5CB4CB1468292"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of the rates and causes of pregnancy-related injuries and deaths, including deaths due to unsafe abortions;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8FD625EFF781471F943A81B201E0A607"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a description of—</text><subparagraph id="HD07EA5E35BB0440BA6ACA511FC0D04D3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the nature and extent of instances of discrimination, coercion, and violence against women, girls and LGBTQI+ individuals in all settings where health care is provided, including in detention;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9B8C9772996143A08550C1252B56FCDA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>instances of coerced abortion, coerced pregnancy, coerced sterilization, use of incentives or disincentives to lower or raise fertility, withholding of information on reproductive health options, and other forms of reproductive and sexual coercion; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC8B60E5F3BC345EBBD1C2D36E2E11024"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the actions, if any, taken by the government of such country to respond to such discrimination, coercion, and violence, if applicable;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8EFD60506A5148F3995C415B56846D01"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a description of—</text><subparagraph id="HD6F286EF525A4F4CA68F1209E7C69DBF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the proportion of individuals of reproductive age (15 through 49 years of age) whose need for family planning is satisfied with modern methods;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE8E1311CD66A4429957825F8B450A115"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the barriers such individuals face in accessing such services;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H23924BD57BE049F89EA065C2CE6A7374"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the nature and extent of instances of denial of comprehensive and accurate family planning information and services in such country; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H561B374F32EF49E4B48DA2903C2221B1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the actions, if any, taken by the government of such country to respond to such denials; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDE2D66DC156D47CD86E43F7FE939614B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>a description of—</text><subparagraph id="H428E2920949C42D68E9CF22B80EB21AF"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">disparities in access to family planning and reproductive health services and pregnancy-related health outcomes, including pregnancy-related injuries and deaths, based on race, ethnicity, indigenous status, language, religious affiliation, age, marital status, disability, sexual orientation and gender identity, or other marginalized identity; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBC1C35FF943840F0B1A4B6418795A07B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any measures taken by the government of such country to hold health systems accountable for addressing such disparities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDA0085233BA2446CBE3D7613ABFB6FBF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation required</header><text>In preparing the Annual Country Reports on Human Rights Practices required under sections 116(d) and 502B of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961, as amended by subsection (a), the Secretary of State, the Assistant Secretary of State for Democracy, Human Rights, and Labor, and other relevant officials, including human rights officers at United States diplomatic and consular posts, shall consult with—</text><paragraph id="HC95B0397F3084989BE7523EEF5A5FF03"><enum>(1)</enum><text>representatives of United States civil society and multilateral organizations with demonstrated experience and expertise in sexual and reproductive health and rights or promoting the human rights of women, girls, and LGBTQI+ persons;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDEF5487070D647A7BEA3EE37C832A0DB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>relevant local nongovernmental organizations in all countries included in such reports, including organizations serving women, girls, and LGBTQI+ persons that are focused on sexual and reproductive health and rights; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5A2ED1864E44432ABB8543CCF97D6057"><enum>(3)</enum><text>relevant agencies and offices of the United States Government that track or are otherwise involved in the monitoring of reproductive and sexual health around the world.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

