<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF20E975273D245ACB02BFB04F5F2E08D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3820 IH: To name the Department of Veterans Affairs women’s health clinic in Milwaukee, Wisconsin, as the Anna Mae Robertson VA Well Woman Clinic.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3820</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250606">June 6, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor
          name-id="S001213">Mr. Steil</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr.
          Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000471">Mr. Fitzgerald</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor
          name-id="W000829">Mr. Wied</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred
        to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans'
        Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To name the Department of Veterans Affairs women’s health clinic in Milwaukee, Wisconsin, as the Anna Mae Robertson VA Well Woman Clinic.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H476AA2A58F3946508B3A39A4FE1700C2" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HA82230DEA9FE40B8A68CC863ACB59376" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Name of Department of Veterans Affairs women’s health clinic, Milwaukee, Wisconsin</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The women’s health clinic (Red Team clinic) of the Clement J. Zablocki Veterans' Administration Medical Center in Milwaukee, Wisconsin, shall, after the date of the enactment of this Act, be known and designated as the <quote>Anna Mae Robertson VA Well Woman Clinic</quote>. Any reference to such women’s health clinic in any law, regulation, map, document, record, or other paper of the United States shall be considered to be a reference to the Anna Mae Robertson VA Well Woman Clinic.</text> </section> 
</legis-body></bill>

