<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC4DCD44D0FF04011ABFBF90334DA4783" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5483 IH: Chloe Cole Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5483</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250918">September 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="O000177">Mr. Onder</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001210">Mr. Murphy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001218">Mr. McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000459">Mr. Fleischmann</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001212">Mr. Moore of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001307">Mr. Baird</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000603">Mr. Gill of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000612">Mr. Rose</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001235">Mr. Moore of West Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000490">Mr. Taylor</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001148">Mr. Simpson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001325">Mrs. Biggs of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001120">Mr. Crenshaw</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001052">Mr. Harris of Maryland</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001101">Mr. Harrigan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000055">Mr. Aderholt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000175">Mr. Ogles</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001129">Mr. Collins</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit health care professionals, hospitals, or clinics from participating in the chemical or surgical mutilation of a child and to provide a private right of action for children and the parents of children whose healthy body parts have been damaged by medical professionals practicing chemical and surgical mutilation.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC7C048277D96463CB9DF7C659C934811" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HFC85C4D716F54ED0A3774DA218137A83" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Chloe Cole Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H9C61AECAEF4F4039B5A883EB1EA6D72A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
<paragraph id="HDE5FFDED486B4E058FB8E4950985C36C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Chemical or surgical mutilation</header>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H60CE428EC73347E4AC9BCDC07E47133C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>chemical or surgical mutilation</term> means engaging in any one or more of the following for the purpose of intentionally halting the natural development of the individual’s body so that it no longer corresponds to the individual’s sex or intentionally changing the individual’s body, including the individual’s external appearance or biological functions, to no longer correspond to the individual’s sex:</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC25D41BF886E47F69F513E909098E346"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The use of puberty blockers, including gonadotropin releasing hormone agonists and other interventions, to delay the onset or progression of normally timed puberty in an individual.</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2DB1CAA89C384CD08F72292EF07E7872"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The use of sex hormones, such as androgen blockers, estrogen, progesterone, or testosterone.</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE8304A1F32C84AA0BA731A5AFEB6AA30"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Surgical procedures that attempt to transform an individual's physical appearance or that attempt to alter or remove an individual's sexual organs.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA266A42E9DC546078D89F10E9ED135DE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such term does not include any of the following:</text> <clause id="HDD999646EA594E8780EDB6DE3FC21370"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Appropriate and medically necessary procedures to treat a verifiable disorder of sexual development, including an individual born with 46 XX chromosomes with virilization, with 46 XY chromosomes with undervirilization, or having both ovarian and testicular tissue.</text></clause>
<clause id="H03FF46EDDD234A49954396639E91E4FD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The treatment of any infection, injury, disease, or disorder that has been caused or exacerbated by the performance of an intervention described in subparagraph (A) without regard to whether the intervention was performed in accordance with State or Federal law or whether the intervention is covered by the private right of action under section 4.</text></clause> <clause id="H1DAF611B33E545099E00396E54AD83B7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Any intervention undertaken because the individual suffers from any diagnosed and verifiable condition of the body’s organ systems, including the following:</text>
<subclause id="HF791360BAC774B44B50C172D367A148D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Traumatic bodily injuries (such as fractures, organ rupture, or penetrating trauma).</text></subclause> <subclause id="H0C3810EE2B424D39B307D21B9CDAA70B"><enum>(II)</enum><text>Congenital structural anomalies of major organs or systems, including the cardiovascular, respiratory, renal, hepatic, neurological, or musculoskeletal systems.</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H9814077C5A1A46C6BAFF09BAA8550A54"><enum>(III)</enum><text>Acute illnesses with a high probability of rapid mortality.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H387CA6E5D6DE42C6A97D6967BF12EA09"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Detransition treatment.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H24EF679655B349BDAED614C565965519"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Child</header><text>The term <term>child</term> means an individual under 18 years of age.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3E0A01D3FB934F6797D7674EF76D662A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Detransition treatment</header><text>The term <term>detransition treatment</term> means any treatment, including a mental health treatment, medical intervention, or surgery, that does either or both of the following:</text>
<subparagraph id="H6958B1C96FD6461084022D3B0E752BD5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Stops or reverses the effects of a prior chemical or surgical mutilation.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H683C7C7C3BCA4D998C87AEAC0DC4F98F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Helps an individual cope with the effects of a prior chemical or surgical mutilation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB32D7E85D2C8479181572AA0D829898B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Health care professional</header><text>The term <term>health care professional</term> means a person, including a physician, who is licensed, certified, or otherwise authorized by the laws of a State to administer health care in the ordinary course of the practice of his or her profession or performing such acts which require such licensure.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF40F1A3CC19345EDA7729FDEA987E31E"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Mental health professional</header><text>The term <term>mental health professional</term> means a person who is licensed to diagnose and treat mental health conditions in a State.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC09DFA484380479E980B33AFA1EE69FE"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Participate</header><text>The term <term>participate</term>, with respect to acts constituting chemical or surgical mutilation as defined in paragraph (1), means directly engaging in the planning, authorization, prescription, administration, or performance of any such act, including any of the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HD9BE43C606E44FECBE44F3113C06ABFF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Prescribing puberty blockers, sex hormones, or related medications with the intent to alter an individual’s physical appearance or reproductive function to align with an identity differing from his or her sex.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H6F6C86D6E15247F49837063B80AAD440"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Administering medications or treatments described in subparagraph (A) with such intent, whether by injection, oral delivery, or other means.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCCBD904E11ED4B3B97AD77DB3A474C38"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Performing surgical procedures that attempt to transform an individual’s physical appearance to confirm a patient’s physical appearance to be of the alternate sex, or that alter or remove sexual organs as part of chemical or surgical mutilation.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H740523F67C3A47CA88F9F37B5652DE76"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Authorizing or directing such chemical or surgical mutilation procedures as a supervising health care professional or institutional representative.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4E389E49FCB24656ADB7DCFD43955FFE"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Knowingly planning or coordinating the provision of treatments or procedures described above in subparagraph (A), (C), or (D) with the intent to facilitate chemical or surgical mutilation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H33BD41EEFAED40EFBB8ED7CB01E92035"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Sex</header><text>The term <term>sex</term> means a person's immutable biological classification, determined at the moment of conception, as either male or female, as follows:</text> <subparagraph id="HDDC094968B684D5EABD82C3453597ACF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The term <term>female</term> is a person who naturally has, had, will have, or would have but for a congenital anomaly or intentional or unintentional disruption, the reproductive system that produces, transports, and utilizes the large gamete (ova) for fertilization.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H58A58B276A3942CD90ECF8B173051142"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The term <term>male</term> is a person who naturally has, had, will have, or would have but for a congenital anomaly or intentional or unintentional disruption, the reproductive system that produces, transports, and utilizes the small gamete (sperm) for fertilization.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> <section id="HF6DCC03F528C4A0598F2EF4F42D94B49"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibition on chemical or surgical mutilation</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4585112BAEF24BF791A99DE3DABDAF87"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>No health care professional, hospital, or clinic shall, in a circumstance described in subsection (b), participate in the chemical or surgical mutilation of a child, and a health care professional, hospital, or clinic may commence participation in a treatment that qualifies as an exception specified in clauses (i) through (iv) of section 2(1)(B) only after determining that clear and convincing evidence supports a determination that the treatment so qualifies.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H31CC7171121442509E183F286990C1E9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Circumstances described</header><text>The circumstances described in this subsection are that—</text> <paragraph id="HE653FDB48CFF4E24BC71B79EC39C0EE0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the defendant or child traveled in interstate or foreign commerce, or traveled using a means, channel, facility, or instrumentality of interstate or foreign commerce, in furtherance of or in connection with the participation in the chemical or surgical mutilation;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H653635EA12934D88AAA0322D6D8F92B1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the defendant used a means, channel, facility, or instrumentality of interstate or foreign commerce in furtherance of or in connection with the participation in the chemical or surgical mutilation;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3CFDD7BA44104283A028719DAACEA599"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any payment of any kind was made, directly or indirectly, in furtherance of or in connection with the participation in the chemical or surgical mutilation using any means, channel, facility, or instrumentality of interstate or foreign commerce or in or affecting interstate or foreign commerce;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H42AF203D96444E57A30A2D201B6F5D7B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the defendant transmitted in interstate or foreign commerce any communication relating to or in furtherance of the participation in the chemical or surgical mutilation using any means, channel, facility, or instrumentality of interstate or foreign commerce or in or affecting interstate or foreign commerce by any means or in any manner, including by computer, mail, wire, or electromagnetic transmission;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H05B73855A89343B4A57A261788996518"><enum>(5)</enum><text>any instrument, item, substance, or other object that has traveled in interstate or foreign commerce was used to perform the chemical or surgical mutilation;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H15678EE5C3FC42E492ED2987D178B68A"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the chemical or surgical mutilation occurred within the District of Columbia, the special maritime and territorial jurisdiction of the United States, or any territory or possession of the United States; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0623AA7DB63C440D80E01DBB0D1D13CD"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the chemical or surgical mutilation otherwise occurred in or affected interstate or foreign commerce.</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="H92DF3E9F138A4EA29AD274A774F87F6A"><enum>4.</enum><header>Private right of action</header>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H68573B78C99D4A1190D1FEA1868D9FC2"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual subjected as a child to chemical or surgical mutilation prohibited by section 3, or the parents or legal guardians of such individual, may bring a civil action in an appropriate district court of the United States for damages against any health care professional, hospital, or clinic, who participates in the chemical or surgical mutilation of that child. Such a cause of action shall be available regardless of whether the alleged chemical or surgical mutilation occurred before, on, or after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB3BEB81CAD554E7DAEA8A89A228ACCBD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Damages</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Damages available pursuant to such an action may include—</text>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9C8F33D86FBD463596F69A79146BA767"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">compensatory damages, including all economic damages associated with undoing, correcting, or ameliorating the effects or results of any chemical or surgical mutilation procedures;</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H12ED53D694EB428DB8CC16A1F3835CB1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">non-economic damages for emotional distress and pain and suffering; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H39A8F47B290E45D69FF4DDA58DB46A07"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">punitive damages, if the claimant proves by clear and convincing evidence that the defendant against whom punitive damages are sought acted maliciously, intentionally, fraudulently, or recklessly.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2B1FDC78B29D4ABF86B0ED00F9EADEFE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Strict liability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any health care professional, hospital, or clinic whose participation in the chemical or surgical mutilation of a child after the date of enactment of this Act is proven by clear and convincing evidence shall be strictly liable for damages for any such act of mutilation. If a treatment qualifies under an exception specified in clauses (i) through (iv) of section 2(1)(B), and that is raised as an affirmative defense to a violation of this Act, the health care professional, hospital, or clinic shall bear the burden of proving by clear and convincing evidence that such exception applies.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="HEB593602922242D49CF5FD4940CFD014"><enum>5.</enum><header>Rules of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H1373D0B8F4C94C9799580F61E9EB321D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>No private right of action is established based on counseling, referrals to mental health professionals, or discussions of treatment options, including counseling, referrals, or options available upon reaching adulthood, or in circumstances not described in section 3(b), provided by health care professionals, or mental health professionals, provided that such actions do not constitute participation in chemical or surgical mutilation, as defined in section 2.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1DD7DA3E73A64BF288C66069E5301DB5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>No liability for a health care professional under these provisions may be waived.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H289319AB9465433F82246CE18B520AD9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Any ambiguities shall be resolved against any party found to have engaged in participation, as defined in section 2(6), in the chemical or surgical mutilation of a child.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H52891CEFC70B4222A2BA1DE48F19FD3A" commented="no">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>In any cases in which chemical or surgical mutilation of a child is shown to have occurred before the date of enactment of this Act, there is limited deference to prevailing standards of care to the extent that such standards contradict the intent of this Act and it is shown that the health care professional knew or should have known that such standards of care were in serious, scientific, and medical dispute at the time of the chemical or surgical mutilation.</text>
            </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9C2B545A922A47F1BCF40120923E909E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to prohibit a health care professional or mental health professional from providing information about all available treatment options, discussing risks and benefits, or expressing professional medical opinions, so long as such actions do not constitute participation in chemical or surgical mutilation.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HC2F3491E7101487482F1EF307C52E1AE"><enum>6.</enum><header>Statute of limitations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">An action under section 4 may be brought within 25 years from the date of the eighteenth birthday of an individual subjected to chemical or surgical mutilation as a child or within 4 years from the time the cost of a detransition treatment is incurred, whichever date is later.</text></section>
<section id="HD0C4E1AB84E34604BFF6C262C7279B12"><enum>7.</enum><header>Severability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any provision of this Act, or the application of such a provision to any person or circumstance, is held to be unconstitutional, the remainder of this Act, and the application of the provision held to be unconstitutional to any other person or circumstance, shall not be affected.</text></section> </legis-body></bill>

