<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-MDM25B67-2LH-1X-X4J">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 274 IS: Commending Federal, State, and local law enforcement for their efforts in protecting Americans by combating drug trafficking and agroterrorism and for their recent actions in Kansas and across the country.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress>
<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num>S. RES. 274</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20250612">June 12, 2025</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S411">Mr. Marshall</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">Commending Federal, State, and local law enforcement for their efforts in protecting Americans by combating drug trafficking and agroterrorism and for their recent actions in Kansas and across the country.</official-title>
</form>
<preamble>
<whereas><text>Whereas the illegal trafficking of drugs poses a severe threat to the health, safety, and well-being of communities across the United States, and contributes to addiction, violence, and economic disruption;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas drug trafficking has exacted a devastating human toll, resulting in the annual loss of tens of thousands of American lives to drug overdoses;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas an American dies from a drug overdose every 7 minutes, on average;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, Federal, State, and local law enforcement agencies have demonstrated unwavering commitment, bravery, and dedication in their efforts to disrupt and dismantle drug trafficking networks;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas Federal, State, and local law enforcement also play a vital role in protecting our Nation’s food security by preventing the intentional introduction of harmful substances or agents;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, in May 2025, a joint team consisting of agents from U.S. Customs and Border Protection, Homeland Security Investigations, the Kansas Bureau of Investigation, and the Emporia Police Department arrested 6 individuals who were transporting more than 85 gallons of liquid methamphetamine from Mexico to Emporia, Kansas;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas, in June 2025, the Federal Bureau of Investigation arrested 2 nationals of the People’s Republic of China, with alleged ties to the Chinese Communist Party and were caught smuggling the fungal plant pathogen Fusarium graminearum (also known as <quote>Gibberella zeae</quote>) into the United States;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas this fungus causes <quote>fusarium head blight</quote>, which devastates wheat, barley, maize, and rice crops, and which has caused billions of dollars in economic losses globally;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas had this fungus been released into the Kansas wheat crop, it would have devastated America’s largest wheat producer, accounting for between 20 and 25 percent of the Nation’s annual wheat production;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, in June 2025, the Federal Bureau of Investigation and the Drug Enforcement Administration executed a record drug bust, seizing illicit substances in quantities that could have killed nearly 50,000,000 people; and</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas these Federal agents confiscated more than 93 kilograms of fentanyl, 97 kilograms of methamphetamine, nearly 18 kilograms of heroin, and about 10 kilograms of cocaine, the combined value of which exceeds $9,000,000: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble> <resolution-body id="H669350B9E0F34AD8A9860FA9F3FF5618"> <section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text>
<paragraph id="id706c3dbdd5f247029f38a1af2efd8be9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>commends Federal, State, and local law enforcement agencies and personnel for their tireless efforts in combating drug trafficking and agroterrorism;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id00272d034acc4279865565ab2c2b369a"><enum>(2)</enum><text>expresses gratitude for their bravery and dedication to protecting American communities, public health, and our Nation’s food supply; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="id9795f1568d9e4bcfa2f5ae8a47dc0bd1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>encourages them to continue their efforts to keep our communities and food supply safe and secure.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body> </resolution> 

