<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ROS25407-TV2-CJ-5WD"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1360 IS: Protecting American Capital Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1360</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250408">April 8, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S404">Mr. Scott of Florida</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require an annual report on United States portfolio investments in the People's Republic of China, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting American Capital Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id08B304624F494994AB9631B84C15B38D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Annual report on United States portfolio investments in the People's Republic of China</header><subsection id="id823A621F5CBB4175A232C292019ABB23"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Secretary of the Treasury shall submit to Congress a report on portfolio investments by United States persons in the People's Republic of China, including such investments routed through a jurisdiction outside the United States.</text></subsection><subsection id="idAC6450B5627347AC8FE9538FF92823B4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>Each report required by subsection (a) shall include an assessment of the involvement of the following in portfolio investments in the People's Republic of China:</text><paragraph id="id1F9A0B520D4742348908DEB971BCC081"><enum>(1)</enum><text>United States persons making such investments, including an assessment of—</text><subparagraph id="id5ee25e3a35c944c7baf712ab4c18ef0a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the types of United States persons making such investments, including State pension funds; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6ac8e548edcd4cb6a65908b99ef4877a"><enum>(B)</enum><text>United States persons making more than 2 percent of the total of such investments in a year. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idC3583EEEA3D64ADDA4F1C86D679CE5E6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Chinese entities receiving such investments, including an assessment of—</text><subparagraph id="id91CCBD3A85A54717B2755D6BC85882ED"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such entities in individual sectors of the economic of the People's Republic of China, including the housing sector;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id281d87d1fdc94a4894ce4e8fb3e7ebf4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any Chinese entities subject to sanctions imposed by the United States receiving such investments; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idab335bc42e6e47d9bde97afb980eac43"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Chinese entities that receive more than $100,000,000 from such investments.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idD17A108C6C1043228A91AB48A4A5D2B6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Period covered</header><text>The period covered by a report required by subsection (a) shall be—</text><paragraph id="id16FFA9B235D24B6EBE382F16881DF4B8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the case of the first such report, the period beginning on January 1, 2008, and ending on the date of the report; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idEDA6380EB3EC40359863ADF241DD03C0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the case of each subsequent such report, the one-year period preceding submission of the report.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id3AB76407019749A697FF4D0997977D0B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="id054f40561ce4451abfa3689ae89a0cc5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Chinese entity</header><text>The term <term>Chinese entity</term> means an entity organized under the laws of the People's Republic of China or otherwise subject to the jurisdiction of the Government of the People's Republic of China. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id40cfb13b04244e9293c7cfd6f692f892"><enum>(2)</enum><header>United states person</header><text>The term <term>United States person</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="ide4fe39dccf07445e9abad2aa47c3b824"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a United States citizen or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence to the United States; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1f4423ba43a949f8a870bcd5b0215ae3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an entity organized under the laws of the United States or any jurisdiction within the United States, including a foreign branch of such an entity. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

