<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H05A155C1EA9D4BF8918C00549379EB70" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4730 IH: Restoring Truth and Sanity to American History Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4730</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250723">July 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001224">Mr. Self</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">House Administration</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To codify Executive Order 14253 relating to restoring truth and sanity to American history, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0F5DC07EE2244AC9A1BA1091D0DB9244" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H23CCE5463DE848F5819D2607627109C9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Restoring Truth and Sanity to American History Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HCB8157141EC448C1A22DCD49EA045034"><enum>2.</enum><header>Codification of Executive Order 14253</header> <subsection id="H7D308961789845F291254CA6584D134A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
<paragraph id="H48046205FD534A00A47E256CEEFA94A2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Over the past decade, Americans have witnessed a concerted and widespread effort to rewrite our Nation's history, replacing objective facts with a distorted narrative driven by ideology rather than truth. This revisionist movement seeks to undermine the remarkable achievements of the United States by casting its founding principles and historical milestones in a negative light. Under this historical revision, our Nation's unparalleled legacy of advancing liberty, individual rights, and human happiness is reconstructed as inherently racist, sexist, oppressive, or otherwise irredeemably flawed. Rather than fostering unity and a deeper understanding of our shared past, the widespread effort to rewrite history deepens societal divides and fosters a sense of national shame, disregarding the progress America has made and the ideals that continue to inspire millions around the globe.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8BDCAC8430454BFFB2D15F8BE51AACF6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The prior administration advanced this corrosive ideology. At Independence National Historical Park in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania—where our Nation declared that all men are created equal—the prior administration sponsored training by an organization that advocates dismantling <quote>Western foundations</quote> and <quote>interrogating institutional racism</quote> and pressured National Historical Park rangers that their racial identity should dictate how they convey history to visiting Americans because America is purportedly racist.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB4786ECD39244916BA2EAD0140501DE4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Once widely respected as a symbol of American excellence and a global icon of cultural achievement, the Smithsonian Institution has, in recent years, come under the influence of a divisive, race-centered ideology. This shift has promoted narratives that portray American and Western values as inherently harmful and oppressive. For example, the Smithsonian American Art Museum today features <quote>The Shape of Power: Stories of Race and American Sculpture</quote>, an exhibit representing that <quote>[s]ocieties including the United States have used race to establish and maintain systems of power, privilege, and disenfranchisement.</quote> The exhibit further claims that <quote>sculpture has been a powerful tool in promoting scientific racism</quote> and promotes the view that race is not a biological reality but a social construct, stating <quote>Race is a human invention</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H36B2AE34469844909D2DA181AE80CFEB"> <enum>(4)</enum> <text>The National Museum of African American History and Culture has proclaimed that <quote>hard work</quote>, <quote>individualism</quote>, and <quote>the nuclear family</quote> are aspects of <quote>White culture</quote>. The forthcoming Smithsonian American Women's History Museum plans on celebrating the exploits of male athletes participating in women's sports. These are just a few examples.</text>
        </paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H4788729CE5404AF880101492CA08C1C6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Policy statement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the policy of this Act—</text> <paragraph id="H180FC51380814EB3A043DBECEF7E873C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to restore Federal sites dedicated to history, including parks and museums, to solemn and uplifting public monuments that remind Americans of our extraordinary heritage, consistent progress toward becoming a more perfect Union, and unmatched record of advancing liberty, prosperity, and human flourishing;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6FC5B5378E274711BD6B3C2DA4A6B10B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>that Museums in our Nation's capital should be places where individuals go to learn—not to be subjected to ideological indoctrination or divisive narratives that distort our shared history; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD3E666CDF83844348AF441ECB2D5FA7F"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to restore the Smithsonian Institution to its rightful place as a symbol of inspiration and American greatness—igniting the imagination of young minds, honoring the richness of American history and innovation, and instilling pride in the hearts of all Americans.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H8C04923FF6AB48A684CA655B57CBA17E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Saving our Smithsonian</header>
<paragraph id="HFA80C204B8C54CAFACB4D7B6075AC399"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Vice President, in consultation with the Assistant to the President for Domestic Policy and the Special Assistant to the President and Senior Associate Staff Secretary, shall—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HADEAF7EA55934DEFB8E3324D40684B63"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">work to effectuate the policies of this Act through the Vice President's role on the Board of Regents of the Smithsonian Institution with respect to the Smithsonian Institution and its museums, education and research centers, and the National Zoo, including by seeking to remove from such properties anything that—</text>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCC847317372B468D9AB816F47CD93E34"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">violates the policy of this Act as articulated in subsection (b) or Federal civil rights laws; or</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H90F3B69944CC42A1A549EF6D0EFE5FB8"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">divides Americans based on race; and</text>
                        </clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD462FCE6B6024C64A3E6F6F06627A721"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommend to the President any additional actions necessary to fully effectuate such policies.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA8B04283B8AB48B5B51F8EE90055B867"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Future appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Vice President and the Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall work with Congress to ensure that future appropriations to the Smithsonian Institution—</text>
<subparagraph id="H744896C4DAC94AE495A4FB9D02A2C322"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prohibit expenditure on exhibits or programs that—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCC80927F768343A48475E2AC1226A902"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">degrade shared American values;</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBEC5B1D0575D43C2A07045A2BC0E9724"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">divide Americans based on race; or</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H15665E67C97443D0BCDFE4356231B9C6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">promote programs or ideologies inconsistent with Federal law, the policy of this Act as articulated in subsection (b), or Federal civil rights laws; and</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H9C8BF99057644477BCA06AE897230379" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>celebrate the achievements of women in the American Women's History Museum and do not recognize men as women in any respect, including by—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD43D40003D6C458486F0F5ED422DF59C"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">promoting, celebrating, or favorably depicting biological males competing in women’s sports, winning awards designated for women, dressing as women, or entering private facilities designated for women;</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9B0A3845D8184D82BD006B214871C2A3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">promoting, celebrating, or favorably depicting gender-affirming medicine, especially for minors; or</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD22FAEF899D24D7B989C727792F57390"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">including any other material that degrades the biological nature of sex or violates Federal civil rights laws.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD1592F111D924ABAA1BC48B9729F886D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Other measures to promote policy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Office of Management and Budget and the Secretary of the Interior shall take any other measures within their authority to promote the policy of this Act.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD9EECA2EA2E6439AB75AC5FACF90F751"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Board of Regents of the Smithsonian Institution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As appropriate, the Vice President shall, in consultation with the Assistant to the President for Domestic Policy and Special Assistant to the President and Senior Associate Staff Secretary, work with the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the Majority Leader of the Senate to seek the appointment of citizen members to the Board of Regents of the Smithsonian Institution committed to advancing the policy of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H4BC1F0D992224210B6657E5630B07064"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Restoring Independence Hall</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Interior shall provide sufficient funding, as available, to improve the infrastructure of Independence National Historical Park, which shall be complete by July 4, 2026, the 250th anniversary of the signing of the Declaration of Independence.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HF9C2D5E4C40A429EBD6DD884D491092C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Restoring truth in American history</header><text>The Secretary of the Interior shall—</text>
<paragraph id="HAC8D47008472486D8B3F92F792FFAA92"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">determine whether, since January 1, 2020, public monuments, memorials, statues, markers, or similar properties within the Department of the Interior's jurisdiction have been removed or changed to perpetuate a false reconstruction of American history, inappropriately minimize the value of certain historical events or figures, divide Americans based on race, recognize men as women, or include any other improper partisan ideology;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF5492E246F29430FA8B15230AED576D0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>take action to reinstate the pre-existing monuments, memorials, statues, markers, or similar properties, as appropriate and consistent with section 437 of the Revised Statutes (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1451">43 U.S.C. 1451</external-xref>), division A of subtitle I of title 54, United States Code, and other applicable law; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD3588B0A88BE4F3ABBB3813DF4838097"><enum>(3)</enum><text>take action, as appropriate and consistent with applicable law, to ensure that all public monuments, memorials, statues, markers, or similar properties within the Department of the Interior’s jurisdiction—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC71CDAF3852E44EA9D7F5902367D2F58"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">do not contain descriptions, depictions, or other content that inappropriately disparage Americans past or living (including persons living in colonial times), divide Americans based on race, or recognize men as women; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCB185B2CA2ED4A9BA2C39457CE32C299"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">instead focus on the greatness of the achievements and progress of the American people or, with respect to natural features, the beauty, abundance, and grandeur of the American landscape.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H0EFCCC3043084D8EBEE6D940080EBAC1"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed to—</text>
<paragraph id="HE823FF177046453A92982A274C36D601"><enum>(1)</enum><text>impair or otherwise affect—</text> <subparagraph id="H13922A43B0C04B009376466850279003"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the authority granted by law to an executive department or agency, or the head thereof; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H86BF23EB6B2B48AF8F4D4001D7ADC2A2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the functions of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget relating to budgetary, administrative, or legislative proposals; or</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC53F1D85D2CF4BC4B209511D5E99CDB8"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or in equity by any party against the United States, its departments, agencies, or entities, its officers, employees, or agents, or any other person.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

