<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H09AEA9A1DA25475480D317775E53EF08" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 662 IH: Expressing support for the designation of the week of August 25 through August 31, 2025, as “Black Breastfeeding Week”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 662</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250826">August 26, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="A000370">Ms. Adams</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of the week of August 25 through August 31, 2025, as <quote>Black Breastfeeding Week</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, according to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention statistics from 2020 to 2021, Black mothers’ breastfeeding initiation rate was 74 percent compared to White mothers’ rate of 85 percent;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas breastfeeding directly impacts the health and wellness of infants and the mothers who care for them;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Black mothers have reported greater barriers to breastfeeding compared to their counterparts, including pain or discomfort while breastfeeding, concerns about breastfeeding in public, insufficient availability of promotional and educational efforts, and the interference of breastfeeding with paid employment and other activities;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas some Black mothers have also reported lack of a social support system for continued breastfeeding;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas in North Carolina, only 70 percent of Black mothers attempted to breastfeed in 2019 versus 84 percent of White mothers and state average of 81 percent of all birthing parents in the state who breastfed during the same period;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Black babies suffer over a 3 times higher infant mortality rates than White babies in North Carolina;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas low breastfeeding initiation rates directly correlate to high infant mortality rates;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas babies who are breastfed for at least 3 months have a 38-percent reduced risk of infant mortality annually across the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Black children are at a greater risk for childhood disease, and the inability to exclusively breastfeed for the recommended 6 months has been attributed to twice as many deaths and 3 times as many childhood diseases in Black infants as compared to White infants;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 1 in 4 mothers in the United States return to work within two weeks of giving birth;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 60 percent of working mothers in the United States who are breastfeeding express breast milk in inadequate and unsanitary places on the job;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas understanding historical and contemporary racial inequities is important to address systemic injustices preventing families from achieving their breastfeeding potential;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas if mothers could meet current medical recommendations for breastfeeding, it would save the United States economy nearly $13,000,000,000 per year in pediatric health costs and premature deaths;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas <quote>Black Breastfeeding Week</quote> is an opportunity to raise awareness about the maternal child health crisis in Black communities and the important role that breastfeeding plays in improving maternal and infant health outcomes;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas this week is dedicated to increasing awareness of the critical role of breastfeeding and the work of Black community-led groups in improving family health and reducing infant mortality rates in Black communities;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas a week highlighting a unique and targeted approach to address the challenges facing Black mothers and families is critical to eliminating racial disparities in breastfeeding and breast cancer survival; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas <quote>Black Breastfeeding Week</quote> was created by Kimberly Seals Allers, Kiddada Green, and Anayah Sangodele-Ayoka to bring national attention to the United States maternal child health crisis in the Black community and the important role that breastfeeding plays in improving maternal and infant health outcomes: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H3A026EFC63CD42FE9BDBD22A0839FD31"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H341475C4EC85455381E18305FB45AB42"><enum/><text>That the House of Representatives recognizes—</text><paragraph id="H27677DAC453C4E69B6E7E2728FFCEFB2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>that systemic and institutional racism creates greater barriers for Black women committed to meeting breastfeeding guidelines set out by Federal public health officials;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H95641C9FE8C14A63B7A3B2660F69F884"><enum>(2)</enum><text>that these barriers contribute to increasing health disparities leaving Black mothers and infants particularly vulnerable;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H567C5ABBC8144509AB57294F90EBB18D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>that disproportionate rates of maternal mortality and morbidity in the United States and the alarmingly high rates of maternal mortality among Black women are unacceptable;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4E100994C2474753BBC0D2FEBAE5983B"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that Congress must fully support and encourage policies that ensure Black parents have access to affordable health care, allow parents to take paid leave after the birth of a child, and ensure that breastfeeding mothers have appropriate places to express breast milk; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H671483A31A4649EFAFF82ED7FB4D7A45"><enum>(5)</enum><text>that, in order to better mitigate the effects of systemic and structural racism, Congress must work toward ensuring that Black communities have—</text><subparagraph id="H6C985F549B824142859630D28DD93D3A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>adequate housing;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9942BD6411BA490BA3A7F0DD0D159434"><enum>(B)</enum><text>transportation equity;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF75F7D0A8F0B427F95330ADCF32DA975"><enum>(C)</enum><text>nutritious food;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3B7C9405E7254D6ABD87F73B73966944"><enum>(D)</enum><text>clean water;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC6F4C9A5EE6B45E8AD53C5188FE289FA"><enum>(E)</enum><text>environments free from toxins;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7ED3A40072284F409F566B596DA5AF47"><enum>(F)</enum><text>fair treatment within the criminal justice system;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAF2D1554AC4449DB92C1E1BC4FC4CFD5"><enum>(G)</enum><text>safety and freedom from violence;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4A0E0B0A98624114BC8AAA8C90077DC9"><enum>(H)</enum><text>a living wage;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H435B8EA7A9424833AE97B3B999FB95AE"><enum>(I)</enum><text>equal economic opportunity; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H12610911643349C29E1CA401B84EC009"><enum>(J)</enum><text>comprehensive, quality, and affordable health care.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

