<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-GOE25778-2DF-1K-V88"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2948 IS: Help Federal Employees During Shutdowns Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2948</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250930">September 30, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S428">Ms. Alsobrooks</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S327">Mr. Warner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S353">Mr. Schatz</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend section 303 of the Social Security Act to require States to provide unemployment compensation benefits to Federal employees during a government shutdown, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HF0947EA4A2CF4B77ADE581C945EBCDE5"><section id="idee4d15adfc51496a9dc1fd2d71e93d72" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Help Federal Employees During Shutdowns Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Help FEDS Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H493D805E57C743B9A4DC545F703EF1EF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Regular compensation required for Federal employees during a shutdown</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 303 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/503">42 U.S.C. 503</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H59F518355056474788BD545D4CF6E97D"><subsection id="H2804652EEB0C49319F9619A3F3BC9F3F"><enum>(n)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H1D7806B25B7842D7B99D78BBBABB36A9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>For purposes of subsection (a), the unemployment compensation law of a State must—</text><subparagraph id="H0093083EFF6E4B1395E18100D6C33972" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">allow for excepted Federal employees to apply for and receive unemployment compensation for any week in which such employee is performing emergency work (as such term is defined by the Office of Personnel Management) during a lapse in appropriations during fiscal year 2026 or 2027;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB84AE2BACDE84A589DBBA59160A2C87B" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case that an excepted Federal employee receives pay under section 1341(c)(2) of title 31, United States Code, for any period in which such employee received compensation pursuant to subparagraph (A), require such an excepted Federal employee to repay such compensation to the State; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0AA0FC935F164DD69502D77B406C2B8D" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>treat as an overpayment any such compensation not repaid to the State and allow for the recovery of such compensation in the same manner the State recovers any overpayment paid pursuant to the unemployment compensation law of the State; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H574BDA86D7D548318A4F29354F5DF0D8" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>deposit all money repaid or recovered pursuant to subparagraphs (B) and (C) in the unemployment fund of such State.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5B45048B6E7F49199D7A94BA2BEC5826" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H520268BD9BC745C3BED87DD9939F5EF3"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Treasury shall pay to each State, for the purpose of providing unemployment compensation to excepted Federal employees pursuant to paragraph (1)(A), the amount described in subparagraph (B). The Secretary of Labor shall, from time to time, certify to the Secretary of the Treasury the amount to be paid under this paragraph.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H907AF67611BC4A0B86EFC24C03C41059" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>There shall be paid to each State an amount equal to 100 percent of—</text><clause id="H94C5A0E0C2EC44E9B7F4D5C8FE531A8B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the total amount of unemployment compensation provided to excepted Federal employees by the State pursuant to paragraph (1)(A); and</text></clause><clause id="H09BC96691CCC46F08DE84B49AF032F5F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any additional administrative expenses incurred by the State in relation to such compensation.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H190C400F837A4087AEE1C0B930E53F7F" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Funds in the Unemployment Trust Fund (as established by section 904(a)) shall be used to make payments to States pursuant to subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8D1EE5A99C004CAA9F4CCA003B293E38" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In this section, the term <quote>excepted Federal employee</quote> means, with respect to a lapse in appropriations, a Federal employee who—</text><subparagraph id="H2928C26BD53F44978CDCC6B783C02B1B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is an excepted employee, as defined in section 1341(c)(1) of title 31, United States Code; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF4EB24BC416343CFA4EBCB781F66A4F5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is not being paid due to the lapse in appropriations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

