<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0F44FB78CDD84A0399987A01E15B4823" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 392 IH: Expressing support for the designation of May as “National Bladder Cancer Awareness Month”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 392</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250506">May 6, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001210">Mr. Murphy</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="D000230">Mr. Davis of North Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001157">Mr. David Scott of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barrag&#225;n</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000055">Mr. Aderholt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of May as <quote>National Bladder Cancer Awareness Month</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas increased public awareness and early treatment of bladder cancer will save thousands of lives;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas more than 800,000 families in the United States live with bladder cancer;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas it is estimated that more than 84,870 people in the United States, or over 230 Americans every day, will be diagnosed with bladder cancer in 2025, including over 65,080 men and 19,790 women;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas it is estimated that bladder cancer will kill more than 17,420 Americans this year alone;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas bladder cancer can directly impact all people, regardless of age, sex, and race;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas bladder cancer is among the top 7 most diagnosed cancers in the United States, and the top 4 most commonly diagnosed cancers for our honored veterans;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, if diagnosed early, bladder cancer is highly treatable, but survivability rates decrease substantially with later detection;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas smoking and environmental or occupational exposure to carcinomic chemicals are the top causes of bladder cancer;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas studies have shown a higher level of bladder cancer in firefighters, veterans, and senior citizens than in the general public;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas bladder cancer symptoms, such as blood in the urine, are easily recognized, however, many Americans are unaware of the warning signs and often put off diagnostic testing and treatment;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas bladder cancer is known as one of the most expensive cancers to treat on a per patient basis and has a reoccurrence rate of approximately 50 to 80 percent, requiring lifelong surveillance;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, while bladder cancer is more prevalent in men, women are commonly diagnosed at a later stage and face a worse prognosis even when diagnosed at the same stage as men;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas there have been limited significant breakthroughs in the past 30 years to advance the treatment of and move toward a cure for bladder cancer;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the quality of life and chance of survival for a bladder cancer patient depends largely on new advancements and a renewed focus on research from both the Federal Government and private industry;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas increased awareness for bladder cancer will promote earlier diagnosis and increased chances of survival;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, in 2025, Congress will require the Department of Veterans Affairs to dramatically increase bladder cancer treatments for the Nation’s veterans exposed to toxins from burn pits under the Honoring our PACT Act of 2022, living up to the promise the Nation made decades ago;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas based on the Nation’s experience diagnosing and caring for Vietnam veterans exposed to carcinogenic chemicals such as Agent Orange and Agent Blue;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Congressionally Directed Medical Research Programs, working concurrently with the National Institutes of Health, annually fund the high-risk, high-reward research required to one day discover a cure for bladder cancer;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas traditionally throughout May, survivors, caregivers, and loved ones unite for walks in communities across the United States to raise awareness for bladder cancer along with funds for bladder cancer research;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Bladder Cancer Advocacy Network has worked for 20 years to raise public awareness for bladder cancer while providing patients with the knowledge, resources, and support they need to navigate their personal bladder cancer journey;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Bladder Cancer Advocacy Network annually funds cutting edge research in search of better treatments and a final cure for bladder cancer while working every day to raise public awareness, support patients, and increase research; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas May would be an appropriate month to designate as <quote>National Bladder Cancer Awareness Month</quote>: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HB56D0125BC514FFE870CF8897C6FB8EC"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H9E5F4C4AB12749C08582113ACCA6B1BD"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="H8D1006A67C67441B951E842E84D52378"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the designation of <quote>National Bladder Cancer Awareness Month</quote>;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7265CD0E17B940DB857AE67BC325A8BF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>supports the goals and ideals of <quote>National Bladder Cancer Awareness Month</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H34E57CFFEE74461B96FC481994C52B0F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>calls on the people of the United States, interested groups, the research community, and affected persons to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H4A33703CF30F4BF4A8790DBE3A0114B4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>promote awareness of bladder cancer and foster understanding of the impact of the disease on patients, their families, caregivers, and their community;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H80E4F739C3B3465995560046FBFB112D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>take an active role in the fight to end bladder cancer; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8C47077C90644C1DA2CC59A0A602B7E3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>observe <quote>National Bladder Cancer Awareness Month</quote> with appropriate ceremonies and activities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

