<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6491425E21F74A648E20A67FE59BCAC7" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1523 IH: Promoting Responsible and Effective Virtual Experiences through Novel Technology to Deliver Improved Access and Better Engagement with Tested and Evidence-based Strategies Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1523</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250224">February 24, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000197">Ms. DeGette</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="B001257">Mr. Bilirakis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001121">Mr. Crow</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001216">Ms. Schrier</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for the inclusion of virtual diabetes prevention program suppliers in the Medicare Diabetes Prevention Program Expanded Model, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB5E2CF55341440B9889C0643A9550F0B" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H2C7F0E554CF5470C9D07B55E4855E7C6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"> This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Promoting Responsible and Effective Virtual Experiences through Novel Technology to Deliver Improved Access and Better Engagement with Tested and Evidence-based Strategies Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>PREVENT DIABETES Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H3202EB18FD0B4048A75C42224F9BF359" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Inclusion of virtual diabetes prevention program suppliers in MDPP Expanded Model</header> <subsection id="H3501558225FA4ED4B8EB66D440642DD9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than January 1, 2026, the Secretary shall revise the regulations under parts 410 and 424 of title 42, Code of Federal Regulations, to provide that, for the period beginning January 1, 2026, and ending December 31, 2030—</text> 
<paragraph id="H7D5CDD3D129148B79D298E801AEC8843"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an entity may participate in the MDPP by offering only online MDPP services via synchronous or asynchronous technology or telecommunications if such entity meets the conditions for enrollment as an MDPP supplier (as specified in section 424.205(b) of title 42, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation));</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HBBE6EF194C53461393E71DA9595A9DA8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>if an entity participates in the MDPP in the manner described in <internal-xref idref="H7D5CDD3D129148B79D298E801AEC8843" legis-path="2.(a)(1)">paragraph (1)</internal-xref>—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H9AAF139ABF89461280323BAB0821D88D" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the administrative location of such entity shall be the address of the entity on file under the Diabetes Prevention Recognition Program; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFC2B6CD9D7AE42D499004A1692D8B09C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of online MDPP services furnished by such entity to an MDPP beneficiary who was not located in the same State as the entity at the time such services were furnished, the entity shall not be prohibited from submitting a claim for payment for such services solely by reason of the location of such beneficiary at such time; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4A856762C9904BD8AEAFF805E3F5FB9D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>no limit is applied on the number of times an individual may enroll in the MDPP.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H04425485066940C5A42FD1224C134505"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="HEA5EF1C828B84660B4AA6A06B65A7E4B" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>MDPP</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>MDPP</term> means the Medicare Diabetes Prevention Program conducted under section 1115A of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1315a">42 U.S.C. 1315a</external-xref>), as described in the final rule published in the Federal Register entitled <quote>Medicare and Medicaid Programs; CY 2024 Payment Policies Under the Physician Fee Schedule and Other Changes to Part B Payment and Coverage Policies; Medicare Shared Savings Program Requirements; Medicare Advantage; Medicare and Medicaid Provider and Supplier Enrollment Policies; and Basic Health Program</quote> (88 Fed. Reg. 78818 (November 16, 2023)) (or a successor regulation).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5F5F3D07C273498D8D0BC2FA0AAF38CE" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Regulatory terms</header><text>The terms <term>Diabetes Prevention Recognition Program</term>, <term>full CDC DPRP recognition</term>, <term>MDPP beneficiary</term>, <term>MDPP services</term>, and <term>MDPP supplier</term> have the meanings given each such term in section 410.79(b) of title 42, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8D8C83D69BB348AC85AE4FC36D311235"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

