<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H355664B3CCAC4FF98A3BD2D63B9D4919" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2325 IH: Central African Exploitation and Manipulation of American Companies Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2325</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250325">March 25, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001058">Mr. Huizenga</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001204">Mr. Meuser</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To withhold United States support for any action in the International Monetary Fund relating to member states of the Central African Economic Monetary Community until a determination as to gross foreign exchange reserves is made.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H26F75500DE8E4DFDABFCD9903DC59570" style="OLC"><section id="H18AD3A13E87748268E46857733FF5C92" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Central African Exploitation and Manipulation of American Companies Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>CEMAC Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H640690761ABE41EEB62766F76170CB1F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds as follows:</text><paragraph id="H6E855B3229ED4ED1B27B736E7F7366A2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The member states of the Central African Economic Monetary Community (CEMAC) hold significant oil and gas reserves and have enjoyed decades long relationships and investments with international oil companies (IOCs).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1A21FE97E3544596A4D56F692098E2AE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In 2018, the central bank for CEMAC, the Bank of Central African States (BEAC) introduced and intended to enact a foreign exchange regulation that mandates extractive industry companies repatriate restoration funds for site rehabilitation to the BEAC.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H57069A54D0794C699851B2BEC75408E2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Significant progress has been made in mediated dialogues over the last 7 years to rectify 23 issues with this regulation raised by the IOCs. However, significant issues remain including the refusal of BEAC to remove its sovereign immunity from execution, the role of BEAC as custodian of restoration fund accounts, and the implementation of double jeopardy and material adverse change clauses.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF3E2FD1018D640E9B928CB98704C0735"><enum>(4)</enum><text>BEAC has imposed a completely arbitrary deadline of April 30, 2025, for the IOCs to sign this agreement with penalties equivalent to 150 percent of the restoration fund starting May 1, 2025.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6279A996549D4A17AEBE19A82894CFDF"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Implementation of this regulation is expected to create a lasting negative impact on oil and gas investment in the Central African region, and will drastically compound an already challenging investment environment.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE4DDE14FBFDA4FCE87FB7D75D3AD36E2"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The member states of BEAC have indicated that these restoration funds will help them shore up their foreign exchange reserves, despite restoration funds being exclusively allocated for restoration work costs and therefore not meeting the criteria of the International Monetary Fund (IMF) for foreign exchange reserves.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H67B1EED9123A4FCD91CF6F71C2B56F4C"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The IMF’s Balance of Payments and International Investment Position Manual states that assets must be <quote>readily available</quote> and <quote>controlled</quote> by a country’s monetary authorities to count towards a country’s foreign exchange reserves.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBDC185F4B5B941F8819B71243DBF8592"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Oil and gas investments in the CEMAC region have been declining since 2018 and this BEAC foreign exchange regulation is expected to drastically accelerate this decline.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE760BB84FA4B44CEA501EF983BF4599B"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Standard &amp; Poor’s estimates that the regulation by 2050 will result in a reduction of government revenue for CEMAC member states of $86,000,000,000, and a reduction in capital investment of $45,000,000,000 in the region.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD94A6CFBD43A446F80EC24AB803FBC87"><enum>(10)</enum><text>By refusing to clarify that these restoration funds will not count towards gross foreign exchange reserves, the IMF has misled the CEMAC member states and directly put tens of billions of dollars of IOCs investment in the region at risk.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H319B61D487EC4D5BB44738615D5D5FD6"><enum>3.</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the policy of the United States that—</text><paragraph id="H6C9092637E614C618AC962F5630275F1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the presence of United States companies is a good thing for the regions in which they invest;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H09175C21FF8D4724A73855586BDCDD1F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any funds provided to the Bank of Central African States (in this Act referred to as <quote>BEAC</quote>) by any extractive industry company for site rehabilitation are ineligible to count towards the gross foreign exchange reserves of a member state of the Central African Economic Monetary Community (in this Act referred to as <quote>CEMAC</quote>) based on the requirements of the Balance of Payments and International Investment Position Manual of the International Monetary Fund (in this Act referred to as the <quote>IMF</quote>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4E4218304E04444887698A1B28A4C2B8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the IMF has a responsibility to accurately clarify to countries what are eligible and ineligible assets to count towards the gross foreign exchange reserves of a country, so that countries are able to create appropriate financial policies; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H605A3045376D49A48DD23CDF38815B01"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the IMF would be responsible for the loss of investment that the CEMAC region would face if a foreign exchange regulation that mandates extractive industry companies repatriate restoration funds for site rehabilitation to the BEAC is enacted.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H9BE4143408854CF6924E00CB411E196D"><enum>4.</enum><header>Withdrawal of funding</header><subsection id="H7F7C6D57D7CE4234B777A9C0ACB8BBE0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Until the Secretary of the Treasury, in coordination with the United States Executive Director at the IMF and the Secretary of State, makes the determination described in subsection (b)—</text><paragraph id="H8AB03315AA80427C8F5F281E18D4C5DA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>neither the President nor any person or agency shall, on behalf of the United States, vote to approve any action by the IMF relating to any CEMAC member state; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3DA1CAC8B3C443F68A35E31B2BEF0BAB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Secretary of the Treasury shall direct the United States Executive Director at the IMF to use the voice and vote of the United States to oppose any proposal to—</text><subparagraph id="H53BFCFB8950446F2B75388E1A00337F3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>increase the quota in the IMF for any CEMAC member state; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC4964180DFA14CAA97DD0BFE55E86542"><enum>(B)</enum><text> modify the exceptional access policy of the IMF for any CEMAC member state.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H207FDDE87105469387275C8138144229"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Determination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The determination referred to in subsection (a) is a determination that the IMF has publicly clarified that any funds provided to BEAC by any international oil company for site rehabilitation are ineligible to count towards the gross foreign exchange reserves of any country.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF71D5A393E404654AAA126C0A8702B6A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>On making the determination described in subsection (b), the Secretary of the Treasury shall publicize the determination and transmit a copy of the determination to the appropriate congressional committees.</text></subsection><subsection id="H48765F49833C4D2A80BFF4905FA64130"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No later than 30 days after the date the determination described in subsection (b) is made, and no later than 180 days after the enactment of this Act if the determination has, by then, not been made, the Secretary of the Treasury shall provide to the appropriate congressional committees a report that details the actions taken by the United States Government at the International Monetary Fund, including those by the United States Executive Director at the IMF, to have the IMF publicly clarify that any funds provided to BEAC by any international oil company for site rehabilitation are ineligible to count towards the gross foreign exchange reserves of a country.</text></subsection><subsection id="H32E0D73512CE4DCE94702F082EB1C2F8"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means—</text><paragraph id="HA5671A4577114E5C95594FB9554B8ACE"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Financial Services and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8836491E1ED14B6FAA057D9C1B2EF97C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Finance and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

