<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-KAT25472-LT4-P0-PKL">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2128 IS: Monarch Action, Recovery, and Conservation of Habitat Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>II</distribution-code>
        <congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session>1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. 2128</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action>
            <action-date date="20250618">June 18, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S316">Mr. Whitehouse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S359">Mr.
                    Heinrich</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</cosponsor>,
                    <cosponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>,
                and <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill;
                which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEV00">Committee on Environment and Public Works</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title>To encourage and facilitate efforts by States and other stakeholders to
            conserve and sustain the western population of monarch butterflies, and for other
            purposes.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause">
        <section section-type="section-one" id="H9AA7508E5FD340C990358B949E0721C1">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Monarch Action, Recovery, and Conservation of Habitat Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>MONARCH Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section commented="no" id="HD30B2736F644406BB111E512E485F985">
            <enum>2.</enum>
            <header>Findings</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="H02C2F37856824936940C427805F2A9DC"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>the population of western monarch butterflies is at imminent risk of extinction;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph commented="no" id="H52F97990F1E2434BB7B501F3B0E1485F">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>over the past 3 decades, the population of western monarch butterflies has declined by more than 99 percent due to prolonged drought, loss of milkweed and native pollinator habitat, loss of breeding and overwintering habitat, and climate change;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph commented="no" id="HCCACBFCEF35D4EAD8CDF10E446F75860">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in 2020, the population of western monarch butterflies reached a new historic low of 1,914 butterflies, falling below the predicted extinction threshold for the third year in a row;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3141cfde01614bcbbc11218a05128ec6">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>in 2024, the population of western monarch butterflies reached the second lowest on record, with less than 10,000 butterflies recorded;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph commented="no" id="HF7B87C37686E4B3E9F381D28D6AD8606">
                <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text>the extinction of the population of migratory western monarch butterflies is now likely to occur within the next 2 decades if urgent action is not taken;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph commented="no" id="HA4303050DC934E2FA6FC3148F7745451">
                <enum>(6)</enum>
 <text>actively restoring native milkweed and nectar plants, monarch overwintering habitat, and other pollinator habitat, and ensuring that key habitats are protected from destruction, are critical to ensuring the survival of western monarch butterflies and can also help facilitate conservation of other essential pollinators; and</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph commented="no" id="H3A9C2053CA5949168CEAF420717C7584">
                <enum>(7)</enum>
 <text>enhancing pollinator populations can result in improved pollination services for neighboring land, including agriculture and wildlife ecosystems.</text>
            </paragraph>
        </section>
        <section id="H89C8E36B03D24008B6B885335F15CAF3">
            <enum>3.</enum>
            <header>Definitions</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="HE1D3362DA9A046CA8D06EAA83EBD4000"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>Conservation</header> <text>The term <term>conservation</term> means the use of each method or procedure necessary to protect habitats of western monarch butterflies and other pollinators within the range of western monarch butterflies, including—</text>
                <subparagraph id="HFC4656B6EFB2488291A5C724CFEBFD2D">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>the protection, restoration, and management of overwintering, breeding, and migratory habitats;</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H6DC4F885B6B0483F97A9A298658CA3D3">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>assistance in the development and implementation of national, regional, State, Tribal, and local conservation and management plans; and</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="HB269E8ACE90E47458261B46BAEC34257">
                    <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>community outreach and education.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HD06659BE617544E2AD6E38A63068BDA8"> <enum>(2)</enum> <header>Fund</header> <text>The term <term>Fund</term> means the Western Monarch Butterfly Rescue Fund established by section 5(a).</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H7133A94B6F3246528F7EBFB07B08E6F7">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
                <header>Secretary</header>
 <text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6ae92307da36414e932116316dada75b"> <enum>(4)</enum> <header>Tribal government</header> <text>The term <term>Tribal government</term> means the governing body of a federally recognized Indian Tribe.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H6F87207871274670AFB7966E084F05C5">
                <enum>(5)</enum>
                <header>Western monarch butterfly</header>
 <text>The term <term>western monarch butterfly</term> means the monarch butterfly population that overwinters along the coast of the State of California and breeds across the States of California, Arizona, Nevada, Washington, Oregon, Idaho, and Utah.</text>
            </paragraph>
        </section>
        <section id="HD533C84925D04A1BA7A12C90645E034A">
            <enum>4.</enum>
            <header>Western monarch butterfly conservation grant program</header>
            <subsection id="H254D49FD12D64E4EBC789E0D329CE4E2">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
 <text>Subject to the availability of funds and in consultation with other relevant Federal agencies, amounts deposited in the Fund shall be available to the Secretary to provide grants for projects for the conservation of western monarch butterflies, and other pollinators within the range of western monarch butterflies, for which project proposals are approved by the Secretary in accordance with this section.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H3C800377796E42F09D0A2F88790967D3">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Project proposals</header>
                <paragraph id="HEAD3B88D46374ECE8676A4689FEBA828">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                    <header>Eligible entities</header>
 <text>An entity that is eligible to receive a grant for a project under this section is—</text>
                    <subparagraph id="HEE69E761B8CB48558A6FBBD956162AD7">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>a relevant local government or Tribal government agency, research institution, or nonprofit organization with expertise required for the conservation of western monarch butterflies and other pollinators within the range of western monarch butterflies; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="HF77E733877924C34A42BBA553CF26591">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>any other entity, as determined appropriate by the Secretary, with the expertise required for the conservation of western monarch butterflies and other pollinators within the range of western monarch butterflies.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HBAC3255613374AF0ABF332386092B58F">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Federal partnership opportunities</header>
 <text>A State or Federal agency—</text> <subparagraph id="HB382456F01E246268FAC7852791BF0F4"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>may not be a lead entity or receive a grant for a project under this section; but</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H2CC545ACB0414D3CA0AF5B75EA06B645">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>may be included as a partner or collaborator on a project that receives a grant under this section.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H3ABFF787826E4064AE7D1FE39882F4A6">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
                    <header>Required elements</header>
 <text>A proposal for a project under this section shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="H5C808BC45B4845A08DD13089B0085F5E"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>a statement of the purposes of the project;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H0C5E634EF63145859BB96E5EA5544A80">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>the name of the entity with overall responsibility for the project;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="HC831284FC89F48E98C6467191F631DC3">
                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>a description of—</text> <clause id="H13F31FA717E84EE8B9445C2852E98F90"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>the qualifications of the entity that will conduct the project;</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="HDBC2EFF1A22E4935BFD9F5CB75E8D358">
                            <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>methods for project implementation and outcome assessment; and</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="H0E8C1BC530DB419AB1482B66A0772728">
                            <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>anticipated outcomes;</text> </clause> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD97C1AB0F66145418576EA5E267C090E"> <enum>(D)</enum> <text>assurances that the project will be implemented in consultation with relevant wildlife management authorities, Tribal governments, and other appropriate local government, State government, and Federal Government agencies;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="HE442CBAC8B304BB089F644FD7E1D4EF8">
                        <enum>(E)</enum>
 <text>assurances that the conservation efforts outlined in the proposal do not conflict with food safety measures or practices;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H82665BF991B745DE8E62CE7EBAEA9017">
                        <enum>(F)</enum>
 <text>information that demonstrates the clear potential of the project to contribute to the conservation and recovery of western monarch butterflies and other pollinators within the range of western monarch butterflies; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H477ADF507B02484980C96F648C9C4075">
                        <enum>(G)</enum>
 <text>such other information as the Secretary may require.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="H75D7BF80679A47D6A4664FB726AABBA7"> <enum>(c)</enum> <header>Project review and approval</header> <text>The Secretary shall annually—</text>
                <paragraph id="H11D5E01E5C5C4CD3AC06FA31B09D940E">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>solicit project proposals for funding under this section; and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H46F84C8777C54F61B4B92B432C261FC8"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>review each proposal described in paragraph (1) on a timeline that recognizes the urgency of the declining number of western monarch butterflies and other pollinators within the range of western monarch butterflies to determine whether the proposal meets the criteria described in subsection (d).</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H403781558CF44B33B4B4A86139312D9F">
                <enum>(d)</enum>
                <header>Criteria for approval</header>
 <text>The Secretary may approve a project proposal under this section if the proposal demonstrates a likelihood that the project will contribute to the conservation of western monarch butterfly populations in the wild.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="HCF5C1D48D8B7491188FAB165C358ABAF">
                <enum>(e)</enum>
                <header>Technical assistance</header>
 <text>The Secretary shall provide technical assistance for a project that receives a grant under this section.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="HCAF89372E92843F29365C6C82DD85DAD">
                <enum>(f)</enum>
                <header>Project reporting</header>
                <paragraph id="H184E68DDC4CF4355BDC877020C710B7A">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                    <header>In general</header>
 <text>Each entity that receives a grant for a project under this section shall submit to the Secretary, at such intervals as the Secretary may require, reports that include any information that the Secretary determines is necessary to evaluate the progress and success of the project for the purposes of ensuring positive results, assessing problems, and fostering improvements.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HA0A99157C3FA498980F93FDF49BA0BA8">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Availability to State legislatures</header>
 <text>At the request of the Governor of the State in which a project is conducted, each entity that receives a grant for a project under this section shall submit each report under paragraph (1) to the State legislature of that State.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HD8A369EDE34045519E3FB744B3DB03EE">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
                    <header>Availability to the public</header>
 <text>The Secretary shall make available to the public, in a timely manner—</text>
                    <subparagraph id="H6352C8D460964D55881B2582AC7D4938">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>each report submitted under paragraph (1); and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEE390207CD22497FB9A6A6CBA1BC0485"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>any other documents relating to projects for which a grant is provided under this section.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
        </section>
        <section id="H0E1D59FE99C345A2A71D836918AC3E2D">
            <enum>5.</enum>
            <header>Western Monarch Butterfly Rescue Fund</header>
            <subsection id="HE9A2435A4FED4655B235F35FDC6ACFA2">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>Establishment</header>
 <text>There is established in the Treasury of the United States a fund, to be known as the <quote>Western Monarch Butterfly Rescue Fund</quote>.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="HE200EF33D9D5400482AECD0E761EB748">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Administrative expenses</header>
 <text>Of the amounts available in the Fund for each fiscal year, the Secretary may expend not more than 3 percent to pay the administrative expenses necessary to carry out this Act.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection commented="no" id="HB620D685036141D4B29F123E459ADFE3">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
 <text>There is authorized to be appropriated for deposit into the Fund $12,500,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030, to remain available until expended.</text>
            </subsection>
        </section>
        <section id="H4631C40117884417BD179514C320BF79">
            <enum>6.</enum>
            <header>Implementation of the Western Monarch Butterfly Conservation Plan</header>
            <subsection id="id20E90B25D8A44F98B3F4B6521C36967A">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall enter into an agreement with the National Fish and Wildlife Foundation pursuant to the National Fish and Wildlife Foundation Establishment Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/3701">16 U.S.C. 3701 et seq.</external-xref>) to facilitate updating and implementing the Western Monarch Butterfly Conservation Plan prepared by the Western Association of Fish and Wildlife Agencies and dated January 2019.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id4DFE329265794C9DBD0110A47F085967">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Administration</header>
 <text>Section 10(a) of the National Fish and Wildlife Foundation Establishment Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/3709">16 U.S.C. 3709(a)</external-xref>) shall not apply with respect to—</text>
                <paragraph id="id8DF6738A59044FA68B380C8CFC097E42">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>the agreement entered into under subsection (a); or</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="idBDA348F8BB614E50BCE2FB26979C8F6C"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>amounts made available to carry out this section.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id1A34FFED0E7D46A6873DA90E02E028B4">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this section $12,500,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030.</text>
            </subsection>
        </section>
        <section id="H1EA122BF808E446EA684807F1F586458">
            <enum>7.</enum>
            <header>Report to Congress</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than January 31 of each year, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report describing the status of western monarch butterflies, including, with respect to the year for which the report is submitted—</text>
            <paragraph id="H1B1FBA237AC84AFD92AC86295F20C5EE">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>a summary of the projects for which the Secretary has provided funding under section 4 and an evaluation of those projects; and</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB9CACF230E6B4B5DB2498267684DE042">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>a summary of the projects for which the Secretary has provided funding through the Western Monarch Butterfly Conservation Plan prepared by the Western Association of Fish and Wildlife Agencies and dated January 2019.</text>
            </paragraph>
        </section>
    </legis-body>
</bill>

