<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6A4922C67A6C4E82A69F607B51609EF9" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1061 IH: Protecting Sensitive Locations Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1061</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250206">February 6, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001156">Ms. Sánchez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001229">Mrs. McIver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000034">Mr. Pallone</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001081">Mrs. Hayes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000557">Mr. Larson of Connecticut</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001130">Ms. Crockett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000617">Mrs. Ramirez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000586">Mr. García of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001117">Mr. Casten</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000173">Ms. Omar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000305">Ms. Jacobs</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000489">Mr. Turner of Texas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="O000172">Ms. Ocasio-Cortez</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend section 287 of the Immigration and Nationality Act to limit immigration enforcement actions at sensitive locations, to clarify the powers of immigration officers at sensitive locations, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0985DEB7FBB2486AA511785C0B0D00AC" style="OLC"><section id="H222A0C0CDBCD4449AC16010E957730AB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting Sensitive Locations Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H8278A6C44D5140E388C85B7644C9BE80"><enum>2.</enum><header>Powers of immigration officers and employees at sensitive locations</header><subsection id="HB07F9F3D04824F61910426B81B1DA38C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 287 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1357">8 U.S.C. 1357</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HAD673F88D9584CF1A91D5CE707AED8B5" style="OLC"><subsection id="H039E1B28796F406B947518815C567F22"><enum>(i)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H65D917B5D3664CC38ED9D3C6A78C4CB6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In order to ensure individuals’ access to sensitive locations, this subsection shall apply to any enforcement action by—</text><subparagraph id="H61F040F2BCBE4CC092BF136CA4714EA9" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>officers or agents of the Department of Homeland Security, including officers and agents of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement and U.S. Customs and Border Protection; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEDFF0EA4BBDC494F8212A898FBBB2E11" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any individual designated to perform immigration enforcement functions pursuant to subsection (g).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF0919FB5DF814B4CB6AB329B1320339C" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HCD4FD4B06EFF4D1698DACE6A6C2C20D3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An enforcement action may not take place at, be focused on, or occur within, 1,000 feet of a sensitive location, except under exigent circumstances.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1E073181B9354AE88F4B797A06D1BA75"><enum>(B)</enum><text>If an immigration enforcement action is taking place under exigent circumstances, and the exigent circumstances permitting the enforcement action cease, the enforcement action shall be discontinued until such exigent circumstances reemerge.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3463B84C609548F5B1C788CC59304F31"><enum>(C)</enum><text>If an individual referred to in subparagraph (A) or (B) of paragraph (1) is not certain as to whether exigent circumstances exist, the individual shall cease the enforcement action immediately, consult with their supervisor in real time as to the existence of exigent circumstances, and shall not continue the enforcement action until the individual’s supervisor affirmatively confirms the existence of exigent circumstances.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE80C2A758FB14B76B14D4EAD065E7A61" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HB115824A879947429C1D57AC96AF96D0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>When proceeding with an enforcement action at or near a sensitive location, individuals referred to in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (1) shall make every effort—</text><clause id="H349793BAF6264C1EB8A5DFFD0DF398F1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to conduct themselves as discreetly as possible, consistent with officer and public safety;</text></clause><clause id="H8D28297EAAAD49ECB65B88AFACF85811"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to limit the time spent at the sensitive location; and</text></clause><clause id="H90A6F9B64C8E41DCBB66D182186A912B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to limit the enforcement action to the person or persons for whom prior approval was obtained.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H55878CE2C6C64F2881307A66DC23EC65"><enum>(B)</enum><text>If, in the course of an enforcement action that is not initiated at or focused on a sensitive location, individuals referred to in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (1) are led to or near a sensitive location, and no clear exigent circumstance with respect to the sensitive location exists, such individuals shall—</text><clause id="H65ED0D5DA3CF4C72AC809976932AB9AB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>cease before taking any further enforcement action;</text></clause><clause id="H28A2AF536A7C4FCE8571DBCE9556BEC8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>conduct themselves in a discreet manner;</text></clause><clause id="H76DBC0C5708E4357BC0EAD7E6A0B042E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>maintain surveillance; and</text></clause><clause id="HD48F9670220243C3A294737FA699E258"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>in the event that uncertainty exists about the existence of exigent circumstances, immediately consult their supervisor in order to determine whether such enforcement action should be discontinued pursuant to paragraph (2)(C).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB5515A4B72EE46719C634E8D242E89D3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>This subsection shall not apply to the transportation of an individual apprehended at or near a land or sea border to a hospital or health care provider for the purpose of providing such individual medical care.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H780D3F495D6F4D3EB9C99229AA61B50C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>This subsection shall not apply to a rare premeditated arrest operation, undertaken with the prior written approval of an appropriate authorizing official, involving the targeted arrest of a terrorist suspect, an individual who poses a clear threat to national security, or an individual who poses an extraordinary danger to public safety.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD4F4305A56C4412FAB657100433E3B71" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>If an enforcement action is carried out in violation of this subsection—</text><subparagraph id="H6BCD0B1A39864D77B54E967032FDBFA7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>no information resulting from the enforcement action may be entered into the record or received into evidence in a removal proceeding resulting from the enforcement action; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF594734FB9D84156A759105E0FB2D59B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the alien who is the subject of such removal proceeding may file a motion for the immediate termination of the removal proceeding.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7B1EEAEF1BE94962BCA6A6F6117630D9" indent="up1"><enum>(5)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H67CFBE1D824E46DDA01FB86521597076"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Each official specified in subparagraph (B) shall ensure that the employees under the supervision of such official receive annual training in compliance with the requirements of this subsection, section 239, and section 384 of the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1367">8 U.S.C. 1367</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7937192D45CF4F60AFC1AD8540B714D7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The officials specified in this subparagraph are the following:</text><clause id="H14CDE431D56D4123A81A68051CCB07AD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The Chief Counsel of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement.</text></clause><clause id="H6F73706E66BF4247B146D61E5FF6728C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The Field Office Directors of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement.</text></clause><clause id="H144FCA1ADF074B9DB956DB1E470EDAAD"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Each Special Agent in Charge of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement.</text></clause><clause id="H84522CD633DB4322BFACA087129CB6E6"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Each Chief Patrol Agent of U.S. Customs and Border Protection.</text></clause><clause id="HB7CB01BFDC3A458DA3F33FA43E23495B"><enum>(v)</enum><text>The Director of Field Operations of U.S. Customs and Border Protection.</text></clause><clause id="H60E6A32EF53242CD8AD933BB2A2BD8F6"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>The Director of Air and Marine Operations of U.S. Customs and Border Protection.</text></clause><clause id="H4A5607BD703E4D1DB21315531DC5B320"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>The Internal Affairs Special Agent in Charge of U.S. Customs and Border Protection.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H09A4D31470924090BFDC347A2F608EFB" indent="up1"><enum>(6)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H5578F054BB1F4244A48F59AECAFC1115"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Not later than 30 days after any enforcement action is taken at a sensitive location by any individual referred to in subparagraph (A) or (B) of paragraph (1), the Secretary of Homeland Security shall provide a report to both the Office of the Inspector General of the Department of Homeland Security and the Office for Civil Rights and Civil Liberties of the Department of Homeland Security for each of these individual enforcement actions, which shall contain the following information:</text><clause id="H02065FF84B834D18AF6A93A23D33ACFC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The date, State, and local political subdivision (such as city, town, or county) in which each enforcement action occurred.</text></clause><clause id="H6BA75459A37D47C18721B2F3A2614FC7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The specific sensitive location site where the enforcement action occurred.</text></clause><clause id="HAE879267644240E38C771DE5A389F345"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The type of enforcement action that occurred.</text></clause><clause id="H7CDA1ED094C74581A03F3C831F4E7318"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The specific department, agency, and officers responsible for the enforcement action.</text></clause><clause id="HC4AC232C1CD84C4B8AB58EED03C84B79"><enum>(v)</enum><text>A thorough description of the circumstances which purportedly justified the enforcement action, including either—</text><subclause id="H0DAA752005C94B6080F599DDFB665E00"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a clear description of the exigent circumstances involved; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H326D554CA1B7440E8BBC2939C55B8D60"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a certified copy of the written approval for the immigration arrest that was signed by an appropriate authorizing officer, along with a clear description of the specific and rare threat which justified the premediated arrest at this sensitive location.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H4762620AB5D14042A087CCEEADF359B1"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>A description of the intended target of the enforcement action.</text></clause><clause id="H19B1C4E4CF774307B1EFDDCF597FE630"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>The number of individuals, if any, arrested or taken into custody through the enforcement action.</text></clause><clause id="H063467643AD944A99490875C0CAF775A"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>The number of collateral arrests, if any, from the enforcement action and the reasons for each such arrest.</text></clause><clause id="H48E450C2E38C4D5495DC57B8273D456E"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>A certification of whether a supervisor was contacted prior to, during, or after each such enforcement action.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H41A7095FF1BA406D899A2613A29580E7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An appropriate committee of Congress shall, at any time, be able to request and successfully receive a confidential or redacted copy of one of the individual reports described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2719CD91F3954CFCB42BFB2712316FF4" indent="up1"><enum>(7)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H5D5339253D7C4B3A860E5FD1CF2FB632"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Director of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement and the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection shall each submit to the appropriate committees of Congress each year a report on the enforcement actions undertaken by U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement and U.S. Customs and Border Protection, respectively, during the preceding year that were covered by this subsection.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H10B52056DC034E12A05171B09707B504"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Each report on an agency for a year under this paragraph shall set forth the following:</text><clause id="H7EB98CBEF23A43AF9F3B912C80A9C7B3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The number of enforcement actions at or focused on a sensitive location.</text></clause><clause id="HB8B5DD283E8743F1B646937DFB550F99"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The number of enforcement actions where officers or agents were subsequently led to or near a sensitive location.</text></clause><clause id="H3FC8D05E46034F3BADE62EAEDFDBFCCC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The date, site, State, and local political subdivision (such as city, town, or county) in which each enforcement action covered by clause (i) or (ii) occurred.</text></clause><clause id="H72DE697CBF5D4ADF8F179A1D6F04EC33"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The component of the agency responsible for each such enforcement action.</text></clause><clause id="H6275E3C975514BD89CE0AA2FF4121A2E"><enum>(v)</enum><text>A description of the intended target of each such enforcement action.</text></clause><clause id="HC4E2F9294DF54B72960338227CD7BA3A"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>The number of individuals, if any, arrested or taken into custody through each such enforcement action.</text></clause><clause id="HBF38209543D54A54BF85787ABB966E9F"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>The number of collateral arrests, if any, from each such enforcement action and the reasons for each such arrest.</text></clause><clause id="H25F329387D724F56BA8CC5A51FE30A0F"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>A certification of whether the location administrator was contacted prior to, during, or after each such enforcement action.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC5CC0EDDFF67499C83290458CCD1624F" indent="up1"><enum>(8)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H10F9973AC4DC4237AF0235FA8B984B8D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Office of the Inspector General of the Department of Homeland Security shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress each year a report on the complaints of enforcement actions taken in sensitive locations by U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement and U.S. Customs and Border Protection during the preceding year that were covered by this subsection.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H928611CA37D94B3A80A5B18355D661F7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Each report for a year under this paragraph shall set forth the following:</text><clause id="H28FD1FD737494CEE8B9E9D1324E1830F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The number of complaints of enforcement actions reported at or focused on a sensitive location.</text></clause><clause id="HA797B7643FB44CB782E3981BCD20C35C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The reported date, site, State, and local political subdivision (such as city, town, or county) in which each enforcement action covered was by clause (i) occurred.</text></clause><clause id="HFB6157DFE8094299B3626AC9B6785EF4"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The reported agency responsible for each such enforcement action.</text></clause><clause id="H22B227BF191F4482AA4074DD9546206A"><enum>(v)</enum><text>A description of the intended target of each such enforcement action.</text></clause><clause id="HBC7EC8BEF6AB4B26B9EAAD9D7190B811"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>The reported number of individuals, if any, arrested or taken into custody through each such enforcement action.</text></clause><clause id="H096F9B0A01934CAD9F9D6FDAA241D9BA"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>The reported number of collateral arrests, if any, from each such enforcement action and the reasons for each such arrest.</text></clause><clause id="H0046FA391A7D459E96E60D694494419F"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>If available, a certification of whether the location administrator was contacted prior to, during, or after each such enforcement action.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDE19FB510D6A442781B184BAFDDC9F1F" indent="up1"><enum>(9)</enum><text>In this subsection:</text><subparagraph id="H984C47E7F253416FB301BB859A0A25CC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The term <quote>appropriate authorizing official</quote> means the following:</text><clause id="H2938C9DA757144EF96A3CC9B098F0E29"><enum>(i)</enum><text>In the case of officers and agents of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement, one of the following officials:</text><subclause id="HD0309053DB49431BB849D0BE6BA66341"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The Assistant Director of Operations, Homeland Security Investigations.</text></subclause><subclause id="HCD97EE293CA643C3A05F07562E8835B6"><enum>(II)</enum><text>The Executive Associate Director of Homeland Security Investigations.</text></subclause><subclause id="H41A2E5A3C2184BF892C7CDF897FE33C3"><enum>(III)</enum><text>The Assistant Director for Field Operations, Enforcement, and Removal Operations.</text></subclause><subclause id="H19DF8EA4ACC548E7A45BE2B691A04B77"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>The Executive Associate Director for Field Operations, Enforcement, and Removal Operations.</text></subclause><subclause id="HEC3A956E58DC4B9895E7CB3C79BE65DF"><enum>(V)</enum><text>Any other individual who is determined to be an appropriate authorizing official by the Secretary of Homeland Security.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HBBC16E646E044847B5535ACDFF2B8319"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>In the case of officers and agents of U.S. Customs and Border Protection, one of the following officials:</text><subclause id="HFDB040516EE54C45BE98A81FD90DC7C0"><enum>(I)</enum><text>A Chief Patrol Agent.</text></subclause><subclause id="H6C80C177FEC649FF9DA4408F3909C0EA"><enum>(II)</enum><text>The Director of Field Operations.</text></subclause><subclause id="HBEC86AB3F96843D2BC770939A7CC96F1"><enum>(III)</enum><text>The Director of Air and Marine Operations.</text></subclause><subclause id="H98F5BA3786F84DBD85FBEA4BF0FBAB34"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>The Internal Affairs Special Agent in Charge.</text></subclause><subclause id="H1E02AB65F8574E5E9A347E3ABA62214F"><enum>(V)</enum><text>Any other individual who is determined to be an appropriate authorizing official by the Secretary of Homeland Security.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H4CB1B3D7EA63420DA056E8CA29214E06"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>In the case of all other individuals referred to in subparagraph (A) or (B) of paragraph (1), an official determined under rules promulgated by the Secretary of Homeland Security not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this subsection.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3E321A3A153049C7AE317D416CEED8FF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The term <quote>appropriate committees of Congress</quote> means—</text><clause id="HFF89DA3564CB454296EEEDFE25FB1C2B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate;</text></clause><clause id="HD7A16FE1D49E4666AFBE2460D3276518"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate;</text></clause><clause id="HD8A1D791C57442FD9C12B6A506535EAA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate;</text></clause><clause id="H42AC6F6A7E4D4AF2872B8F5EA28FCF7A"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives;</text></clause><clause id="H807AFBD5FCEC4EA799B78FA71F0B8479"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives; and</text></clause><clause id="H47E267F5E7C0491E882667705DBDFB60"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE1828BE71F3B40FD86252B5BB0170C3B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The term <quote>early childhood education program</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 103 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1003">20 U.S.C. 1003</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB0355ED52F4240C9ADB40E4BCF1B8523"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The term <quote>enforcement action</quote> means an apprehension, arrest, interview, request for identification, search, or surveillance for the purposes of immigration enforcement, and includes an enforcement action at, or focused on, a sensitive location that is part of a joint case led by another law enforcement agency.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5B232EC35C594D09B9294D202D40CD3B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The term <quote>exigent circumstances</quote> means a situation involving any of the following:</text><clause id="H5703B39680C34A4BAD3DD944ABBD4A12"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The imminent risk of death, violence, or physical harm to any person, including a situation implicating terrorism or the national security of the United States in some other manner.</text></clause><clause id="H06D4505378034584BBD0131B4A7C9DBA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The immediate arrest or hot pursuit of an individual presenting an imminent danger to public safety, including the imminent risk of death, violence, or physical harm to a person.</text></clause><clause id="H6945E0EC919944DCADD1D74F572EA2BB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>A rare, premeditated arrest operation described in paragraph (3)(D), undertaken with the prior written approval of an appropriate authorizing official, involving the targeted arrest of a terrorist suspect, an individual who poses a clear threat to national security, or an individual who poses an extraordinary danger to public safety.</text></clause><clause id="H8D34DF64C5784AAC8F390CFB0820EF03"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>A direct threat to national security.</text></clause><clause id="H87D7D26D17ED402EB1F37E00DA33EED0"><enum>(v)</enum><text>The imminent risk of destruction of evidence that is material to an ongoing criminal case.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF456474248AC4056ABB6CAF851833673"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The term <quote>sensitive location</quote> includes all of the physical space located within 1,000 feet of the following:</text><clause id="H69593BD699CC4384865D29355FB56D58"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Any medical or mental healthcare facility, including any hospital, health care practitioner’s office, accredited health clinic, vaccination or testing site, or emergent or urgent care facility, or community health center.</text></clause><clause id="H548B4233DB2A4027A6C221193AB2C642"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Public and private schools (including preschools, primary schools, secondary schools, and postsecondary schools (including colleges and universities)), sites of early childhood education programs, other institutions of learning, such as vocational or trade schools, and other sites where individuals who are unemployed or underemployed may apply for or receive workforce training.</text></clause><clause id="HA86C970A43404D68A1956B4D590B72BD"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Any scholastic or education-related activity or event, including field trips and interscholastic events.</text></clause><clause id="H4DF407537C3A4FF1953D2D14C73A9777"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Any school bus or school bus stop during periods when school children are present on the bus or at the stop.</text></clause><clause id="H680C4DAAA375493695293BE7314671A7"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Any recreational facility for children such as playgrounds and formal recreational facilities.</text></clause><clause id="H0E5C732F85774433BE346E10AF8F86B2"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Any child care focused facilities including child care centers, before or after school care centers, foster care facilities, and group homes for children.</text></clause><clause id="H0A2F486681854DA38399FA021D25557C"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Locations where disaster or emergency response and relief is being provided by Federal, State, or local entities, such as the distribution of emergency supplies, food, and water; places of temporary shelter; along evacuation routes; and sites where registration for disaster-related assistance or family reunification is underway.</text></clause><clause id="H2F653670B9D844D6882C503D97F53DCB"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Locations of any organization that—</text><subclause id="H843EC858D9504193A1AB5CCDF64AF3B5"><enum>(I)</enum><text>assists children, pregnant women, victims of crime or abuse, or individuals with significant mental or physical disabilities, including domestic violence shelters, child advocacy centers, facilities that serve disabled persons, drug or alcohol counseling and treatment facilities, rape crisis centers, supervised visitation centers, family justice centers, victims’ services providers, and community-based organizations providing social services; or</text></subclause><subclause id="HCFB3F0A3591B43A69AF29142B94D2E6A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>provides disaster or emergency social services and assistance, or services for individuals experiencing homelessness, including food banks, pantries, or other establishments distributing food, and shelters.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H68F4990058B24C41BD60AE40B4126355"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>Churches, synagogues, mosques, and other places of worship or religious study, such as buildings rented for the purpose of religious services, or a temporary facility or location where such activities are taking place.</text></clause><clause id="H578C43201E8D46FD97526C555D13B8CD"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>Sites of funerals, graveside ceremonies, weddings, or sites where other religious or civil ceremonies or observances occur.</text></clause><clause id="HB4D038D8C1F742C682EC0B6021E53B10"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>Sites during the occurrence of a public demonstration, such as a march, rally, or parade.</text></clause><clause id="HBCFFECA4144A4AFF8B18251ABD2F85BF"><enum>(x)</enum><text>Any Federal, State, or local courthouse, including the office of an individual’s legal counsel or representative, and a probation office.</text></clause><clause id="HE102E60A9B4746C2B9FEAAD44E8982E8"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>Congressional district offices.</text></clause><clause id="H5FC5F8B6B28345B09917F7FA2413A8CE"><enum>(xii)</enum><text>Social Security offices.</text></clause><clause id="HB9B467C8DF6C4FEE959A5DFC4DFBBED8"><enum>(xiii)</enum><text>Public assistance offices, including locations where individuals may apply for or receive unemployment compensation or report violations of labor and employment laws.</text></clause><clause id="HAE5D4C8E26B646C5B1FA920526BEB56C"><enum>(xiv)</enum><text>Indoor and outdoor premises of departments of motor vehicles.</text></clause><clause id="H02767691467C4B08A3B38241604A7AA2"><enum>(xv)</enum><text>A polling place, which includes any building or infrastructure where voting takes place during an election.</text></clause><clause id="HEDAFB35E17734547A2D0D4EBAD4E7E87"><enum>(xvi)</enum><text>A labor union hall or any other union-operated building or office where registered applicants are referred in rotation to jobs.</text></clause><clause id="HDBCD96192B16486584C97BD389F1029D"><enum>(xvii)</enum><text>Any public library.</text></clause><clause id="H672862904F8444EC8D345C2BC6651727"><enum>(xviii)</enum><text>Such other locations as the Secretary of Homeland Security shall specify for purposes of this subsection.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3DA934C259FD49ADBBC0B5AEA81F278C"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The term <quote>supervisor</quote> means an official determined under rules promulgated by the Secretary of Homeland Security not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this subsection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H247C35F836C6433482082FB04512D851"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by subsection (a) shall take effect 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="HACE62E7E43A847F988A5D2199F12AAC4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall promulgate regulations to carry out the amendment made by subsection (a).</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

