<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H093FD2C7789049C3BBB8679D43A5057A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4891 IH: Secure Our Embassies Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4891</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250805">August 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To address the growing complexity of the threat environment at United States diplomatic posts.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H7B8E40B6BD6944E381A95569DF1E9A7F" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HC8CDCC611B67461590B60BA57D94A7F7" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Secure Our Embassies Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H46BAE57FC2AC496F8336195BFA7B8AC9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress—</text> <paragraph id="H5AA8E2E6252F46178B88C0FDD6E4F9AD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognizes the growing complexity of the threat environment at United States diplomatic posts and the critical need for seamless coordination among personnel responsible for information security, physical security, and facility operations;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H986759DB900A4253B4503406E760EE4F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>supports the Department of State’s efforts to strengthen coordination among Regional Security Officers (RSOs), Diplomatic Technology Officers (DTOs), Regional Security Engineering Officers (RSEOs), and personnel from the Bureau of Overseas Buildings Operations (OBO), particularly during the design, construction, and operations of overseas facilities;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD8557BA919514553A29ED0FB0C6811DF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>supports that Department of State personnel serving in these positions receive appropriate and role-specific counterintelligence (CI) and regional specific security training, which should address regional and functional threat vectors, as well as protocols for identifying and mitigating insider threats, foreign intelligence collection risks, and cyber vulnerabilities; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0655291934944FD991A06FDC42D2E04E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>supports the development of joint training modules or inter-bureau CI briefings to reinforce shared security responsibilities and to prevent siloed operational cultures.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H8C297D7DA295446A921625D30FADCBB3"><enum>3.</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall submit to Congress a report on actions the Secretary has taken and will take to improve coordination across the positions described in section 2 and to implement CI training standards for such positions. The report should include a description of current CI training requirements, planned improvements, and any resource needs to support implementation.</text> </section> 
</legis-body></bill>

