<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H49F3141CD498477CBC13937FF0F8ECC3" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 314 IH: Of inquiry requesting the President and directing the Secretary of Health and Human Services to transmit, respectively, certain documents to the House of Representatives relating to the effect on taxpayer and child privacy of the seizure by the so-called “Department of Government Efficiency” of legally-protected identity and financial data stored in the National Directory of New Hires and the Federal Parent Locator Service.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 314</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250409">April 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Davis of Illinois</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="N000015">Mr. Neal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000399">Mr. Doggett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000557">Mr. Larson of Connecticut</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001156">Ms. S&#225;nchez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001296">Mr. Boyle of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001190">Mr. Schneider</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000585">Mr. Gomez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001066">Mr. Horsford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000610">Ms. Plaskett</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001201">Mr. Suozzi</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Of inquiry requesting the President and directing the Secretary of Health and Human Services to transmit, respectively, certain documents to the House of Representatives relating to the effect on taxpayer and child privacy of the seizure by the so-called <quote>Department of Government Efficiency</quote> of legally-protected identity and financial data stored in the National Directory of New Hires and the Federal Parent Locator Service.</official-title></form><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H98BAFDC554AA4D3FA602E01F83CB4E49"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HE5250302BE4345669E102434D73FD64C"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the President of the United States is requested, and the Secretary of Health and Human Services is directed, to transmit, to the extent that such documents are in the possession of the President or the Secretary, to the House of Representatives, not later than 14 days after the date of adoption of this resolution, copies of any document, record, audio recording, memorandum, call log, correspondence (electronic or otherwise), activity logs, audit trails, audit logs, written agreements, or other communication or any portion of any such communication, that refers or relates to the following:</text> <paragraph id="H48E0D5A762B64644A52B9B82E18CD9C2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Any request from the United States DOGE Service (commonly referred to as the <quote>Department of Government Efficiency</quote> or “DOGE”), and any authorization provided to DOGE, to access any information on any American worker which is protected under section 453 of the Social Security Act or <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6103">section 6103</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and stored in the National Database of New Hires (in this resolution referred to as <quote>NDNH</quote>). </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7397951663424601A14A0BC6994737FC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The location of, and data security protections applied to, any copies of all or part of the data made by DOGE employees. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2BEB47F23D9A40C0936BB77BAB3D0378"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Prior legal opinions or other internal communications regarding requests to access NDNH data for purposes not specified in such section 453 or without a negotiated memorandum of understanding setting forth conditions of access, limiting the number of individuals with access, or requiring training, background checks, and other qualifications for those individuals accessing the data.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAF7FEBC156094F0CA0CD072FE1538543"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Any request from DOGE for any confidential financial information or personally identifiable information of more than 40,000,000 Americans, including over 19,000,000 which is stored in the Federal Parent Locator Service (in this resolution referred to as <quote>FPLS</quote>), which is used to facilitate child support payments to children from non-custodial parents.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1CD5AC1A3F02452580F25B71DDF1CEF8"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Staff terminations, retirements, or resignations of employees of the Department of Health and Human Services with responsibilities related to the FPLS or the NDNH after the date of the first request by DOGE for information stored in the Federal Case Registry.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5F6BF5822968434A9597C817CF84FF0D"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Any attempt by DOGE employees to access information obtained pursuant to section 453(a)(2) of the Social Security Act.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution> 

