<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE68E5C5757E64AF5A7CD0BCFA8CEC05A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5151 IH: Quiet Communities Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5151</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250904">September 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001241">Mr. Min</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000593">Mr. Levin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000191">Mr. Neguse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001117">Mr. Casten</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001201">Mr. Suozzi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001112">Mr. Carbajal</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To reestablish the Office of Noise Abatement and Control in the Environmental Protection Agency, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H26317A24AE384E50808133576A05D454" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H3483938DF4C74E3185B418B7E2A47449"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Quiet Communities Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H04DD2BCA33CE4A27B2E4DC6D0FA51C1F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text>
<paragraph id="HEE0C6A93757449D78B06D46171B08949"><enum>(1)</enum><text>approximately 28,000,000 individuals in the United States are afflicted with some hearing impairment, and it has been estimated that 10,000,000 of those impairments are at least partially attributable to damage from exposure to noise;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4A3760358D1E4CDCB239D2D044C58E7C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for millions of individuals in the United States, noise from aircraft, vehicular traffic, and a variety of other sources is a constant source of torment;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC84B7304D88142B890116C8C16204329"><enum>(3)</enum><text>millions of individuals in the United States are exposed to noise levels that can lead to sleep loss, psychological and physiological damage, and work disruption;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7D6F1EFF654742B7ADE29983156366C9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>chronic exposure to noise has been linked to increased risk of cardiovascular disorders, learning deficits in children, stress, and diminished quality of life;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H38B749F0288E471BBF025C1C1F0C33B9"><enum>(5)</enum><text>excessive noise leading to sleep deprivation and task interruptions can result in untold costs to society as a result of diminished worker productivity;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2242740F1AAF4E00AB94981B4230BF3E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>pursuant to the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7401">42 U.S.C. 7401 et seq.</external-xref>), the Noise Control Act of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4901">42 U.S.C. 4901 et seq.</external-xref>), and the Quiet Communities Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4901">42 U.S.C. 4901</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/95/609">Public Law 95–609</external-xref>; 92 Stat. 3079), the Environmental Protection Agency established and maintained an Office of Noise Abatement and Control, which has not received funding since 1982;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HEDB29C3580BE4E4AA21847BFCDB91A5E"><enum>(7)</enum><text>responsibilities of the Office of Noise Abatement and Control included promulgating noise emission standards, requiring product labeling, facilitating the development of low-noise-emission products, coordinating Federal noise reduction programs, assisting State and local noise abatement efforts, and promoting noise education and research;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H151DA20EC92E4786A229959E8C7DEBD4"><enum>(8)</enum><text>because the Environmental Protection Agency remains legally responsible for enforcing regulations issued under the Noise Control Act of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4901">42 U.S.C. 4901 et seq.</external-xref>), even though funding for the activities of the Office of Noise Abatement and Control described in paragraph (7) was terminated, and because that Act prohibits State and local governments from regulating noise sources in many situations, noise abatement programs across the United States lie dormant; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5E84E342B99845B483993FEAD7324DF9"><enum>(9)</enum><text>as population growth and air and vehicular traffic continue to increase, noise pollution is likely to become an even greater problem in the future, and the health and welfare of individuals in the United States demands that the Environmental Protection Agency, the lead Federal agency for the protection of public health and welfare, once again assume a role in combating noise pollution.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H37CC072213814E67BA76B4B416421620"><enum>3.</enum><header>Reestablishment of Office of Noise Abatement and Control</header> <subsection id="H70FE2C33B87149AD9D747C301E4E4839"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reestablishment</header><text>The Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (referred to in this section as the <quote>Administrator</quote>) shall reestablish within the Environmental Protection Agency an Office of Noise Abatement and Control (referred to in this section as the <quote>Office</quote>).</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H12E458D315F6458E9D174458AF33002D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The responsibilities of the Office shall include—</text> <paragraph id="H5714D5ADA5D54FA3B635C5BD10762EB3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>promoting the development of effective State and local noise control programs by providing States with technical assistance and grants to develop those programs, including the purchasing of equipment for local communities;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HAB756FF40A8542639BE344D290614EE3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>carrying out a national noise control research program to assess the impacts of noise from varied noise sources on mental and physical health;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC24429D26A7C4EE29C2D2E34D4E28539"><enum>(3)</enum><text>carrying out a national noise environmental assessment program—</text>
<subparagraph id="H9F342B744E1947AD9D9ACBF0207CCC44"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to identify trends in noise exposure and response, ambient levels, and compliance data; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H18E0236ED76D448B87D25EE5946DC82F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to determine the effectiveness of noise abatement actions, including actions for areas around major transportation facilities (such as highways, railroad facilities, and airports);</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF503B2CBE00D4CF3A4C770A52B411F57"><enum>(4)</enum><text>developing and disseminating to the public information and educational materials relating to the mental and physical effects of noise and the most effective means for noise control through the use of materials for school curricula, volunteer organizations, radio and television programs, publications, and other means;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7C8CA5F1974F44DA958FBE1BACB95C49"><enum>(5)</enum><text>developing educational and training materials and programs, including national and regional workshops, to support State and local noise abatement and control programs;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H280F45FF02164D58926530C028177A7B"><enum>(6)</enum><text>establishing regional technical assistance centers to use the capabilities of institutions of higher education and private organizations to assist State and local noise control programs; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1AEC664B2DFC4FCA93E2B2FEC01DB188"><enum>(7)</enum><text>undertaking an assessment of the effectiveness of the Noise Control Act of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4901">42 U.S.C. 4901 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HA727988FDD9B4B5A9016FAB45F83426A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Preferred Approaches</header><text>In carrying out the duties of the Office under subsection (b), the Office shall emphasize noise abatement approaches that rely on local and State activities, market incentives, and coordination with other public and private agencies.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HB0DA260374664C32A0751AEA4D4F202A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Study</header> <paragraph id="H72DE10482BDD40A3ABF480CF26121104"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator shall carry out a study of aircraft noise and the effects of that noise on surrounding communities.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB1873A944F8C4202A54058DDC09B2738"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contracts and other agreements</header><text>The Administrator shall enter into contracts or other agreements with independent scientists with expertise in noise measurements, noise effects, and noise abatement techniques to conduct the study under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD73CC3AFADC84F71A7048D99B1F4C3C6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The study under paragraph (1) shall examine—</text>
<subparagraph id="H4F12215D9F074534BD2956127DC43B98"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the selection of noise measurement methodologies by the Federal Aviation Administration;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H43B63460653B4CD19263CD803A1B1FE6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the threshold of aircraft noise at which health impacts are felt; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H69C309152C794672AB395166513CB5BA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the effectiveness of aircraft noise abatement programs at airports around the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7BB4077391B1426FA287321CE4F9B458"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Report</header> <subparagraph id="H4F86727EDE1741F8A3D71F1A60A6109E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall submit to Congress a report on the results of the study conducted under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H56B2876164644DF1A19F14A16418444D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The report submitted under subparagraph (A) shall include specific recommendations on new measures that can be implemented to mitigate the impact of aircraft noise on surrounding communities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H9BDB7FC10BEE4302B670C02E186FCE99"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>The Noise Pollution and Abatement Act of 1970 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/91/604">Public Law 91–604</external-xref>; 84 Stat. 1709) is repealed.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="HD8A45FEE8D3C47839A40EC039865DE33"><enum>4.</enum><header>Grants under Quiet Communities Program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 14 of the Noise Control Act of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4913">42 U.S.C. 4913</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H1820B657752647458BE2912C20B32FAB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text>
<subparagraph id="HE411AADEC0424A939E8CE361755247FD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the matter preceding paragraph (1) by striking <quote>but not limited to</quote>;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF676FB84F2BC428E8203C925828632D8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2) by striking <quote>sections 6, 7, and 8 of this Act</quote> and inserting <quote>section 6 or 8 of this Act, or section 44715 of title 49, United States Code</quote>; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD94F3C1C2797435E8E134EA9FFC1A026"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (1) through (5) as subparagraphs (A) through (E), respectively, and indenting appropriately;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H78657CD1537D439687D44C49156C6A01"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text>
<subparagraph id="H90B5EC5B85F1493F8F1F1A1E5EEA1DF5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the matter preceding paragraph (1) by striking <quote>but not be limited to</quote> and inserting <quote>in accordance with the Federal authority pursuant to this Act to regulate sources of noise in interstate commerce</quote>;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8AED6A691C1244E88A4472F9A503A352"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text>
<clause id="H079C6FA212254764862F6494C4536D13"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C) by striking <quote>and,</quote> at the end;</text></clause> <clause id="HE5F0F60156A045D6BCE953482948E3A0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (A) through (D) as clauses (i) through (iv), respectively, and indenting appropriately; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H74EF4454062E41E39836032D8D6826B7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H140C672D065A4630A3A492EF7CA83EC5"> <clause id="H4B141C5A7F604CB6B34FF155EA88AFAE"><enum>(v)</enum><text>establishing and implementing training programs on use of noise abatement equipment; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H4B9432C9828746199090411A61C5E7FB"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>implementing noise abatement plans;</text></clause><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCD363FBE5E5D45BFADC064ED76273651"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking the undesignated matter following paragraph (5); and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H5B248AB7E80D4D9A8606C1F79F972B1F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (1) through (5) as subparagraphs (A) through (E), respectively, and indenting appropriately; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5551D3F6F3E147D29C76D1E88F673878"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (a) through (g) as paragraphs (1) through (7), respectively, and indenting appropriately.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="HA3793DE399C64DCDBF3D1503B2EACD04"><enum>5.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated for the Office of Noise Abatement and Control reestablished under section 3(a) $25,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030.</text></section> </legis-body></bill>

