<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB3AE9F655C6444039F09F347BC0956CA" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5289 IH: Semiconductor Sovereignty Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5289</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250910">September 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000138">Mr. Vindman</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001219">Mr. Moylan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Commerce to submit reports on strategies regarding the manufacturing of, and research relating to, semiconductors and other similar technologies, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HCC5784379308421C96911BCC65BBCC1E" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H34B56331AA72466A99813E2D48856CB8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Semiconductor Sovereignty Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HA588CFDE9EF440F49F7649A6607213D4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Reports on strategies regarding the manufacturing of, and research relating to, semiconductors and other similar technologies</header> 
<subsection id="H7F085A216377407B8B5AF1F5AD1D0B0C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Initial report</header> 
<paragraph id="H2CC4227223554D8CA4AFC10DC93641A1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 240 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Commerce, acting through the Under Secretary of Commerce for Industry and Security, shall carry out the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H57B54BD5D7E2493A85CAEA6283C8FB64"><enum>(A)</enum><text>To the extent practicable, identify the following:</text> 
<clause id="HBFA98F9A46514F72A089D4A9868A37B1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The critical and foundational inputs for semiconductors and other similar technologies, including the following:</text> <subclause id="HB788713DB9BA448082627A04231B297F" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Tools for the manufacturing of, and research relating to, such semiconductors and technologies, including the following:</text> 
<item id="HF0BF34AFA05E42638B63FC500F17574A"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>Equipment for photolithography, including photomasks.</text></item> <item id="H83AB2567FD2647AA95C3EA67E7090B91"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>Software.</text></item></subclause> 
<subclause id="H8D9B140380EF4D0DA7E947934C67448B"><enum>(II)</enum><text>The processes for such manufacturing and research, including the following:</text> <item id="H7D2A3BCD6B2D4F1289DEC6AB56C50797"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>Designing.</text></item> 
<item id="HE9E91C80D85E4ABC82C381292F292612"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>Packaging.</text></item></subclause> <subclause id="HC5A0B240E13E4686A4165F4F236B745C"><enum>(III)</enum><text>The minerals, gases, and other chemical substances utilized in such manufacturing and research.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H7F3FE9F92058463382FBE01492B94CF1"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>The supply chains for such minerals, gases, and substances.</text></subclause> </clause> <clause id="H9689CC69D2CC410E9E6BBCFD1AE736F0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The trends with respect to the following:</text> 
<subclause id="H5EACE42D015F497DBC5DAD64A4F7A678"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The offshoring of such manufacturing and research from January 1, 1990, to such date of enactment.</text></subclause> <subclause id="H923E18B06562477FA2C827813E147C1F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>Any reshoring of such offshored manufacturing and research.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H5262536C171D4D2C8D5D3704588A7D50"><enum>(III)</enum><text>Partnerships between domestic entities and foreign entities for such inputs.</text></subclause> <subclause id="HCAC6A7F775B848B2AF87ECC64DB0273A"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>Investments by such entities for the domestic manufacturing of, and research relating to, such semiconductors and technologies.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H2968A4B888B94C689A48A26D4019F50B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each location to which such manufacturing and research is being offshored.</text></clause> <clause id="HCA962F1568AA4A628F9AEEA3DFD3E611"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The bottlenecks with respect to the following:</text> 
<subclause id="H6E7B9FC9AA5C4EEB90B738EE14615E60"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Such manufacturing and research.</text></subclause> <subclause id="HEAFBA3313D2D41838165FE8CCF9BE6F3"><enum>(II)</enum><text>The international trade of such semiconductors and technologies.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="HDC27010299F44E918FC52DE07FF172D5"><enum>(v)</enum><text>The role of foreign nationals who receive in the United States an education or work experience in the manufacturing of, and research relating to, such semiconductors and technologies, and subsequently work for foreign entities, including adversaries of the United States, in fields relating to such semiconductors and technologies.</text></clause> <clause id="H552513D8816040A4A16A64D8C33F54CC"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>The role of private sector officials and public sector officials who are American and work for such foreign entities.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HED3416AF34D643B78B723DAA149160A9"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>The domestic assets, including intellectual property, for such manufacturing and research that such foreign entities have acquired, including by means of a bankruptcy.</text></clause> <clause id="H7500224F687240409F535B4CC2EA14E0"><enum>(viii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The domestic entities and foreign entities that have received funding or other incentives from the Federal Government, including by means of the CHIPS Act of 2022 (division A of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/167">Public Law 117–167</external-xref>), for the domestic manufacturing of, and research relating to, such semiconductors and technologies and, subsequent to such receipt, have engaged in the offshoring of such manufacturing and research.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAAFAD8519C5F48FD982292B68868B988"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Based upon such identifications, determine the trends in such offshore manufacturing and research from such date of enactment to a date that is not earlier than 30 years after such date of enactment.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2198583C956544D3954AA8B88783220F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Conduct an assessment of the implications to or on, as the case may be, the following as a result of such offshore manufacturing and research:</text> 
<clause id="H6C8E2D98D7D948D9AC551A65B94B89A1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The national economy.</text></clause> <clause id="H7CCE5C00058747309D6AA57FB7E4AF16"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>National security.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H08498585EC9F4BF989CD9ABB02F1F7D7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The supply chains of the United States for such semiconductors and technologies.</text></clause> <clause id="H05969741E7654AC4AB98C6950912A3AB"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Allies and partners of the United States.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HB1D6E645C91545839671F6E059B3648B"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Adversaries of the United States, including the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea, the Islamic Republic of Iran, the People’s Republic of China, and the Russian Federation, and the proxies of such adversaries.</text></clause> <clause id="H542E60C5AFA44EB6A8C96E0062094B1E"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Geopolitically vulnerable markets, including Taiwan.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6A8308B92CE046FC8610B178B19602ED"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Based upon such determination and assessments, identify and, as appropriate, recommend strategies for the following:</text> <clause id="HEA3A48EF42E24EEB9C0027612C7F1ED3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Disincentivizing such offshore manufacturing and research.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H6A5E099ED3FF47C2BEEFB949E5C52170"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Increasing, including by means of tax incentives, subsidies, and the attraction and retention of foreign human capital, the domestic manufacturing of, and research relating to, such semiconductors and technologies.</text></clause> <clause id="H0DAF934321A34694B59DCFF7AB8D0E3A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Strengthening the long-term competitiveness of the United States with respect to such semiconductors and technologies as a result of so increasing such domestic manufacturing and research.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H53EDD82AADE345FF83D0A53AACC4A180"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Strengthening governmental oversight of acquisitions described in subparagraph (A)(vii).</text></clause> <clause id="HBCED98B61E5D4EA293AF24E85FBA090A"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Reducing the incidence of such acquisitions.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H61F9CB6857E34F1BBFC964EA561FDDEE"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Submit to Congress and publish in the Federal Register a report that includes information relating to the following:</text> <clause id="H59D9DEA125EC4DF0A2A19D37BF7B02CC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The determination made pursuant to subparagraph (B).</text></clause> 
<clause id="H51BDE5019FB5408CB79ABC3B919DAE68"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The assessments conducted pursuant to subparagraph (C).</text></clause> <clause id="HA75DFDF2C6644CA98C7131A64FC7EA38"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Each strategy identified pursuant to subparagraph (D).</text></clause> 
<clause id="H41559E40F6E54D5D955D972D39945197"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Each strategy recommended pursuant to such subparagraph and, for each such strategy, recommendations on policy to implement such strategy.</text></clause> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H53E112F32F004AEAA33612C970527EDA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>The Secretary of Commerce may not include in the report under paragraph (1) personally identifiable information of the foreign nationals described in subparagraph (A)(v) of such paragraph or the officials described in subparagraph (A)(vi) of such paragraph.</text></paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H92A81EDC443E4A8E9CF2CB1086A52532"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Subsequent reports</header> 
<paragraph id="HA95C92B90EFB49D4806057102488F5A3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the report under subsection (a) is submitted and annually thereafter, the Secretary of Commerce, acting through the Under Secretary of Commerce for Industry and Security, shall determine whether the strategies submitted in such report are outdated.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCC1567FC47F74199972DE31DB6061420"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Updated strategies</header><text>If the Secretary of Commerce, pursuant to paragraph (1) or (3), as the case may be, makes a determination in the affirmative pursuant to either of such paragraphs, the Secretary shall submit to Congress and publish in the Federal Register a report that includes information relating to updated strategies.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB426C376A2294C08BD28978FF0A7E6B9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Further determinations</header><text>If a report is submitted pursuant to paragraph (2), the Secretary of Commerce, not later than one year after such submission and annually thereafter, shall make a determination described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H087565BC17B64EB690AA92AD7A80153B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out this section, the Secretary of Commerce, acting through the Under Secretary of Commerce for Industry and Security, shall consult with the heads of other Federal agencies and departments, as appropriate.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H3031CEF334E34FDEA88DE88A5B9E6B04"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Foreign entity defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>foreign entity</term> means a corporation, partnership, or other entity that satisfies any of the following requirements:</text> <paragraph id="HA9FF17B6206A48E5A273DB6899D0D5C0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Is organized under the laws of a foreign country.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H99418E21EF9146449DBBFD14D6D698DA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Has a principal place of business located outside of the United States.</text> </paragraph></subsection> </section> </legis-body></bill>

