<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HAC863C04B94B45178E24DA2A00B78E36" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3184 IH: Protecting Firefighters and Advancing State-of-the-Art Alternatives Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3184</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250505">May 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="G000546">Mr. Graves</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000398">Mr. Kean</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="I000058">Mr. Ivey</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000467">Mr. Thompson of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To drive innovation in developing next-generation protection for firefighters by accelerating the development of PFAS-free turnout gear, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H84F63EDD474B4D36B194D46072D5F6A4" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H9C838F9C950145C1A2C579A28A50CEBC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting Firefighters and Advancing State-of-the-Art Alternatives Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>PFAS Alternatives Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H86EFAAE3A00A4628A42E7B7CDFE1ED35"><enum>2.</enum><header>Preventing occupational illness and injury by expanding the availability of next-generation turnout gear</header> <subsection id="H9E28529E50AA4F29AD48B097E9309E15"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H740A8E58D9524DFF9DFEC66CAC57BF96" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <quote>eligible entity</quote> means a nonprofit organization, institution of higher education, national fire service organization, or national fire safety organization, as determined by the Secretary, with experience in not fewer than three of the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H0D8578FEF4044752BB9E630D47101AB8" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Conducting research on issues related to cancer and other occupational illnesses among firefighters.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDCD44ABF3DC7461E843303D1510CF0F8" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Educating firefighters and other users of turnout gear on safe use, cleaning, and decontamination of turnout gear.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD050E8A4F38F49A194F5771A5DBBEAF9" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Educating firefighters on matters related to physical health, safety, and wellness.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD4E20154E3DF4F529AEFC0C69F101919" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Experience collaborating with other national nonprofit organizations to support research on firefighter safety and health.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0CEEAE91B25640548A4FB00F44FE11FB" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Demonstrated ability to collaborate with researchers on matters related to firefighter health and safety.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H565D8FB6726F44118F4EC309E64AB3CE" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Representing membership comprised of structural, wildfire, and aircraft firefighters and supervisors.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H37C8B751F78F43F7BD3C4CC6CAF5AB6F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Moisture barrier materials</header><text>The term <quote>moisture barrier material</quote> means the component of turnout gear that principally prevents the transfer of hazardous liquids, including hot liquids, fireground chemicals, and infectious fluids, and contributes to the overall thermal insulation of the firefighter without imposing undue burdens or otherwise compromising the performance of turnout gear.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H44D0213D2BF64B769BA22EC7BE561A0D" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>PFAS</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>PFAS</quote> means per- and polyfluoroalkyl substances that contain at least one fully fluorinated carbon atom or any other substance the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H234B377061AF498C9208268E164C2582"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H011A6823B1A6420B93AF27501A75481B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Turnout gear</header><text>The term <quote>turnout gear</quote> means protective clothing worn as a main source of protection for firefighters and emergency medical services personnel during firefighting and post-fire operations to minimize exposure to hazards that cause serious injuries and illnesses that may result from contact with thermal, physical, chemical, biological, or other workplace hazards. Turnout gear—</text> <subparagraph id="HBD3032C7C38147B0BF3EE12E5F398835"><enum>(A)</enum><text>includes protective clothing designed to protect firefighters performing structural firefighting, proximity firefighting, wildland firefighting, and urban interface firefighting; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC53F6CD686604BCFA007F0B789DB5B6F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may also include other personal protective equipment referred to in section 33(c)(3)(I)(i) of the Federal Fire Prevention and Control Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/2229">15 U.S.C. 2229(c)(3)(I)(i)</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H8C0498F22AF34BBB98BAB75ACB8F1F8A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Research programs</header> <paragraph id="H5E8E00CF7614405A8738379D2F3AB2DA" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to the availability of appropriations, not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Director of the National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health, in consultation with the heads of other Federal agencies as appropriate, shall establish a program to award grants to eligible entities to support research, development, and testing of next-generation turnout gear and associated materials.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7BC36406903B478D82F77CE3D54F8322"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header> 
<subparagraph id="H8B2E5D27D60B4AAA8EDAC0735951EF16"><enum>(A)</enum><header>PFAS-free components</header><text>Grants awarded under this subsection shall support the research, development, and testing of materials to design and produce PFAS-free turnout gear.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB865340C37674A7DBB98405173A44116" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Partnership</header><text>The Secretary shall require that applications for grants under this subsection include a description of how the eligible entity will partner with organizations in, and relevant to, the firefighting industry, including organizations that directly represent members who serve in nonmanagerial firefighting roles, and how such partnership will help move the results of research, development, and testing described in subparagraph (A) into practice, including guidance and training for first responders and others who regularly use turnout gear.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5B0A3F746CAE4CC5A7BD827092846378" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In making awards under this subsection, the Secretary may consider the extent to which the activities proposed support the research, development, and testing described in subparagraph (A) that is likely to prevent occupational illness and injury for firefighters, including innovations that provide the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H32CC919C78AA47D6A46AB5DEAA8F4182" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Enhanced protection against primary and secondary exposure to particulates and byproducts of combustion.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD6955C5E575440419C8DC5DF7E5646CA" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Reduced maintenance that includes contamination resistance and greater ease of cleaning or visible warning indicators to alert firefighters to hazardous exposures or the need for decontamination.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5E38CEDE4DBE41FD9E2076191EB6AEE0" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Consideration of body composition in development of prototypes and other products.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6B03CA3DB96C403890CA40248AEF608A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated $25,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2025 through fiscal year 2029 to carry out this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC651D798CCD842A6BD5BB5CCFC339D2B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Training programs</header> <paragraph id="HAB1C0A75FCE04175B8245AC89286661C" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to the availability of appropriations, the Secretary, beginning in fiscal year 2027, shall award grants to, or enter into contracts or cooperative agreements with, eligible entities, as determined by the Secretary, to develop and disseminate guidance and training for firefighters and other first responders on best practices for reducing potentially harmful exposures by safely wearing, decontaminating, and caring for turnout gear developed in accordance with section (b).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9BF340D0CB1448C6A481DC75FB0FB206"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated $2,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through fiscal year 2031 to carry out this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H3B7C5781DDFB452B8FF3B86EC0D13D10"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than two years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report describing the progress made in achieving the goals under subsections (b) and (c).</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

