<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-HEY25200-V3K-T5-NC3"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S926 IS: Saving Our Veterans Lives Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 926</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250311" legis-day="20250310">March 11 (legislative day, March 10), 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S363">Mr. King</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S435">Mr. Sheehy</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSVA00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend title 38, United States Code, to direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to establish a program to furnish to certain veterans items used for the secure storage of firearms, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Saving Our Veterans Lives Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idc2fd9c9a65f44d99819470c7c285f7ec"><enum>2.</enum><header>Program of Department of Veterans Affairs to furnish to certain veterans items used for secure storage of firearms</header><subsection id="idd239d881e86b412cb7c4b08f1cf60436"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Program</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id17559ac28b7044c687da031170930f8b"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/17">chapter 17</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id86c3d6e66ab7486a8d7bc7422b0ccb44"><section id="idae9b88d663534f74a21ad314627cb1a4"><enum>1720M.</enum><header>Program to furnish to eligible individuals items intended to be used for the secure storage of firearms</header><subsection id="id12ce54835f6148c18d311ccfea8df7e5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall carry out a program to provide to an eligible individual, upon the request of the eligible individual—</text><paragraph id="id8bf2a3549af34bebadba2aef02ddcb90"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a covered item or a redeemable voucher to aid in the distribution of a covered item; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id42a6ce6d2ffa48159f498e956be82abf"><enum>(2)</enum><text>information relating to the benefits of, and options for, secure firearm storage.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id40594ea84a194b3c933f230f9c948f02"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Distribution of covered items</header><text>In carrying out the program under subsection (a), the Secretary is authorized to work with organizations that have experience, expertise, and business knowledge regarding secure firearm storage and secure firearm storage devices.</text></subsection><subsection id="id34594fa1fd284e8ebc043e073050e26a"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Public education campaign</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb0c1153ad97e49918e56199360e2644b"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall design and carry out a public education campaign to inform eligible individuals of the availability of covered items under the program under subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0bcbf678cf29480392bf197f20407349"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Partnership</header><text>In carrying out the public education campaign required under paragraph (1), the Secretary may partner with organizations that have experience with respect to secure firearm storage devices.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc204377d911749f3bdd1793ebd690b1a" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Assurance about lawful ownership of firearms</header><text>The Secretary shall include in the public education campaign required under paragraph (1) material that assures eligible individuals that their participation in the program under subsection (a) does not impact lawful ownership of firearms. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id3b415d8c05f643998c3b2bb3e31bf852"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than October 1, 2025, and not less frequently than annually thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report that includes—</text><paragraph id="id689014b054d44452a741e20866e171e3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a description of the program under subsection (a) in a manner consistent with applicable law;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbc5a9f659a6e49c0bb41ac36108b44fd"><enum>(2)</enum><text>during the period covered by the report, the number of covered items distributed by the Veterans Health Administration and the number of covered items redeemed outside of the Veterans Health Administration under the program;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id34f7e6077f9a48f89c78282c328f9925"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an assessment of efforts made to increase outreach and distribution of covered items under the program to eligible individuals who are not enrolled in the system of annual patient enrollment of the Department established and operated under section 1705 of this title;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1898792af0de45c585fcff1ef3ab7636"><enum>(4)</enum><text>an assessment of any obstacles to increasing outreach to eligible individuals who are enrolled in such system and those who are not enrolled in such system; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id79165287c1f1497d8ba17fb8a1b5f731" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(5)</enum><text>an identification of additional steps that will be taken during the one-year period after the submission of the report to improve the processes through which eligible individuals receive a covered item under the program. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idf426615091844a9b808c8f0f430d11d6"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="id7573f35f36374eac8a28c79b11bb30f1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="id98ca99ab9ebc47c6a938fc12189453bc"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Veterans' Affairs and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1ad8c74068904d7789de3c2873429200"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Veterans' Affairs and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2df105c47b8243e4a50eb7855bdfe7b5"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered item</term> means a lockbox that—</text><subparagraph id="id155f328e22da48a79525934a5203758d"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is used for the secure storage of a firearm and ammunition;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id47e6cf2d02834406be1389c8017bf636"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is designed, intended, and marketed to prevent unauthorized access to a firearm or ammunition;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb1fabe26c0cc40b3bdae23656c7a44f2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>may be unlocked only by means of a key, combination, or other similar means;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2c4f616fd2ef4a8a87a3fe5e32d9a24a"><enum>(D)</enum><text>is in compliance with the standard of the American Society for Testing and Materials F2456–20, or any successor standard;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id25c68da63ff747f4a9a9c4d0f469ba94"><enum>(E)</enum><text>is manufactured in the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8f1800c409a8473d93959f83b3722686"><enum>(F)</enum><text>is not eligible or intended for commercial or individual resale.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="iddc6e43b5d3ae4eeb8db1f32e08ed33ba" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <term>eligible individual</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="idecd308340d1f4087a175d735e438aae8" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a veteran; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5f16a1a2a734491d8ff2127f7c04c385" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an individual described in section 1720I(b) of this title.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="id5298d66871ec4f668ae0ec15541189cd"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of such chapter is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 1720L the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="id29d9d2e3-c083-47ad-8cdd-0d404a07f9c4"><toc><toc-entry level="section" idref="idae9b88d663534f74a21ad314627cb1a4">1720M. Program to furnish to eligible individuals items intended to be used for the secure storage of firearms.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id9b84e54f9d3a4d399e2d4cc478db8096"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Education and training</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall—</text><paragraph id="iddbc22a6ea43641a7a3847a1d919b0fd5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in consultation with representatives of organizations and agencies that are subject to a memorandum of understanding with the Secretary on preventing veteran suicide and other such entities as the Secretary determines appropriate—</text><subparagraph id="id7ff76d9f9c5e4d48b568490c024055ef"><enum>(A)</enum><text>develop an informational video on secure storage of firearms as a suicide prevention strategy; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0f37133a47234ab0af0eb126d438c76e"><enum>(B)</enum><text>publish such informational video on an internet website of the Department of Veterans Affairs; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idbfcac9243aaf4614b7833c09c86c6084"><enum>(2)</enum><text>publish information to inform individuals who participate in the program under section 1720M of title 38, United States Code (as added by subsection (a)(1)) that any lockbox furnished pursuant to such program is not eligible or intended for commercial or individual resale.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id1642d388997946f59080a757bde66e68"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this Act or the amendments made by this Act may be construed—</text><paragraph id="idb8560ea6a5b744aea33ce4011274074f"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to collect personally identifiable information of an individual who participates in the program under section 1720M of title 38, United States Code (as added by subsection (a)(1)) for the purposes of tracking firearm ownership;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id522c5fcdc9df42f1b16a9b5a08750fbd"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to require any such individual to register a firearm with the Department of Veterans Affairs, or any other Federal, State, Tribal, or local unit of government;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc746439a53f14487859dc944286b8b78"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to require mandatory firearm storage for any such individual;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7bd7e5c7b760407aa8847bb5628a753d"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to prohibit any such individual from purchasing, owning, or possessing a firearm under section 922 of title 18, United States Code;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id03e8ed442ca64c7f929f2e00ea17d0b8"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to discourage the lawful ownership of firearms; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4417004db3914656a80c022f17d8986b"><enum>(6)</enum><text>to create or maintain a list of individuals participating in such program.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id2b881245c9b24ba9a9f2c66143efd371"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs $5,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2036 to carry out this section and the amendments made by this section. </text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

