<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-RIL25459-915-HM-D8M"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1654 IS: Safe and Private Rides Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1654</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250507">May 7, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S422">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require transportation network companies to provide customers notice when a driver has a camera in their motor vehicle and provide customers an opportunity to opt out of riding in motor vehicles with cameras, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H3A6D103EB6D340018B0FBB6A15721946"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Safe and Private Rides Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfe2ad88ccd8e4b88b36e9878c0900ace"><enum>2.</enum><header>Requirements for transportation network companies pertaining to cameras in motor vehicles</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id837112cb7c144dfe9458ede7bb534aba"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Registering requirement, notice and opportunity To opt out of riding in cars with cameras, and restriction on use of passenger recording</header><text>A transportation network company shall—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1be2e01d50764413ac82272f99de7811"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for the purpose of enabling the notification described in paragraph (2), require each driver affiliated with the transportation network company to register with such company any camera in the motor vehicle of the driver that records video images of passengers; </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0ae436eb5ae44e549feeeb8f6278d417"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">notify each passenger of each camera registered with the transportation network company;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7c7b73d77db64e88824efd346ef7d084"><enum>(3)</enum><text>develop and implement a process to address any violation of the requirement under paragraph (1); </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7ca69061050a4ef9a6a5f437ba46d3a7"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide any customer of the transportation network company with—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id77fcd713fe9d4f27a963c6275c97e913"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a clear and prominent notice on the application of the transportation network company when a driver affiliated with such company uses a motor vehicle that has a camera in the motor vehicle that records video images of passengers; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide5d5d815b83f4dfc9467ecbc7678c16d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>subject to the standards described in subsection (b), an opportunity on such application to opt out of riding in any motor vehicle that has a camera in the motor vehicle that records video images of passengers;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc5fbfa6ca06147d3ad040cf4cff26b55"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not retain or transfer a recording of a passenger except as necessary to report criminal activity, for insurance purposes, or to determine compliance with the terms of service of a transportation network company; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id823f71447c0a46a4b7c22c52e73ff4b7"><enum>(6)</enum><text>establish a mechanism by which a passenger of the transportation network company may report instances of being—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7d0cee4a8d9d450c9fe8378fb38e22ef"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recorded without being notified; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd63a97889c9b4163b5e6fbd0aa57ba55"><enum>(B)</enum><text>connected with a driver with a camera in the motor vehicle that records video images of passengers after such passenger opted out pursuant to paragraph (4)(B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4daebd1b42534b4f83400d4dc7419fb8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Standards for the opportunity To opt out</header><text>For purposes of the opportunity to opt out described in subsection (a)(2)(B), a transportation network company shall—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3cb969a7fb9a454581862c99a21e077e"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">allow any customer to revoke consent to ride in a motor vehicle that has a camera in such vehicle through an accessible and easily navigable mechanism;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfd8d7dfde4e54bf9b01d2ebfe45fafc6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide an option to opt out that is clearly displayed in the application settings or another easily accessible location in that application;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id79c2d8fb991c4833b6406ec1b27836ba"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide to a customer an opportunity to opt out of riding in a motor vehicle that has a camera in such vehicle that is independent from the customer agreeing to the terms of service of the transportation network company; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id20774e5775e14bd1a0c2ddcf7401c547"><enum>(4)</enum><text>only infer a customer's decision to opt out based on the customer taking a direct action that a reasonable person would constitute as an affirmative revocation of consent.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idfcaa08649c2444fb81636d2c26ef9a25"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Limitation of liability</header><text>No transportation network company that has complied with subsections (a) and (b) shall be liable for the actions of a driver affiliated with such company who otherwise violates such subsections.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7b409a6333304a1a98f08cabce3a4b3d"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Enforcement by the Commission</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf727a728e3e24ae09532830c1ab03c3b"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Unfair or deceptive act or practices</header><text>A violation of this Act shall be treated as an unfair or deceptive act or practice in violation of a rule promulgated under section 18(a)(1)(B) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/57a">15 U.S.C. 57a(a)(1)(B)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbc3bc57358514b55b312939c3027c311"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Powers of the Commission</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4dba5d83dfa84bfdb0aa89d9441f89c7"><enum>(A)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>The Commission shall enforce this Act in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though all applicable terms and provisions of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>) were incorporated into and made a part of this section.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idec9ce7fd5e64418794d84b509ba9f389"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Privileges and immunities</header><text>Any transportation network company that violates this Act shall be subject to the penalties and entitled to the privileges and immunities provided in the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id496aa348c7834a5b8ceb9c1edbd9a0f3"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Authority preserved</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to limit the authority of the Commission under any other provision of law.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2aeee6d377a54ff1b325cc44be32cb81"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The requirements established in this Act shall take effect on the date that is 180 days after the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id08ce77dc784f44228975fef9aef90adf"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this Act:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idda4ea85fb2d0424f894b153e0f5779a8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Federal Trade Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4c41b2fe942c411a99378ac4d50153f5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Motor vehicle</header><text>The term <term>motor vehicle</term> means any vehicle which is manufactured primarily for use on public streets, roads, and highways (not including a vehicle operated exclusively on a rail or rails) and which has at least 4 wheels.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id52d40e70b2384fd8ab962f07f5cc92e8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Transportation network company</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc1a95b5f25a643fcbfc7dc5175db7d95"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>transportation network company</term> means any entity that uses a digital network to connect a customer to a driver affiliated with the company in order for the driver to provide transportation services using a motor vehicle to the customer.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id230571c95c1845ea85c7e46a3e5c5f22"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusions</header><text>The term <term>transportation network company</term> does not include—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2d7654b377414409bfa55ea778e43d27"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a shared-expense carpool or vanpool arrangement that is not intended to generate a profit for the driver; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4c3672a229be4bdba1da3d1fac861621"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>microtransit or other dedicated transportation services provided exclusively on behalf of a government entity, a nonprofit organization, or a third-party commercial enterprise. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

