<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE4C71513325E4309B0814B03E4F56379" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4961 IH: Public Utility Remediation and Enhancement for Water Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4961</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250812">August 12, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001221">Ms. Scholten</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001215">Ms. Stevens</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000530">Mr. Deluzio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to direct the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to establish a program to provide grants to owners and operators of publicly owned treatment works for use complying with requirements regarding the treatment of emerging contaminants, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9F7676E030DC46F0862980522198B65C" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H1A1F47E9D32B4818828DB92F00108D25" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Public Utility Remediation and Enhancement for Water Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H707DFDCBA19447B9B95F36BF2F287C52"><enum>2.</enum><header>Grants for treatment of emerging contaminants</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title II of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1281">33 U.S.C. 1281 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H5C9712DA51F94A92A61AEAF27E12CD8A" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="HBE6B5363A2D24D77954E9BE50B605E74"><enum>228.</enum><header>Emerging contaminants</header> 
<subsection id="H1633A0E886774B5489472C0F21EA0E0A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this section, the Administrator shall establish a program under which the Administrator may award grants to an owner or operator of a publicly owned treatment works for use—</text> <paragraph id="HB1DB42793B1A4534A214950E7CA3641F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the planning, design, and construction of treatment works to prevent, limit, or treat the discharge of a perfluoroalkyl substance, a polyfluoroalkyl substance, or any other emerging contaminant, as identified by the Administrator; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4579A7E1E811498E96F536A7E25CBAA9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>complying with the requirements of a pretreatment standard or an effluent limitation under this Act that relates to the introduction or discharge of a perfluoroalkyl substance, a polyfluoroalkyl substance, or any other emerging contaminant, as identified by the Administrator.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H4DD355E910744DAEBD8C9BAF4F52C55C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Cost sharing</header> <paragraph id="H4150058AD9F04145829A243320D06726"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Federal share</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal share of the cost of activities carried out using grant funds awarded under subsection (a) shall be not less than 75 percent of the total estimated cost of such activities.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H30A2B4421A5841AF9305B728E88AFC3E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Non-Federal share</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The applicable non-Federal share of the total estimated cost of such activities may include, in any amount, public and private funds and in-kind services, and may include, notwithstanding section 603(h), financial assistance, including loans, from a State water pollution control revolving fund.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H21E2E61277814B0F87A6A29890B85275"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Administrative requirements</header> <paragraph id="H6E486E4725CA4FC0B70864F20B9ABDDC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An activity carried out using grant funds awarded under subsection (a) shall be carried out subject to the same requirements as a project that receives assistance from a State water pollution control revolving fund under title VI, except to the extent that the Administrator determines that a requirement of title VI is inconsistent with the purposes of this section.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9D88F09BF74D4B588DE9C50CB82867D3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>For the purposes of this subsection, the Administrator may not determine that a requirement of title VI relating to the application of section 513 or 608 are inconsistent with the purposes of this section.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H2D84E9C3A6C246C38A02F5F33AB3C6EF"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Administrator to carry out this section $200,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2028.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

