<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H963241DD5C76409782928B797DDE2E26" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 802 IH: Requiring the House of Representatives to convene and hold recorded quorum calls during a Government shutdown, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 802</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251010">October 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001217">Mr. Moskowitz</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="H001094">Ms. Hoyle of Oregon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000830">Mr. Whitesides</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001066">Mr. Horsford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001232">Mrs. McClain Delaney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000476">Mr. Frost</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001238">Ms. McBride</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000483">Ms. Friedman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001241">Mr. Min</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000601">Mr. Landsman</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Committee on Rules</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">House Administration</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Requiring the House of Representatives to convene and hold recorded quorum calls during a Government shutdown, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><resolution-body style="OLC" id="HFA3B74CF0D564D8992B7C8DCDACC36E8"><section display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="section-one" id="H81C47DC1F0E848EB9F58B05F21EA8F35"><enum>1.</enum><header>Requiring House to convene during Government shutdown</header><subsection id="HB25597B9CD92409281BD0B2884B12D24"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided under subsection (b), on each day on which a Government shutdown is in effect, the Speaker of the House of Representatives shall convene a meeting of the House.</text></subsection><subsection id="H314FC0538DEF43399813F5877BE883ED"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Restrictions on recess or adjournment</header><text>During a meeting of the House on a day on which a Government shutdown is in effect, it shall not be in order for the House to consider a motion to adjourn or for the Speaker to declare a recess unless—</text><paragraph id="HCBFC39498EC046A6B7EC417214202052"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the House met for each of the first 5 consecutive calendar days on which the Government shutdown is in effect;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6BB36526C27A43458361B5F764208B01"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the proposed period of adjournment or recess does not last for more than 2 consecutive calendar days; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC33D8A6AE73A4FEE94C1401673CE37B1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the House has met for at least 5 consecutive calendar days since the expiration of the most recent period of adjournment or recess under this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H9A82593095934DCD9819A6551442E565"><enum>2.</enum><header>Mandatory recorded quorum calls</header><subsection id="H8A60F94934FF498B9DCCCDD2103EA287"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On each day on which the House is in session while a Government shutdown is in effect, there shall be one or more recorded quorum calls under which each Member of the House shall record the Member’s presence by electronic device. </text></subsection><subsection id="HC16CA721F0434E35A67226537C9CC323"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Imposition of fines for failure To record presence</header><paragraph id="H0831CD24254E44A384C262B231581E79"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Imposition by Sergeant-at-Arms</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HAF955A6F94964CFD8CD475C9A8B5F877"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Sergeant-at-Arms is authorized and directed to impose a fine against a Member for failure to record the presence of the Member on a quorum call under subsection (a) on 2 or more consecutive days, except that the Sergeant-at-Arms may not impose a fine against a Member who notifies the Speaker that the reason for the failure is the illness of the Member or the illness of a member of the Member’s family.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDFF67E4473C34DABA73674B6C44FE710" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A fine imposed pursuant to this resolution shall be $500 for a first offense and $2,500 for any subsequent offense.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE6126A4815E54B54949241218DC0FE04" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Sergeant-at-Arms shall promptly notify in writing the Member, the Speaker, the Minority Leader, the Committee on Ethics, and the Chief Administrative Officer of any fine under this subsection. Such notification shall include findings detailing the violation and shall also be made publicly available by the chair of the Committee on Ethics. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H775CE7FE46804721AC1B91DA0AD37501"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appeal to Committee on Ethics</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HBEDBB4867C8D4F1AAE7099E620F0F66D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Member may appeal the fine imposed under subsection (a) in writing to the Committee on Ethics not later than 30 calendar days or five legislative days, whichever is later, after notification pursuant to paragraph (1)(C). Such appeal shall include a response to the findings issued by the Sergeant-at-Arms pursuant to such paragraph. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H532C84E140F94105897630685016C5D8" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Upon receipt of an appeal pursuant to subparagraph (A), the Committee on Ethics shall have a period of 30 calendar days or five legislative days, whichever is later, to consider the appeal. The fine will be upheld unless the appeal is agreed to by a majority of the Committee. Upon a determination regarding the appeal or if no appeal has been filed at the expiration of the period specified in subparagraph (A), the chair of the Committee on Ethics shall promptly notify the Member, the Speaker, the Sergeant-at-Arms, and the Chief Administrative Officer, and shall make such notification publicly available. The Speaker shall promptly lay such notification before the House.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7DFE57EDB58742698D233BD1B0C3DCCD" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>If a Member files an appeal under subparagraph (A) prior to the date on which the Committee on Ethics has adopted written rules, the period for the Committee’s consideration of the appeal under subparagraph (B) shall begin on the date on which the chair of the Committee notifies the Member that the Committee has adopted such rules.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H94357F21F5AF4E22AF74B8507CB8992B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Deducting fine from pay</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HF9ED1E76A89442A9A747A9F0024F3462"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a Member against whom a fine is imposed by the Sergeant-at-Arms under paragraph (1) has not paid the fine prior to the expiration of the 90-calendar day period which begins on the date described in subparagraph (B), the Chief Administrative Officer shall deduct the amount of the fine from the net salary otherwise due the Member, in accordance with timetables and procedures established by the Committee on House Administration for purposes of carrying out this subsection.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H827D0D12541245CD8DFABEE7903E4F1C" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The date described in this subparagraph is, with respect to a fine imposed on a Member—</text><clause id="HD91654006D104670A2C346479C0D17A6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the date of the determination of the Committee on Ethics under paragraph (2)(B); or</text></clause><clause id="HD3DA6F1055414EBD9973C84A628690B9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if the Member does not file an appeal with the Committee on Ethics prior to the expiration of the period specified in paragraph (2)(B), the first day after the expiration of such period.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1A9507925833466AB1567C5E70816163"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Prohibiting use of campaign or official funds to pay fines</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A Member may not use campaign funds or official funds, including amounts in the Members’ Representational Allowance, to pay a fine imposed under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD477524E5373471C853188B135B8ECC1"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Policies and procedures</header><text>The Sergeant-at-Arms, Committee on Ethics, Committee on House Administration, and Chief Administrative Officer are authorized to establish policies and procedures for the implementation of this section.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H7C35D1C415AD433490C5ECE16986DB22"><enum>3.</enum><header>No effect on other business</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this resolution may be construed to prohibit or otherwise affect the authority of the House of Representatives to conduct any business on a day on which a Government shutdown is in effect which is consistent with the Rules of the House.</text></section><section id="HAD2FE09B92D141099E56E1DFAC091BB7"><enum>4.</enum><header>Period of Government shutdown</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For purposes of this resolution, a Government shutdown shall be considered to be in effect if there is a lapse in appropriations for any Federal agency or department as a result of a failure to enact a regular appropriations bill or continuing resolution.</text></section><section id="HAEAD514FD1D64E9A99568A88F6425182"><enum>5.</enum><header>Application to Delegates and Resident Commissioner</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this resolution, the term <term>Member of the House of Representatives</term> includes a Delegate or Resident Commissioner to the Congress.</text></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

