<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H250DEA2878A7405E8C44EEF922B1D38B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5683 IH: Military Consumer Protection Task Force Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5683</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251003">October 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001238">Ms. McBride</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Veterans' Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a task force to protect members of the Armed Forces, veterans, and military families, from financial fraud.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HADD2F936F8384C3DA1B7BD24F140BBD6" style="OLC"><section id="HF79D0E31E57B4147BC3C339F128DFD54" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Military Consumer Protection Task Force Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HC2087F0D7EA648DBAC442DE24DCBBCDE"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H826BCFA09BA64B76A49C0F124058AE0E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Members of the Armed Forces, veterans, and military families continue to be disproportionately targeted and impacted by imposter scams, investment-related schemes, fake check scams, veterans’ charity scams, pension poaching, and other methods of financial fraud.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5FB2027878014640A01289FA2824610B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In 2023, financial fraud targeting military consumers resulted in an estimated $477,000,000 in total losses, an increase of approximately $63,000,000 over 2022.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H75F4AEB23FD6427490AE455639DF21E3"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In 2023, the Federal Trade Commission received more than 74,000 fraud complaints from veterans and military retirees that resulted in approximately $350,000,000 in total losses.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB8367793260040BD9333976CC151D8E1"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In 2024, financial fraud targeting military consumers resulted in an estimated $584,000,000 in total losses, an increase of approximately $107,000,000 over 2023.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9CE4126E81AE4C3A97DE663E742C3CF8"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In 2024, the Federal Trade Commission received nearly 80,000 fraud complaints from veterans and military retirees that resulted in approximately $419,000,000 in total losses.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF948E28B39D4447095687C2A2F6E50CA"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The exponential increase in financial fraud targeting members of the Armed Forces, veterans, and military families demands a robust and coordinated interagency approach that examines current and emerging fraudulent schemes to safeguard the financial security of our military consumers.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H8B0FB01FCD084BF28116344B2F4211C7"><enum>3.</enum><header>Interagency task force to protect members, veterans, and military families from financial fraud</header><subsection id="H2FC30DF7C7474757B8A81062600BD782"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, shall establish an Interagency Task Force on Financial Fraud targeting members of the Armed Forces and veterans (referred to in this section as the <quote>Task Force</quote>).</text></subsection><subsection id="HA81A1EC909AC4D229AE4AE662525B546"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>The Task Force established under this section shall include representatives from the following:</text><paragraph id="H8728920DCAD646DFBE77D232A82D6356"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Department of Defense.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H975B5E99B728458DB79824841F51C65C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Department of Veterans Affairs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H02DE397D6C754DC8AFA62B0E26F47D46"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Federal Trade Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE2145A6F9AD0421392CA4BFA6828E753"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Consumer Financial Protection Bureau.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2C997C4F274D43699F7AF0030C756C45"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Department of Justice.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H88447F90DFB344A78612B6DAB97DF4DB"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The Federal Communications Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9E40973F58144A27B397A24AE488A2AE"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The Postal Inspection Service.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H198722D0929D46C9B10201A863E8CD6C"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Three representatives, appointed by the Secretary of Defense in consultation with the Secretary of the Department of Veterans Affairs, of non-governmental organizations (at least one of whom is a representative of a veterans’ service organization) with expertise in identifying, preventing, and combatting financial fraud targeting members of the Armed Forces, veterans, and military families.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA59010EF2F2A43879549CFB95426D3C3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>The Task Force shall regularly consult with the following:</text><paragraph id="H19A253CA36F14E779E2746FB9425D2AE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Members of the Armed Forces, veterans, and members of military families that have been victims of financial fraud.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB2B4A67185B149AF86AE07C37CF0941A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Relevant Federal agencies and departments that are not represented on the Task Force.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDD8287DE29514B30AA52651224B58F68"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Other relevant public and private sector stakeholders, including State and local law enforcement agencies, financial services providers, technology companies, and social media platforms.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2D03053E657544A79846B05D2AC70488"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text>The Task Force shall not meet less frequently than three times per calendar year.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD79105190F6A4992827676065B1D8869"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The purpose of the Task Force is to identify and examine current and developing methods of financial fraud targeting members of the Armed Forces, veterans, and military families and issue recommendations to enhance efforts undertaken by Federal agencies to identify, prevent, and combat such financial fraud.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2524188F0CD34E538A58B2A3F734CCBB"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The duties of the Task Force shall include the following:</text><paragraph id="H1A09ACF430714F369D34ED0A4012CE63"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Collecting and reviewing robust data pertaining to medical billing, credit reporting, debt collection, and other serious financial challenges facing members of the Armed Forces, veterans, and military families.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDCA62AAB00C84969A236D4BF120983B5"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Identifying and reviewing current methods of financial exploitation targeting members of the Armed Forces, veterans, and military families, including—</text><subparagraph id="HC5010E7A5F2A4451BC9579BFA60113E4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>imposter or phishing scams;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5EFC6E3277E74677A2441DEE3CCF8237"><enum>(B)</enum><text>investment-related fraud;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5A52721AC7BE48159EAC6EB87E1EB913"><enum>(C)</enum><text>pension poaching;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H73A54279EBC74776B86AD2FD711DF081"><enum>(D)</enum><text>veterans benefit fraud;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE16681AB75404A48ADE28C58D39B9EFB"><enum>(E)</enum><text>fraudulent offers pertaining to employment or business opportunities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1CD5A754D0C24448AA25915FC4179989"><enum>(F)</enum><text>predatory lending;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0DDB2FB4388F48198D22BF561C3C0F8B"><enum>(G)</enum><text>veteran charity schemes;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAC257C1D65994AFC91107E442F715ED4"><enum>(H)</enum><text>foreign money offers and fake check scams;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H81B35DAF54F8486A8F7A6C82A0A93EB1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>mortgage foreclosure relief and debt management fraud;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H795437EE86AC40F19B582958438E5A89"><enum>(J)</enum><text>military allotment system abuse; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB9124170644C4FA9BF46CB4AD244D1A4"><enum>(K)</enum><text>military records fraud.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5D9E489482974BC5A523EF8800BC5B52"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Identifying and evaluating the new financial risks that emerging financial technologies, including buy-now-pay-later credit and digital payment ecosystems, may present to members of the Armed Forces, veterans, and military families.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBD16CC0E899C4F0E8D192D0E618B1D11"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Evaluating the efficacy of current Federal programs, educational campaigns, policies, and statutes, including the Military Lending Act and the Servicemembers Civil Relief Act, in preventing and combatting financial fraud targeting members of the Armed Forces, veterans, and military families.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD17245BF97BC4F15B48AF8BD1B27527D"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Developing recommendations to enhance efforts of Federal agencies to detect, prevent, and combat financial fraud targeting members of the Armed Forces, veterans, and military families.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDB41826C585A45A6B88EAFA8676C3381"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act and annually thereafter, the Task Force shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on its findings to date and recommendations to enhance the efforts of Federal agencies to identify, prevent, and combat financial fraud targeting members of the Armed Forces, veterans, and military families.</text></subsection><subsection id="H785C951BA0A242E4BC7201B0E191FF9F"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means the following:</text><paragraph id="H8C2AC8111E4E423EBFA295B9AE28F73F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Committee on Oversight and Reform of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0A12723B15284232B886325343DFBC1B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC9448280D20047C5A4A528727CBFEB3E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7318C3CD76294E638045AF69D9C413BF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H13DBB55F880B41D69320C8A58CB0CF60"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Committee on Armed Services of the Senate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H220B4A42CEDA445A9CF0B6D2AB6CB781"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

