<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H344C734E19574140BE17933B33AA2F15" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4594 IH: Military Learning for Credit Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4594</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250722">July 22, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000604">Ms. Goodlander</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S001196">Ms. Stefanik</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000614">Mr. Pappas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001133">Mr. Ciscomani</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the use of veterans educational assistance for examinations and assessments to receive credit toward degrees awarded by institutions of higher learning, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H02F71A8B016D42428E86E8A741CF7307" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HCFFF16E27CEE43D4B49578490EE25613" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Military Learning for Credit Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HBC07AD2022B147F48FB12CA1933C2C4A" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Authority for use of veterans educational assistance for examinations and assessments to receive credit toward degrees awarded by institutions of higher learning</header> <subsection id="H14205F3BBC6642D1B4F1D171A5C7CA28"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual who is entitled to veterans educational assistance may use such assistance to cover the costs of covered examinations and assessments to receive credit toward degrees awarded by institutions of higher learning for approved programs of education.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HD618EABBC1E24DDF8B3ADCC07B41BF1B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Veterans educational assistance</header><text>For purposes of this section, veterans educational assistance is educational assistance available to veterans and other eligible individuals under the provisions of law as follows:</text> <paragraph id="HB37EF87F49AB4D689243E3E4CF951AA9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Chapters 30, 32, 33, 34, and 35 of title 38, United States Code.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HBFBDE0E900434FE09782A7C789405EC6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Any other provision of law providing educational assistance to a veteran, or to another individual in connection with the service of a veteran in the Armed Forces.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H56CBC54806394FABB1C02115F9556164"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Limitation on amount usable</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The total amount of veterans educational assistance that may be used for the costs of a covered examination or assessment under subsection (a) may not exceed the lesser of—</text>
<paragraph id="HEA18406193154545AEB22C9E31B9FDA2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the amount charged for the examination or assessment by the entity administering the examination or assessment; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD2FD8161987E4D30AD613774990B682C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$500.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H0DD3AA81E38A4184AA5D2121999D27F2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Charge against entitlement</header>
<paragraph id="H6E4833B818E743718B09412BBEE2A934"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number of months (or fraction thereof) of entitlement charged an individual under the applicable provision of law specified in subsection (b) for use of veterans educational assistance for costs of covered examinations and assessments under this section shall be equal to the quotient obtained by dividing—</text> <subparagraph id="H020A57A3C07A457E99648B740E1670B2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the cost of the examination or assessment (as determined pursuant to subsection (c)); by</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H90E086D6699447109B68B0B369A586FE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the monthly rate of veterans educational assistance to which the individual is entitled under such provision of law at the time of the examination or assessment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB87E07D79018450EA0E5A7E7C454DD11"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>A charge against entitlement to educational assistance under a law administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs in order to receive assistance under this section shall not be construed to affect entitlement to educational assistance under a law administered by the Secretary of Defense, including entitlement to educational assistance under the Department of Defense Tuition Assistance Program.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HF196554549FD40D5A61D45699947439C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H21DBFDF312324D4583FFDD85A74FF1D5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>approved program of education</term> means a program of education approved for use of veterans educational assistance pursuant to chapter 35 or 36 of title 38, United States Code, or another applicable provision of law.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD047BB89ED494D259D90BA50FF32B20B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>covered examinations and assessments</term> means the following:</text> <subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5A0C05864AD843259C1061B3BF0C45A6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A DANTES Subject Standardized Test Program (DSST) examination.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H1FD4C36E411E45DFBCD54151F730D0B9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A College Level Examination Program (CLEP) examination.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H08E3697629F54433A36DB3DBEC99A8AD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The National Career Readiness Certificate examination.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H9BDBCE3FCF7446B3B22A6218FAF4F6A0"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Any other examination of a similar nature to an exam specified in subparagraph (A), (B), or (C) specified by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs for purposes of this section.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H20FCDB2A68E44487827202C76D7492FC"><enum>(E)</enum><text>An assessment by an institution of higher learning of a portfolio or written narrative by a student with supporting documentation that demonstrates prior military training or learning.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD3439713968C486FAEC3E05FAC9BE35A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <term>institution of higher learning</term> has the meaning given such term in section 3452(f) of title 38, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

