<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-ELL25018-KT4-M5-5TG"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 25 IS: Condemning the commutation of the death sentence of Marvin Charles Gabrion II granted by President Biden on December 23, 2024.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 25</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250114">January 14, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S374">Mr. Cotton</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Condemning the commutation of the death sentence of Marvin Charles Gabrion II granted by President Biden on December 23, 2024.</official-title></form><resolution-body><section id="idf6cf5e71a4e64b63b3024be849ea73e4" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Sense of the Senate regarding the commutation of the death sentence of Marvin Charles Gabrion II granted by President Biden on December 23, 2024</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of the Senate that— </text><paragraph id="idf895c52c294b4fa7b3688ec85841de5d"><enum>(1)</enum><text>President Joseph R. Biden undermined the rule of law and robbed victims of justice when he commuted the death sentence of Marvin Charles Gabrion II on December 23, 2024;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id85fe795b004940c69c445babda7382c3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Marvin Gabrion was sentenced to death for murdering 19-year-old Rachel Timmerman just 2 days before she was scheduled to testify that Gabrion had abducted and raped her;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide603567b0d5c49f986faee90fa936ba7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Marvin Gabrion was also the prime suspect in the disappearance and murder of several other individuals, including Rachel Timmerman’s 11-month-old daughter and 2 potential witnesses at his rape trial;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idee39b4f13ba4496d990a63a4ff5c3c2b"><enum>(4)</enum><text>this commutation is a reprehensible insult to the victims of Marvin Gabrion;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide7b13154a4da42638f7c9c5d35183d08"><enum>(5)</enum><text>President Biden claimed that he commuted the death sentences of Marvin Gabrion and 36 other murderers out of a principled opposition to the death penalty but refused to commute the death sentences of the 3 most controversial death row inmates, demonstrating that President Biden was motivated by politics, not principles; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9e053b2676514a39887991a84ccf7778"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the Senate unequivocally condemns this commutation. </text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

