<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCEB80A70D4B34465AF48577ACC4EDEFB" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4376 IH: AV Safety Data Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4376</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250714">July 14, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001225">Mr. Mullin</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To improve incident reporting with respect to certain autonomous vehicles, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0C2B70A3B09042ADA2B5A9088AE99090" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HB48419417DC74F7A860B0EA040801A8E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>AV Safety Data Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HE598FB84E0BA4C7FAF7556793A528CD4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Incident reporting with respect to certain autonomous vehicles</header> <subsection id="H12604EDAFE1546E3944F01009C40CF4C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reporting to National Highway Traffic Safety Administration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration shall promulgate regulations to require each covered entity to submit to the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration—</text> 
<paragraph id="H99EA6098C85E4554A9585CA9B4C5231E">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>information as required by the Third Amended Standing General Order 2021-01; and</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2AD97B9C96C948D6B3A4ABB82F8275D2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a monthly report that includes, with respect to the preceding month—</text> <subparagraph id="HFA22F4A750D94450B7FDB733F6BEAAE1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of miles traveled on public roads by covered vehicles manufactured or operated by such covered entity, disaggregated by make, model, model year, major software version, road type (freeway or non-freeway), location (including State and county), and whether an occupant was present in the vehicle;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0CB51AE787864E9AA6C67CB3D209CF58"><enum>(B)</enum><text>information on any event during which a collision with a covered vehicle manufactured or operated by such covered entity resulted in an injury to a vulnerable road user or an occupant of a vehicle other than such covered vehicle; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5ECF6A3A232E4881B5E81457EC7D86B8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>information on any unplanned stoppage event that involved a covered vehicle manufactured or operated by such covered entity, including—</text> 
<clause id="H3104A262ED174B048297472CFA6E4CF5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the license plate number and vehicle identification number of such vehicle;</text></clause> <clause id="HD643FE0DD18C4BD2849FACE07B8A34BC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the make, model, model year, and major software version of such vehicle;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H9E805BE74212475C9EF51C2C711EAB31"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the date, time, and location (including State, county, and latitude and longitude) with respect to such event;</text></clause> <clause id="H9E50F8D1D7394C35AE1D3796F3B8063D"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the type of road (freeway or non-freeway) on which such event occurred;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H9D10689D42494102BADA2233019F684F"><enum>(v)</enum><text>a description of such event;</text></clause> <clause id="H202C2B068F934A8B90B759AB1FCBC94C"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information about any environmental conditions (including geography and weather) affecting the operation of such vehicle with respect to such event;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H6D4E25FF4F2B4947A309A5AFFAB036B2"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>information about any involvement of law enforcement, first responders, or public transit authorities with respect to such event;</text></clause> <clause id="H252686769403489CB3A05747A406F2D2"><enum>(viii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information about the impact of such event on passengers, vulnerable road users, or other vehicles;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H25EF3ECF04FF4833BE6780512911B17B"><enum>(ix)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information about the resolution of such event;</text></clause> <clause id="H90F7C0AE94B44FE1A350DDD0E56D987A"><enum>(x)</enum><text>information about any intervention by such covered entity with respect to such event; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H388EE0D1B7FB43168F81DE2026E25214"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>the amount of time in seconds between the beginning and resolution of such event and, if such covered entity intervened in such event, the amount of time in seconds between the beginning of such event and the intervention by such covered entity.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H769726DE7029485DB7BC4499DF014CAD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Scope of Level 2 Advanced Driver Assistance System reporting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to the monthly report required under subsection (a)(2), a covered entity may only submit data from a covered vehicle with a Level 2 Advanced Driver Assistance System if such data—</text> 
<paragraph id="HBFB6A11FA4AD4D6DA9266C9E422180A7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>was collected while such System was engaged or during the 30-second period preceding an unplanned stoppage event; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7074AA5F8C9249DEAD84746F397CFFF5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>does not contain personally identifiable information about a human driver of such vehicle.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1164624B64B842EF81B5E753BAC01A7A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning on the date that is 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration shall make publicly available on the website of the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration, in a machine-readable format that includes datasets, any information and reports submitted pursuant to subsection (a).</text> </subsection> <subsection id="HAD8FBF6E2078443CB1857B88B8696E1B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Amendment of regulations</header> <paragraph id="H6EC22442790443258686F8857C2EECC2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Beginning on the date that is 10 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, and not before such date, the Administrator of the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration may rescind the regulations required by subsection (a) or amend such regulations so as to reduce the frequency and scope of information required to be submitted pursuant to such subsection.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H46AEA74843674891AD2D33E02ADF40F5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in paragraph (1) may be construed to prevent the Administrator of the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration, at any time, from amending the regulations required by subsection (a) in a manner consistent with such subsection.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H33240F0745B1449B896E786A4293EAD9"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H2FB5E5B2CAED4552AE70F1EA9B2BAACD">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Covered entity</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>covered entity</quote> means a manufacturer or operator that is subject to the requirements of the Third Amended Standing General Order 2021-01.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H12A1D6589C8C442296F16B096967392E">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Covered vehicle</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>covered vehicle</quote> means a vehicle with an Automated Driving System or a Level 2 Advanced Driver Assistance System.</text>
                </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDB4A2B61B3B74152B6436C5EBB5F62B8">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Third Amended Standing General Order 2021-01</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Third Amended Standing General Order 2021-01</quote> means the Third Amended Standing General Order 2021-01 (relating to Incident Reporting for Automated Driving Systems (ADS) and Level 2 Advanced Driver Assistance Systems (ADAS)) of the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration with an effective date of June 16, 2025.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6B8F0B1467864F1B8B1FD00966660F24"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Unplanned stoppage event</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>unplanned stoppage event</quote> means an event, other than a collision or an incident intentionally caused by a human driver, during which, as a result of an Automated Driving System or Level 2 Advanced Driver Assistance System (or if such a System was engaged or an attempt was made to engage such a System during the 30-second period preceding such event), a covered vehicle—</text> <subparagraph id="H501B007509EA4BD1B22C4900F5F15B5A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">stops on a public road in a travel lane and is unable to proceed without retrieval, manual intervention, or the assistance of a remote operator;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB456AC11A14340FFB123073C5CE345C2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>interferes with the normal functioning of public transit or public transit vehicles, including light rail;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEDDA62F1A41F462C90509195F8176B11"><enum>(C)</enum><text>interferes with the activities of law enforcement or first responders; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4EEF959FDE854F8BB6EA125EB02EAACB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>interferes with a construction or work zone.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H452A755C6FAA4696B8A04F94FBBD490A"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Vulnerable road user</header><text>The term <quote>vulnerable road user</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 148(a) of title 23, United States Code.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD7F69C0DE4C54C1EBEBB24BAD16608BE">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
          <header>Terms defined in Third Amended Standing General Order 2021-01</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <quote>Advanced Driver Assistance System</quote>, <quote>Automated Driving System</quote>, <quote>Level 2</quote>, <quote>manufacturer</quote>, and <quote>operator</quote> have the meaning given such terms in the Third Amended Standing General Order 2021-01.</text>
        </paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

