<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA91B113F45F54B708ECA59C85B9FB738" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3020 IH: Addressing Anti-Competitive Health Care Contract Clauses Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3020</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250424">April 24, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000929">Mrs. Spartz</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Government Accountability Office to evaluate the effects of anticompetitive contracting clauses in contracts between health insurers and health care providers and to determine actions taken by the Federal Trade Commission and the Department of Justice relating to the use of such clauses in such contracts and to assess their ability to effectively enforce the Federal antitrust laws with respect to such use.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H700C92A1C8DA44839E29E951AF54176C" style="OLC"><section id="HBF2264CA78F7427DA078777099C6F102" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Addressing Anti-Competitive Health Care Contract Clauses Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H7A88D7E9FE4145478754C2EDF0EDEF1F"><enum>2.</enum><header>GAO study</header><subsection id="HA4C3A811FD084A81BC3C23EDDDE7F8B6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States, in coordination with the Federal Trade Commission and the Assistant Attorney General of the Antitrust Division of the Department of Justice, shall carry out a study that—</text><paragraph id="H7490FF011E024CBC9473644C07ABCDDB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>evaluates the effect of anticompetitive contract clauses known as anti-steering clauses, anti-tiering clauses, all-or-nothing clauses, and gag clauses in contracts between health insurers and health care providers, including the effects such contracts have on consolidation in the health care industry, prices paid by consumers for medical services, and consumer access to health care,</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1BB6ADD4E18E42748D25AD7F6AFAF50D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>contains a list of all actions the Federal Trade Commission and the Department of Justice have taken directly or indirectly related to use of such contract clauses in contracts between health insurers and health care providers,</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H648A85B4DA2A4FD3A978AB4743534CF3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>contains an assessment of whether the Federal Trade Commission and the Department of Justice have the resources and the capability to effectively enforce the Federal antitrust laws as applied to the use of such clauses in such contracts, and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7E13F62BF4944EAD90021F05B62D59BB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>includes recommendations for legislative or administrative actions if necessary to increase such resources.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2932A3296C37487AA144857ECB113E3B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report containing the results of the study carried out under subsection (a) shall be submitted timely by the Comptroller General as follows:</text><paragraph id="HE330D8CCE312425D912DACEC059F984A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>To—</text><subparagraph id="H5DA50ADADA2B4731B96EE5F12AB505DE"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Energy and Commerce,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9F1FB9AD6CBC44D6870C0508CA9CE141"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Ways and Means,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7F5E11F69FAB4166B779786854BD0B1F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Committee on Education and Workforce, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC3D08ABF11EF4FDFB552FD241C3AD108"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Committee on the Judiciary,</text></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">of the House of Representatives.</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6E0C0B60A57144EBB247BE62E526DEBE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>To—</text><subparagraph id="H68C95A1F6B144AC985F88BB03C715CDF"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H24ECA57D275745BA966AB8FAE0148974"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Committee on the Judiciary,</text></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">of the Senate.</continuation-text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H9D020C658ED042C7A6A6B06051A75347"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For purposes of this Act:</text><paragraph id="H80136A6FC2B74C5FB041E5C62F4B065A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>All-or-nothing clause</header><text>The term <term>all-or-nothing clause</term> means a provision of a health care contract that requires—</text><subparagraph id="H5B2B45EC13174CA29141431AA42E9BCC"><enum>(A)</enum><text> a health insurance carrier or health plan administrator to include all members of a health care provider in a network plan; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD899D4A9C8C242DEB7A12BF42809081C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a health insurance carrier or health plan administrator to enter into an additional contract with an affiliate of the health care provider as a condition of entering into a contract with such health care provider.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H210ADB1C37494218BFFD9E8C3A3E8422"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Anti-steering clause</header><text>The term <term>anti-steering clause</term> means a provision of a health care contract that restricts the ability of a health insurance carrier or a health plan administrator from encouraging an enrollee to obtain a health care service from a competitor of the hospital or health system, including offering incentives to encourage enrollees to utilize specific health care providers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBDB43B0B2CC24C4A959C2764E1B37A87"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Anti-tiering clause</header><text>The term <term>anti-tiering clause</term> means a provision in a health care contract that—</text><subparagraph id="H4151E408B75C4BD9BC4B08F00D45CD2F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>restricts the ability of a health insurance carrier or a health plan administrator to introduce or modify a tiered network plan or assign health care providers into tiers; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8C4E53A6DFD444E3A669CCB6CDF39ED7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>requires the health insurance carrier or health plan administrator to place all members of a health care provider in the same tier of a tiered network plan.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD47632FD71004699B2414928DB899897"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Gag clause</header><text>The term <term>gag clause</term> means a provision of a health care contract that—</text><subparagraph id="H4783264FD6B74C46A6A4A4C12A6F33C8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>restricts the ability of a health insurance carrier, a health plan administrator, or a health care provider to disclose a price or quality information, including the allowed amount, negotiated rates or discounts, fees for services, or any other claim-related financial obligations included in the provider contract to—</text><clause id="HE74FC40DA52B4B2EBC5AF91B6BC60DE9"><enum>(i)</enum><text> a governmental entity as authorized by law,</text></clause><clause id="H392DD372552B49ADAF14C2E8D388C8EA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>its contractors or agents,</text></clause><clause id="H66201F810DEA4EADB82FA3B288C10A10"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>an enrollee,</text></clause><clause id="HB51DFC447AE1403E8E2FF0710B0D15B7"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a treating health care provider of an enrollee,</text></clause><clause id="HFB98328B2F56430B937BE9AA449403B2"><enum>(v)</enum><text>a plan sponsor, or</text></clause><clause id="HFC932612E7444089809A635C5CC3EF3A"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>potential eligible enrollees and plan sponsors; or</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H10866EFF98EC4B11961EB6335A2C85B6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>restricts the ability of a health insurance carrier, a health plan administrator, or a health care provider to disclose out-of-pocket costs to an enrollee.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H774F2A9C7D5746D1BBFE2DAD76BA7FDE"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Tiered network plan</header><text>The term <term>tiered network plan</term> means a health benefit plan that sorts some or all types of health care providers into specific groups to which different provider reimbursement, enrollee cost sharing, health care provider access requirements, or a combination thereof, are applied for the same services.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

