<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H49ACE3DA103A458EB7E2DC8ABBB68D09" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5191 IH: To direct the Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering to issue guidance for private entities on demonstrating how biobased products meet Department of Defense requirements, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5191</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250908">September 8, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000230">Mr. Davis of North Carolina</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering to issue guidance for private entities on demonstrating how biobased products meet Department of Defense requirements, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB397577822DA463689EA88CE772ACE8D" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HB1DEB614633C4F89B824C4DED74D2F88" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Establishing biobased product merit guidance</header> 
<subsection id="H0C41380A0D7D42DBBCE43A88892645A7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering, in coordination with the Secretaries of the military departments (as defined in section 101(a) of title 10, United States Code), shall develop and make publicly available guidance for private entities on how such entities can effectively prove that a biobased product of such entity provides capabilities meeting the requirements of the Department of Defense.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HBBDBEBA3B68A4164A313555433D5845D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Analysis</header> <paragraph id="H04DD239EAFB74786A03C5D899D924F2A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct an analysis of the process of the Department of Defense for developing requirements to determine if such processes intentionally or unintentionally exclude biobased products.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H229A053FA2EF4BE9A6D8668E214638AE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the congressional defense committees (as defined in section 101(a) of title 10, United States Code) a report on the findings of the analysis conducted under paragraph (1) and, if Comptroller General determines through such analysis that the processes described in such paragraph exclude biobased products, containing recommendations of the Comptroller General to reduce such exclusion.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE49BD4398C964C8F9725CEF1D498CC0C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Biobased product defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>biobased product</term> means a product manufactured, produced, or developed through the application living organisms to alter living or non-living materials.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

