<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2AD7FF458A5D485FA03E6F7FDBFC22D7" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1223 IH: Accelerating Networking, Cyberinfrastructure, and Hardware for Oceanic Research Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1223</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250212">February 12, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000480">Mr. Fong</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S001215">Ms. Stevens</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require a plan to improve the cybersecurity and telecommunications of the U.S. Academic Research Fleet, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9EED3988210642F7A52A0F9B086F620D" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H5455D23C5FAC4F8BB7F5F2E98EC04F08" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"> This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Accelerating Networking, Cyberinfrastructure, and Hardware for Oceanic Research Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>ANCHOR Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H10DB776F22E54832A1D10430EEF5C2F2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Plan to improve cybersecurity and telecommunications of U.S. Academic Research Fleet</header> <subsection id="H5FA6281B44184EEB85C5304F2A0E1C65"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director, in consultation with other Federal agency owners and the head of any university or laboratory that owns or operates a vessel of the U.S. Academic Research Fleet, shall submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives a plan to improve the cybersecurity and telecommunications of the U.S. Academic Research Fleet.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4ACA938934DE4EF8BD98C368556EE580"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The plan required by subsection (a) shall include—</text> <paragraph id="H091EB575BF9040CEBF76C92CD446FDDD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an assessment of the telecommunications and networking needs of the U.S. Academic Research Fleet, consistent with the typical scientific mission of each vessel;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCDE10A77DC274F8AAC5604E182B2C470"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in accordance with guidance issued by the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency and the National Institute for Standards and Technology, an assessment of cybersecurity needs appropriate for—</text> <subparagraph id="HD504CFD9E16B46569901F9582656AC33"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the operation of vessels within the U.S. Academic Research Fleet; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2CFE1771AB58486181F36219438BE456"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the specific research functions and activities of such vessels;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H96B8299E4E3B446DBDFFAC19AEF90FBF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an assessment of the costs necessary to meet the needs described in paragraphs (1) and (2), including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H3FB0853E4E994F328F0F39C152E1BF62"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any necessary equipment costs in excess of current expenditures, such as satellite communications equipment, software, high-performance computing infrastructure shipboard and shoreside, or enterprise hardware;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF76C0455685045269686D67E4E71DA6D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>estimated personnel costs in excess of current expenditures, including any necessary training, support, or logistics; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF998318AA8AC4588B510877E2EC08917"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the estimated impact on daily charter rates associated with the costs described in subparagraphs (A) and (B);</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3BF7CB56247A4CA3897A203F765476FD"><enum>(4)</enum><text>an assessment of the time required to implement any upgrades required to meet the needs described in paragraphs (1) and (2) under varying budgets and funding scenarios;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H796328B17DCC4419BAB408C28A0B6E01"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an assessment of opportunities for the adoption of common solutions or consortial licensing agreements, or for the centralization of elements of fleet cybersecurity, telecommunications, or data management at a single facility; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1C386B226FA6442FA40C160F5594A7CC"><enum>(6)</enum><text>in consultation with any non-Federal owners of a vessel of the U.S. Academic Research Fleet, a spending plan for the National Science Foundation, the Office of Naval Research, non-Federal owners of vessels of the U.S. Academic Research Fleet, users of the U.S. Academic Research Fleet, or any combination thereof, to provide funding to cover the costs described in paragraph (3).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2260CE2D57724250AB2933A049FA21EA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>The Director in preparing the plan required by subsection (a), shall, as appropriate, consider the following:</text> <paragraph id="HE867A77BEB9042F7AF0FCCC22D534A79"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The network capabilities, including speed and bandwidth targets, necessary to meet the scientific mission needs of each class of vessel within the U.S. Academic Research Fleet for such purposes as—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HFE0A7FED95454EB28B697032E62D53DD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>executing the critical functions and communications of each vessel;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB8B3EB73C84F4941AF1D6AB090183716"><enum>(B)</enum><text>providing network access for the health and well-being of deployed personnel, including communications to conduct telemedicine (including mental health care), counseling, interviews with crisis response providers, and other remote individual care and services;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC1AA316BE14447DA92324658EF4D9614"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">as necessary to meet operations, uploading any scientific data to a cloud-based server or shoreside server, including the copying of data off ship for disaster recovery or risk mitigation purposes;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAEA0D46836A74FE4A966EAA91DB8C25F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>conducting real-time streaming to enable shore-based observers to participate in ship-based maintenance or research activities;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H05C197882BE9476FAF0AF0894B862E64" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>scientific instrumentation so that it is possible to conduct scientific surveys and seafloor mapping with fully remote subject matter experts;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4EC8026BD99B47BC8DC947CE302B057B" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text>critical operational technology by manufacturers and vendors so that it is possible to carry out maintenance and repairs to systems with limited expertise on each vessel, with fully remote subject matter experts advising; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4579FF76D5D64E88893CA56145091366" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><text>enabling video communications to allow improved outreach to, and other educational services for, K–12 students, including occasional remote classroom teaching for instructors at sea to improve oceanographic access for students.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H320C45415B2C4827823AB46692DE9B8C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In consultation with the Director of the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency, the Director of the National Institute for Standards and Technology, and the heads of other Federal agencies, as appropriate—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HC06F158691794AF59B9466F7B7BD658C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the cybersecurity recommendations in the report of the private scientific advisory group known as JASON entitled <quote>Cybersecurity at NSF Major Facilities</quote> (JSR–21–10E) and dated October 2021 as applied to the U.S. Academic Research Fleet;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3555433BA90D4F7B874DF089FED98582"><enum>(B)</enum><text>aligning with international standards and guidance for information security, including the use of encryption for sensitive information, the detection and handling of security incidents, and other areas determined relevant by the Director;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE41B38FC64B64F58960603BDE7E4D9D6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>facilitating access to cybersecurity personnel and training of research and support personnel; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8C8DB6AC2775450B84AD5B6A4FE38341"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the requirements for controlled unclassified or classified information.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H09E667303BFF4E38AA5C02C5CF380560"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Implementation of and report on plan</header> 
<paragraph id="H7EA0B054BFA244EABDCE39BF841683C4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director, in coordination with the Office of Naval Research, non-Federal owners of vessels of the Academic Research Fleet, users of the U.S. Academic Research Fleet, or any combination thereof, may support upgrades to the cyberinfrastructure and cybersecurity of the U.S. Academic Research Fleet consistent with the plan required by subsection (a).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H480DC256F53041C7A3F73606C1FAEB4C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report required</header><text>Not later than two years after the submission of the plan required by subsection (a), the Director shall submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives a report describing the progress made in implementing the plan.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4615654C2C2348E8AEFF495B2EEF71C3"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H756D359037584B558006ECC547CC4442"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The term <quote>Director</quote> means the Director of the National Science Foundation.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDF0BE5E8E4024F629E51594EB15483FC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Oceanographic research vessel</header><text>The term <quote>oceanographic research vessel</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 2101 of title 46, United States Code.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H727CAAB2C8D24B82A5A2EF3C4039B736"><enum>(3)</enum><header>U.S. Academic Research Fleet</header><text>The term <quote>U.S Academic Research Fleet</quote> means the United States-flagged vessels that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H6FD2DFAC46C848D4BCD3807136605B78"><enum>(A)</enum><text>are operated as oceanographic research vessels by research universities and laboratories;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB44423E8A780465E9E04C7F3C45D0C69"><enum>(B)</enum><text>have achieved designation as a member vessel of the U.S. Academic Research Fleet through the standard U.S. Academic Research Fleet evaluation process; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFB69D3033D744E938066C987429DCE9A"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have been accepted into, and are active participants within, the University-National Oceanographic Laboratory System.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

