<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD45DDA2D62C44D95AC0873926120C525" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2921 IH: Federal Firefighter Cancer Detection and Prevention Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2921</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250417">April 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="N000188">Mr. Norcross</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Defense to provide to firefighters of the Department of Defense medical testing and related services to detect and prevent certain cancers.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H12A45CFE31D341418F8A3A4AE628EB47" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HC0B899C7E661453F98E1AFB2C7E93EF9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Federal Firefighter Cancer Detection and Prevention Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H144D54FAF9344B0DACAD2894B3BC3209"><enum>2.</enum><header>Medical testing and related services for firefighters of Department of Defense</header> <subsection id="H72C0A1691E654C3E8DCE3C66258EDF09"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Provision of services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the annual periodic health assessment of each firefighter of the Department of Defense, or at such other intervals as may be indicated in this subsection, the Secretary shall provide to the firefighter (at no cost to the firefighter) appropriate medical testing and related services to detect, document the presence or absence of, and prevent, certain cancers. Such services shall meet, at a minimum, the following criteria:</text>
<paragraph id="H0D59882C4D704DA9B2A532FC79719DD0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Breast cancer</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to the breast cancer screening, if the firefighter is a female firefighter—</text> <subparagraph id="H989D0C8D58C740F5B0488562BEC98B09"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such services shall include the provision of a mammogram to the firefighter—</text>
<clause id="H17C302CEE9E94893BF966C2A5430FA34"><enum>(i)</enum><text>on at least a biannual basis if the firefighter is 40 years old to 49 years old (inclusive);</text></clause> <clause id="HB7F2E63B6AE743698ED1690AA6108167"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>on at least an annual basis if the firefighter is at least 50 years old; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H5A0C47BB32F14A91A8A922C60D905B3D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>as clinically indicated (without regard to age); and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H933F008D554D46B78F01115F062F0D8F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in connection with such provision, a licensed radiologist shall review the most recent mammogram provided to the firefighter, as compared to prior mammograms so provided, and provide to the firefighter the results of such review.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HCD781AF82446452C9863F329701C5F1B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Colon cancer</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to colon cancer screening— </text> <subparagraph id="H03839B04A5D24EAB94F555E9614DF96B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the firefighter is at least 40 years old, and as otherwise clinically indicated, such services shall include the communication to the firefighter of the risks and benefits of stool-based blood testing;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HDCE9F7607E464669927C99315633D4EC"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the firefighter is at least 45 years old, and as clinically indicated (without regard to age), such services shall include the provision, at regular intervals, of visual examinations (such as a colonoscopy, CT colonoscopy, or flexible sigmoidoscopy) or stool-based blood testing; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H53C4C9990345412FAAA02F4DB40D4CF9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in connection with such provision, a licensed physician shall review and provide to the firefighter the results of such examination or testing, as the case may be.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HDA7FE0A1D2C946658F7BC4E35CB6C426"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Prostate cancer</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to prostate cancer screening, if the firefighter is a male firefighter, the communication to the firefighter of the risks and benefits of prostate cancer screenings and the provision to the firefighter of a prostate-specific antigen test—</text> <subparagraph id="HCF77FC7ED5A341A0B5F1712EDC2F7FB6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>on an annual basis, if the firefighter is at least 50 years old;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H218398607AFA439E8CF40A1AA80A1167"><enum>(B)</enum><text>on an annual basis, if the firefighter is at least 40 years old and is a high-risk individual; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD1D03FD13D114C0D8EB036BF22C34E7C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>as clinically indicated (without regard to age).</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB8DE551FD7284D02B8F709DE173D7DBB"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Other cancers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such services shall include routine screenings for any other cancer the risk or occurrence of which the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention has identified as higher among firefighters than among the general public, the provision of which shall be carried out during the annual periodic health assessment of the firefighter.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HA4437EDB75E1459998125B8E4DC76DB0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Optional nature</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A firefighter of the Department of Defense may opt out of the receipt of a medical testing or related service provided under subsection (a).</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H5E49A17C06E54395BF0B27033EDC9F06"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of consensus technical standards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In providing medical testing and related services under subsection (a), the Secretary shall use consensus technical standards in accordance with section 12(d) of the National Technology Transfer and Advancement Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/272">15 U.S.C. 272</external-xref> note).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H89303600293245729BE77177047992CB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Documentation</header> <paragraph id="H34262660CA4A4F76BEC9E25935BF68EB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In providing medical testing and related services under subsection (a), the Secretary—</text>
<subparagraph id="H084112C0A39846EE8EE17039B371F3DF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall document the acceptance rates of such tests offered and the rates of such tests performed;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFD73C0D64A7846B9BD743CC0E29C79DA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall document tests results, to identify trends in the rates of cancer occurrences among firefighters; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H97A3302B3761419BBFD96AEBE390F0C7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>may collect and maintain additional information from the recipients of such tests and other services, to allow for appropriate scientific analysis.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD738234405D64251BBA056325999A5D4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Privacy</header><text>In analyzing any information of an individual documented, collected, or maintained under paragraph (1), in addition to complying with other applicable privacy laws, the Secretary shall ensure the name, and any other personally identifiable information, of the individual is removed from such information prior to the analysis.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H45673307A30842A0A5A20EA1AAE0C5BD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Sharing with Centers for Disease Control and Prevention</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may share data from any tests performed under subsection (a) with the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, as appropriate, to increase the knowledge and understanding of cancer occurrences among firefighters.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HAE277F9F0B0140548D183B09CE23698F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text>
<paragraph id="HB3F73C0E935F4E56A724081FF21D3D21"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>firefighter</term> has the meaning given that term in section 707 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/92">Public Law 116–92</external-xref>; 133 Stat. 1441; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/1074m">10 U.S.C. 1074m</external-xref> note).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6131512C6C02458CBB24C3ECB8D9D7D8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>high-risk individual</term> means an individual who—</text>
<subparagraph id="H0BF445F7C20E491F97E529A7AA25AD26"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is African American;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4334D934C9DC4B10934D96373375B865"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has at least one first-degree relative who has been diagnosed with prostate cancer at an early age; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H83EAA412432B4D4B922B67D906E8EA64"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is otherwise determined by the Secretary to be high risk with respect to prostate cancer.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

