<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H53E8E0ECC5F448C28221679654A175F7" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 784 IH: Recognizing the value of coffee to the United States and expressing support for September 29, 2025, to be designated as “National Coffee Day”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 784</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250930">September 30, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="T000480">Mr. Timmons</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001055">Mr. Case</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001103">Mr. Hern&#225;ndez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000491">Mr. Tran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000474">Mrs. Torres of California</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing the value of coffee to the United States and expressing support for September 29, 2025, to be designated as <quote>National Coffee Day</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas more than 150,000,000 Americans drink over 400,000,000 cups of coffee each day, making coffee one of the most consumed beverages in the United States;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the United States coffee industry supports more than 2,200,000 American jobs and contributes over $343,000,000,000 annually to the national economy, including $38,000,000,000 in Federal, State, and local tax revenue;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas every congressional district in the United States includes coffee shops, roasters, or stakeholders in the coffee supply chain;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas domestic coffee farms and farmers in Hawai’i and Puerto Rico have grown coffee for centuries and produce a high-quality and iconic crop that helps fuel a growing specialty coffee market;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas domestic coffee businesses exported more than $1,100,000,000 of coffee and coffee products in 2024;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas coffee plays a vital role in United States trade and economic development policy, with over 99 percent of coffee consumed in the United States imported from coffee-growing regions around the world;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas more than 80 percent of coffee is grown by more than 25,000,000 smallholder farmers in developing countries and 125,000,000 people around the world depend on coffee for their livelihoods;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the resilience of the global coffee supply chain is critical to United States economic stability, consumer choice, and sustaining global partnerships;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the bipartisan Congressional Coffee Caucus provides a forum for Members of the House of Representatives to uplift coffee’s positive impact on the United States economy, advance health research into the benefits of coffee for consumers, and strengthen the resilience of the global coffee supply chain, including United States and global coffee farmers and distributors;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, on June 12, 2025, Members of the Congressional Coffee Caucus sent a bipartisan letter to the U.S. Trade Representative affirming the value of coffee to the United States economy and urging the removal of tariffs on imported coffee to protect American jobs, support trade partnerships, and ensure stable access for consumers; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas National Coffee Day will be recognized this year on September 29, 2025: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HB8C6179768DD486181AD52D38318966A"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HB0D86EADE9B74D77B270FFEE7CBD1BFD"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text> 
<paragraph id="H3897EDAF623148A0B33687FC34F125E3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the designation of <quote>National Coffee Day</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDE733768586945FDA40EF5B9F64D3D24"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the contributions of coffee growers, importers, roasters, retailers, baristas, researchers, and other workers across the coffee value chain;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H60C5612738284456B160391FA39877B1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>supports efforts to strengthen domestic and global coffee supply chains, including investment in agricultural research, climate resilience, and farmer livelihoods; </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0154C071CF414E2E92F979046A427773"><enum>(4)</enum><text>encourages continued scientific research into the health effects of drinking coffee;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCA6D92CDC5EE4E67B3DC0B6BF2921D0E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>supports coffee as a key part of trade and economic policies to build a strong United States coffee market and to advance broad-based social and economic development in coffee-growing countries that advance United States national security interests; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC1C6F505AB01498DB95A26AD9150A821"><enum>(6)</enum><text>celebrates coffee’s unique and valuable role in the American culture and economy.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

