<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCD3506ABE3D44A17ABABA28EB487B1C2" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2834 IH: Selena Commemorative Coin Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2834</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250410">April 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000594">Ms. De La Cruz</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of the Treasury to mint commemorative coins in recognition of Selena Quintanilla.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF0B2D8A6BD3045C5A84005DAD9DB2326" style="OLC"><section id="H895BF14B5367419EA146B5CEFB678DB8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Selena Commemorative Coin Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H49EABA0CABA04090A42FAB4C3A6A81E5" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following: </text><paragraph id="H0B2CE3CA3AFB433EA19EB5BF7320B06B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Selena Quintanilla, born on April 16, 1971, was a South Texas music artist who greatly contributed to the rise of Tejano music and culture across the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H668888B434BE4833A077780304B67D30"><enum>(2)</enum><text>She was an extremely talented young artist who started singing at the age of eight. Her parents took joy in her talent and had her start performing with her family. The band they formed was known as Selena y Los Dinos. Selena was just thirteen years old when she was introduced on the Johnny Canales Show.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB70C2A1FCCCD433C8924A70FDE7727C9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Selena first won the Tejano Music Awards’ <quote>Female Vocalist of the Year</quote> in 1986 at the age of fifteen. From 1987 to 1996, she won as <quote>Female Entertainer of the Year</quote> every year, along with other awards such as <quote>Song of the Year</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBAEC4A835B8E4EC0B9D802E8310D5CA2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Selena’s musical accomplishments are recognized by the Guinness World Record where she holds the most wins of Female Entertainer of the Year at the Tejano Music Awards.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H10DA283445484D268698F41DA8A8B7F2"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Selena’s album Selena Live! won a Grammy Award in 1994, making her the first Tejano artist to win a Grammy. Also in 1994, Texas Monthly named her one of the twenty most influential Texans.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H61DD0EAF60254E27A843FA314AB975B6"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Selena’s fourth album, Amor Prohibido, became the first Tejano record to peak at number one on the Billboard Top Latin Albums chart. As of October 2017, it is the fourth best-selling Latin album of all time in the United States with over 1.2 million copies sold.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H70C05CEB29E54A8187E06C43F5E8BED2"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Selena’s final album, Dreaming of You, was released after her death in 1995 and was the first Tejano album to debut atop the United States Billboard 200.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE6227495A4EE4913B0ED7EE9BD66FA58"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Aside from her musical contributions, Selena also was passionate about public service. She participated with the Texas Prevention Partnership, sponsored by the Texas Commission on Alcohol and Drug Abuse Tour to Schools. She was involved with the D.A.R.E. program and worked with the Coastal Bend Aids Foundation. Selena also taped a public service announcement for the Houston Area Women’s Center, a shelter for battered women, in 1993.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H93A8D0DBA62A42189FEAF246D3D58A08"><enum>(9)</enum><text>After her untimely death at the age of 23, she was honored in many ways. Then Texas Governor George W. Bush proclaimed April 16, 1995, <quote>Selena Day</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBC08ADAD90A1493B960660CC7C22DF90"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Selena, a movie about Selena’s life, was released in 1997 and starred Jennifer Lopez in the leading role.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H149062A9908E41AF9AD0A77A26EEA659"><enum>(11)</enum><text>The City of Corpus Christi unveiled a life-size bronze statue of Selena, named <quote>Mirador de la Flor</quote>, or Overlook of the Flower, in 1997 to honor Selena Quintanilla-Perez and her contributions to music and Corpus Christi.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC40B78F99E91490EA8E8BB05013FE685"><enum>(12)</enum><text>In 2011, the United States Postal Service honored Selena as a <quote>Latin Legend</quote> with the issuance of a memorial postage stamp.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0F48D0895F7644DCA60BFA680D7B98DA"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Selena did not realize all of her dreams, but she remains a beacon for young Tejanas and Latinas in Texas and the United States to follow their dreams.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HA1AAC58E1E7C469BB9E4251A75011BD1"><enum>3.</enum><header>Coin specifications</header><subsection id="H49F4327C28E1459588D567CF4A3C3AC0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Denominations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In recognition and celebration of Selena Quintanilla, the Secretary of the Treasury (hereafter in this Act referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall mint and issue the following coins:</text><paragraph id="HE1915EC89224475A8C5681CF489CE232"><enum>(1)</enum><header>$5 gold coins</header><text>Not more than 50,000 $5 coins, which shall—</text><subparagraph id="H871E859982AA47D0B180373B06F9640F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>weigh 8.359 grams;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H03C7AAEC0C1E4CE2AC154D6E1DBD5B86"><enum>(B)</enum><text>have a diameter of 0.850 inches; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8736757496134C14BD91026D94258EE5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>contain not less than 90 percent gold.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H308F24E3FF1F476A81A19FEF02873D5A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>$1 silver coins</header><text>Not more than 400,000 $1 coins, which shall—</text><subparagraph id="H87440421F01246FD966AB2CEB96F1412"><enum>(A)</enum><text>weigh 26.73 grams;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2BD54DEB637343688D9688BCC822B171"><enum>(B)</enum><text>have a diameter of 1.500 inches; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H15D64ADA7ED84077BC7F112518FF1072"><enum>(C)</enum><text>contain not less than 90 percent silver.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEACF8B8089EA4C22A8CE617CB65436E3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Half-dollar clad coins</header><text>Not more than 750,000 half-dollar coins which shall—</text><subparagraph id="H55CCAF0D520E42D68A2BD00639BF75FA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>weigh 11.34 grams;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7E106FEA42484F6C9E333A505A1EBF8C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>have a diameter of 1.205 inches; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4495110FB61B43C093D73280463D42A8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>be minted to the specifications for half-dollar coins contained in section 5112(b) of title 31, United States Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H401AC864E1D84EBC986332DA423E5B7C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Legal tender</header><text>The coins minted under this Act shall be legal tender, as provided in section 5103 of title 31, United States Code.</text></subsection><subsection id="H6F0537E59D964CF6B2F9519CC388A9DB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Numismatic items</header><text>For purposes of sections 5134 and 5136 of title 31, United States Code, all coins minted under this Act shall be considered to be numismatic items.</text></subsection></section><section id="H0E23F56C446740BB898A0F9DD28813BC"><enum>4.</enum><header>Designs of coins</header><subsection id="H1B3791143BA64484A0A87D9DE311C327"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Design requirements</header><paragraph id="H7EC69B3C010B41EA884E80081B35D028"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The designs for the coins minted under this Act shall be emblematic of Selena Quintanilla and her life and accomplishments. At least one obverse design shall bear the image of Selena Quintanilla.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4A3FF758ADC848DBB8265DC65475557D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Designation and inscriptions</header><text>On each coin minted under this Act, there shall be—</text><subparagraph id="HF650C9BBB6C74D3DA2ED57B7197DC6C7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a designation of the denomination of the coin;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC97BB13F92B74764A41315AC9714EBBC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an inscription of the year <quote>2029</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H84D16F17BD4B460EAC751C2A4429E13A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>inscriptions of the words <quote>Liberty</quote>, <quote>In God We Trust</quote>, <quote>United States of America</quote>, and <quote>E Pluribus Unum</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEBE50F103CE64B499E9B86694BA21883"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Selection</header><text>The designs for the coins minted under this Act shall be—</text><paragraph id="H29FED014ABAF4CE68C5676480C68B1DB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>selected by the Secretary, after consultation with the Friends of the Corpus Christi Museum of Science and History; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1B3EEBEDD51E40128A72B16DDD44B9F2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>reviewed by the Citizens Coinage Advisory Committee.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H9C0B57892CD14A65865B1AA88A912549"><enum>5.</enum><header>Issuance of coins</header><subsection id="HAADA3208743949F496DE00942F005F7B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Quality of coins</header><text>Coins minted under this Act shall be issued in uncirculated and proof qualities.</text></subsection><subsection id="H48E99BD0733F40BF8A81E480B25080D6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Period for issuance</header><text>The Secretary may issue coins minted under this Act only during the calendar year beginning on January 1, 2029.</text></subsection></section><section id="H3CC0B48800244E1189B19E4E33770EA0"><enum>6.</enum><header>Sale of coins</header><subsection id="HB71FAFDC628F471F9FF13B5D1C074DDF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sale price</header><text>The coins issued under this Act shall be sold by the Secretary at a price based upon the sum of—</text><paragraph id="H726F2E5F2BEC433A93F804F9F62AD8E6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the face value of the coins;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE34F6EC4C1E042F5888D4CC09BFBD10A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the surcharge provided in section 7(a) with respect to such coins; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H65B4B0E806824440B76F289416394441"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the cost of designing and issuing the coins (including labor, materials, dies, use of machinery, overhead expenses, marketing, and shipping).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDA5EE7705A2A48D599E92518BB3F8FA8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Bulk sales</header><text>The Secretary shall make bulk sales of the coins issued under this Act at a reasonable discount.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF2D3D2C414784DDDB8A6E9ECAE4FA069"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Prepaid orders</header><paragraph id="H27C7AB5F405540CEAE5CFB9A1CFE0980"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall accept prepaid orders for the coins minted under this Act before the issuance of the coins.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF937A3C3E643408292FE134737F63F88"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Discount</header><text>Sale prices with respect to prepaid orders under paragraph (1) shall be at a reasonable discount.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H330D7EDBE7B341E88F78FD3006D3741C"><enum>7.</enum><header>Surcharges</header><subsection id="HF50F6327E0634BAFA43A0A332B5BC58A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>All sales of coins minted under this Act shall include a surcharge as follows:</text><paragraph id="H7774FEE2C8734EB7904BE5F718A7EF60"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A surcharge of $35 per coin for the $5 coin.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H08C775B9AF6743AB9250E5D1C4DAA857"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A surcharge of $10 per coin for the $1 coin.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF02B2F3A4397482882063457AC94FA83"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A surcharge of $5 per coin for the half-dollar coin.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAD7B3AC76B39413AAE0BC7303BE98251"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Distribution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to section 5134(f) of title 31, United States Code, all surcharges received by the Secretary from the sale of coins issued under this Act shall be paid to the Friends of the Corpus Christi Museum of Science and History for application to general expenses associated with the fulfillment of the mission of the Friends the Corpus Christi Museum of Science and History, including costs associated with—</text><paragraph id="H3E1F3056DB454CF3BC516DE78B3A3926"><enum>(1)</enum><text>museum operations; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC98EFDCA5AE8479FBDDE1A09158DF509"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a Selena exhibit.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H62B8236BA1A54FCD8B609E04CB7EB8AB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Audits</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Friends of the Corpus Christi Museum of Science and History shall be subject to the audit requirements of section 5134(f)(2) of title 31, United States Code, with regard to the amounts received under subsection (b).</text></subsection><subsection id="H1E9697B0DA16444CA51372BBA18EB370"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Notwithstanding subsection (a), no surcharge may be included with respect to the issuance under this Act of any coin during a calendar year if, as of the time of such issuance, the issuance of such coin would result in the number of commemorative coin programs issued during such year to exceed the annual 2 commemorative coin program issuance limitation under section 5112(m)(1) of title 31, United States Code. The Secretary may issue guidance to carry out this subsection.</text></subsection></section><section id="HBF65AFB022094CD0BD311C3DDBBD97BA"><enum>8.</enum><header>Financial assurances</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary shall take such actions as may be necessary to ensure that—</text><paragraph id="HB179FCD6A9F94EE09A009FED1638B531"><enum>(1)</enum><text>minting and issuing coins under this Act will not result in any net cost to the Federal Government; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H26EFD412CBB54EED9BCE0235D9B7C0AF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>no funds, including applicable surcharges, are disbursed to any recipient designated in section 7(b) until to the total cost of designing and issuing all of the coins authorized by this Act, including labor, materials, dies, use of machinery, overhead expenses, marketing, and shipping is recovered by the United States Treasury, consistent with sections 5112(m) and 5134(f) of title 31, United States Code.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

