<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0015BA1EAAD04194BA168EEC92639BE0" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2807 IH: Postal Service Transparency and Review Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2807</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250410">April 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001116">Mr. Clyde</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001218">Mr. McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001189">Mr. Austin Scott of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000372">Mr. Allen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000583">Mr. Loudermilk</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="J000311">Mr. Jack</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Rules</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 39, United States Code, to provide for increased oversight over significant proposed changes to postal services, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H41E078C18E01411B92F62B124F41E3C6" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HB70648E4B6A542CC9F19E4252890A761" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Postal Service Transparency and Review Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section> <section id="H82295E0908D5405E8A574BB38BA5E64D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Oversight of proposed significant changes to postal services</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 3661 of title 39, United States Code, is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="H568E7C13CB7040AE876248904C9C5874"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking subsection (b) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="H35D364ED1AE342679263E01820474E51" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="H5BC94F32293E4AA88171EADD3345E6B8"><enum>(b)</enum> <paragraph id="H68349E519BDA46B4AE3440A48C2CEE1E" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Prior to implementing any change in the nature of postal services which will generally affect service on a nationwide or substantially nationwide basis, or which will significantly affect service within a postal district, not later than the date that is 180 days before the proposed effective date of such change the Postal Service shall submit a proposal for such change to the Postal Regulatory Commission requesting an advisory opinion on the change. </text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H280E04D11618410E8321AE6F07367230" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum>
<subparagraph id="HAC05CAD0A8F74005ADDDD836CCB5D402" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Not later than 180 days after the date the Commission receives such a proposal from the Postal Service under paragraph (1), the Commission shall issue an advisory opinion on the proposal. </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2DA6F8A71DA445FB8BD9AFE17E6AB8A8" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Postal Service may not take any action, or obligate or expend any funds, to implement, administer, or otherwise carry out the applicable proposed change at anytime before the date the Commission issues an advisory opinion under this paragraph, consistent with paragraph (3).</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H37679366BC9F48F29AF0CC2E0386FAED" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum>
<subparagraph id="HBD764DB5CC254A958827BA44B0C9C73B" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Commission may issue a ruling to suspend implementation of any such change if the Commission determines that the Postal Service failed to seek an advisory opinion required under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB647753B76144E8C9B656FD60BEBB76E" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>On and after the date of such ruling, no funds may be obligated or expended by the Postal Service to implement, administer, or otherwise carry out such change until the Postal Service seeks an advisory opinion under such paragraph, and mail service levels shall be returned to and maintained at the service level in effect prior to the applicable change in the nature of postal service that occurred.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB53F506ECAD94FFAA10ED71A731501FE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding after subsection (c) the following:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="HCE40C133488D4268837DDB7419371619" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="H8F2CC26BA5AC42A88CC059C2ED0C7C83"><enum>(d)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/8">Chapter 8</external-xref> of title 5 shall apply to proposals submitted by the Postal Service under subsection (b)(1) to the Postal Regulatory Commission, except that in applying such chapter to such a proposal—</text>
<paragraph id="H929825ABF7EC48A385DBDE272D8F9FA1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>joint resolution</term> means only a joint resolution introduced in the period beginning on the date the Commission issued an advisory opinion under subsection (b)(1) with respect to such proposal was so submitted and ending 60 legislative days thereafter, the matter after the resolving clause of which is as follows: <quote>That Congress disapproves the proposal submitted by the United States Postal Service relating to ____, and such change shall have no force or effect.</quote> (The blank space being appropriately filled in); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1E56DBFCD9FC454FAFBA611E1397E353"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>submission or publication date</term> means the date such opinion was so issued.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

