<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" slc-id="S1-RIL25856-47C-RH-TX8"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 368 IS: Commemorating the continuation of the semicentennial of hip hop and designating August 11, 2025, as “Hip Hop Celebration Day”, designating August 2025 as “Hip Hop Recognition Month”, and designating November 2025 as “Hip Hop History Month”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 368</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250802">August 2, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S270">Mr. Schumer</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S373">Mr. Cassidy</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Commemorating the continuation of the semicentennial of hip hop and designating August 11, 2025, as <quote>Hip Hop Celebration Day</quote>, designating August 2025 as <quote>Hip Hop Recognition Month</quote>, and designating November 2025 as <quote>Hip Hop History Month</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas 2023 was the 50th anniversary of the creation of hip hop;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas, on August 11, 1973, Clive <quote>DJ Kool Herc</quote> Campbell introduced his innovative style of disc jockeying at an event organized by his sister, Cindy Campbell, called the <quote>Back To School Jam</quote> , which was held in the recreation room of 1520 Sedgwick Avenue in the Bronx, New York;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas, together, Clive <quote>DJ Kool Herc</quote> Campbell and the master of ceremonies engaged the crowd with rap on the microphone, while partygoers known as B-boys and B-girls danced, and introduced a new style, later known as <quote>hip hop</quote>, which combined the elements of a disc jockey (commonly known as a <quote>DJ</quote>), a master of ceremonies (commonly known as an <quote>MC</quote>), music, art, and dance;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas Clive <quote>DJ Kool Herc</quote> Campbell was inducted into the Rock and Roll Hall of Fame in 2023;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, from the humble beginnings of hip hop in New York City, the music, lyricism, dance, and art of hip hop has become a culture found in communities across the United States, and has long been a worldwide phenomenon;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the art and culture of hip hop is an original creation of the United States and one of the most popular genres of music within the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas hip hop has had notable Southern influences following its Northern inception, such as jazz and bounce from New Orleans, Louisiana, the blues from Mississippi, and country from the South, and these influences along with other celebrated genres of music, such as disco, gospel, soul, rock and roll, and Indigenous music from across the United States, have all helped hip hop transcend boundaries and contributed significant intellectual heritage and regional influence to the creation and progression of hip hop over the last century;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the hip hop genre has been reinvented often over the years since 1973, reflecting the State, city, and region of the music, from G-funk and hyphy on the West Coast, to bass and trap in the South, to drill in the Midwest, to reggae and dancehall influences, to many other sounds from coast to coast and from abroad, including contemporary hip hop, which continues that trend by allowing listeners not only to unwind and escape through a rhythmic beat but also to resonate and empathize with the stories being told;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas hip hop artists and supporters, originally of African heritage, now transcend many different ages, ethnicities, religions, locations, political affiliations, and socioeconomic statuses, which demonstrates the versatility and inclusivity of hip hop art and culture;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the art and culture of hip hop have been adapted in many innovative forms that are inspirational, challenging, humorous, thought-provoking, and spiritual;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas hip hop as a multidimensional art form and lifestyle continues to produce new subgenres of music and stylistic lexicons and promotes new cultural imprints, trends, and movements that reverberate across the United States and around the globe; </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas hip hop has provided opportunities for extracurricular activities, youth empowerment, creative outlets, physical fitness, vocabulary exercises, poetry, analytical thinking, entertainment, employment, and economic impact and has become an industry that generates billions of dollars annually;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas hip hop art, education, and culture have positive effects on society;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on August 11, 2025, the Federal Government, States, cities, and towns will observe Hip Hop Celebration Day;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, during the month of August 2025, the Federal Government, States, cities, and towns will observe Hip Hop Recognition Month; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, during the month of November 2025, the Federal Government, States, cities, and towns will observe Hip Hop History Month: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="S1"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="ide172a5ae4fe04d69aaa5b84f6a033d95"><enum>(1)</enum><text>designates August 11, 2025, as <quote>Hip Hop Celebration Day</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id20cbba15ab7a4cc3b4ebeb1a1bbcfb88"><enum>(2)</enum><text>designates the month of August 2025 as <quote>Hip Hop Recognition Month</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id30aecbb2a04b45e7a58868456e35ddfa"><enum>(3)</enum><text>designates the month of November 2025 as <quote>Hip Hop History Month</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc6adb526d88a406c8a8af5ff12ebaad2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>recognizes the decades of contributions of hip hop to art and culture;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id59b653768037401b9780077823645bb4"><enum>(5)</enum><text>encourages Senators to commemorate the anniversary of hip hop and support appropriate activities that recognize the historic milestone and cultural legacy of the <quote>Back to School Jam</quote> of August 11, 1973; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1d8830f782b44125a3d46e0cce1a4767"><enum>(6)</enum><text>encourages local governments in the United States to build partnerships with local hip hop entities and other members of the creative arts and music communities in celebration of the anniversary of hip hop. </text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

