<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H16BCEDA67ECC487CA60EE088BCCFB3F1" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2710 IH: People Over Parking Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2710</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250408">April 8, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000598">Mr. Garcia of California</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="O000173">Ms. Omar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001225">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000476">Mr. Frost</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001131">Mr. Casar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000483">Ms. Friedman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To allow property owners the discretion to make decisions regarding how many parking spots to provide in connection with certain new residential and commercial developments, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HEDF377D793AF4A618D9DD628A04F9E92" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HDF6F7F9E0B5547F2961E130FC0B2F107" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>People Over Parking Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H0BE133FA281F4D96866CAAE4B16D39E6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Preemption of State and local laws requiring the provision of parking spots for new developments</header> <subsection id="H6290BEE837A44155B10121AA58040904"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority regarding provision of parking spots</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a newly constructed or substantially reconstructed or rehabilitated residential, retail, commercial, or industrial structure in or affecting interstate or foreign commerce that is located not more than 0.5 miles from the closest covered public transit point, or a project for such new construction or substantial reconstruction or rehabilitation that has been permitted or otherwise authorized by the appropriate agency of local government to be undertaken, the owner of such structure or project shall have the sole discretion to determine how many automobile parking spots to provide in connection with such structure.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H45B7D8AB2E1E4F439C66C69DD468A7F4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Relation to State law</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any law, regulation, or other requirement of a State or political subdivision of a State that is inconsistent with this section is preempted, but only to the extent of such inconsistency.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H8FCD53550A5F49818C50B6EC3AB237F8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section, the following definitions shall apply:</text> 
<paragraph id="H8A4FEFC9646246BA91FD69855114B5D8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered public transit point</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered public transit point</term> means a passenger point of access to a fixed guideway, except that—</text> <subparagraph id="HCB9328D39B4A4CA0817874EC79691155"><enum>(A)</enum><text>with respect to a passenger ferry system, only a point of access that is serviced by an additional mode of public transportation; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4F13F8F33D1A4B25B2546DC6F1002FCE"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to a bus system that is not a bus rapid transit station, only a point of access that intersects 2 or more bus routes with a frequency of service interval at such point of access of not more than 15 minutes during morning and afternoon peak commuting periods.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF11B8F68212F4A708ED508C3DEBA95DE" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Fixed guideway; public transportation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <term>fixed guideway</term> and <term>public transportation</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 5302 of title 49, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

