<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4A5CE71D207D48AF93A40A2CD70C3455" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 453 IH: Designating a day in May 2025, as “Disability Reproductive Equity Day”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 453</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250529">May 29, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000617">Ms. Pressley</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S001231">Ms. Simon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000299">Ms. Escobar</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000617">Mrs. Ramirez</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Designating a day in May 2025, as <quote>Disability Reproductive Equity Day</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, in the United States, there are approximately 1 in 4 adults with disabilities, 1 in 10 people with disabilities who are able to become pregnant, and approximately 4,100,000 parents with disabilities;</text></whereas> <whereas> <text>Whereas this country has witnessed a long history of reproductive coercion impacting people with disabilities, including through the discriminatory Supreme Court decision Buck v. Bell, 274 U.S. 200 (1927), which upheld State laws authorizing involuntary sterilization of people with disabilities and which has never been overturned;</text>
        </whereas> 
<whereas>
 <text>Whereas 31 States and Washington, DC currently have laws explicitly allowing the forced sterilization of people with disabilities;</text>
                </whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas people with intellectual and developmental disabilities living in congregate care facilities are at an increased risk of physical and sexual abuse, and the majority of these abuses go unreported;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas women with disabilities are almost twice as likely as women without disabilities to experience sexual violence in their lifetime;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas people with disabilities face unique barriers when accessing reproductive health care and exercising their reproductive and sexual health, autonomy, and freedom, including—</text> <paragraph id="H08EFD280567343E99625A167939A4C06"><enum>(1)</enum><text>harmful stereotypes about, and attitudes towards, people with disabilities;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFD3AB7F40D034BC5AE6D30257E26E13C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>legal barriers and lack of consent due to guardianship;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC720CE5C574242018A23E53AE45351F1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>financial barriers;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCDA30EFBF96D4043BF5DF85A14075A08"><enum>(4)</enum><text>language and communication barriers;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF6216BC8B4BE44AB9158ABBFC7E2BF72"><enum>(5)</enum><text>delays in receiving preventative services;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB4D154313F7A44D3AA407AF727E9FFB0"><enum>(6)</enum><text>a lack of accessible health care facilities, medical diagnostic equipment, and travel; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF916DE21B7F5424FBCE54FDE46CFDBA0"><enum>(7)</enum><text>a lack of health care providers with training on, and knowledge of, the needs of people with disabilities receiving reproductive health care;</text></paragraph></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas people with and without disabilities want children at the same frequency, but people with disabilities are less likely to receive contraception counseling and timely prenatal care, experience a higher rate of sterilization, and are at a greater risk for adverse pregnancy outcomes;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas an ongoing legacy of reproductive oppression of people with disabilities, especially women with disabilities, people of color with disabilities, people with disabilities with low incomes, and LGBTQI+ people with disabilities, has deprived many of their reproductive autonomy;</text></whereas> 
<whereas>
 <text>Whereas nearly 3 years after the Supreme Court overturned Roe v. Wade, 410 U.S. 113 (1973) in Dobbs v. Jackson Women’s Health Organization, 142 S. Ct. 2228 (2022), nearly 3,000,000 reproductive-aged women with disabilities live in States that have, or are likely to have, abortion bans;</text>
        </whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas State laws and court decisions in at least 21 States have restricted access to reproductive health care, including abortion care, disproportionally harming people who already face barriers to reproductive health care, including people with disabilities;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas section 504 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/794">29 U.S.C. 794</external-xref>), titles II and III of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12131">42 U.S.C. 12131 et seq.</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12181">42 U.S.C. 12181 et seq.</external-xref>), and section 1557 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18116">42 U.S.C. 18116</external-xref>) prohibit discrimination against people with disabilities and provide them with the right to equitably access and receive health care; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas all people, including people with disabilities, have the right to decide if, when, and how to start and raise a family: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HE94817BD328B4D3080D5027B5CADD135"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H1BEBF94CADAC4476A9E68F7F2C7B1C44"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> 
<paragraph id="HA1A4CF3889104E1DBF01AB665653DC50"><enum>(1)</enum><text>designates <quote>Disability Reproductive Equity Day</quote> to support and bring awareness to the right of people with disabilities to reproductive and sexual health, autonomy, and freedom;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H353D82B453DF4F79AEF18DD07373388F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>pledges to advance the right of people with disabilities to reproductive and sexual health, autonomy, and freedom; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD05A3773494048539A926CD1223539AE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>calls on the President to continue to fulfill the promise of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973, the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990, and the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act to support, bolster, and protect the right of people with disabilities to reproductive and sexual health, autonomy, and freedom.</text></paragraph> </section> </resolution-body></resolution>

