<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC9FB7DD0EF5440289012E7A9C4AC9001" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4573 IH: Innovate to Save Lives Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4573</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250721">July 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000191">Mr. Neguse</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001133">Mr. Ciscomani</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000631">Ms. Dean of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000635">Ms. Dexter</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide a credit to small businesses for research activities related to the mitigation of certain drug threats.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6055953F482249248382289C9B9DC849" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HE6CE9A4E954341D28A06C58889E8B3B4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Innovate to Save Lives Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section>
<section id="HE39E9598B03443AFAA73643A9827BBFD"><enum>2.</enum><header>Credit for research activities of small businesses related to the mitigation of certain drug threats</header> 
<subsection id="H3CC09634085D4B6C8A783690BAFF34E4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/41">Section 41(a)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of paragraph (2), by striking the period at the end of paragraph (3) and inserting <quote>, and</quote>, and by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H06E0C80E14EF40EEA1F1A772F7B2A780" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="H172BD8048A2647CE94821E28D9A6FF2E"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a small business (as defined in subsection (b)(3)(D)(iii)), 10 percent of the qualified drug threat mitigation research expenses (as defined in subsection (i)) for the taxable year.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8E4CFC33993B4E81A4276814AF6097E3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>Section 41 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H61C04D782B6C4F00AF7541DB1630285E" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="H474828DCA8B2424B8B52C8D1B8DC633F"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Qualified drug threat mitigation research expenses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section—</text> 
<paragraph id="HD00D4BC9D5E5464D913BC1C2F88A48E7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Qualified drug threat mitigation research expenses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>qualified drug threat mitigation research expenses</quote> means the qualified research expenses which would be determined under subsection (b) if <quote>qualified drug threat mitigation research</quote> were substituted for <quote>qualified research</quote> each place it appears therein.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBD2053E18963459FB68EA57C0EC7D67F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualified drug threat mitigation research</header><text>The term <quote>qualified drug threat mitigation research</quote> means qualified research which is undertaken for the purpose of discovering information related to mitigating or treating the effects of the use of a specified drug or to preventing, diverting, or intervening in such use. Such term shall not include any clinical research unless such research complies with the policies and guidelines of the National Institutes of Health for clinical research.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H61DBE2B844EE4E46B3A9FD5B824B7FF7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Specified drug</header> 
<subparagraph id="H1D1013B57A834068A6BB8C40919E0BE1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>specified drug</quote> means any emerging drug, fentanyl, fentanyl-related substance, or methamphetamine.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD9693DFE2C9549EE92C6B3D812884193"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Emerging drug</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>emerging drug</quote> means a drug designated as an emerging drug threat under section 709(c) of the Office of National Drug Control Policy Reauthorization Act of 1998 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/1708">21 U.S.C. 1708(c)</external-xref>). Such term shall include any such drug for any taxable year if such designation is in effect under such section at any time during such taxable year.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1B2CAB25FA054CA79B0BE66D004DB775"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Fentanyl-related substance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>fentanyl-related substance</quote> means any substance that is structurally related to fentanyl by 1 or more of the following modifications:</text> <clause id="HAC760308A3664615920D023829652A4C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>By replacement of the phenyl portion of the phenethyl group by any monocycle, whether or not further substituted in or on the monocycle.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HC7F1FDEAB0434B00919D0C1096F9DE16"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>By substitution in or on the phenethyl group with alkyl, alkenyl, alkoxyl, hydroxyl, halo, haloalkyl, amino, or nitro groups.</text></clause> <clause id="H02E0B550F00940D0A8EE92D0AE858E15"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>By substitution in or on the piperidine ring with alkyl, alkenyl, alkoxyl, ester, ether, hydroxyl, halo, haloalkyl, amino, or nitro groups.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H19633CCD5C5E4590B80A108C324B605D"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>By replacement of the aniline ring with any aromatic monocycle whether or not further substituted in or on the aromatic monocycle.</text></clause> <clause id="H53F72293DD434F3C83A4EA8CEB73A166"> <enum>(v)</enum> <text>By replacement of the N–propionyl group with another acyl group.</text>
                </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF871DEE22B6344A8AF87F24361BF0D2F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HC3557FC2B38C453DB404774D34BF11D6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>GAO report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">5 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General shall submit a written report to Congress regarding the amount of tax credits allowed under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/41">section 41(a)(4)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 for qualified drug threat mitigation expenses and the types of qualified drug threat mitigation research with respect to which such credits were allowed. The Comptroller General shall ensure that the data in such report is anonymous and that any studies undertaken to prepare such report do not impede qualified drug threat mitigation research.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

