<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB51CCF74DFA44E2BAFD146D256623CC2" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1973 IH: No Pay for Congress During Default or Shutdown Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1973</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250310">March 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000138">Mr. Vindman</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To reduce the annual rate of pay of Members of Congress if the public debt limit is reached or a Government shutdown occurs during a year, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HFEE9BCF3C7824259B8A56930AE493CB1" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H8C5B4AC451FD44AEA5464F00E900820A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No Pay for Congress During Default or Shutdown Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section> <section id="H7121CE37B45540B09D0125FE349E4E90" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Requiring reduction of pay of Members of Congress if public debt limit is reached</header> <subsection id="HC959776F594A4A6896C42ED8723960BD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reduction of Pay for Each Day of Government Shutdown</header> <paragraph id="HD0900EE2FB4642B1B118FAD3EAE6F388"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If on any day during a year the public debt limit is reached, the annual rate of pay applicable under section 601(a) of the Legislative Reorganization Act of 1946 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/4501">2 U.S.C. 4501</external-xref>) with respect to each Member of Congress for the year shall be reduced by an amount equal to the product of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H3CE96B26A1644D2EA0FC24E3B92EA943"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an amount equal to one day’s worth of pay under such annual rate; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA250121C602F4B86B7E2481F1C09C20E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of 24-hour periods during which the public debt limit is reached.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H41FEA710FDB548D098ABB0111E3D8DFB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This subsection shall apply with respect to days occurring after the date of the regularly scheduled general election for Federal office held in November 2026.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HA9497B821A61400997A1525D76CDDE9A" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Special rule for One Hundred Nineteenth Congress</header> <paragraph id="H4C85E86F75334BDFA213B43EFE035FA1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Holding Salaries in Escrow</header><text>If on any day during the One Hundred Nineteenth Congress the public debt limit is reached, the payroll administrator of that House of Congress shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HA71EE860CC634F45968073CFDBEB83A2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>withhold from the payments otherwise required to be made with respect to a pay period for the compensation of each Member of Congress who serves in that House of Congress an amount equal to the product of—</text> <clause id="HF9FE5AA74D3D4AEEB073589E13377888"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an amount equal to one day’s worth of pay under the annual rate of pay applicable to the Member under section 601(a) of the Legislative Reorganization Act of 1946 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/4501">2 U.S.C. 4501</external-xref>), and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H6EFA3BA963F04C4F8784640D9B75E185"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the number of 24-hour periods during which the public debt limit is reached which occur during the pay period; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF94B0DE5CB1A48D1B6C473CFC0EA4B1E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>deposit in an escrow account all amounts withheld under subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE25E2524A6684B5283263E5EF61D5FF3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Release of amounts at end of the Congress</header><text>In order to ensure that this subsection is carried out in a manner that shall not vary the compensation of Members of Congress in violation of the twenty-seventh article of amendment to the Constitution of the United States, the payroll administrator of a House of Congress shall release for payments to Members of that House of Congress any amounts remaining in any escrow account under this subsection on the last day of the One Hundred Nineteenth Congress.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB9367ED24B5440DBBA1F779A16DD6AB3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exception for days occurring after general election</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This subsection does not apply with respect to any day during the One Hundred Nineteenth Congress which occurs after the date of the regularly scheduled general election for Federal office held in November 2026. </text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H16A900FEF3AE48A2AE21D80551854AAD" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Determination of reaching of public debt limit</header><text>For purposes of this section, the public debt limit shall be considered to be reached if the Federal Government is unable to make payments or meet obligations because the public debt limit under section 3101 of title 31, United States Code, has been reached.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H9E23CA6396B841CE961B04583B4416F6" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Requiring reduction of pay of Members of Congress if Government shutdown occurs</header> <subsection id="H5DD4B0BF52024B2BA3F6C9F5A5847B5E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reduction of pay for each day of Government shutdown</header> <paragraph id="HCD4A380A9E454DC5A4B96FFE4DF0EC69"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If on any day during a year a Government shutdown is in effect, the annual rate of pay applicable under section 601(a) of the Legislative Reorganization Act of 1946 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/4501">2 U.S.C. 4501</external-xref>) with respect to each Member of Congress for the year shall be reduced by an amount equal to the product of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H3F9DCC51CE024ABB827EBBF9923EA2C2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an amount equal to one day’s worth of pay under such annual rate; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD2B96FFF59D64A4280073395CBF040F9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of 24-hour periods during which the Government shutdown is in effect.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA01099021B1C4711953046D50FAF37BB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This subsection shall apply with respect to days occurring after the date of the regularly scheduled general election for Federal office held in November 2026.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HCF94EA587BA7493592898E51F716A3E2" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Special rule for One Hundred Nineteenth Congress</header> <paragraph id="H058E41713DFF42BAB6D905773D3F3775"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Holding salaries in escrow</header><text>If on any day during the One Hundred Nineteenth Congress a Government shutdown is in effect, the payroll administrator of that House of Congress shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB74D1603B783484F974AD56741F7C435"><enum>(A)</enum><text>withhold from the payments otherwise required to be made with respect to a pay period for the compensation of each Member of Congress who serves in that House of Congress an amount equal to the product of—</text> <clause id="H0F408F71A7BF4B9982418D3A38950CBA"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an amount equal to one day’s worth of pay under the annual rate of pay applicable to the Member under section 601(a) of the Legislative Reorganization Act of 1946 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/4501">2 U.S.C. 4501</external-xref>); and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H455E48EBEAAF4A1199BAEE15E16ECDD7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the number of 24-hour periods during which the Government shutdown is in effect which occur during the pay period; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE2B412CBFCE84A65BF7B38AF78B3117E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>deposit in an escrow account all amounts withheld under subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4B0B1DCE961649D398ACCBF34A7F93AC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Release of amounts at end of the Congress</header><text>In order to ensure that this subsection is carried out in a manner that shall not vary the compensation of Senators or Representatives in violation of the twenty-seventh article of amendment to the Constitution of the United States, the payroll administrator of a House of Congress shall release for payments to Members of that House of Congress any amounts remaining in any escrow account under this subsection on the last day of the One Hundred Nineteenth Congress.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA46C00C4AD7F4AD9B00BF0A850AC63E2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exception for days occurring after general election</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This subsection does not apply with respect to any day during the One Hundred Nineteenth Congress which occurs after the date of the regularly scheduled general election for Federal office held in November 2026.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H94529B8E34B84E139853C2B12F6F4F5C" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Determination of Government shutdown</header><text>For purposes of this section, a Government shutdown shall be considered to be in effect if there is a lapse in appropriations for any Federal agency or department as a result of a failure to enact a regular appropriations bill or continuing resolution.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HF7B0C89FDCB047D5B4C85C2C815E1902"><enum>4.</enum><header>Role of Secretary of the Treasury</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury shall provide the payroll administrators of the Houses of Congress with such assistance as may be necessary to enable the payroll administrators to carry out this Act.</text></section> 
<section id="HFDFE527A7E4044329219CFC2E4283B5A"><enum>5.</enum><header>Definitions</header> 
<subsection id="HA1B426298B5F4E93BC4641C42719B944"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Member of Congress</header><text>In this Act, the term <term>Member of Congress</term> means an individual serving in a position under subparagraph (A), (B), or (C) of section 601(a) of the Legislative Reorganization Act of 1946 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/4501">2 U.S.C. 4501</external-xref>).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H2F271328C8CC4941B605A1D5E7C78841"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Payroll administrator</header><text>In this Act, the <quote>payroll administrator</quote> of a House of Congress means—</text> 
<paragraph id="H1F30DFF9E0A44BBE905CB55DBF4B2D79"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of the House of Representatives, the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives, or an employee of the Office of the Chief Administrative Officer who is designated by the Chief Administrative Officer to carry out this Act; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H769CD48ABFEE439BBF098250113410B8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the case of the Senate, the Secretary of the Senate, or an employee of the Office of the Secretary of the Senate who is designated by the Secretary to carry out this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

