<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H94279E2E9FC741789F313CB0B40B63C9" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5619 IH: Federal Firefighter Paycheck Protection Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5619</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250930">September 30, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001326">Ms. Bynum</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="N000191">Mr. Neguse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000830">Mr. Whitesides</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000530">Mr. Deluzio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000301">Ms. Elfreth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000110">Mr. Fields</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001066">Mr. Horsford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001094">Ms. Hoyle of Oregon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000273">Ms. Leger Fernandez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001227">Ms. McClellan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000305">Ms. Ross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001226">Ms. Salinas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001211">Mr. Stanton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001216">Ms. Schrier</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAP00">Committee on Appropriations</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To ensure continuity of pay and allowances for Federal firefighters and protect Federal firefighters from reductions in force in the event of a lapse in appropriations, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H356717322D8943078F4F5664E7F6165A" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HC776AB935FA74C00BA19A4D8A4945DCE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Federal Firefighter Paycheck Protection Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HD78B724600BA4AB98B79E1F4C096B0AD"><enum>2.</enum><header>Continuing appropriations for pay and allowances for firefighters</header> <subsection id="H4528C96748824471AA4BE77752C850E3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are hereby appropriated for fiscal year 2026, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, for any period during which interim or full-year appropriations for fiscal year 2026 are not in effect, such sums as are necessary to provide pay and allowances to Federal firefighters.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC939E9DAFEDB426992CE9DAC196725C5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>Appropriations and funds made available and authority granted pursuant to this section shall be available until the earlier of—</text> <paragraph id="HE9B1E31A6C83440D91BD0B0DB3AE7849"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the date of the enactment of an appropriation (including a continuing appropriation) for any purpose for which amounts are made available under subsection (a);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2046D715FBD94F16B298AA2C7400D1C9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the date of the enactment of the applicable regular or continuing appropriations resolution or other Act without any appropriation for such purpose; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB312E7764CF24AC88EC353E8A2B346A9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>January 1, 2027.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HF193823B718D43AC9E58C95B7672C41F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibition on reductions in force of firefighters during Government shutdowns</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, during any period in which there is a lapse in discretionary appropriations, no Federal firefighter may be removed from the civil service due to a reduction in force.</text></section> <section id="H73253325EA1D4DFBBDB7332E8F93CEED"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="H349C5295DFA24431B31C04D8BEB7FD68"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Civil service, Executive agency; military department</header><text>The terms <term>civil service</term>, <term>Executive agency</term>, and <term>military department</term> have the meanings given such term in sections 2101, 105, and 102, respectively, of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H34772381F78B47DD934F0669BD7C9462"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federal firefighter</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Federal firefighter</term> means an employee of an Executive agency or military department, the duties of whose position are primarily to perform work directly connected with the control and extinguishment of fires.</text></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

