<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-EHF25619-TPL-9L-VMF"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1545 IS: Repeatedly Flooded Communities Preparation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1545</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250430">April 30, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S365">Mr. Scott of South Carolina</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S353">Mr. Schatz</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 to ensure community accountability for areas repeatedly damaged by floods, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H75140846EB284BE788430F602B008AD9"><section section-type="section-one" id="H1BBFE7B4D2DA4886A0E2F5C17C59569E"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Repeatedly Flooded Communities Preparation Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H90731721386A4B378488FA0EEA555AD6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Community accountability for repeatedly flooded areas</header><subsection id="H832B78BF282C432599B812AFC8672169"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1361 of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4102">42 U.S.C. 4102</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HE104A4A58FF84C1E9F5A00154B9B7855"><subsection id="HCC5725D8FF1A41D3AD28EA49B39EBCF2"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Community accountability for repeatedly damaged areas</header><paragraph id="H40172AE9E14C4D38B9881F186A9EC1D6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection—</text><subparagraph id="idB8CB739D40AB4ECEA825D74DF3EC5141"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the term <term>covered community</term> means a community—</text><clause id="H02CC9D98B3454823B440412AF3A0EB57"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that is participating in the national flood insurance program under section 1315; and</text></clause><clause id="HCE41F881BCCF4F05B5F8CE161CA8187C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>within which are located—</text><subclause id="H2D0810A015C2421BA3908FCABD2799C3"><enum>(I)</enum><text>not fewer than 50 repetitive loss structures with respect to each of which, during any 10-year period, there have been not fewer than 2 claims for payments under flood insurance coverage for a total amount that is more than $1,000;</text></subclause><subclause id="HE1B43CED550D481CBA87A08103D9A51F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>not fewer than 5 severe repetitive loss structures for which mitigation activities meeting the standards for approval under section 1366(c)(2)(A) have not been conducted; or</text></subclause><subclause id="HDEE98C3A890E41E48A0B192E1986A2B9"><enum>(III)</enum><text>a public facility or a private nonprofit facility that has received assistance for repair, restoration, reconstruction, or replacement under section 406 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5172">42 U.S.C. 5172</external-xref>) relating to more than 1 flooding event during the most recent 10-year period;</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idCCDD947ED8524111BCDA8922A18DD814"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the terms <term>private nonprofit facility</term> and <term>public facility</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 102 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5122">42 U.S.C. 5122</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id406D13964D044C78A85721BF5F375568"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the term <term>severe repetitive loss structure</term> has the meaning given the term in section 1366(h).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H06FFFE51825C474A814B5F7C8ECE221B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements for covered communities</header><text>The Administrator shall, by regulation, require a covered community to—</text><subparagraph id="H1F85011F2CA944908CE22EE575B291DF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>determine the areas within the covered community in which properties described in paragraph (1)(A)(ii) or flood-damaged facilities are located in order to identify areas that are repeatedly damaged by floods;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id18077615F1BD4C22B5FB7E7AFFAAF2EF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>assess, with assistance from the Administrator, the continuing risks to the repeatedly damaged areas identified under subparagraph (A);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA92A22D1D1164BB7A209B90361518B34"><enum>(C)</enum><text>develop a community-specific plan for mitigating continuing flood risks to the repeatedly damaged areas identified under subparagraph (A);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1AA0AC4B6FA64012A8312AE9D9D16A90"><enum>(D)</enum><text>submit the plan described in subparagraph (C), and any plan updates, to the Administrator at appropriate intervals;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5A5D4AE4647D495BAE0DDEB6035C2B2C"><enum>(E)</enum><text>implement the plan described in subparagraph (C) and any updates to the plan; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3232AE83D9EB428B93DE94289E930BAE"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">subject to section 552a of title 5, United States Code, make the plan described in subparagraph (C), any updates to the plan, and reports on progress in reducing flood risk available to the public.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9978E14A0F154648AD0923B97C4C9E69"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Incorporation into existing plans</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A covered community may incorporate a plan developed under paragraph (2)(C), including any updates to such a plan, into a mitigation plan developed under—</text><subparagraph id="idAA6EDDB6635A41FF9AF29DB219D27F1D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">section 1366; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC17D277055884C869F42D4A007B51509"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">section 322 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5165">42 U.S.C. 5165</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0EBC670D060944B8A6286B10755397F3"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Assistance to communities</header><subparagraph id="HA784566267544D61A4C723F37B374E54"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Data</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To assist a covered community in developing a plan required under paragraph (2)(C), including any updates to such a plan, the Administrator shall, upon request, provide the covered community with appropriate data regarding the property addresses and dates of claims associated with insured properties within the covered community.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF45DC645FD88474790F56BDBB86C190E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Mitigation grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In making a determination regarding financial assistance under this Act, the Administrator may consider the extent to which a covered community—</text><clause id="id29A5A78A51E344E5BB71481599DD9681"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has complied with this subsection; and</text></clause><clause id="idA70FED81C593422C941B29A80B94FCED"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is working to remedy problems with respect to repeatedly flooded areas.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8D933EDE50A94A7D94E405E5EA8200EC"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Sanctions</header><subparagraph id="idB3C8C1CBDAAD4A0FA493CA1C6A814221"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator may, by regulations issued in accordance with the procedures required under section 553 of title 5, United States Code, impose appropriate sanctions on a covered community that fails to—</text><clause id="id733344F0F5474F469EFAE6CED47F6036"><enum>(i)</enum><text>comply with this subsection; or</text></clause><clause id="id051C1873C1EB470D9741FA468CD22FCB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>make sufficient progress in reducing the flood risks to areas in the covered community that are repeatedly damaged by floods.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3DCDE4A04FC543BD9B15B342C47D6D8B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Suspension and probation</header><text>The sanctions described in subparagraph (A) may include suspension from the national flood insurance program or probation under that program, as provided under section 59.24 of title 44, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on the date of enactment of this subsection.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC08887DBAEDD4C61885E41E43C540387"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Notice</header><clause id="idFFE17419608E49D589A5B9D339B40C3B"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Before imposing any sanctions under this paragraph, the Administrator shall provide the covered community that is subject to the sanctions with notice of the violation that may subject the covered community to the sanctions.</text></clause><clause id="id698C4080E2314D92A176919311472969"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The notice required under clause (i) shall include recommendations for actions that the covered community receiving the notice may take in order to bring the covered community into compliance.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id36C2EC85E3174568B9DA6B3298BACB30"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In determining appropriate sanctions to impose under this paragraph, the Administrator shall consider the resources available to the covered community that is subject to the sanctions, including—</text><clause id="id9C4771B151BD47B98D2B2FB031176018"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any Federal funding received by the covered community;</text></clause><clause id="id6934B72BC05E4EC59725162E05056424"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the portion of the covered community that lies within an area having special flood hazards; and</text></clause><clause id="id76B08ABB84974C3DB74A6D91E475EC88"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any other factor that makes it difficult for the covered community to conduct mitigation activities for flood-prone structures.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8A048C18D2714FE1889470386D161090"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header><text>Not later than 6 years after the date of enactment of this subsection, and not less frequently than once every 2 years thereafter, the Administrator shall submit to Congress a report regarding the progress made by covered communities with respect to implementing plans developed under paragraph (2)(C), including any updates to those plans.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF003029DFE394E0B8EAEC1FEBE5F8149"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall issue regulations necessary to carry out subsection (e) of section 1361 of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4102">42 U.S.C. 4102</external-xref>), as added by subsection (a) of this section.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

