<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H887DEDB04D3C409BAA48B17FDA64F7FE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1690 IH: Stopping Communist Regimes from Engaging in Edits Now Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1690</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250227">February 27, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000590">Mr. Green of Tennessee</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001219">Mr. Moylan</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S000168">Ms. Salazar</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To limit the use of funds for the production of films using assets of the Department of State under certain circumstances, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H27D9615FF8BC48B192F39944EF1919B2" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H64429F5D32B044D3A65DCA9CE813E1EE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stopping Communist Regimes from Engaging in Edits Now Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SCREEN Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section> <section id="HB5216AFA0B924C5EADEB6B0E74D3AF67"><enum>2.</enum><header>Limitation on use of funds for production of films and prohibition on use of such funds for films subject to conditions on content or altered for screening in the People's Republic of China or at the request of the Chinese Communist Party</header> <subsection id="H4AFF6A6FE44D4460A1BD2DD262F0B74F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Limitation on use of funds</header><text>The Secretary of State may only authorize the provision of technical support or access to an asset controlled by or related to the Department of State to enter into a contract relating to the production or funding of a film by a United States company if the United States company, as a condition of receiving the support or access—</text>
<paragraph id="H38C56FBE3C864719A20C03EB891B11E1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provides to the Secretary a list of all films produced or funded by that company the content of which has been submitted, during the shorter of the preceding 10-year period or the period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, to an official of the Government of the People’s Republic of China or the Chinese Communist Party (CCP) for evaluation with respect to screening the film in the People’s Republic of China (PRC);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H517A49C3ADD1458A850CF9FC0CE3D9A4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>includes, with respect to each such film—</text>
<subparagraph id="H3D97D632B2BE41D9A1F3B2443738D7D4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the title of the film; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H09153B66ABB6493A8C0DED31F7C10A45"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the date on which such submission occurred;</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H205A2804BF1B45F0AA5F55A2DE3B393E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>enters into a written agreement with the Secretary not to alter the content of the film in response to, or in anticipation of, a request by an official of the Government of the PRC or the CCP; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEBDC0325746E47A7B9EA5B9AAF9C2953"><enum>(4)</enum><text>submits such agreement to the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H6D7D69B9D8E64A24B69983A9CB1A45E3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition with respect to films subject to conditions on content or altered for screening in the people’s republic of china</header><text>Notwithstanding subsection (a), the President may not authorize the provision of technical support or access to any asset controlled by the Federal Government for, or authorize the head of a Federal agency to enter into any contract relating to, the production or funding of a film by a United States company if—</text> <paragraph id="H64738DCAB30E49B7AED697B31321ABEC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the film is co-produced by an entity located in the PRC that is subject to conditions on content imposed by an official of the Government of the PRC or the CCP; or</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4F805C89694D4563BEB07EED430D3CA5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>with respect to the most recent report submitted under subsection (c), the United States company is listed in the report pursuant to subparagraph (C) or (D) of paragraph (2) of that subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD067CB07DD4C41CABA659C89AF426489"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report to congress</header> <paragraph id="HD3319C4FE801406A8C3CA0E781BC7B53"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report on films disclosed under subsection (a) that are associated with a United States company that has received technical support or access to an asset controlled by the Department of State for, or has entered into a contract with the Federal Government relating to, the production or funding of a film.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H765FDF8CFB1349908B744A53AD4EE008"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The report required by paragraph (1) shall include the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H40993B268E6144C2A6B9B10FA4709576"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A description of each film listed pursuant to the requirement under subsection (a)(1), the content of which was submitted, during the shorter of the preceding 10-year period or the period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, by a United States company to an official of the Government of the PRC or the CCP for evaluation with respect to screening the film in the PRC, including—</text>
<clause id="H1A8E94C625614B6195990418E84792E1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the United States company that submitted the contents of the film;</text></clause> <clause id="H70D0FF34302B4EF6A7EDEF809FCC280E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the title of the film; and</text></clause>
<clause id="HB8EC4C78260F45AE92F610849F42C5BD"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the date on which such submission occurred.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA389DDD1555C4A0B9C08BCAEFE867F95"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A description of each film with respect to which a United States company entered into a written agreement with the Department of State, providing the support or access, pursuant to the requirement under subsection (a)(2) not to alter the content of the film in response to, or in anticipation of, a request by an official of the Government of the PRC or the CCP, during the shorter of the preceding 10-year period or the period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, including—</text>
<clause id="H8D4783D2E67140ECB9102BDCC4DB66DB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the United States company that entered into the agreement; and</text></clause> <clause id="HCD820C99C65640FFB963E6203362A2EF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the title of the film.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H4FA127D0C4934076BD31E16F7CBADEAB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The title of any film described pursuant to subparagraph (A), and the corresponding United States company described pursuant to clause (i) of that subparagraph—</text> <clause id="H85337C6D90994D8BB94DC1757B100D73"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that was submitted to an official of the Government of the PRC or the CCP during the preceding 3-year period; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H1453F2050C3C41A893E93D39838E63BC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for which the Secretary assesses that the content was altered in response to, or in anticipation of, a request by an official of the Government of the PRC or the CCP.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC62C693BFB93489F87672F02D9E52D3C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The title of any film that is described in both subparagraph (A) and subparagraph (B), and the corresponding one or more United States companies described in clause (i) of each such subparagraph—</text>
<clause id="HFD58B193FF6049BBB87F290FF7F485C2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that was submitted to an official of the Government of the PRC or the CCP during the preceding 10-year period; and</text></clause> <clause id="H823016B895D8448488132661131C4437"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for which the Secretary assesses that the content was altered in response to, or in anticipation of, a request by an official of the Government of the PRC or the CCP.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HE0DB86BDFC5742C1B2A64E496DAB9E9D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HD26FBA5EB39647E18842F8C6A0FD1B5C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of congress</header><text>The term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text>
<subparagraph id="HE8F7731433F54587A747B89C3790CC7A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF512764E3A2140FFAC8D7EA7C2934C4B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H246183D9A6DF40CFBEC782890E19DDC2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Content</header><text>The term <term>content</term> means any description of a film, including the script.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H07FA9280416A4020A294A2B1EDAB79D6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>United states company</header><text>The term <term>United States company</term> means a private entity incorporated under the laws of the United States or any jurisdiction within the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

