<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" slc-id="S1-HLA25182-1N2-DJ-W9C"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 138 ATS: Supporting the goals and ideals of “Deep Vein Thrombosis and Pulmonary Embolism Awareness Month”. </dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 138</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250325">March 25, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S153">Mr. Grassley</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S430">Ms. Blunt Rochester</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S411">Mr. Marshall</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S409">Mr. Luján</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Supporting the goals and ideals of <quote>Deep Vein Thrombosis and Pulmonary Embolism Awareness Month</quote>. </official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas deep vein thrombosis (referred to in this preamble as <quote>DVT</quote>) is a condition that occurs when a blood clot forms in the deep veins of the body, such as in the arm, abdomen, around the brain, and most commonly in the leg;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas a potentially life-threatening complication of DVT is a pulmonary embolism (referred to in this preamble as a <quote>PE</quote>), where a blood clot breaks off, travels through the blood stream, and lodges in the lung;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas DVT and PEs are serious but often preventable medical conditions;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas DVT and PEs affect as many as 900,000 individuals in the United States each year;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas DVT and PEs kill an estimated 60,000 to 100,000 individuals in the United States each year, and 1 out of 4 individuals who have a PE die without warning;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas deaths caused by DVT and PEs are often preventable;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas DVT and PEs are among the leading causes of preventable hospital deaths in the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas DVT and PEs are common complications faced by cancer patients, and survival rates are lower for individuals with cancer who also have blood clots;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas pregnancy increases the risk of DVT and PEs, and that risk remains elevated for up to 3 months after giving birth;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas immobility, surgery, older age, and a family history of clotting and thrombophilia increase the risk of DVT and PEs;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas DVT and PEs contribute to up to $10,000,000,000 in incremental medical costs each year in the United States; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the establishment of March as <quote>Deep Vein Thrombosis and Pulmonary Embolism Awareness Month</quote> would raise awareness about these life-threatening but preventable conditions: Now, therefore, be it </text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="S1"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id0218c922b8c84618aa3e66d7f7c1e2f4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the goals and ideals of <quote>Deep Vein Thrombosis and Pulmonary Embolism Awareness Month</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide79c350eb5474d86a4fbc402040e976b"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the importance of raising awareness of deep vein thrombosis and pulmonary embolisms.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

