<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5C17ED9A53BD43F2BD0F13A16006F1F8" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2842 IH: Stop Raising Prices on Food Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2842</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250410">April 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000605">Mr. Gray</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Rules</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To limit the authority of the President to impose new or additional duties with respect to articles imported from countries that are major agricultural trade partners with the United States.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA5828DEA0C054E4EBC364CEC4188B1A1" style="OLC"><section id="H4D73BD987B6345E794CB79067F84900E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop Raising Prices on Food Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H563F33DF84F145B2A66D846ABEEB3D2B" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Limitation on authority of the President to impose duties on agricultural trading partners of the United States</header><subsection id="H0990604F75624CACB506F0E099A3E882"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph id="H9C001F0386A3432094F37E2A1E873DBF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered country</header><subparagraph id="H437E3C2E3A2245AAB7F39EFC6CD9186F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>covered country</term> means a country that is one of the 5 countries with the highest volume of United States agricultural goods imported into the country in the preceding fiscal year, as determined by the President.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAD401B990026454DB02A5A5E3C2D1A2E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>EU countries</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A), the European Union and its member countries shall be treated a single country.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H38D0AD01867D403A87846B0C43B2CD75"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered duty</header><text>The term <term>covered duty</term> means a duty proclaimed pursuant to—</text><subparagraph id="H5E218D29BE4A42CA87CA864F0EC3A59B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>section 232 of the Trade Expansion Act of 1962 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1862">19 U.S.C. 1862</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD0550AD004AF4476942EE2647E5846A2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>section 338 of the Tariff Act of 1930 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1338">19 U.S.C. 1338</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBEDA67A3AE504811BD46111A920E22E9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Trading with the Enemy Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4301">50 U.S.C. 4301 et seq.</external-xref>); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2B583BE1981F4DF6BDA806A11DC7BE09"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3AEC87858248461C8D9ABEDC72733F57"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authority To proclaim or increase duty rates</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the President may proclaim a new or additional covered duty with respect to an article imported into the United States from a covered country, only if—</text><paragraph id="HAE79685A75094028B9CEB4272A842258"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the President submits to Congress a request for authorization to proclaim or increase the duty that includes—</text><subparagraph id="HC4D5D61A4D424C9889120EC120537843"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of the objective the President seeks to achieve through proclamation or increase of the duty;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF1D044881A8543EC9B9A1FB027DC6803"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an explanation of why such objective cannot be achieved more effectively through diplomatic engagement, trade dispute resolution processes, or other mechanisms; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD57BD11AA11445A9BA1F42D0BA4C3E04"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an assessment of the likely impact of the proposal on the United States agricultural economy; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDEA8B7A7C86145D794C8897BEE523762"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a joint resolution of approval under subsection (c) is enacted into law.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAFEA50AC4BCF4AFCA134D5C35867481A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Joint resolution of approval</header><paragraph id="HE833484C3BAF47588CDB6A23CC68BD47"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Joint resolution of approval defined</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>joint resolution of approval</term> means a joint resolution the sole matter after the resolving clause of which is as follows: “That Congress authorizes the President to proclaim duty rates as set forth in the request of the President submitted to Congress on ________________”, with the blank space being filled with the date of the request submitted under subsection (b)(1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD31B649641974F7C9DCCD9670EC16D49"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Introduction</header><text>A joint resolution of approval may be introduced in either House of Congress by any Member during the 15-legislative day period beginning on the date on which the President submits to Congress the request under subsection (b)(1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7C43A7ABDF504D86A63D054F71778905"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Expedited procedures</header><text>The provisions of subsections (b) through (f) of section 152 of the Trade Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/2192">19 U.S.C. 2192</external-xref>) apply to a joint resolution of approval to the same extent that such subsections apply to joint resolutions under such section 152.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H949009A5AE8C443182EFABFFAA0B7EE1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Rules of the Senate and the House of Representatives</header><text>This subsection is enacted by Congress—</text><subparagraph id="H3FFD379349AB4F488160019A25CC241B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>as an exercise of the rulemaking power of the Senate and the House of Representatives, respectively, and as such is deemed a part of the rules of each House, respectively, but applicable only with respect to the procedure to be followed in that House in the case of a joint resolution of approval, and supersedes other rules only to the extent that it is inconsistent with such rules; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA25704E456D6496CAAC5F8330FA65CD8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with full recognition of the constitutional right of either House to change the rules (so far as relating to the procedure of that House) at any time, in the same manner, and to the same extent as in the case of any other rule of that House.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

