<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1E75C4E170624D75ACAD73DD0F393D5D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4303 IH: To establish a Special Envoy for Humanitarian Aid Workers, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4303</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250707">July 7, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000172">Ms. Ocasio-Cortez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000631">Ms. Dean of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a Special Envoy for Humanitarian Aid Workers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF8089DF47CCB4E3293A47165F16B0768" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HA2515102824D484593F9E69E2B84E946" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Special Envoy for Humanitarian Aid Workers</header> 
<subsection id="HAE8D01DAEAC14B60B016CBF8A0E3C22C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1 of the State Department Basic Authorities Act of 1956 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2651a">22 U.S.C. 2651a</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H66B5C96D27884B79AD17E9F47BEEE59C" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="HB84BDB8BACF94345A235D8BF9C7FDAD2"><enum>(p)</enum><header>Special Envoy for Humanitarian Aid Workers</header> <paragraph id="H6C3D658A2C9649969E79BD261C7C7172"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There shall be a Special Envoy for Humanitarian Aid Workers, who shall be appointed by the President and shall report to the Secretary of State.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2AEDFFDD4107408DB963F3C203A18EEE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rank and status of ambassador</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Special Envoy shall have the rank and status of ambassador.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAFED971E124648ADB50FDEB9EB4639D1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Duties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Special Envoy shall be responsible for—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H532B4BF4766E41349B39E31524F6EB3C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>inquiring into the death, fatal injury, or detention of any aid worker in the course of providing assistance as part of a humanitarian mission supported by the United States;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5BD2571458D649CD8D05FE5724DF07CD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>advocating for the robust coordination and deconfliction between humanitarian missions supported by the United States, international bodies, and relevant foreign security forces;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEF0995817FB94765BB26E184D6CBD4CD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>advocating for foreign countries to adopt best practices, including security for aid workers, to enable nongovernmental organizations to freely deliver humanitarian aid and assistance;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H26B36481EDEA4E3B9954E13831EAA506"><enum>(D)</enum><text>developing and advocating, in consultation with the Secretary of State, best practices for foreign countries to work with humanitarian nongovernmental organizations and civil society organizations; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2D0583A0ED2A4C1AA061FE9241227203"><enum>(E)</enum><text>advocating for any other matter that supports the efforts of nongovernmental organizations to provide humanitarian assistance without the interference of the security of a foreign country.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H07671B4D4A40476098024AACC103CA62"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this section, and annually thereafter, the Special Envoy shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report regarding the working environment of the conflict areas in which humanitarian aid workers operate to provide humanitarian assistance as part of a humanitarian mission supported by the United States, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HA915776D8D134F27A347E86D0817C067"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any security challenges that nongovernmental organizations face in providing United States humanitarian assistance;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H550CF92256594FEE9B0983AB8768E799"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the effectiveness of the United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs in deconflicting between nongovernmental organizations providing humanitarian assistance and parties to conflict;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H30EA5EB8EB1447FAA4B8BBBCDF1BEADA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>how much humanitarian assistance the United States has distributed in the preceding 1-year period; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H60006AF2B82E4E8385C067A0E626A047"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any policy recommendations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4CE28EEBF6BC44908603D0EC5C873515"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <subparagraph id="H11B55D452EB94D59A47C909DAE57AEF0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Aid worker</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>aid worker</term> means an individual who provides humanitarian assistance to those in need outside the United States.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFC330B9D62734D86A66940EACC1C7552" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> <clause id="H390ED598BA6A48D0BDB3A42D60834139"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and Senate;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H2F44B0B37B2D4CEAABB4713E0BB9DAD1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives; and</text></clause> <clause id="H3452882C49854166B9250FE0B6B2DEC4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate.</text></clause> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2A78D89E069D4F988F6CC927C9DDBB20"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report on OCHA</header> 
<paragraph id="H1BD3DF78FFE34B5AAA2C2CD6FADE3115"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this section, the Special Envoy for Humanitarian Aid Workers shall, in consultation with the Secretary of State, submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report regarding the effectiveness of the efforts of the United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs with respect to coordination and deconfliction between humanitarian nongovernmental organizations and foreign countries as part of a humanitarian response supported by the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7B27ABC86C534A2699D3592068C57160"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HA20FC997F55F4D2B89CD3C66C7B05AF4"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and House of Representatives;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H64CC2226EAA24E5C9ABBDC2F9AD3B12D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H987D0BB468CF4AA3A82CADDDBBA7A33C"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate.</text></subparagraph> </paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H78537E76693643098AA4D1B157F2098B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Investigations into any killing or fatal injury of humanitarian aid workers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Chapter 1 of part III of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2351">22 U.S.C. 2351 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H695F1F2BDCFF4B2BAB5291E344269723" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="H5791D2D22A464CF98FB6F754B9E182F7"><enum>620N.</enum><header>Prohibition on assistance to countries that unlawfully kill or fatally injure humanitarian aid workers</header> 
<subsection id="H9F4B20E031084A26864A25E3069802A7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition on assistance to countries that unlawfully kill or fatally injure humanitarian aid workers</header> 
<paragraph id="H12C1BC55B031444FBB1E994AA469B56E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No security assistance (as such term is defined in section 502B) and no defense article or defense service subject to the requirements of section 36 of the Arms Export Control Act may be furnished to any foreign country if the Secretary of State certifies to the appropriate congressional committees that such foreign country has unlawfully killed or fatally injured humanitarian aid workers or refused reasonable requests to furnish relevant information to the Secretary of the United States, unless the Secretary of State also certifies to the appropriate congressional committees that, in the determination of the Secretary, such foreign country—</text> <subparagraph id="H056B6D01168D4151A4F95FD8F0FAA2C9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has taken sufficient action to investigate previous violations, adopt corrective actions, take effective steps to bring the responsible members of the security force unit to justice, and coordinate active humanitarian aid missions; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6FF0BC22292C4BA8A3E3D14567592141"><enum>(B)</enum><text>will enable humanitarian aid workers to participate in such missions without being unlawfully killed or fatally injured.</text></subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H22B83CA14DD74384B0FC1A38F21B7B1A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>A certification under paragraph (1) shall be submitted not later than 15 days before the entry into effect of such certification.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6BFCE85580D44EE0A846342551B98128" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Aid Worker Independent Inquiry Group</header> 
<paragraph id="HE25896E4031A4605B6DCEE0C773DDA88" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after appointment of the Special Envoy for Humanitarian Aid Workers, the President shall establish an interagency group, to be known as the Aid Worker Independent Inquiry Group (in this section referred to as the <quote>Group</quote>), to assess and analyze the death or detention of any individual participating in an active humanitarian aid mission after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB86D27A7FA95416A8CAA95B3E4E23A32"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Membership</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Group shall be led by the Special Envoy and consist of such number of representatives as the Special Envoy may determine appropriate from—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H24E62D6F91D94331952E3CB5848EB0C9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Department of Justice;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8BEAC15A700A4299AF483257EF2A70F2"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Department of State, including—</text> 
<clause id="H58B7920DFF24495394FC6C6DC48796BA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>relevant embassies;</text></clause> <clause id="HDC9ECAFDF80D44269118F8EFDDF2EBD2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Office of Foreign Assistance; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H4E37D713DB344189A3B5799F45474C6D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">relevant offices under the Undersecretary for Political Affairs;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6FB371F5EB1B4CC885058797524CC059"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Federal Bureau of Investigation;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H893F35F163BB4010BEB2AEE267C1FC79"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Office of the Director of National Intelligence; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H48F0C115D7C74B939433E9DA8DD874AB"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other Federal department or agency that the Special Envoy may determine appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEEEBD8333D6441378FC5DE56DE3CAC6F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the incidence of a death or detention described in paragraph (1), the Special Envoy, in coordination with the Group, shall submit to Congress a report that includes—</text> <subparagraph id="H8FB4BD31EBA24E67AA6E9707168EDCD4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the cause of such death or detention;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H25CA986AB68842E9B170BA5BECB4E8C9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to a death—</text> <clause id="H3BA92F6CE3514A3EB170AA43505368C4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a description of the events leading up to such death;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HD03E38A6B643487BA58E1CB12E87AD7A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if the military of a foreign country is responsible for causing the death of any such aid worker;</text></clause> <clause id="HDC0249D0A7E54B549052EB5FD85001AE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>an assessment of the circumstances surrounding such death, including the information available to and intentions of the unit of such military involved;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HFEED4482165741C7AB955904D31A3399"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>information on the source of such death, including the type of munitions used in connection with such death, if any;</text></clause> <clause id="H5EEBDBD6E61D43B2934FD606AD811F83"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether it is more likely than not that any defense article used was transferred from the United States or purchased by the perpetrator from United States assistance; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H6EA17CAD8A7D4FFCAF86D0428501B0C9"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>any other detail that the Special Envoy determines relevant to the circumstances of the death;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3FBEB6DEDD9D476AB702DCE05F92E50D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>with respect to a detention, information on the grounds for such detention, including any criminal charges and evidence against the detainee;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H34353F05AA244444A1292BFC5889B4B1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an assessment of the degree of cooperation with the investigation of the death or detention by the relevant foreign country, including whether such country has furnished all requested information; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB356B2C637BD4011AF9605B323A2B6F8"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a final assessment as to whether such death or detention was consistent with the laws of the international community, of the host country, and the Department of Defense’s Law of War Manual.</text></subparagraph> </paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE4A5BC8B74524B4B8F46EF7AC68DEF0B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H6692DBF5FEE2461B8AC10FEA0D475282"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Active humanitarian aid mission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>active humanitarian aid mission</term> means an ongoing, organized effort outside the United States where United States humanitarian assistance is being delivered or administered by the international community, individual countries, or international organizations to prevent and control non-political and non-military crises and to mitigate their effects.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6ACF414E313D4FEAA65F4E4CC858BB5D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H59860BEBE8084A1DB139AF22610A664D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and Senate;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCDB85A8F88014987BA49541DBD52603F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0C0F72AD6A8E410B9D2BA85809A738F4"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate.</text></subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8F35AAC4B0EA43B9B0E8FA7C7D812080"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Humanitarian aid worker</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>humanitarian aid worker</term> means an individual participating in an active humanitarian aid mission to provide assistance and resources to those in need.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H19703F3944DE4190956C5A380A5B0256"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Unlawful killing</header><text>The term <term>unlawful killing</term> means the use of lethal force by a government or its agents that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD5A249AD692C40E89039E1F799D7E4B4"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if in a state of armed conflict, is inconsistent with the requirements of international humanitarian law that are enshrined as principles in the United States Department of Defense Law of War Manual; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H29B29520F55A4912992ABD0185F61747"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if outside of a state of armed conflict, would constitute homicide as defined in section 1111 or 1112 of title 18, United States Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> </subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

