<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H28EF0EC6CBA74399B3BBB674B7F31839" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1273 IH: Korean American Divided Families National Registry Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1273</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250212">February 12, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001230">Mr. Subramanyam</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="K000397">Mrs. Kim</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M000317">Ms. Malliotakis</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of State to establish a national registry of Korean American divided families, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H504B62656ABA4563AC030EAF18C728C3" style="OLC"><section id="H61DD4BC231974805A00B54927CED6288" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Korean American Divided Families National Registry Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H02FD2BFF11494E77A036E27214CA3C73"><enum>2.</enum><header>National registry of Korean American divided families</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of State, acting through the Special Envoy on North Korean Human Rights Issues or such other individual as the Secretary may designate, shall—</text><paragraph id="H74D1DA86102045749D4B573650C99793"><enum>(1)</enum><text>collate information on Korean American families who wish to be reunited with family members in North Korea from which such Korean American families were divided after the signing of the Agreement Concerning a Military Armistice in Korea, signed at Panmunjom July 27, 1953 (commonly referred to as the <quote>Korean War Armistice Agreement</quote>), in anticipation of future reunions for such families and family members, including in-person and video reunions; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5E1DC162ED104B029AFEE5C2B2C8724C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>establish a private internal national registry of the names and other relevant information of such Korean American families—</text><subparagraph id="H547F77D6A9A243059550251C51F649ED"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to host such future reunions in South Korea, the United States, or third countries; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD58AB2799D1C4165894548CDD67226FE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to provide for a private internal repository of information about such Korean American families and family members in North Korea, including information about individuals who may be deceased.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="HCD184866035C424CBDDC8986535F8EF6"><enum>3.</enum><header>Actions to facilitate dialogue between the United States and North Korea</header><subsection id="HE58888B142D2471FB8AEEB7755B74FD1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of State shall take such actions as may be necessary to ensure that any direct dialogue between the United States and North Korea includes progress towards holding future reunions for Korean American families and their family members in North Korea as described in section 2.</text></subsection><subsection id="H0CE2BAA864A74325AAE310A5CB0635CE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultations</header><text>The Secretary of State shall consult with the Government of the Republic of Korea in carrying out this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H209432116E204D0083848C804975724D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>No later than one year after enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter for 5 years, the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on—</text><paragraph id="HF9601108BC674E199C6ABA50AD7631F3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the status of the national registry established pursuant to section 2(a)(2);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC6EB241472E24EEEBC7D43FC458C2C56"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the number of individuals included on the registry who—</text><subparagraph id="H0F1A025A5B8149D09FB4726803E8DF17"><enum>(A)</enum><text>have met their family members in North Korea during previous reunions; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9B6322FB8BDD4435A34B61CC7179D9C0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>have yet to meet their family members in North Korea during previous reunions;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H98121CD58626447C838787EBFFDCD3FA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a summary of responses by North Korea to requests to hold reunions of divided families; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8F86AA2A6B8948548C98DE589A9204A2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a description of regulations in North Korea and actions taken by North Korea in the year previous to submission of each report that prevent the emigration of family members of Korean American families.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2F089BEFADBA4959AB3C148545647FC6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text>In this Act, <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

