<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ROM25512-PRD-D7-G7M">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2697 IS: National Biotechnology Safety Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>II</distribution-code>
        <congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session>1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. 2697</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action>
            <action-date date="20250903">September 3, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S391">Mr. Young</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was
                read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on
                    Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title>To authorize the National Science Foundation to conduct research for
            biotechnology risk assessment, and for other purposes.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body>
        <section id="idc2537df015354cd48286e5ff59a043c1" section-type="section-one">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>National Biotechnology Safety Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section id="id0e80ab33fd294167802320019d26b00f">
            <enum>2.</enum>
            <header>Findings</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> <paragraph id="ided7784d97b4849af8e39e22648e90333"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>Biotechnology is routinely used to modify genetic sequences in plants, animals, and microorganisms, resulting in useful products across agriculture, medicine, industry, and defense.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="id9cda739e69f8448c8d0e0294b61896d4">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>Specific research would help inform the Federal Government, State governments, industry, and other stakeholders on how best to address safety of biotechnology products.</text>
            </paragraph>
        </section>
        <section id="id2465aea1eb3843b6bbbc3494152c3262">
            <enum>3.</enum>
            <header>Biotechnology risk assessment research</header>
            <subsection id="id8671a7acec8c4216be18c2f5cb2b6d60">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>Purposes</header>
 <text>The purposes of this section are to authorize and support research—</text> <paragraph id="idf40beca49c5543ff9be735a686f72e06"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>to address regulatory concerns about potential environmental, human health, or animal health risks of organisms produced with biotechnology; and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="ida4659ee4641447f585afa4abcfb52ba6">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>that aids regulators in developing clear regulatory pathways for products produced with biotechnology.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id1e4bb45b674c468293ccb9d312d0d275">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Establishment</header>
                <paragraph id="idab6204c7617b436eaa6a00fd8c51d600">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                    <header>In general</header>
 <text>The Director of the National Science Foundation (referred to in this section as the <quote>Director</quote>) shall establish a program within the Directorate for Technology, Innovation, and Partnerships to provide funding for research concerning the introduction into the environment of organisms that were produced with biotechnology.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id927b6778b9c7466684f253481b9e23af">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Mechanisms</header>
 <text>The Director may choose funding mechanisms under this section as appropriate to meet the scientific need, including research grants, cooperative agreements, and temporary research consortia.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="idc9606087f34348ada11dc764731a4fd4">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Recipients</header>
 <text>Recipients of funds under this section may include—</text> <paragraph id="id7ce1a0b7143b4938b4fad17b1973c867"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>institutions of higher education, as defined in section 102 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1002">20 U.S.C. 1002</external-xref>);</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id025041367b9f44efa81ec4ab9c1b6254">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>federally funded research and development centers;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="idfce95bade786446ebbe4dac8421127e5"> <enum>(3)</enum> <text>nonprofit research institutions;</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id8387e7ca60f24526b6b404c4392eb276">
                    <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>industry and other private sector entities;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="id5a1fc4aaf7e34449b2dba78c41207527"> <enum>(5)</enum> <text>other entities determined appropriate by the Director to carry out the purposes of this section; and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id6705b6e052174dc59c01a5152aa4c46d">
                    <enum>(6)</enum>
 <text>consortia of entities described in paragraphs (1) through (5).</text> </paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="ide801a6056aa04ce9a3e160276a4e457d"> <enum>(d)</enum> <header>Award basis</header> <paragraph id="id57faab3386b54c2189a34691b4924ee9"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>Selection criteria</header> <text>In selecting recipients for an award under this section, the Director shall consider, at a minimum—</text>
                    <subparagraph id="idf66994a79b1b4464882083a62366258b">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>the path for developing and, as appropriate, commercializing the organism or similar organisms produced with biotechnology and resulting products in the United States;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id449141e4d73246848f602fe7905ba22a">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>the current knowledge of similar organisms (as of the date of the award), the limits of such current knowledge, and the novelty and risks of the proposed project;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="idb7e6e5e3aa734bf5829255e921696fdd">
                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>the relevance of the project to the research priorities under paragraph (2) and the potential of the project to advance such priorities; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id27ba1002fe6746b4ab7838f08c1bc4b3">
                        <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>the ethical, legal, and social implications of the project.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="id8eb80d85866d47d7805a5f22d895c0fa"> <enum>(2)</enum> <header>Research priorities</header> <text>In awarding funding under this section, the Director shall give priority to research designed to—</text>
                    <subparagraph id="idc2d26acbe262488fa49d1dcedc32f7ac">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>identify unintended effects of biotechnology methods, including unintended genetic changes;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id4ad2979bb342485e801f12c645b6a130">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>identify and develop management practices to minimize environmental, human health, or animal health risks associated with organisms produced with biotechnology, in research or field trial conditions, in commercial production, and in use as a final product;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id0e1729d2c176401cbef1672097f6db6e">
                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>develop methods to monitor the dispersal and persistence of organisms produced with biotechnology, including gene drives;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="ide77c9e9b46214eb48d5f6357b071c673">
                        <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>identify the characteristics, rates, and methods of gene transfer that may occur between organisms produced with biotechnology and related wild and agricultural organisms;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="idff9414fd8d864e598aabec326eaefab2">
                        <enum>(E)</enum>
 <text>compare the impacts of organisms produced with biotechnology to impacts of comparable organisms that were not produced with biotechnology or to other human activities in the environment;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="iddc9d6827a1b244ab91056c1273d61be6">
                        <enum>(F)</enum>
 <text>identify potential risks of convergence of biotechnology with artificial intelligence and other emerging technologies; or</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="idb2fde066a06f43b8853aded42569dada">
                        <enum>(G)</enum>
 <text>address other topics that further the purposes of this section.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="id16d0174968b44266bbecccece078cd33"> <enum>(e)</enum> <header>Metrics</header> <text>When appropriate, the Director may—</text>
                <paragraph id="idba2efbd3fc084785a9aa1a3f81b51870">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>set metrics in the terms of an award under this section, including goals and deadlines; and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="idedb27b4aa57944f1aa736782b4a8656d">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>use such metrics to determine whether a project carried out under this section shall be eligible for continued or additional funding.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="idd4f52c28d83c41f292f6de5399e83232">
                <enum>(f)</enum>
                <header>Regulatory coordination</header>
 <text>The Director shall consult with the Secretary of Agriculture, the Commissioner of Food and Drugs, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, and the heads of other Federal agencies with relevant expertise as determined by the Director, to—</text>
                <paragraph id="ida235a6d147a84d0eb6388ad68417137c">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>determine the applicability of specific areas of research to the regulation of products produced with biotechnology;</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id618a7dbacbb04f9488dce1e1a3091557">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>provide ongoing oversight and execution of projects carried out under this section; and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id8096ab66edb3403094abc054024cf22a">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>provide regulatory assistance to facilitate the purposes of this section.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id0e3e2e1446754a8f8f0b020affee8b21">
                <enum>(g)</enum>
                <header>Funding</header>
                <paragraph id="id0a57f593e58c4c66afd4d7de91968b06">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                    <header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
 <text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Directorate for Technology, Innovation, and Partnerships to carry out this section $50,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id2b998b7a28734f5bb1ac3e442bc2f693">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Additional funding</header>
 <text>In addition to using amounts made available under paragraph (1) for the program carried out under this section, the Director may—</text>
                    <subparagraph id="idc7eef003d2b743c68110a5815a8e784c">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>make this program a priority of the National Science Foundation; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id262b104a56ca4f40bcec5b9f47ed0c96">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>elect to use other funds that are available to the Director and not otherwise restricted in their use to carry out the program.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
        </section>
        <section id="idab15dc4036aa456786b2960a704f086d">
            <enum>4.</enum>
            <header>National academies biotechnology 2-phase study and reports</header>
            <subsection id="id11a37613ee334f7cbd736f6e3e71d214">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
 <text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director of the National Science Foundation (referred to in this section as the <quote>Director</quote>), in consultation with the Secretary of Agriculture, the Commissioner of Food and Drugs, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, and heads of other Federal agencies with relevant expertise as determined by the Director, shall enter into an agreement with the National Academies of Science, Engineering, and Medicine (referred to in this section as the <quote>National Academies</quote>)—</text>
                <paragraph id="idd76f0f07d6234aed8c6f51784e82c7f7">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>to conduct a 2-phase study, in accordance with subsections (b) and (c), on the safety and benefits of biotechnology; and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id82c855a3c662469c84ba7ceb6268c6d3">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>to submit reports describing the results of the studies and including findings and recommendations, in accordance with subsection (d).</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id70a4b462dc714222aa60b8355afecf8b">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Phase one of study</header>
 <text>Not later than 1 year after the date on which the agreement described in subsection (a) is entered into, the National Academies shall complete phase one of the study, which shall, at a minimum—</text>
                <paragraph id="id48fb346b22684b62a7a8bf1241895088">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>consider the characteristics and risks of biotechnology tools used to modify genetic sequences in comparison to the characteristics and risks of comparable conventional methods used to modify genetic sequences;</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="idf4c3b9e74eba43afb96b3039eea539ef">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>make recommendations about risk-proportionate frameworks to assess risks of products made with biotechnology tools; and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="idadd6cae2b4e04588933a90c4dfab0a10">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>identify research needed to further understand the safety of biotechnology tools.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id3d95f19f75854a45970e535ae988b65a">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Phase two of study</header>
 <text>Not later than 2 years after the date on which the agreement described in subsection (a) is entered into, the National Academies shall complete phase two of the study, which shall, at a minimum—</text>
                <paragraph id="id9394e8a636754d1ea956f78b11acd954">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>consider the safety and benefits of commercialized biotechnology products alongside comparable conventional products and other human activities that may impact human health or the environment;</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id5702b28c84304e42a694088d66be9a65">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>make recommendations about evaluating the safety and potential benefits of future biotechnology products that are under development or not yet widely commercialized;</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id766fa405dbb841f4a85c82211e947ad6">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>make recommendations about processes, analysis, or tests that could be used to rapidly reduce or remove biotechnology-specific oversight of products that do not present a greater risk than comparable conventional products or other human activities; and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="iddd3ffe6133c5439991c093915a2cd837">
                    <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>identify research needed to further understand safety or benefits of biotechnology products.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id05ab14f61f174718a72d2db4ed2f80bf">
                <enum>(d)</enum>
                <header>Reports</header>
 <text>Within 90 days of completion of each phase of the study under subsections (b) and (c), the National Academies shall—</text>
                <paragraph id="ida736add2240f473593688d12b1497454">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>submit a report that includes any findings and recommendations of the National Academies made pursuant to the applicable phase of the study to the Director, the heads of the agencies with which the Director consulted under subsection (a), and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives; and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id9c8cc7e4cb0b4152aff4b9583b3c02ff">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>make each such report submitted under paragraph (1) available on a publicly accessible website.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id2f403146e9a7411dad1004ddc9803551">
                <enum>(e)</enum>
                <header>Implementation plan</header>
 <text>Not later than 180 days after the date on which all reports from the National Academies under subsection (d) have been submitted to the Director, the Director, in consultation with the heads of the agencies named in subsection (a), shall submit to Congress an implementation plan for Federal research, development, and demonstration activities for the purpose of closing any research gaps related to the safety of biotechnology tools and products.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id2a83dd72727f4899b90807022629d390">
                <enum>(f)</enum>
                <header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
 <text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $1,500,000 for fiscal year 2026.</text>
            </subsection>
        </section>
    </legis-body>
</bill>

