<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ELL25533-MTH-RC-GWL"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2542 IS: Federal Building Threat Notification Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2542</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250730">July 30, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S380">Mr. Peters</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S378">Mr. Lankford</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S376">Ms. Ernst</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To direct the Director of the Federal Protective Service to establish guidance relating to emergency protocols for buildings, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Federal Building Threat Notification Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id0da2575374cd46c6b183f0cd85652183"><enum>2.</enum><header>Guidance for buildings</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id821c6a54a2c0445091699df0d076461d"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <term>law enforcement-related</term> means requiring a law enforcement response.</text></subsection><subsection id="id63138718a06d4c7ebba4c0e5f995b04d"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Guidance</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4d83e0080672447096c73a69c66a8532"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director of the Federal Protective Service shall, in coordination with the Secretary of Homeland Security, develop and implement guidance for emergency communication regarding law enforcement-related events for Federal tenants in buildings under the protection of the Federal Protective Service.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb190d3ad778141deb6f1adee5657b8de"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The guidance developed under subsection (b) shall include best practices and protocols relating to—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8d23cc88193d471c995db74ecc576d13"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">standard operating procedures to inform building tenants in a timely manner of violent threats in the building or within approximately 150 feet of the building perimeter, including all firearm events, other weapons threats, acts of or threats of potential, suspected, or confirmed terrorism, and the discovery of suspicious devices or materials; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id25c1c57595bd439880b3af1fdc43b4fd"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensuring that tenants receive instructions for safety practices in response to an immediate threat or a heightened risk of a threat.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc1eaca67f7d4426191aa1b97ff304df6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Security officials</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6c3d0087baa34f6781fc69032df34306"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The designated official of the Facility Security Committee for each building under the protection of the Federal Protective Service shall be responsible for implementing the guidance at the respective building.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id77296d8a17d046a99bc508a7e69d0e30"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Designated official</header><text>Consistent with the Interagency Security Committee guidelines and applicable Federal law, the Director of the Federal Protective Service shall confirm that each department or agency with a building or office space under the protection of the Federal Protective Service has a designated official of the Facility Security Committee.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id667918b8a57346878c6f67736d8bea56"> <enum>(d)</enum> <header>Assessment of law enforcement-Related crisis response</header> <text>The Director of the Federal Protective Service shall—</text>
        <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
          id="ida25fe7e01d894aa69958752989db6975">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure that all Federal tenants in buildings under the protection of the Federal Protective Service are able to adequately respond to a law enforcement-related crisis; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
          id="id733d619833ce4e289ad05e5c97f03549">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conduct periodic testing to prepare for such event.</text>
        </paragraph>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1b6c7fe492f14aeda538c2bcb010a65d"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id66225f252fbc4410bcb42f1b70b1db69"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director of the Federal Protective Service shall, in coordination with the Secretary of Homeland Security, electronically submit to Congress a report, not longer than 10 pages, on the best practices and protocols implemented under this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id239f64ba16e4438893200e7ccf36de5e"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Briefing</header><text>The Director of the Federal Protective Service shall provide to Congress a briefing on the report required under paragraph (1) and shall present any information relating to support needed to maintain the safety of buildings under the protection of the Federal Protective Service.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

