<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-OLL25663-YM2-JV-X24">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2155 IS: Keeping Gun Dealers Honest Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>II</distribution-code>
        <congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session>1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. 2155</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action>
            <action-date date="20250624">June 24, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S364">Mr.
                    Murphy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S259">Mr. Reed</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S247">Mr.
                    Wyden</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S316">Mr. Whitehouse</cosponsor>,
                    <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>,
                    <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S394">Ms. Smith</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was
                read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on
                    the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title>To ensure greater accountability by licensed firearms
            dealers.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H11434DE2C30F408D966684B944D903BD">
        <section section-type="section-one" id="id1C56897674004629B9C7009AED2145E8">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Keeping Gun Dealers Honest Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section id="HB31D2D1EDC77476680B2290D2002659F">
            <enum>2.</enum>
            <header>Increasing the number of allowed compliance inspections of firearms
                dealers</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 923(g)(1)(B)(ii)(I) of title 18, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>once</quote> and inserting <quote>3 times</quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section id="H292E5FDEDCE847FE9B14A1860434AC1A">
            <enum>3.</enum>
            <header>Increasing penalties on firearms licensees</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 924(a)(3) of title 18, United States Code, is amended in the matter following subparagraph (B) by striking <quote>one year</quote> and inserting <quote>5 years</quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section id="H394B38666C66449BA4EA5D4CC22F9C43">
            <enum>4.</enum>
            <header>Serious recordkeeping offenses that aid gun trafficking</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 924(a)(3) of title 18, United States Code, is amended by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>. If the conduct described in subparagraph (A) or (B) is in relation to an offense under subsection (a)(6) or (d) of section 922, the licensed dealer, licensed importer, licensed manufacturer, or licensed collector shall be fined under this title, imprisoned for not more than 10 years, or both.</quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section id="H7183825BB35C4C7D821161BEFD5AC1DD">
            <enum>5.</enum>
            <header>Suspension of firearms dealer’s license and civil penalties for violations of
                the Gun Control Act</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 923 of title 18, United States Code, is amended by striking subsections (e) and (f) and inserting the following:</text>
            <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H35ADE72A74974E4699F0E99407626A1A">
                <subsection id="H0FF17ABAC84741B195B89058AF789E61">
                    <enum>(e)</enum>
                    <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idCB1A265F26134D0DBC94267A7B513CDA">
                        <enum>(1)</enum>
                        <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id70A4734E163540588F52B971819EEB29">
                            <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>The Attorney General may, after notice and opportunity for hearing, suspend or revoke any license issued under this section, or may subject the licensee to a civil penalty of not more than $10,000 per violation, if the holder of the license—</text>
                            <clause id="id0B34963BEE414939AC5319F4FC062909" indent="up2">
                                <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>has violated any provision of this chapter or any rule or regulation prescribed by the Attorney General under this chapter; or</text>
                            </clause>
                            <clause id="id1E834CEBD92B4B3EBCF5D0C459FEA9AF" indent="up2">
                                <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>except as provided in subparagraph (B), fails to have secure gun storage or safety devices available at any place in which firearms are sold under the license to persons who are not licensees.</text>
                            </clause>
                        </subparagraph>
                        <subparagraph id="id39F1B2520B5B433E860303C234C1F8E5" indent="up2">
                            <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>Subparagraph (A)(ii) shall not apply in any case in which a secure gun storage or safety device is temporarily unavailable because of theft, casualty loss, consumer sales, backorders from a manufacturer, or any other similar reason beyond the control of the licensee.</text>
                        </subparagraph>
                    </paragraph>
                    <paragraph id="id9DF26039911749E682E3536CF40B2DF9" indent="up1">
                        <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>The Attorney General may, after notice and opportunity for hearing, suspend or revoke the license of, or assess a civil penalty of not more than $10,000 on, a dealer who transfers armor piercing ammunition.</text>
                    </paragraph>
                    <paragraph id="id0B0D1E42FC8A4A25ADD3D5E54BC1F162" indent="up1">
                        <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>The Attorney General may at any time compromise, mitigate, or remit the liability with respect to any violation of this chapter or any rule or regulation prescribed by the Attorney General under this chapter.</text>
                    </paragraph>
                    <paragraph id="id1690C4619AC442B1A899304FCB879AAD" indent="up1">
                        <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>The Attorney General’s actions under this subsection may be reviewed only as provided in subsection (f).</text>
                    </paragraph>
                </subsection>
                <subsection id="H70F8EB5DD50E418EBF66ED7051860C48">
                    <enum>(f)</enum>
                    <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HDAC4BC4B06AB4963AFAD0FD02AAA93A2">
                        <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>Any person whose application for a license is denied and any holder of a license which is suspended or revoked or who is assessed a civil penalty shall receive a written notice from the Attorney General stating specifically the grounds upon which the application was denied or upon which the license was suspended or revoked or the civil penalty assessed. Any notice of a suspension or revocation of a license shall be given to the holder of the license before the effective date of the suspension or revocation.</text>
                    </paragraph>
                    <paragraph id="H74D23443502A4D49B981606113D82E61" indent="up1">
                        <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>If the Attorney General denies an application for a license, or suspends or revokes a license, or assesses a civil penalty, the Attorney General shall, upon request by the aggrieved party, promptly hold a hearing to review the denial, suspension, revocation, or assessment. In the case of a suspension or revocation of a license, the Attorney General shall, on the request of the holder of the license, stay the effective date of the suspension or revocation. A hearing under this paragraph shall be held at a location convenient to the aggrieved party.</text>
                    </paragraph>
                    <paragraph id="H83846C4E266A4A749924EA53A72E98B7" indent="up1">
                        <enum>(3)</enum>
                        <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id97EBF9F81BD54CA898A75B1401AB4440">
                            <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>If after a hearing held under paragraph (2) the Attorney General decides not to reverse the decision to deny an application or suspend or revoke a license or assess a civil penalty, the Attorney General shall give notice of the decision to the aggrieved party.</text>
                        </subparagraph>
                        <subparagraph id="id816EC41D16C34BA2981A71A018816259" indent="up1">
                            <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>The aggrieved party may at any time within 60 days after the date notice is given under subparagraph (A) file a petition with the United States district court for the district in which the party resides or in which the party’s principal place of business is located for a de novo judicial review of the denial, suspension, revocation, or assessment.</text>
                        </subparagraph>
                        <subparagraph id="id677437B065234776ABE176C00DA0E1B1" indent="up1">
                            <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>In a proceeding conducted under this paragraph, the court may consider any evidence submitted by the parties to the proceeding without regard to whether such evidence was considered at the hearing held under paragraph (2).</text>
                        </subparagraph>
                        <subparagraph id="id845DE2EF740B4C24B78DD04E55A5CC2A" indent="up1">
                            <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>If the court decides that the Attorney General was not authorized to deny the application or to suspend or revoke the license or to assess the civil penalty, the court shall order the Attorney General to take such action as may be necessary to comply with the judgment of the court.</text>
                        </subparagraph>
                    </paragraph>
                </subsection>
                <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
            </quoted-block>
        </section>
        <section id="H4AC13AF3B51D42B6881BB652D88D7AA4">
            <enum>6.</enum>
            <header>Termination of firearms dealer’s license upon felony conviction</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 925(b) of title 18, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>until any conviction pursuant to the indictment becomes final</quote> and inserting <quote>until the date of any conviction pursuant to the indictment</quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section id="H93DF6CA2C0F24D8CBB2E864F99286E9A">
            <enum>7.</enum>
            <header>Authority to hire additional personnel</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Director of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives may hire at least 80 additional employees for the purpose of carrying out additional inspections as provided for in the amendments made by this Act.</text>
        </section>
        <section id="H41328AA44DD64C7D83F6D9DCEF5EF2CA">
            <enum>8.</enum>
            <header>Authority to require licensed dealer to conduct a physical inventory and provide
                inventory record if dealer has unlawfully transferred a firearm or
                    <enum-in-header>10</enum-in-header> or more crime guns are traced to the
                dealer</header>
            <subsection id="H0A75A74F103944FF835071534141C9E2">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 923(g)(1) of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
                <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDBAE3E59594F46E484B25491662D5C94">
                    <subparagraph id="HC6B5631A52264AD4AA20E63BF0D904BD" indent="up2">
                        <enum>(E)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General may require a licensed importer, licensed manufacturer, or licensed dealer to conduct a physical inventory of the firearms in the business inventory of the licensee, and provide the Attorney General with a detailed record of the physical inventory if—</text>
                        <clause id="HE1377AF3A7A949D9902BF5632AE51AEC">
                            <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>the licensee has been convicted of transferring a firearm unlawfully; or</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="HE973756108F14C48B13A9B9C70E6EB5D">
                            <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>the Attorney General finds that 10 or more firearms used in a crime under Federal, State, or local law have been traced back to the licensee.</text>
                        </clause>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
                </quoted-block>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H40F77143DF4746A29DA8CBFA97FC9BD9">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Conforming amendments</header>
                <paragraph id="H3966D745B9294FCFBC1335511292B5E3">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 923(j) of title 18, United States Code, is amended in the sixth sentence by inserting <quote>, except as required under subsection (g)(1)(E)</quote> before the period.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HEDB76001A8474165AFCC8088EE4D5A16">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The matter under the heading <quote><header-in-text level="appropriations-small" style="OLC">salaries and expenses</header-in-text></quote> under the heading <quote><header-in-text level="appropriations-intermediate" style="OLC">Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives</header-in-text></quote> under title II of division B of the Consolidated and Further Continuing Appropriations Act, 2013 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/6">Public Law 113–6</external-xref>; 127 Stat. 247) is amended in the fifth proviso by inserting <quote>, except as required under subsection (g)(1)(E) of such section 923</quote> before the colon.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
        </section>
        <section id="HCC12E0D3E6D04BFEB322C5743FD4A6AC">
            <enum>9.</enum>
            <header>Issuance of licenses</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 923 of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text>
            <paragraph id="H6384B56FE69142C3B904265EE35C3699">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>in subsection (c)—</text> <subparagraph id="id655E63DC24CB4162B091A4F2C05C796A"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>by inserting <quote>(1)</quote> before <quote>Upon</quote>;</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="id79CF1D468C884BD6BBC923BB1BF04CC2">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>in the first sentence, by inserting <quote>, subject to paragraph (2),</quote> after <quote>Attorney General shall</quote>; and</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="idF39E441E576548C7A6B24455BA979FE4">
                    <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id92E1664F916D457DA714122892507E56"> <paragraph id="id65E1276D30264C54B389247AEC2805CE" indent="up1"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>The Attorney General may deny an application submitted under subsection (a) or (b) if the Attorney General determines that—</text>
                            <subparagraph id="id65EEF69389564888B6A75FBE1B5E52E7">
                                <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>issuing the license would pose a danger to public safety; or</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <subparagraph id="id2CABEFAFF5EE466385903FB72B6FC34B">
                                <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>the applicant—</text> <clause id="idA6E35B729E9647E5A8F910117F1D8D8C"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>is not likely to comply with the law; or</text>
                                </clause>
                                <clause id="id5C8EDD4FBFDC44F1999F85678556E26A">
                                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>is otherwise not suitable to be issued a license.</text> </clause> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block> </quoted-block> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H8107615731EB424C810A3EF22A16602F"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>in subsection (d)(1), in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by inserting <quote>, subject to subsection (c)(2),</quote> after <quote>shall</quote>.</text>
            </paragraph>
        </section>
        <section id="H5B014FC4DA344C3CB44E466DE3029F11">
            <enum>10.</enum>
            <header>Liability standards</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 923 of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text>
            <paragraph id="id0B796AAFA9B14A68AF13427F59CAF615">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (c), in the third sentence, by striking <quote>willfully</quote>; and</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="id3B25F82BE5024182B01D13B2232E78D7">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>in subsection (d)(1), by striking <quote>willfully</quote> each place it appears.</text>
            </paragraph>
        </section>
        <section id="HA6CD3154AB7246FA92880A7D4257E0AB">
            <enum>11.</enum>
            <header>Regulatory flexibility</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 926(a) of title 18, United States Code, is amended, in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by striking <quote>only</quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section id="H30FEA3AC614B432A81013D80996537E9">
            <enum>12.</enum>
            <header>Report to Congress</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Director of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives shall submit biennial reports to Congress on the implementation of this Act and the amendments made by this Act, which shall include—</text>
            <paragraph id="id15A42A68681E4B61971D2E2D7F6CC842">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a statement by the Director as to what additional resources, if any, are necessary in order to implement this Act and the amendments made by this Act; and</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="idEDEC17B8A15A4062A1D529E8C36AEBAE">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any recommendations of the Director for how better to ensure that—</text>
                <subparagraph id="id386BDFAB3DBF40CA9CA33603018A9F70">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">firearms dealers are complying with all laws and regulations that apply with respect to dealing in firearms; and</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="idA1A33001AF634D688C07FF3A65ACB5CC">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">noncompliant firearms dealers are subject to appropriate action in a timely manner.</text>
                </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
        </section>
        <section id="idd22258af00344b058dcd0ee2e9f24ba4">
            <enum>13.</enum>
            <header>Severability</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any provision of this Act or of an amendment made by this Act, or the application of such a provision to any person or circumstance, is held to be invalid, the remainder of this Act or of such an amendment, or the application of this Act or of such an amendment to other persons or circumstances, shall not be affected.</text>
        </section>
    </legis-body>
</bill>

