<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-RYA25362-FH7-CS-032">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2450 IS: Biochar Research Network Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>II</distribution-code>
        <congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session>1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. 2450</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action>
            <action-date date="20250724">July 24, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S153">Mr. Grassley</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S359">Mr. Heinrich</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which
                was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAF00">Committee
                    on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title>To amend the Agricultural Research, Extension, and Education Reform Act of
            1998 to direct the Secretary of Agriculture to establish a national biochar research
            network, and for other purposes.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HA3D2524570544EC791C047386DD1029D">
        <section section-type="section-one" id="H071CF66B97B3451C94DCEC676C0EC015">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Biochar Research Network Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section id="H68F1D2FE1717457584C61290BD76B5E5">
            <enum>2.</enum>
            <header>National biochar research network</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title IV of the Agricultural Research, Extension, and Education Reform Act of 1998 is amended by inserting before section 404 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/7624">7 U.S.C. 7624</external-xref>) the following:</text>
            <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7F711297592F49FB8BFE52B6901E4960">
                <section id="H3B31043F913C4040BF76F3035ACA3751">
                    <enum>403.</enum>
                    <header>National biochar research network</header>
                    <subsection id="H9007CC77BE9241FD960DB878B0FB58B6">
                        <enum>(a)</enum>
                        <header>Establishment</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish a national biochar research network (referred to in this section as the <term>research network</term>) of not more than 20 research sites or facilities described in subsection (c) to test the full range of biochar types across soil types, soil health and soil management conditions, application methods, and climatic and agronomic regions—</text>
                        <paragraph id="HCB8554BB45534B7495CAA6B1640B4AB0">
                            <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>to assess the soil carbon sequestration potential of various biochars and management systems integrating biochar use; </text>
                        </paragraph>
                        <paragraph id="H406F42EDB2384524B8D6AD660887B732">
                            <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>to understand how to use biochar productively to contribute to climate mitigation, crop production, resilience to extreme weather events, ecosystem and soil health, natural resource conservation, and farm profitability; and</text>
                        </paragraph>
                        <paragraph id="HE454F98FA6E441DFB18B6526AB5F8010">
                            <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>to deliver science-based, region-specific, cost-effective, and practical information to farmers, ranchers, foresters, land reclamation managers, urban land managers, and other land and natural resource managers and businesses on sustainable biochar production and application.</text>
                        </paragraph>
                    </subsection>
                    <subsection id="H97BE5FFC8A0646968C0AC1926D598B9A">
                        <enum>(b)</enum>
                        <header>Scope</header>
                        <paragraph id="id2657161762A4428EAB8054A53166FBD0">
                            <enum>(1)</enum>
                            <header>In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The research network shall encompass—</text>
                            <subparagraph id="idC0FFD0EF279E4CA7B36A285BB97CAF51">
                                <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">agriculture, horticulture, rangeland, forestry, and other biochar uses; and </text>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <subparagraph id="id46AB2845164A4A478BBD455A899F79B4">
                                <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a broad range of feedstocks, production processes, and application treatments. </text>
                            </subparagraph>
                        </paragraph>
                        <paragraph id="id3FCD6FC8A62649BBBC51FB7A5F6BB441">
                            <enum>(2)</enum>
                            <header>Research</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The research conducted by the research network shall include—</text>
                            <subparagraph id="HA1EE270339F5462AB39B298E5D5EA17D">
                                <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">cross-site and mechanistic experiments—</text>
                                <clause id="H6ED3F06549B74B979EF9E40DFE08E79B">
                                    <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>to fill critical knowledge gaps and gain a more complete understanding of the impact of various types of biochar in varying site conditions on soil properties, plant growth, greenhouse gas emissions, and carbon sequestration in different soils, climates, and other natural and agronomic conditions;</text>
                                </clause>
                                <clause id="H754030F2254B4AA6B104BAD31341BD62">
                                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>to provide mechanistic and technoeconomic insights on thermochemical conversion processes in biochar production and the coproduction of biochar and bioenergy, including interactions of feedstock properties with reactor conditions and processes on the relative proportions and properties of biochar, biofuels, and value-added coproducts, as well as process efficiency;</text>
                                </clause>
                                <clause id="H8C5CB9EA2AA84BD1A4532EF1175CD4D8">
                                    <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>to generate data to develop, calibrate, and validate robust mechanistic models to predict the full life cycle of greenhouse gas, crop response, and related agronomic and environmental implications of particular applications of biochar; </text>
                                </clause>
                                <clause id="HF4C5D9EFA8CE416694AE303539429D0E">
                                    <enum>(iv)</enum>
 <text>to generate data to help guide the design of new, more efficient biochar and bioenergy production reactors and biorefineries; and</text>
                                </clause>
                                <clause id="H4A8A70B67E1840578951481C9C1555DB">
                                    <enum>(v)</enum>
 <text>to generate data to develop, calibrate, and validate testing methodologies for biochar to identify potential contaminants or other factors that may cause unintended consequences; and</text>
                                </clause>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <subparagraph id="HBB6A8AE52689458F926C3FCBF27F4B6B">
                                <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">site-specific farm and forestry systems assessments and pilot-scale biochar production and application systems—</text>
                                <clause id="H4FFE37F8FBC548A8A765D1EE559C6734">
                                    <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to refine the most promising soil-based uses, sources, and methods of producing and applying biochar in particular regions—</text>
                                    <subclause id="idF19FE87A0A5D4C01A069407B95E0C9D5">
                                        <enum>(I)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to enhance productivity;</text>
                                    </subclause>
                                    <subclause id="id6FB20BE0179542C8A50AD126FEFE603E">
                                        <enum>(II)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to increase profitability, scalability, and portability;</text>
                                    </subclause>
                                    <subclause id="id98A69E7CE2DC4D5DAB30E1D7D6935713">
                                        <enum>(III)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to reduce greenhouse gas emissions;</text>
                                    </subclause>
                                    <subclause id="id7147D7F4C99B4293BB2C8FD5AF41770E">
                                        <enum>(IV)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to improve ecosystem and soil health; </text>
                                    </subclause>
                                    <subclause id="idBBD63A78D3A54AAFB7F59C518ABA4E6A">
                                        <enum>(V)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to strengthen resilience to extreme weather events; and </text>
                                    </subclause>
                                    <subclause id="id2DBAB8E8023046BC8E0A551FCD885443">
                                        <enum>(VI)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to explore soil, crop, climate, management, and biochar interactions;</text>
                                    </subclause>
                                </clause>
                                <clause id="HAAE6C5B7B2314B4687AFC0DBE1C83CB7">
                                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>to develop new knowledge to support decisions on sustainable production and use of biochar;</text>
                                </clause>
                                <clause id="H9F53767A86924FE18DC94855037764E8">
                                    <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>to collect relevant data needed for full life cycle greenhouse gas and economic analyses and complete those analysis; </text>
                                </clause>
                                <clause id="HDEC5C10B02D5423DB405AFA6A01DBEFA">
                                    <enum>(iv)</enum>
 <text>to predict plant response, soil health, soil carbon sequestration, ecosystem health, water quality, greenhouse gas, and economic outcomes for specific implementations of biochar technology; </text>
                                </clause>
                                <clause id="H698753C55BEC4EC1A2F4010C63B4DBC9">
                                    <enum>(v)</enum>
 <text>to provide data to evaluate local biomass feedstocks, support selection of sustainable biochar production methods, and address biochar production issues; and</text>
                                </clause>
                                <clause id="H8DE21C9774E64393A6FF45C3C3891FC6">
                                    <enum>(vi)</enum>
 <text>to share research results to inform farmers, horticulturalists, ranchers, foresters, urban biochar users, extension agents and specialists, and technical assistance providers on the most advantageous ways to use biochar to increase profitability, raise productivity, lower costs, improve soil and plant health, and enhance resilience to extreme weather events while contributing to carbon sequestration and greenhouse gas reductions.</text>
                                </clause>
                            </subparagraph>
                        </paragraph>
                    </subsection>
                    <subsection id="H4162EF79257345AAA6B8ACCCAF8AEAB8">
                        <enum>(c)</enum>
                        <header>Eligibility</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An entity shall be eligible to be selected to conduct research as part of the research network if the entity is—</text>
                        <paragraph id="HE54496A3896648EEA68532F86E18061B">
                            <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>a State agricultural experiment station or a State forestry experiment station;</text>
                        </paragraph>
                        <paragraph id="H3079B215A2BC4BC0A0C15E0ACD790FD9">
                            <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>a research facility of the Agricultural Research Service, the Forest Service, or any other agency of the Department of Agriculture that the Secretary determines to be appropriate; or</text>
                        </paragraph>
                        <paragraph id="HAF4DD6D0C4C5484CB03CC7DCF9B8F0DA">
                            <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>a research facility of the Department of Energy, the Department of Commerce, or the Department of the Interior.</text>
                        </paragraph>
                    </subsection>
                    <subsection id="HD81861E057C449BBBF3BBDB5ED82AC7B">
                        <enum>(d)</enum>
                        <header>Administration</header>
                        <paragraph id="HD73EF447A92046859519F49FB7F7F250">
                            <enum>(1)</enum>
                            <header>In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The research network shall be administered by the Administrator of the Agricultural Research Service, in partnership with—</text>
                            <subparagraph id="idF376BFC7A90447C29194696BA641231B">
                                <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Chief of the Forest Service;</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <subparagraph id="id25F8F060D2FE47A78176A6A6535E174B">
                                <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Director of the National Institute of Food and Agriculture;</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <subparagraph id="id713831E974294FC8AFC61C7717ABB2EB">
                                <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary of Energy;</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <subparagraph id="idF55B477CD37440B9AAA67A20B49BABF7">
                                <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary of Commerce;</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <subparagraph id="id0638BE9D00DA4D109038D050D4AFB8D0">
                                <enum>(E)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary of the Interior; and </text>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <subparagraph id="idE47A716BE84A484C9FE34E40778A4CB7">
                                <enum>(F)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such other agencies of the Department of Agriculture as the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                        </paragraph>
                        <paragraph id="H18B480CC9FBD4C1C9EF37DFA15265541">
                            <enum>(2)</enum>
                            <header>Conservation</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, acting through the Chief of the Natural Resources Conservation Service—</text>
                            <subparagraph id="HB3634FC7E26B418DB551DBBFEDE0A09D">
                                <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>may develop or revise practice standards informed by the research conducted by the research network; and</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <subparagraph id="H0CDF0166E94B4D0A9FC2B823514D9237">
                                <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>shall coordinate the activities of the research network with—</text>
                                <clause id="HBD100DF9623A40B3940FF7BACAECC3F3">
                                    <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the development, expansion, and refinement of conservation practice standards for biochar production and use for soil and forest health, climate adaptation and mitigation, and other conservation purposes; and </text>
                                </clause>
                                <clause id="H510549B136BE4D9CB6EF99F9CF25FC45">
                                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>improvements and expansion of conservation program technical and financial support for biochar production, application, and integration into soil health management systems and other conservation approaches.</text>
                                </clause>
                            </subparagraph>
                        </paragraph>
                    </subsection>
                    <subsection id="HE1D67342B12A43DBB0D19F2D7E51020D">
                        <enum>(e)</enum>
                        <header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $50,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2025 through 2030.</text>
                    </subsection>
                </section>
                <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
            </quoted-block>
        </section>
    </legis-body>
</bill>

