<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-BAG25119-98P-Y1-0C4"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S435 IS: Increasing Response Options and Deterrence of Missile Engagements Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code> 
<congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>S. 435</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20250205">February 5, 2025</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S383">Mr. Sullivan</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S398">Mr. Cramer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To improve the missile defense capabilities of the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HC1A6C1ACECB441A1B78A42AB08F7AE95"> 
<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Increasing Response Options and Deterrence of Missile Engagements Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>IRONDOME Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd62e8872041341b49574a54c99c27887"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings; sense of the Senate</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide75cab845de9458392ab2a95eb5e9b14"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Findings</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfaef7a5c638d4d9d836d77b9b357302d"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Missile Defense review</header><text>Congress finds that the 2022 Missile Defense Review found the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="idc98997b77cd9479eb1164f149340a8e4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Since the release of the 2019 Missile Defense Review, missile-related threats have rapidly expanded in quantity, diversity, and sophistication.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id783b20f9c57b43238f8876498da31951"><enum>(B)</enum><text>United States national security interests are increasingly at risk from wide-ranging missile arsenals that include offensive ballistic, cruise, and hypersonic weapons.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="id5b198db0afec4379b039e8381034d8e5"><enum>(C)</enum><text> In support of the homeland missile defense mission, continued modernization and expansion of the Ground-based Midcourse Defense (GMD) system will remain an essential element of our comprehensive missile defeat approach. In addition, the United States will also continue to improve defensive capabilities to address the threat of evolving cruise missile strikes by any adversary against the homeland.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id41740deb76644e2ebbe9f2d233d01509"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The continued evolution and progress of missiles as a principal means by which adversaries seek to project conventional or nuclear military power makes missile defense a core deterrence-by-denial component of an integrated deterrence strategy.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="id46cfffe125844e11b07d5152efcdb078"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Missile defense capabilities add resilience and undermine adversary confidence in missile use by introducing doubt and uncertainty into strike planning and execution, reducing the incentive to conduct small-scale coercive attacks, decreasing the probability of attack success, and raising the threshold of conflict. </text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id45d0a0e0e1654894b7202d3803cec93c"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Congressional Commission on the Strategic Posture of the United States</header><text>Congress finds that, in its October 2023 report, the Congressional Commission on the Strategic Posture of the United States recommended the following: </text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id12c504367745431e93b78cb841bf09b7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The United States should develop and field homeland integrated air and missile defense (IAMD) that can deter and defeat coercive attacks by Russia and China, and determine the capabilities needed to stay ahead of the North Korean threat.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id7d9cabdbf1574499a5c74420d761c5d7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Secretary of Defense should direct research, development, test and evaluation into advanced integrated air and missile defense capabilities leveraging all domains, including land, sea, air, and space. These activities should focus on sensor architectures, integrated command and control, interceptors, cruise and hypersonic missile defenses, and area or point defenses. The Department of Defense should urgently pursue deployment of any capabilities that prove feasible.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="id157bc6d4e7534f41b3ac19b09c507c57"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Secretary and the military departments should transfer operations and sustainment responsibility for missile defense to the appropriate military departments by October 1, 2024, to allow the Missile Defense Agency (MDA) to focus on research, development, prototyping, and testing. </text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide406c11022a34f19aadccb68ff452482"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Commission on the National Defense Strategy</header><text>Congress finds the following:</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id06a37259f2ea4f2a8a7a7ec312718561"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In its July 2024 report, the Commission on the National Defense Strategy found the following:</text> <clause id="idaade4e3b02d7455aa9ed15a5c508a3ec"><enum>(i)</enum><text>There is an increasing threat from expanding ability of China, Russia, and North Korea to deliver nuclear weapons against the United States, including the territories of the United States.</text></clause> 
<clause id="id85ed64e643d0423b995fe9c248ba176e"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The military planners of the Department of Defense and United States Northern Command need to prepare for a worst-case scenario in which nuclear and other strikes are launched against the United States, which could be done in large numbers with specialized delivery systems.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id1d051793b0924250916ea49072d20cc3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>In the report described in subparagraph (A), the Commission shared the same threat assessment about missile attacks as the Commission on the Strategic Posture of the United States and agreed with the recommendation that the United States should enhance missile defense for the homeland.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="id407756905b9b42ae9171b6cba2d5c363"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Policy</header><text>Congress finds that it is the policy of the Federal Government that<italic></italic>—</text> <subparagraph id="idaf72f9c485b24e06a6d162de46729e08"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Federal Government will provide for the common defense of the citizens of the United States and the United States by deploying and maintaining a next-generation missile defense shield;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="iddfeb7164e11148938af7bbfcb3fde3a4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Federal Government will deter and defend the citizens and critical infrastructure of the United States against any foreign attack on the United States homeland; and </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idc46fb05b50174b28b28ede0b95cc8acc" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Federal Government will guarantee the secure second-strike capability of the Federal Government. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id33e67ab5097d4e53a9295da7afeccf32"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of the Senate</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of the Senate that—</text> <paragraph id="ida13714eab30745d48f662d62d9db4ad2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the threat of attack by ballistic, cruise, and hypersonic missiles remains a catastrophic threat facing the United States and defense against it is a form of both national security and border security;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="ida0fff3cac3044b98ab2f48d3f596ba6b"><enum>(2)</enum><text>China is rapidly expanding and modernizing its conventional forces to include ballistic missile systems posing an increasing threat to citizens, forces, and allies of the United States;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="idcdec567586c74bc69b4b2615a52e279b"><enum>(3)</enum><text>over the past 40 years, rather than lessening, the threat from next-generation strategic weapons, including hypersonic, has become more complex with the development of next-generation delivery systems by adversaries of the United States;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="idb021a73f6159461e81318732b8646891"><enum>(4)</enum><text>notwithstanding this increasing threat, homeland missile defense policy of the United States has been severely limited to staying ahead of rogue nation threats and accidental or unauthorized missile launches;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id26eb40e1759a4589b5fd6ac80a52d4a4"><enum>(5)</enum><text>by empowering the United States with a second-strike capability, the Iron Dome will deter adversaries from attacks on the homeland;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="id84e5a22c40c3436d936e73d40b0363be"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the midcourse defense system is the primary system capable of defending the United States homeland from long-range ballistic missile threats and is critical to our national security;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id4a6283f8c4a449608111b718f25fca14"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the Next Generation Interceptor is a top priority for the Missile Defense Agency and a critical element to increasing system reliability to build warfighter competence; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="id183293d96b084571b33e2cfc4b697e50"><enum>(8)</enum><text>the United States must gain and maintain total domain awareness to provide early warning and defeat of missile threats from both the northern and southern hemispheres and from outer space.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id578adac278164d5a94207a9809f7a80b"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcd604a675e9c46b5bafa1ee32f55cc40"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Congressional defense committees</header><text>The term <term>congressional defense committees</term> has the meaning given such term in section 101(a) of title 10, United States Code.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id0196730125fd4d4ca194cce84bbd772f"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Defense.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id521a6e9f933a4fc283134d854f435aa7"><enum>4.</enum><header>Improving United States missile defense capabilities</header> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6fcbf742a4f04ee99252543528f20a58"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Plan for transfer of operations and sustainment of missile defense to the military departments</header> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida2a6a5e8be2f4397ab29ea4c0cd10f9c"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Plan required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a multi-year phased plan to transfer operations and sustainment responsibility for missile defense from the Missile Defense Agency to the appropriate military departments to allow the Missile Defense Agency to focus on research, development, and prototyping and testing.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id76446b3b2be44948956508528d668ee3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Execution of plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall execute the plan submitted pursuant to paragraph (1) pursuant to a specific authorization of such plan enacted after the date of the enactment of this Act. </text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="id5bfb6bcbbd3b499381886b916bad4ed8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Middle-Tier acquisition program for drone-Based missile threat audio detection system</header><text>The Commander of United States Northern Command shall use a process for conducting a middle tier acquisition described in section 3602 of title 10, United States Code, as added by section 804 of the Servicemember Quality of Life Improvement and National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2025 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/118/159">Public Law 118–159</external-xref>), for rapid fielding and prototyping of a drone-based network for both forward deployed armed forces and homeland defense capable of detecting through audio sensing technology the approach of advanced missiles, including advanced cruise missiles and hypersonic missiles.</text></subsection> <subsection id="idaacb2dde2576414bb121c0d223c3722a"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Middle-Tier acquisition program for proliferated warfighter space architecture of Space Development Agency</header><text>The Director of the Space Development Agency shall use a process for conducting a middle tier acquisition described in section 3602 of title 10, United States Code, as added by section 804 of the Servicemember Quality of Life Improvement and National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2025 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/118/159">Public Law 118–159</external-xref>), for rapid fielding of satellites and associated systems for tranches 3, 4, and 5 of the proliferated warfighter space architecture of the Agency.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="id2d2bd5d4816f47d684b67d8544722081"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Requirement for next generation interceptor fielding and silo construction</header><text>The Secretary shall take such actions as may be necessary to expand Next Generation Interceptor production and silo construction at Fort Greely, Alaska, to field a minimum of 80 interceptors at Fort Greely for defense of the United States to be completed not later than January 1, 2038.</text></subsection> <subsection id="id7f718dcec99b4a43815a1bad7dfb03ea"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Requirement for combatant commands To account for missile defense interceptors and sensor requirements in their annual requests</header><text>For each fiscal year beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act, each commander of a combatant command shall include the missile defense interceptor requirements, terrestrial-based sensor requirements, and space-based sensor requirements of the combatant command of the commander in the supporting information for the Department of Defense submitted along with the budget of the President to Congress for such fiscal year pursuant to section 1105(a) of title 31, United States Code.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="idf84d8f7d19ed4ac68fa271c0c9cb5cc8"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Accelerating development of Glide Phase Interceptor</header> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0535cb1bdcd9472b9512c087857ea8a7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Use of authorities to accelerate development</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall use all authorities available to the Secretary to accelerate development of the Glide Phase Interceptor to defend against hypersonic threats to the United States homeland.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id166c397dce084907994d22c3c25ab84b"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report on potential for parallel development</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of the Missile Defense Agency shall submit to the Secretary a report on the potential for parallel development of capabilities, revised program schedule, and the risk associated with pursuing only one alternative for the Glide Phase Interceptor.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="id6e14dc59d2144b9cbb4a03ff7aefbe40"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Accelerating production and fielding of Terminal High Altitude Area Defense system</header><text>The Secretary shall use all authorities available to the Secretary to accelerate the production and fielding of the Terminal High Altitude Area Defense (THAAD) system (including AN/TPY–2 radars) for forward deployment and homeland defense as the Secretary and President consider appropriate.</text></subsection> <subsection id="id54e07e713e944516bc2aa8ca97916ade"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Accelerating development of autonomous agents To defend against cruise missiles and drones</header><text>The Secretary shall use all authorities available to the Secretary to accelerate development of autonomous agents to cost-effectively defend the United States homeland and forward-deployed armed forces against raids of both large cruise missiles and drones.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="id167499f4e68846a099f04d7033801fbe"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Accelerating development and deployment of space-Based interceptors</header><text>The Secretary shall use all authorities available to the Secretary to accelerate development and deployment of proliferated space-based interceptors capable of boost-phase intercept.</text></subsection> <subsection id="id8287aa36335043dca052c0bf36a074a3"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Report To reduce cost savings per round for space-Based interceptors</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall submit a feasibility study to the congressional defense committees outlining multiple methods for reducing the cost per round of various space-based interceptors including kinetic and non-kinetic capabilities. </text></subsection> 
<subsection id="id07102dcfd90940fca88bf9ffa8ca718b"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Accelerating modernization of certain terrestrial domain capabilities</header><text>The Secretary shall use all authorities available to the Secretary to accelerate modernization of terrestrial-based radar capabilities, including those located at or known as Cobra Dane, Thule Ballistic Missile Early Warning System (BMEWS), Upgraded Early Warning Radar (UEWR) in Greenland and Cape Cod, Homeland Defense Radar in Hawaii, and the Alaska Radar System.</text></subsection> <subsection id="id02f19a94d8d54e989091354b8c72b1e4"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Modernization of Perimeter Acquisition Radar Attack Characterization System</header><text>The Secretary shall use all authorities available to the Secretary to accelerate the modernization and digitization of the Perimeter Acquisition Radar Attack Characterization System (PARCS) to improve detection of intercontinental and sea-launched missile threats, as well as improve space domain awareness capabilities. </text></subsection> 
<subsection id="ida130d721a93b40dc8a0fd537c3444cc9"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Site selection and program execution plan for southern hemisphere-Facing early warning radar system</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report detailing a site selection and proposed program execution plan for a southern hemisphere-facing early warning radar system capable of detecting threats from next generation complex missile attacks.</text></subsection> <subsection id="idfadb70f6bbea42538eaece86471717d3"><enum>(n)</enum><header>Site selection and program execution plan for construction of east coast-Based Aegis Ashore system</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report detailing a site selection and proposed program execution plan for an east coast-based Aegis Ashore missile defense system.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="id6f8d3440e01144bba6036fae297df363"><enum>(o)</enum><header>Site selection and program execution plan for construction of Alaska-Based Aegis Ashore system</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report detailing a site selection and proposed program execution plan for an Alaska-based Aegis Ashore missile defense system.</text></subsection> <subsection id="id12548171bae0444b850e8f09d54123f9"><enum>(p)</enum><header>Completion and certification of Aegis Ashore system in Hawaii</header><text>The Secretary shall use all authorities available to the Secretary to accelerate completion and certification of an Aegis Ashore system based in Hawaii.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="id6dd3cb654f60420cbe39d75082ff54ca"><enum>(q)</enum><header>Acceleration of munitions production for missile defense</header><text>The Secretary shall use all authorities available to the Secretary to accelerate production of critical munitions used for missile interception, including Standard Missile 3 Blocks IB and IIA and PAC–2 and PAC–3 munitions.</text></subsection> <subsection id="id0226e2dfd5604b2fa1f3d871f75082e4"><enum>(r)</enum><header>Expedited military construction authority</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id19f3665863fb4c20951e3edde7015402"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Waiver of regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may waive any and all regulations, including environmental regulations, that the Secretary determines would slow down, impede, block, or otherwise hinder the construction, upgrade, or modernization of infrastructure supporting a Joint Urgent Operational Need (JUON) associated with homeland or forward deployed missile defense.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1b882156e78d47bda70d37a242ac61da"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Congressional notice</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whenever the Secretary uses the authority provided by paragraph (1), the Secretary shall, not later than 45 days after using the authority, submit to the congressional defense committees notice of such use.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="id3fbbcc6acd384e20a65221702243b6f1"><enum>(s)</enum><header>Acceleration of integrated air and missile defense technology exchanges</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id40af368b11b84d769f9cf10d8f9d4972"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall, in collaboration with the Secretary of State, look for and exploit opportunities to accelerate technology exchanges and transfers of integrated missile defense technology, including over the horizon radar with trusted allies under current defense agreements and arrangements.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8cc639ba3e8941469c65d6d79e2ca11b"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to require the Secretary to exchange technology with a foreign country if the President or the Secretary determines that doing so would present a grave national security threat to the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="id102d245244eb49c1bad5bd0ef5d3971d"><enum>(t)</enum><header>Development and securing of supply chains critical to missile defense</header><text>The Secretary shall, in collaboration with the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Commerce, and the Secretary of the Interior, identify critical shortages and vulnerabilities in supply chains critical to missile defense component production and shall use all authorities available to the Secretaries to develop and secure such supply chains.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="id7de836a04f3b4bd78d700c1e121a4db0"><enum>(u)</enum><header>Requirement for procurement and fielding of dirigibles <enum-in-header>T</enum-in-header>o support missile defense</header> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ided3f1df1d5f940b4b3de0f6512a9ec27"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Army shall procure and field dirigibles, including airships and aerostats, in support of the missile defense of the United States homeland from ballistic, hypersonic, and cruise missiles, and drones.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7cf24d79e0d642bf90a3474d79b5716b"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The requirements of paragraph (1) cover—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfc86f5fb21504f13b3cf87075bbb3d85"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">high altitude air defense systems to detect, characterize, track, and engage current and emerging advanced missile threats; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb392a6d2eee9470599aaabf49a4e0ff7"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">both short-term and long-term solutions that leverage the innovative dirigible and associated sensor development that the Armed Forces, partners of the United States, such as Israel, and United States industry have undertaken during the 30-year period ending on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id578faa36a8ed4913b62ddf3e0a2dbc1d"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Consideration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out paragraph (1), the Secretary of the Army shall consider the use of dirigibles in supporting resilient military and emergency communication networks in a crisis. </text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="idb41ffae7c45943388211e242e36979e6"><enum>5.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act $19,548,100,000 for fiscal year 2026, of which—</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4391ea42b9984796a3379a6f8cfa7837"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$500,000,000 shall be available for requirements of this Act relating to SM–3 Block 1B;</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0b967758bb2144fc854b90326a71377e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$500,000,000 shall be available for requirements of this Act relating to SM–3 Block IIA;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb25fd981ed2641ba99d87e4f82cb7946"><enum>(3)</enum><text>$1,400,000,000 shall be available for requirements of this Act relating to Terminal High Altitude Area Defense (THAAD) Systems;</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9df83c322d414c008abd57aaceec820e"><enum>(4)</enum><text>$1,500,000,000 shall be available for requirements of this Act relating to PAC–2 and PAC–3 Munitions and MM–104 Patriot batteries;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4204d150b2fe46c798c326b6195c7f50"><enum>(5)</enum><text>$1,000,000,000 shall be available for requirements of this Act relating to east coast and Alaska-based Aegis Ashore station construction;</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id91226f86f7c448ef8b30a60fe5c26f19"><enum>(6)</enum><text>$12,000,000,000 shall be available for expansion of missile interceptor fields available at Fort Greely, Alaska, to 80 units with the Next Generation Interceptor;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3ee573aabbee4b00af10d1c339ce7b4a"><enum>(7)</enum><text>$250,000,000 shall be available for requirements of this Act relating to completion and certification of Hawaii Aegis Ashore system;</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcc01973787344c91bd68e9b88290be63"><enum>(8)</enum><text>$60,000,000 shall be available for requirements of this Act relating to Space Development Agency satellite sensors;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9bd31bab39ea4afca285b4813739e9d0"><enum>(9)</enum><text>$750,000,000 shall be available for requirements of this Act relating to modernization of terrestrial-based domain awareness radars;</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1eff3c33ff4341c09cd84cafb0f171d1"><enum>(10)</enum><text>$500,000,000 shall be available for requirements of this Act relating to research and development relating to directed energy or missile interception across the military departments;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1262d77e14af4ab2ac5a0f0ad8271f00"><enum>(11)</enum><text>$900,000,000 shall be available for requirements of this Act relating to research and development of space based missile defense;</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc93d9d310b3d43908bb691ad6a3dd191"><enum>(12)</enum><text>$63,100,000 shall be available for requirements of this Act relating to Missile Defense Complex (MDC) and Fire Team Readiness Facility (FTRF);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida8c9039d2a2640f0ac04182731b7a6e7"><enum>(13)</enum><text>$100,000,000 shall be available for requirements of this Act relating to procurement and fielding of dirigibles; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9f63a2251e484df8bb575a11df2e647d"><enum>(14)</enum><text>$25,000,000 shall be available for Missile Defense Agency military construction to continue planning and design activities for an east coast missile defense interceptor site.</text></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 


