<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4B693995200841C7AE10EDE5B54D7D55" public-private="public" resolution-type="constitutional-amendment" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HJ 8 IH: Proposing an amendment to the Constitution of the United States to provide certain line item veto authority to the President.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IA</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. J. RES. 8</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250103">January 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001177">Mr. McClintock</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>) submitted the following joint resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>JOINT RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Proposing an amendment to the Constitution of the United States to provide certain line item veto authority to the President.</official-title></form><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H4011E9E74EA646C2BE7EB2C07620FDE4"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H0177B9030CE446BCB5C9886F3EF235FC"><enum/><text>That the following article is proposed as an amendment to the Constitution of the United States, which shall be valid to all intents and purposes as part of the Constitution when ratified by the legislatures of three-fourths of the several States within seven years after the date of its submission for ratification: </text><quoted-block style="traditional" id="H8B523CD4C03E426DBEC71063D5AE2E02" display-inline="no-display-inline"><constitution-article id="H2BA858836AB14F08A70E89F07A09C339"><enum> —</enum><section id="H5E21AC1207224C91B9CF8B112F178876" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In approving and signing a bill or joint resolution that is presented under section 7 of article I, the President may reduce an appropriation in such bill or joint resolution, and such bill or joint resolution shall become law with such reduction incorporated.</text></section><section id="H3D603BF4523D4641BE2423E6849A2E61" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="section-one"><enum>2.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the President reduces an appropriation under section 1 of this article—</text><paragraph id="HDF98A64C511048A793F9E64E7D6EE52E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 10 days after the date of such reduction, the President shall notify the House of Representatives and the Senate of such reduction;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7D5DDC32EB3E4BB7925B82EEFF3D5336"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the House of Representatives and the Senate may consider disapproval of such reduction; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H47B99ACC5CED4392B1677343C9B78BE2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>if two-thirds of each House votes to disapprove of such reduction, the amount of the appropriation in law subject to such reduction shall be treated as returned to the amount originally presented to the President under section 1.</text></paragraph></section></constitution-article><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

