<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" slc-id="S1-RIL25455-0XY-8R-VXT"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 189 IS: Expressing support for the designation of April 1, 2025, through April 30, 2025, as “Fair Chance Jobs Month”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 189</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250430">April 30, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S366">Ms. Warren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S422">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S394">Ms. Smith</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S426">Mr. Kim</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of April 1, 2025, through April 30, 2025, as “Fair Chance Jobs Month”.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, in the United States—</text><paragraph id="id511d85a2fcb841f7a30148eedd1ffdbb"><enum>(1)</enum><text>nearly 80,000,000 people have a record of arrest or conviction;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0c8e2b601a3a4874bf9961d191dc9958"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an estimated 19,000,000 people have felony convictions;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5ccad589c8474ff1a68154e5dcc03eae"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">nearly 13,000,000 people are charged each year with misdemeanor offenses;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddabc0a929ed546c0a71400665491321d"><enum>(4)</enum><text>600,000 people are released each year from Federal and State prisons;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id58175268903e4d98aa5681b8c76f6f6a"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Black, Indigenous, and Latino people are 5, 4.2, and 2.4 times more likely than White people to be incarcerated, respectively, and also face higher rates of arrest; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6485eb46aee14e0da7bb78531976f331"><enum>(6)</enum><text>LGBTQ+ individuals are 3 times more likely to be incarcerated and also face higher rates of arrest;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas people who have been convicted of a crime and served their sentence continue to face consequences after release due to systemic biases and stigmas against formerly incarcerated individuals;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas recidivism rates in the United States are among the highest in the world, with almost 44 percent of people who are released returning to incarceration within 1 year;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in the United States, nearly <fraction>2/3</fraction> of the formerly incarcerated population is jobless at any given time;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in the United States, nearly 14,000 laws and regulations and 48,000 collateral consequences restrict formerly incarcerated individuals from getting professional licenses needed to work in some jobs;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 20 States and the District of Columbia allow occupational licensing boards to categorically reject applicants with prior convictions;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas obstacles to employment, such as difficulty obtaining identification needed for employment, add undue burdens on returning citizens and formerly incarcerated individuals;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas formerly incarcerated individuals earn nearly $100 less per week than the average worker;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas fair-chance employers can leverage financial incentives, such as the work opportunity tax credit, to benefit from hiring formerly incarcerated individuals;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas employing returning citizens and formerly incarcerated individuals will result in a robust, vibrant, diverse, and resilient workforce;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas having jobs that pay living wages, are conducive to health, provide opportunities for skillset development, provide opportunities for promotion, and provide benefits will facilitate stable employment and reduce recidivism;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas returning citizens who have received vocational training while incarcerated are 28 percent more likely to obtain employment within 1 year of reentry into society than those lacking such training; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in addition to employment insecurity, returning citizens and formerly incarcerated people face numerous other obstacles to reentry and societal reintegration, including—</text><paragraph id="id84bb0ad92b0940ddad3c72ad895d2aaa"><enum>(1)</enum><text>housing insecurity and homelessness rates that are 10 times higher than the general public;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id15b4337e7d3e42e8b6663a6552f25d45"><enum>(2)</enum><text>near total restrictions in 12 States on access to temporary assistance for needy families established under part A of title IV of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/601">42 U.S.C. 601 et seq.</external-xref>) or the supplemental nutrition assistance program established under the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2011">7 U.S.C. 2011 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id231928546a9c454c85450c40a5b8f156"><enum>(3)</enum><text>greater prevalence of chronic health conditions, lower quality and coverage of health insurance, and mortality rates that are 13 times higher than the general public: Now, therefore, be it</text></paragraph></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="S1"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id0ed6ef3fdc86450da28670d52bfe97a6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>expresses support for the designation of April 1, 2025, through April 30, 2025, as <quote>Fair Chance Jobs Month</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6c377c12a48a4f11a513b569f8072f8d"><enum>(2)</enum><text>supports efforts to—</text><subparagraph id="id7187b9b992804ad1a95d1ede8ee82b1c"><enum>(A)</enum><text>ensure that people directly impacted by incarceration obtain stable and high-quality employment, housing, healthcare, and nutrition;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idba76a6645e7547c3bf16f4c7cb62d19e"><enum>(B)</enum><text>dismantle structural barriers to fair-chance hiring and employment, such as licensing restrictions, employer liability, and insurance restrictions;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2a2a13479f9f472fa998a2826c0b0b29"><enum>(C)</enum><text>expand workforce development programs for returning citizens, formerly incarcerated individuals, and others directly impacted by incarceration, including—</text><clause id="id9c633e254afd4a15a4d82a0468fb523d"><enum>(i)</enum><text>pre-apprenticeship programs;</text></clause><clause id="id9b85811db7e84aab84b6a1135c0a87d3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>registered apprenticeship programs;</text></clause><clause id="id10e01e999eb64fa28963c084676d0f87"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>career coaching, résumé-building, technology literacy, and other skillset development programs; and</text></clause><clause id="ide4becd68a3924b959d01c69bb0d21952"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>programs that educate employers on best practices for, and the benefits of, fair-chance hiring;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3490504b9fc64ea4aa202f71a3614e66"><enum>(D)</enum><text>match jobs providers with returning citizens and formerly incarcerated individuals seeking jobs;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7e7b856ce047412ea47498872694ffcd"><enum>(E)</enum><text>support efforts from labor unions and worker organizations to engage returning citizens and formerly incarcerated individuals who are seeking jobs;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide076c32a6198437fa237b64d0ddb0cbc"><enum>(F)</enum><text>publicize work opportunities that are open to applicants with prior arrest or conviction records; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida9a87982186648e299527d9d4e9b770f"><enum>(G)</enum><text>foster greater collaboration and dialogue between Federal, State, and local government agencies, community-based organizations, advocacy groups, employers, labor unions, currently and formerly incarcerated individuals, and others directly impacted by incarceration to enhance fair-chance hiring and employment and help to heal communities impacted by mass incarceration. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

