<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H22E0F99537FF45A39EC67D4C8CC0ABBD" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 745 IH: Expressing support for the designation of October 1 as “National Latino and Latina Physician Day”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 745</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250918">September 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000599">Mr. Ruiz</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S000168">Ms. Salazar</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of October 1 as <quote>National Latino and Latina Physician Day</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Latino and Latina population in the United States will rise from 42,000,000 individuals in 2005 to 128,000,000 individuals by 2050;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Latinos and Latinas comprise 60 percent of the population growth in the United States;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, by 2050, Latinos and Latinas will account for more than 1 in 4 individuals in the United States and 1 in 3 children in the United States;</text></whereas> <whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas, as of 2023, only 6.5 percent of active physicians in the United States are Latino or Latina;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas only 2 percent of physicians in the United States are Latina;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Latino and Latina population faces significant barriers to accessing medical care, including high poverty, fewer facilities in Latino and Latina communities, and language and cultural barriers;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas a lack of diversity in the medical field leads to worse health outcomes for Latino and Latina patients, including higher rates of chronic disease and maternal mortality;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas research shows that when physicians are of the same ethnicity, culture, and language as the patients of such physicians, care and outcomes improve;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the health of the Nation depends on increasing diversity in medicine and increasing the number of Latino and Latina physicians;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the first National Latino and Latina Physician Day occurred across the United States on October 1, 2022, and was supported by multiple national organizations and the Latino and Latina community, including premedical students, resident physicians, and attending physicians; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the designation of October 1 as <quote>National Latino and Latina Physician Day</quote> will bring awareness to the benefits Latino and Latina physicians bring to the growing Latino and Latina population and the health of the United States as a whole: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H8CFEFAFEE59F46CE92625AB3D029C846"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HD05496FD7D2F4BA9850C44B0AD93F8A0"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> 
<paragraph id="H5CFDA76EAF3F4EC0954FD603E0B2A3CB"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supports the goals of increasing the number of Latino and Latina physicians in the United States and increasing diversity in the medical field; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H07BF1BA546444C0394F13891333AAE0C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supports the designation of <quote>National Latino and Latina Physician Day</quote>.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

