<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H73BCE1B67BE948F9ADE4C5614371A636" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4872 IH: Ending Homelessness Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4872</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250805">August 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000187">Ms. Waters</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide a path to end homelessness in the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H52B42C2C2C774800AE9AFD8537C48C32" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H3FF7E796089A4A9AA50727E48D659DD8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header> 
<subsection id="HF4E6605D56D14DB789C5BF67167F0BC3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Ending Homelessness Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H74A85806E22848DCA0979597A9C3BCBD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text> 
<toc container-level="legis-body-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"> 
<toc-entry idref="H3FF7E796089A4A9AA50727E48D659DD8" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HF1BE8DF3959944E9A8F34FD3CC9B3DF7" level="section">Sec. 2. Expansion of housing choice voucher program.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HEEAD7E676B984F10905EECDEB3B36398" level="section">Sec. 3. Entitlement program for housing choice vouchers.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H50A23200005D4A5EBB3E7DDD4B928070" level="section">Sec. 4. Repeal of ineligibility criteria.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H67CE4A9E6BC74BE7B08635CC1DDB84E9" level="section">Sec. 5. Prohibiting housing discrimination based on source of income.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H4885067A7F994300AA9A97DE747EFF57" level="section">Sec. 6. Funding to address unmet need.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HFD946B5A86004924907AED237A1257D3" level="section">Sec. 7. Housing Trust Fund.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H6D4528DBE66E4FA4933CD605A0F8A0B3" level="section">Sec. 8. Technical assistance funds to help States and local organizations align health and housing systems.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H52396BC95BB74FFB8F0639938298C705" level="section">Sec. 9. Permanent authorization of appropriations for McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act grants.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HCBC287C6FE7C4B86BDDE1A9DF04C0323" level="section">Sec. 10. Permanent extension of United States Interagency Council on Homelessness.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HDAFAC2BEE4774D76A83A86C73AB6CF32" level="section">Sec. 11. Eligibility of private nonprofit organizations for funding.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HB1C4BC3817DB4DF8A15BA948B44DA37B" level="section">Sec. 12. Eligibility of faith-based organizations.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H6F8E10C4E3924C5EBDA6E62F1367A385" level="section">Sec. 13. Conforming amendments.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H24B5C880CFFB44BF9BB6516051751949" level="section">Sec. 14. Funding priority.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section> 
<section id="HF1BE8DF3959944E9A8F34FD3CC9B3DF7" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Expansion of housing choice voucher program</header> 
<subsection id="HE503CF49490D479883D03C59EC75B5FF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is appropriated out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, for providing incremental voucher assistance in accordance with this section for each of fiscal years 2025 through 2028, the amount necessary to fund—</text> <paragraph id="H589AEFFE27674199AFEF2E340BEE38DD"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of incremental vouchers required to be allocated under subsection (c);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H941962F9B71F4975B81B40AB8C38279F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">annual renewals of the vouchers allocated under subsection (c); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC0251B7AC04E47ECBAE97D6159DEA502"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">administrative fees for vouchers allocated under subsection (c).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HCF051CCACEB844449C038B4A84D75AB2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible households</header><text>Amounts made available under subsection (a) may be used only for providing rental housing assistance under section 8(o) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437f">42 U.S.C. 1437f(o)</external-xref>) for an eligible family who initially—</text> <paragraph id="H38FD48C4559746D689A5A1B778A80CED"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has an income that does not exceed 50 percent of the maximum income limitation for extremely low-income families established by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (in this section referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) pursuant to section 3(b)(2)(C) of the United States Housing Act of 1937; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8A3F2873BD51493B9C25ED0AD6BFA37E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is an extremely low-income family that includes an individual who is an individual who is a recipient of supplemental security income benefits under title XVI of the Social Security Act.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HFC86C13DF8FC45ACBD9EB016C0AFD5D3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Allocation</header> <paragraph id="H32C3CCDA3B234BABBF8F4853B46B5A37"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Incremental vouchers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development shall allocate 500,000 incremental vouchers in fiscal year 2025 and 1,000,000 incremental vouchers in increments of 500,000 in each calendar year from 2026 through 2028 under this section to public housing agencies pursuant to section 213(d) of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1439">42 U.S.C. 1439</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H92E74558339149C28A4D8B033B24701C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Selection criteria</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall, by notice in the Federal Register, establish selection criteria under such section 213(d) that prioritizes housing needs among families targeted under subsection (b) and severe housing hardship, such as experiencing homelessness, overcrowding or evictions.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCE764E81427D423085032245122DA64D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rental assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Vouchers allocated under this subsection shall be vouchers for rental assistance under section 8(o) of the United States Housing Act of 1937.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HEEAD7E676B984F10905EECDEB3B36398"><enum>3.</enum><header>Entitlement program for housing choice vouchers</header> 
<subsection id="H81918ED01A144A889BA1FBFBFF372EBC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Entitlement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During fiscal year 2029 and each fiscal year thereafter, any family that is otherwise eligible for tenant-based rental assistance under section 8(o) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437f">42 U.S.C. 1437f(o)</external-xref>) shall be entitled to such rental assistance in accordance with this section during such period that such family meets the requirements under subsection (c) or (d) as a qualified family.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H79F6C213DBE14859A256CB37566B8ACE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For fiscal year 2029 and each fiscal year thereafter, there is appropriated out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated the amount necessary—</text> 
<paragraph id="H146290579B5D4BEA8D15F3727141613F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to provide assistance under section 8(o) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 in accordance with the entitlement under subsection (a) of this section for each qualified family in the amount determined under such section 8(o); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H44EE118514484448B86649C636A32FBA"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to provide administrative fees under such section 8(q), as modified pursuant to subsection (i) of this section, in connection with each voucher for assistance provided pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3CAB0EA45A8C4B52AD7CC0C817750628"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Qualified families</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the term <quote>qualified family</quote> means the following:</text> <paragraph id="HC738F9C7D76648CB9DC33E75DAC4D2D7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Fiscal year 2029</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For fiscal year 2029, a family that meets the requirements under section 2(b) of this Act.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4FE74872131C4CBF957EFC6DFE03F3D6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Fiscal year 2030</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For fiscal year 2030, a family having an income that—</text> <subparagraph id="HE489144627D449D292EDBF0D8E6CC5E8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>meets the requirements under section 2(b) of this Act; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF676F3C35392434D82A09E266A73DA81"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not exceed 75 percent of the maximum income limitation for extremely low-income families established by the Secretary pursuant to section 3(b)(2)(C) of the United States Housing Act of 1937.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4B4E49D408554FD098C084C2BDC3CCD1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Fiscal year 2031</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For fiscal year 2031, an extremely low-income family.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB320C16AD8B04B38BDCD8BE877D9A397"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Fiscal year 2032</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For fiscal year 2032, a very low-income family.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1CDA9423F53546EBB0EBF393792F9740"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Fiscal year 2033 and after</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For fiscal year 2033 and each fiscal year thereafter, a low-income family.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HBEA67112FC284F7A96C4015564F31FD1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Continuing eligibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A family shall meet the requirements under this subsection as a qualifying family if the family—</text> <paragraph id="HACAC574D29B847FDB24FCAD40508D568"><enum>(1)</enum><text>does not meet the requirements under subsection (c); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8CD3FAFE5DCE4EE9AA637D953A219287"><enum>(2)</enum><text>was initially assisted under this section or section 2 of this Act and continues to be assisted.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H2091E092C33142B9B482903441216112"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Repeal of income targeting requirement</header><text>Effective October 1, 2030, section 16 of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437n">42 U.S.C. 1437n</external-xref>) is amended by striking subsection (b).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H710457A5B86F4488B18FEA58C0431BF0"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Administering agencies</header> 
<paragraph id="HEBE0FCB34E4247808A4661BC8AAF71BF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Regional consortia</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall encourage and provide for public housing agencies to form regional consortia to administer the program for rental assistance under this section with respect to geographical areas.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAAECD139EA274FABB22C2DEFCB98509F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>PHA designation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall designate a public housing agency to administer assistance under this section in any area where no existing public housing agency has jurisdiction or where no agency with jurisdiction is adequately administering such assistance, subject to public comment and after consultation with States, public housing agencies, local governments, Indian tribes, and tribally designated housing agencies.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H259179F97D684FA0A9941A029364B123"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Use of small area fair market rents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (1) of section 8(o) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437f">42 U.S.C. 1437f(o)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H9F68FD0CB95F44A0851561E60AB439F7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>subparagraph (D)</quote> and inserting <quote>subparagraphs (D) and (F)</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD4892EE4DCD74CE5AE3A8E24D46BA7F2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HA24A3E6BF48440AC80F08E4027E46B74" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subparagraph id="HF69ACBCE795D4DCE8C67B1D7CA84DA3E"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Use of small area fair market rents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except with respect to any metropolitan statistical area with a vacancy rate of 4 percent or less, effective for fiscal year 2025 and each fiscal year thereafter, the area fair market rents used for purposes of subparagraph (B) shall be established by the Secretary for ZIP Code areas.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H811728190AAC4ED9AEE1D2A1A30A7A57"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Project-Basing</header> 
<paragraph id="HDD5100074E3E4A4E8B30F3E651D320E5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding subparagraph (A) of paragraph (13) of section 8(o) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437f">42 U.S.C. 1437f(o)(13)(A)</external-xref>), a public housing agency administering assistance under this section may enter into agreements to attach such assistance to a project in accordance with such paragraph, except that—</text> <subparagraph id="H3419656F976F467C92A4BB88ABD777A6"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a qualified family residing in a dwelling unit so assisted may at any time opt to use such assistance on a tenant-based basis for a different dwelling unit and, upon such a move, the public housing agency shall provide the qualified family with tenant-based rental assistance under this section; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H83C3378F91F1459DAD8D92537B0847F7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>subparagraph (B) of such section 8(o)(13) (relating to percentage limitation) shall not apply with respect to assistance under this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4E79D02A0FEE45D28E15C1630B882E18"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Percentage limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of section 8(o)(13)(B) of the United States Housing Act of 1937, all families assisted by a public housing agency under this section shall be counted as authorized units for the agency.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD13799CF282445B7A1E8FACB97C78D7D"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Security deposits</header> 
<paragraph id="H6B4224975C554405A36C25528D8EEDDA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An agency administering assistance under this section may authorize a qualified family assisted under this section to use such assistance for security deposits and broker and application fees relating to obtaining a dwelling unit, except that the Secretary may establish a limitation on the amount of such assistance used pursuant to this subsection and for each authorized purpose under this subsection.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0AA05AEEDEB147C6B9DA060170D2B966"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Recapture</header><text>The Secretary shall require the return to the Secretary of any amounts used for a security deposit with respect to a dwelling unit upon the termination of the residence in such unit by an assisted family.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H88B33DD0D97940EC818C3E62A6F52B8B"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Administrative fees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding the administrative fee with respect to tenant-based assistance in effect on October 1, 2023, pursuant to section 8(q) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437f">42 U.S.C. 1437f(q)</external-xref>), the Secretary shall, by regulation, establish a new administrative fee for such assistance, applicable to fiscal year 2025 and thereafter, that reflects local variation in the cost of administering a well-run housing choice voucher program and which encourages public housing agencies to expand housing choice for assisted families and increase the rate at which families issued vouchers use them successfully to lease housing.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H6FEF7014B4D04101B17AB18A7634DBBC"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Prohibition of use under Moving to Work program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the amounts made available by subsection (b) of this section or by section 2 of this Act may be used under, to carry out, or otherwise in connection with the Moving to Work demonstration program authorized by section 204 of the Departments of Veterans Affairs and Housing and Urban Development and Independent Agencies Appropriations Act, 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/134">Public Law 104–134</external-xref>; 110 Stat. 1321), as expanded by section 239 of the Transportation, Housing and Urban Development, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2016 (division L of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/113">Public Law 114–113</external-xref>; 129 Stat. 2897) or any other provision of law.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8100D8A9973947B8B7E6BD1045D86243"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section, the following definitions shall apply:</text> <paragraph id="H273BAD6BCC324B3996CD90F1B104F693"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Indian tribe; tribally designated housing agency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <quote>Indian tribe</quote> and <quote>tribally designated housing agency</quote> have the meanings given such terms in section 4 of the Native American Housing Assistance and Self-Determination Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/4103">25 U.S.C. 4103</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB9DCD85B8B8D4F169A11266112841117"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Low-income family; very low-income family; extremely low-income family</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <quote>low-income family</quote>, <quote>very low-income family</quote>, and <quote>extremely low-income family</quote> have the meanings given such terms in section 3(b) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437a">42 U.S.C. 1437a(b)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H54C907A714F24A9185D397070AD53507"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public housing agency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>public housing agency</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 3(b) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437a">42 U.S.C. 1437a(b)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H90DBD25002CC475EA17EC3D7713AA0AB"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H864279942CB64574A9D96AF3D1A69D75"><enum>(5)</enum><header>State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>State</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 3(b) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437a">42 U.S.C. 1437a(b)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H50A23200005D4A5EBB3E7DDD4B928070"><enum>4.</enum><header>Repeal of ineligibility criteria</header> 
<subsection id="H75311FEA14AB41CFB1F49248F123A04F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>United States Housing Act of 1937</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Effective October 1, 2027, section 6 of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437d">42 U.S.C. 1437d</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H15D033E4E0614F229523C61E531CE7A6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (q)(1), by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HCE2116B86CDC48549F077127F81560B9" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subparagraph id="HA3BF012BA0554538AF6B1B214838842B"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Inapplicability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This subsection shall not apply to applicants for, or families assisted under, the entitlement program for housing choice vouchers under section 3 of the <short-title>Ending Homelessness Act of 2025</short-title>. </text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA5C7C17C2D634B629A00863976B2FE6E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (s), by striking <quote>or assisted housing program</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H47864942A9804B47A3B6E9DDED38A7FC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Quality Housing and Work Responsibility Act of 1998</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Quality Housing and Work Responsibility Act of 1998 is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H5769B81747D04FE988AAD16E799B8229"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 576 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/13661">42 U.S.C. 13661</external-xref>)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H9B318FC69AF84E169447E258435B4851"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>covered</quote> before <quote>federally assisted housing</quote> each place such term appears; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF445D73E671542E58688B02144C5880A"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HDCD25EC6FAC640929F956A3245274BEE" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="HBCD4DF74274246E59D6059CA9FBFEFAE"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definition of covered federally assisted housing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>covered federally assisted housing</quote> has the meaning given the term <quote>federally assisted housing</quote> in section 579, except that the former term shall not include housing specified in subsection (a)(2)(B) of such section.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDD7D33F3B6F84CEE90B2B709BC1DB832"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 577(a) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/13662">42 U.S.C. 13662(a)</external-xref>), by adding after and below paragraph (2) the following new flush material:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H20B07314879646E59EBABEDF486AD155" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<quoted-block-continuation-text quoted-block-continuation-text-level="section">This subsection shall not apply to applicants for, or families assisted under, the entitlement program for housing choice vouchers under section 3 of the <short-title>Ending Homelessness Act of 2025</short-title>.</quoted-block-continuation-text><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H67CE4A9E6BC74BE7B08635CC1DDB84E9" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>5.</enum><header>Prohibiting housing discrimination based on source of income</header> 
<subsection id="H5D0AB2A3EF584FB8A35B83D074B9E1FE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Fair Housing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3601">42 U.S.C. 3601 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HC8F67D3550E34051891F0DABBFA9513F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 802 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3602">42 U.S.C. 3602</external-xref>), by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0D1F369678E4498D91FD27C3DF0DA2CD" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="H1008EB371E654C65B6BA6B18CDC7529A"><enum>(p)</enum><text><term>Source of income</term> includes—</text> <paragraph id="H4C050E1FD3014553B74A34EA5CD8F974"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">current and future use of a tenant- or project-based housing voucher under section 8 of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437f">42 U.S.C. 1437f</external-xref>) and any form of Federal, State, or local housing assistance provided to a person or family or provided to a housing owner on behalf of a person or family, including rental vouchers, rental assistance, down payment assistance, other homeownership assistance, assistance to cover housing costs, and other rental and homeownership subsidies, or guarantees or financial assistance provided through government and nongovernment organizations, including both receipt of such assistance and compliance with its terms thereof;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H240AF13523674609B84DF68991E48069"><enum>(2)</enum><text>income received as a monthly benefit under title II of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/401">42 U.S.C. 401 et seq.</external-xref>), as a supplemental security income benefit under title XVI of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1381">42 U.S.C. 1381 et seq.</external-xref>), or as a benefit under the Railroad Retirement Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/45/231">45 U.S.C. 231 et seq.</external-xref>) or income provided through Federal, State, or local governments or nongovernment organizations, or through any public or State-supported general or disability income assistance program or the terms of such income;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4425216568E64F31BE65F55297886CBC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>income received by court order, including spousal support and child support;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFE0092922C05431DB5BC922A78F5E89F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>any payment from a trust, guardian, conservator, co-signer, or relative; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF85901F027EA41238F6E949B23165A05"><enum>(5)</enum><text>any other source of income or funds, including savings accounts and investments.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H82D65C383E1C464C885D908B7F9C4C6D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 804 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3604">42 U.S.C. 3604</external-xref>)—</text> <subparagraph id="HC727AB626B0A45238CA589924A6FA2AF"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>by inserting <quote>source of income,</quote> after <quote>familial status,</quote> each place that term appears;</text>
                    </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H75690045B4BC48ADA84110BA4C376582"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in section 805 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3605">42 U.S.C. 3605</external-xref>)—</text> <subparagraph id="H020767D76C474C78BD35C477C298CCCD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by inserting <quote>source of income,</quote> after <quote>familial status,</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC57E8DA9AFF845A5A8A76D680836C2C2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (c), by inserting <quote>source of income,</quote> after <quote>handicap,</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7CA4A38F4775478BA01B512BDFA24FE8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in section 806 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3606">42 U.S.C. 3606</external-xref>), by inserting <quote>source of income,</quote> after <quote>familial status,</quote>;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7BE8D853B252446CB71190FF9B15FE24"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in section 807 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3607">42 U.S.C. 3607</external-xref>), by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H28C2EE9B065C4D77A13CF3D5A3219558" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="H73C0264683934C31B8955CCCED2ED8C6"><enum>(c)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing under this title shall be construed to prohibit any entity from providing a preference for veterans or based on veteran status in the sale or rental of a dwelling or in the provision of services or facilities in connection therewith.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="HCE531C9B31A34D4CB3D7958E782F98C0"><enum>(6)</enum><text>in section 808(e)(6) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3608">42 U.S.C. 3608(e)(6)</external-xref>), by inserting <quote>source of income,</quote> after <quote>handicap,</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="HDB5B051AEEA8420AB65B524A6C3E1B66"><enum>(7)</enum><text>in section 810(f) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3610">42 U.S.C. 3610(f)</external-xref>), by striking paragraph (4) and inserting the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA4643F23AC2C495196C91051FB080D98" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="H2493D02D6892451EAA40F86FAC9FD91A" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>During the period beginning on the date of enactment of the <short-title>Ending Homelessness Act of 2025</short-title> and ending on the date that is 40 months after such date of enactment, each agency certified for purposes of this title on the day before such date of enactment shall, for purposes of this subsection, be considered certified under this subsection with respect to those matters for which the agency was certified on that date. If the Secretary determines in an individual case that an agency has not been able to meet the certification requirements within this 40-month period due to exceptional circumstances, such as the infrequency of legislative sessions in that jurisdiction, the Secretary may extend such period by not more than 6 months.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H6E75789399134841A10F546BF6265BA6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prevention of intimidation in fair housing cases</header><text>Section 901 of the Civil Rights Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3631">42 U.S.C. 3631</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>source of income (as defined in section 802),</quote> before <quote>or national origin</quote> each place that term appears.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H18DAA8ADF4A94F76A8FDEFD0744EAF1B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations for enforcement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated for contracts, grants, and other assistance—</text> <paragraph id="HE42C8995AE0B4596BFE1624006C0C66B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$90,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2025 through 2034 for the Fair Housing Initiatives Program under section 561 of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1987 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3616a">42 U.S.C. 3616a</external-xref>);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD339862587134CCDA6F20693FE46886B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$47,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2025 through 2034 for the Fair Housing Assistance Program under the Fair Housing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3601">42 U.S.C. 3601 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2F613FA796F947699FEA48DED7B883A3"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$3,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2025 through 2027 to the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development for a carrying out national media campaign to raise public awareness to help individuals understand their expanded rights under the Fair Housing Act and learn how to report incidents of housing discrimination.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H4885067A7F994300AA9A97DE747EFF57"><enum>6.</enum><header>Funding to address unmet need</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title IV of the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/11360">42 U.S.C. 11360 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H3CC4EA0C6BFE4EFFBA1CAF2860CACA20"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating section 491 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/11408">42 U.S.C. 11408</external-xref>; relating to rural housing stability grant program) as section 441;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF628C6F2BD544949B949965FCA2E0DAD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating section 592 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/11408a">42 U.S.C. 11408a</external-xref>; relating to use of FMHA inventory for transitional housing for homeless persons and for turnkey housing) as section 442; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDE66CBBD6F184F3ABF47078222CC37F1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subtitle:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H03E1D7C2C2FC49C4BF2D53378767BA52" style="OLC"> 
<subtitle id="HDF5FB0D942E64021BCC41078FA2349ED"><enum>E—Emergency Funding To Address Unmet Need</enum> 
<section id="HF72B7E5AFB7D41BCAE02D758B1218F01"><enum>451.</enum><header>Funding to address unmet needs</header> 
<subsection id="H65EABC237500445587BD21DB42018D90"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Direct appropriations</header><text>There is appropriated out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated for each of fiscal years 2025 through 2029, $1,000,000,000, to remain available until expended, for emergency relief grants under this section to address the unmet needs of homeless populations in jurisdictions with the highest need.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H0E873C886C2A498DA995CCA06D219580"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Formula grants</header> <paragraph id="HEA0A118403EE49219129112BEF1B9554"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Allocation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts appropriated under subsection (a) for a fiscal year shall be allocated among collaborative applicants that comply with section 402, in accordance with the funding formula established under paragraph (2) of this subsection.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE7994019B72F4CBAA4E143CDD4F96586"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Formula</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall, in consultation with the United States Interagency Council on Homeless, establish a formula for allocating grant amounts under this section to address the unmet needs of homeless populations in jurisdictions with the highest need, using the best currently available data that targets need based on key structural determinants of homelessness in the geographic area represented by a collaborative applicant, which shall include data providing accurate counts of—</text> <subparagraph id="H47AF7D6015DA4D6FA49158F0F85C018C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the poverty rate in the geographic area represented by the collaborative applicant;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD7726385284C4214A4BD79CC5622A9C0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shortages of affordable housing for low-, very low-, and extremely low-income households in the geographic area represented by the collaborative applicant;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC5AAC2561E3F40EBAAC9C3980DD460E3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the number of overcrowded housing units in the geographic area represented by the collaborative applicant;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H438FC76CCCF1452DAF780AC037C52DC6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the number of unsheltered homeless individuals and the number of chronically homeless individuals; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H63D9E1F2151F491D8F1531A0C505999F"><enum>(E)</enum><text>any other factors that the Secretary considers appropriate.</text></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">The formula shall provide priority to (i) collaborative applicants for which the local governments, within the area served by the applicant, have adopted local policies, such as through zoning and regulation, that leverage the private sector’s participation to provide housing that is reserved and affordable to low-, very low-, and extremely low-income households, as defined by the Secretary, for a minimum term of 15 years, and (ii) collaborative applicants for which the local governments have adopted policies that decriminalize homelessness. The Secretary shall establish by regulation the process and manner that local governments will be evaluated. The Secretary shall ensure that local governments are not incentivized or otherwise rewarded for eliminating or undermining the intent of zoning regulations or other regulations or policies that establish fair wages for laborers, ensure health and safety of buildings for residents and the general public, protect fair housing, establish environmental protections, establish standards for resiliency, prevent tenant displacement, or any other requirements that the Secretary determines it is in the public interest to preserve. </continuation-text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA3D92F9601F94D0C85A5981E9E7BAA6B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For each fiscal year for which amounts are made available under subsection (a), the Secretary shall make a grant to each collaborative applicant for which an amount is allocated pursuant to application of the formula established pursuant to paragraph (2) of this subsection in an amount that is equal to the formula amount determined for such collaborative applicant.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA0473496AA7945C2BD58E541AB24B948"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Timing</header><text>The funding formula required under paragraph (2) shall be established by regulations issued, after notice and opportunity for public comment, not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of this section.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H91C94584454A4F4F9DF2E70637F81F3F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of grants</header> 
<paragraph id="HE79F529560EF4471AC8C7D495137B827"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to paragraphs (2) through (4), a collaborative applicant that receives a grant under this section may use such grant amounts only for eligible activities under section 415, 423, or 441(b).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7488BF6EBC7B4E098F661090329CCBC0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Permanent supportive housing requirement</header> <subparagraph id="HF8CF1865DAB34FB8A84B988E8749E68B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), each collaborative applicant that receives a grant under this section shall use not less than 75 percent of such grant amount for permanent supportive housing, including capital costs, rental subsidies, and services.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEAA1416A5AA94B81BDC746C0521E9664"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exemption</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall exempt a collaborative applicant from the applicability of the requirement under subparagraph (A) if the applicant demonstrates, in accordance with such standards and procedures as the Secretary shall establish, that—</text> <clause id="H02BDC18035494502B907CDBCCBCF319F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>chronic homelessness has been functionally eliminated in the geographic area served by the applicant; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H1BCBA1FCB02F43688364C53E06DF64D3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the permanent supportive housing under development in the geographic area served by the applicant is sufficient to functionally eliminate chronic homelessness once such units are available for occupancy.</text></clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">The Secretary shall consider and make a determination regarding each request for an exemption under this subparagraph not later than 60 days after receipt of such request. </continuation-text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9C3C96F88267492284F9A1F960D89FD5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitation on use for administrative expenses</header><text>Not more than 5 percent of the total amount of any grant under this section to a collaborative applicant may be used for costs of administration.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H26034C5970F4436889045E7362DDEEDC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Housing First requirement</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that each collaborative applicant that receives a grant under this section is implementing, to the extent possible, and will use such grant amounts in accordance with, a Housing First model for assistance for homeless persons.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H9298A472EBDE4A3C9DE440B83FD6018D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Renewal funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Expiring contracts for leasing, rental assistance, or permanent housing shall be treated, for purposes of section 429, as expiring contracts referred to in subsection (a) of such section.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFE7A32D7D4084B218CABD108B706FEF8"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reporting to Congress</header> 
<paragraph id="H458FEB4047F74AB38E9EA8F41D7BDA3E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Annual reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than the expiration of the 12-month period beginning upon the first allocation of amounts made after the date of the enactment of this Act pursuant to subsection (b)(1), and annually thereafter, the Secretary and the United States Interagency Council on Homelessness shall submit a report to the Committees on Financial Services and Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Committees on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs and Appropriations of the Senate providing detailed information regarding the grants made under this section during the preceding year, the activities funded with such grant amounts, and the impact of such activities on the communities where such activities took place.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H62D280031ED14440A8702ABE9B93270A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Collection of information by Secretary</header><text>The Secretary shall require each collaborative applicant that receives a grant under this section to submit such information to the Secretary as may be necessary for the Secretary to comply with the reporting requirement under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB9B62CED19A84CB9BA865DDBE25492ED" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>452.</enum><header>Outreach funding</header> 
<subsection id="H2BDDBE5870B0439A9B72805D81FE1244"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Direct appropriation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is appropriated out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated for each of fiscal years 2025 through 2029, $100,000,000, to remain available until expended, to the Secretary for grants under this section to provide outreach and coordinate services for persons and households who are homeless or formerly homeless.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H333D76B49CC04649846317DEA571E9A5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grants</header> <paragraph id="HABE40C9FAB3247F4B5051103BA06F0FA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall make grants under this section on a competitive basis only to collaborative applicants who comply with section 402.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1DC303F8656C46F1B6EF8CB6342017A7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Priority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The competition for grants under this section shall provide priority—</text> <subparagraph id="H0FF03C44F2524002886158C358206D2F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to collaborative applicants who submit plans to make innovative and effective use of staff funded with grant amounts pursuant to subsection (c);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBA6D9BF1F566413396B7507EC15B60B3"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to collaborative applicants for which the local governments, within the area served by the applicant, have adopted local policies, such as through zoning and regulation, that leverage the private sector’s participation to provide housing that is reserved and affordable to low-, very low-, and extremely low-income households, as defined by Secretary, for a minimum term of 15 years; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H17BE0C524A92451EB8FCCF59358D8643"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to collaborative applicants for which the local governments have adopted policies that decriminalize homelessness.</text></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">The Secretary shall establish by regulation the process and manner that local governments will be evaluated. The Secretary shall ensure that local governments are not incentivized or otherwise rewarded for eliminating or undermining the intent of zoning regulations or other regulations or policies that establish fair wages for laborers, ensure health and safety of buildings for residents and the general public, protect fair housing, establish environmental protections, establish standards for resiliency, prevent tenant displacement, or any other requirements that the Secretary determines it is in the public interest to preserve. </continuation-text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H07DB0F562F584F24A1A7E0B855F17321"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A collaborative applicant that receives a grant under this section—</text> <paragraph id="H95843CBE946C4BF0A384DFE14EC74287"><enum>(1)</enum><text>may use such grant amounts only for providing case managers, social workers, or other staff who conduct outreach and coordinate services for persons and households who are homeless or formerly homeless; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H033F54F07A7D470CA1B64EED2C9AD824"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall not use grant amounts for any law enforcement purposes.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H508FECA929644386BA5B59F3AC51684D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Timing</header><text>The Secretary shall establish the criteria for the competition for grants under this section required under subsection (b) by regulations issued, after notice and opportunity for public comment, not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of this section.</text></subsection></section></subtitle><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HFD946B5A86004924907AED237A1257D3" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>7.</enum><header>Housing Trust Fund</header> 
<subsection id="HA0F33C01C1CB4904897B1C152A2DFB75"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Funding</header> 
<paragraph id="HA18CCE42B81745B49D046474FC63B609"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Annual funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is appropriated, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, for each of fiscal years 2025 through 2029, $1,000,000,000, to remain available until expended, which shall be credited to the Housing Trust Fund established pursuant to section 1338 of the Federal Housing Enterprises Financial Safety and Soundness Act of 1992 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/4568">12 U.S.C. 4568</external-xref>) for use under such section.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5F59DA2284C14078BA9DD72683904031"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Priority for housing the homeless</header> <subparagraph id="H890A7509A79E4973988DA1C0D5CD4888"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Priority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the first 5 fiscal years that amounts are made available under this subsection, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development shall ensure that priority for occupancy in dwelling units described in subparagraph (B) that become available for occupancy shall be given to persons and households who are homeless (as such term is defined in section 103 of the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/11302">42 U.S.C. 11302</external-xref>)).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7042BAF205AB4BCA9D5D4524D8DEFC6D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Covered dwelling units</header><text>A dwelling unit described in this subparagraph is any dwelling unit that—</text> <clause id="H55E85E4DB489426CAC2ACAAB3EB886E8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is located in housing that was at any time provided assistance with any amounts from the Housing Trust Fund referred to paragraph (1) that were credited to such Trust Fund by such paragraph; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="HE315F85B4D2F452FA38926EE5EBD836F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is receiving assistance described in paragraph (2) with amounts made available under such paragraph.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H301656B56A7545C180897ACA442F9768"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Tenant rent contribution</header> <paragraph id="H479B24E290894936BA8055C1C4C341D8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subparagraph (A) of section 1338(c)(7) of the Federal Housing Enterprises Financial Safety and Soundness Act of 1992 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/4568">12 U.S.C. 4568(c)(7)(A)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H90E69468AB5747C2AD2ADB580E1AEC1A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>except that not less than 75 percent</quote> and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H2DC572CC5BAA4F0ABBF6CAF3BC5C778B" style="OLC"><text>except that—</text> 
<clause id="HE1AA3F5C7C5642EF8F8347A819588D7E"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not less than 75 percent</text></clause><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD1F47048E03640288446955EADA60943"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new clause:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6D37426FFE4E430D9E4436061AF5A22C" style="OLC"> 
<clause id="H3D884825387945A78FF7EF5330E51B67"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">notwithstanding any other provision of law, all rental housing dwelling units shall be subject to legally binding commitments that ensure that the contribution toward rent by a family residing in the dwelling unit shall not exceed 30 percent of the adjusted income (as such term is defined in section 3(b) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437a">42 U.S.C. 1437a(b)</external-xref>)) of such family; and</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9FC849BF472140FD8872B29773E38D75"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development shall issue regulations to implement section 1338(c)(7)(A)(ii) of the Federal Housing Enterprises Financial Safety and Soundness Act of 1992, as added by the amendment made by paragraph (1)(B) of this section, not later than the expiration of the 90-day period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H6D4528DBE66E4FA4933CD605A0F8A0B3"><enum>8.</enum><header>Technical assistance funds to help States and local organizations align health and housing systems</header> 
<subsection id="HDEAC6541647C4445A6586C7AB949946B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is hereby made available to the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development $20,000,000, to remain available until expended, for providing technical assistance under section 405 of the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/11361">42 U.S.C. 11361(b)</external-xref>) to integrate and coordinate assistance provided under the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/11301">42 U.S.C. 11301 et seq.</external-xref>) with health care funded by Federal programs, in collaboration with the United States Interagency Council on Homelessness and the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HEF4F9B24A8704D7CBE9236F29D2858CB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In allocating amounts made available by subsection (a), the Secretary shall seek to—</text> 
<paragraph id="H1DB8D841C23A4E7399EBEE7D0F830D0B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>assist States and localities in integrating and aligning policies and funding between Medicaid programs, behavioral health providers, and housing providers to create supportive housing opportunities; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9A340D76561F4620B72F30DFC28A588A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>engage State Medicaid program directors, Governors, State housing and homelessness agencies, any other relevant State offices, and any relevant local government entities, to assist States in increasing use of their Medicaid programs to finance supportive services for homeless persons.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4DA2A1C15E2A4A8C84D870A737F855F8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In using amounts made available under this section, the Secretary shall give priority—</text> <paragraph id="HA8B137E88854434D9AD3DBB9BC102A61"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to use for States and localities having the highest numbers of chronically homeless persons; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFA95D36CBDFD4B0FB7671A0B70540295"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to assist localities that have adopted local policies, such as through zoning and regulation, that leverage the private sector’s participation to provide and make housing affordable for low-, very low-, and extremely low-income household, as defined by the Secretary, for a minimum of 15 years. The Secretary shall establish by regulation the process and manner that local governments will be evaluated. The Secretary shall ensure that local governments are not incentivized or otherwise rewarded for eliminating or undermining the intent of zoning regulations or other regulations or policies that establish fair wages for laborers, ensure health and safety of buildings for residents and the general public, protect fair housing, establish environmental protections, establish standards for resiliency, prevent tenant displacement, or any other requirements that the Secretary determines it is in the public interest to preserve.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H52396BC95BB74FFB8F0639938298C705"><enum>9.</enum><header>Permanent authorization of appropriations for McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act grants</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 408 of the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/11364">42 U.S.C. 11364</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC0DD7E33E6A14A9BA5DD5BCC5D972163" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HA2CB22F56CA84C65AB88CFF111438B89"><enum>408.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this title such sums as may be necessary for each fiscal year.</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section id="HCBC287C6FE7C4B86BDDE1A9DF04C0323"><enum>10.</enum><header>Permanent extension of United States Interagency Council on Homelessness</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 209 of the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/11319">42 U.S.C. 11319</external-xref>) is hereby repealed.</text></section> 
<section id="HDAFAC2BEE4774D76A83A86C73AB6CF32"><enum>11.</enum><header>Eligibility of private nonprofit organizations for funding</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development shall provide that private nonprofit organizations (as such term is defined in section 401 of the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/11360">42 U.S.C. 11360</external-xref>)) that are eligible entities (as such term is defined in such section 401), including faith-based such organizations that are eligible entities, shall be eligible for assistance made available or authorized by this Act or by the amendments made by this Act (but not including assistance under section 452 of the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act, as added by section 3 of this Act), and shall be eligible to be subgrantees for entities receiving amounts made available or authorized by this Act or by the amendments made by this Act.</text></section> <section id="HB1C4BC3817DB4DF8A15BA948B44DA37B"><enum>12.</enum><header>Eligibility of faith-based organizations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, in determining eligibility for assistance made available by this Act or the amendments made by this Act or for which appropriations are authorized by this Act or the amendments made by this Act, the status of an entity as faith-based or the possibility that an entity may be faith-based may not be a basis for any discrimination against such entity in any manner or for any purpose.</text></section> 
<section id="H6F8E10C4E3924C5EBDA6E62F1367A385"><enum>13.</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The table of sections in section 101(b) of the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H46AF174C0ADC44C3ABC0EF886C7C20A0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the item relating to title II, by striking <quote>INTERAGENCY COUNCIL ON THE HOMELESS</quote> and inserting <quote>UNITED STATES INTERAGENCY COUNCIL ON HOMELESSNESS</quote>;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HADB175DF99174E459FEB8D092041F753"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking the item relating to section 209;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H372E33772EF84D23B3DE82D918050868"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the item relating to section 491, by striking <quote>491</quote> and inserting <quote>441</quote>;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC3679CBF5DAC4163B4C6DF503029B7EA"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in the item relating to section 492, by striking <quote>492</quote> and inserting <quote>442</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC6E2DE574836464C801F1C32897C15B0"><enum>(5)</enum><text>by inserting before the item relating to title V the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H01BA5738FBC54D7C8D23A7B9F2D5427E" style="OLC"> 
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry level="subtitle">Subtitle E—Emergency Funding To Address Unmet Need </toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 451. Funding to address unmet needs. </toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 452. Outreach funding.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H24B5C880CFFB44BF9BB6516051751949"><enum>14.</enum><header>Funding priority</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In selecting entities to receive amounts authorized to be appropriated by this Act and amounts made available by this Act, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development shall provide priority to entities serving areas for which the local governments having jurisdiction have adopted policies that decriminalize homelessness.</text></section> </legis-body></bill>

