<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H66783B87F0D14617A3E21DE2088EBD1D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3813 IH: Special Relationship Military Improvement Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3813</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250606">June 6, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000590">Mr. Green of Tennessee</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Arms Export Control Act to provide to the United Kingdom an exemption for licensing of defense items for export in the absence of a relevant bilateral agreement.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H78E81D47F0FF4A79B9467CE90AC88F32" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HC04A8E2A14A0441096066640CDAF6095" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Special Relationship Military Improvement Act of 2025</short-title></quote>. </text></section> <section id="HBC29736EA0B54AB2BC1F3D719385432E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Exemption</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 38 of the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2778">22 U.S.C. 2778</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="HE50E73A464744AA881A51D995C56CEDE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (f)(3), by inserting <quote>or the United Kingdom</quote> after <quote>Canada</quote>; and </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB8E450299102432892818CF6B9F50006"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (j)(1), by striking subparagraph (C) and inserting after subparagraph (B) the following new subparagraphs:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H1794B22A6F024D5EB15B77604337C05F" display-inline="no-display-inline">
<subparagraph id="HA323D3427F254617A3A6E89BB6D4CFFC"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Exception for the United Kingdom</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The requirement to conclude a bilateral agreement in accordance with subparagraph (A) shall not apply with respect to an exemption for the United Kingdom from the licensing requirements of this chapter for the export of defense items.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H39C8593EF0D94E5DB53AE5452CFC1A07"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Exception for defense cooperation treaties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The requirement to conclude a bilateral agreement in accordance with subparagraph (A) shall not apply with respect to an exemption from the licensing requirements of this chapter for the export of defense items to give effect to the Treaty Between the Government of the United States of America and the Government of Australia Concerning Defense Trade Cooperation, done at Sydney September 5, 2007 (and any implementing arrangement thereto), except that the United States shall exempt from the scope of such treaty—</text>
<clause id="HF1BDE600F51C469CB37B5736D148D839"><enum>(i)</enum><text>complete rocket systems (including ballistic missile systems, space launch vehicles, and sounding rockets) or complete unmanned aerial vehicle systems (including cruise missile systems, target drones, and reconnaissance drones) capable of delivering at least a 500 kilogram payload to a range of 300 kilometers, and associated production facilities, software, or technology for these systems, as defined in the Missile Technology Control Regime Annex Category I, Item 1;</text></clause> <clause id="H9B7BD94D15A642129BA10B8EEC6AD864"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>individual rocket stages, re-entry vehicles and equipment, solid or liquid propellant motors or engines, guidance sets, thrust vector control systems, and associated production facilities, software, and technology, as defined in the Missile Technology Control Regime Annex Category I, Item 2;</text></clause>
<clause id="H40DACC7C3BDF44ECB457515E7E7DC794"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>defense articles and defense services listed in the Missile Technology Control Regime Annex Category II that are for use in rocket systems, as that term is used in such Annex, including associated production facilities, software, or technology;</text></clause> <clause id="HF39683F918654014AB3E1E20EB871F11"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>toxicological agents, biological agents, and associated equipment, as listed in the United States Munitions List (part 121.1 of chapter I of title 22, Code of Federal Regulations), Category XIV, subcategories (a), (b), (f)(1), (i), (j) as it pertains to (f)(1), (l) as it pertains to (f)(1), and (m) as it pertains to all of the subcategories cited in this paragraph;</text></clause>
<clause id="HC92EBF1D83A24796B0996E8C84C089F0"><enum>(v)</enum><text>defense articles and defense services specific to the design and testing of nuclear weapons which are controlled under United States Munitions List Category XVI(a) and (b), along with associated defense articles in Category XVI(d) and technology in Category XVI(e); and</text></clause> <clause id="H7296167C88904FD19C1839FD25BF97B8"><enum>(vi)</enum><text> defense articles for which Australian laws, regulations, or other commitments would prevent Australia from enforcing the control measures specified in such treaty.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

