<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H229A491C4CD2463A9B4CB6CA56D05C39" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4615 IH: Small Business Payment for Performance Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4615</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250722">July 22, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001212">Mr. Stauber</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="N000188">Mr. Norcross</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSM00">Committee on Small Business</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Small Business Act to provide interim partial payment to small business contractors that request an equitable adjustment due to a change in the terms of a construction contract, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HAAE03B8AD5A144A98C7A9E34A2ED1D29" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H472A1F3FD7E14A70A2F48DD33F2BF8CF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Small Business Payment for Performance Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H1FDF54ABE2CE426DA9FE263A263DDDAC"><enum>2.</enum><header>Equitable adjustments to construction contracts</header> <subsection id="HF74AED86C7F241CD835CCFAE8B847D67"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 15 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/644">15 U.S.C. 644</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="HEABCC1A97B4C4BE4949954B3593047B6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (x) and (y) as subsections (y) and (z), respectively; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEAAB8EE3933240859CCFB30F53A09050"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (w) the following new subsection:</text>
<quoted-block id="HF0E6EE4BC9C840569638CBFAF542C26C" style="OLC">
<subsection id="HCCCF647549D848D697025E7BCEC1EDC8"><enum>(x)</enum><header>Interim partial payments for equitable adjustments to construction contracts</header>
<paragraph id="HE54868FF00994E1F9F3BDB92A77930E4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Request for an equitable adjustment</header><text>A small business concern that was awarded a construction contract by an agency may submit a request for an equitable adjustment to the contracting officer of such agency if the contracting officer directs a change in the terms of the contract performance without the agreement of the small business concern. Such request shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H1B8E97B9FA524B33B8B5C4DFBCEBA2B7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be timely made pursuant to the terms of the contract; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H4CDD687393EF41BC8D801EDA790AEAE9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>specify the estimated amount required to cover additional costs resulting from such change in the terms.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9CF611F6224349FD9BFF0116DD032880"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Amount</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon receipt of a request for equitable adjustment from a small business concern under paragraph (1), the agency shall provide to such concern an interim partial payment in an amount equal to not less than 50 percent of the estimated amount under paragraph (1)(B).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6D4EE325D4EA49A29D1E02EE4C1930E8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Any interim partial payment made under this section may not be deemed to be an action to definitize the request for an equitable adjustment.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF6F01557AD5E493DB1C391BCF79E2605"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Flow-down of interim partial payment amounts</header><text>A small business concern that receives an equitable adjustment under this subsection shall pay to a first tier subcontractor of such concern the portion of each interim partial payment received that is attributable to the increased costs of performance incurred by such subcontractor due to the change in the terms of the contract performance described in paragraph (1). A first tier subcontractor that receives a portion of an interim partial payment under this section shall pay to a subcontractor (at any tier) the appropriate portion of such payment.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H043A1FAE85D6461E97A9D08C2FFE6528" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the Small Business Administration shall implement the requirements of this section not later than the earlier of the following dates:</text> <paragraph id="HB53B18D61E1B499ABEDDBF35D130D778"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The first day of the first full fiscal year beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5123E9D213154D85905659597720B5F4" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>October 1, 2027.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

