<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-EHF25546-RC0-92-JN0"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1471 IS: Climate Change Financial Risk Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1471</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250410">April 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S353">Mr. Schatz</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S366">Ms. Warren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S316">Mr. Whitehouse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S229">Mrs. Murray</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S359">Mr. Heinrich</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, in consultation with the heads of other relevant Federal agencies, to develop and conduct financial risk analyses relating to climate change, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H0D8966292E5745349D080FC710B70D94"><section section-type="section-one" id="H6538B265257541CA96BF92F53A0A3B6B"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Climate Change Financial Risk Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H8CA4AC3148AD42B6825844BC18643C84"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="H79FB6C0430BF4ACA869DB5061776B13B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>2024 was the warmest year on record globally and the first calendar year that the average global temperature exceeded 1.5 degrees Celsius above pre-industrial levels;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE902F489E5144A6AA5CE58E952FE271F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>if current trends continue, average global temperatures over the long term are likely to surpass 1.5 degrees Celsius above pre-industrial levels between 2030 and 2050;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8445E2C1E48F4AA4ABE67C152D42BB65"><enum>(3)</enum><text>global temperature rise has already resulted in an increased number of heavy rainstorms, coastal flooding events, heat waves, hurricanes, wildfires, and other extreme events;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H51C4185E178D44A4B44F1DB67DFAAEB2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>since 1980—</text><subparagraph id="H791288A1FD4B452990B399E71DE2C0E3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of extreme weather events per year that cost the people of the United States more than $1,000,000,000 per event, accounting for inflation, has increased significantly; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFDBAA78FBE834B47A93D952A16667144"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the total cost of extreme weather events in the United States has exceeded $2,915,000,000,000;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H84F7C11B545F4982B13234A1EDB97326"><enum>(5)</enum><text>as physical impacts from climate change are manifested across multiple sectors of the economy of the United States—</text><subparagraph id="HA3B9B6DE219041A4ADB54CBCB6B42429"><enum>(A)</enum><text>climate-related economic risks will continue to increase;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDC18052B3DF646C9B1AECB6A52CC3437"><enum>(B)</enum><text>climate-related extreme weather events will disrupt energy and transportation systems in the United States, which will result in more frequent and longer-lasting power outages, fuel shortages, and service disruptions in critical sectors across the economy of the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H10A5C7C973364033BD55D4B159F51F43"><enum>(C)</enum><text>projected increases in extreme heat conditions will lead to decreases in labor productivity in agriculture, construction, and other critical economic sectors;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H48428423BAA647BE9DCDAE16F8725B72"><enum>(D)</enum><text>food and livestock production will be impacted in regions that experience increases in heat and drought, and small rural communities will struggle to find the resources needed to adapt to those changes; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAAD534D7E0954EDBB8D7A916955E4D45"><enum>(E)</enum><text>sea level rise and more frequent and intense extreme weather events will—</text><clause id="HC608178F2837448BB89CEAF312585DBF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>increasingly disrupt and damage private property and critical infrastructure;</text></clause><clause id="H8EE2D9B72A3A4515BDAE94E6C46A68FF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>drastically increase insured and uninsured losses; and</text></clause><clause id="HA1D9F9DB197947AC98C4F0F8670FE377"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>cause supply chain disruptions;</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0794DB64C19E43B58191AA14B9DB025D"><enum>(6)</enum><text>advances in energy efficiency and renewable energy technologies, as well as climate policies and shifting societal preferences, will—</text><subparagraph id="H4B2CFA27F3AC489882B6CF2DDEAC5C84"><enum>(A)</enum><text>reduce global demand for fossil fuels; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD2B5DF38B2BB4244982966395FAE8F9E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>expose transition risks for fossil fuel companies and investors domestically and globally, and for companies and investors in other energy-intensive industries, which could include trillions of dollars of stranded assets around the world;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5551E51B06444117804074309C6977AB"><enum>(7)</enum><text>climate change poses uniquely far-reaching risks to the financial services industry, including with respect to credit, counterparty, and market risks, due to the number of sectors and locations impacted and the potentially irreversible scale of damage;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6C03F0D4AE02426D92CB4C95A1CD2170"><enum>(8)</enum><text>weaknesses in how a financial institution identifies, measures, monitors, and controls for the physical risks and transition risks associated with climate change could adversely affect the safety and soundness of a financial institution;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9566FBE8ABEF4EAC8E3ECD774F187760"><enum>(9)</enum><text>financial institutions must take a consistent approach to assessing climate-related financial risks and incorporating those risks into existing risk management practices, which should be informed by scenario analysis;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA2FCECA24ED64E5AB80F6CE33D55FA7A"><enum>(10)</enum><text>the Board of Governors conducts annual assessments of the capital adequacy and capital planning practices of the largest and most complex banking organizations (referred to in this section as <quote>stress tests</quote>) in order to promote a safe, sound, and efficient banking and financial system;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCCEB6A09E7F34F0ABA818A97DB7639B9"><enum>(11)</enum><text>as of the date of enactment of this Act—</text><subparagraph id="H876D428C0C4C4023842B5A666A75C746"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the stress tests conducted by the Board of Governors are not designed to reflect the physical risks or transition risks posed by climate change; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBE40B05BBF0E4BA9BDB08A200E87AA2C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Board of Governors has conducted 1 pilot climate scenario analysis exercise with only 6 United States banking organizations;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8D9A1CBE08F1498AB3F5A345F87DB5D9"><enum>(12)</enum><text>the Board of Governors—</text><subparagraph id="H2189224BCD74476AA6A5C008C0229A39"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has stated that economic effects of climate change and the transition to a lower carbon economy pose an emerging risk to the safety and soundness of financial institutions and the financial stability of the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0B0A9884C5474D749CD1403A57756C8A"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has the authority under section 39 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1831p-1">12 U.S.C. 1831p–1</external-xref>) and section 165 of the Financial Stability Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5365">12 U.S.C. 5365</external-xref>) to take into account the potentially systemic impact of climate-related risks on the financial system to preserve the safety and soundness of supervised institutions and the financial stability of the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCF25FCE0732A4F488F76E315E0E2CF40"><enum>(C)</enum><text>should develop new analytical tools with longer time horizons to accurately assess and manage the risks described in subparagraph (B); </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H60ED1BDB42CE44E6B4919F78EA3459BC"><enum>(13)</enum><text>the Climate-Related Market Risk Subcommittee of the Commodity Futures Trading Commission has identified the importance of researching <quote>climate-related <quote>sub-systemic</quote> shocks to financial markets and institutions in particular sectors and regions of the United States</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H02D3CBEA29CA420FA2BED6B1E5D38E5B"><enum>(14)</enum><text>the Financial Stability Oversight Council likewise identified <quote>[c]limate change [a]s an emerging threat to the financial stability of the United States</quote> and recommended that members of the Council, including the Board of Governors, take action to <quote>strengthen the financial system and make it more resilient to climate-related shocks and vulnerabilities</quote>.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H3BF3A949A6BD4DCAB75188E17EBB82C5"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H6B3E33A93A5548CB92525F9E9F8C1A4D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Bank holding company</header><text>The term <term>bank holding company</term> has the meaning given the term in section 102(a) of the Financial Stability Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5311">12 U.S.C. 5311(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0B9F05D226594951B9636CA987CBBD46"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Board of Governors</header><text>The term <term>Board of Governors</term> means the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC2EA266B41F94349B54A36B30E5B318F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Climate science leads</header><text>The term <term>climate science leads</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="HD9EF8C5BA2444994BFCC08ADCF5F8BE0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCA26DC82D2BF4FB6A1507BB097965064"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H38FF949134684F1CB0AE1AE2DF9F8FE2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Secretary of Energy;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA8A0A01A771C4A6286F1D85BEF751438"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Assistant Secretary for the Office of International Affairs of the Department of Energy;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3DF2EFAD6CD94B7CB6DA51A8F66A4B5A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H724AD738FB1C4F5888EF69C3263B472A"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Assistant Secretary for the Bureau of Oceans and International Environmental and Scientific Affairs of the Department of State;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBCB3C4E9CFAD4BFD8513B070E138101B"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the Director of the United States Geological Survey;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBEA06BAE919A4CA48A27DCCBC56A52E6"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the Secretary of the Interior; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0EEDE2D73AFA465ABCCC8870A86A5647"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the Director of the National Climate Assessment;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEEFA9074528541B2B7536CB6DF555440"><enum>(J)</enum><text>the individual from the United States elected to the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change Bureau; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAD881E04BE364E8DA141050B1E93AAE5"><enum>(K)</enum><text>the Permanent Representative of the United States to the World Meteorological Organization; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1175267900B048C4A05914A35B955059"><enum>(L)</enum><text>the head of any other Federal agency that the Board of Governors determines to be appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD79B003E46444F74B2FFB1AFACBD8BCF"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Covered entity</header><text>The term <term>covered entity</term> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H1396DF43D2834993A252631DBFAA8691"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a nonbank financial company or bank holding company that has not less than $250,000,000,000 in total consolidated assets; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE1CC5A4F230040EEACCD74F58A85F674"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a nonbank financial company or bank holding company—</text><clause id="HA97DD6A26BE54D918E0F73F02DDF8C60"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that has not less than $100,000,000,000 in total consolidated assets; and</text></clause><clause id="HF3DE400757794F1C9DF0749ABF4264A9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>with respect to which the Board of Governors determines the application of subparagraph (C) of section 165(i)(1) of the Financial Stability Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5365">12 U.S.C. 5365(i)(1)</external-xref>), as added by section 6 of this Act, is appropriate—</text><subclause id="H8D662B07C39841AFA0B400CE46D7D095"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to—</text><item id="H3940F6118BF4446A9721B45853449D98"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>prevent or mitigate risks to the financial stability of the United States; or</text></item><item id="H52475B51A244472CB279190C4673F0C6"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>promote the safety and soundness of the company; and</text></item></subclause><subclause id="H884A5D6E65AF447D8E4856DE6748530F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>after taking into consideration—</text><item id="HAC9AC4DC1FDD47D4950DD23487E9AA3C"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the capital structure, riskiness, complexity, financial activities, and size of the company, including the financial activities of any subsidiary of the company; and</text></item><item id="H0894489916194ED99A62D15B84659CFD"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>any other risk-related factor that the Board of Governors determines to be appropriate.</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H441601BE31404892832CC1C9FFE1184D"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Nonbank financial company</header><text>The term <term>nonbank financial company</term> has the meaning given the term in section 102(a)(4)(C) of the Financial Stability Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5311">12 U.S.C. 5311(a)(4)(C)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD435D99703F34C00A59ECC766B2F4D47"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Physical risks</header><text>The term <term>physical risks</term> means financial risks to assets, locations, operations, or value chains that result from exposure to physical, climate-related effects, including from—</text><subparagraph id="HF1B42EE01CC9465AA821DEBE52ABF35D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>increased average global temperatures;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC621975A22AE4643AFE4251D3E1822B2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>increased severity and frequency of extreme weather events;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFD332206BE3B45E8BD11B2A8F391B5B5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>increased flooding;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCDBC33C202FE4944946F7B6E8AD187F6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>sea level rise;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5849587A6EFD4D19B1D7D9AD2670C326"><enum>(E)</enum><text>ocean acidification;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC92FBAED1B03404B83031D02FE775D08"><enum>(F)</enum><text>increased severity and frequency of heat waves;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5387151B0FA641019C57819F36928126"><enum>(G)</enum><text>increased frequency of wildfires;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDC04D3C7562542199CE45488160F7E86"><enum>(H)</enum><text>decreased arability of farmland; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H56DCA9D969894546B3900B21EB2D6154"><enum>(I)</enum><text>decreased availability of fresh water.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H33F6F4A7360B45D39DC7036D4523929A"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Surveyed entity</header><text>The term <term>surveyed entity</term> means a bank holding company, nonbank financial company, or other entity that— </text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id18294465560442f299ca0cbeef1ab095"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is supervised by the Board of Governors, the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency, or the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCFCEC9732FC64BDE966F28408FFE4C2E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has total consolidated assets of not less than $10,000,000,000; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE076B6B96F074EBD9C582EB6277F8D61"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is not a covered entity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H322AB4669227499AA26F148B3CE3D0B2"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Technical Development Group</header><text>The term <term>Technical Development Group</term> means the Climate Risk Scenario Technical Development Group established under section 4(a).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idac3a13158c924734a652c728b94dec4e"><enum>(9)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Transition risks</header><text>The term <term>transition risks</term> means financial risks that are attributable to climate change mitigation and adaptation, including efforts to reduce greenhouse gas emissions and strengthen resilience to the impacts of climate change, including—</text><subparagraph id="H964E461A20A3453EA9A9A85B83BF4123"><enum>(A)</enum><text>costs relating to—</text><clause id="H302941A32A1F423ABD09BC65F23B6E22"><enum>(i)</enum><text>international treaties and agreements;</text></clause><clause id="H78AE9474B32040A697DD4DD231CE79D5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Federal, State, and local policies;</text></clause><clause id="H114FD1F431E84987ACFC26E10853A2BA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>new technologies;</text></clause><clause id="H29DF604E79A64FD48D3A5F1148048869"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>changing markets;</text></clause><clause id="H632A93BBADF54C38A5C2CCB47FD36FA8"><enum>(v)</enum><text>reputational impacts relevant to changing consumer behavior; and</text></clause><clause id="HE6EA3CACCCE443348776340D57085634"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>litigation; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAD3FF534210C4BB99C1C8E813C31DD16"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a loss in the value, or the stranding, of assets due to any of the costs described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA47C2F02AD1843E1AB57212E50958D35"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Value chain</header><text>The term <term>value chain</term>—</text><subparagraph id="H3CDEEF7766C840369E7BAB3F913C93FB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means the total lifecycle of a product or service, both before and after production of the product or service, as applicable; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC90D1EDEDEEE45B797793F4ED5E549F2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may include the sourcing of materials, production, and disposal with respect to the product or service described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H863108F8BBBC45FE848B795EF4DD97F2"><enum>4.</enum><header>Climate Risk Scenario Technical Development Group</header><subsection id="H05703EC0230944EE85985F12A3B95AE9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Board of Governors shall establish a technical advisory group to be known as the <quote>Climate Risk Scenario Technical Development Group</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HFAB739020C8E4256B038B810FCD48D82"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership</header><paragraph id="H00C7E0D341AE43B2848C0CFC7A399AF2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Composition</header><text>The Technical Development Group shall be composed of 10 members—</text><subparagraph id="HE158F365D7EC40ECBEB2EF28993AC17A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>5 of whom shall be climate scientists, with a demonstrated record of peer-reviewed publications and professional contributions to climate modeling, climate risk assessment, or related areas; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCEAB72252AEE4159822BA42D11A56B19"><enum>(B)</enum><text>5 of whom shall be economists, with expertise in either the United States financial system or the financial risks posed by climate change.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0A5AEC8B5A1648869A01BC41BFF9AB74"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Selection</header><text>The Board of Governors shall select the members of the Technical Development Group after consultation with the climate science leads.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0C502BDEB17D45D099495896E1DEEA01"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Technical Development Group shall—</text><paragraph id="H9A445001E6D349589C6E8BCE90A82430"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide recommendations to the Board of Governors regarding the development of, and updates to, the climate change risk scenarios under section 5;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H61963DA6265246E1B6F96E73F13D9D36"><enum>(2)</enum><text>after the establishment of the climate change risk scenarios under section 5, determine the financial and economic risks resulting from those scenarios;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H833E3F1A7D5B45F8BC47B1D486B5813A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>make any final work product, and any information used in the development of the final work product, publicly available;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1529B34955D84A928EF11AD9965EBCCA"><enum>(4)</enum><text>provide technical assistance to covered entities in assessing physical risks or transition risks; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA37DA10A6A8F44BBB81BDB16A42BC644"><enum>(5)</enum><text>provide publicly available resources to entities that are not covered entities to help those entities assess physical risks and transition risks.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H562BBE25B4774BF5A88698BD453AC6CF"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Prohibition on compensation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Members of the Technical Development Group shall serve without pay.</text></subsection><subsection id="H8662386558984F7183084AC67FE3C664"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Inapplicability of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/10">chapter 10</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/10">Chapter 10</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, shall not apply with respect to the Technical Development Group.</text></subsection></section><section id="H0A61AB30A077496AA55F11EF9340B81B"><enum>5.</enum><header>Development and updating of climate change risk scenarios</header><subsection id="H4B2578E3454A445388F819236FD63DA1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><paragraph id="H85E9337617884861A437A219E1A15B5F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial development</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Board of Governors, in coordination with the climate science leads, and taking into consideration the recommendations of the Technical Development Group, shall develop 3 separate climate change risk scenarios as follows:</text><subparagraph id="H98EC24AB21C34CC899FDD538CF73BB07"><enum>(A)</enum><text>One scenario that assumes an average increase in global temperatures of 1.5 degrees Celsius above pre-industrial levels.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H967BB48D2A144F0D9D9051DC80956383"><enum>(B)</enum><text>One scenario that assumes an average increase in global temperatures of 2 degrees Celsius above pre-industrial levels.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H86960C3C9DA346478FD4969E753ECAA2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>One scenario that—</text><clause id="H75EA019E1E4E427F9B1DFC4134EB085B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>assumes the likely and very likely average increase in global temperatures that can be expected, taking into consideration the extent to which national policies and actions relating to climate change have been implemented, as of the date on which the scenario is developed; and</text></clause><clause id="HDEBC0E399F8D426980951C68C7FC7BD3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>does not take into consideration commitments for national policies and actions relating to climate change that, as of the date described in clause (i), have not been implemented.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3539896F0F1A497A89A0ABD7172F52BD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>International coordination</header><text>In developing and updating the 3 scenarios required under this subsection, the Board of Governors shall take into consideration analytical tools and best practices developed by international banking supervisors relating to climate risks and scenario analysis in an effort to develop consistent and comparable data-driven scenarios.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H79CDAEE1896E414FB310B3A98F7E66B0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Recommendations</header><text>If the Technical Development Group determines that the average increase in global temperatures described in subparagraph (A) or (B) of paragraph (1) is no longer scientifically valid, the Technical Development Group may recommend that the Board of Governors, in coordination with the climate science leads, update the average increase in global temperatures described in the applicable subparagraph to reflect the most current assessment of climate change science.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDA0DF18852164C949B27BFD4CD66C2EE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In developing and updating each of the 3 scenarios required under subsection (a), the Board of Governors, in coordination with the climate science leads, shall account for physical risks and transition risks that may disrupt business operations across the global economy, including through—</text><paragraph id="H91D6B0A586EB486293FCEB0F0634270B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>disruptions with respect to—</text><subparagraph id="HBE6EFF2E0DA34AF18E058AB5B53E2F56"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the sourcing of materials;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9AEA31E3E28D45E1BED1748458520393"><enum>(B)</enum><text>production;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0A80A30FB5034BC6B0EB6F321E10D200"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">transportation; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB55E1BA08A144F46BCD9E3C9FE1F2CCF"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the disposal of products and services;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF1E35A01B68749E5A1A01A077C6B4256"><enum>(2)</enum><text>changes in the availability and prices of raw materials and other inputs;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6016798A58744946AA9A77591DEE0CFC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>changes in agricultural production and with respect to food security;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCDCEEA5830294683B85A5EF014B6C47B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>direct damages to fixed assets;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H32E60F995F63403CAE10CFC241E1B21C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>increases in costs associated with insured or uninsured losses;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFA8363147FB3476887BD53B1347601F9"><enum>(6)</enum><text>changes in asset values;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB0D7C85DC0814B21AB48AF6CF7A0791C"><enum>(7)</enum><text>impacts on—</text><subparagraph id="HB527AE733CA04BBDB41E640B031F0243"><enum>(A)</enum><text>aggregate demand for products and services;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF6448DF4DA164871A8448E4169C33B57"><enum>(B)</enum><text>labor productivity;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H75A4BD5880A7441DA14764547D0BFE07"><enum>(C)</enum><text>asset liquidity; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCC4DC9A4A24F42DB8EA8A2250CFDFA3E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>credit availability;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA2DB8CF66CC94D6881314C319AA8D9E8"><enum>(8)</enum><text>mass migration and increases in disease and mortality rates;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H431F3A4D679C49249172D8A42401C9D3"><enum>(9)</enum><text>international conflict, as such conflict relates to global economic activity and output; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2483F1B30807458FB9E15E1ADF29770B"><enum>(10)</enum><text>changes in any other microeconomic or macroeconomic condition that the Board of Governors, in coordination with the climate science leads, determines to be relevant.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HB4A967F624C74425BAFCFFD12E4D748B"><enum>6.</enum><header>Climate-related enhanced supervision for certain nonbank financial companies and bank holding companies</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 165(i)(1) of the Financial Stability Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5365">12 U.S.C. 5365(i)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HB813ED5013D141CB9E2BAD3AE318D808"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)(i), by inserting <quote>except as provided in subparagraph (C)(ii)(I),</quote> before <quote>shall provide</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF373F1E6B58E4E7E95A5E3BFC4A06851"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H15943EC605BD40BC87626000875E5E65"><subparagraph id="HD1716E2DE6C64254971C0CD098E6A03D"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Biennial tests required</header><clause id="HD6B62A9DED9846D6B95978032C940740"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subparagraph—</text><subclause id="H0B0C7ADF6DBD4EBA8A956CD92CA2F0E9"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the term <term>capital distribution</term> has the meaning given the term in section 225.8(d)(4) of title 12, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on the date of enactment of this subparagraph;</text></subclause><subclause id="HC615DF53D7104BE8A846CF24123BA70B"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the term <term>capital policy</term> has the meaning given the term in section 225.8(d)(7) of title 12, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on the date of enactment of this subparagraph; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H3776A14A88104679B91A4708F20D9C7B"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the terms <term>climate science leads</term> and <term>covered entity</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 3 of the <short-title>Climate Change Financial Risk Act of 2025</short-title>.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HCBA93C6511AD4A308C8B024AEC60C5E9"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Tests</header><subclause id="H3FC8160F1BC346A7BA8CC62B38EEDD34"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Board of Governors, in coordination with the appropriate primary financial regulatory agencies and the climate science leads, shall conduct biennial analyses in which each covered entity shall be subject to evaluation, under an adverse set of conditions, of whether that covered entity has the capital, on a total consolidated basis, necessary to absorb financial losses that would arise under each climate change risk scenario developed under section 5 of the <short-title>Climate Change Financial Risk Act of 2025</short-title>.</text></subclause><subclause id="H9024A2587CC94E529E71C7B4154B9D99"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Initial tests</header><text>With respect to each of the first 3 analyses conducted under subclause (I)—</text><item id="H681B9692991347F78D2B9CB0ED563C7C"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the covered entity to which such an analysis applies shall not be subject to any adverse consequences as a result of the analysis; and</text></item><item id="H08A48FFAD357430BA0142F916951942E"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the Board of Governors shall—</text><subitem id="HB4ECF6116FDC45B4807F5D6E4B33DC2C"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>not later than 60 days after the date on which the Board of Governors completes the analysis, make a summary of the analysis publicly available; and</text></subitem><subitem id="H5F9AF259590944F9AB899AF5D0059B9F"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>submit a copy of the results of the analysis to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives.</text></subitem></item></subclause><subclause id="H3CAE97DF98BC42B7B6828E7C65480414"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Climate risk resolution plan</header><item id="H650201C0674B4162A389A8083F244A30"><enum>(aa)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except with respect to the first analysis conducted under subclause (I), each covered entity shall, before being subject to an analysis under that subclause, submit to the Board of Governors a resolution plan with respect to climate risk planning (referred to in this subclause as a <quote>climate risk resolution plan</quote>), which shall be based on the results of the most recently conducted analysis of the covered entity under that subclause.</text></item><item id="HB8920999406E4D8C91DA034709B4906B"><enum>(bb)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Each climate risk resolution plan required under item (aa) shall include—</text><subitem id="H1C71B4E4B51E4BC8B7FC284189F0BFB0"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>a capital policy with respect to climate risk planning; and</text></subitem><subitem id="H1CD6E4D9F67747B1912DE48D1081B107"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>qualitative and quantitative targets for balance sheet and off-balance sheet exposures, and other business operations, that remedy vulnerabilities identified in the most recently conducted analysis of the applicable covered entity under subclause (I).</text></subitem></item><item id="H63F61D72B5A042D187420F5A78A56DDC"><enum>(cc)</enum><header>Rejection</header><text>The Board of Governors may object to a climate risk resolution plan submitted by a covered entity under item (aa) if the Board of Governors determines that—</text><subitem id="H50DC880D01704A2CA26AF730BEDA771A"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>the covered entity has not demonstrated that such plan is reasonable to maintain capital above each minimum regulatory capital ratio on a pro forma basis under the adverse set of conditions described in subclause (I);</text></subitem><subitem id="H0AB7346577E9441A8DF2DF94AB594FB5"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>the climate risk resolution plan is otherwise not reasonable or appropriate, including because the climate risk resolution plan no longer provides fair services to vulnerable and disadvantaged communities;</text></subitem><subitem id="HCF2152688C3246BC85FA7A41FAF9EF76"><enum>(CC)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the assumptions and analysis underlying the climate risk resolution plan, or the methodologies and practices that support that plan, are not reasonable or appropriate; or</text></subitem><subitem id="HC19F81128EB14C05A051F5DE23FAE29D"><enum>(DD)</enum><text>the climate risk resolution plan otherwise constitutes an unsafe or unsound practice.</text></subitem></item><item id="H3CE3A85700A74473BF0554B4BFDEF817"><enum>(dd)</enum><header>General distribution limitation</header><text>If the Board of Governors objects to a climate risk resolution plan submitted by a covered entity under item (aa), the covered entity may not make any capital distribution, other than a capital distribution arising from the issuance of a regulatory capital instrument eligible for inclusion in the numerator of a minimum regulatory capital ratio.</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="H87E828BEEA8E4AE4868A5F11E65953A7"><enum>7.</enum><header>Sub-systemic exploratory survey</header><subsection id="H25B39251345C45E197E4170CDC3F5312"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Development of survey</header><text>The Board of Governors, in consultation with the Comptroller of the Currency and the Board of Directors of the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, shall develop a survey to assess—</text><paragraph id="H1EB62AF81E5E43A0B44372D9EF16D75A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the ability of surveyed entities to withstand each climate risk scenario developed under section 5;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAE1706E369654D9B864DCD839E36657C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>which surveyed entities possess a large concentration of business activities in geographical areas or industries that are significantly exposed to the short- and long-term impacts of climate change; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE4060CD87E124E919EB9AF647912DC09"><enum>(3)</enum><text>how the surveyed entities identified under paragraph (2) plan to make adaptations to the business models and capital planning of those entities in response to the risks presented in each climate change risk scenario developed under section 5.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD8A8FAB0B90A415D82937B96234AD70D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Administration of survey</header><paragraph id="H37F2E6ACCE5D45A98B228997A968F127"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial administration</header><subparagraph id="H86A850DAE696497BA6879525FBF67F2C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the completion of the first analysis under subparagraph (C) of section 165(i)(1) of the Financial Stability Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5365">12 U.S.C. 5365(i)(1)</external-xref>), as added by section 6 of this Act, the Board of Governors, in consultation with the Comptroller of the Currency and the Board of Directors of the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, shall administer the survey developed under subsection (a) to each surveyed entity.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAF71621021024EC8A98BAC80268E51D4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Assessment and report</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date on which the Board of Governors completes the administration of the survey under subparagraph (A), the Board of Governors shall publicly release a report that—</text><clause id="H907F85FD290D415A9BF82564FAFCB2E5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>summarizes the results of the survey; and</text></clause><clause id="HDA75064658F24B16B8463B5B1FE7A041"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>analyzes whether the planned actions of the surveyed entities, in the aggregate, are plausible and would be effective.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA88E1FB28AB04221B759EE5172AE84D0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Subsequent administration</header><subparagraph id="H5DA67D2E16A04AFB8A08F68A233B8722"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date on which the Board of Governors releases the report required under paragraph (1)(B), and biennially thereafter, the Board of Governors shall readminister to each surveyed entity the survey developed under subsection (a).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H95B652B3159D4F11B75575534FF64750"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Subsequent report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date on which each survey described under subparagraph (A) is completed, the Board of Governors shall publicly release a report that summarizes the results of the survey, which shall include the analysis described in paragraph (1)(B)(ii).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H901AB1FFA6D144D19303B2019E5B46DD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effect of survey participation</header><text>In any report released with respect to a survey conducted under this section, the Board of Governors may not identify any individual surveyed entity that responded to the survey.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H11D65A85D2454F0A8A283E30AACBCB77"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to preclude the Board of Governors from pursuing an enforcement action against a surveyed entity because of a violation discovered by the Board of Governors during an examination of the surveyed entity that is independent of a survey administered under this section. </text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

