<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7C49B305F5564D86B58F9BE9D23B35C3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2135 IH: Caza Ranches LLC and Department of Homeland Security Land Exchange Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2135</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250314">March 14, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000273">Ms. Leger Fernandez</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="F000478">Mr. Fry</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for an exchange of certain Federal and non-Federal land in Artesia, New Mexico, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H56409A2EBCB640BC808D03194E8A0A6D" style="OLC"><section id="HD9223D70ABB5483292631658D584F704" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Caza Ranches LLC and Department of Homeland Security Land Exchange Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H3A20761453AD47ADAAFFED2BBFB72E41"><enum>2.</enum><header>Land exchange</header><subsection id="H8C8E5A2F2D9E4721B58159EF50CA742A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph id="H33FB06CAC6844414A5619B6CAF935A1A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Centers</header><text>The term <quote>Centers</quote> means the Federal Law Enforcement Training Centers and related facilities that are located in Artesia, New Mexico.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H72626DBAC0EA4C2A8209C72EF4F82C8B" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federal land</header><text>The term <quote>Federal land</quote> means the approximately 160 acres of land in Artesia, New Mexico, generally depicted as <quote>FLETC/DHS Federal Land to be Exchanged to CAZA</quote>, with the following identification and description:</text><subparagraph id="H9A903037568644DB801CF2C25438E827" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Identification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Parcel Number: 4–149–096–266–460.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H937DF2F1E1754B5F8A708C332DE4DB08" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Description</header><text>Township 16 South, Range 25 East, Section 35: S ½ S ½.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H292C304043ED473093167AE85B15D334" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Map</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Map</quote> means a map depicting the Federal land and the non-Federal land, as agreed to by the Centers and Caza Ranches LLC.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC78ADAD62DFB4B5F9C43D8D895093D12" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Non-Federal land</header><text>The term <quote>non-Federal Land</quote> means the approximately 160 acres of land owned by Caza Ranches LLC, generally depicted as <quote>CAZA to be Exchanged to FLETC/DHS Federal Land</quote> on the Map, but does not include any subsurface rights to the land vested in a third party, with the following identification and description:</text><subparagraph id="HA2D85A38B4644CA394F4F2405BEA2F4C" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Identification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Parcel Number: 4–147–097–132–132.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7C432BD47FB54CD1AF4939897E629511" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Description</header><text>Township 17 South, Range 25 East, Section 4: NW ¼.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCC3CF890BE964785AB6822AF4822ACD7"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of Homeland Security.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA871ED3CA473415291FC1D96C21D94DC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exchange of lands</header><paragraph id="HA897210120ED493A89917A0BB7CBF712"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Upon receiving an offer from the Caza Ranches LLC to convey to the Secretary all right, title, and interest of the Caza Ranches LLC in and to the non-Federal land, the Secretary is authorized to accept the offer and to convey to Caza Ranches LLC all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to the Federal land.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H05589E0D3F104AD89ADE44291D2127C4" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Land title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title to the non-Federal land conveyed to the Secretary under this section shall conform to the title approval standards of the Attorney General of the United States applicable to land acquisitions by the Federal Government.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA03DCB7C31AC4046A6525C48C2EFBF50"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exchange terms and appraisals</header><paragraph id="H14EFC04E78D14235BE942B51C631DBB2" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The exchange of Federal and non-Federal lands under subsection (b) shall be subject to the following:</text><subparagraph id="H61F35CCAEF9C47E494245ACF18F9621B" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Any valid existing rights as of the date of the enactment of this section.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H72FDEAA999A8482B88356641820D3158" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Any additional terms and conditions the Secretary determines appropriate to protect the interests of the United States, including with respect to any of the rights referred to in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0314695F9649482FB3F523706F1D4EB8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Costs</header><text>The costs of carrying out the exchange of lands under subsection (b) shall be shared equally by the Secretary and the Caza Ranches LLC.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1283F466CBB549FE99737AF44595B83A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Equal value exchange</header><text>The value of the lands exchanged under subsection (b) shall be deemed equal.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H59AD1AEFF7644856926B4ECA166B1756"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Memorialization</header><text>All terms and conditions for the exchange of lands under subsection (b) shall be memorialized in a written exchange agreement that is signed by Caza Ranches LLC and the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9663CDB0E7944C9C86D22DA8915153E2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Acquisition of land for training purposes boundary adjustment</header><text>On acceptance of title to the non-Federal land by the Secretary—</text><paragraph id="H4354A3B7B90A487BB94035F98C66E882"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the non-Federal land shall be added to and administered as part of the Centers;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H97F0CEB5362747DEBDFBFC4939BE765F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Centers shall use such land to erect structures in support of the Federal Law Enforcement Training Centers’ training mission; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB3634294ECA24672B159D52E80F61929"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the boundaries of the Centers shall be adjusted to exclude the exchanged Federal land.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF8D40DA17F79471DAB021F20D8C6337F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Maps, estimates, and descriptions</header><paragraph id="H34DD7FE47674490482D5E9B7049DDE92"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Minor errors</header><text>The Secretary and the Caza Ranches LLC may, by mutual agreement, carry out the following:</text><subparagraph id="H1D060A75FA014D90AD811A7CC9C5C7A8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Make minor boundary adjustments to the Federal and non-Federal lands involved in the exchange under this section.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H50849F69D89541CF9C10034E55140F89" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Correct any minor errors in the Map or any other map, acreage estimate, or legal description of any such lands.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF61132BBE56441A0AF7D2C79C7A52E9B" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conflict</header><text>If there is a conflict between a map, an acreage estimate, or a legal description of the lands involved in the exchange under this section, the Map shall control unless the Secretary and the Caza Ranches LLC mutually agree otherwise.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H35A11B34303B460E9BA0C578A80D43E6" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>The Secretary shall file and make available for public inspection in the New Mexico headquarters of the Department of Homeland Security a copy of the Map and any other map referred to in this section.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

