<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB0018FDAC89F47A1B5F305BFD2534ACE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2162 IH: Honey Integrity Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2162</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250314">March 14, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001214">Mr. Steube</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="E000235">Mr. Ezell</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for the protection of the integrity of honey marketed in the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H2D47DB3474864793B421034F6226E99E" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="HD9059EC62CF946B089D4E4D5AAB3A91C"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Honey Integrity Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H4A75997866184BF7BBFA6676D5B519CF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Standard of identity for honey</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall establish a standard of identity for honey in accordance with applicable United States Pharmacopeia standards under section 401 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/341">21 U.S.C. 341</external-xref>). </text></section> 
<section id="HD5A863F707AC4419BABBD155E1807A63"><enum>3.</enum><header>Report to Congress on enforcement actions with respect to misbranded honey</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit a report to Congress on enforcement actions taken under the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/301">21 U.S.C. 301 et seq.</external-xref>) with respect to—</text> <paragraph id="H1524283B60D14449B3BCBBFA99957C45"><enum>(1)</enum><text>honey that is adulterated under section 402 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/342">21 U.S.C. 342</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2589AE15B5BB446CA7087BCCD3303651"><enum>(2)</enum><text>honey that is misbranded under section 403 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/343">21 U.S.C. 343</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H62B5FD68FE4C4D118C1A6C64218BAF27"><enum>4.</enum><header>Honey Integrity Program</header> <subsection id="HDBF6BDB329674EE896C6C5C2CE479AE3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish a program for the purposes of detecting economically motivated adulteration and improving honey integrity for honey introduced, or delivered for introduction, into interstate commerce. Such program shall be known as the Honey Integrity Program.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB51A2DD44EA149DAA254F299EF4151DB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Testing required</header> 
<paragraph id="H6B5690BE28574772A5D6338718EDE45B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Pursuant to the Honey Integrity Program, beginning 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall require that each qualifying commercial honey packer in the United States—</text> <subparagraph id="HA9F985E8B00549A1881335389E4DA9A8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>conduct testing on honey the packer intends to be marketed in the United States, as described in paragraph (2);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9D4597F9C8E9466CBAB2E5060B1C1242"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">certify to the Secretary that the packer has complied with the requirements of this section and that the packer has no reason to believe that the packer has traded in honey that has been the subject of economically motivated adulteration; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H92312260C927442BA5C41BBD48E0C6A3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>report the results of such testing to the Secretary at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may specify.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEDDFAD60844C4387A513919B395C7297"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Testing requirements</header><text>A qualifying commercial honey packer shall ensure that testing conducted pursuant to paragraph (1) shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H450506AB981C45C2BED46F0C7AC3F32F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">use all the best available science, including nuclear DNA testing, mitochondrial DNA testing, and any other established forensic DNA identity testing methods, nuclear magnetic resonance, high-resolution mass spectrometry, and other tests in a combined protocol designed to produce the most scientifically valid outcomes with respect to detecting economically motivated adulteration;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H31A4733A53064C5FA1E57A3059BA3E8B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure that a minimum volume of honey is tested to be effective according to law enforcement protocols to be developed by the Secretary, in consultation with the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection, and the heads of other Federal agencies, as the Secretary determines appropriate; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEDF9FDF190D142F383AF59AD09CBB3BA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>be consistent with, or superior to, the best practices of other countries with respect to conducting testing of honey for economically motivated adulteration (as defined by the Secretary).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H83F73BC94E7B4CF6A080EEB7CD3F0DBD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Packer obligations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall require each qualifying commercial honey packer to—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF2452042F3FC482EAB1771690B9104FE"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">report to the Secretary findings of testing conducted under this section, at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may specify; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H569B7BC0BE8B44E78B6623E478454BE2"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a packer identifying economically motivated adulteration (as defined by the Secretary) in any honey the packer intends to market in the United States—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H21121AAEAF8143EE96554E18FE019246"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">report such information to the Secretary and such law enforcement officials as the Secretary may require, not later than 24 hours after that identification; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HF228E327695A45EC8CAD520E8F397278"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>refuse receipt of such honey.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H158630E4658549109523723F048B149F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Effect of EMA identification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon receipt of an alert of the identification of economically motivated adulteration (as defined by the Secretary), the Secretary shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H89F6CF7A68CC4B00B7231DA1CEF09016"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">investigate, test, and destroy honey determined to be so adulterated after confirming results through Federal laboratory findings; </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4909DB0ED6934CF59C82EA9C80FD5BB4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>maintain and share data on such identification with relevant enforcement agencies at the Federal, State, and local level, including the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection and the Secretary of Agriculture; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1F81D7D9B4994D1E9317D2A37DDE8656"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">maintain and share data on such identification with stakeholders, including national domestic producer associations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H025B59A5DA4D4777A25FECE61DB40630"><enum>(c)</enum><header>List of packers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H1D2FB031EAFB4A94A713644A5FB4A703"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">publish, and update as necessary, a list of each qualifying commercial honey packer in the United States, including packers excluded by the Secretary from being considered a qualifying commercial honey packer; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5AEB43CEFE0E4CAD9C10C130A28F5FCA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>distribute such list, upon initial publication, and upon each update, to relevant stakeholders, as determined by the Secretary<italic>.</italic></text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H141CEE586FF24434937807BA443C332B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Interagency cooperation</header> 
<paragraph id="H5846C89FFC7143AE99C809677E2676B3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In developing the testing requirements under subsection (b), the Secretary shall consult with the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection, the Secretary of Agriculture, and the head of any other Federal agency the Secretary determines to be appropriate, and the Secretary may consult with such Commissioner, such Secretary, and the heads of such other Federal agencies in otherwise carrying out this section. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H199DA22301944ADCBBBE89554C81DD91"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Resources</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case that the Food and Drug Administration lacks the necessary resources and laboratories available to test honey, U.S. Customs and Border Protection and the Department of Agriculture shall make available to the Secretary laboratory and other resources required by the Secretary for purposes of carrying out this section. </text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD2000329BFFA4E0F823A2A9B1A8A83E0"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Fees and funding</header> 
<paragraph id="HC9F9082AA9BF4D04B441FF93D351AB1E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Assessment</header><text>Each qualifying commercial honey packer shall be subject to a fee due at such time and in such amounts as the Secretary may specify.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6D24B8D4832542278CD34C28C368FE89"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Crediting and availability of fees</header><text>Fees authorized under paragraph (1) shall be collected and available for obligation only to the extent and in the amount provided in advance in appropriations Acts. Such fees are authorized to remain available until expended.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1A1C6BC4236F4A6781841AB0967BF3F2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated for fees under this section an amount equal to the amount necessary to carry out this section. </text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H4C8650C46B124810A2174E4A0BCBB68F"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="HD5DCB5D1EBD14E3F874323EC56FF616B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>economically motivated adulteration</term> means any practice, such as intentionally leaving out, taking out, substituting a valuable ingredient or part of a food, or adding a substance to a food, that is intended to increase the value of a food (as defined in section 201 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/321">21 U.S.C. 321</external-xref>)) that makes such food adulterated within the meaning of section 402 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/342">21 U.S.C. 342</external-xref>). <italic></italic></text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCC973571CC304FD59B5B4FAC2830BC0E"><enum>(2)</enum> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H13BBE5C5EF634824AB6492242899C4CF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The term <term>qualifying commercial honey packer</term> means any packer who is required to pay an assessment to the National Honey Board established pursuant to the Commodity Promotion, Research, and Information Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/7411">7 U.S.C. 7411 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H952336C94B0A4F4287F74EBEC519188B" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Such term excludes packers who meet such criteria for exclusion as the Secretary may develop.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H77CF4612F49E442B90EBE6063BBBAF51"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Secretary</term>, except as otherwise specified, means the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Commissioner of Food and Drugs.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

