<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDED0C37CE2C84436BA99F91ED2A7E13A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5747 IH: Preventing Illegal Laboratories and Protecting Public Health Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5747</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251014">October 14, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="V000129">Mr. Valadao</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Assistant Secretary for Preparedness and Response, to carry out a program under which the Secretary requires each covered distributor of a highly pathogenic agent to comply with certain logbook requirements, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9536DB30629D45BCB765503393880134" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H0960F78FF43444C4A5088A7A8ED3E874" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Preventing Illegal Laboratories and Protecting Public Health Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HB6D2FA05D2C04B80B4DC1EEE539827CA"><enum>2.</enum><header>Requiring certain distributors of highly pathogenic agents to keep a logbook of sales, leases, loans, and other transfers</header> <subsection id="HA38CFA29C71148958196F514F12AB722"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Program</header><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Administration for Strategic Preparedness and Response, shall carry out a program under which the Secretary requires each covered distributor of a highly pathogenic agent to comply with the logbook requirements of subsection (c).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HAE2F1CE8CDC84EB2A4D009A78F3A54D4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>List of highly pathogenic agents</header> 
<paragraph id="H0BFC340E6433480AB43AA9E26EFDA7B9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Development</header><text>The Secretary shall develop and maintain a list of all agents that meet the definition of a highly pathogenic agent in subsection (e).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBD70DC4C26AB421AA15C7F01C33E6BC0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Initial list</header><text>The Secretary shall develop the initial list required by paragraph (1) not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0969876D99CB4F79AA0113DAB05573A7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Periodic review</header><text>The Secretary shall annually review and update the list required by paragraph (1).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7489305E1A1244D1AF3672DBF4A8D080"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Consultation; consideration</header><text>In developing and updating the list required by paragraph (1), the Secretary shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H1E30037C66E9478391CF4890B042429C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>consult with relevant agencies, including the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, the National Institutes of Health, the Department of Homeland Security, the Department of Agriculture, the Department of the Interior, and the Department of Defense;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFC85E18AE1A34A8BACADF8F7CDE177CB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>take into consideration the latest edition of <quote>Biosafety in Microbiological and Biomedical Laboratories</quote> published by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention and the National Institutes of Health (or any successor to such publication); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDE1ABEF327644DD189EDD13A1573E0FB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>take into consideration the latest edition of <quote>NIH Guidelines for Research Involving Recombinant or Synthetic Nucleic Acid Molecules</quote> published by the National Institutes of Health (or any successor to such publication).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HA973574D525B45E1BD706103EAEB6B7A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Logbook requirements</header> <paragraph id="HC6A41395FF6A4A53AA2E1988845184AB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each covered distributor shall maintain, in accordance with such criteria and format as the Secretary may require, an electronic list (in this section referred to as a <quote>logbook</quote>) of the sales, leases, loans, or other transfers by such distributor of each highly pathogenic agent on the list under subsection (b).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H76ACCDF8A3144D1DBFFEAF295E573224"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The covered distributor shall, for each sale, lease, loan, or other transfer referred to in paragraph (1), include in the logbook—</text> <subparagraph id="H146F3FC282C64A1B8CBE73D5522140F9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the agent by name;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H99100098882A42B68A3444A6F5B69F07"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the name, address, telephone number, and email address of the purchaser;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H42387D86056C4765B3460C8EB88FDA76"><enum>(C)</enum><text>other relevant identifying business information of the purchaser, as deemed necessary by the Secretary;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2AB319ECE3004B22A17A40FFE74528E6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a short description of—</text> <clause id="HA401C7C71C624ED1987A8EF73423F871"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the purchaser’s intended use of the highly pathogenic agent; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H37417016F28C416E8311AE15AEF83F7D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>where the purchaser will house the agent;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF44B38241E5A475D898C4B62694336FD"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the date and time of the sale, lease, loan, or other transfer;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5D98FA3E3B594969AEF780767CD6DFF4"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the method, date, and time of transfer of the highly pathogenic agent;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAB81C71D3D1F488CAF802DE4897347A5"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a physical or electronic signature of the purchaser; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H086BD2ADFD754BC79F8F9076A7DDF28E"><enum>(H)</enum><text>such other data elements as the Secretary may require.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H493D099F04CB4A3B854E0999DA11FBD4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Sale requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a sale, lease, loan, or other transfer to which paragraph (1) applies, the covered distributor shall not sell the highly pathogenic agent unless—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H2223CC95AA3944389C4BCEE27A441BB4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the prospective purchaser, in physical form or electronically in compliance with the Electronic Signatures in Global and National Commerce Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7001">42 U.S.C. 7001 et seq.</external-xref>)—</text> <clause id="H6B44590E52C249F5832BFFC045F63EE2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>presents an identification card that provides a photograph and is issued by a State or the Federal Government, or a document that, with respect to identification, is considered acceptable for purposes of sections 274a.2(b)(1)(v)(A) and 274a.2(b)(1)(v)(B) of title 8, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations); and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA3A98124F7E84A9AACAA8C70677EF441"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>verifies by signature in the logbook—</text> <subclause id="H1CB90DD98B9C47DCB295AE7500230CED"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the purchaser’s name and address;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HF907D21ECFF34E8784B8B92CD892822F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a short description of—</text> <item id="H156290B0AC824E0FA8547A3AF4F1B9F6"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the purchaser’s intended use of the agent; and</text></item> 
<item id="H48DBEBC030CC4E488F6199269FC0A3B1"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>where the purchaser will house the agent;</text></item></subclause> <subclause id="H1D706CCD563345EC867ACD032F351F83"> <enum>(III)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the date and time of the sale, lease, loan, or other transfer; and</text>
                            </subclause> 
<subclause id="HB504DF6F431A4FEAA971AA74EA646A05"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the method, date, and time of transfer of the agent; and</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5C475E466C7C4FE0B993F646CD93F731"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the covered distributor—</text> 
<clause id="H6753F83CA8C44D45A71E32DE1D1FA2D1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>determines that the name entered in the logbook corresponds to the name provided on the identification card referred to in subparagraph (A)(i), and that the information entered pursuant to subparagraph (A)(ii) is correct; and</text></clause> <clause id="HD5D080A29DC04D99AD4D94C32D4ADA1D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>enters in the logbook the name of the highly pathogenic agent.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF56EC5F947C940828989BF594FC1F815"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The covered distributor shall include in the logbook, in accordance with criteria of the Secretary, a notice to purchasers that entering false statements or misrepresentations in the logbook may subject the purchasers to criminal penalties under section 1001 of title 18, United States Code, which notice specifies the maximum fine and term of imprisonment under such section.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF758EE7DFA98487A898B62E3C8EED735"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Duration of maintenance of entries</header> <subparagraph id="H8719FC38F5E24F91AED12A398D50AC48"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Retention period</header><text>The covered distributor shall maintain each entry in the logbook for not fewer than three years after the date on which the entry is made.</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC21D302D99CF403885B98B76FC7E5C54"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Successor entity</header><text>If ownership of a covered distributor changes, the successor entity shall assume custody of and responsibility for all logbooks for the balance of the three-year retention period required by subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEF4EE5890A954BAB8FD03FD006905929"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Disclosure of logbooks</header><text>The Secretary shall establish restrictions on disclosure of information in logbooks. Such regulations shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HDCE6948531B34540BF0DEDAD3E7CA9E0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide for the disclosure of the information as appropriate to the Secretary, Federal, State, local, Tribal, and territorial law enforcement agencies, and State health officials; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB29DE5E17B1348219072A1BE650351EE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>prohibit accessing, using, or sharing information in the logbooks for any purpose other than—</text> 
<clause id="H5BD42F602AB44B78AA58306FD7338EC2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to ensure compliance with this section;</text></clause> <clause id="HA71C16FB69594300A157861BDAC1A654"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to protect public health and safety; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="HC6A32C88B78143218B8C78DB51B45266"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to protect national security.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4FA2A5FC194E4666819C5F9B6E365EB7"><enum>(7)</enum><header>FOIA exemption</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Logbooks and any derivative data are exempt from disclosure under section 552(b)(3) of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7A4209462CDC486FA04B4255C581B50E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>False statements or misrepresentations by purchasers</header><text>For purposes of section 1001 of title 18, United States Code, entering information in a logbook shall be considered a matter within the jurisdiction of the executive, legislative, or judicial branch of the Government of the United States.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H63FA64ECD8BF456CA7497AA95001DD89"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H333FE6CC01EB4DFF96C2A2A721A31B47"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>highly pathogenic agent</term>—</text> <subparagraph id="H13CE172A6D824FACA44E51415F3E9241"><enum>(A)</enum><text>subject to subparagraph (B), means a pathogenic agent that meets the criteria of <quote>risk group 3</quote> or any higher level risk groups as such risk groups are defined in the latest edition of <quote>NIH Guidelines for Research Involving Recombinant or Synthetic Nucleic Acid Molecules</quote> published by the National Institutes of Health (or any successor to such publication); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1F53CD1AB7284F2FA733F6D16E37D350"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">excludes any biological agent or toxin that is regulated under section 351A of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/262a">42 U.S.C. 262a</external-xref>) or section 212 of the Agricultural Bioterrorism Protection Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/8401">7 U.S.C. 8401</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H83342177FFDF425E8B21F1F7C471F28A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered distributor</term>—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H3D313F6EF10B452CA811AA5815BF9134"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means an entity that sells, leases, loans, or otherwise transfers for value or without value a highly pathogenic agent, except that such term does not include an employee or agent of such a distributor; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H57B1857318C147E4853FBDD7647528AC"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes a publicly funded repository or biobank that sells, leases, loans, or otherwise transfers a highly pathogenic agent, as described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H24C9D56E0F7E421B9C02501D739D3651"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Administration for Strategic Preparedness and Response.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H1DF81BFB7F004ADF8B5041772B9C3EAA" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to supersede or otherwise affect the Federal Select Agent Program under section 351A of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/262a">42 U.S.C. 262a</external-xref>) and section 212 of the Agricultural Bioterrorism Protection Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/8401">7 U.S.C. 8401</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HCB5A51AB9327482C9E9F09F7CD6BB93F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Evaluation of high-containment laboratories</header> 
<subsection id="H18E6A0F025A6413694CD4DE942149560"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The National Security Advisor, in consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Secretary of the Interior, the Director of National Intelligence, and such other Federal officials as the National Security Advisor determines appropriate, shall identify a single Federal entity to oversee a periodic strategic evaluation of high-containment laboratories in the United States.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H4338E3041ACC4F729E7DDF3487EC6F37"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Topics</header><text>Each strategic evaluation under subsection (a) shall include—</text> 
<paragraph id="H585EFCDBB5964FCF9B9D2ED590365EE2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an assessment of—</text> <subparagraph id="H26DB8818F7AD40AD8D0D008BA57804ED"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number, location, and mission of high-containment laboratories;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDBF3135EA4FA4339852C44B3FB71591D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the capacity of such existing laboratories to effectively meet national goals to counter threats to biosafety and biosecurity;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEE9CB6D2AB484453AB632461754E388B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the physical security measures at high-containment laboratories;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8F49D4858C4F4A3289319AAEE76DDE40"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the aggregate risks associated with—</text> <clause id="H9AC434EE0DF8407BA5AB98F3AFF5DB16"><enum>(i)</enum><text>such existing laboratories; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HB4C7213E309E45B885CF4759E18DB308"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>expanding the numbers and facilities of such laboratories; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCBF14F13365C44568892F3ED10D8C710"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the type of oversight needed for high-containment laboratories; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBDFEA08D744F44E8A038900406ACADE9" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">up-to-date national standards, developed by the Federal entity identified under subsection (a)—</text> <subparagraph id="H59296677DADC4B5BBF4E7468FEED0FCB" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>are developed by the Federal entity identified under subsection (a) in consultation with members of the scientific community, for the design, construction, commissioning, operation, and long-term maintenance of high-containment laboratories; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H201BD66A0D3E474D84E1477D4968B1A8" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>take into consideration applicable regulations and guidance for high-containment laboratories.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H4517DAB34ACB49ED92F423D4A25B0C83"> <enum>(c)</enum> <header>Reporting</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon completion of each strategic evaluation under subsection (a), the Federal entity identified under subsection (a) shall submit to the President and the Congress a report on the results of such evaluation and include in each such report recommendations on—</text>
        <paragraph id="HFB6F6653A3D5427085CC6DB27878C0F1">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>addressing gaps in Federal oversight of high-containment laboratories; and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HB11BB7DCE04B425CA8D7B531C514A10F"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>utilizing high-containment laboratories for protecting public health and ensuring biosafety and biosecurity in the United States.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HD7B1924D659E4C2E9AE2BAFE0D1EB8DC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Public health biosafety and biosecurity team</header> 
<paragraph id="H560D4CD4B4E74261A85A3EAAF756B29C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal entity identified under subsection (a) shall maintain a team, to be known as the Public Health Biosafety and Biosecurity Team, to serve as a single point of contact for State, local, Tribal, and territorial agencies regarding questions relating to laboratory biosafety and biosecurity.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H95BD2B20173D4D25865316178EB4C93D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal entity identified under subsection (a) shall establish the Public Health and Biosecurity Team, as required by paragraph (1), not later than one year after such official is first designated.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H66C4C4C769C54AAF955345DB105654BE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Public Health Biosafety and Biosecurity Team shall be the single point of contact in the Federal Government for State, local, Tribal, and territorial agencies on—</text> <subparagraph id="HB6E377B3553840209C4B5560DFB87E55"><enum>(A)</enum><text>issues related to—</text> 
<clause id="HABC59FB8F5104DA584502466CB19E927"><enum>(i)</enum><text>oversight of high-containment laboratories;</text></clause> <clause id="HD2E36A7078E54F549EB02D978DE0D6E0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the impact of high-containment laboratories on public health; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA61BD488F03B4BFC8FD5374FB06F66D5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>connecting State, local, Tribal, and territorial officials with the relevant Federal agency or agencies on matters related to high-containment laboratories; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCA2CD6AF802545B0B940F2BDC1455FD6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>other issues as determined necessary by the Federal entity identified under subsection (a).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC768D7B8D05C4D009D76ECB2FE5AA52C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Feasibility study</header> 
<paragraph id="H8EB63D2CCAF144D1A7107BFDAAC1F944"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Federal entity identified under subsection (a) shall conduct a feasibility study on establishing and maintaining a database on existing high-containment laboratories in the United States for the purpose of making such database accessible to Federal, State, local, Tribal, and territorial officials.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H57C4825E8B4C44CCA4F0826CFCF673E7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Database described</header><text>The database to be studied under paragraph (1) should be designed to include, with respect to each high-containment laboratory, the following information:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HFB25C94926FA4D46AA2599C925906721"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The identity of the owners of the laboratory.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBD6C1E66A4EF45A68506B5423FEEA8B1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The address of the laboratory.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBED50322BC3B4E84BAF3509983CD97BA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The status of any licensing or certification of the laboratory required under Federal, State, local, Tribal, or territorial law.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0458CC81222F4655A4803280003C1048"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Any legal violations by, and disciplinary action taken against, the laboratory.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA6F205B4A49C4CBDBC0E3AA15CAC8471"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such additional information as the Federal entity identified under subsection (a) determines appropriate to protect biosafety and biosecurity.</text></subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H3AAC8383DA5440BFBEF02BF913EFD649"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon completion of the feasibility study under this subsection, the Federal entity identified under subsection (a) shall submit to the Congress a report on the results of such study.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD86FEDA0A5EA47719667CE1A2142AEA4"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <term>high-containment laboratory</term> means laboratories that are suitable for <quote>biosafety level 3</quote> or any higher biosafety level procedures as defined in the latest edition of <quote>Biosafety in Microbiological and Biomedical Laboratories</quote> published by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention and the National Institutes of Health (or any successor to such publication).</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

