<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-MDM25B27-4HX-VR-WWH"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 264 IS: To support the naming of certain United States Navy ships after notable civil rights leaders and to strongly encourage the Department of Defense not to change the names of such ships.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 264</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250605">June 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To support the naming of certain United States Navy ships after notable civil rights leaders and to strongly encourage the Department of Defense not to change the names of such ships.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the John Lewis-class fleet replenishment oilers serve a vital role in replenishing fuel to United States Navy ships and aircraft assigned to aircraft carriers;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas naming the class of ship and the first of its members after former United States Congressman John Lewis is a befitting tribute to a true United States civil rights icon;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the other ships in the class, including ships that are still under construction or are not yet constructed, have been named after other civil rights luminaries, including Harvey Milk, Earl Warren, Robert F. Kennedy, Lucy Stone, Sojourner Truth, Thurgood Marshall, Ruth Bader Ginsburg, Harriet Tubman, Dolores Huerta, Joshua L. Goldberg, and Thomas D. Parham; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, by naming these ships, the United States Navy has appropriately celebrated notable civil rights leaders and their legacy in promoting a more equal and just United States: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id7ddf3bfb2df94f318f305042dd1518c9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>strongly supports the naming of John Lewis-class fleet replacement oilers after the aforementioned civil rights leaders as a fitting tribute to honor their contributions to the advancement of civil rights; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id90f1ca8504264da381a85c8c6850532f"><enum>(2)</enum><text>strongly encourages the Department of Defense not to take any action to change the names of any of the ships referred to in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

