<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-HEY25B83-57F-16-DL6"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>118 S2389 IS: Advanced Reactor Modernization for Operational Resilience Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2389</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250723">July 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S426">Mr. Kim</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S435">Mr. Sheehy</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Secretary of the Army to carry out a pilot program to provide resilient energy to critical infrastructure of installations of the Army through the use of advanced nuclear reactors, to authorize multi-year contracts for such reactors, and to include nuclear energy and technology as a covered technology category for the Office of Strategic Capital of the Department of Defense, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Advanced Reactor Modernization for Operational Resilience Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>ARMOR Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id981eefd77caa41ec9d3f18e117bff810"><enum>2.</enum><header>Pilot program to provide resilient energy to critical infrastructure of installations of the Army</header><subsection id="id2f7ede9800564bdcbbcb4133a291cbae"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Pilot program required</header><text>The Secretary of the Army (in this section referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>), in conjunction with the Director of the Defense Innovation Unit, shall carry out a pilot program to provide resilient energy to critical infrastructure of installations of the Department of the Army through the deployment of a fixed facility advanced nuclear micro-reactor or small modular reactor (in this section referred to as the pilot program).</text></subsection><subsection id="idddb2ac81f3f948a7a2cc1e255598644c"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Locations</header><text>The Secretary shall carry out the pilot program at installations in the United States under the jurisdiction of the Secretary that are identified by the Secretary for purposes of the pilot program.</text></subsection><subsection id="id2b9e592c346d48549e0eefc97c2ebf10"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Objectives</header><text>The objective of the pilot program is to develop and provide a source of resilient energy for critical infrastructure of installations of the Department of the Army selected under subsection (b) by not later than December 31, 2030, utilizing a fixed facility advanced nuclear reactor.</text></subsection><subsection id="id30c75c0efa7c4ac487bc897602814295"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In carrying out the pilot program, the Secretary shall consider whether a fixed facility advanced nuclear reactor under the pilot program—</text><paragraph id="id7748d06635f748e68e3d9760b305ebb4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>should be owned and operated by a contractor;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4a7c6c3e8cf6479b9fb085560dd63ca4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>should be licensed as a commercial reactor by the Nuclear Regulatory Commission, with advice and consent of the Secretary; or</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5dfadbe4cdc747289dadd369d59a1a1a"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">as feasible and consistent with military requirements, should be co-located with artificial intelligence infrastructure and data centers.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4aabfe4bf21441cd8517a5862dd939aa"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Capabilities</header><text>In carrying out the pilot program, the Secretary shall ensure that a fixed facility advanced nuclear reactor under the pilot program—</text><paragraph id="id65011d8bbb854cf8b34f463cb1e7840d"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is capable of power generation output of up to 300 megawatts; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8b07e706f6984cfd8f9bd6859742ca62"><enum>(2)</enum><text>as feasible and consistent with military requirements, is capable of connecting to the commercial grid in order to sell excess energy pursuant to section 2916 of title 10, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id18e3741eb369452892995fc110307571"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Licensing priority</header><text>Licensing of advanced reactors covered under the pilot program shall, consistent with the Accelerating Deployment of Versatile, Advanced Nuclear for Clean Energy Act of 2024 (division B of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/118/67">Public Law 118–67</external-xref>; 138 Stat. 1448), be prioritized by the Office of Nuclear Reactor Regulation and the Nuclear Regulatory Commission.</text></subsection><subsection id="id61a478faf2dd4fe39b9996003ab11eb0"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Expansion of pilot program</header><text>Upon request to the Secretary of Defense, and with notice to the congressional defense committees (as defined in section 101(a) of title 10, United States Code), the Secretary of another military department may participate in the pilot program to provide resilient energy to critical infrastructure at installations under the jurisdiction of that Secretary through the deployment of a fixed facility advanced nuclear micro-reactor or small modular reactor.</text></subsection><subsection id="idc7cb2b7075584bb6967a0dfe2466e342"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>All costs of the pilot program may be paid from any appropriation available for the purposes of the pilot program.</text></subsection><subsection id="idc276b8a640b34be6abf9a3573d0789e0"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Termination date</header><text>The authority to develop and construct a fixed facility advance nuclear micro-reactor or small modular reactor under this section shall terminate on December 31, 2035.</text></subsection></section><section id="id2e6fd0e8c3c345faacc4c614082762e3"><enum>3.</enum><header>Authority for multi-year contracts for energy from advanced nuclear reactors</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/173">chapter 173</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5c2729c8ee3d436091526ac0af81714d"><section id="id2cbdf77fc1c44e9eab9ebc54cc41aaf7"><enum>2922K.</enum><header>Multi-year contracts for energy from advanced nuclear reactors</header><subsection id="id41a6496232254268a3f0aa47422aca14"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subsection (b), the Secretary of a military department may enter into a contract or contracts for a duration of not more than 50 years for the operation of an energy production facility through the use of an advanced nuclear reactor, as that term is defined in section 951(b)(1) of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/16271">42 U.S.C. 16271(b)(1)</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection id="idb5e0679431ab4657ab21eb9bf3cd557e"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>The costs of any contract under this section may be paid from any appropriation available for that purpose.</text></subsection><subsection id="ide24813c892f8427682f73003e060d6fc"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consideration</header><text>As part of any consideration under a contract made under this section for the operation of an energy production facility, the Secretary of a military department may include the value of land leased for the siting of the energy production facility.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="id44d490589e3d4ea19964e8d5dc3c74db"><enum>4.</enum><header>Modification of covered technology category for Office of Strategic Capital</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 149(e)(2) of title 10, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id884c490a012a4ba992919869a757a09b"><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id232321829c684965bd93ec42c920872a"><enum>(HH)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nuclear energy.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcdd87aa1525d407081338368bc8c6812"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nuclear technologies.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill>

