<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HFFE116D73F6D4D17A9BD5B28FDC3E511" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 548 IH: Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives to commend President Donald J. Trump for his successful diplomatic efforts in deescalating the recent armed conflict between India and Pakistan.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 548</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250626">June 26, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000626">Mr. Davidson</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives to commend President Donald J. Trump for his successful diplomatic efforts in deescalating the recent armed conflict between India and Pakistan.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the United States has consistently supported efforts to promote peace and stability in South Asia;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas tensions between India and Pakistan rose sharply following a recent armed confrontation, heightening concerns about the potential for broader military conflict between two nuclear-armed states;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas President Donald J. Trump, with the support of senior diplomatic and security officials, acted decisively to engage both parties and urge a peaceful resolution to the crisis;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Governments of Pakistan and India played a constructive and supportive role by encouraging United States engagement and signaling willingness to reduce hostilities;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the President’s leadership and timely diplomatic intervention contributed significantly to the deescalation of tensions and the prevention of further conflict; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas peace and stability in South Asia is critical to global security and is in the national interest of the United States: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HB346FE3FCA3A42FBBF1EC513B943A530"> 
<section id="H1213FC282C1F4C808A1E1D430C3998D3" section-type="undesignated-section" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That it is the sense of the House of Representatives that—</text> <paragraph id="H4EB87563379E40A0B4E2C54534DB8B6F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the House of Representatives commends President Donald J. Trump for his successful diplomatic efforts to deescalate the recent crisis between India and Pakistan;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF40D307E5F604E3487B381D78A0CB977"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the House of Representatives acknowledges and appreciates the constructive role played by the Governments of Pakistan and India in supporting dialogue and encouraging diplomatic engagement;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA3524A43E2B54B44BF2E1BF1BC6CF55E"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the House of Representatives reaffirms the importance of continued United States leadership in promoting peace and conflict resolution in South Asia; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFFD41524983D45C8A48E1063F3B65872">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the House of Representatives encourages both India and Pakistan to pursue sustained dialogue and mutual cooperation to ensure long-term stability and prosperity in the region.</text>
      </paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

