<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MAZ25509-4GY-HG-S1H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2291 IS: Flex Fuel Fairness Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2291</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250715">July 15, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S423">Mr. Ricketts</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEV00">Committee on Environment and Public Works</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to ensure that flexible fuel vehicles may use certain gram per mile carbon dioxide values for purposes of determining fleet average carbon dioxide standards for certain vehicles.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="id0ba6b4f6473b435aaf947200d501199e"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Flex Fuel Fairness Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section section-type="subsequent-section" id="S1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Finding</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that the Greenhouse gases, Regulated Emissions, and Energy use in Technologies (GREET) model developed by Argonne National Laboratory finds that E85 fuel made with average corn starch ethanol reduces greenhouse gas emissions by 37 percent per mile traveled as compared to gasoline with no ethanol.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id379bb330eb8c47739b891ce69901f9ff"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd9ba048aa2a24fa7bc5491da99d9b5ba"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9923161efa724c39834fffa9c93bf3a0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Flexible fuel vehicle</header><text>The term <term>flexible fuel vehicle</term> has the meaning given the term in section 86.1803–01 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act). </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf4edc7c875404ab6bd3dc66b04446532"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Manufacturer</header><text>The term <term>manufacturer</term> has the meaning given the term in section 216 of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7550">42 U.S.C. 7550</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida49f073a9011404396412c03d7a774f8"><enum>4.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Flexible fuel vehicle compliance value</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id03d6074fcc6846528270f97bf8f4124a"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall revise section 86.1818–12 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations, to ensure that, for purposes of determining fleet average CO<subscript>2</subscript> standards under that section, manufacturers may use a gram per mile CO<subscript>2</subscript> value for flexible fuel vehicles that is 31 percent lower than the gram per mile CO<subscript>2</subscript> value for the same vehicle make and model that is not a flexible fuel vehicle. </text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5ecc6ab160094bc498d113a87842f50f"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Further adjustment</header><text>The Administrator may, by regulation, apply a larger percentage reduction in the gram per mile CO<subscript>2</subscript> value for flexible fuel vehicles than the percentage described in subsection (a) if the Administrator determines that the larger percentage reduction is appropriate based on a version of the Greenhouse gases, Regulated Emissions, and Energy use in Technologies (GREET) model developed by Argonne National Laboratory after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

