<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" dms-id="H4339C865CA24458EA7435F25C517F5BC" public-private="public" key="G" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2591 : Mental Health in Aviation Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2591</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250909">September 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration to revise regulations for certain individuals carrying out aviation activities who disclose a mental health diagnosis or condition, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" style="OLC" id="H2C2B12EDC7094E2EA19DA72AFE3C3C30"><pagebreak></pagebreak><section id="HB106ADAF742443E5B00CC36F660B0E5F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Mental Health in Aviation Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H9010F22D9F424D44B322DB3D151F3A5F" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Regulations for individuals carrying out aviation activities</header><subsection id="H89FAD37293F94F8AA93B9BEE24B5DF7F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall update regulations, including in part 67 of title 14 of Code of Federal Regulations, as appropriate, to encourage individuals to—</text><paragraph id="HFDCC3FFDEFBC41F4B80FA27AEA08DE06"><enum>(1)</enum><text>seek help for mental health conditions or symptoms of mental health conditions; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0E471358CC544298BA5F6F82B5F449CB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>disclose conditions or symptoms described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2AE208B936A8460A9A635FE5862E7329"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation; report requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 411(d) of the FAA Reauthorization Act of 2024 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/44703">49 U.S.C. 44703</external-xref> note(d)) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H6326AD2A247640DBAB3DC37806F7E469"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)—</text><subparagraph id="H76183A51C3F440A0B0AB19373B905A34"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (A) by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H27762F5EA8BE4116AA22B20870BF3D06"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B) by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEC5CA962B7194B2DBFB04A8EA1ECC72A"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (C) by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEBAA060231F94C95ADB36F5163B57A73"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1F16BBF047DD44A5964089CD598D42AD"><subparagraph id="HBCF3C146BD2E4B8EBBA7C7F8459A2487"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a review and evaluation of any recommendations reached by the National Transportation Safety Board related to aviation workforce mental health; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H64C8782BA86149C5AA592B22CBD932CE"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of relevant clinical studies, research, diagnostic manuals, and protocols used by the licensed professionals as of the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF2AE05C535194E8EB13C62EFB8ABE97F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HFD972C77F2454CEE8C0E09A527EE5536" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="HB6D2BD785A2C479BAE5FD249A87218AC"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out this subsection, the task group shall consult with relevant stakeholders from the aviation and medical communities, as necessary, including—</text><subparagraph id="H7DC884FBA2C747CAA4ABE7D0DC436CAF" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the certified exclusive bargaining representatives of air traffic controllers of the Administration certified under section 7111 of title 5, United States Code;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF9DC2806727B4F44A37AB4040F7A840C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>organizations representing certified collective bargaining representatives of airline pilots;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEA201E4B13A542C492BD264846461DCB"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">aviation medical examiners, as described in section 183.21 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5D2636ACE015468DB5BE956493ED064A"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other stakeholder determined relevant by the task group, including any stakeholders described in paragraph (3)(B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7609665041D448CA81C402A2DB88FD7A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Implementation</header><paragraph id="H6207DCF48E7649B1B65BCAB379E1DF74"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the submission of the report required under section 411(f) of the FAA Reauthorization Act of 2024 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/44703">49 U.S.C. 44703</external-xref> note), the Administrator shall take such actions as are necessary to implement the mental health-related recommendations of such report.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H95100049735E475FA91234656F358AC4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Justification</header><text>If the Administrator decides not to implement any of the recommendations described in paragraph (1), the Administrator shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress the justification for such decision.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H1FC5BEFC35BF4CB28A4D80A594CFA00B"><enum>3.</enum><header>Annual review of mental health special issuance process</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Administrator shall conduct an annual review, and update, as appropriate, the applicable regulations, policies, orders, and guidance on mental health-related special issuance for pilots and air traffic controllers to— </text><paragraph id="HAB573562B8B14887B2F115AB49C6EA3A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reclassify and approve additional medications that may be safely prescribed to airmen to treat mental health conditions;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HECE5309E1100402CA9DD859134187104"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">improve mental health knowledge and training for aviation medical examiners;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H40DF247E6DD847CA8692F84F6902FDF4"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the Administrator determines appropriate, delegate additional authority to aviation medical examiners consistent with the recommendation of the Mental Health Aviation Rulemaking Committee described in section 5; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4584BD59FF0D48ACB41FD18D50435C4D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>improve the special issuance process for pilots and air traffic controllers.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H540856F89E03471BAC6FBC3EBB7A9B04"><enum>4.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriation for additional aviation medical examiners</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Of the amounts made available pursuant to section 106(k)(1) of title 49, United States Code, the Administrator shall set aside $13,740,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2028 to—</text><paragraph id="HF7272ED84D3E446AAC2C904ED08C6BC4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recruit, select, train, and delegate the necessary authorities to additional aviation medical examiners and human intervention motivation study aviation medical examiners, including those who are psychiatrists;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9F8058551BEB40EAA5872E2E678592B4"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">expand capacity to provide oversight of aviation medical examiners and clear the backlog of special issuance requests and cases awaiting review at the Office of Aerospace Medicine; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6F2EA9CF626E40289D480DA78E15D64C"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">support any other related activities, as the Administrator determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H2539273CA54E4B15BFF1E805DC095469"><enum>5.</enum><header>Implementation of aviation rulemaking committee recommendations</header><subsection id="H7A4824A54F6B4D5C95718BEA3EE80604"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall implement, to the greatest extent practicable, the recommendations of the Mental Health and Aviation Medical Clearances Aviation Rulemaking Committee which were submitted to the Administrator on April 1, 2024.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1F0B99E6FCC14D75896CDD7F284452CD" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out subsection (a), the Administrator shall consult with the parties described in section 411(d)(5) of the FAA Reauthorization Act of 2024 (as added by this Act). </text></subsection><subsection id="HC793C48434F644B7829FCADE8BB14AED"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Justification</header><text>If the Administrator decides not to implement any of the recommendations described in subsection (a), the Administrator shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress the justification for such decision.</text></subsection></section><section id="H1B8EF4069A724ACAA367BE27A3C0F95C"><enum>6.</enum><header>Public information campaign</header><subsection id="H823FF312700743FDA67957FCB5304F49"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the amounts made available under section 106(k)(1) of title 49, United States Code, the Administrator shall set aside $1,500,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2028 for a public information campaign or similar public education efforts to destigmatize individuals in (or interested in joining) the aviation industry who seek mental health care, to broaden awareness of available supportive services, and establish trust with pilots and air traffic controllers.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF53367E4EC494A4ABDAA9C0D2A5627E3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the Administrator creates the public information campaign described in subsection (a), the Administrator shall submit to appropriate committees of Congress a report describing the actions taken to develop such campaign and the plans for implementation.</text></subsection></section><section id="H41B4444ED9A949A2A1AF1B806CA92228"><enum>7.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H06F17FFA5F2841B9B6AD053137AEA058"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of Congress</header><text>The term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H18DC49ECB70847C6B99A473542A67FFC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBB3C32D0175D46CABF4E82391A7CECFC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1CAD326C346D4905AF7DE7DF9E0E84DD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Special issuance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>special issuance</term> has the meaning given the term in section 67.401 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20250908" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives September 8, 2025.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Kevin F. McCumber,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation></bill> 

