<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H07E2795CC681432C8279486B17CB9C98" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2841 IH: Putting Trust in Transparency Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2841</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250410">April 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000565">Mr. Gosar</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001302">Mr. Biggs of Arizona</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001317">Mr. Brecheen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001309">Mr. Burchett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001132">Mr. Crane</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000026">Mr. Nehls</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000190">Mr. Norman</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to require the public disclosure of the names and partial addresses of contributors to 501(c) organizations that receive Federal funding.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8C4A03361AD74E08BA975C0E307E8DD3" style="OLC"><section id="HFBC99FB294714F5382D8A6A3F6873341" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Putting Trust in Transparency Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="HED62D106DB244AB8AA651D549A078677"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings and Sense of Congress</header><subsection id="H4608FF6BC2AD41E7837D0F5D63CE5779"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H63FA62C88DD846F6AE79A6F449497F3A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the United States, nongovernmental organizations, or NGOs, often assist the Federal government with distribution of resources to the American People and abroad. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8D08A74C258E42719A81F097FB3B1870"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The executive Memo entitled <quote>Memorandum for the Heads of Executive Departments and Agencies</quote>, published February 6, 2025, requires executive departments and agencies to review all Federal funding to nongovernmental organizations; however, this review does not apply to these organizations’ non-Federal sources of funding. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H83B038523AFF4D74BAE61A676A67FC4D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The non-Federal sources of NGOs’ extravagant revenue are already reported to the Internal Revenue Service through the Form 990 Schedule B, but these Forms are not shared government wide. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4A8075EA33E74A0498EBBEBC1A835BC2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Article I, Section 8 of the U.S. Constitution empowers Congress to make rules for the government and regulate the use of taxpayer dollars. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H98A423DB439345DC96CFE157C4DA65A2"><enum>(5)</enum><text>NGOs that operate independently of the Federal government and any Federal grants or contributions of any amount are not subject to rigorous Congressional oversight and face limited restrictions on expression and association. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H662C38BC410B47BBA7CD0E6F7A85A773"><enum>(6)</enum><text>To empower lawmakers to make responsible decisions with Americans’ tax dollars and provide transparency to the American People, all Americans should have access to the megadonors of NGOs that leverage Federal dollars for their own agenda.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD19F81B66BC449069048A3CCDE94B92E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that any nongovernmental organization that receives Federal funding of any kind is acting on behalf of the United States government and subject to the same fiscal oversight requirements as executive agencies.</text></subsection></section><section id="HA6EFB4F7B7E744819E174586174D5AF5"><enum>3.</enum><header>Annual disclosure of contributors to exempt organizations</header><subsection id="H6301550628D5434C876306BD3D9A13C0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Amendments to Internal Revenue Code of 1986</header><paragraph id="H8DE89CCDBC454D6B870DC3E0E6A38D0E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Public disclosure of names and partial addresses of donors</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6104">Section 6104</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended—</text><subparagraph id="H051F95AF65D54569ACE920D6CEE193EF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>(except as provided in subsection (e))</quote> after <quote>name or address</quote> each place it appears, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H14A9BDFF0C94440588C0693CC6B52F7C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HD3D630696888485D95DBE604E853DBE8" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="HBBF4D3ABB7384824A48A51CBB0280CD7"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Public disclosure of Form 990</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an organization described in subsection (c) of section 501 and exempt from taxation under section 501(a) which receives Federal funding during the taxable year, the Secretary shall make public any schedule B of Form 990 (or successor Form) filed by such organization—</text><paragraph id="HDF78FF85ECAB4E4B90858E4EACF66972"><enum>(1)</enum><text>within 60 days of processing such Form, and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA21913235A814D8A8FEAECC260186667"><enum>(2)</enum><text>with the name, zip code, and total contribution of any contributor unredacted. </text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2D396655EF434224B9B88AC8C450D777"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Loss of exempt status for failure to file schedule B of Form 990</header><text>Section 6033(j) of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H4025CABF5720426380FA6EEEA7722EBC" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="HC90946DF78EB459A9A3CC9AC8855640D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Revocation of exempt status for failure to file schedule B of Form 990</header><subparagraph id="H6EF41DFD710F469A8641D26416BFFDD5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Notice</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an organization described in subsection (e) fails to file the Form required under such subsection by the due date for the return of tax for such organization for the taxable year, the Secretary shall notify the organization—</text><clause id="H326EEA115BD8471EA5EFA655B46279C2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that the Internal Revenue Service has no record of such a return or notice from such organization, and </text></clause><clause id="H05385D9A3D584B61AE8C42344B21AF24"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>about the revocation that will occur under subparagraph (B) if the organization fails to file such a return or notice within 60 days of such notification. </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFAF127063CE94D1B8609CFC77EDBD409"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Revocation</header><text>If an organization described in subsection (e) fails to file schedule B of Form 990 of the Internal Revenue Service (or any successor schedule or Form) with the return or notice of such organization for the taxable year, such organization's status as an organization exempt from tax under section 501(a) shall be considered revoked on and after the date set by the Secretary under subparagraph (A)(ii). The Secretary shall publish and maintain a list of any organization the status of which is so revoked.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H36B02DC8D9414810850E557712A3EBCA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application necessary for reinstatement; Retroactive reinstatement allowed if cause shown</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"> Section 6033(j) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>paragraph (1)</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>paragraph (1) or (4)</quote>. </text></subsection><subsection id="HE2137AE48F04457A860E5B0D2B44927C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to returns filed for taxable years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

