<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD07AA926898C4E52A3119548D1787FC9" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 118 IH: No Federal Funds for Political Prosecutions Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 118</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250103">January 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001302">Mr. Biggs of Arizona</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the use of forfeited funds made available to certain State or local law enforcement agencies pursuant to equitable sharing for certain purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF2AEDF9D5EC44902890E569E5372EF1D" style="OLC"><section id="H0E850637D49D4E139DE0C4BB5D6861D6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No Federal Funds for Political Prosecutions Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HB81FB081D1AF4C939716AFADE9BC1277"><enum>2.</enum><header>Limitation on use of forfeited funds made available pursuant to equitable sharing</header><subsection id="H7C77212E619742A49766496601930F83"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No funds or property received pursuant to section 511(e) of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/811">21 U.S.C. 811(e)</external-xref>), section 981 of title 18, United States Code, or section 524 of title 28, United States Code, by a State or local law enforcement agency with the authority to prosecute a criminal case may be used to investigate or prosecute the President or Vice President, a former President or Vice President, or a candidate for the office of President. </text></subsection><subsection id="HADB0DBFB8FCD429A937E344A83366F1F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Certification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State or local law enforcement agency referred to in subsection (a) shall certify to the Attorney General that the law enforcement agency will comply with subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="HAE3ED8E1ECC2428BB65EFC6B4FF28536"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Disqualification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a State or local law enforcement agency that the Attorney General determines has failed to comply with this section, the Attorney General may not transfer, under section 511(e) of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/811">21 U.S.C. 811(e)</external-xref>), section 981 of title 18, United States Code, or section 524 of title 28, United States Code, any property seized by the Attorney General and forfeited to the United States, or any of the proceeds from the sale of such property to such State or local law enforcement agency.</text></subsection><subsection id="HFB01034D704A420D8F523C2521DCBBC3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>candidate</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 301 of the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/30101">52 U.S.C. 30101</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

