<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="H189D85128AA54B45BAEA4F3DCF5D3B4A"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>88 HR 3950 IH: Truth in Gender Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3950</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250612">June 12, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and Workforce</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To defend women’s rights and protect freedom of conscience by using clear and accurate language and policies recognizing that women are biologically female and men are biologically male, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8127FE421C134D1BA36585AED5F36E60"><section id="HB6DE44002E9043EBAE770585B74DE0A5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Truth in Gender Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H7E2D6C0A2CA84886B21EB8EAE4693AB5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><subsection id="HB92ECDBF5E2843188A19BF765F034619"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of this Act:</text><paragraph id="H8888B803DD354A3198C773FDDABC06A3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Sex</header><text>The term <quote>sex</quote>—</text><subparagraph id="H53237D0B777D4A708F5D9F5FB2C4B7D9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means an individual’s immutable biological classification as either male or female; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD2D0C1DB5330475686388626B688A781"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is not a synonym for, and does not include, the concept of gender identity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAE81BCC7267D474DAC4A6BEAF77C54A1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Women, woman; girls, girl</header><text>The term <quote>women</quote> or <quote>woman</quote> and the term <quote>girls</quote> or <quote>girl</quote> mean an adult or juvenile human female, respectively.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1B8F0E0874EE460098C6924E32A75EA1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Men, man; boys, boy</header><text>The term <quote>men</quote> or <quote>man</quote> and the term <quote>boys</quote> or <quote>boy</quote> mean an adult or juvenile human male, respectively.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDAACC781C22F4F6F8476D1928C9FEE7B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Female</header><text>The term <quote>female</quote> means a person belonging, at conception, to the sex that produces the large reproductive cell.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9536F5E50FF7488EBA554AB014D135BB"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Male</header><text>The term <quote>male</quote> means a person belonging, at conception, to the sex that produces the small reproductive cell.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H80CA8B52C96E43D190E8C8379B2667FA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Gender ideology; gender identity</header><text>Congress finds that—</text><paragraph id="H8F55B0AB02AE4ADAB201A3BBF61FF84C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>gender ideology—</text><subparagraph id="HA739D4FF5C5244F4B205D30980B0ACB3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>replaces the biological category of sex with an ever-shifting concept of self-assessed gender identity—</text><clause id="H793163165D874A08A822F0D3A95D0903"><enum>(i)</enum><text>permitting the false claim that males can identify as and thus become women and vice versa; and</text></clause><clause id="HD8E46BDFAA824A5E8641DED6E03F832F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>requiring all institutions of society to regard this false claim as true;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD5CF7F6453B447608F6A85439600CCB6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes the idea that there is a vast spectrum of genders that are disconnected from one’s sex; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H55048B88B2624A1099DED66315C4B9B7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is internally inconsistent, in that it diminishes sex as an identifiable or useful category but nevertheless maintains that it is possible for a person to be born in the wrong-sexed body; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFAE26586EF1A46CCA95898E092A3C02B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>gender identity reflects a fully internal and subjective sense of self, disconnected from biological reality and sex and existing on an infinite continuum, that does not provide a meaningful basis for identification and cannot be recognized as a replacement for sex.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H9206DC954B3C41FF9CEC9A5563443414"><enum>3.</enum><header>Recognizing women are biologically distinct from men</header><subsection id="HDCB69A10755A47CF90579B8DD630B8BD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Issuance of HHS guidance</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall provide to the Federal agencies, and the public clear guidance expanding on the definitions set forth in section 2.</text></subsection><subsection id="H44E81EAD2A4E451191985FC6FA89BA53"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Enforcement of sex-Based rights</header><paragraph id="HB4F1E1FC91AA4C3AB2E2F30803C4ECE2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The head of a Federal agency and the employees of such agency shall enforce laws governing sex-based rights, protections, opportunities, and accommodations to protect men and women as biologically distinct sexes.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7C6543E8647B4EFC85E5D100F8B79B9C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of definitions in conducting agency functions</header><text>In carrying out paragraph (1), head of a Federal agency shall use the definitions set forth in section 2 when—</text><subparagraph id="HAA9D8D1AA0C444BEB2CEAA75BB0A4907"><enum>(A)</enum><text>interpreting or applying statutes, regulations, or guidance; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7C34287955DC4E0BA99420F1BF3EEE56"><enum>(B)</enum><text>conducting all other official agency business, documents, and communications.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE8B461B26C214C5EBE85C057435085B4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of terms in federal policies and documents</header><text>In administering and enforcing sex-based distinctions, the head of a Federal agency, and the employees of such agency acting in an official capacity on behalf of the agency, shall use the term <quote>sex</quote> and not the term <quote>gender</quote> in all applicable Federal policies and documents.</text></subsection><subsection id="H3136B066D638489BBF40463E96797FA8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Government-Issued identification documents; personnel records</header><paragraph id="H15AA909406384D5BA53A3B994FF877D9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Identification documents</header><text>The Secretary of State, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and the Director of the Office of Personnel Management shall each implement changes to require that Government-issued identification documents (including passports, visas, and Global Entry cards) accurately reflect the holder’s sex, as defined under section 2.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA269C8E399EB4EB3926A2238893CA3A1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Personnel records</header><text>The Director of the Office of Personnel Management shall ensure that applicable personnel records accurately report the sex of a Federal employee, as defined by section 2.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H89586C861E3841D8991EA236BCB700BA"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Federal government communications and forms</header><paragraph id="H63297D64AF9D472CABAD203481D1C8E1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Modification of internal and external messages</header><text>The head of a Federal agency shall—</text><subparagraph id="H1E19FC4253ED470CA143C17ACF758560"><enum>(A)</enum><text>remove all statements, policies, regulations, forms, communications, and other internal and external messages that promote or otherwise inculcate gender ideology; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H60A71E89704B48D680C1DCD799A0E088"><enum>(B)</enum><text>cease issuing such statements, policies, regulations, forms, communications, or other messages.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H26E432B7A92945B8AE9E0D39ABCD103E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Modification of agency forms</header><text>The head of a Federal agency—</text><subparagraph id="H30CC4D95A54D43C3BA4907B8A37566DE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall ensure that the forms used by the agency require an individual’s sex to be listed as male or female; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H62368D5D7FBB410B9122283EC2356CE0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may not request gender identity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEDA0233B7213448ABB558F199E7E3AB2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Prohibition on use of funds</header><text>The head of a Federal agency shall take all necessary steps, as permitted by law, to end the Federal funding of gender ideology.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7FA222FA195743B6B00413E45B932378"><enum>(f)</enum><header>DOJ actions</header><text>The Attorney General shall—</text><paragraph id="H3EF75CC1003D427DAFF7C1AB6721C18F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>promptly issue guidance to the heads of Federal agencies to correct the misapplication of the Supreme Court’s decision in Bostock v. Clayton County (590 U.S. 644; 2020) to sex-based distinctions in agency activities; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4BE795B3E15B4580A9A47F1F39189329"><enum>(2)</enum><text>issue guidance and assist the heads of Federal agencies in protecting sex-based distinctions, which are explicitly permitted under constitutional and statutory precedent.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1208F32F6CB140C69F037AE57D3565E2"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Prohibition on use of funds</header><paragraph id="HC951530B26B04226ACFEDFF0761F8073"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Federal funds may not be used to promote gender ideology.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H569D18EBB03C4B7B93E0E9012BA54BF7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Grants; grant preferences</header><text>The head of each Federal agency shall—</text><subparagraph id="H59FC4DC3F1AA401F8D6E9DEDD120063F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>assess grant conditions and grantee preferences; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF4E5FB5B06674A288548A7496A7C978D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensure that grant funds do not promote gender ideology.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HBDA88DCEA4504CB1991A47C8E45742E7"><enum>4.</enum><header>Privacy in intimate spaces</header><subsection id="HFE2C8690C7584BE88389209CB3632EEB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Detention in prisons</header><text>The Attorney General and Secretary of Homeland Security shall each ensure that males are not detained in women’s prisons or housed in women’s detention centers, including through—</text><paragraph id="H8679A45E32D8481F869B3076A6D2093D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>amendment, as necessary, of section 115.41 of title 28, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H78139A9933964E97902E62EED3A71BEF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>interpretation of guidance regarding the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/101/336">Public Law 101–336</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H256EE38C995A41F9950263839AC39A8B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rescission of HUD final rule; access to single-Sex rape shelters</header><text>The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development shall—</text><paragraph id="H536968D884494A1D93A13592CDBB3CE6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>prepare and submit for notice-and-comment rulemaking a policy to rescind the final rule entitled <quote>Equal Access in Accordance with an Individual’s Gender Identity in Community Planning and Development Programs</quote> (dated September 21, 2016; 81 Fed. Reg. 64763); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H56B7BBA6ADE74D859D1DBAF7DC634FFB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submit for public comment a policy protecting women seeking single-sex rape shelters.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H87498E762C3043C2B7D78740B5F4CBBE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Medical care in prisons</header><text>The Attorney General shall ensure that—</text><paragraph id="HE2ED3BE5D2B5485FBAB840D0B2C7B01F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Bureau of Prisons revises its policies concerning medical care to be consistent with this Act; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF3A5F0DDFA204C68A292FBAC29DBD4B7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>no Federal funds are expended for any medical procedure, treatment, or drug for the purpose of conforming an inmate’s appearance to that of the opposite sex.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE275A08B4ED742CF9A7F2BF3A175C9D9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Other intimate spaces</header><text>The head of a Federal agency shall take appropriate action to ensure that intimate spaces designated for women, girls, or females (or for men, boys, or males) are designated by sex and not identity.</text></subsection></section><section id="H3B78B036AB934F78B1D4EF01A77BFD29"><enum>5.</enum><header>Protecting rights</header><subsection id="H683CE7E6D0C1419DA0D61A0BEC4F8A5D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Freedom To express the binary nature of sex; right to single-Sex spaces in workplaces</header><text>The Attorney General shall issue guidance to ensure—</text><paragraph id="H79CBB82723D74654BF38208C221B9A1B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the freedom to express the binary nature of sex; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H98B8B6F327344D5F8856B9BE5BEC8A7A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the right to single-sex spaces in workplaces and federally funded entities covered by the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/88/352">Public Law 88–352</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCA0B2F5340CD4596AE749BC264E2D514"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prioritization of investigations and litigation</header><text>In accordance with the guidance to be issued under subsection (a), the Attorney General, the Secretary of Labor, the General Counsel and Chair of the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, and each other head of a Federal agency with enforcement responsibilities under the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/88/352">Public Law 88–352</external-xref>) shall prioritize investigations and litigation to enforce the rights and freedoms identified.</text></subsection></section><section id="HAFD40C278237455C98AC01D913B5371B"><enum>6.</enum><header>Agency implementation and reporting</header><subsection id="H510D46A0A36748898AFF866E4C44891C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reporting requirement</header><paragraph id="HB997B0C52B1A42B292AF99FBD4148BA2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the head of each Federal agency shall submit to the President, acting through the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, an update on implementation of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD56A509791414CE0824727B7F46F6B5E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The head of each Federal agency shall include in the update of the agency to be submitted under paragraph (1)—</text><subparagraph id="HC807D171C24E4BF68FD4ED0FD330BACB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>changes to the documents of the agency (including regulations, guidance, forms, and communications) made to comply with this Act; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3458A7A7BB6946B28FE1618A5B47868C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>agency-imposed requirements on federally funded entities, including contractors, to achieve the policy of this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H91B7BAA9F6FE4C5BAB474A86E47357AB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Relationship to other laws</header><text>The requirements of this Act supersede conflicting provisions in any other law.</text></subsection><subsection id="H7C8A23F5F11141BB8A11F31E546EE677"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rescission of certain guidance documents</header><paragraph id="HB181D26DA0754B5888E3414F0CB974B5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The head of a Federal agency shall—</text><subparagraph id="H78A43A3863394B33B86BC117C42DD14B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>promptly rescind all guidance documents of the agency that are inconsistent with the requirements of this Act or guidance issued by the Attorney General pursuant to this Act; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAA2E94900AE5493F898CAEBD1585BDCF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>as appropriate, rescind such parts of such documents that are inconsistent in such manner.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H886FAD5560DB4EA98AAABB90994A7757"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Included documents</header><text>The documents referred to in paragraph (1) include each document identified in section 7(c) of Executive Order 14168, as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H7DA8A81797C0461BA8C172233EED83B1"><enum>7.</enum><header>General provisions</header><subsection id="H90EF98AA24AB4DFAB1B00421346EFA87"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Rights and benefits</header><text>This Act is not intended to, and does not, create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or in equity by any party against the United States, its departments, agencies, or entities, its officers, employees, or agents, or any other person.</text></subsection><subsection id="H57D1CDBF82D343DF9088836B99087937"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Severability</header><text>If any provision of this Act, or the application of any provision of this Act to any person or circumstance, is held to be invalid, the remainder of this Act and the application of the provisions of this Act to any other persons or circumstances shall not be affected thereby.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

