<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2D6BB7AB926E4C60AA50B1E467B42F81" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 654 IH: Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives with respect to Marcus Garvey.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 654</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250815">August 15, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives with respect to Marcus Garvey.</official-title></form><preamble>
<whereas><text>Whereas Marcus Mosiah Garvey, Jamaica’s first national hero, was born in St. Ann’s Bay, Jamaica, on August 17, 1887, and died on June 10, 1940;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Marcus Garvey emigrated to the United States, where he founded the Universal Negro Improvement Association;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas Marcus Garvey was the father of the largest African-American movement for human rights and economic self-sufficiency of all time, attracting millions of followers in the United States, the Caribbean, Latin America, Africa, and Europe;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Marcus Garvey’s philosophy inspired some of the world’s great Black leaders;</text></whereas>
<whereas>
 <text>Whereas, leading a movement for economic independence among Black Americans, Marcus Garvey became the target of surveillance and harassment by United States Government law enforcement agencies;</text>
        </whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas Marcus Garvey was prosecuted and convicted of mail fraud, imprisoned, and later, deported to Jamaica;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the case against Marcus Garvey was politically motivated, the charges unsubstantiated, and his conviction unjust;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas millions of petitioners have appealed for his exoneration;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Marcus Garvey is recognized as a national hero in his native Jamaica, and as a towering figure in nations around the world; and</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas Marcus Garvey’s life and contributions to the United States should be recognized and appropriate steps taken to restore his name and reputation in this country: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HDE36F2EF5CEA400BAB2756AC03EEED6E"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HE9A1C909D6734671947D413D654381E0"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That it is the sense of the House of Representatives that—</text>
<paragraph id="H131D771FAB134FF3ACE36CC75C86E6C5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Marcus Garvey was innocent of the charges brought against him by the United States Government;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF8787F456A95413CBCC86E2576AEFF24"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Marcus Garvey was and should be recognized internationally as a leader and thinker in the struggle for human rights; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9D0541214E094DA7A13B1D8FEFB1C411"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the President should take appropriate measures within his power to exonerate Marcus Garvey and clear his good name.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

