<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE013283C734C4AD49828A8FD0E8448C3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3177 IH: To require the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency to ensure that cost estimates, acquisition of proper materials, and any other activity related to certain projects under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act are performed by professionals licensed in the relevant State, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3177</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250505">May 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000235">Mr. Ezell</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001112">Mr. Carbajal</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001260">Mr. Buchanan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency to ensure that cost estimates, acquisition of proper materials, and any other activity related to certain projects under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act are performed by professionals licensed in the relevant State, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H32555E47CFCD44479483F6D76C48D901" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H54CC828021C947F3974742C758B96451" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Cost estimates by appropriately licensed professionals</header> 
<subsection id="H140CCEC2010E495CB81A58E3DC100675"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall use appropriately licensed professionals to perform any covered activity with respect to a project eligible for assistance under sections 406 or 428 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5172">42 U.S.C. 5172</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5189f">42 U.S.C. 5189f</external-xref>).</text></subsection> <subsection id="HA4A4B28305924649BF70E4A70DBE1E40"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header> <paragraph id="H631A092130904866A034C20370F28961"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Consent of appropriately licensed professional</header><text>The Administrator may not disapprove, with respect to a project described under subsection (a), any plan, rebuilding proposal, material suggestion for rebuilding, or direct purchase of materials without the direct consent of an appropriately licensed professional.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H87C0769A3F6E45A5A7CCF4BD6C2B612C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Purchase approval</header><text>Any purchase suggested by an appropriately licensed professional for any project described under subsection (a) shall be approved by the Administrator.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC3A817FD4BD540ADBBAD3A58EEAA813D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Acceptance of plans, projects, and materials</header><text>Unless fraud is evident and traceable, any plans proposed, projects prepared, and materials requested or purchased by an appropriately licensed professional may not be rejected, rescinded, or stalled by the Administrator.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H34DB67A8C5884D2E897FE243C42EF53D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Contract process</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator may not reject or hinder the process of entering into a contract with an appropriately licensed professional if such process is suggested by a State or local government.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H92C9609C18084A378941D9A1EDC0C66F"><enum>(5)</enum><header>State hiring responsibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It shall be the responsibility of the State to hire an appropriately licensed professional to develop the scope of work related to performing a covered activity.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAA1380304D99464BAFC0520B1223A4FA"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Employee of FEMA</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any employee of the Agency that assists directly with the management of a rebuilding project eligible for assistance under section 406 or 428 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5172">42 U.S.C. 5172</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5189f">42 U.S.C. 5189f</external-xref>) shall be an appropriately licensed professional.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H97736B1E3CF84BB2A30DD9EA53748A12"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Administrator shall update regulations and policies, to the extent necessary, to implement the requirements of this Act.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H46ADC6D20F7642C0BB08C7F95D86B284"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="HA938829EC76249DF9EE6C1277C6A72EB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriately licensed professional</header><text>The term <term>appropriately licensed professional</term> means an individual—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H4C30B7159FA146228282A5F41BC6E987"><enum>(A)</enum><text>who is—</text> <clause id="H3BC8CC95B499443888319B8C636D5E05"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">employed by the Agency to perform a covered activity; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H593B59DE16D24D0FAD64ABABDD22533F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>contracted by the Agency or a State or local governmental entity; and</text> </clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA5AE9AC1F1AB4653A42450DA7CE9655F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>licensed—</text> 
<clause id="HCE449B7FA0B046619F74BF8D6F3D4E7D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the State in which a project described under this section shall be carried out; and</text></clause> <clause id="H06809365ED964FD484FF98153C2C8A1F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">as an engineer, architect, builder, tradesperson, or any other profession related to performing a covered activity relating to such project.</text></clause></subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7125ABE69E7C4FD78755676ABEB9F1AF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered activity</header><text>The term <term>covered activity</term> includes—</text> <subparagraph id="H22F5D10C39ED4EBD8F304DA013E5A735"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">preparing a cost estimate for a project eligible for assistance under section 406 or 428 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5172">42 U.S.C. 5172</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5189f">42 U.S.C. 5189f</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6BE6C070F50B49AE959933DE9C879EDD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>purchasing the proper materials, equipment, vehicles, and any other items necessary to carry out a project described under subparagraph (A).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

