<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD3E27372BD3C4D25A27C4B5CF358A91D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>105 HR 806 IH: District of Columbia Code Returning Citizens Coordination Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 806</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250128">January 28, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Director of the Bureau of Prisons to provide information on certain persons under the jurisdiction of the Bureau of Prisons to the Mayor of the District of Columbia, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H94B4BE345AE74A9CBD0AF0760F2FA7EA" style="OLC"><section id="HBB73944A419342DBA4F487EE75B6607B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>District of Columbia Code Returning Citizens Coordination Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H8884511711A84584A12BB34FD3D0E6A0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Provision of information to the District of Columbia related to certain persons under the jurisdiction of the Bureau of Prisons</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Director of the Bureau of Prisons shall provide to the Mayor of the District of Columbia for each person under the jurisdiction of the Bureau of Prisons pursuant to the National Capital Revitalization and Self-Government Improvement Act of 1997 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/105/33">Public Law 105–33</external-xref>), the following:</text><paragraph id="HF5D943CA159C4895AD0B317B7F956882"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Every 90 days, the following information:</text><subparagraph id="H35EAB02C21804C17B17E7B810536DEAE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The name, age, and Federal Register Number of the person. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB70858D326B64BD996A0ECD1BA2A2686"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The facility where the person is housed.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFEA878259CDB486FABE75F29CE534F78"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The scheduled release date.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDF0DE85D494B487EAEBDA935A02F5744"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Upon the request of the Mayor, the information that the Director provides for such person to the Director of the Court Services and Offender Supervision Agency for the District of Columbia.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H874250A38AD845E093F3E908C7F45BD4"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibition on District of Columbia disclosure</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Mayor of the District of Columbia may not disclose the information provided pursuant to this Act outside of the District of Columbia government, except that the Mayor—</text><paragraph id="H7229EDC89A9D412B907296E64EE51AED"><enum>(1)</enum><text>may not provide such information to any District of Columbia law enforcement agency; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H13F121DA0D9540F4AB60FE39C5B3184A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may provide the information provided under paragraph (1) of section 2 to counsel for the persons, and to organizations that provide legal representation to persons in criminal or post-conviction matters, or in matters related to reentry.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

