<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF6B93F92764E47479D268EFFBE404727" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 534 IH: To commemorate the enactment of title IX and to celebrate the contributions women and girls make in education and athletics.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 534</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250623">June 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001136">Mrs. McClain</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To commemorate the enactment of title IX and to celebrate the contributions women and girls make in education and athletics.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas title IX, a part of the Education Amendments of 1972, was signed into law on June 23, 1972, to end discrimination against women and girls in education and athletics;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas title IX has served as the bedrock of equal opportunity in education and athletics, ensuring millions of women and girls have access to high-quality educational opportunities and competitive athletic programs;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas girls’ high school sports participation rate is greater than 11 times what it was when title IX passed, an increase of more than 1,000 percent;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, when title IX was enacted, only 1 in 27 girls participated in school sports, today, it is 2 in 5;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas over 1,000,000,000 women have played college sports since title IX’s enactment; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the ripple effect of title IX has extended far beyond participation numbers, but has also led to increased funding for women’s athletics, increased representation of women in coaching and leadership positions, and paved the way for countless women and girls to excel in fields from science and technology, to business, politics, and the arts: Now, therefore, be it enacted</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H06E69C70B5EB4D248DA76932C9350782"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H7E00D996F01C4C86918418C2F72C20E1"><enum/><text>That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="H34CF64262B8D47A1ADE3AC629A39BE6A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">commemorates the anniversary of the day title IX was signed into law;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF780CE4EF08A48E882CF121671F43691"><enum>(2)</enum><text>celebrates the women and girls who committed their lives toward advancing equal opportunity in school and athletics;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1E0DC61073134AA58A5A9DE995E90841"><enum>(3)</enum><text>celebrates the contributions of female athletes and the coaches and parents of female athletes; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8A099523E66648C6B21EF00F871AAACF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>supports protecting the rights of female athletes to compete on a fair and equal playing field.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

