<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H66F24B21DC76412BB28F7D585B113104" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 527 IH: Strengthening Wildfire Resiliency Through Satellites Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 527</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250116">January 16, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000620">Ms. Pettersen</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="O000019">Mr. Obernolte</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the United States Geological Survey, to establish a grant program for monitoring wildfires by satellite.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H15049F15A1BA4503B2F3C74858314A9F" style="OLC"><section id="H6E7A323A88F84A4BA528511B86414427" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Strengthening Wildfire Resiliency Through Satellites Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HFC3B10D7142246BE94BBE96716FCE7E4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Monitoring wildfires by satellite</header><subsection id="H0C8975236AF9495788BAA49B7BD43019"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grant program To monitor wildfires by satellite</header><paragraph id="HE06C784DB52446FBBC58D20C3E447749"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary shall establish a competitive grant program under which the Secretary shall make at least three grants to eligible entities to monitor wildfires by satellite (in this section referred to as the <quote>Program</quote>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H144DB0C6FBFC44118A75E4ABBE1F75B8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible projects</header><text>Each eligible entity awarded a grant under the Program shall only use such grant to—</text><subparagraph id="H36FE456E2BBA48B89C08526A3D2BA2D7" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>purchase and integrate, through a public-private partnership, high-resolution multi- and hyper-spectral full spectrum imaging capability from visible, near-infrared, shortwave infrared, thermal infrared, and radar data from the latest-generation of wildfire monitoring satellites; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9B0A989E793A4F17B8C31EE822DCD984"><enum>(B)</enum><text>use the data acquired under subparagraph (A), as well as any analyses relating to such data, to detect, assess, respond to, and manage wildfires, with an emphasis on—</text><clause id="H897D5DA0EC244745BC75C02F075C7F60"><enum>(i)</enum><text>monitoring active fire behavior, burned area, intensity, and severity;</text></clause><clause id="H629CC070784E4E4085C275A1827C9E7F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>ensuring the safety and effectiveness of prescribed fire treatments; and</text></clause><clause id="H2DCE303AC5AA44D8BA0FEB6F326C2D59"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>guiding post-fire risk assessment and disaster recovery.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HADAB9DA8EB484B0589F2ABC03244F3FA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Application</header><text>To be eligible for a grant under the Program, an eligible entity shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H180B4A798479458AAB556EAA88F78377"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Grant amount</header><text>Each grant awarded under the Program shall be in an amount the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAC05A31883CB4E819A58793F21840E4C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than the last day of the second fiscal year beginning after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report that includes—</text><subparagraph id="H6D50DF06CED643F48929E9FBE0E89321"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of applications received for a grant under the Program;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD6A8A27ADADD4D2DB685155A59E0C3CC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>details of each eligible entity that was awarded a grant under the Program;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0023D8763B784C8080EA771A23DE76BE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the impact of the Program on wildfire prevention;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3C58438B2B144113BF4F25EBCC85255D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any recommendation that the Secretary determines appropriate to establish the Program as a long-term grant program; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H495EEE2E901947ACA15C57B72BEF75B3"><enum>(E)</enum><text>any other information on the effectiveness of the Program that the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7E6793660C9746578866304298C10A50" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary $20,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2028 to carry out the Program.</text></subsection><subsection id="H62D15237E14A4018B49668763470C576"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text><paragraph id="H1783A67AB84742EF94AA9A329A2B6A96"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <quote>eligible entity</quote> means a State forester, emergency manager, or equivalent State official; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H52BDB8EACC4B420D9361FFAB345AD075"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the United States Geological Survey.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

