<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-LIP25893-39R-GD-JXN">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2817 IS: Fed Integrity and Independence Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
<congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>S. 2817</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
<action>
<action-date date="20250916">September 16, 2025</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S432">Mr. Gallego</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S426">Mr. Kim</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S366">Ms. Warren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S428">Ms. Alsobrooks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S385">Ms. Cortez Masto</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S430">Ms. Blunt Rochester</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S415">Mr. Warnock</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title>To amend the Federal Reserve Act to prohibit dual appointments of employees of the Federal Reserve System, and for other purposes. </official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="HEF438ABEFDF7496CB0602589ECD4C5D6">
<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Fed Integrity and Independence Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5e96606b1b36493e8fccf9c826bbbc3a"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header> <subsection id="id9229455b3d0c44e69b56e5dbbb78d199"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that—</text>
<paragraph id="idab6ba31f44ab432db0c91e7df5b4450f"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Federal Reserve System plays a critical role in maintaining the stability of the economy of the United States by conducting monetary policy, supervising and regulating financial institutions, and supporting the payments system;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id65b28253e6664ef29736ddd9d54c57f1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>historically, the insulation of the Federal Reserve System from political interference has been essential in preventing an electoral consideration or partisan agenda from driving any monetary policy decision;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="idd8ba4b3dc1524db2baa98a3070d6b041"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the credibility and effectiveness of the Federal Reserve System depend on the ability of the Federal Reserve System to operate independently of any short-term political pressure, particularly from an elected official or individual in a position of public trust;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id22d653c345c6445598b32887da031580"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the presence of a current government official, Member of Congress, or other politically affiliated individual in a role within the Federal Reserve System raises legitimate concerns about conflict of interest and undue influence; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="id5540abb6b717435296ac314198dca8c8"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the purpose of this Act, and the amendments made by this Act, is to strengthen the institutional integrity and independence of the Federal Reserve System by more categorically prohibiting dual appointments, preventing conflicts of interest, and ensuring a clear separation between a political actor and a monetary policy decision.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4d3d55fc8d87465e9f52144e5e555953"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibition of Dual Appointment</header> <subsection id="id2081916729ba47a39579ea733a0334d3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Board of Governors</header><text>The fourth sentence of the first undesignated paragraph of section 10 of the Federal Reserve Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/241">12 U.S.C. 241</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>business of the Board and shall each receive</quote> and inserting <quote>business of the Board, may not simultaneously hold any other office, position, or employment for which the member is appointed by the President, including under a leave of absence from such other office, position, or employment, and shall each receive</quote>. </text></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idac27e5d108d34772989d781534c63e5f"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Federal Reserve Bank Presidents, Vice Presidents, Officers, and Employees</header><text>The fifth subparagraph of the fourth undesignated paragraph of section 4 of the Federal Reserve Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/341">12 U.S.C. 341</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following: <quote>A president, vice president, officer, or employee of the bank may not simultaneously hold any other office, position, or employment for which the president, vice president, officer, or employee is appointed by the President, including under a leave of absence from such other office, position, or employment.</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaa18fc700e174aa0b5165c76b46b9725"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Federal Reserve Bank Board of Directors</header><text>The ninth undesignated paragraph of section 4 of the Federal Reserve Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/302">12 U.S.C. 302</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following: <quote>A member of such board of directors may not simultaneously hold any other office, position, or employment for which the member is appointed by the President, including under a leave of absence from such other office, position, or employment.</quote>.</text></subsection></section>
</legis-body>
</bill> 


