<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-SIL25860-2KL-GD-0T7"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2322 IS: Appraisal Modernization Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code>II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2322</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250717">July 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S415">Mr. Warnock</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S428">Ms. Alsobrooks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S430">Ms. Blunt
                    Rochester</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S426">Mr. Kim</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S366">Ms.
                    Warren</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and
                referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing,
                    and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Federal Housing Enterprises Safety and Soundness Act of 1992 to
            require that financial institutions, appraisal management companies, appraisers, and
            other valuation professionals are serving the housing market in a manner that is
            efficient and consistent for all mortgage loan applicants, borrowers, and communities,
 and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Appraisal Modernization Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id73a1cd948cc544c6a10dddfc50423454"><enum>2.</enum><header>Public appraisal database</header><subsection id="idb88e6ca5ec9241b2b2a41fb5f8f7bceb"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Federal Housing Enterprises Safety and Soundness Act of 1992 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/4501">12 U.S.C. 4501 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 1313B (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/4513b">12 U.S.C. 4513b</external-xref>) the following:</text><quoted-block id="idb6e513727c2e48a2bf0fe729a9ad95d8" display-inline="no-display-inline" style="OLC"><section id="ide9936ea0f9544c29aeda3382d670499c"><enum>1313C.</enum><header>Public appraisal database</header><subsection id="id10c66b748287498eaf97a1f1f04d9437"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of this section is to provide the public, the Federal Government, and State governments with residential real estate appraisal data to help determine whether financial institutions, appraisal management companies, appraisers, and other valuation professionals are serving the housing market in a manner that is efficient and consistent for all mortgage loan applicants, borrowers, and communities.</text></subsection><subsection id="id6bb6c8bcc8ec47ba9ffc6643792909ce"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="id0a691d91e87b468395228eba72701061"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Application</header><text>The term <term>application</term> means the submission of a consumer’s financial information for the purposes of obtaining an extension of credit.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc99d6927516549f288069ae56973a787"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Dwelling</header><text>The term <term>dwelling</term>—</text><subparagraph id="id305b1ecda9e14230881bac7cd00aa157"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means a 1-to-4 unit residential structure, whether or not attached to real property; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id020d534504de44fd9184f1795753321d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes a detached home, an individual condominium or cooperative unit, and a manufactured home or other factory-built home.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9a6213c6704b4630bd82c76f1bec009f"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Financial institution</header><text>The term <term>financial institution</term> means any partnership, company, corporation, association (incorporated or unincorporated), trust, estate, cooperative organization, or other entity that engages in financial activity.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide3b7c181bbfd45858564b015cb0bde02"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Mortgage loan</header><text>The term <term>mortgage loan</term> means any extension of credit that is secured by a lien on a dwelling.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id405bbd124164426fbaf50b6002661dfd"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Agency Appraisal Data Sharing</header><paragraph id="id74d3f06b3ac54c6a98d2cf2d939f0902"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Legacy appraisal data</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this section, the Federal National Mortgage Association, the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation, the Federal Housing Administration, the Department of Agriculture, and the Department of Veterans Affairs shall provide to the Agency—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfa3d7481cd11485d8deb7487e1ee4133"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the appraisal data collected in connection with mortgage loan applications and mortgage loans that financial institutions submitted to the Federal National Mortgage Association, the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation, the Federal Housing Administration, the Department of Agriculture, and the Department of Veterans Affairs, as applicable, during the period beginning on January 1, 2017, and ending on the date of enactment of this section; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id52b63b210ee8442b855468339b26a656"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the corresponding census tract of the subject property, agency loan identifier, the Universal Loan Identifier required by the Home Mortgage Disclosure Act of 1975 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/2801">12 U.S.C. 2801 et seq.</external-xref>), the mortgage loan purpose, whether the property is owner occupied, the acquiring agency, and the race and ethnicity of the borrower as required by that Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id8e59be8e3d844c87ac237348211ac53f"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Modernized appraisal data</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section, and on a quarterly basis thereafter, the Federal National Mortgage Association, the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation, the Federal Housing Administration, the Department of Agriculture, and the Department of Veterans Affairs shall provide to the Agency—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idebcd54d0fb57422eb096622f8373ef6a"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the appraisal data collected in connection with mortgage loan applications and mortgage loans that financial institutions submitted in the previous quarter to the Federal National Mortgage Association, the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation, the Federal Housing Administration, the Department of Agriculture, and the Department of Veterans Affairs, as applicable; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd3c2b657ef014ad981545fa5d2515889"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the corresponding census tract of the subject property, agency loan identifier, the Universal Loan Identifier required by the Home Mortgage Disclosure Act of 1975 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/2801">12 U.S.C. 2801 et seq.</external-xref>), the mortgage loan purpose, whether the property is owner occupied, the acquiring agency, and the race and ethnicity of the borrower as required by that Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0300b7b1ff8041d7893b95580db3799c"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Public searchable database</header><paragraph id="idc0211406e6284a6499da8d6abd23319f"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Legacy appraisal database</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this section, the Director, in consultation with the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, the Secretary of Agriculture, and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, shall make publicly available online a searchable and downloadable appraisal-level public use file of the data shared pursuant to subsection (c)(1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id74421829eef64ed79f6273a1994088ff"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Modernized appraisal database</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this section, and on a quarterly basis thereafter, the Director, in consultation with the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, the Secretary of Agriculture, and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, shall make publicly available online a searchable and downloadable appraisal-level public use file of the data shared pursuant to subsection (c)(2).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id38a412b5f7e04a57b80dbc7d6b908949"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Form and manner of valuation data</header><paragraph id="idf68c589edcdd4018bc8ab346a941f1ad"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any appraisal data required to be disclosed under subsection (d) shall be itemized at the appraisal level to clearly and conspicuously disclose—</text><subparagraph id="id2f64c417074a4f9a95550bf3e9a00ae9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the assignment data, including the assignment reason, property valuation method, client or lender name, appraisal management company name, appraiser company name, appraiser credential level, appraiser identification number, and State, exterior scope of inspection, interior scope of inspection, and the inspection date;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2947b5b6a5174757966ddece8681d315"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the subject property data, including the physical address, zip code, county, State, neighborhood name, attachment type, number of units excluding accessory dwelling units, number of accessory dwelling units, special tax assessments, whether the subject property is a planned unit development, condominium, cooperative, property on Native American lands, subject site owned in common, homeowner responsible for all exterior maintenance of dwelling, or new construction, the property rights appraised, whether all rights are included in the appraisal, and the legal description;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5add1a0fc3b74de5a48d71b2786b27d6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the market data, including the market area boundary, search criteria description, number of active listings and their median days on market, lowest list price, median list price, and highest list price, the number of pending sales, the number of sales in the past 24 months and their lowest sale price, median sale price, and highest sale price, whether there is distressed market competition, the price trend source, the demand and supply trend, the marketing time, and the market commentary;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2c6bef4fe8fd4937b2e7e9b6b2ff98e4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the project information, including the project information data source, the monthly amount of mandatory fees, the common amenities and services included, the utilities included, whether the developer or sponsor is in control, any known legal actions, unit special assessments, and unit tax abatements or exemptions;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc5d6315dc24c4962a51d21e43615b9ad"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the subject listing information, including the subject listing identification number, the start date, end date, days on market, starting list price, and current or final list price;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb15be0fe0ec74554959d8b7385460aa3"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the sales contract data, including whether there is a sales contract, whether the contract was analyzed, and whether the transaction appears to be an arms length transaction, the contract price, the contract data, transfer terms, any personal property conveyed, any known sales concessions, total sales concessions and whether such concessions are typical for the market, and sales contract analysis;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id41b17edbca6b4b5e8e297f1d8f53c741"><enum>(G)</enum><text>for the subject property and each comparable property relied on for the opinion of value, as applicable—</text><clause id="id82c7a0da391d453f959207a7608605d7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the general data, including the property address, data source, proximity to the subject, list price, listing status, contract price or sale price, sales concessions, contract date, sale data, days on market, whether attached or detached, and property rights appraised;</text></clause><clause id="id5c0347d13cc74f0bb31ac4ebbfac73b8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the site data, including the site size, neighborhood name, topography, site influence or location, site view, and site range;</text></clause><clause id="ida2feb5c205f54e218a05d86e6ed20d24"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the dwelling data, including the year built, dwelling style, heating, and cooling;</text></clause><clause id="id6beb985f3db84714a861653f8546a509"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the energy efficient and green features, including the efficiency rating;</text></clause><clause id="idf5a3e6724a934eea861607b0cd3cc897"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the unit data, including the number of bedrooms, number of full baths, number of half baths, finished area above grade, finished area below grade, unfinished area below grade, and below grade exterior access;</text></clause><clause id="idc6d28fc95f2a43b3a2f78e1613f4772e"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the exterior quality and condition ratings data, including the quality rating, exterior walls and trim, roof, and condition rating;</text></clause><clause id="id09f967f5c43f4004b3bca10f758d1a15"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>the interior quality and condition ratings data, including the quality rating, condition rating, kitchen, and overall flooring;</text></clause><clause id="id4ae2ef3ab7934878b0de70901548b83c"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>the overall quality and condition ratings data, including the quality rating and the condition rating;</text></clause><clause id="id4be8b63b8a064ffa8dbe2e5731e97c5c"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>the property amenities data, including the outdoor living, water features, and miscellaneous;</text></clause><clause id="idf92fee31ac9745f79dba9a3ed7da33da"><enum>(x)</enum><text>the vehicle storage data, including type, spaces, and detail; and</text></clause><clause id="idd926ad125d3742da96dd4c1f6c7acf16"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>for each comparable relied on for the opinion of value, any adjustments related to each of the above data fields;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd8bef3e388b54194a0dd0f29df1af434"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the summary data for the comparable properties relied on for the opinion of value, including the list price, sale price, net adjustment total, price per finished area above grade, adjusted price, and comparable weight;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4f1434ee9e124edca28925e3beca5c9d"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the reconciliation data, including the approaches to value, the contract price, opinion of market value, market value condition, reasonable exposure time, effective date of appraisal, and final value condition statement;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id44e6a2ea623e4967964b3eec32cd98d7"><enum>(J)</enum><text>the corresponding census tract of the subject property, agency loan identifier, the Universal Loan Identifier required by the Home Mortgage Disclosure Act of 1975 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/2801">12 U.S.C. 2801 et seq.</external-xref>), the mortgage loan purpose, whether the property is owner occupied, the acquiring agency, and the race and ethnicity of the borrower as required by that Act, based on the data provided by the Federal National Mortgage Association, the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation, the Federal Housing Administration, the Department of Agriculture, and the Department of Veterans Affairs, as applicable, to the Agency and added to the public appraisal database by the Agency; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9e075651053e489da9e2688ec04c6d69"><enum>(K)</enum><text>such other information as the Agency may require by regulation, after notice and comment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id87ac3fc5f116451ba6987411841d891f"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Discretion to modify publicly available data</header><text>The Agency may modify data collected under this section, to be made publicly available, if the Agency determines by regulation, after notice and comment, that the release of the unmodified data creates risks to a mortgage loan applicant or mortgage loan borrower privacy interests that are not justified by the benefits of such release to the public in light of the statutory purposes.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id175b697ae8ca4724af339f3341e54749"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Access to the unmodified database</header><text>For enforcement and other purposes, the Agency shall, upon request, provide access to all information collected for the database pursuant to this section, in unredacted form, to any Executive agency, as defined in section 105 of title 5, United States Code, the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, the National Credit Union Administration, the Appraisal Subcommittee of the Federal Financial Institutions Examination Council, the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection, and any State attorney general, State appraiser regulator, or other State agency with responsibility for laws related to appraisals.</text></subsection><subsection id="id6ac03c79311a43808c72faa3143326c4"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to encourage unsafe or unsound lending, appraisal, or valuation practices.</text></subsection><subsection id="idd82fafbaa31744b9b925ac4ab3431b27" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Rules and interpretive guidelines</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section, the Agency shall issue a final rule after notice and comment and issue such guidance as may be necessary to carry out and enforce this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="id613f4aa58b534594aea466c1de476a04"><enum>3.</enum><header>Reconsideration of value</header><subsection id="id0c6f09fbc42f4bfcae87b9ab3bb7e3e1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 129E of the Truth In Lending Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1639e">15 U.S.C. 1639e</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="id4a07e5578da749c5991372b4afe77a14"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (j) and (k) as subsections (k) and (l), respectively; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id920cd4304967416d96ce7384501b82bc"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (i) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id99c5a14bc8e34ea6b59fe024ef90621b"><subsection id="id42d7030f01484f22aeec7143c484a7ce"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Consumer right to reconsideration of value or subsequent appraisal</header><paragraph id="idc25836fd7f4f44f3b2c8ff4c31c0f334"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><subparagraph id="id013b905c884e4e76874c7a72560889d6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Unacceptable appraisal practice</header><text>The term <term>unacceptable appraisal practice</term> means an appraisal report that—</text><clause id="id7c4645e4487e426095f709de7ba9173b"><enum>(i)</enum><text>uses unsupported or subjective terms to assess or rate the property without providing a foundation for analysis and contextual information;</text></clause><clause id="id579cd67b02a841239157ba50fe7fdb6d"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>uses inaccurate or incomplete data about the subject property, the neighborhood, the market area, or any comparable property;</text></clause><clause id="id565d1b448b384324aee8a6e5a52b901a"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>includes references, statements or comparisons about crime rates or crime statistics, whether objective or subjective;</text></clause><clause id="id6b51f2d1f2ae421da34e061d8a1d7285"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>relies in the appraisal analysis on comparable properties that were not personally inspected by the appraiser when required by the appraisal’s scope of work;</text></clause><clause id="idee0fe535b7cd43ffaea1ab692510cac0"><enum>(v)</enum><text>relies in the appraisal analysis on inappropriate comparable properties;</text></clause><clause id="id79dad61dbc8f4e32b1ed57798cc71e84"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>fails to use comparable properties that are more similar, or nearer, to the subject property without adequate explanation;</text></clause><clause id="id095676404cf34e7a8fc2fb1f3a3e1616"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>uses comparable property data provided by any interested party to the transaction without verification by a disinterested party;</text></clause><clause id="idc005fade00b1425f9d0fa20a5b3bc1df"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>uses inappropriate adjustments for differences between the subject property and the comparable properties that do not reflect the market’s reaction to such differences; or</text></clause><clause id="idbacc8e3e38b14d46a662e8be53042333"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>fails to make proper adjustments, including time adjustments for differences between the subject property and the comparable properties when necessary.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc44d4b0ec66b4cd2b954a69e154aec57"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Unsupported</header><text>The term <term>unsupported</term> means, with respect to an appraisal report or an appraiser’s opinion of value, that the appraisal report or the opinion of value is not supported by relevant evidence and logic.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idfa0d3a48c0e14450877c7681763b7502"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Review</header><text>In connection with a consumer credit transaction secured by a consumer’s principal dwelling, a creditor shall have a review and resolution procedure for a consumer-initiated reconsideration of value or subsequent appraisal that complies with the following requirements:</text><subparagraph id="id86ef0859e31540638abed9df0600278e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The creditor shall complete its own appraisal review before delivering the appraisal to the consumer.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id66ea4ac7e9b14756bc261e823feb20d7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The creditor shall have policies and procedures that provide the consumer with a process to submit one request for a reconsideration of value and subsequent appraisal prior to the loan closing or within 60 calendar days of denial of a credit application if the consumer believes the appraisal report may be unsupported, may be deficient due to an unacceptable appraisal practice, or may reflect discrimination.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3c8a1b604ead451892771da5c1fa1bd6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>At the time of application and upon delivery of the appraisal report to the consumer, the creditor shall provide a written disclosure to the consumer describing the process for requesting a reconsideration of value or subsequent appraisal, which written disclosure shall include a standardized format for the consumer to submit the request for a reconsideration of value, including—</text><clause id="idfba253735e364f33bbb9cdd8085e716a"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the name of the borrower;</text></clause><clause id="id79d5aa66f5e5464991e2ff7ab6e4be1a"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the property address;</text></clause><clause id="id7e8b8725910b4950bcd867489b58e4a3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the effective date of the appraisal;</text></clause><clause id="idf1f3080604db4983b2bcb4bf72af7d07"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the appraiser’s name;</text></clause><clause id="id50a5824e3f2a4439acf002ff92bb320e"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the date of the request;</text></clause><clause id="id50b9fc18a97041c59c8954287d235413"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>a description of why the consumer believes the appraisal report may be unsupported, may be deficient due to an unacceptable appraisal practice, or may reflect discrimination;</text></clause><clause id="id353aa38721c04d3a8528c29bff5a1018"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>any additional information, data, including not more than 5 alternative comparable properties and the related data sources that the consumer would like the appraiser to consider; and</text></clause><clause id="idb30ab4d8949f4c70b8b90c545d32ceec"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>an explanation of why the new information, data, or comparable properties support the reconsideration of value.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id258c4b0b96e7459c898e4c899198bcbe"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The creditor shall obtain the necessary information from the consumer if the consumer’s request for reconsideration of value or subsequent appraisal is unclear or requires more information.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide5f272098ea74421a6dff8468846ee9b"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The creditor shall have a standardized format to communicate the reconsideration of value to the appraiser, which format shall include—</text><clause id="id1432f726914b4a78a997689381fe69d4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the name of the borrower;</text></clause><clause id="id2db175817dac47a8b612eaa966e3a6b5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the property address;</text></clause><clause id="idac23048bb20f423d8ded9e08fefbb158"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the effective date of the appraisal;</text></clause><clause id="id4205314eefcd4c27b6b7af16876f54bc"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the appraiser’s name;</text></clause><clause id="ida7f4e6578f0c4ffebfe04a46f9630157"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the date of the request;</text></clause><clause id="id5e357f1036c548bab469fbf5cf1f4892"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>a description of any area of the appraisal report that may be unsupported, may be deficient due to an unacceptable appraisal practice, or may reflect discrimination;</text></clause><clause id="id4348592f97e34baeaa59d9eab05b6681"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>any additional information, data, including not more than 5 alternative comparable properties and the related data sources that the consumer would like the appraiser to consider;</text></clause><clause id="idecd552d24bae4659afcaf28267e05ac0"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>an explanation of why the new information, data, or comparable properties support the reconsideration of value;</text></clause><clause id="idea58ea8c770440e7accaa35dc4ee89a4"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>a definition of turn-time expectations for the appraiser to communicate the reconsideration of value results back to the creditor;</text></clause><clause id="id1a079276f0fd4adbb12eeb15dfc22da8"><enum>(x)</enum><text>instructions for delivering the reconsideration of value response as part of a revised appraisal report that includes commentary on conclusions regardless of the outcome; and</text></clause><clause id="id71ffb4349d5a426ca5f6dfaa03159827"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>a reference for appraisers on how to correct minor appraisal issues or non-material errors not related to the reconsideration of value process.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id92618d18b22b49a6be6cc282a0a5d4ef"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Subsequent appraisal and referral</header><subparagraph id="id03abc3c6a96140ef93896c74890c81bd"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the creditor identifies material deficiencies in the appraisal report that are not corrected or addressed by the appraiser upon request of the creditor, including through a consumer-initiated reconsideration of value, or if there is evidence of unsupported or unacceptable appraisal practices, the creditor shall—</text><clause id="id5240bc9d20d045f994afe39577a1d749"><enum>(i)</enum><text>at the request of the consumer, order a subsequent appraisal at the creditor's own expense; and</text></clause><clause id="idf762b85cc9394fe181cc9cd25b2a1c49"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>forward the appraisal report and the creditor’s summary of findings to the appropriate appraisal licensing agency or regulatory board.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id93474a444d7e41e48e294d1417e30cb0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Discrimination</header><text>If the creditor has reason to believe that an appraisal report reflects discrimination, the creditor shall—</text><clause id="id2bfaeec3f0244dc690c4eea25779ba68"><enum>(i)</enum><text>order a subsequent appraisal, at the creditor's own expense;</text></clause><clause id="idbfed778eb3854e259497520ab4ba3e06"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>forward the appraisal report and the creditor’s summary of findings to the appropriate local, State, or Federal enforcement agency; and</text></clause><clause id="id7006b255a1524786a81d6ecd644cc1c9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>upon a final determination of discrimination by the appropriate local, State, or Federal enforcement agency, receive a reimbursement from the appraiser covering the cost of the subsequent appraisal ordered by the creditor.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id49d9d239a47841a6bcb9c65d97aff289"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Definition</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idee5d2f946a0c45acb2b77ff31e6785c3"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in clause (ii), in this paragraph, the term <term>reason to believe</term> means that the creditor has reviewed the applicable law and available evidence and determined that a potential violation of Federal or state antidiscrimination law exists. The available evidence may include the appraisal report, loan files, written communications, credible observations by persons with direct knowledge, statistical analysis, and the appraiser’s response to the request for a reconsideration of value. </text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id91141d1ceedd477d8928b31eb9e5cee9"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>reason to believe</term> does not mean that there is a final legal determination of discrimination.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id2676ad3bf6534fe6becdb48003c91e3c"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Document retention</header><text>The creditor shall retain all documentation and written communications related to the request for reconsideration of value or subsequent appraisal in the loan file during the seven-year period beginning on the date on which the consumer submitted the credit application.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id590cb474f7ef489f8d1b3b089ad63f0d"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>This subsection is consistent with the exceptions to the appraiser independence requirements found in Section 129E(c) of the Truth in Lending Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1639e">15 U.S.C. 1639e(c)</external-xref>). Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to require a creditor to submit a reconsideration of value to the original appraiser before ordering a subsequent appraisal from a subsequent appraiser.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idb4733b115f5c4777adc6382712c44214"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rules and interpretative guidelines</header><text>Section 129E(g) of the Truth in Lending Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1639e">15 U.S.C. 1639e(g)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="idfed56a53665547aabad4796d272ad2ab"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>paragraph (2), the Board</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraphs (2) and (3), the Bureau</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida1ce2b6e38964ce48b9d692d91eeef6e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6c829866dc68410d9dfaac0b4480c442"><paragraph id="idf504dbd48f5a4f9f96a7f1247ee46202"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Final rule</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this paragraph, the Federal Housing Finance Agency shall issue a final rule after notice and comment and issue such guidance as may be necessary to carry out and enforce subsection (j).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


