<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-TAM25A15-SVY-PH-SM9"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2954 IS: Health Care Workforce Expansion Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2954</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250930">September 30, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S313">Mr. Sanders</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To establish grant programs for health professional schools, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Health Care Workforce Expansion Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idc1e064aa7a7d4fbdbcba94c6f81ab042"><enum>2.</enum><header>Grant programs for health professional schools</header><subsection id="id329a92001f8a4ffd809f86a8843f5d41"><enum>(a)</enum><header>MED, DENTAL, and NURSE Grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Part A of title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070">20 U.S.C. 1070</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="id5b4e99294acf4f25a7536c73bffa3007" display-inline="no-display-inline" style="OLC"><subpart id="id84414712d52e41d7aecc919629e41117" style="OLC"><enum>11</enum><header>MED Grants</header><section id="ID2B873AC4B0604639AA876C491C9FCC02"><enum>420S.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For the purposes of this subpart:</text><paragraph id="ID737E7D17EC3B4E6E9AF75E72EE3462C1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible institution</header><text>The term <term>eligible institution</term> means an institution of higher education, as defined in section 101, that is a school of medicine or school of osteopathic medicine as defined in section 799B of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/295p">42 U.S.C. 295p</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ID22307A39CED54147A60256CA4ECE4B6C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Medical school candidate</header><text>The term <term>medical school candidate</term> means a student in attendance at an eligible institution pursuing a professional doctor of medicine or doctor of osteopathic medicine degree.</text></paragraph></section><section id="ID0FF51532F9804478A5DE273F7B25DCB5"><enum>420T.</enum><header>Program established</header><subsection id="IDE6EBDD6D80694682870A4C753A5DCC9B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Program authority</header><paragraph id="IDFC69E92BAFFA4FF29EB11ED009335D66"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Payments required</header><text>The Secretary shall pay to each eligible institution such sums as may be necessary to pay to each medical school candidate who files an application and agreement in accordance with section 420U, and who qualifies under such section, a MED Grant in the amount of tuition and required fees for each year during which that medical school candidate is in attendance at the institution.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ID6F3EEB912D4049A7AB03EE79BB0939E8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>References</header><text>Grants made under paragraph (1) shall be known as <quote>MED Grants</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID37839CCD6FDA4A96B068681523730E5B" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Payment methodology</header><paragraph id="IDA25DDC5DD3574096BFC7C98E9243CA85" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Prepayment</header><text>Not less than 85 percent of any funds provided to an eligible institution under subsection (a) shall be advanced to the eligible institution prior to the start of each payment period and shall be based upon an amount requested by the institution as needed to pay medical school candidates until such time as the Secretary determines and publishes in the Federal Register with an opportunity for comment, an alternative payment system that provides payments to institutions in an accurate and timely manner, except that this sentence shall not be construed to limit the authority of the Secretary to place an institution on a reimbursement system of payment.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="IDB6A531CBCC7F40BBB45ABC530C449903" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Direct payment</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be interpreted to prohibit the Secretary from paying directly to medical school candidates, in advance of the beginning of the academic term, an amount for which medical school candidates are eligible, in cases where the eligible institution elects not to participate in the disbursement system required by paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID2D6A1BEB366E4A31AF0D735CF207AEF5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>No exceeding cost</header><text>The amount of a grant awarded under this subpart, in combination with Federal assistance, shall not exceed the cost of attendance (as defined in section 472) at the eligible institution at which that medical school candidate is in attendance.</text></subsection><subsection id="ID62F94D0C3A4E4AEA92A6FBEE64CA3F68"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Period of eligibility for grants</header><text>The period during which a medical school candidate may receive a MED grant under this subpart shall be the period required for the completion of the professional medical degree being pursued by the medical school candidate at the eligible institution at which the medical school candidate is in attendance, except that the period during which a medical school candidate may receive a MED Grant under this subpart shall not exceed 8 years.</text></subsection></section><section id="IDFC8BDA25A19E4578ADCB53B9EAE5A59E"><enum>420U.</enum><header>Application; award</header><subsection id="ID0CDAA9CAF86647C3B3136F2A07F3B048"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Application; award</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida06be8b8500b49f3a806de9c342472de"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall periodically set dates by which medical school candidates shall file applications for grants under this subpart. Each medical school candidate desiring a grant under this subpart for any year shall file an application containing such information as is necessary to demonstrate that the medical school candidate—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id774532d86f334ccb9de7297fd22b3041"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is an eligible student for purposes of section 484;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2a0b3432c27846c988ca84cdb42dc74e"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has completed a FAFSA;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id79acbb92898144c0874557f4ff30e8fb"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">would like to receive a MED grant; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf2dc921b99d14317acc046ab242ea2d4"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">understands and agrees to the terms and conditions of the agreement to serve described in subparagraph (b).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idba9086bff0474c17b0e96f84c07ef4fc"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Award</header><text>The Secretary shall award a MED grant to each eligible medical school candidate who meets the requirements described in paragraph (1) for each year that the application under such paragraph is submitted and such requirements are met.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="IDB36FE2824E39450C897CD2C2AE4A2D7F"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Agreements To serve</header> <text>Each application under subsection (a) shall contain or be accompanied by an agreement by the applicant that—</text>
                <paragraph id="ID31754528AEFC44A7A27A47CCD0FF1175">
                  <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>the applicant will—</text> <subparagraph id="IDF43B4F7D6EB94BE2B3ECCCE40EE17267"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>practice primary care, as defined in section 1886 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395ww">42 U.S.C. 1395ww</external-xref>), as a physician for at least 10 years after their related training is completed (including residency or fellowship programs) within 15 years after completing the degree for which the applicant received a MED Grant under this subpart or such related training (referred to in this section as the <quote>service obligation window</quote>); and</text>
                  </subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="IDAF32C8B9AB364CAA991FC96E55380317">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>annually submit an employment certification, for each year of service, showing that the requirement under subparagraph (A) is being met;</text>
                  </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="ID3A67AC736A3448AFA1A9FF55447175DE">
                  <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>in the event that the applicant is determined to have failed or refused to carry out such service obligation, a specified amount of any MED Grants received by such applicant will be treated as a loan and collected from the applicant in accordance with subsection (c) and the regulations thereunder; and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="IDA1E1740F68874038AC1763535F08FD06">
                  <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>contains, or is accompanied by, a plain-language disclosure form developed by the Secretary that clearly describes the nature of the MED Grant award, the service obligation, and the loan repayment requirements that are the consequence of the failure to complete the service obligation.</text>
                </paragraph>
              </subsection><subsection id="ID451C3227E92A43CA84143614B7D831F7">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Repayment for failure To complete service</header>
                <paragraph id="id275B6A9AA9B8498191767AA73FAE8191" commented="no"
                  display-inline="no-display-inline">
                  <enum>(1)</enum>
                  <header>In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the event that any recipient of a grant under this subpart fails or refuses to comply with the service obligation in the agreement under subsection (b), a specified amount as described in paragraph (3) of the MED Grants received by such recipient shall, upon a determination of such a failure or refusal in such service obligation, be converted to a Federal Direct Unsubsidized Stafford Loan under part D of title IV, and shall be subject to repayment, in accordance with paragraph (2).</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                  id="id63a593a343e545adb7556df05a358228">
                  <enum>(2)</enum>
                  <header>Interest and repayment</header>
 <text>Amounts that are converted to a Direct Unsubsidized Stafford Loan under paragraph (1) shall accrue interest at the rate applicable to such Direct Unsubsidized Stafford Loans for borrowers as of the date of conversion, and the recipient shall be eligible for the same repayment plans and borrower protections with respect to such converted loans as that recipient would otherwise be eligible for with respect to a Federal Direct Unsubsidized Stafford Loan under part D of title IV for a borrower that is disbursed on the same date.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                  id="id557345c8c37d4928bbfbc74f2ae0dade">
                  <enum>(3)</enum>
                  <header>Specified amount to be repaid</header>
                  <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                    id="id855112007b134aed9760b7a893708e18">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
                    <header>5 years or less</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a MED Grant recipient has completed 5 years or less of required service, the lesser of—</text>
                    <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                      id="id2191dfd491d24bcba295ca90060885ff">
                      <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the total amount of MED grants received by the recipient; or</text>
                    </clause>
                    <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                      id="idaaff58d58d664e4c8e581a4721374dc1">
                      <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$50,000.</text> </clause> </subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id62385051c6fd4a01b50973ece2924d36"> <enum>(B)</enum> <header>Greater than 5 years and less than 10 years</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a MED Grant recipient has completed more than 5 years of required service but less than 10 years of required service, the lesser of—</text>
                    <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                      id="id25b17426cf0c45bfbc4d9d6af8f7aae9">
                      <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the total amount of MED grants received by the recipient; or</text>
                    </clause>
                    <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                      id="id7be0ec002bda47909a1b0b61ea404611">
                      <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$25,000.</text> </clause> </subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbca9575835594e43b38a3ea30ee968b3"> <enum>(C)</enum> <header>Cap</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount of MED Grants that is converted to a loan and required to be repaid under this subsection shall not exceed $50,000.</text>
                  </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id5D98C8A884B5475BAA30C0696529600C" commented="no"
                  display-inline="no-display-inline">
                  <enum>(4)</enum>
                  <header>Reconsideration of conversion decisions</header>
                  <subparagraph id="id8C0766867CE0438AA55D677EC65807C6" commented="no"
                    display-inline="no-display-inline">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
                    <header>Request to reconsider</header>
 <text>In any case where the Secretary has determined that a recipient of a grant under this subpart has failed or refused to comply with the service obligation in the agreement under subsection (b) and has converted the grant into a Federal Direct Unsubsidized Stafford Loan under part D in accordance with paragraph (1), (including cases where such loans have been fully or partially paid), the recipient may request that the Secretary reconsider such initial determination and may submit additional information to demonstrate satisfaction of the service obligation. Upon receipt of such a request, the Secretary shall reconsider the determination in accordance with this paragraph not later than 90 days after the date that such request was received.</text>
                  </subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="id9527779870FF409EA6D5A75DE7203176" commented="no"
                    display-inline="no-display-inline">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
                    <header>Reconsideration</header>
 <text>If, in reconsidering an initial determination under subparagraph (A) (including cases where such loans were fully or partially paid), the Secretary determines that the reason for such determination was the recipient's failure to timely submit a certification required under subsection (b)(1)(B), an error or processing delay by the Secretary, a change to the fields considered eligible for fulfillment of the service obligation (as described in subsection (b)(1)(A)), a recipient having previously requested to have the MED Grant converted to a loan, or another valid reason determined by the Secretary, and that the recipient has, as of the date of the reconsideration, demonstrated that the recipient did meet, or is meeting the service obligation in the agreement under subsection (b), the Secretary shall—</text>
                    <clause id="id978992061A9549A2A4722537773BFB78" commented="no"
                      display-inline="no-display-inline">
                      <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>discharge the Federal Direct Unsubsidized Stafford Loan under part D, and reinstate the recipient's grant under this subpart;</text>
                    </clause>
                    <clause id="idA068F8899B6C47268952B667540D6654" commented="no"
                      display-inline="no-display-inline">
                      <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>discharge any interest or fees that may have accumulated during the period that the grant was converted to a Federal Direct Unsubsidized Stafford Loan under part D;</text>
                    </clause>
                    <clause id="id53CC31F107424A98B3EB724A2939287F" commented="no"
                      display-inline="no-display-inline">
                      <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>if the recipient has other loans under part D, apply any payments made for the Federal Direct Unsubsidized Stafford Loan under part D during such period to those other loans under part D;</text>
                    </clause>
                    <clause id="id4B434E7CDFF54A6ABB1C80F3975C8D07" commented="no"
                      display-inline="no-display-inline">
                      <enum>(iv)</enum>
 <text>if the recipient does not have other loans under part D, reimburse the recipient for any amounts paid on the Federal Direct Unsubsidized Stafford Loan under part D during such period;</text>
                    </clause>
                    <clause id="id2C229DB4C1EF4C309A95F6A7DB572BDC" commented="no"
                      display-inline="no-display-inline">
                      <enum>(v)</enum>
 <text>request that consumer reporting agencies remove any negative credit reporting due to the conversion of the MED Grant to a loan; and</text>
                    </clause>
                    <clause id="id03EFFD25A723410BA2F686A1C93836A9" commented="no"
                      display-inline="no-display-inline">
                      <enum>(vi)</enum>
 <text>use the additional information provided under subparagraph (A) to determine the progress the recipient has made in meeting the service obligation.</text>
                    </clause>
                  </subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="id5E3ED8C069AD473C98CF5533E08A26C0" commented="no"
                    display-inline="no-display-inline">
                    <enum>(C)</enum>
                    <header>Extension of time to complete service obligation</header>
 <text>In the case of a recipient whose MED Grant was reinstated in accordance with subparagraph (B), the Secretary shall, upon such reinstatement—</text>
                    <clause id="id0614C3A554A44471BBF79A9E84E7C257" commented="no"
                      display-inline="no-display-inline">
                      <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>extend the time remaining for the recipient to fulfill the service obligation described in subsection (b)(1) to a period of time equal to—</text>
                      <subclause id="idF200162B68104E36BE31DC9D86FF29DA" commented="no"
                        display-inline="no-display-inline">
                        <enum>(I)</enum>
 <text>10 years; minus</text> </subclause> <subclause id="idA06E2A6CE1C24938AF1A2DC07ABDA00D" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <enum>(II)</enum> <text>the number of years that the recipient completed service as a physician in primary care prior to the reconversion of the loan to a MED Grant under subparagraph (B), including any years of qualifying service completed during the period when the MED Grant was in loan status; and</text>
                      </subclause>
                    </clause>
                    <clause id="id4F7225E896BD4E1CADFCF3B9FC458540" commented="no"
                      display-inline="no-display-inline">
                      <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>treat any years of service described in subclause (II) of clause (i) as years that count toward the individual’s service obligation (regardless of whether the MED Grant funds were in grant or loan status) if that time otherwise meets the requirements of this section.</text>
                    </clause>
                  </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
 </subsection><subsection id="ID129FC1A69B4F464690DF22188F97CE21"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Additional administrative provisions</header><paragraph id="ID298297463B2E48359C030D8EFA547888"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Extenuating circumstances</header><text>The Secretary shall establish, by regulation, categories of extenuating circumstances under which a recipient of a grant under this subpart who is unable to fulfill all or part of the recipient's service obligation may be excused from fulfilling that portion of the service obligation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idB3BAE2EBE86C48EDB6E6397B30F5D291" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Communication with recipients</header><text>The Secretary shall notify MED grant recipients not less than twice per calendar year regarding how to submit the employment certification under subsection (b)(1)(B) and the recommendations and requirements for submitting that certification under paragraph (3).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idA9A4C66BD6CD4B7BA40D3CB0A74FC490" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Submission of employment certification</header><subparagraph id="idC96AFF8C221948F180FC783A523887CF" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Recommended submissions</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id733bcdf694384f4ea6e27f115156c35b"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall notify MED Grant recipients that the Department recommends that MED Grant recipients submit the employment certification described in subsection (b)(1)(B) as soon as practicable after the completion of each year of service.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id65e661ab73704b0e89b02c9ede817b98"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The Secretary shall provide a standardized annual certification form for use under this section and allow electronic submission by the recipient or employer.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8CF642FE9F9F4D73B6D3550E24EAD64B" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Required submission</header><text>A MED Grant recipient shall be required to submit to the Department employment certification within the timeframe that would allow that individual to complete their service obligation before the end of the service obligation window.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3532A3BAE90B4FFAA2B7C6D5847393B3" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Notification</header><text>The Secretary shall notify MED Grant recipients of the required submission deadlines described in this paragraph.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC884D94E837D422A9F25E8826B5108C4" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Adjustment of deadline</header><text>The Secretary shall adjust the submission deadline described in subparagraph (B) to account for a service obligation window extension.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0173E5A5C049492E8B81B299D85CC074" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Alternative to certification</header><text>The Secretary shall provide an alternative to the certification of employment described in subsection (b)(1)(B) for recipients who cannot obtain such required certification of employment because the recipient can demonstrate the employer is no longer in existence or the employer refuses to cooperate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="IDB38F89D917D64B109A08D8324F240B26"><enum>420V.</enum><header>Program period and funding</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Beginning on July 1, 2026, there shall be available to the Secretary to carry out this subpart, from funds not otherwise appropriated, such sums as may be necessary to provide MED Grants in accordance with this subpart to each eligible applicant.</text></section></subpart><subpart id="id5e06e626882a4a2db337b94dd22119d1" style="OLC"><enum>12</enum><header>DENTAL Grants</header><section id="idc66517db5a0847cc9f750d0d1fdb1c9e"><enum>420W.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For the purposes of this subpart:</text><paragraph id="idedb0f754a2f94620af85c43b49e3d37f"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible institution</header><text>The term <term>eligible institution</term> means an institution of higher education, as defined in section 101, that is a school of dentistry as defined in section 799B of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/295p">42 U.S.C. 295p</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8a7cad8cb2cc4d1db83187f389dac7be"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Dental school candidate</header><text>The term <term>dental school candidate</term> means a student in attendance at an eligible institution pursuing a professional dental degree.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3dee9840d783425cbc10282a98ef6d6c"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rural area</header><text>The term rural area has the meaning given that term in section 861(b)(2).</text></paragraph></section><section id="ideb4a4ae06e8d4088b4554b69ba50413b"><enum>420X.</enum><header>Program established</header><subsection id="id5ff23b5d61e0412ea1bf6fb656717069"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Program authority</header><paragraph id="idba34b25c80774c76a5bc824ab2c0ae76"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Payments required</header><text>The Secretary shall pay to each eligible institution such sums as may be necessary to pay to each dental school candidate who files an application and agreement in accordance with section 420Y, and who qualifies under such section, a DENTAL Grant in the amount of tuition and required fees for each year during which that dental school candidate is in attendance at the institution.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id94d176de245d46ea82c1e0f1078adc67"><enum>(2)</enum><header>References</header><text>Grants made under paragraph (1) shall be known as <quote>DENTAL Grants</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id71218f3b049b432a99e9d6bc1fc9d38a" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Payment methodology</header><paragraph id="idfed70eec6258478686087ccf2fa5fef3" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Prepayment</header><text>Not less than 85 percent of any funds provided to an eligible institution under subsection (a) shall be advanced to the eligible institution prior to the start of each payment period and shall be based upon an amount requested by the institution as needed to pay dental school candidates until such time as the Secretary determines and publishes in the Federal Register with an opportunity for comment, an alternative payment system that provides payments to institutions in an accurate and timely manner, except that this sentence shall not be construed to limit the authority of the Secretary to place an institution on a reimbursement system of payment.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id79a850c4967a4bd68fedd10788840cbf" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Direct payment</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be interpreted to prohibit the Secretary from paying directly to dental school candidates, in advance of the beginning of the academic term, an amount for which dental school candidates are eligible, in cases where the eligible institution elects not to participate in the disbursement system required by paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idf161866e1f5241ddba5c1ad465565740"><enum>(c)</enum><header>No exceeding cost</header><text>The amount of a grant awarded under this subpart, in combination with Federal assistance, shall not exceed the cost of attendance (as defined in section 472) at the eligible institution at which that dental school candidate is in attendance.</text></subsection><subsection id="id34362551338c458e9d9b9af4b6a38d6b"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Period of eligibility for grants</header><text>The period during which a dental school candidate may receive a DENTAL grant under this subpart shall be the period required for the completion of the professional dental degree being pursued by the dental school candidate at the eligible institution at which the dental school candidate is in attendance, except that the period during which a dental school candidate may receive a DENTAL Grant under this subpart shall not exceed 8 years.</text></subsection></section><section id="id44f94b0a68f9417087ef5dc728dda554"><enum>420Y.</enum><header>Application; award</header><subsection id="id0f478cd109894aebba905c5a0fd30b8b"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Application; award</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbc86aebb5ded434ea0dbadb279c68ea4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall periodically set dates by which dental school candidates shall file applications for grants under this subpart. Each dental school candidate desiring a grant under this subpart for any year shall file an application containing such information as is necessary to demonstrate that the dental school candidate—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id988d96116224461a913a8133805a034e"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is an eligible student for purposes of section 484;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida749d9f93683478184db01a153360366"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has completed a FAFSA;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id34ff91d3b60b4e83924978aa414725fd"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">would like to receive a DENTAL grant; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcdc2f4ba0dcd41db9c823f62d5f832b5"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">understands and agrees to the terms and conditions of the agreement to serve described in subparagraph (b).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9c1aac17f8164444aa96874ab46a6b72"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Award</header><text>The Secretary shall award a DENTAL grant to each eligible dental school candidate who meets the requirements described in paragraph (1) for each year that the application under such paragraph is submitted and such requirements are met.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id1c4c2355b7ac402fa3ee62f0a7c181dd"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Agreements To serve</header> <text>Each application under subsection (a) shall contain or be accompanied by an agreement by the applicant that—</text>
                <paragraph id="id1afde80895d544759ab71d6486fa7bc7">
                  <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>the applicant will—</text> <subparagraph id="idf55708ced3ee4f2c9028500595f4f784"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>practice general dental care in a rural area, with the option for service to be completed cumulatively across eligible sites and locations, for at least 10 years after their related training is completed (including a residency or fellowship program) within 15 years after completing the degree and such related training for which the applicant received a DENTAL Grant under this subpart (referred to in this section as the <quote>service obligation window</quote>); and</text>
                  </subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="id760657cffb644550874ec494d5757ea1">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>annually submit an employment certification, for each year of service, showing that the requirement under subparagraph (A) is being met;</text>
                  </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id8146a0e3246d443b9f533583e4ce4fb6">
                  <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>in the event that the applicant is determined to have failed or refused to carry out such service obligation, the specified amount of any DENTAL Grants received by such applicant will be treated as a loan and collected from the applicant in accordance with subsection (c) and the regulations thereunder; and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id2b93a8bfbad94b42abc0882607f312f8">
                  <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>contains, or is accompanied by, a plain-language disclosure form developed by the Secretary that clearly describes the nature of the DENTAL Grant award, the service obligation, and the loan repayment requirements that are the consequence of the failure to complete the service obligation.</text>
                </paragraph>
              </subsection><subsection id="idbca029cd9099424387fa44a10f620f34">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Repayment for failure To complete service</header>
                <paragraph id="ida15a9ccdf6a04cc5bf24e89e90ba0f88" commented="no"
                  display-inline="no-display-inline">
                  <enum>(1)</enum>
                  <header>In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the event that any recipient of a grant under this subpart fails or refuses to comply with the service obligation in the agreement under subsection (b), a specified amount as described in paragraph (3) of the DENTAL Grants received by such recipient shall, upon a determination of such a failure or refusal in such service obligation, be converted to a Federal Direct Unsubsidized Stafford Loan under part D of title IV, and shall be subject to repayment, in accordance with paragraph (2).</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                  id="id74addf10683a42aab1515471e379a778">
                  <enum>(2)</enum>
                  <header>Interest and repayment</header>
 <text>Amounts that are converted to a Direct Unsubsidized Stafford Loan under paragraph (1) shall accrue interest at the rate applicable to such Direct Unsubsidized Stafford Loans for borrowers as of the date of conversion, and the recipient shall be eligible for the same repayment plans and borrower protections with respect to such converted loans as that recipient would otherwise be eligible for with respect to a Federal Direct Unsubsidized Stafford Loan under part D of title IV for a borrower that is disbursed on the same date.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                  id="idaf304f8536fc4116abfe7ce03b8295ee">
                  <enum>(3)</enum>
                  <header>Specified amount to be repaid</header>
                  <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                    id="id82ddd5a745954108be723f32f3c6988b">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
                    <header>5 years or less</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a DENTAL Grant recipient has completed 5 years or less of required service, the specified amount to be repaid is the lesser of—</text>
                    <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                      id="ida68f59ae4bc74e9f937000eec9c230b6">
                      <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the total amount of DENTAL Grants received by the recipient; or</text>
                    </clause>
                    <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                      id="iddaa49036785d481583f74f465a2f6bdb">
                      <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$50,000.</text> </clause> </subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7d58ca146e2d497bbc5d8dad17f2c052"> <enum>(B)</enum> <header>Greater than 5 years and less than 10 years</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a DENTAL Grant recipient has completed more than 5 years of required service but less than 10 years of required service, the specified amount to be repaid is the lesser of—</text>
                    <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                      id="idaaf46344b6e84d65bdd6d0757e32a602">
                      <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the total amount of DENTAL Grants received by the recipient; or</text>
                    </clause>
                    <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                      id="id9a7cde98f5314a6fa1c472fe47a718bd">
                      <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$25,000.</text> </clause> </subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2cc7fd75f69d49e19a7fc877ee48e3df"> <enum>(C)</enum> <header>Cap</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount of DENTAL Grants that is converted to a loan and required to be repaid under this subsection shall not exceed $50,000.</text>
                  </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id98df6a03d1d145aa9dcd3160ef8f4f6b" commented="no"
                  display-inline="no-display-inline">
                  <enum>(4)</enum>
                  <header>Reconsideration of conversion decisions</header>
                  <subparagraph id="id8c960ca69fd3475eac9fb0db1d61c4bd" commented="no"
                    display-inline="no-display-inline">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
                    <header>Request to reconsider</header>
 <text>In any case where the Secretary has determined that a recipient of a grant under this subpart has failed or refused to comply with the service obligation in the agreement under subsection (b) and has converted the grant into a Federal Direct Unsubsidized Stafford Loan under part D in accordance with paragraph (1), (including cases where such loans have been fully or partially paid), the recipient may request that the Secretary reconsider such initial determination and may submit additional information to demonstrate satisfaction of the service obligation. Upon receipt of such a request, the Secretary shall reconsider the determination in accordance with this paragraph not later than 90 days after the date that such request was received.</text>
                  </subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="ide089d123c6e1411d9c72873bfcc95b7a" commented="no"
                    display-inline="no-display-inline">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
                    <header>Reconsideration</header>
 <text>If, in reconsidering an initial determination under subparagraph (A) (including cases where such loans were fully or partially paid), the Secretary determines that the reason for such determination was the recipient's failure to timely submit a certification required under subsection (b)(1)(B), an error or processing delay by the Secretary, a change to the fields considered eligible for fulfillment of the service obligation (as described in subsection (b)(1)(A)), a recipient having previously requested to have the DENTAL Grant converted to a loan, or another valid reason determined by the Secretary, and that the recipient has, as of the date of the reconsideration, demonstrated that the recipient did meet, or is meeting the service obligation in the agreement under subsection (b), the Secretary shall—</text>
                    <clause id="idef7f6268100242af9fc102c9a5a8d982" commented="no"
                      display-inline="no-display-inline">
                      <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>discharge the Federal Direct Unsubsidized Stafford Loan under part D, and reinstate the recipient's grant under this subpart;</text>
                    </clause>
                    <clause id="ida63afa30102a4697b0a9e452dcb4705a" commented="no"
                      display-inline="no-display-inline">
                      <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>discharge any interest or fees that may have accumulated during the period that the grant was converted to a Federal Direct Unsubsidized Stafford Loan under part D;</text>
                    </clause>
                    <clause id="id360761c18e3d4020b5fe364ca17a22de" commented="no"
                      display-inline="no-display-inline">
                      <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>if the recipient has other loans under part D, apply any payments made for the Federal Direct Unsubsidized Stafford Loan under part D during such period to those other loans under part D;</text>
                    </clause>
                    <clause id="id764d80dc4f1b45039b629a265998d27a" commented="no"
                      display-inline="no-display-inline">
                      <enum>(iv)</enum>
 <text>if the recipient does not have other loans under part D, reimburse the recipient for any amounts paid on the Federal Direct Unsubsidized Stafford Loan under part D during such period;</text>
                    </clause>
                    <clause id="id28b58d85615a4e338d3c4c348237adc2" commented="no"
                      display-inline="no-display-inline">
                      <enum>(v)</enum>
 <text>request that consumer reporting agencies remove any negative credit reporting due to the conversion of the DENTAL Grant to a loan; and</text>
                    </clause>
                    <clause id="id507c276aeb2641ceae0fcdd5ae80e0a1" commented="no"
                      display-inline="no-display-inline">
                      <enum>(vi)</enum>
 <text>use the additional information provided under subparagraph (A) to determine the progress the recipient has made in meeting the service obligation.</text>
                    </clause>
                  </subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="idd583ce3b881b4d909dd3c07ecc92130f" commented="no"
                    display-inline="no-display-inline">
                    <enum>(C)</enum>
                    <header>Extension of time to complete service obligation</header>
 <text>In the case of a recipient whose DENTAL Grant was reinstated in accordance with subparagraph (B), the Secretary shall, upon such reinstatement—</text>
                    <clause id="id0c8a27553052459aae9ec9810487f95e" commented="no"
                      display-inline="no-display-inline">
                      <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>extend the time remaining for the recipient to fulfill the service obligation described in subsection (b)(1) to a period of time equal to—</text>
                      <subclause id="idda4fce2dbaab4c049d82aa024847bb3a" commented="no"
                        display-inline="no-display-inline">
                        <enum>(I)</enum>
 <text>10 years; minus</text> </subclause> <subclause id="id98a5a6fb03c0484bb5a2fb34cdd533f6" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <enum>(II)</enum> <text>the number of years that the recipient completed required service in general dentistry in a rural area prior to the reconversion of the loan to a DENTAL Grant under subparagraph (B), including any years of qualifying service completed during the period when the DENTAL Grant was in loan status; and</text>
                      </subclause>
                    </clause>
                    <clause id="id530fb300f7264539af9b906534890b0b" commented="no"
                      display-inline="no-display-inline">
                      <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>treat any years of service described in subclause (II) of clause (i) as years that count toward the individual’s service obligation (regardless of whether the DENTAL Grant funds were in grant or loan status) if that time otherwise meets the requirements of this section.</text>
                    </clause>
                  </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
 </subsection><subsection id="id465ae1bc9bde46cf91563a2cba9138db"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Additional administrative provisions</header><paragraph id="id261f147158df4086ae366e905f04a22f"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Extenuating circumstances</header><text>The Secretary shall establish, by regulation, categories of extenuating circumstances under which a recipient of a grant under this subpart who is unable to fulfill all or part of the recipient's service obligation may be excused from fulfilling that portion of the service obligation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id00b075c3945c4264b59a7972ac00ef6d" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Communication with recipients</header><text>The Secretary shall notify DENTAL grant recipients not less than twice per calendar year regarding how to submit the employment certification under subsection (b)(1)(B) and the recommendations and requirements for submitting that certification under paragraph (3).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0c82f96ae60941918806fed56c7da2d8" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Submission of employment certification</header><subparagraph id="id9640e8f6889a465a9dc3a0742ad68b41" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Recommended submissions</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id49a8e94552144ec9996deaba0c5c0a2b"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall notify DENTAL Grant recipients that the Department recommends that DENTAL Grant recipients submit the employment certification described in subsection (b)(1)(B) as soon as practicable after the completion of each year of service.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8b4c20fab24d40bc80d6a6d62bf534aa"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The Secretary shall provide a standardized annual certification form for use under this section and allow electronic submission by the recipient or employer.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf113e34235b04666942c648ad89d7107" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Required submission</header><text>A DENTAL Grant recipient shall be required to submit to the Department employment certification within the timeframe that would allow that individual to complete their service obligation before the end of the service obligation window.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7a1ed2da1a6f455491e86d83ae06d171" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Notification</header><text>The Secretary shall notify DENTAL Grant recipients of the required submission deadlines described in this paragraph.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0704f3e2170b4987bfeb54e66299b5fd" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Adjustment of deadline</header><text>The Secretary shall adjust the submission deadline described in subparagraph (B) to account for a service obligation window extension.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id89fb9625dfde4867b17ca6db6caca95a" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Alternative to certification</header><text>The Secretary shall provide an alternative to the certification of employment described in subsection (b)(1)(B) for recipients who cannot obtain such required certification of employment because the recipient can demonstrate the employer is no longer in existence or the employer refuses to cooperate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id8ffbf58dc4bd454998e1ce5c1effc2cd"><enum>420Z.</enum><header>Program period and funding</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Beginning on July 1, 2026, there shall be available to the Secretary to carry out this subpart, from funds not otherwise appropriated, such sums as may be necessary to provide DENTAL Grants in accordance with this subpart to each eligible applicant.</text></section></subpart><subpart id="id25d9887038c3407da75ab20a6d645f51" style="OLC"><enum>13</enum><header>NURSE Grants</header><section id="idee5ea4acdd1b489a876cd18a0eba017e"><enum>420AA.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For the purposes of this subpart:</text><paragraph id="idadb54773a05a4f10af548a16200f8b8c"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible institution</header><text>The term <term>eligible institution</term> means an accredited school of nursing, as defined in section 801 of the of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/296">42 U.S.C. 296</external-xref>), at an institution of higher education, as defined in section 101.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf3ea598e6ea045cbb3c45405d4c1a8b0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Nursing student</header><text>The term <term>nursing student</term> means a student in attendance at an eligible institution.</text></paragraph></section><section id="idc2d004c26874479ea9f7708622d358d4"><enum>420BB.</enum><header>Program established</header><subsection id="id0e6a58f7e2604c4b8ffeec186a602e01"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Program authority</header><paragraph id="ida557ee630bd34bcc87dc7bd127b58fc2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Payments required</header><text>The Secretary shall pay to each eligible institution such sums as may be necessary to pay to each nursing student who files an application and agreement in accordance with section 420CC, and who qualifies under such section, a NURSE Grant in the amount of tuition and required fees for each year during which that nursing student is in attendance at the institution.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id050a4eb4ecaf4ca29c966e12035320a6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>References</header><text>Grants made under paragraph (1) shall be known as <quote>NURSE Grants</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idf3ead286e512416180dd3cd54b6f916d" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Payment methodology</header><paragraph id="id506ba2a25b2a450587f5a569e2839422" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Prepayment</header><text>Not less than 85 percent of any funds provided to an eligible institution under subsection (a) shall be advanced to the eligible institution prior to the start of each payment period and shall be based upon an amount requested by the institution as needed to pay nursing students until such time as the Secretary determines and publishes in the Federal Register with an opportunity for comment, an alternative payment system that provides payments to institutions in an accurate and timely manner, except that this sentence shall not be construed to limit the authority of the Secretary to place an institution on a reimbursement system of payment.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id392b50eae8dc48bb8477552a899e8875" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Direct payment</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be interpreted to prohibit the Secretary from paying directly to nursing students, in advance of the beginning of the academic term, an amount for which nursing students are eligible, in cases where the eligible institution elects not to participate in the disbursement system required by paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idea8b582745a0439cbc65ad7a57111aec"><enum>(c)</enum><header>No exceeding cost</header><text>The amount of a grant awarded under this subpart, in combination with Federal assistance, shall not exceed the cost of attendance (as defined in section 472) at the eligible institution at which that nursing student is in attendance.</text></subsection><subsection id="id741459fa5b90428eac70254f2d55344e"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Period of eligibility for grants</header><text>The period during which a nursing student may receive a NURSE grant under this subpart shall be the period required for the completion of the professional nursing degree being pursued by the nursing student at the eligible institution at which the nursing student is in attendance, except that the period during which a nursing student may receive a NURSE Grant under this subpart shall not exceed 8 years.</text></subsection></section><section id="id62da47cdd8cb44579e90121a79858856"><enum>420CC.</enum><header>Application; award</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id49e61c7a5a90476db496604d8f4cb3d4"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall periodically set dates by which nursing students shall file applications for grants under this subpart. Each nursing student desiring a grant under this subpart for any year shall file an application containing such information as is necessary to demonstrate that the nursing student—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbda2b2691ed74a2b86970b1330406b09"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is an eligible student for purposes of section 484;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idebf64780dd784660b01fd393e819065f"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has completed a FAFSA; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id30bfcbc15efd41d7992b032c65887da7"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">would like to receive a NURSE grant.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id23f1d6da02c74636a272e6c1378ae7a5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Award</header><text>The Secretary shall award a NURSE grant to each nursing student who meets the requirements described in subsection (a) for each year that the application under such subsection is submitted and such requirements are met.</text></subsection></section><section id="id84bdebb3fd044a1c8bf147dbf4fba3c4" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>420DD.</enum><header>Program period and funding</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Beginning on July 1, 2026, there shall be available to the Secretary to carry out this subpart, from funds not otherwise appropriated, such sums as may be necessary to provide NURSE Grants in accordance with this subpart to each eligible applicant.</text></section></subpart><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id06442052afc4415787782aee5b7158d6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Increasing enrollment at health professions schools</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Part E of title VII of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/294n">42 U.S.C. 294n et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="id21f89a18e3ec40c692581e329997e99d" display-inline="no-display-inline" style="OLC"><subpart id="id6d6433af2a4241a4ac3371db07ae3371" style="OLC"><enum>4<?LEXA-Enum 4?></enum><header>Increasing enrollment at health professions schools</header><section id="idce845c4d8ed64aea9176b0c181051ce7"><enum>779.</enum><header>Grant program to increase enrollment at health professions schools</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbcf325d9bb4d4b698e4a1e61d7c431a2"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Schools of medicine and schools of osteopathic medicine</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8e9211b1e9544d7996ad570a14461b3b"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall award grants to eligible schools of medicine and schools of osteopathic medicine to assist such schools in expanding student enrollment.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7d5da57bdc564ee482cea10b06cea63f"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, a school of medicine or school of osteopathic medicine shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require, including a plan to increase enrollment in the school by at least—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb0a19d5c3eae40a5abcd096eed10eb2b"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">50 percent by year 2 of the grant; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0763ae6ca57945d1af4a961b4714bdf4"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an additional 50 percent by year 4 of the grant.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5b94b9fd9be847699ae90e41af556b64"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>A school of medicine or school of osteopathic medicine that receives a grant under this section shall use the funds awarded through such grant for activities that include—</text><subparagraph id="id51afddb7e7514842bbcb85a2633dc943"><enum>(A)</enum><text>enhancing enrollment and retention of students at such school using evidence-based practices, with a priority for students from disadvantaged backgrounds (including racial or ethnic groups underrepresented in the physician workforce), individuals from rural and underserved areas, low-income individuals, individuals with a disability, and first generation college students (as defined in section 402A(h)(3) of the Higher Education Act of 1965), including through mentorship programs, providing tools and programming for underrepresented students, and addressing other student needs;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb98715cc2f0c44d9ac000b87ede3473e"><enum>(B)</enum><text>retaining current faculty and clinical preceptors, and recruiting and hiring new faculty and clinical preceptors, including by increasing wages and providing loan repayment, with an emphasis on faculty and clinical preceptors from racial or ethnic groups who are underrepresented in the physician workforce;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0c57c6ed0b2747798a69e9653aff467f"><enum>(C)</enum><text>partnering with a health care facility, community health center, or other facility that provides health care in order to provide educational opportunities for the purpose of establishing or expanding clinical education, with emphasis on community-based clinical education;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id75742595546c43e28769dc1b8c033ff5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>modernizing infrastructure at such school, including audiovisual or other equipment, simulation and augmented reality resources, telehealth technologies, and virtual and physical laboratories;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2707f9c9864440fa9c789e72f9661b8d"><enum>(E)</enum><text>creating, supporting, or modernizing educational programs and curriculum, including rural and community-based clinical education, at such school; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id34868d91a97c450d89130836ee7498ae"><enum>(F)</enum><text>other activities that the Secretary determines further the development, improvement, and expansion of schools of medicine and schools of osteopathic medicine.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9339d3d361b44f01954ef24f72b631c2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Schools of nursing</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4ddf5165f3934f568d46d4c872bc55ba"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall award grants to eligible schools of nursing to assist such schools in expanding student enrollment.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbe02e2d1d8d84fe9a1c899416ab78a93"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, a school of nursing shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require, including a plan to increase enrollment in the school by at least—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8ea9f227102d45c9a680e95df31c74d7"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">30 percent by year 2 of the grant; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb79301945c7b4174bb6475b13f502710"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an additional 30 percent by year 4 of the grant.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id37f7322b229042998553cc46503b4e89"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>A school of nursing that receives a grant under this section shall use the funds awarded through such grant for activities that include—</text><subparagraph id="idbe98ad6b31e14125b7c89a8937d917b4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>enhancing enrollment and retention of students at such school using evidence-based practices, with a priority for students from disadvantaged backgrounds (including racial or ethnic groups underrepresented in the nursing workforce), students who identify as an underrepresented sex in the nursing workforce, individuals from rural and underserved areas, low-income individuals, individuals with a disability, and first generation college students (as defined in section 402A(h)(3) of the Higher Education Act of 1965), including through mentorship programs, providing tools and programming for underrepresented students, and addressing other student needs;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idec93d513f1ce4fe689c02ca3c8c1be66"><enum>(B)</enum><text>retaining current faculty and clinical preceptors, and recruiting and hiring new faculty and clinical preceptors, including by increasing wages and providing loan repayment, with an emphasis on faculty and clinical preceptors from racial or ethnic groups who are underrepresented in the nursing workforce;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id609cb605a021485bb78bb11bea614370"><enum>(C)</enum><text>partnering with a health care facility, nurse-managed health clinic, community health center, or other facility that provides health care in order to provide educational opportunities for the purpose of establishing or expanding clinical education, with emphasis on community-based clinical education;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idab9b4f36d5f941679f02901b9b5d9684"><enum>(D)</enum><text>modernizing infrastructure at such school, including audiovisual or other equipment, simulation and augmented reality resources, telehealth technologies, and virtual and physical laboratories;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id530e2e6caac44cb89bc2b5a6af7ad4ef"><enum>(E)</enum><text>creating, supporting, or modernizing educational programs and curriculum, including rural and community-based clinical education, at such school;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd235b544c483419ba55a91adb17446df"><enum>(F)</enum><text>enhancing and expanding nursing programs that prepare nurse researchers and scientists;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbd15eec937bb43b4b1c3596bd40e31c1"><enum>(G)</enum><text>establishing nurse-led intradisciplinary and interprofessional educational partnerships;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9e46e0d786d4420293d3e3659e4cf07e"><enum>(H)</enum><text>supporting registered nurses in baccalaureate degree programs or advanced degree programs described in section 811(b), with a goal of becoming nurse faculty and clinical preceptors; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id28a2ec35b7e74fdeb9b2f946e5c08cd1"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">other activities that the Secretary determines further the development, improvement, and expansion of schools of nursing.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf235cb8b83374c78a255ca36d0725bd9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <term>school of nursing</term> has the meaning given such term in section 801(2).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id501a7b70da6641ea84ea1335058ed5ad"><enum>(c)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Schools of dentistry</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf3b5071c62544f22a38150f641e9e1c6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall award grants to eligible schools of dentistry to assist such schools in expanding student enrollment.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida1c3dfdc27fc410dafa46b34c2eb0113"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, a school of dentistry shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require, including a plan to increase enrollment in the school by at least—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9848fdb0751c47d981c1f23de6a3f0e4"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">20 percent by year 2 of the grant; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf99f226161a948509ad296a44ef615ce"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an additional 20 percent by year 4 of the grant.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id844b8f12cd404e899eac7e1964066c85"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>A school of dentistry that receives a grant under this section shall use the funds awarded through such grant for activities that include—</text><subparagraph id="id8db25544e8544f9597fbae85b093d398"><enum>(A)</enum><text>enhancing enrollment and retention of students at such school using evidence-based practices, with a priority for students from disadvantaged backgrounds (including racial or ethnic groups underrepresented in the dental workforce), individuals from rural and underserved areas, low-income individuals, individuals with a disability, and first generation college students (as defined in section 402A(h)(3) of the Higher Education Act of 1965), including through mentorship programs, providing tools and programming for underrepresented students, and addressing other student needs;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9a99bbcedca7429fb0d853b917f58548"><enum>(B)</enum><text>retaining current faculty and clinical preceptors, and recruiting and hiring new faculty and clinical preceptors, including by increasing wages and providing loan repayment, with an emphasis on faculty and clinical preceptors from racial or ethnic groups who are underrepresented in the dentistry workforce;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id962d92ee11eb4a1f9b6fb000d73e4052"><enum>(C)</enum><text>partnering with a dental clinic, community health center, or other facility, including a school-based dental clinic, that provides dental care in order to provide educational opportunities for the purpose of establishing or expanding clinical education, with emphasis on community-based clinical education;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1360e41d7f84434db3b8291240709d7c"><enum>(D)</enum><text>modernizing infrastructure at such school, including audiovisual or other equipment, simulation and augmented reality resources, telehealth technologies, and virtual and physical laboratories;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd00726d9b98c4cddb37faa964d9e2c00"><enum>(E)</enum><text>creating, supporting, or modernizing educational programs and curriculum, including rural and community-based clinical education, at such school; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id347fd03cfdfb4df38a4bbb6a988e312b"><enum>(F)</enum><text>other activities that the Secretary determines further the development, improvement, and expansion of schools of dentistry.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id94ad7f4acab84bdfb846e72e763e51c9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Grant amounts; grant period</header><text>Each grant awarded under this section shall be in an amount determined by the Secretary, and for a period of 10 years.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id97bdb6050473414b9a1b2c242168c3b4"><enum>(e)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Reporting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each recipient of a grant under this section shall submit to the Secretary an annual report that describes—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5d01263aea39498593f9a3ba8b7e759d"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of students enrolled during the year preceding the date of the report;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbe8f6b52dbaf428e8315b8de6f11cb98"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the percentage by which such enrollment for such year has increased or decreased, as compared to enrollment for the year preceding such year;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id987c2e0ad3ec4ae7aa0893eed9cd4e37"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the number of new faculty and clinical preceptors that were hired during such year; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id50213e8218004cc994059d1fef00643a"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in the case of a recipient of a grant under subsection (c), with respect to graduates of the applicable school of dentistry—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcdc09fcc34924a16bcc4792fd871427f"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number who are practicing dentistry in a rural community;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9a3476de83384e668aef144a1d847642"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number who are enrolled as a participating provider under a State plan under title XIX of the Social Security Act or under a waiver of such a plan;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide481c54c3db645668c5de46cb92de9f3"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the rates of passage of the Integrated National Board Dental Examination, and of any exam or process by which a dentist obtains a license to practice dentistry; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idceb5fbf1adf24252b1ee51c1e671059d"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the rates at which such graduates are practicing dentistry 3 and 5 years after graduation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf973a6bea71c435f8c3b6718dec222de"><enum>(f)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated, for the period of fiscal years 2026 through 2035—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1207d50eb34544fa9b99a008a1ba04d2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$2,800,000,000 for purposes of carrying out subsection (a);</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd303a449597a4cf8b0e3611f1295618e"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$1,980,000,000 for purposes of carrying out subsection (b); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id810a4d2e3cb140f3a2938e43b681867c" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$615,000,000 for purposes of carrying out subsection (c).</text></paragraph></subsection></section></subpart><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="id49ca18426e0246269711596ccb0c5678"><enum>3.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Program of payments to teaching health centers that operate graduate medical education programs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 340H of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/256h">42 U.S.C. 256h</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="idf353eaf646c24ef3b7d57a2d579ed0c8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (c)(2)(B), by adding at the end the following: <quote>Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, the Secretary shall update such per resident amount for each such qualified teaching health center such that such amount for fiscal year 2026 is not less than $170,000, and such amount for fiscal year 2027 and each fiscal year thereafter is not less than the sum of the amount determined for the previous fiscal year plus $10,000.</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id14072f421b5f46b484c2f299836babd0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (g)(1)—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf6f929c0055347bf9cfadfa846a557c0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (E), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id905df96dc3f74ca889b666f839f55a80"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (F), by striking the period and inserting a semicolon; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7a678a1258be45b4ab1d005db9bd7c6f"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ideeba77dc1cbf44eba59b27cf7ac19572"><subparagraph id="idf75107933dda4799a2cf05be4fe12f93"><enum>(G)</enum><text>$892,500,000 for fiscal year 2026;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id23679e22d1b44a68a4da553e899c11ea"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$1,890,000,000 for fiscal year 2027;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc738c6f0a7014235b9731b5061e06998"><enum>(I)</enum><text>$2,992,500,000 for fiscal year 2028;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id07e02e6d755b4fc8859df835a3d9e551"><enum>(J)</enum><text>$3,150,000,000 for fiscal year 2029;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id866d00b571fb43949df47dd712e0918d"><enum>(K)</enum><text>$3,307,500,000 for fiscal year 2030;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id02331dcfd2074f3baf622a31c1ce2d7b"><enum>(L)</enum><text>$3,465,000,000 for fiscal year 2031;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc88d04a641444fd1b9f118093ca94d20"><enum>(M)</enum><text>$3,622,500,000 for fiscal year 2032;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8e1c971df595488aa6619cc73ed43f64"><enum>(N)</enum><text>$3,780,000,000 for fiscal year 2033;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf475441ee2ad4c8ca755655e123930b9"><enum>(O)</enum><text>$3,937,500,000 for fiscal year 2034; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0ec05a919d694a52bfcedc740afd9d59"><enum>(P)</enum><text>$4,095,000,000 for fiscal year 2035.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="id28b420258f4940bb95e8e5957b1acb45"><enum>4.</enum><header>Distribution of additional Medicare GME residency positions</header><subsection id="id61a2d3b9816143c7930e6518d39a5dec"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Distribution</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8aa45964073948f18cbd1003b49d78ea"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>Section 1886(h) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395ww">42 U.S.C. 1395ww(h)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="id2c88f90bcf6a4fc9807cbf498e26f459"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)(F)(i), by striking <quote>and (10)</quote> and inserting <quote>(10), and (11)</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id765dc29dac7f4a0d8a68f5c4a9d88801"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)(H)(i), by striking <quote>and (10)</quote> and inserting <quote>(10), and (11)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2e6a4f979fb4411c98f55a46aaa53574"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf142215691e74ac78dea6eb85d3652f6"><paragraph id="id347e136e03c342de8800d0cbdb23d4bf"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Distribution of additional residency positions in psychiatry and psychiatry subspecialties and primary care</header><subparagraph id="id54a65b638a2c4d5fbddfdf62978b927d"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Additional residency positions</header><clause id="ide764641032f84d70b84f5a0edc7399f3"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For each of fiscal years 2027 through 2036 and for each succeeding fiscal year until the aggregate number of full-time equivalent residency positions distributed under this paragraph is equal to the aggregate number of such positions made available (as specified in clause (ii)(I)), the Secretary shall, subject to the succeeding provisions of this paragraph, increase the otherwise applicable resident limit for each qualifying hospital that submits a timely application under this subparagraph by such number as the Secretary may approve effective beginning July 1 of the fiscal year of the increase.</text></clause><clause id="idcec4303db7af4b8fbfab71272abed37f"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Number available for distribution</header><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id08e63f4f56aa44bab636a3f2d9d9395e"><enum>(I)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Total number available</header><text>The aggregate number of such positions made available under this paragraph shall be equal to 50,220.</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0006d4777e494de793792f509665cae0"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Annual limit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The aggregate number of such positions so made available shall not exceed 5,022 for a fiscal year.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="ided40fc2f2dde4cb4bd10ebe8a36de230"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Distribution for psychiatry or psychiatry subspecialty residencies; primary care residencies</header><text>For each of fiscal years 2027 through 2036, of the positions made available under this paragraph—</text><subclause id="ide47952e3199a44f68953fa8bcbced306"><enum>(I)</enum><text>at least 15 percent shall be distributed for a psychiatry or psychiatry subspecialty residency (as defined in subparagraph (F));</text></subclause><subclause id="id3b16243d778945588db9f72573e9df06"><enum>(II)</enum><text>at least 30 percent shall be distributed for a primary care residency (as defined in such subparagraph); and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="ide4df94d8688f446a950b26bcf5468872"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Timing</header><text>The Secretary shall notify hospitals of the number of positions distributed to the hospital under this paragraph as a result of an increase in the otherwise applicable resident limit by January 31 of the fiscal year of the increase. Such increase shall be effective beginning July 1 of such fiscal year.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id96926411e9a84d0fb5b5f7b276e7a8c2" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Considerations in distribution</header><text>In determining for which qualifying hospitals an increase in the otherwise applicable resident limit is provided under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall take into account the demonstrated likelihood of the hospital filling the positions made available under this paragraph within the first 5 training years beginning after the date the increase would be effective, as determined by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idcb8e7b6cc70c4ab4b2bb258b641ea226" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Requirements</header><clause id="id9a46aae350fd4544baedcb3f0d508e87"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Prohibition on distribution to hospitals without an increase agreement</header><text>No increase in the otherwise applicable resident limit of a hospital may be made under this paragraph unless such hospital agrees to increase the total number of full-time equivalent residency positions under the approved medical residency training program of such hospital by the number of such positions made available by such increase under this paragraph.</text></clause><clause id="id411e35bb39c1401bbd3451b2f5cb415d"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Requirement for hospitals to expand programs</header><text>If a hospital that receives an increase in the otherwise applicable resident limit under this paragraph would be eligible for an adjustment to the otherwise applicable resident limit for participation in a new medical residency training program under section 413.79(e)(3) of title 42, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation), the hospital shall ensure that any positions made available under this paragraph are used to expand an existing program of the hospital and not for participation in a new medical residency training program.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4ad0f2d892d34d4aadd015c55859b45c"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Application of per resident amounts for nonprimary care</header><text>With respect to additional residency positions in a hospital attributable to the increase provided under this paragraph, the approved FTE per resident amounts are deemed to be equal to the hospital per resident amounts for nonprimary care computed under paragraph (2)(D) for that hospital.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide815e3ae49a64c419c24dcc71d11beec"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Permitting facilities to apply aggregation rules</header><text>The Secretary shall permit hospitals receiving additional residency positions attributable to the increase provided under this paragraph to, beginning in the fifth year after the effective date of such increase, apply such positions to the limitation amount under paragraph (4)(F) that may be aggregated pursuant to paragraph (4)(H) among members of the same affiliated group.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id50968e9945324c69b0996f3ee9f41df3"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this paragraph:</text><clause id="ida605d48cdbb348e7966a2a783883ea47"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Otherwise applicable resident limit</header><text>The term <term>otherwise applicable resident limit</term> means, with respect to a hospital, the limit otherwise applicable under subparagraphs (F)(i) and (H) of paragraph (4) on the resident level for the hospital determined without regard to this paragraph, but taking into account paragraphs (7)(A), (7)(B), (8)(A), (8)(B), (9)(A), and (10)(A).</text></clause><clause id="idd9da3ef26e534197a6086319e51ddbed"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Primary care residency</header><text>The term <term>primary care residency</term> means a residency in a program described in paragraph (5)(H).</text></clause><clause id="id07b2a1c1d45e4817bde4b8acfcd20c62"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Psychiatry or psychiatry subspecialty residency</header><text>The term <term>psychiatry or psychiatry subspecialty residency</term> has the meaning given that term in paragraph (10)(F).</text></clause><clause id="idd419dbef52724ae0b48143e3a04abf44"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Reference resident level</header><text>The term <term>reference resident level</term> means, with respect to a hospital, the resident level for the most recent cost reporting period of the hospital ending on or before the date of enactment of this paragraph, for which a cost report has been settled (or, if not, submitted (subject to audit)), as determined by the Secretary.</text></clause><clause id="iddd7b4cb3c2af4024aed5dc096b93d76c"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Resident level</header><text>The term <term>resident level</term> has the meaning given such term in paragraph (7)(C)(i).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id04359578c9d74a24a41741de444cc7ea"><enum>(2)</enum><header>IME</header><text>Section 1886(d)(5)(B) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395ww">42 U.S.C. 1395ww(d)(5)(B)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="id802b6c325a2a48a8b8c06852dc4eb330"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in clause (v), in the third sentence, by striking <quote>and (h)(10)</quote> and inserting <quote>(h)(10), and (h)(11)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2614b99c66b44d368319034a2f6a4c4f"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new clause:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id050bde3dc340485badbd355aa9661a8d"><clause id="ide8b49c70403b4f969bdefed0be512f74"><enum>(xiii)</enum><text>For discharges occurring on or after July 1, 2027, insofar as an additional payment amount under this subparagraph is attributable to resident positions distributed to a hospital under subsection (h)(11), the indirect teaching adjustment factor shall be computed in the same manner as provided under clause (ii) with respect to such resident positions.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide5d3dcfd0bc7460ebf94cbcf1fdab628" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Prohibition on judicial review</header><text>Section 1886(h)(7)(E) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395ww">42 U.S.C. 1395ww(h)(7)(E)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>paragraph (11),</quote> after <quote>paragraph (10),</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id05ac5c227e264da6a3cf58c3b0ce71f8"><enum>5.</enum><header>Rural relocation grant program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subpart 2 of part E of title VII of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/295">42 U.S.C. 295 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd8c5df132f584dd5aafc574591ce6597"><section id="id0741192d2d2a41d583188431c531c34e"><enum>778A.</enum><header>Rural relocation grant program</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida4f1c9bf72eb468b90c366b41c55c9e7"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>The Secretary shall award grants to eligible physicians, nurses, and dentists for purposes of assisting such individuals in relocating to a rural area in which the individual intends to practice medicine, nursing, or dentistry, as applicable.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id07fa8b5326b249ba849a420322118271"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, a physician, nurse, or dentist shall—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id344a3e4cb55f4a8d94011e4dc9dbb811"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be licensed to practice medicine, nursing, or dentistry, as applicable, in the State in which the rural area to which the individual is relocating is located;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5520948bca5b4bc092cef5044d6728e8"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prior to such relocation, be practicing in an area that is not a rural area;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb94ba1a3fb894328b2c76575f7766ad8"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">upon such relocation, have a permanent position in the area to which the individual is relocating and intend to practice in such area for not fewer than 3 years; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide9922dafbac6435fb812b6deda162c51"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide09554695079442998ba8744aef220f0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Grant amounts; use of funds; repayment</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id58fc33990cfe41289ed9f48b978d30c4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A grant awarded under this section shall be in an amount determined by the Secretary, not to exceed $20,000.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide4f5165ca26c4e93bb39c22644879c96"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual receiving a grant under this section may use such grant for eligible life and relocation expenses, as determined by the Secretary.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id827b4292406345b5b40865df14128504"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Repayment</header><text>If an individual receiving a grant under this section leaves the area described in subsection (b)(3) before the expiration of the 3-year period described in such subsection, such individual shall repay to the Secretary an amount equal to 50 percent of the amount of the grant.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id801942393c344c579eda318bc83a92e5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To carry out this section, there is authorized to be appropriated $1,800,000,000 for the period of fiscal years 2026 through 2035.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill>

