<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB7F542DEDDD04CB584DC89321362E09F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5765 IH: Affordable, Reliable, Clean Energy Security Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5765</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251017">October 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001306">Mr. Balderson</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct Federal departments or agencies to implement certain definitions for the terms affordable, reliable, and clean energy, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H70384D02734742B39CFEBD9429D58513" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H55D6AE9D18234B41B05BB8CF65ED0041" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Affordable, Reliable, Clean Energy Security Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H8778510AEA9B41B18053AD35DDDC7374"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">For purposes of this Act:</text> <paragraph id="HB7315CD035C9463FA858A11B12B8C18F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Affordable</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>affordable</term> with respect to energy means a low cost method of producing electricity, factoring in the full system cost of each generation source.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE278471FDA7B456ABED27784D516C572"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reliable</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>reliable</term> with respect to energy means a source of electricity that—</text> <subparagraph id="HF21D34BB07F84F3DBF3208CD5C94EA44"><enum>(A)</enum><text>except as required during a period of routine maintenance or repairs, has an Effective Load Carrying Capability of 60 percent or greater;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC5620D74332A4C6F97F796B22668F614"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is not subject to intermittent availability; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H12E63C96CB5E4EB7977CB30FDA490CE0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is not subject to routine weather that impacts energy production.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H88E22E76574448DDA102ACBDF238254F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Clean</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>clean</term> with respect to energy means any energy generated using—</text> <subparagraph id="HB20482BD66DF493D9E39C8B567986F55" display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an energy source listed in section 203(b) of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/15852">42 U.S.C. 15852(b)</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H04E36D7034DE4344A24EB63C392298D9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a nuclear reactor; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9E3CE81FF4CD479BA759D908241FDD5E" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the combustion of hydrocarbons, in accordance with the national ambient air quality standards under title I of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7401">42 U.S.C. 7401</external-xref>, et seq.), including any such energy that is generated using natural gas.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H5C737C81FE0444A6B405B1BEA693FEDE"><enum>3.</enum><header>Directing certain Federal departments and agencies to incorporate definitions of affordable, reliable, and clean energy</header> 
<subsection id="H6AB7013426B3443CAEE0FF9E7CA740E6" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Identification report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Energy, in coordination with the Secretary of the Interior and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, shall submit to Congress a report that identifies regulations, grants, guidance, and policies within their respective departments or agencies relating to affordable energy, reliable energy, and clean energy.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="HBA6499C417E94B489ADE8A4DEDAD3052"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Identification report publication</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Energy, the Secretary of the Interior, and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency shall publish the report required by subsection (a) on the respective public websites of the Department of Energy, the Department of the Interior, and the Environmental Protection Agency.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8BB4911344A4443EAC8DB413FEB5291E" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definition adoption</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the report required by subsection (a) is submitted to Congress, the Secretary of Energy, the Secretary of the Interior, and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency shall update all regulations, grants, guidance, and policies of their respective department or agency relating to affordable energy, reliable energy, and clean energy to incorporate the definitions in section 2 of this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H7A740EE0C4384AE8A0EF0BC55C3EC79F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Incorporation report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Energy, the Secretary of the Interior, and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency shall each submit a report to Congress that identifies the manner and extent to which each department or agency has incorporated the definitions in this Act relating to affordable energy, reliable energy, and clean energy into their respective department or agency regulations, grants, guidance, and policies.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H20E8E405888543EAA5CB7949B2FD57FE"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Incorporation report publication</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Energy, the Secretary of the Interior, and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency shall publish the reports required by subsection (d) on the respective public websites of the Department of Energy, the Department of the Interior, and the Environmental Protection Agency.</text></subsection> </section> </legis-body></bill>

