<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCB8FEDAE35BA40008DD4F40B63D6EADC" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3771 IH: Protecting Coasts and Cities from Severe Weather Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3771</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250605">June 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000398">Mr. Kean</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To increase observations, understanding, and forecasting of coastal flooding and storm surge events, to address weather observation gaps in highly vulnerable areas, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8AD23DAAA96B401390FF66A963609515" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H1AC2903A535B4909AB8F35CF155BC535" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting Coasts and Cities from Severe Weather Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HE959AFEF34084139B5A1678F7A8BABF7"><enum>2.</enum><header>Coastal flooding and storm surge forecast improvement program</header> <subsection id="HE05B2C380C594FFCA233703D770A2DBD" commented="no"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Under Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere (in this Act referred to as the <quote>Under Secretary</quote>), in collaboration with the United States weather industry (as such term is defined in section 2 of the Weather Research and Forecasting Innovation Act of 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/8501">15 U.S.C. 8501</external-xref>)) and academic partners, shall establish a coastal flooding and storm surge forecast improvement program (in this section refer to as the <quote>program</quote>).</text>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="HF4DC21FAAE874E619FE9F6DC2A54BDB0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Goal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The goal of the program shall be to reduce the loss of life or property from coastal flooding, including high tide flooding, and storm surge events through the development and extension of accurate, effective, actionable, and probable forecasts and warnings.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H1627E536D03541BDA9AA0C62092BCC31"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In implementing the program, the Under Secretary shall prioritize activities that carry out the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H193600ACCC75434AB357A4C428F1E79B" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Improve understanding and capacity for real-time operational prediction of the ocean’s role in coastal flooding, including high tide flooding, and storm surge events.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H568640ECFDB0484B993E0B440CF35173" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Improve the capacity to mitigate, adapt to, or prevent the impacts of coastal flooding, including high tide flooding, and storm surge events, including by improving the understanding and capacity of coastal communities to perceive, comprehend, and respond to forecast information.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8ED9B97923744D92BE4FBA224311F532"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Incorporating data from in situ distributed sensors into predictive models and re-analyses.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9B71E3ECC33B4EC4AA6A96F0BC90D005"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Developing probabilistic coastal flooding, including high tide flooding, and storm surge estimates to complement worst-case scenario estimates, including for use in long-term planning and risk management by States, Tribal governments, localities, and emergency managers in coordination with the Federal Emergency Management Agency, as appropriate.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7FE7365678EF49D297F942A6E1985C54"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Establishing skill metrics for coastal inundation forecasting that quantify the benefits of dynamical modeling, data assimilation, and machine learning improvements in the probabilistic forecast of coastal flooding, including high tide flooding, and storm surge risk and impacts.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2184FFFED1194CBE936D28735293FC70"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Improving operational regional storm surge models and, in collaboration with the United States Geological Survey, wave prediction models to enhance probabilistic guidance and messaging.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1CC0EEE7B01C40518EC2AC64005C4F08"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Innovative observations and modeling</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Under Secretary shall ensure the program periodically examines, tests, and evaluates the value of incorporating enhanced model physics, hybrid dynamical or machine learning based prediction systems, and innovative observations, such as novel sensor technologies, observation networks, crewed or uncrewed systems, and hosted instruments on commercial aircrafts, vessels, and satellites, with respect to the improvement of coastal flooding, including high tide flooding, and storm surge forecasts, predictions, and warnings.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H2844090951FF428FBAD0D168FAA987E8"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Program plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Under Secretary shall develop a plan that details the specific research, development, data acquisition, and technology transfer activities, as well as corresponding resources and timelines, necessary to achieve the goal of the program under subsection (b).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H12BB3708AC9A4A71962E011C612DDDAE"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Annual budget for plan submission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After the development of the plan pursuant to subsection (e), the Under Secretary shall, not less frequently than annually, submit to Congress a proposed budget corresponding with the activities identified in such plan.</text></subsection> </section> <section id="H93DBA6295BFB4831AA007B669E223A2A"><enum>3.</enum><header>Data voids in highly vulnerable areas of the United States</header> <subsection id="HA3352866EF37403488B6093D2E5A293C" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Under Secretary, in coordination with the Director of the National Weather Service and the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, in consultation with the United States weather industry, academic partners, and in accordance with activities implemented through existing regional atmospheric, coastal, ocean, and Great Lakes observing systems, shall carry out activities to ensure equitable and comprehensive weather observation coverage, impact-based decision support services, and emergency information sharing in the United States, including the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H09D81BF493BC4A97A7526BC5ED87A1FC" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Identifying regions in the United States and the territories of the United States that are under-observed or highly vulnerable to weather impacts that threaten human life, health, and the economy.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3FED74905D054D3CAF6EDB45C0A331F2" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Identifying any challenges that contribute to the lack of operations under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA285E3E29B4E4179BB64EF2D27C82B71" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Increasing weather observations and developing new weather observational capabilities, such as urban heat island mapping campaigns, with respect to the regions identified under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE943E098C77045BCA84C2C2232330CD4" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Establishing or supporting testbeds and deployments of decision-support services to Federal, State, and local emergency operations centers to develop and integrate new weather, water, and climate observation or emergency information sharing tools, with respect to the regions identified under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H69E6D0D350CE4E1BA5176DE9352A5689" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To the maximum extent practicable, advancing weather and water forecasting and climate modeling capabilities for the regions identified under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H77627A389233428B89EF167EBC4FFE2E" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Undertaking workforce development efforts for emergency management officials and meteorologists in the regions identified under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCCCA8F16541B4D0CADE8B02197BA44BB" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Using data-void-filling observations to better resolve extreme rainfall in complex topography.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3FD552A59AF94478BB3A271816236064" commented="no"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Contributing to a national integrated heat health information system.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD14AD839E3204D8EB76BF11EA0E695A2" commented="no">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Interagency partnership To support pilot projects</header>
 <text>In carrying out this section, the Under Secretary, acting through the Director of the National Weather Service and the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, shall establish an interagency partnership to support pilot projects that accelerate coordination and use of localized weather data in infrastructure and emergency management decisions by Federal, State, and local officials.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H5E25CED15AC64BCD9D11D508CC8BCCCA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Priority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At least one pilot project under subsection (b) shall address key science challenges to using mesonet data in local decision making and development of new tools and training for owners and operators of critical infrastructure (as such term is defined in section 1016(e) of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/107/56">Public Law 107–56</external-xref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5195c">42 U.S.C. 5195c(e)</external-xref>)), such as dams, energy generation and distribution facilities, nuclear power plants, and transportation networks.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

