<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-NEW25512-RHP-9H-G6P"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 223 ATS: Commending and congratulating the Trinity College men’s basketball team for winning the 2025 National Collegiate Athletic Association Division III Men’s Basketball National Championship.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 223</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250513">May 13, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S364">Mr. Murphy</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Commending and congratulating the Trinity College men’s basketball team for winning the 2025 National Collegiate Athletic Association Division III Men’s Basketball National Championship.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, on Saturday, March 22, 2025, the Trinity College men’s basketball team (referred to in this preamble as the <quote>Trinity College Bantams</quote>) won the 2025 National Collegiate Athletic Association (referred to in this preamble as the <quote>NCAA</quote>) Division III Men’s Basketball National Championship (referred to in this preamble as the <quote>National Championship</quote>), defeating the New York University Violets by a score of 64 to 60, at the Allen County War Memorial Coliseum in Fort Wayne, Indiana;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the 2025 NCAA National Championship win is the first in the history of the Trinity College Bantams;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Trinity College Bantams finished the 2024–2025 season with a record of 30 wins and 3 losses, tying a program record for wins;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas, during the 2024–2025 season, the Trinity College Bantams won the New England Small College Athletic Conference title for the second straight year;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the head coach of the Trinity college Bantams, James Cosgrove, was named the 2025 National Association of Basketball Coaches Division III Coach of the Year; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in addition to outstanding athletics, Trinity College is a premier academic institution that—</text><paragraph id="ida94356363735463ba41ef88f34bec434"><enum>(1)</enum><text>was founded in 1823;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4de63084e3dd4c268fcc6b1d3d9c50ae"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the 2024–2025 school year, enrolled 2,235 students from 48 States and 82 countries; and </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5438d1b5f2304eb0806acf4990b6159c"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has faculty and alumni that have been awarded the Pulitzer Prize, the MacArthur award, and many other recognitions for exemplary academic and cultural contributions: Now, therefore, be it</text></paragraph></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id2deebe6b8ea146a29912fd8556e0cc5f"><enum>(1)</enum><text>commends the Trinity College men’s basketball team for winning the 2025 National Collegiate Athletic Association Division III Men’s Basketball National Championship;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf80091febedd440d8eaa7e776474ebdd"><enum>(2)</enum><text>congratulates the fans, students, and faculty of Trinity College; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id56e21ceb1c51449b849f1d10fd6e3d1c"><enum>(3)</enum><text>respectfully requests that the Secretary of the Senate transmit an enrolled copy of this resolution to—</text><subparagraph id="id0d73f8125bb94200a5efe0ffe509a730"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the President of Trinity College, Joanne Berger-Sweeney; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0e320513a0bd4fdba7989ac44cb4378c"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the head coach of the Trinity College men’s basketball team, James Cosgrove.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

