<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ROS25371-53W-35-RRJ"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 S817 IS: Falun Gong Protection Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 817</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250303">March 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S355">Mr. Cruz</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S345">Mr. Johnson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S404">Mr. Scott of Florida</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S384">Mr. Tillis</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To provide for the imposition of sanctions with respect to forced organ harvesting within the People’s Republic of China, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HE637C80972D34FA7ACA035E5806F67E6"><section section-type="section-one" id="H501F0A13050E4FFA88784BC32D1134E8"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Falun Gong Protection Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H04C8D4BAA0144F629EAA18087038CEC1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the policy of the United States—</text><paragraph id="HDF0E731779BD45A79F8248F0685A544C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to avoid any cooperation with the People's Republic of China in the organ transplantation field while the Chinese Communist Party remains in power;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2C647383CA6E4DCDA95E3A8B5B6D4187"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to take appropriate measures, including using relevant sanctions authorities, to coerce the Chinese Communist Party to end any state-sponsored organ harvesting campaign; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEB3CC96D1EE24DF1AA6D81DE344323AB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to work with allies, partners, and multilateral institutions to highlight the People's Republic of China’s persecution of Falun Gong; and </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3da8cd4b24944c45a7b4ed26d1b5ce55"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to coordinate closely with the international community on targeted sanctions and visa restrictions.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H40428924CC9A4334BA84A9BB3E1DEB6A"><enum>3.</enum><header>Imposition of sanctions with respect to forced organ harvesting within the People’s Republic of China</header><subsection id="HD6FDFA7892E548619D38CEBCABF27898"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Imposition of sanctions</header><text>The President shall impose the sanctions described in subsection (c) with respect to each foreign person included in the most recent list submitted under subsection (b).</text></subsection><subsection id="HB2F48472106E4C40A4B23E73BB342B81"><enum>(b)</enum><header>List of persons</header><paragraph id="H58585A537F694DACA1CD0779BDDEAF28"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a list of foreign persons that the President determines to have knowingly and directly engaged in or facilitated the involuntary harvesting of organs within the People’s Republic of China.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE957D2411A924844BFB6A99B8FD12A99"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Updates of lists</header><text>The President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees an updated list under paragraph (1)—</text><subparagraph id="H3B17C07A645747DDB7A755B5B1E07056"><enum>(A)</enum><text>as new information becomes available;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3FDF274E25804446AEC57925A0EF1094"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9C148BFD125B4C82A765C82F087618D8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>annually thereafter until the date of termination under subsection (h).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4CC8486B4D9046EE9D22EE2A574DBD4E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The list required by paragraph (1) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC9D0697C378543378121B50CA35516AC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Sanctions described</header><text>The sanctions described in this subsection are the following:</text><paragraph id="H5D4E5BF604B2448F98BF99B266056A52"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Blocking of property</header><text>The President shall exercise all of the powers granted to the President by the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>) (except that the requirements of section 202 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref>) shall not apply) to the extent necessary to block and prohibit all transactions in property and interests in property of a foreign person on the most recent list submitted under subsection (b) if such property and interests in property are in the United States, come within the United States, or are or come within the possession or control of a United States person.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA51259F65CFA4CC4A3B017B9327EB6B9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Inadmissibility of certain individuals</header><subparagraph id="H299D6E564CC6402D91E2B3DDF4409B83"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Ineligibility for visas, admission, or parole</header><text>An alien included in the most recent list submitted under subsection (b) is—</text><clause id="H550A094EF2824FC68A7C89C615DE0786"><enum>(i)</enum><text>inadmissible to the United States;</text></clause><clause id="H6953F6E556BF4E7998A45D9A8A28E832"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>ineligible to receive a visa or other documentation to enter the United States; and</text></clause><clause id="HFFCB4350E23547069B7FF7650915E02E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>otherwise ineligible to be admitted or paroled into the United States or to receive any other benefit under the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6f0c08b66e804684808b0e716a34062e"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Current visa revoked</header><clause id="id915d374a43454968b06e79a02c06b263"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An alien described in subparagraph (A) is subject to revocation of any visa or other entry documentation regardless of when the visa or other entry documentation is or was issued.</text></clause><clause id="ided53539290ce46bfa2150eefef65c1e4"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Immediate effect</header><text>A revocation under clause (i) shall—</text><subclause id="id53ef2bef677641ba86b05ed47c3be754"><enum>(I)</enum><text>take effect immediately; and</text></subclause><subclause id="idbccffa0cc04c44f9a33b487d8a4f5119"><enum>(II)</enum><text>automatically cancel any other valid visa or entry documentation that is in the alien’s possession. </text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1C17BF38B7BA4BEF832647F8299501F5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Sanctions under paragraph (2) shall not apply to an alien if admitting or paroling the alien into the United States is necessary to permit the United States to comply with the Agreement regarding the Headquarters of the United Nations, signed at Lake Success June 26, 1947, and entered into force November 21, 1947, between the United Nations and the United States, or other applicable international obligations of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC6F438587B30483CA37D5AD7CE8BE1C4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text>The penalties provided for in subsections (b) and (c) of section 206 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1705">50 U.S.C. 1705</external-xref>) shall apply to a person who violates, attempts to violate, conspires to violate, or causes a violation of regulations promulgated to carry out subsection (a) to the same extent that such penalties apply to a person who commits an unlawful act described in section 206(a) of that Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC6219357DB094FBA8777366EA9F3D8F1"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Exception To comply with national security</header><text>The following activities shall be exempt from sanctions under this section:</text><paragraph id="HBF375791247F46BBA2DC425B73340F8C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Activities subject to the reporting requirements under title V of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3091">50 U.S.C. 3091 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE974F7A60A0744559791D98724C08DF6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Any authorized intelligence or law enforcement activities of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6B85A97EEBAB4AAABFC17F1FE08564B9"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Exception relating to provision of humanitarian assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Sanctions under this section may not be imposed with respect to transactions or the facilitation of transactions for—</text><paragraph id="H9D4434CD1A54479CA72C7C08F5A162CC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the sale of agricultural commodities, food, or medicine;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H38465134CC4D4E70A45C42632B32B555"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the provision of vital humanitarian assistance;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBD92ECD290414952A080D0372505A8AE"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">financial transactions relating to humanitarian assistance or for humanitarian purposes; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8171180620B24DA08F79D9659E08978B"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">transporting goods or services that are necessary to carry out operations relating to humanitarian assistance or humanitarian purposes.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0438391E02FC4FCA8B304B8FE96F38AC"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Waiver authority</header><paragraph id="HCDEB51E33BC14BEFABD10FF89AA6BFF9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>The President may, on a case by case basis, waive the imposition of any sanction under this section if the President determines such waiver is in the vital national security interest of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H8407FF5E5FCE48A789D6FBEC4605C592"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reports</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date on which the President submits the first list under subsection (b)(1), and every 120 days thereafter until the date of termination under subsection (h), the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the extent to which the President has used the waiver authority under paragraph (1) during the 120-day period preceding submission of the report.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H20A516255CE545D0B5A03F30A3AA1A8F"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>The authority to impose sanctions under this section shall terminate on the date that is 5 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="id48df42199aad41a38511368cbb68736c"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="id78248533786d491e90a72f5872fe7841"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Admission; admitted; alien; lawfully admitted for permanent residence</header><text>The terms <quote>admission</quote>, <quote>admitted</quote>, <quote>alien</quote>, and <quote>lawfully admitted for permanent residence</quote> have the meanings given those terms in section 101 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide26f02dc5c8e48e5b61f8d8310455db4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Foreign person</header><text>The term <term>foreign person</term> means an individual or entity that is not a United States person.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb5f5820f36e246569e931e9623c4d9f6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Knowingly</header><text>The term <term>knowingly</term>, with respect to conduct, a circumstance, or a result, means that a person had actual knowledge, or should have known, of the conduct, the circumstance, or the result. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfccc71615fc14be9ae692f74beb41fba"><enum>(4)</enum><header>United states person</header><text>The term <term>United States person</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="id5fddd1a7cab44e6598ac07c7cba75c37"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a United States citizen or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence to the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idcdbbb5cb00774374956b8f014bf95de1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an entity organized under the laws of the United States or any jurisdiction within the United States, including a foreign branch of such an entity; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id21529d4a5806486a97d0c9f1d2238b75"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any person located in the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H6B865330AD1C4F10BEACD8152157FE14"><enum>4.</enum><header>Report on organ transplant policies and practices of the People’s Republic of China</header><subsection id="H8CE80672192241129FFE6A5FBACE33BB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services and the Director of the National Institutes of Health, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the organ transplant policies and practices of the People’s Republic of China.</text></subsection><subsection id="HFD58535F61644DA880852756BB8FADBC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Matters To be included</header><text>The report required under subsection (a) shall include—</text><paragraph id="HB9C4512F630B48C68154E66AAF25451D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a summary of de jure and de facto policies toward organ transplantation in the People's Republic of China, including with respect to prisoners of conscience (including Falun Gong) and other prisoners;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC1A08EF91FD140739542B62AC6386890"><enum>(2)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H43D31403C4EF4E45BD27073CD20BB0F0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of organ transplants that are known to occur or are estimated to occur on an annual basis in the People's Republic of China;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAD7F3C30E6A441369B0C4BD1D4670671" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of known or estimated voluntary organ donors in the People's Republic of China;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H619FE32D37334984BE70079FE06F9447" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an assessment of the sources of organs for transplant in the People's Republic of China; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAC22B7558B52499CB15AF93570AC3BDA" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an assessment of the time, in days, that it takes to procure an organ for transplant within the Chinese medical system and an assessment of whether such timetable is possible based on the number of known or estimated organ donors in the People's Republic of China;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB2CC1A7B9EC84C2AB71A60B1E639BA3C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a list of all United States grants during the 10 years before the date of the enactment of this Act that have supported research on organ transplantation in the People's Republic of China or in collaboration between a Chinese entity and a United States entity; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBD92BCD4A25C4534A721526A950E8B40"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a determination as to whether the persecution of Falun Gong practitioners within the People’s Republic of China constitutes an <quote>atrocity</quote> (as such term is defined in section 6 of the Elie Wiesel Genocide and Atrocities Prevention Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/441">Public Law 115–441</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2656">22 U.S.C. 2656</external-xref> note)).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H58979352E8454F30BC0EBAB5AA1D0BFD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required under subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</text></subsection></section><section id="H6CD7F415108E4DCBBD50DDE42F462DEB"><enum>5.</enum><header>Exception relating to importation of goods</header><subsection id="HA176002C7F834E21978FE5EF0F97E2E7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The authorities and requirements to impose sanctions authorized under this Act shall not include the authority or requirement to impose sanctions on the importation of goods.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB62712C96C3A4123999341F46D400BB1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Good defined</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>good</quote> means any article, natural or man-made substance, material, supply or manufactured product, including inspection and test equipment, and excluding technical data.</text></subsection></section><section id="H1C513E8E29CE457BBFAD00754A3EFB3D"><enum>6.</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means—</text><paragraph id="HFAF675A6A7164133B35883F747F61302"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFF362AEA98C742868DE81150EE72F103"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

