<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MIR25617-XRX-DG-HJ0">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2148 IS: End Junk Fees for Renters Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>II</distribution-code>
        <congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session>1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. 2148</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action>
            <action-date date="20250624">June 24, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S313">Mr. Sanders</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was
                read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on
                    Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title>To prohibit owners of covered dwelling units from assessing or collecting
            certain fees from tenants, and for other purposes.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H50D2A2C6E8854226B6815C4AC8D45A9E">
        <section section-type="section-one" id="H90650E01D5F8467BAE35A5FEA3CBB186">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>End Junk Fees for Renters Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc0cd19c720664cba88d2c2cb4d123ab6">
            <enum>2.</enum>
            <header>Definitions</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H4A7FFCF39CD943C79DB1363272398AE4"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>Appropriate regulator</header> <text>The term <term>appropriate regulator</term> means—</text>
                <subparagraph id="HF208C357BFA44347B1E2AFE5B51C11BC">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, with respect to covered dwelling units described in—</text>
                    <clause id="HC234933DA1394C55A2C0E60472BFE7F9">
                        <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>paragraph (2)(A);</text> </clause> <clause id="H64F1A27D81FD45A78ABEB71B3737F9E1"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>paragraph (2)(B), to the extent the Federally backed mortgage loan referred to in such paragraph is described in subparagraph (A), (B), or (C) of paragraph (3); or</text>
                    </clause>
                    <clause id="H07B03B20F80D4B9AA89E6B96F033D68B">
                        <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">paragraph (2)(B), to the extent the Federally backed mortgage loan referred to in such paragraph is described in paragraph (4) and is made in whole or in part, or insured, guaranteed, supplemented, or assisted in any way under or in connection with a housing or urban development program administered by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development;</text>
                    </clause>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H3D3E4B20651D463FB987D8E5A7164BCE">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, with respect to covered dwelling units described in paragraph (2)(B), to the extent the Federally backed mortgage loan referred to in such paragraph is described in—</text>
                    <clause id="H8E1FD86717954B73A2F8977DFF1584F9">
                        <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">paragraph (3)(D); or</text> </clause> <clause id="HA8BE06AF6C2F455AB53B17EA18C65177"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">paragraph (4) and is made in whole or in part, or insured, guaranteed, supplemented, or assisted in any way, by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs or under or in connection with a housing or related program administered by Secretary of Veterans Affairs;</text>
                    </clause>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBDAE856B02D14D2491EE41D2E5883D21">
                    <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary of Agriculture, with respect to covered dwelling units described in paragraph (2)(B), to the extent the Federally backed mortgage loan referred to in such paragraph is described in—</text>
                    <clause id="HD8104B403E304779A8DD6F3BAA7BB372">
                        <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">subparagraph (E) or (F) of paragraph (3); or</text>
                    </clause>
                    <clause id="H1029682710484B08B1BB1A327C826AFE">
                        <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">paragraph (4) and is made in whole or in part, or insured, guaranteed, supplemented, or assisted in any way, by the Secretary of Agriculture or under or in connection with a housing or related program administered by Secretary of Agriculture; and</text>
                    </clause>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6752C72AF5244F92A7BD06A2F50FACE5">
                    <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Director of the Federal Housing Finance Agency, with respect to covered dwelling units described in paragraph (2)(B), to the extent the Federally backed mortgage loan referred to in such paragraph is described in—</text>
                    <clause id="HFE37131E9BEC42D9882F4D2311FBDB78">
                        <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">paragraph (3)(G); or</text> </clause> <clause id="HAEFDF6C657174A71B96778B3E08E7D41"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">paragraph (4) and is purchased or securitized by the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation or the Federal National Mortgage Association.</text>
                    </clause>
                </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H5D97AFA14B9F4A228A83B320C389EFF6">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <header>Covered dwelling unit</header>
 <text>The term <term>covered dwelling unit</term> means a dwelling unit that—</text> <subparagraph id="HBCC3D823C9004844BAB2A4A449E1C01F"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>is provided assistance within the jurisdiction of the Department, as defined in section 102(m) of the Department of Housing and Urban Development Reform Act of 1989 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3545">42 U.S.C. 3545(m)</external-xref>); or</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H0521B1EB044244C0AA87A5B17D6C293F">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is subject to, or is on or in a property that is subject to, a Federally backed single-family mortgage loan or a Federally backed multifamily mortgage loan.</text>
                </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H3D04139335E04CD898C04D21AA96672B">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
                <header>Federally backed single-family mortgage loan</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Federally backed single-family mortgage loan</term> includes any loan that is secured by a first or subordinate lien on residential real property (including individual units of condominiums and cooperatives) designed principally for the occupancy of from 1- to 4-families that is—</text>
                <subparagraph id="HD1A6B3AA72484E928DF70C69D38876FC">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>insured by the Federal Housing Administration under title II of the National Housing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1707">12 U.S.C. 1707 et seq.</external-xref>);</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="HB5F59A12AF6A447DBB2E44E8269729FF">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>insured under section 255 of the National Housing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1715z-20">12 U.S.C. 1715z–20</external-xref>);</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H3F2C1B9F790B4552B56488BA0CD98899">
                    <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>guaranteed under section 184 or 184A of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1992 (12 U.S.C. 1715z–13a, 1715z–13b);</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="HCBB9764FDA32481AB92C033E80BA217F">
                    <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>guaranteed or insured by the Department of Veterans Affairs;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCF971432F0434C968F61D12CF678F356"> <enum>(E)</enum> <text>guaranteed or insured by the Department of Agriculture;</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H2D38B6DF8F654B339B680C383F55E517">
                    <enum>(F)</enum>
 <text>made by the Department of Agriculture; or</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEB82E345D09843638432821A49C1A268"> <enum>(G)</enum> <text>purchased or securitized by the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation or the Federal National Mortgage Association.</text>
                </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HE4656B5A04934B1191424A8AAB7053A3">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
                <header>Federally backed multifamily mortgage loan</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Federally backed multifamily mortgage loan</term> includes any loan (other than temporary financing such as a construction loan) that—</text>
                <subparagraph id="HCDE8AF04536040C985AAC7C8BC22FA6F">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>is secured by a first or subordinate lien on residential multifamily real property designed principally for the occupancy of 5 or more families, including any such secured loan, the proceeds of which are used to prepay or pay off an existing loan secured by the same property; and</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H8E0944F2415948D5A91F4C090EC5AA2A">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>is made in whole or in part, or insured, guaranteed, supplemented, or assisted in any way, by any officer or agency of the Federal Government or under or in connection with a housing or urban development program administered by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development or a housing or related program administered by any other such officer or agency, or is purchased or securitized by the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation or the Federal National Mortgage Association.</text>
                </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H2BFA591CA9CD41ED8B1615978F95AD03" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline">
                <enum>(5)</enum>
                <header>Owner</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>owner</term> means, with respect to a dwelling unit, any private person or entity, including a cooperative, an agency of the Federal Government, or a public housing agency, having the legal right to lease or sublease the dwelling unit.</text>
            </paragraph>
        </section>
        <section id="HACDA4A2CE4144ACFBE074561F3362DB6">
            <enum>3.</enum>
            <header>Rental junk fees</header>
            <subsection id="HBE4A850BB1184E5E97C5DCD0FB73BB3F">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>Application fees</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The appropriate regulator shall prohibit the owner of a covered dwelling unit from assessing or collecting a fee or charge, from any household in connection with the submission of an application for rental of the dwelling unit.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="HF5C064C3BBDF49A7B477A44DA8153C85">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Tenant screening fees</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The appropriate regulator shall prohibit the owner of a covered dwelling unit from assessing to or collecting from any household applying to rent the dwelling unit any fee or charge for costs of conducting any criminal history, tenant screening, consumer report, or other background check of the household.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection commented="no" id="H889673825F3B49F7BA5B6F1423CB6530">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Late fees</header>
 <text>The appropriate regulator shall require that owners of covered dwelling units—</text>
                <paragraph id="H2B44EC75390347D1B8D34BF0025EA39A">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">only impose fees or charges on tenants in connection with the late payment of rent for a covered dwelling unit if the amount of the fee or charge is less than 3 percent of the monthly rent the tenant pays for the covered dwelling unit;</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H3A5229CAACD2412C99D8F7EE03FAD854">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">only impose fees or charges on tenants in connection with the late payment of rent for a covered dwelling unit if 15 days have elapsed since the date on which the rent was due; and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HB108885784E845559690A58BF6399A7C">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">disclose the requirements imposed under paragraphs (1) and (2) in any lease entered for a covered dwelling unit on or after the date on which rules are issued under section 4.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H6BDA0BB882854A699F0F68BDA57E1B0E">
                <enum>(d)</enum>
                <header>Required disclosures</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The appropriate regulator shall require each owner of a covered dwelling unit to disclose to the tenant before a lease is signed—</text>
                <paragraph id="H9C259B3C65284FA5A58F897F7B46585F">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the total amount due each month, including any fees;</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HC4EE2782BB4F46D08ACDC85CE6CC2986">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>to the degree practicable, a summary of any past litigation between the the owner and any former or current tenants;</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HB613A43B00D247A587352F1C90050DEF">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of any ongoing pest and maintenance issues; and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H302473FB5610497DA6DDDBDF421159CC">
                    <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the amount rent increase for the property in each of the 10 previous years.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
        </section>
        <section id="HF06B65C53CD84D039FF95786064ACFE6">
            <enum>4.</enum>
            <header>Rulemaking</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection and the Federal Trade Commission shall issue a rule that—</text>
            <paragraph id="H77B940881A3740D9913293DADA83BF86">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>defines the term <term>junk fee</term> with respect to rental housing; and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HCAD16C4644D34078BBBF008723BC7A90"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>finds the furnishing of any information about a unpaid junk fee (as such term is defined pursuant to paragraph (1)) to a consumer reporting agency to be a unfair or unconscionable means to collect or attempt to collect debt in violation of section 808 of the Fair Debt Collection Practices Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1692f">15 U.S.C. 1692f</external-xref>).</text>
            </paragraph>
        </section>
    </legis-body>
</bill>

