<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HFA4D5D663C61473B84E1B93EE14E9648" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5173 IH: No Social Media at School Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5173</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250908">September 8, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001119">Ms. Craig</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require social media companies to use geofencing to block access to their social media platforms on K–12 education campuses, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H65F416D4666D4AB0BB9E0B5F1ED2BFEA" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H3868B0CC7C304019B148CD30717EA0F3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No Social Media at School Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H19DFEC8029754E56B17760D3755B3A4B" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Requirement to block access to social media on K–12 education campuses</header> <subsection id="HE1AAC54B2122432E84641541F56A68D0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A social media company shall use geofencing to block access to their social media platform on a K–12 education campus during the regular school day (as determined by the local educational agency associated with such campus), except for any push notification that includes a weather alert, an amber alert, and other uses from emergency responders for public safety purposes.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H23AE7AC960BF4E46A68021873AEF7E51" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Protections for privacy</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to require—</text> <paragraph id="H8C4C8B9A63684B29978457CB776B5FC4" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the affirmative collection of any personal data with respect to the age of users by a social media company that the company is not already collecting in the normal course of business; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDD6C7A94A77946C5A13EB31CF24021C2" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a social media company to implement an age gating or age verification functionality.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H4137347FF9C3414CACE1716B95E3C6CD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Enforcement</header> <paragraph id="H83D9991B9AF947A0880FAE45766889C4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Enforcement by Federal Trade Commission</header> <subparagraph id="H2BBFF5965C774ACA9974CEF0644E0F29"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Unfair and deceptive acts or practices</header><text>A violation of this section shall be treated as a violation of a rule defining an unfair or deceptive act or practice prescribed under section 18(a)(1)(B) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/57a">15 U.S.C. 57a(a)(1)(B)</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H126ADDB602604ADEA18D3356A9E513EE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Powers of the commission</header> 
<clause id="HD41982FF3130418CA07E3405C3F35EC7"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Federal Trade Commission shall enforce this section in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though all applicable terms and provisions of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>) were incorporated into and made a part of this section.</text></clause> <clause id="H626196DD945F4AF59EA7BA3A53BABAC1"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Privileges and immunities</header><text>Any person that violates this section shall be subject to the penalties, and entitled to the privileges and immunities, provided in the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H781BC2FA1604407AA621D3A82F838284"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Authority preserved</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit the authority of the Commission under any other provision of law.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="H80A217250C9E4532AB206A012D88706A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Enforcement by state attorneys general</header> <paragraph id="H6CB3F570932946E4AC9A104B526FB023"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header> <subparagraph id="H940E00EE43CF4CDABB0CF37989B42E1C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Civil actions</header><text>In any case in which the attorney general of a State has reason to believe that a covered platform has violated or is violating this section, the State, as parens patriae, may bring a civil action on behalf of the residents of the State in a district court of the United States or a State court of appropriate jurisdiction to—</text> 
<clause id="H67B9A2F93BE945A48976510F3CA3C75E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>enjoin any practice that violates subsection (a);</text></clause> <clause id="HA5AA81D530684CB98925963E20E56757"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">enforce compliance with subsection (a);</text></clause> 
<clause id="HC5883A3F3D9E4CCBA014D8935BA6BAC7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>on behalf of residents of the State, obtain damages, restitution, or other compensation, each of which shall be distributed in accordance with State law; or</text></clause> <clause id="H08CC05EA893E4DE48865598DF110A75E"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>obtain such other relief as the court may consider to be appropriate.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H36F871236C334803A49483EF2C09F674"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Notice</header> 
<clause id="H8FF04BC521864EDE98D578E4E7F90B70"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Before filing an action under subparagraph (A), the attorney general of the State involved shall provide to the Commission—</text> <subclause id="H1288626C43374908A0F044C82C711A55"><enum>(I)</enum><text>written notice of that action; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H4093B8A9B1F947749E5B9962FF1B1B7F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a copy of the complaint for that action.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H966FE94926B643FC9D4FA1565ADB6215"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Exemption</header> <subclause id="H917ACD8C82554482A2A3CD95016D7F54"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Clause (i) shall not apply with respect to the filing of an action by an attorney general of a State under this paragraph if the attorney general of the State determines that it is not feasible to provide the notice described in that clause before the filing of the action.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H2E2333C553B54B0384231BA2181BF7C6"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Notification</header><text>In an action described in subclause (I), the attorney general of a State shall provide notice and a copy of the complaint to the Commission at the same time as the attorney general files the action.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0EB4E556722246A8B05C0313255451EE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Intervention</header> <subparagraph id="H8DEA1ED7AA7A43FCB5EAEAE1F70C893C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>On receiving notice under paragraph (1)(B), the Commission shall have the right to intervene in the action that is the subject of the notice.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC31561B34D014618B61286C718518FB8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Effect of intervention</header><text>If the Commission intervenes in an action under paragraph (1), the Commission shall have the right—</text> <clause id="HBFA63A72885D48A99891EBF3C53FBC2F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to remove the action to the appropriate United States district court;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H3698E4D7F3CF4BC08497F1C3B5BF3B5B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to be heard with respect to any matter that arises in that action; and</text></clause> <clause id="H4083FDA39C284CDBAE76A04224DD2AF2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to file a petition for appeal.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDCAF3FB343D14C76838FA70BA8C0D6E8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Construction</header><text>For purposes of bringing any civil action under paragraph (1), nothing in this section shall be construed to prevent an attorney general of a State from exercising the powers conferred on the attorney general by the laws of that State to—</text> <subparagraph id="HCC4C12E434CA438BB044B01C3836CCB2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>conduct investigations;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBC1D57BDDF3D4486B868056B8E21F6D2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>administer oaths or affirmations; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H695875A21B914D88955A8318B9CB4ECD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>compel the attendance of witnesses or the production of documentary and other evidence.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3512B043C86E4EB097B6BDC7F474B90B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Actions by the commission</header><text>In any case in which an action is instituted by or on behalf of the Commission for violation of this section, no State may, during the pendency of that action, institute a separate action under paragraph (1) against any defendant named in the complaint in the action instituted by or on behalf of the Commission for that violation.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5AB3706A97414F8B8FBC25D6B7D6909F"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Venue; service of process</header> <subparagraph id="HD00F66A2485A4283B7AC353A402A8834"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Venue</header><text>Any action brought under paragraph (1) may be brought in—</text> 
<clause id="HB2EBF017B5C148BD9565FA65FABD42C8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the district court of the United States that meets applicable requirements relating to venue under section 1391 of title 28, United States Code; or</text></clause> <clause id="HBD2F2F7CAC0940CD8D0F9E58A9F2C059"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a State court of competent jurisdiction.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9BC188870C764036976D2F1BD1CAE938"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Service of process</header><text>In an action brought under paragraph (1) in a district court of the United States, process may be served wherever defendant—</text> <clause id="H0C9C4E9D3A1D42FE921AEC17EB4FF95C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is an inhabitant; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="HCEDEEE645E73456595FA70570A3059E2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>may be found.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="H2940ABC8A26B4F4FB8610EFB114AAC8C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="HAD1E9FE54C0446C1826BC60B639AAC71"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Federal Trade Commission.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HCF5CC82B81F8462FBB08A13FDE30E4E9" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Geofencing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>geofencing</term> means a virtual boundary maintained by a social media platform.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H25C14CA393BC481B8A9DBFF002217132" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>K–12 education</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>K–12 education</term> means an elementary school or secondary school (as such terms are defined in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>)).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9B5BB81C1D474171949DA494D0D1C9A9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Local educational agency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>local educational agency</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0462685423AB43F78C6FE3617CD61B7F"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Social media company</header><text>The term <term>social media company</term>—</text> <subparagraph id="HB60C8B26AB4047D7A108BAC1C2B8E0E8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means a company that runs a social media platform; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6296FA26080742FDA5F4FD14212EA2BC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include—</text> <clause id="H359EB0096D3C47F78ABDB01A3013D632"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an organization not organized to carry on business for its own profit or that of its members; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H915B2AF89942477585F676DEC3220322" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an educational agency or institution (as defined in section 444 of the General Education Provisions Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1232g">20 U.S.C. 1232g(a)(3)</external-xref>)).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H403493EBF63C40DE9F65BBD56766AA3B"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Social medial platform</header> <subparagraph id="H691D2D3B9735492090AE3E74AB4FEB99"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>social media platform</term> means a public-facing website, online service, online application, or mobile application that—</text> 
<clause id="HABC7C35561644EE9935843360C486FF8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is directed to consumers;</text></clause> <clause id="H3D26C19B310241F8AB581570ED9174DA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>collects personal data;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H8D91A1DBD5C8428C8B2B229AD95CB0F4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>primarily derives revenue from advertising or the sale of personal data; and</text></clause> <clause id="H2AFA25222A3D4F1B81210F5E521AC37D"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>as the primary function provides a community forum for user-generated content, including messages, videos, and audio files among users where such content is primarily intended for viewing, resharing, or platform-enabled distributed social endorsement or comment.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3DAFFB5F21E1453DB83630026EB5B971" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The term <term>social medial platform</term> does not include a platform that, as the primary function for consumers, provides or facilitates any of the following:</text> <clause id="HF291D0B00DDD48B997D144660C9AA1C7" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The purchase and sale of commercial goods.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H61D983DC001948E79623F099B9F16F65" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Teleconferencing or videoconferencing services that allow reception and transmission of audio or video signals for real-time communication, provided that the real-time communication is initiated by using a unique link or identifier to facilitate access.</text></clause> <clause id="H52D6367D508E4598BE47BA53AE5929E6" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Crowd-sourced reference guides such as encyclopedias and dictionaries.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HE8E6FC004BD242A3B8A220D13F6ACDCA" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Cloud storage, file sharing, or file collaboration services, including such services that allow collaborative editing by invited users.</text></clause> <clause id="HEA8EE505518D4FC2A1471465E744F214" commented="no"><enum>(v)</enum><text>The playing or creation of video games.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HDED83633D07E492C809C2D8586DE266C" commented="no"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Content that consists primarily of news, sports, sports coverage, entertainment, or other information or content that is not user-generated but is preselected by the platform and for which any chat, comment, or interactive functionality is incidental, directly related to, or dependent on the provision of the content provided by the platform.</text></clause> <clause id="HC50DB919AFC74761B308D85D9E40E2E9" commented="no"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>Business, product, or travel information including user reviews or rankings of such businesses, products, or other travel information.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H7845DE11FF2845228C5058E2C806574E" commented="no"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>Educational information, experiences, training, or instruction provided to build knowledge, skills, or a craft, district-sanctioned or school-sanctioned learning management systems and school information systems for the purposes of schools conveying content related to the education of students, or services or services on behalf of or in support of an elementary school or secondary school, as such terms are defined in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text></clause> <clause id="HFEFD6776234E4953BC8F00045773EEB5" commented="no"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>An email service.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H56E196A293A04C049684EF211B670B8D" commented="no"><enum>(x)</enum><text>A wireless messaging service, including such a service provided through short message service or multimedia messaging protocols, that is not a component of, or linked to, a social media platform and where the predominant or exclusive function of the messaging service is direct messaging consisting of the transmission of text, photos, or videos that are sent by electronic means, where messages are transmitted from the sender to the recipient and are not posted publicly or within a social media platform.</text></clause> <clause id="H74B4F44E749C482E954B9E32C3D09F38" commented="no"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>A broadband internet access service (as such term is defined for purposes of section 8.1(b) of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor regulation).</text></clause> 
<clause id="H941ECF25BCD349798B7F45687A6C7821" commented="no"><enum>(xii)</enum><text>A virtual private network or similar service that exists solely to route internet traffic between locations.</text></clause></subparagraph> </paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

