<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" slc-id="S1-HLA25655-2Y1-HH-2HC"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 369 ATS: Designating August 21, 2025, as “Fentanyl Prevention and Awareness Day”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 369</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250802">August 2, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S153">Mr. Grassley</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Designating August 21, 2025, as <quote>Fentanyl Prevention and Awareness Day</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas families in the United States affected by the use of illicit fentanyl use Fentanyl Prevention and Awareness Day—</text><paragraph id="id2c6ac82f02ce40a6be7b913c3b1a2e3d"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to preserve the memory of individuals lost to illicit fentanyl overdose or poisoning who were unsuspecting victims, experimenting with the drug, or suffering from substance use disorder;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id328db61cc4554f3083b98a2bb7398bc1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to acknowledge the devastation caused by the use of illicit fentanyl and other dangerous drugs; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc71d594bcde44bc99c97a7c16447ef32"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to increase awareness about the dangers of the use of illicit fentanyl to prevent a public health crisis, self-harm, addiction, and death;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Fentanyl Prevention and Awareness Day is celebrated each year on August 21 by State governors and attorneys general, the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, parent-teacher associations, the High Intensity Drug Trafficking Areas program, the Office of National Drug Control Policy, the Drug Enforcement Administration (referred to in this preamble as the <quote>DEA</quote>), and hundreds of other organizations throughout the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas fentanyl is a highly addictive synthetic opioid that is 100 times more potent than morphine;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to the DEA, illicit fentanyl is—</text><paragraph id="iddb105f1ac9d3458da76570d503763af3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">manufactured with other illicit drugs to increase potency;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida2999c1e36d743abbf3cdafc0af2db03"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">sold as a powder or mixed with other illicit drugs; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb484d1552d764e66930950242556f4e3"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">pressed into counterfeit pills to look like a legitimate pharmaceutical drug;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the illicit fentanyl crisis in the United States is a serious public safety threat;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the illicit fentanyl poisoning rate in 2024 was among the highest in the history of the United States, and fentanyl poisoning was the number one cause of death among citizens of the United States aged 18 to 45;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas synthetic opioids, primarily fentanyl and the analogues of fentanyl, are devastating communities and families at an unprecedented rate, claiming <fraction>2/3</fraction> of the more than 82,100 lives lost to drug overdoses in 2024;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas, in 2024, the number of drug-related deaths throughout the United States reached at least 82,138;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas individuals increasingly use pills or other drugs without knowing those substances contain fentanyl;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, as of June 2025, U.S. Customs and Border Protection personnel have seized more than 9,200 pounds of illicit fentanyl, and Federal, State, local, and Tribal law enforcement agencies continue to make record-breaking seizures of illicit fentanyl to ensure the safety of the people of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas families in the United States affected by the use of illicit fentanyl have gained momentum in educating the public about the dangers of the use of illicit fentanyl and other drugs and actively engage with Federal agencies to promote such education and awareness;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas families in the United States affected by the use of illicit fentanyl seek to raise awareness of the use of illicit fentanyl, prevent illicit fentanyl-related deaths, and join together in the effort to save lives on Fentanyl Prevention and Awareness Day; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas parents, young people, schools, businesses, law enforcement agencies, religious institutions and faith-based organizations, service organizations, senior citizens, medical and military personnel, sports teams, and individuals throughout the United States will demonstrate a commitment to healthy, productive, and drug-free lifestyles on Fentanyl Prevention and Awareness Day: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="S1"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="idf99a87e15ef24be39c27abe212d194b5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>designates August 21, 2025, as <quote>Fentanyl Prevention and Awareness Day</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id97c52473092a4887b1be5edd68180a62"><enum>(2)</enum><text>encourages the people of the United States to promote prevention of the use of illicit fentanyl and to educate young people on Fentanyl Prevention and Awareness Day, symbolizing a commitment to a healthy, drug-free lifestyle;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id33edad5b239b4967805b6b9599faafcb"><enum>(3)</enum><text>encourages children, teenagers, and other individuals to choose to live drug-free lives; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id630146267fa046de982fd5f4b4bbcd1d"><enum>(4)</enum><text>encourages the people of the United States—</text><subparagraph id="id21e018502d11465fbbf99a1a8b67f027"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to promote drug prevention and the creation of drug-free communities; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc57c44c8ba5241af9d56f8fe695e1339"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to participate in drug prevention activities to show support for healthy, productive, and drug-free lifestyles. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

