<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF85A3EFD5C37444DB8E696DB904AD586" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 233 IH: Supporting the designation of April 2025 as “National Native Plant Month”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 233</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250321">March 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001055">Mr. Case</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="N000191">Mr. Neguse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000295">Mr. Joyce of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001200">Mr. Soto</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001219">Mr. Moylan</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Supporting the designation of April 2025 as <quote>National Native Plant Month</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas native plants are indigenous species that have evolved alongside native wildlife and occur naturally in a particular geographic region, ecosystem, and habitat;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas there are more than 17,000 native plant species in the United States, which include large shade trees, understory trees, shrubs, perennials, vines, grasses, and wildflowers;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas native plants are essential for healthy, diverse, and sustainable ecosystems and are critical for cleaning air, filtering water, and stabilizing soils;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas native plants are well-adapted to specific soils, temperatures, precipitation, and environmental conditions, making them the best option for conserving and protecting our environment, and adapting to its changes;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas native plants provide shelter, as well as nectar, pollen, seeds, and foliage that serve as food for native butterflies, caterpillars, birds, bees, and other wildlife in ways that non-native plants cannot;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas more than 200 of the native plant species in the United States are estimated to have been lost since the early 19th century;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas habitat loss and degradation, extreme weather events, and invasive species have contributed to the decline of native plants in the United States; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas native plants are essential components of resilient ecosystems and our natural heritage: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H2A64DBDC2CF0447B84FF536B39F5000A"> 
<section id="H9785312487084A60ADE347CE8B7581E2" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="H5F3A1E56C7D2469B9DEA81CB6A278B55"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supports the designation of <quote>National Native Plant Month</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0CED40B33C7B46C881777C86F08883F5"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recognizes the benefits of native plants to the environment and the economy of the United States.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

