<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4FD2CF037E8F4E13A6377658785D0061" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4618 IH: Jamie Reed Protecting Our Kids from Child Abuse Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4618</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250722">July 22, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001214">Mr. Steube</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001211">Mrs. Miller of Illinois</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and Workforce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a Federal tort against pediatric gender clinics and other entities pushing gender-transition procedures that cause bodily injury to children or harm the mental health of children.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H3E5F3628E6344E368E953CAF85D7211D" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H1DCEA5B14191425583E86B6A7BE6B705"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Jamie Reed Protecting Our Kids from Child Abuse Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H4CD5CAFB853346CC807271F57DA9C3F5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Federal tort for harm to children caused by gender-transition procedures</header> <subsection id="H60BFCCA5811547938D2BC1F7DAA36667"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text>
<paragraph id="H70DC85A097E7491B988FF0F57D1E465B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Gender transition procedure</header>
<subparagraph id="HB9915040262D43B8A596ACC9E4E717AC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the term <term>gender-transition procedure</term> means—</text> <clause id="H83170A9258A244DB8C32102E86EDF331"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the prescription or administration of gonadotropin-releasing hormone agonists or any other puberty-blocking drugs for the purpose of changing the body of an individual so that it conforms to the subjective sense of identity of the individual, in the case such identity is at odds with the individual's biological sex of male or female;</text></clause>
<clause id="HF79EB1CCAB6348E682A7404EF96B9BD3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the prescription or administration of testosterone (when prescribed to a female) or estrogen (when prescribed to a male) for the purpose of changing the body of an individual so that it conforms to the subjective sense of identity of the individual, in the case such identity is at odds with the individual’s biological sex of male or female; or</text></clause> <clause id="H34F997CC97B34269A243E37E9033AFD6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a surgery to change the body of an individual so that it conforms to the subjective sense of identity of the individual, in the case such identity is at odds with the individual’s biological sex of male or female.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE5F1CA089E714FEAB6355D95355A4120"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The term <term>gender-transition procedure</term> does not include—</text> <clause id="HE367CBBABD9349F39BF686663E500CC1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an intervention described in subparagraph (A) that is performed on—</text>
<subclause id="HB90D0589A5AC4BF5B31A9D98BBDBA005"><enum>(I)</enum><text>an individual with biological sex characteristics that are inherently ambiguous, such as those born with 46 XX chromosomes with virilization, 46 XY chromosomes with undervirilization, or having both ovarian and testicular tissue; or</text></subclause> <subclause id="H9EC4AC3717EB4C7BA270DCFC38D29F14"><enum>(II)</enum><text>an individual with respect to whom a physician has determined through genetic or biochemical testing that the individual does not have normal sex chromosome structure, sex steroid hormone production, or sex steroid hormone action, for a biological male or biological female;</text></subclause></clause>
<clause id="HD3EE33B02CDB473B8D1A36861DFFF2B8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the treatment of any infection, injury, disease, or disorder that has been caused or exacerbated by the performance of an intervention described in subparagraph (A) without regard to whether the intervention was performed in accordance with State or Federal law or whether the intervention is covered by the private right of action under subsection (c); or</text></clause> <clause id="H3C24AB8697E54E5DB8A14D74ABC456C4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any procedure undertaken because the individual suffers from a physical disorder, physical injury, or physical illness that would, as certified by a physician, place the individual in imminent danger of death or impairment of major bodily function unless the procedure is performed.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H3610771604194B7F90DBD04FF0249863"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Hospital</header><text>The term <term>hospital</term> has the meaning given such term in section 1861(e) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x(e)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H166DA55D5D72434F9066444B8FAD4824"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text>The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given such term in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8FF1D4FD10BE48329D020E6C4EAF9449"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Medical practitioner</header><text>The term <term>medical practitioner</term> means a person who is licensed, certified, or otherwise authorized by the laws of a State to administer health care in the ordinary course of the practice of the person’s profession.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H76D29B813F2149A7981D0C7757082BC2"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Minor</header><text>The term <term>minor</term> means an individual who has not yet reached 18 years of age.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H92A44B6851CC402B8A0CD9C177401181"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Pediatric gender clinic</header><text>The term <term>pediatric gender clinic</term> means a medical facility that specializes in the diagnosis or treatment of gender discordance and gender dysphoria in minors, including medical interventions such as therapeutic diagnosis of gender dysphoria and performance of (or referral for) gender-transition procedures on minors.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HEFC7C125C14445B3892F0609BDEEB6B2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Liability</header><text>The following individuals and entities shall be liable in accordance with this section to any individual who suffers bodily injury or harm to mental health (including any physical, psychological, emotional, or physiological harm) that is attributable, in whole or in part, to a gender-transition procedure performed on the individual when the individual was a minor:</text>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB7A12D22BC6D4A678652A180E60B40B7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A pediatric gender clinic where the gender-transition procedure was provided.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4101B642CA684DE094A7B4E61D7B35C8"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any medical practitioner who administered health care, at the time of the particular procedure, at the pediatric gender clinic where the gender-transition procedure was provided.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H086F323D19334C0FA602D8423428BA41"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An institution of higher education that hosts, operates, partners with, provides funding to, or is otherwise affiliated with the pediatric gender clinic where the gender-transition procedure was provided.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3C0A766D37CA467D892D77979D1DF00E"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A hospital that hosts, operates, partners with, provides funding to, or is otherwise affiliated with the pediatric gender clinic where the gender-transition procedure was provided.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC7903F677F474D5296C7F21DAEE93AA0"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any medical practitioner who performed the gender-transition procedure on the individual.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H77DE3FC15AE04C01947322F65C1BCF74"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Private right of action</header><text>An individual who suffers bodily injury or harm to mental health that is attributable, in whole or in part, to a gender-transition procedure provided to the individual when the individual was a minor may, not later than 30 years after the date on which the individual turns 18 years of age, bring a civil action against an individual or entity described in subsection (b), in an appropriate district court of the United States or a State court of competent jurisdiction for—</text>
<paragraph id="H1ADAE75557944AECBCE7375A76A8075C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>compensatory damages;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC4741933624A48B4B81921C7E0DE4CE0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>punitive damages; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF180502C23DC4D4A84398E617C760823"><enum>(3)</enum><text>attorney’s fees and costs.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H8181EB4035C3413E9DB391ADE9688FF2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Affirmative defense</header><text>It shall be an affirmative defense to an action brought by or on behalf of an individual upon whom a gender-transition procedure was performed under subsection (c) that the pediatric gender clinic or medical practitioner who performed the gender-transition procedure on the individual, at all relevant times, did not know and had no reason to know that the individual in question was a minor.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="HFB9CF09D8D2C486FA501B9E6EEF282F5"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibition on funding</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No Federal funds may be made available—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5F495F2B0BDA40CF8EF94EF31282666C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to a pediatric gender clinic;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7F17D10D32FA4782A76A74F5166E0909"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to an institution of higher education or hospital that hosts, operates, partners with, provides funding to, or is otherwise affiliated with, a pediatric gender clinic; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H14C2A82E1B61460598D04DDB0A6ED676"><enum>(3)</enum><text>for any gender-transition procedure performed on a minor.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="HE9B9A299A88E4FF28F814C064A3BFBE2"><enum>4.</enum><header>Effective date and retroactive application</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act shall—</text> <paragraph id="H4E2426E597204EDBACCDF6640B706331"><enum>(1)</enum><text>take effect on the date of enactment of this Act; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9951FBA2F886496BA6BA196561C0227B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>apply to any gender-transition procedure that took place before, on, or after the effective date under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8DFF219DE8A54322A350F1C0BEB52821"><enum>5.</enum><header>Severability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any provision of this Act, or the application of such provision to any person or circumstance, is held to be unconstitutional, the remainder of this Act, and the application of the remaining provisions of this Act, to any person or circumstance, shall not be affected.</text></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

