<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="H412C7FE289AA4FA6B68256BE18316390"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4838 IH: Establishing Responsibility for Illegals’ Crimes and Adding Deterrence and Accountability for Mayors’ Sanctuary Cities Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4838</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250801">August 1, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish criminal liability for mayors of sanctuary cities in cases of murder committed by undocumented immigrants within their jurisdiction, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H4143F5E63CF64BF49B430C483A26282F"><section id="H044BD82829A6412FB2727EEBD661F96D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Establishing Responsibility for Illegals’ Crimes and Adding Deterrence and Accountability for Mayors’ Sanctuary Cities Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>ERIC ADAMS Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H4C1E870B2F544367BFFD63587FEFA579"><enum>2.</enum><header>Criminal liability for mayors of sanctuary cities</header><subsection id="H17C1047173104665A982A1E272E25A6A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/51">Chapter 51</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/1112">section 1112</external-xref> the following new section:</text></subsection></section><section id="HACC5A617E59746DA91CCD0CB79B94127"><enum>1112A.</enum><header>Criminal liability for mayors of sanctuary cities</header><paragraph id="H4D8627C86A9C425AAFDC62D6A5031028"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Offense</header><text>A mayor of a sanctuary city shall be guilty of criminal negligence resulting in manslaughter if—</text><subparagraph id="H9A739892E744470080E99E1FDCF3363B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an undocumented immigrant commits murder, as defined under applicable State or Federal law, within the jurisdiction of the sanctuary city; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8023570D7891422EA0074F9FA7D4006F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the mayor knowingly adopted, maintained, or failed to repeal a sanctuary policy that materially restricted cooperation with Federal immigration enforcement, and such policy directly and foreseeably contributed to the failure to detain or remove the undocumented immigrant prior to the commission of the murder.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9FFB9D4B08234AEE94B5733A60E94BE3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Penalty</header><text>A mayor convicted under this section shall be subject to—</text><subparagraph id="id460e1bed699548009480c408f5061fe3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>imprisonment for not more than 7 years, a fine under title 18, or both; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id94f8e5a31a0940ff84809cbb252a2a61"><enum>(B)</enum><text>mandatory removal or disqualification from public office upon conviction.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCA89CC16B6164E329397E690FD856E00"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Causation</header><text>For the purposes of this section, a sanctuary policy shall be deemed to have <quote>directly and foreseeably contributed</quote> if it created a substantial risk that an undocumented immigrant who committed murder could avoid detention or removal.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H2A07D95AC2184092A10DC3EEECDED23C"><enum>3.</enum><header>Enforcement</header><subsection id="H03FF130D66AD41A49EFC9FB8B1A932A9"><enum>(a)</enum><text>The Attorney General shall have exclusive authority to investigate and prosecute offenses under this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF5BFE7FBC001477B96146EEC078C3352"><enum>(b)</enum><text>The United States District Courts shall have original jurisdiction over any criminal proceeding arising under this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5F770CEB75354CE09792CD9F269078CF"><enum>(c)</enum><text>Federal courts shall have jurisdiction over cases brought under this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="H0024E0606F1C4DE594AD47864CA1819A"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For the purposes of this Act:</text><paragraph id="HFB3E1AF9FD314765A4F3C112CA5BC199"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Sanctuary city means any political subdivision of a State that, by law, ordinance, policy, or practice, prohibits or substantially restricts local law enforcement or municipal agencies from—</text><subparagraph id="HE2896AB5E44246088FB47A391670905D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>cooperating with or providing information to Federal immigration enforcement authorities; or.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H84F921E3B7F2442DA2AA490A1BBDE686"><enum>(B)</enum><text>complying with lawful detainer requests or administrative warrants issued by U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB64A24ADEBDA49859AC1CFA9E5828272"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Undocumented immigrant means any person who is present in the United States without lawful immigration status as defined by 8 U.S.C. § 1101 et seq.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2DE5C95939A8409FAA38FF991FC6BB89"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Mayor means the chief executive officer of a municipal government, whether elected or appointed.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H4E06342490DD43E2893F78794C7293BC"><enum>5.</enum><header>Severability</header><subsection id="H8A53D00441114A238CE242FDC6A60268"><enum>(a)</enum><text>If any provision of this Act, or the application thereof to any person or circumstance, is held invalid, the remainder of the Act, and the application of such provision to other persons or circumstances, shall not be affected thereby.</text></subsection></section><section id="H7D1FAE83CC324D4C80082005B1F14295"><enum>6.</enum><header>Effective date</header><subsection id="H25ADDD383E1B4FBA8C7BA4CBA5A06914"><enum>(a)</enum><text>This Act shall take effect 90 days after the date of its enactment.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

