<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H61E8D72BD9C74AEB8409F65EF2A320ED" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4560 IH: Building Resilient Infrastructure and Communities for All Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4560</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250721">July 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000481">Mr. Figures</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="E000246">Mr. Edwards</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to provide requirements relating to the funding of predisaster hazard mitigation, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8DCD39C500BB404497CEAE9742FDBFCA" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H816909F92AD94C6FA81007DE88759255" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Building Resilient Infrastructure and Communities for All Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="HB96F3ABA1CAB42F6B01035FEADAC9887"><enum>2.</enum><header>Predisaster hazard mitigation</header> <subsection id="HE86E359B711E43BDBE63330BB4D5DA55"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 203 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5133">42 U.S.C. 5133</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HC251C629C4EB45E6941B800970226DF5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (c) by striking <quote>or local government</quote> in each place it appears;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HF5F5D673974B4775830B1308803F0CF2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (d)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HDA2779BE3BE14AEDBA157E5FEDFC5655"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text> <clause id="HAB826AF2315E4AECA4620D253BAF5415"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A) by striking <quote>not fewer than five local governments to receive assistance under this section</quote> and inserting <quote>projects to receive assistance under this section that are cost-effective and designed to reduce injuries, loss of life, and damage and destruction of property, including damage to critical services and facilities</quote>; and</text> </clause> 
<clause id="H5B06A793AD634FF8BAD8F58000CC4567"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (C);</text> </clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD0E58D0F0CB948F38355235359377188"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text> 
<clause id="HE413E3A136D448C5AA832AB29BD065AE">
                            <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>in subparagraph (A) by striking <quote>in providing assistance to local governments under this section, the President shall select from local governments recommended by the Governors under this subsection.</quote> and inserting <quote>a State that receives funds under this section may use such funds only for projects recommended under paragraph (1)(A)</quote>; and</text>
                        </clause> 
<clause id="H84037F4488F0439598C435E1E2846F98"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (B) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HCA35DC55299B4ED8B6D0C08330F1667A" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subparagraph id="H02F0F556436146618165A39FFEDD0B8E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Presidential approval</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may approve a project that has not been recommended by a Governor under this subsection as an eligible use of funds if the President determines that extraordinary circumstances justify the selection and that making the selection will further the purpose of this section. </text> </subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD0484206C6334B75A7A18DF978F8FDF7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (3) by striking <quote>the President may select, subject to the criteria specified in subsection (g), any local governments of the State to receive assistance under this section.</quote> and inserting <quote>such State may not receive funds under the formula described in subsection (f)(2).</quote>;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8D55E26598084C6AB4F8523F3D9E0AA5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (f)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HCE462F818960491CA15DC4A29A7F927A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text> <clause id="HDDF93FA589D3444BA83485EF53C3CAC6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>on a competitive basis</quote> and inserting <quote>to a State or an Indian tribal government through a direct allocation based on the formula described in paragraph (2)</quote>; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HB6C1147D1F20450CBEEFB6068041E4B0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>and in accordance with the criteria in subsection (g)</quote>;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3EB20174266240E4A8AB9213FCC88CAD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (2) and inserting the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H6817F210C1CA4F949B75A2E6F9557CBF" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="H6CBA503D0B244153B1564EB8EFC2662A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Formula</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In providing financial assistance under this section, the President shall distribute to each eligible State available funds for a fiscal year using the following formula:</text> <subparagraph id="H34751629E98E4DFCB286941B70DF4FCB"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Thirty-three percent of available funds shall be distributed equally among each eligible State.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4E1C70E4461F400EBCDB0D2274E8B9DC"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Thirty-three percent of available funds shall be distributed among each eligible State in a proportion that gives preference to such States that have a higher population, using data from the most recent census of the United States.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7AAED5E720A1466FA3416EE64C19F217"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Thirty-three percent of available funds shall be distributed among each eligible State in a proportion that gives preference to States that have the most vulnerability to natural hazards in the critical infrastructure of such States.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H618797BEB7804CB6BD84E1DCF16E4C1F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)(B) by striking <quote>on a competitive basis pursuant to paragraph (1)</quote> and inserting <quote>under this section</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8E2395DA233648C59ACAD4387D0B14C0"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H33B3D2D7FF1F490389B0CABDA2CD1052" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="H4E8798D464B1437D96CE3154D7BFBD9C" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Tribes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In providing financial assistance under this section, the President shall ensure that the amount of financial assistance made available to an Indian tribal government is not less than $75,000,000. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H35C1F37CC97E4295A66B384B767CAE2E"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Suballocation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each State that receives assistance under this section shall distribute—</text>
<subparagraph id="H6CA6F30C9A9B4865B789CCF9A1D77F50"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not less than 50 percent of the funds distributed under this subsection to the local government carrying out a project recommended under subsection (d)(1); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H013449E42535469E8362951AE9164DDF"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any funds not distributed under (A) to activities described in subsections (b) and (e) of section 203.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6425A4207FE94C8E9E2DB2F293F2A848"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Additional eligibility for hazard mitigation assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The receipt of funds for a project under this section may not be considered in determining eligibility for funding under section 404 for such project. </text></paragraph> <after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDFB3299E60EE451AB45B13AFB6D01BD8"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (g)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H277E5552687B467F9166BA4560202F08"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>In determining whether to provide technical and financial assistance to a State or local government under this section, the President shall provide financial assistance only in States that have</quote> and inserting <quote>The President may only provide financial assistance under this section to a State that has</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE9B77F1951EE486497858C5A1A9AAA98"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>of such States</quote> and all that follows through <quote>in consultation with State and local governments.</quote> and inserting <quote>of such States.</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H16DB7E4181804EFF8E57066D13CAF06F"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (h) by striking <quote>mitigation activities approved by the President</quote> and inserting <quote>mitigation activities under this section</quote>.</text></paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="H62E0E96063774B58B64E2A86F078F561"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Hazard mitigation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 404 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5170c">42 U.S.C. 5170c</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H61F346F5F35745B19DE68614CB06C53D" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="H6A22F65901834D659EEE049D797F238C"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Additional eligibility for predisaster hazard mitigation assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The receipt of funds for a project under this section may not be considered in determining eligibility for funding under section 203 for such project.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

