<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6038F208BD474C98AB2B4C6F1896F467" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4651 IH: Immigration Enforcement Staff Body Camera Accountability Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4651</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250723">July 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require immigration enforcement staff to wear body cameras, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA151CAE7A607430298184AC9038830B5" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H7BE0BADADEDC4FEFA843386F4362784D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Immigration Enforcement Staff Body Camera Accountability Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HEA619BCBAF84449E944FCE9482CC0D57"><enum>2.</enum><header>Use of body cameras by immigration enforcement staff</header> <subsection id="H75335C97CF824B70BE6AB25E409279D2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than the date that the rule under subsection (e) is finalized, the Director of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) and the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection (CBP) shall ensure that all immigration enforcement staff wear body cameras when such agents and officers are engaged in official operations.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD3179EB49B4C4B5EB8502ECC6E0C601F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>To carry out this section, the Director of ICE and the Commissioner of CBP shall establish—</text> <paragraph id="H04A81D0CC95943669A621ACDEF80DC2C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>policies, procedures, and best practices for the use of body cameras by all immigration enforcement staff, including training relating to the use of such cameras;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H032BA8E3C5904C32BEF47EB419B88971"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">policies, procedures, and best practices for the use of artificial intelligence and facial recognition technology to record or review body camera footage by immigration enforcement staff, including policies that acknowledge the limitations and inaccuracies of artificial intelligence and facial recognition technology; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4C9635BB006B4177BCC163D639BA8061"><enum>(3)</enum><text>policies and procedures for carrying out adverse actions under subsection (f).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6FE0F82313124DB89CBA4AD1BF8BC527"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Always-On</header><text>Body cameras worn by immigration enforcement staff shall be turned on at the beginning of the shift of such staff and shall remain on for the duration of such shifts. </text></subsection> <subsection id="H99A2B5100FAF486ABDD0067A23083C59"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Availability of body camera footage</header><text>Footage collected by such a body camera shall be made available to each party to any administrative proceeding, civil action, or criminal prosecution to which such footage pertains in accordance with such requirements as the Secretary of Homeland Security shall by rule require under subsection (e). If such footage is not made available, such a party may notify the Director of ICE or the Commissioner of CBP, as the case may be, in writing for purposes of instigating an adverse action described in subsection (f). </text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC2695087B73D4213AF1DC75D54183BBD" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall commence a rulemaking regarding the use of body cameras and the provision of footage in accordance with subsection (d) that is consistent with the <quote>Civil Rights Principles for Body Worn Cameras</quote> of the Leadership Conference on Civil and Human Rights, May 2015, and <quote>Three Key Reforms for Facial Recognition and Body Cameras</quote> of the Project on Government Oversight, April 2018. The proposed rule shall include a comparison with the American Civil Liberties Union’s July 2021 <quote>Model Act for Regulating the Use of Wearable Body Cameras by Law Enforcement</quote> and <quote>An Act Relative to Body-Worn Cameras for Law Enforcement Officers</quote> (2016 N.H. Legis. Serv. 322 (codified at N.H. REV. STAT. ANN. § 105–D (2016))). </text></subsection> <subsection id="HD4B4219291004A9892032E15491636D7"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Adverse actions for absence of body camera footage</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any immigration enforcement staff member whose body camera does not record footage because of a violation of subsection (c) shall be subject to furlough, reduction in pay or grade, or a suspension of up to 30 days under subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/75">chapter 75</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, as the Director of ICE or the Commissioner of CBP (as the case may be) determines appropriate. If a body camera does not record at a time when the camera is required to be active, the Secretary of Homeland Security may not determine that the camera suffered a malfunction unless the member submits evidence sufficient to establish that a malfunction occurred.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H077D2B08C05E4201A8E1FBEE395ACD25"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Annual assessments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Inspector General of the Department of Homeland Security shall conduct an annual privacy impact assessment of how body camera footage is collected, maintained, stored, and disseminated.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HA89782B7EBC741E0AB3987B1D320F846"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Prohibition on new funding</header><text>No additional funding is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section. This section shall be carried out using amounts otherwise made available for such purposes.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3674C6EB5A3549FD9CD18C83679B3C33"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>immigration enforcement staff</quote> means the following:</text> <paragraph id="H5D138625F68A493C9340035DA0B0B35F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>All agents and officers of U.S. Customs and Border Protection.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5E008608D1BC49258957D1BFEC4A9099"><enum>(2)</enum><text>All agents and officers of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA55C50CE1923485BAB025C4A4FD379CA"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">All staff at any immigration detention facility who interact with detainees.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

