<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-joint" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-FLO25728-RL0-NL-6PN"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SJ 80 IS: Providing for congressional disapproval under chapter 8 of title 5, United States Code, of the rule submitted by the Bureau of Land Management relating to “National Petroleum Reserve in Alaska Integrated Activity Plan Record of Decision”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IIA</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. J. RES. 80</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250918" legis-day="20250916">September 18 (legislative day, September 16), 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S383">Mr. Sullivan</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S288">Ms. Murkowski</cosponsor>) introduced the following joint resolution; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>JOINT RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Providing for congressional disapproval under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/8">chapter 8</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, of the rule submitted by the Bureau of Land Management relating to <quote>National Petroleum Reserve in Alaska Integrated Activity Plan Record of Decision</quote>.</official-title></form><resolution-body><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="S1" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That Congress disapproves the rule submitted by the Bureau of Land Management relating to <quote>National Petroleum Reserve in Alaska Integrated Activity Plan Record of Decision</quote> (issued April 25, 2022, as a record of decision, and a letter of opinion from the Government Accountability Office dated July 24, 2025, printed in the Congressional Record on July 28, 2025, on pages S4768–S4770, concluding that such record of decision is a rule under the Congressional Review Act), and such rule shall have no force or effect.</text></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

