<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H67BABF27E3544ED7BDF91D3C28E07100" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1853 IH: Conservation for Agricultural Leased Land Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1853</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250305">March 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S001226">Ms. Salinas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001218">Ms. Stansbury</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require a study of the barriers to conservation practice adoption on leased agricultural land, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HCEF9ABBC687B4E1AB21AA09E85E38552" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H01519D9B41AC454AAE2CD0A3D5A502B0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Conservation for Agricultural Leased Land Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>CALL Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HD43B4F18F13149E5A89EEC6F356D0AAD" commented="no"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H12203444A6A04D3F87C4B87C368BF9B9" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">According to a 2016 study by the Economic Research Service of the Department of Agriculture, 39 percent of agricultural land in the United States is leased, including the majority (53 percent) of cropland.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0FC4BAAE0FFA4CC780361869F8C40FE9" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The participation of landowners and tenants in Federal, State, and local conservation programs, and the adoption of conservation practices on land that they own or manage, can be limited by a wide range of factors that are not fully understood.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8F8086E52BF54187BFA7FE6E0517DB9B"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Much of the limited information that is known comes from the Tenure, Ownership, and Transition of Agricultural Land (TOTAL) Survey conducted by the National Agricultural Statistics Service, in collaboration with the Economic Research Service; regularly recurring data collection through the TOTAL Survey and other Department of Agriculture reports is vital to understanding land tenure trends, challenges, and opportunities.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H20A128141CDB4B4B95A730F3B94A9130" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Some of the potential barriers to such participation and adoption include the structure or term of the lease or rental agreement, the level of independence given to the operator, the awareness of the landowner of both conservation practice and program opportunities and the costs and benefits associated with those opportunities, and other policy or market factors.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC7F0B1B0F36243718DFF295CD015ECEE" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The solutions to these issues are unlikely to be <quote>one size fits all</quote> and must be better understood.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HB035056BE46F4956A3BECB30AFF69367"><enum>3.</enum><header>Study</header> <subsection id="HA1A60B2E43D54DE8BD3D63F15714149B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall carry out a study of the participation in conservation programs of, and the adoption of conservation practices on, leased agricultural land.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HDB91E0D4D1884FD7A8A6295B5D3538CF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Collaboration</header><text>The study under this section shall be carried out in collaboration with the Economic Research Service.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H258CA72469164C34A6731522785C1C9F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The study carried out under this section shall include—</text> 
<paragraph id="H312D976E823B427897C48EDF699B4F5F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a review of relevant existing research literature, including—</text> <subparagraph id="H23EA7AB98F8C40C792DB98DC93C732D3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Tenure, Ownership, and Transition of Agricultural Land (TOTAL) Survey conducted by the National Agricultural Statistics Service, in collaboration with the Economic Research Service; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7A5E4D7602714458BD1D26EFE6424C05"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the report titled <quote>Understanding and Activating Non-Operating Landlords</quote>, published by the American Farmland Trust in September, 2020;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3685BA17171E4F648AE134BA8C884860"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a review of initiatives conducted by the Cooperative Extension System to increase the adoption of conservation practices on leased agricultural land;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBA75DCE43FDA498EBF5414FE03566E47"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identification and quantification of the various types and structures of current agricultural land leasing relationships;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H159AFCFB1E134F8BB955AAD74163939B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>research on the history, and estimation of future trends, of agricultural land ownership;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDC0E0464A691499CA816BA1CD0351753"><enum>(5)</enum><text>examination of what leasing models have been effective in encouraging the adoption of conservation practices;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB0939B5DCDAE4444930DDE6BF6633F31"><enum>(6)</enum><text>consideration of regional variations;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB38005E46F6F4DDDA45200366D839AAD"><enum>(7)</enum><text>examination of existing Federal incentives for adopting conservation practices, and the degree to which such incentives are currently utilized with respect to leased agricultural lands;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0D07D8AB61E84A40AA420CA4708BA462"><enum>(8)</enum><text>research on State and local incentive programs that are encouraging conservation practice adoption on leased agricultural land;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5C73F31957FA4B72AC1EEE2C91E6A79C"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">research on the benefits of transitioning from land leasing to land ownership on conservation practice adoption and Federal conservation program participation;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4D968142C04C4CF3B9ED7EAD63830586"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">examination of the effects of competition in cash rents on the adoption of conservation practices on leased agricultural lands;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6867A8D564ED4FD399E970D30F545474"><enum>(11)</enum><text>examination of what happens to conservation practices currently underway on leased agricultural land when new tenants take over such land; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H130A682098C34AFD9834733AF86CB64B"><enum>(12)</enum><text>research on how the Department of Agriculture communicates regarding conservation practice adoption to farmers and ranchers who do not own the land they operate and to landowners who lease out their agricultural land.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HEDD85EA01DA942468B82FF41EFEACEBE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Consideration</header><text>The study under this section shall be carried out with particular consideration of farmers and ranchers who are people of color, including Black and indigenous farmers and ranchers, and beginning farmers and ranchers.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H84BFBDE85D2446BEB127353795911B5B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than December 31, 2026, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report containing—</text> 
<paragraph id="H58E04F6DE7044A0589643524F26371A9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the results of the study conducted under this section; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6A506F1D00184144849C82C8C33CCEA0"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommendations, based on such study, for addressing the barriers unique to various agricultural land leasing relationships to adopting conservation practices on leased agricultural land, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H18F16FC0909B4A8DAB8D7ADDFFC6BAF2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>recommendations that can be implemented under existing statutory authorities;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H125D515B18794426907E52220C9428D3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>recommendations that would require congressional authorization in order to be implemented; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H629D25C0387541E39D6C53C6343ABB8B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>recommendations for outreach.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H52F66CFD090C43A9A8C875D40C75D5B7"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>The Secretary may enter into an agreement with a non-Federal entity (such as a nonprofit entity or university), selected through an application process, to carry out this section.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB6923B8256B5461B9623AB435211473E"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H95F594C2E0C2459BB17C7CAC7AD1FC57"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Leased agricultural land</header><text>The term <term>leased agricultural land</term> means agricultural land that is operated, under a lease or other rental agreement, by a farmer or rancher who does not own the land. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8024DB92406A458EB612237E8C0EE4F8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the National Agricultural Statistics Service.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

