<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2104F55BCA6E430588DD77069F87A67B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 316 IH: Natural Disaster Recovery Program Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 316</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250109">January 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000603">Mr. Rouzer</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the President to provide disaster assistance to States and Indian Tribes under a major disaster recovery program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H43A3CF850AF14981A01D335AC756948F" style="OLC"><section id="H67ADE92D73C049488707C762ADC17FBE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header><subsection id="H87B8EDAB741940CC8D456FAC53C33C32"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Natural Disaster Recovery Program Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H80DD64EE63DD493EBE7E4EB8C8A94E84"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text><toc container-level="amendment-block-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"><toc-entry idref="H67ADE92D73C049488707C762ADC17FBE" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HB9ACA66F74A44CC2A97447578E3560BA" level="section">Sec. 2. Natural Disaster Recovery Program.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H0D1903D1245B4CE898B298C33955A726" level="section">Sec. 3. Unmet needs assistance.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H6143F964A5B14129A5BC250F3A4F4160" level="section">Sec. 4. Further considerations for disaster declarations.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H4AEA4DD0CAFF492FAA2387F633520A2F" level="section">Sec. 5. Repair and rebuilding.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HF044AD89C01D480AB9E1E5F5506B2CC1" level="section">Sec. 6. FEMA Emergency Home Repair Program.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H7031E614B12148B6AE8FD46FAC77FC2E" level="section">Sec. 7. Appeals of individuals and households program benefits.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HF9F2703A2477432895A4021C8DED2FE0" level="section">Sec. 8. Report to Congress on major disaster declarations.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H67D8D6D9C15B468392631BBE4654502F" level="section">Sec. 9. Review by Comptroller General.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H77DAD812D674486790131D2FDDF3204C" level="section">Sec. 10. GAO study on timing of closing out disaster recovery.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section><section id="HB9ACA66F74A44CC2A97447578E3560BA"><enum>2.</enum><header>Natural Disaster Recovery Program</header><subsection id="HAD3750B9EC37497B88047645EF413693"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5121">42 U.S.C. 5121 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end of title IV the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HBD41B8027F0849ECBE6220298740476F" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="H1B6DB229D41447A28DD527A173D55FA7"><enum>431.</enum><header>Natural Disaster Recovery Program</header><subsection id="HAF2F94ECD65645969EE15347F1881123"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Natural disaster recovery reserve fund</header><paragraph id="HB74AEC7757FF4D9B948EA84A430B70B1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is established in the Treasury of the United States an account to be known as the Natural Disaster Recovery Reserve Fund (in this section referred to as the <quote>Fund</quote>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB978C218954A437CA518BAC3D05A57D6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Amounts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Fund shall consist of—</text><subparagraph id="HA22B9C719321416BACBABB606F869447"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any amounts appropriated, and deposited in the Fund, for a specific major disaster declared under section 401; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1A9DCA39C39446DB9DDCB26643E9AEF1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>amounts deposited into the Fund pursuant to paragraph (4).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H664F724DD3524D8995260CC2E0411DBA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>Amounts in the Fund shall be available, pursuant to a declaration of a major disaster—</text><subparagraph id="H02CF58117C6D4477BCC995CA4A6C8AAA"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to States and Indian tribal governments for unmet need related to a major disaster is declared under section 401; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCA2E99E99E66452EB013831E1C4D339D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to grantees that have been allocated assistance for such unmet need, for technical assistance and capacity building under subsection (c)(2) to facilitate planning and increase capacity to administer assistance under this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H411DEE84A05A492789DF962D1A3C0720"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Unused amounts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If any amounts made available for assistance under this section to grantees remain unexpended on the earlier of—</text><subparagraph id="H7452E857B6FF496FAE981E90AD4DA0D5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the date that the grantee of such amounts notifies the President that the grantee has completed all activities; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1AF1FE7A9AB64221A271A46EB24441C2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>except as provided in paragraph (5), the expiration of the 6-year period beginning when the President obligates such amounts to the grantee, the President shall transfer such unexpended amounts to the Secretary of the Treasury for deposit into the Fund, except that the President may permit the grantee to retain amounts needed to close out the grant.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD0D959E82C0F4C8396526ABC199F3115"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Extension of period for use of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The period under paragraph (4)(B) may be extended by not more than 4 years if, before the expiration of such 6-year period, the President waives this requirement and submits a written justification for such waiver to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate that specifies the period of such extension.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8815E666A0F24564B72DE88A7A6AA367"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Assessment of unmet need</header><paragraph id="H3529979A248C43979B78B6570B2EDD5C" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To assess unmet need with respect to a major disaster under section, not later than 90 days after the declaration of such a disaster, the President shall coordinate with other Federal agencies, as determined appropriate and including the Administrator of the Small Business Administration, to obtain data on all recovery needs and the amount of such recovery needs that are unmet, including—</text><subparagraph id="H7459F53CF36846AD97D4426E2FE24314" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>all data on damage caused by the disaster;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD58540E71C884E158ADF79AF38330F28" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>information on how any Federal assistance provided in connection with the disaster has been expended; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBE639114F661408ABD11D165960E0BA1" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>information on the effect of the disaster on education, transportation capabilities and dependence, housing needs, health care capacity, and displacement of persons; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7E2ECF4A084C49A3B308E89FCD3FCAE2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the extent of the unmet need remaining in relation to such disaster.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H74A320B4DDC44FA480D379758140AA12"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The President shall make publicly available the data described in paragraph (1) for any major disaster for which assistance is provided from the Fund under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H845B35C216AA434D8905ED531B40B2CE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Protection of personally identifiable information</header><text>In carrying out this subsection, the President and any recipient of funds under this section shall take such actions as may be necessary to ensure that personally identifiable information regarding recipients of assistance provided under this section is not made publicly available by any agency with which information is shared pursuant to this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2752AAD8F1BA4B7A9C0901A6D8CF1FA5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Administrative costs</header><paragraph id="HD3781AE78EC44B5CB442BEF0A202844B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A State or Indian tribal government receiving a grant under this section may use not more than 13 percent of the amount of grant funds received, or within such other percentage as may be established pursuant to subparagraph (B), for administrative costs, including costs related to audits, reviews, oversight, evaluation, and investigations. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1FDA31B0E2B64AB18F1D21D9161D9889"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Discretion to establish sliding scale</header><text>The President may establish a series of percentage limitations on the amount of grant funds received that may be used by a grantee for administrative costs, but only if—</text><subparagraph id="H38C43276B5C74755A143DC56E3D5213E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such percentage limitations are based on the amount of grant funds received by a grantee; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB7DEAA39E4E04DEFA4A81AC72872ED12"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such series provides that the percentage that may be used is lower for grantees receiving a greater amount of grant funds and such percentage that may be used is higher for grantees receiving a lesser amount of grant funds.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H73B4CC943C6A4F0E88DEC81C8AA71398"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Technical assistance; capacity building</header><text>From funds made available for use under this section, the President may provide—</text><subparagraph id="H08C76E750D2348899356AEC8D36F8DBF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>necessary technical assistance to grantees to ensure grantees are compliant with Federal law; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7C160A2ACCC249BAA10A946D896F1AF4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>capacity building assistance, including assistance regarding contracting and procurement processes, including providing solicitation and contractual templates that conform to Federal requirements for use by grantees.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAB4F9E60BB514EA6A197F860051A13ED" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Allocation, process, and procedures; coordination</header><paragraph id="H90BCA1F9E90E4340B65DBDD700B73B4B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Allocation</header><subparagraph id="H70FEA4FB707244E68FB695DB152D29FD"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President shall allocate funds under this section proportionally to grantees based on their level of unmet need as determined under subsection (b).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1E42BBA22DD7417DA4D8DE4FED692371" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Grantee use of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each grantee—</text><clause id="H415DCBA1176A46D1B3ACDC6450B04A9A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall be solely responsible for determining how funds provided under this section are prioritized and expended; and</text></clause><clause id="HA3E97B89F55941E39CB68F8E744264CB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>shall not be required to provide an action or spending plan to the President before or after funds are allocated.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H68815C773FFE4B0BBC0838CA79000987"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Notwithstanding section 312, a loan shall not—</text><clause id="H932757E8A45F4E9A9C4C5B7F1A6C3E0A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>be considered a duplication of benefits with funds provided by a Federal agency; or</text></clause><clause id="HC16D9F4EC03E46B9B114811D36BF4A8F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>limit or otherwise impact the ability of a recipient to receive any other Federal assistance.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE9384CD0F9574EB58E6662B76D1AF5F8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Procedure for provision of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An entity awarded a grant under this section shall be provided an initial amount that equals 50 percent of total grant amount allocated under paragraph (1). To be eligible for the remaining 50 percent of the allocation, a grantee shall submit to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate, the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate, and the Inspector General of the United States a report containing—</text><subparagraph id="H2CAB9CDB5CDB4BDB9E17C3DA68DDAFF0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a detailed description of how such amount was spent; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB7D62A40E30D4717AB9BE53CB66A8D0F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a certification from an auditor of the State or Indian tribal government that none of the funds were wasted or used inappropriately.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFC108880D11A444BA791AD5CDA09F368"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>Each State and Indian tribal government that receives funds under this section shall establish or adhere to existing guidelines for procurement processes and procedures and require that subgrantees—</text><subparagraph id="HDA350E996C784BBE96AD9AEE6321543E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide for full and open competition and require cost or price analysis;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE883519CA35B45B6A5B669C335EC76E6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>specify methods of procurement and their applicability, but not allow cost-plus-a-percentage-of cost or percentage-of-construction-cost methods of procurement;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H16D2447B42D6444E8CD6CE07139A658B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>include standards of conduct governing employees engaged in the award or administration of contracts; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H325FA022B1274FB6B5998296D16F28A0"><enum>(D)</enum><text>ensure that all purchase orders and contracts include any clauses required by Federal statute, Executive order, or implementing regulation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0F1F29B7DD9744C2BA4B8975999CCAFE"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>Any funds provided under this section—</text><paragraph id="H17C2851DE9904237981CE94832C1CBC0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall supplement and not supplant any other assistance provided by the President or any other Federal agency in response to a major disaster; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0F53AB71C0ED451BBED201F7C878CCC1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may not be considered a duplication of assistance.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H90683E1F5EE34B6689A1A350F71A9C61"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Environmental review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any Federal agency or recipient of funds received under this section that fund or use funds to supplement funds provided under section 402, 403, 404, 406, 407, 408(c)(4), 428, or 502 may adopt, without review or public comment, any environmental review, approval, or permit performed by a Federal agency.</text></subsection><subsection id="H0D1B82FF6E34419F947A3D4F8DB6B334"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Best practices</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall identify best practices for grantees on issues including developing action plans, establishing financial controls, building grantee technical and administrative capacity, procurement, and use of grant funds as local match for other sources of Federal funding. Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section, the President shall publish a compilation of such identified best practices and share with all relevant grantees to facilitate a more efficient and effective disaster recovery process.</text></subsection><subsection id="H765A41EFDF2B41BE89AC757DDCDFDA6D"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph id="HCEFCBC8FD1414A6A9B779F403EB8F08E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>State auditor</header><text>The term <term>State auditor</term> means the individual selected by the Governor or head of an Indian tribal government to submit a certification in accordance with subsection (d)(2)(A)(ii).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5C461CDFDCC349258F11AECC7FBD5476"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Unmet need</header><text>The term <term>unmet need</term>—</text><subparagraph id="HC6741EF881414C3AA7741D527F938C01"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means any necessary expenses for activities related to disaster relief, resiliency, long-term recovery, restoration of infrastructure and housing, mitigation, and economic revitalization related to a major disaster declared by the President under section 401; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA5D556A90CA549D7AE16BC6FA63B2C0C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may include—</text><clause id="H88CB786ADB3846D387D58CEBE534CBA9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any unresourced item, support, or assistance that has been assessed and verified as necessary for a survivor to recover from a major disaster, including food, clothing, shelter, first aid, emotional and spiritual care, household items, home repair, or rebuilding; and</text></clause><clause id="H244C9610C6B344B39974808ACDA844DD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">cleaning and removing debris from rivers, creeks, streams, and ditches.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H7BF3B3CD64DD4E2AA7DF32EA195D0BBD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No amounts made available by an appropriations Act that provide funding for any activity not authorized by law for the program established under section 431 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (as added by this Act) may be expended.</text></subsection></section><section id="H0D1903D1245B4CE898B298C33955A726"><enum>3.</enum><header>Unmet needs assistance</header><subsection id="HA24D068B9796407FAABE9867FDF3ACAC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title IV of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5170">42 U.S.C. 5170 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HE5F3D92E4038492396724469A43CCBB8" style="OLC"><section id="HB7C5BEC17EB84779881C96D5E0D5EC99"><enum>432.</enum><header>Unmet needs assistance</header><subsection id="H6303CAF8CF2C49378CD5F2C1D11052F3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In any major disaster, the Governor or the Chief Executive of the Indian tribal government may request a grant from the President to provide assistance to meet unmet needs resulting from a major disaster.</text></subsection><subsection id="H3EB5D8ECA7074ADE93411C5938EA8F5F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Funding</header><paragraph id="H14C9CD7DE60E4316A330F9DA8D8F184E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Amount of funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may set aside from the Disaster Relief Fund, with respect to each major disaster, an amount equal to 10 percent of the estimated aggregate amount of the grants to be made pursuant to sections 406 and 408 of the major disaster in order to provide technical and financial assistance under this section and such amounts shall be deemed to be related to activities carried out pursuant to major disasters under this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H66E5700FF81A4645A17A2CF069BBE02D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Estimated aggregate amount</header><text>Not later than 180 days after each major disaster declared pursuant to this Act, the estimated aggregate amount of grants for purposes of paragraph (1) shall be determined by the President and such estimated amount need not be reduced, increased, or changed due to variations in estimates.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H375046DDD4E84D868F06DCFDD5332677"><enum>(3)</enum><header>No reduction in amounts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount set aside pursuant to paragraph (1) shall not reduce the amounts otherwise made available for sections 403, 406, 407, 408, 410, 416, and 428 under this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4E55693392D54239A28766FDC26C95A3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Unmet needs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State or Indian tribal government may use unmet needs grants to provide assistance, in addition to other assistance made available under this Act, for the following unmet needs resulting from a major disaster:</text><paragraph id="H2E18A0362BDC483EA2514412D4F8F407"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Disaster-related home repair and rebuilding financial assistance to families for permanent housing purposes, including in conjunction with eligible expenditures under section 408.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H705C24A560804CA680118F0AAC420306"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Disaster-related unmet needs of families who are unable to obtain adequate assistance from other sources.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3417DBBE5A314FDD982D0611E0044D5E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Other disaster-related services that alleviate human suffering and promote the well-being of disaster victims.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H884F916D5C3A48789618AFA132A1EFD4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Economic and business activities (including food and agriculture) after a disaster to implement post-disaster economic recovery measures, including planning and technical assistance for long-term economic recovery plans, infrastructure improvements, business or infrastructure financing, market or industry research, and other activities authorized under a comprehensive economic development strategy.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H75206653F6A34F6293299897519289FD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Accounting and fiscal controls</header><paragraph id="H38C57C182E8940FBB37A9FD38E23C2E4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 6 months after receipt of funds and every 6 months thereafter until all such funds are expended, each State or Indian tribal government receiving such funds shall submit to the Administrator a report that includes—</text><subparagraph id="H89CB9AB4165E465C9BAD492EAFB6E883"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the criteria established for determining how the funds are spent;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9477F8EAB3AC4ABC967DBC43BC44C575"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the allocation of such funds; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H089E230E93584883BDB51EA05F7BCE6B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the process for public notice and comment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB1D8BE8EE3444EDFA72694DDE79E4B65"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administrative costs</header><text>A State or Indian tribal government that receives funds under this section may expend not more than 5 percent of the amount of such funds for the administrative costs of providing financial assistance to individuals and households in the State.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H4213A1D853BB41B693FEF6D724A0117C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>This section and the amendments made by this section shall apply to funds appropriated on or after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="H6143F964A5B14129A5BC250F3A4F4160"><enum>4.</enum><header>Further considerations for disaster declarations</header><subsection id="H75927A425A5A4E93986821A2AD3A6EB3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In making recommendations to the President regarding the declaration of a major disaster or emergency pursuant to section 401 or 501 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5170">42 U.S.C. 5170</external-xref>; 5191) or the proposed non-Federal share of the cost of carrying out activities with assistance provided under such Act, the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall give greater weight and consideration to severe local impact resulting from such disaster or emergency and, in the 5-year period preceding such disaster or emergency, whether multiple other disasters or emergencies have occurred in the affected area.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1D5FB8A32F4F4819BC66DCA27603A35E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Revisions to guidance, policies, and regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall take such actions as are necessary to revise any policies, guidance, or regulations of the Agency to implement subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="H7AD465CB25784EB48DF659D15BD883C4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section, the Administrator shall submit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a report on the implementation of this section and shall include in such report a description of—</text><paragraph id="H4B76A6A9C4A04786A4D1D54E3B47994D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>changes made to guidance, policies, or regulations pursuant to subsection (b); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6A6D15A3FD6547D890BCD00A3822FEF2"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of major disasters and emergencies that have been declared pursuant to section 401 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act based on the criteria described in subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H4AEA4DD0CAFF492FAA2387F633520A2F"><enum>5.</enum><header>Repair and rebuilding</header><subsection id="HEF11003268434C648EFFF1E86FACE446"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 408(c) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5174">42 U.S.C. 5174</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HD89CAC19F06640BCB4F9851E2C5B7EE7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by amending paragraph (2) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HD69E9B12811E4C7CB6B1A8F810C3EA2C" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="HE310197ADA5A42ED868A841DEDECBF96"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Repairs</header><subparagraph id="HEF4C8073BC8441D28DC4EDF6EA995437"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Financial assistance for repairs</header><text>The President may provide financial assistance for the repair of owner-occupied private residences, utilities, and residential infrastructure (such as a private access route) damaged by a major disaster, or with respect to individuals with disabilities, rendered inaccessible by a major disaster.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC64386C95BD84A3A861089F8489DDE11"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Direct assistance for repairs</header><clause id="HA769DBBE31604F0CADA26A40E4FE0224"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President may provide direct assistance to individuals and households who are unable to make use of financial assistance under subparagraph (A) and when there is a lack of available resources, for—</text><subclause id="HC783E6BA511041CB90044EB233C07553"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the repair of owner-occupied private residences, utilities, and residential infrastructure (such as a private access route) damaged by a major disaster, or with respect to individuals with disabilities, rendered inaccessible by a disaster; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H9596D9F88835498FB00D63483366E48F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>eligible hazard mitigation measures that reduce the likelihood and future damage to such residences, utilities, and infrastructure.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HAA09D7C98D6E45D09B85263F847B1A84"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>A recipient of assistance under this subparagraph shall not be eligible for assistance under paragraph (1), unless otherwise determined by the Administrator.</text></clause><clause id="H5FBA2D1C925449B98C218728DDE8D583"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Coordination with other assistance</header><text>Assistance allowed under this paragraph may be used in coordination with other sources for the repair and rebuilding of an owner-occupied residence.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA92FB61A714F4608A21D96EE9760A7D1"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Relationship to other assistance</header><text>A recipient of assistance provided under this paragraph shall not be required to show that the assistance can be met through other means, except insurance proceeds.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H944F0F64B68C4C4E80B779F2646ED426"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (4) by striking <quote>in cases in which</quote> and all that follows through the end of the paragraph and inserting <quote>if the President considers it a cost effective alternative to other housing solutions, including the costs associated with temporary housing provided under this section, and long-term rebuilding costs associated with section 431.</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDB1E985964574EEE849A9B1686998662"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>Section 408(b)(1) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5174">42 U.S.C. 5174(b)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H89583F5740674C91966AF8D5FC6642E9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>rendered uninhabitable</quote> and inserting <quote>damaged by a major disaster</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4DF58355D0DA48849B047A242B8D8659"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>uninhabitable, as a result of damage caused by a major disaster</quote> and inserting <quote>damaged by a major disaster</quote>. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1B368952BF3C4220848E85F5A4B5B197"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>This section and the amendments made by this section shall apply to funds appropriated on or after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="HF044AD89C01D480AB9E1E5F5506B2CC1"><enum>6.</enum><header>FEMA Emergency Home Repair Program</header><subsection id="H015C05909E194AD28C874F860565678E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 403(a) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5170b">42 U.S.C. 5170b(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H512A2FDA222441FF8842E152F944E0A2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)—</text><subparagraph id="H3C2FE2B667F9416EAE736FED8AC27853"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (I) by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3931E07A02CC4F91BC0A8C1A051BE8FC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (J) by striking the period and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEE12CCF4910049C389D12722808FDB34"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H1F9B219D8DB8486298D80FBE3646D226" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="H8DD186F124934670B3678BFD1585E966"><enum>(K)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">minor repairs up to habitability of owner-occupied homes damaged by the disaster in order for survivors to safely shelter in place, subject to the availability of appropriations.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H20C9806BDEBE4605A2BEB908F1251411"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HF9978B6B42EE47648935C53417DF2014" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H5422D5F8D3C04AC993B1CE0B1C5C5850" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Sheltering and housing options</header><text>Not later than 15 days after a declaration of a major disaster, the Federal coordinating officer shall identify all sheltering and housing options available under this section or section 408 to a State Governor, or the designated State coordinating officer. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE3A1C0DFE28F4A9D8AAE06A5D5509BC8"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>minor repairs up to habitability</term> means the minimum standards for permanent housing described in section 576.403(c) of title 24, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAC6BF226BDE341AEA8997FF82195D955"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall issue final regulations to implement the amendments made by this section.</text></subsection></section><section id="H7031E614B12148B6AE8FD46FAC77FC2E"><enum>7.</enum><header>Appeals of individuals and households program benefits</header><subsection id="H4662298B6511493C85A36AE07379FC40"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Period of assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Clauses (iii) and (iv) of section 408(c)(1)(B) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5174">42 U.S.C. 5174(c)(1)(B)</external-xref>) are amended by striking <quote>18-month period</quote> and inserting <quote>24-month period</quote>. </text></subsection><subsection id="H94432B5FB4EE438ABDA3B830FC11C0D1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Appeals</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall revise section 206.115 of title 44, Code of Federal Regulations, to require the Federal Emergency Management Agency to provide to any applicant who appeals a determination of eligibility of assistance—</text><paragraph id="HE77FA1C30FC447C8BACC4C10A6FBCE44"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any documentation used to make such determination, including any inspection documents that exist;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7C928FA451CF4713BCC946F11941C57F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of—</text><subparagraph id="H52FC0B5250E34669944542779287B101"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the reasons for such determination; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H42C29D12CA524E51BDB3EE9EA1D9EFBD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>recommended steps that could be taken to remedy a determination of ineligibility, including, as applicable, a list of additional documentation that the applicant may provide; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7C42ED834E614E31A24A0DB0558BECF1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any inspection documents that exist not later than 10 days after the completion of the inspection.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBF4330676F5E4FAA9C5DB5CF535DB2D9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section and the amendment made by this section shall apply to funds appropriated on or after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="HF9F2703A2477432895A4021C8DED2FE0" commented="no"><enum>8.</enum><header>Report to Congress on major disaster declarations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives a report containing the following information with respect to each major disaster declared pursuant to section 401 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5170">42 U.S.C. 5170</external-xref>) during the 5-year period preceding such date of enactment:</text><paragraph id="HC2971A2D566242818DA89A7464DFE906" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The process used by the Federal Emergency Management Agency to determine individual household need.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDBB7CCA17F254E7EA6A67E2A7321310A" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An itemization of the most common reasons for denial of individual and household assistance pursuant to section 408 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5174">42 U.S.C. 5174</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE81758A0ED6B412DA9A90BBF95E63B9D" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The rate of appeals of denial of such assistance.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8CF182EF707346AAAA43A58AA10D8FAC" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The amount of time the Agency takes to issue a decision regarding eligibility for individual assistance, disaggregated by each such major disaster.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H44DDF1F206C84F82840CB8F3225A1444" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Information on the use of Disaster Legal Services and the number of applicants who were eligible for such services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDE05773FB1BE43EF8F7E5186D9D17594" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The total number of Disaster Legal Services volunteers as of such date of enactment.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H956341D418164FAF921FA526EDE9B543" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The number of such volunteers who were activated for each such major disaster.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9C90AAB5DD5D47BE96852CABA613ACA4" commented="no"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount of time taken after the declaration of each such major disaster to set up disaster recovery centers that provide access to individual assistance.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC8FA2FFF1E714B5D82225F2D2B96369F" commented="no"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The number of disaster recovery centers opened for each such major disaster.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE9F730D72FCD4DBB8E9C0E66003E8D6F" commented="no"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The process used for selecting the location of such disaster recovery centers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H167EF0C4C9D645D69E73B66D0470DBB9" commented="no"><enum>(11)</enum><text>The average amount of time disaster recovery centers remained open.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1956086455464AEAAAC1C244C7C85358" commented="no"><enum>(12)</enum><text>The average amount of time individual survivors spend at such centers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCD2A2725659A4434820644A3A0073DF6" commented="no"><enum>(13)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of outreach efforts in low-income, rural, and underserved communities regarding the availability of assistance provided by the Federal Emergency Management Agency under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act. </text></paragraph></section><section id="H67D8D6D9C15B468392631BBE4654502F" commented="no"><enum>9.</enum><header>Review by Comptroller General</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 5 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall—</text><paragraph id="H288739E1C00E4E50ABDE67310EEB1691" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct a review of the fiscal controls of States that receive assistance under section 432 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act, as added by section 3; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBC9E7F37AE7F42E3AFB63AE403F0FFDC" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>make recommendations regarding the program established under such section to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H77DAD812D674486790131D2FDDF3204C"><enum>10.</enum><header>GAO study on timing of closing out disaster recovery</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report on how long it takes the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency to officially close out each major disaster declared under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5121">42 U.S.C. 5121 et seq.</external-xref>) pursuant to section 705 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5205">42 U.S.C. 5205</external-xref>). </text></section></legis-body></bill> 

