<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H04FD9FA5E9BE48D48C0A7DB6A50E7FAC" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4093 IH: Apples to Apples Comparison Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4093</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250624">June 24, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001314">Mr. Bean of Florida</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="H001082">Mr. Hern of Oklahoma</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to publish information on expenditures under the Medicare program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H28C90482187043A4BAD0AA72FAEEAC77" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H5889F1BC0F9545E29B2969388CF73643" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Apples to Apples Comparison Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HCFC59E0E34F043619F19BF7641A982B4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Requiring the Secretary of Health and Human Services to publish information on expenditures under the Medicare program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1874 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395kk">42 U.S.C. 1395kk</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HC4C3B681604D447A865F353BD21B14B1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (g)—</text> <subparagraph id="HDBF1DDFF11C54CF18EF60C7E745E14BF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text> 
<clause id="H94F239CB83704B75A4CDC66DFA89B390"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by inserting <quote>(and, beginning with 2025, publish on the public website of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services in machine-readable files information on)</quote> after <quote>a report on</quote>;</text></clause> <clause id="H52A6FE9E4C974F9E95BE815788EFB490"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by inserting <quote>(and, beginning with 2025, by county and Metropolitan Statistical Area)</quote> after <quote>State</quote>; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H210B2F9EFBDF4C9E8F45BF370571C35D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)—</text> <subclause id="HE16C1F9D2FA6407ABDE994062172CBFA"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in clause (ii), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H983A9C272E274289B0C231E071F5BB87"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in clause (iii), by striking the period and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HF0F250D657924C6A82668DAB1B60C54B"><enum>(III)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new clause:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HA1B889C05C434B3EBE25D0A287EC88A0" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<clause id="HB4DA0A57F34847098D69DEAF4B301C43"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">beginning with 2025, each category of individuals described in subsection (h)(1).</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3454B9AA816041E8A762EE412F77E462"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HB11F829130194C71A28EF956163EA395" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="HD71FCF334DFF4581AAC7B7AB72A68FCE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Special rule for 2025 report and publication of information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As part of the report and publication of information required under paragraph (1) for 2025, the Secretary shall include enrollment information submitted under this subsection for each preceding year (beginning with 2015), broken down by county and Metropolitan Statistical Area and provided for each category of individuals described in subsection (h)(1). </text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE9FC4A36AC784CDE821D7190C371159B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H679456C4AD094EC1A4430F7AFC1B3179" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="H074E4C0CF4F64B548CD83885E1F71D2F"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Information on expenditures</header> 
<paragraph id="H5370C73749244CA6B931D966A43267BB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the last day of each year (beginning with 2025), the Secretary shall, for each county and each Metropolitan Statistical Area, publish on the public website of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services in machine-readable files the total and average expenditures under this title for items and services furnished to individuals entitled to benefits under part A or enrolled under part B residing in such county or Metropolitan Statistical Area for each month occurring in the specified historical period and for each month occurring in the specified projected period with respect to such year, broken down by the following categories of individuals:</text> <subparagraph id="H725232EC655648ECAD439898AA65F383"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Individuals entitled to benefits under part A and not enrolled under part B.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAB3586E5377F49BDA99BFA4F0AE49BEE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Individuals who are—</text> <clause id="H00CCA6A02F1C4685A5F5D8BE36806D60"><enum>(i)</enum><text>not entitled to benefits under part A;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HFD245501FED24680AF633880274A1785"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>enrolled under part B; and</text></clause> <clause id="HE81C732F79204B0782B2B34E1A683F55"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>not enrolled under a Medicare Advantage plan under part C.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H72E360290DA94BE69B1B3E69102DCF5C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Individuals who are—</text> <clause id="HEE7B98F640E945FB84DE8FA993122C41"><enum>(i)</enum><text>entitled to benefits under part A and enrolled under part B; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H272E49813E1C483DAC70EA6D20EDC52B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>not enrolled under a Medicare Advantage plan under part C.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6D4316F15C9C49B7993946C103F88E96"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Individuals described in subparagraph (A) who are enrolled in a prescription drug plan under part D.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H40ACDF0D0EAB4D9687BB6BE93E35EAC1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Individuals described in subparagraph (B) who are enrolled in a prescription drug plan under part D.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H19AC1DDEC7FB4FEAB1540B3253113DA2"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Individuals described in subparagraph (C) who are enrolled in a prescription drug plan under part D.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEF95A506A35B4F718B8812C3F094BBD7"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Individuals described in subparagraph (A) who are not enrolled in a prescription drug plan under part D.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF51F421CB8614A87BA29E808A470CF16"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Individuals described in subparagraph (B) who are not enrolled in a prescription drug plan under part D.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB85D167015AD498BAF7037A1275C59A2"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Individuals described in subparagraph (C) who are not enrolled in a prescription drug plan under part D.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDEDB9EB78CB54618B976F080F8116D24"><enum>(J)</enum><text>Individuals described in subparagraph (A) who are enrolled in a Federal health care program (as defined in section 1128B) or a health plan under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/89">chapter 89</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA4777FB3397A4A1EAF8AEB2C65C4E913"><enum>(K)</enum><text>Individuals described in subparagraph (B) who are enrolled in such a program or plan.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA00EC239C7194CF793BD7018B08112AB"><enum>(L)</enum><text>Individuals described in subparagraph (C) who are enrolled in such a program or plan.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H59050F7CE98442C8A70A98456ECD9E46"><enum>(M)</enum><text>Individuals described in subparagraph (A) who are not enrolled in such a program or plan.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA38E15B513B64B479483C83266662329"><enum>(N)</enum><text>Individuals described in subparagraph (B) who are not enrolled in such a program or plan.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA3B53F6FBA65479FAF09D8E053FC0078"><enum>(O)</enum><text>Individuals described in subparagraph (C) who are not enrolled in such a program or plan.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0109D54758084FD2B1801A94FD789359"><enum>(P)</enum><text>Individuals described in subparagraph (A) who are enrolled in a group health plan (as defined in section 2791 of the Public Health Service Act) or a medicare supplemental policy under section 1882.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2C5767ECDA4A487388B0DF1B923CC5CE"><enum>(Q)</enum><text>Individuals described in subparagraph (B) who are enrolled in such a plan or policy.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC84AF057541D43A1BE8F50D89980B8FD"><enum>(R)</enum><text>Individuals described in subparagraph (C) who are enrolled in such a plan or policy.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF89605FC74704B14B719207303917148"><enum>(S)</enum><text>Individuals described in subparagraph (A) who are not enrolled in such a plan or policy.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6963319EAA664831BC0D5A3B95D3EA70"><enum>(T)</enum><text>Individuals described in subparagraph (B) who are not enrolled in such a plan or policy.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1DDA1764D5574C819B86934F6A71B127"><enum>(U)</enum><text>Individuals described in subparagraph (C) who are not enrolled in such a plan or policy.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H309C68B638144521970D5DF5D10492D2"><enum>(V)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Individuals enrolled in a specialized MA plan for special needs individuals, broken down by each type of plan.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H919884015CAD4C8291DC5EFBC15D4862"><enum>(W)</enum><text>Individuals enrolled in an MA plan other than a plan described in subparagraph (V).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0E1DF41B66A648209D54C9F590E1F524"><enum>(X)</enum><text>Individuals enrolled in an MA plan.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H687063ED6ED844AC8FD66037D7698A43"><enum>(Y)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Individuals described in subparagraph (X) who are enrolled in a Federal health care program (as defined in section 1128B) or a health plan under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/89">chapter 89</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF28097A604CE4F0B8C2E5CA89795928C"><enum>(Z)</enum><text>Individuals described in subparagraph (X) who are not enrolled in such a program or plan.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD022F21FFFAC4155BF9389F493744258"><enum>(AA)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Individuals described in subparagraph (X) who are enrolled in a group health plan (as defined in section 2791 of the Public Health Service Act) or a medicare supplemental policy under section 1882.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H76488EC5BA10413C97EC866171E72BE1"><enum>(BB)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Individuals described in subparagraph (X) who are not enrolled in such a plan or policy.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H78A80DF989DC4B1A8EB43D5F4EA539E5"><enum>(CC)</enum><text>Individuals described in subparagraph (X) who are enrolled in a prescription drug plan under part D.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H37956CDE9D95448C9E770EB8F9412A8C"><enum>(DD)</enum><text>Individuals described in subparagraph (X) who are not enrolled in such a plan.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H37738FCFABC84D16B76A0FC4452A1FFF"><enum>(EE)</enum><text>Individuals described in subparagraph (X) who are enrolled in an MA–PD plan.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDEE8CBED27E34CC5B1F0A2C8157D839C"><enum>(FF)</enum><text>Individuals described in subparagraph (X) who are not enrolled in such a plan.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7FCA3F541CEF48DCBE04D39C02CCC6BA"><enum>(GG)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Individuals described in subparagraph (CC) or (EE) who are enrolled in a Federal health care program (as defined in section 1128B) or a health plan under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/89">chapter 89</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEA7454409EA1405E9F471B507007A751"><enum>(HH)</enum><text>Individuals described in subparagraph (CC) or (EE) who are not enrolled in such a program or plan.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3C76C8E1B86F4C8EBCB2A46BDCA919EE"><enum>(II)</enum><text>Individuals enrolled in an employer group waiver plan.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD1734A11792C4B74B09B30140E14F430"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this subsection:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H355ECF00E0404206B7C279321BB3D908"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Specified historical period</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>specified historical period</quote> means, with respect to a year, the 10-year period ending on the last day of such year.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H88E1D3C8555A4D679AA231115CFDA6CA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Specified projected period</header><text>The term <quote>specified projected period</quote> means, with respect to a year, the period beginning on the first day of the subsequent year of a duration specified by the Secretary (but in no case to exceed a duration of 5 years).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H3661382F9C154D8CB42BFC58A2DA5E9F"><enum>3.</enum><header>MedPAC analysis of Medicare Advantage and fee-for-service expenditures</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1805(b) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395b-6">42 U.S.C. 1395b–6(b)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HD65DF1C67D1E43919E3652EA169315F5" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="H073FF7BA503A4705AAEFC84EBA2F18EB"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Analysis of Medicare Advantage and fee-for-service expenditures</header> <subparagraph id="HBF14CCF53BAA4D80900385724896C52A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall, as part of the report described in paragraph (1)(C) submitted for each year (beginning with 2026), include a retrospective analysis of average expenditures under this title for individuals enrolled in a Medicare Advantage plan under part C compared to average expenditures under this title for individuals entitled to benefits under part A and enrolled under part B who are eligible to enroll under such a plan but who are not so enrolled.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H12229E3121BB4016BD367C9642ED3BE0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In preparing each analysis described in subparagraph (A), the Commission shall—</text> <clause id="H73B73F2705554498AF8B08BE6711491A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>use data provided by the Chief Actuary of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services and the Boards of Trustees of the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund established under section 1817 and the Federal Supplementary Medical Insurance Trust fund established under section 1841 and such other data as the Commission determines appropriate;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HB5EF5AB234004C75A210F90D3C68415F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>take into account—</text> <subclause id="HE24B270B7ED4427B951CADFCB7EC6B13"><enum>(I)</enum><text>differences in value provided under Medicare Advantage plans compared to the value provided under parts A and B, such as the existence of out-of-pocket expenditure caps, supplemental benefits available under such plans, and the integration of benefits for covered part D drugs under certain such plans; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H1331DB51D9FC48A8861B4C051F1A6B77"><enum>(II)</enum><text>demographic differences of individuals enrolled in Medicare Advantage plans compared to individuals entitled to benefits under part A and enrolled under part B who are not enrolled in such a plan; and</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H23423D1FC74C415FBF353AC8AA2B47D9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>take into account differences in HCC risk scores but not take into account any favorable selection differences with respect to enrollment in such plans.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD8A63954B20A409AAC4EAE37EF507829"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Publication requirements</header><text>With respect to each analysis described in subparagraph (A), the Commission shall—</text> <clause id="HF2FC8C6A33FF44899539F722D1406E87"><enum>(i)</enum><text>make public all data used in preparing such analysis in a manner that—</text> 
<subclause id="HB734BE2EDD76479AA4722139121E7651"><enum>(I)</enum><text>allows replication of such analysis; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H4263124F91E642FAA708ABFF28B391ED"><enum>(II)</enum><text>protects the confidentiality of personal information of individuals entitled to benefits under part A and enrolled under part B;</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H6AF568B720D54C2AB6CDF842CAEB637F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>not later than 60 days prior to the submission of such analysis, make public the methodology used to conduct such analysis and allow at least 30 days for public comment on such methodology; and</text></clause> <clause id="H2B7EBA5A6AD4453DA06AE46749AE7A3C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">make public a response to each such comment received on the methodology prior to or concurrent with the submission of such analysis.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
<section id="H0A471E79E6C94461BB3AAB6790E82C9D"><enum>4.</enum><header>Trustees report of expenditure information</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1874 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395kk">42 U.S.C. 1395kk</external-xref>), as amended by section 2, is further amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HD10B3EAB6A1D41739F67A7196C9D6BB0" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="HE1DD7915A1324CB7A9098E4FF06E5CE5"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Trustees’ report of expenditure information</header> <paragraph id="H15A64504D7604DE89A51D3166F2913D6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Boards of Trustees of the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund established under section 1817 and the Federal Supplementary Medical Insurance Trust Fund established under section 1841 shall jointly, as part of the reports described in sections 1817(b)(2) and 1841(b)(2) submitted for a year (beginning with 2026), include information on aggregate and average expenditures under this title for the following categories of individuals, broken down, in the case of the category described in subparagraph (C), by expenditures under part A and expenditures under part B:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H4D2CA19F47B74B8EBC3870621E0162AA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Individuals entitled to benefits under part A and not enrolled under part B.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE7DFBDE51286425C8C7E1C9746FFA70E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Individuals enrolled under part B and not entitled to benefits under part A.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB3A2E0152C5D4E329F0004D4D0ACEF25"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Individuals entitled to benefits under part A, enrolled under part B, and not enrolled in a Medicare Advantage plan under part C.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD7FFBD2C8179461988F39FA723BC1A53"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Provision of disaggregated information</header><text>The Boards of Trustees described in paragraph (1) shall, as part of all expenditure data (including data tables) made public by such Boards, disaggregate such data, to the extent practicable, based on the categories of individuals described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

