<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB177427AD82F47FD84998EC6BAFCD2D2" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1046 IH: Marc Fischer Memorial Interdiction of Fentanyl in Postal Mail at Federal Prisons Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1046</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250206">February 6, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="H001066">Mr. Horsford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001212">Mr. Moore of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001217">Mr. Moskowitz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001205">Mrs. Miller of West Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000614">Mr. Pappas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001063">Mr. Cuellar</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Director of the Bureau of Prisons to develop and implement a strategy to interdict fentanyl and other synthetic drugs in the mail at Federal correctional facilities.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H2A3055FCE3D94F2B9181F2D035C2484D" style="OLC"><section id="H01FF667369A6445EA5FF341091874DC3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Marc Fischer Memorial Interdiction of Fentanyl in Postal Mail at Federal Prisons Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Marc Fischer Memorial Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HE8345924B6224F61B3B3B7C3451A6E9D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H3981A4E248A14DE48AC68B917761CF6D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Bureau of Prisons has 122 institutions located throughout the United States, employs nearly 38,000 employees, and is responsible for more than 150,000 Federal inmates.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3A9E52672DD34A59BB47A4EA846C95E0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Inmate mail is a primary entry point for smuggling drugs into correctional facilities, with tainted mail incidents also on the rise.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H76F726693CE7415081920CED5EA55EC6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Elimination of dangerous contraband, including synthetic drugs, in mail is essential to protecting the health and safety of employees of the Bureau of Prisons and Federal inmates.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD36560A0E33E4184A4055D2C3B3A0A45"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Prisons in the United States are increasingly deadly facilities, with a 600 percent rise in drug overdoses in recent years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC98078B1388E48B5B35F20027F467186"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The introduction of synthetic drugs, particularly fentanyl and fentanyl analogues, into correctional facilities by mail threatens employees, inmates, and the security of correctional institutions, and the practice of deliberately lacing opioids to ensure targeted lethality represents a dramatic emerging concern.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4F8B275842F844B080086E9B81417909"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The foregoing factors add tremendous pressures and workload that further burden existing employees, commonly reassigning officers from other functions to assist in processing mail.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H34A4D2AE9F2540A1A780C58C14820D36"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Employees at correctional facilities at Federal, State, and local levels continue to request drug interdiction technologies to protect themselves and inmates.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD1140840361D46639F3CA971938F170C"><enum>(8)</enum><text>A congressionally authorized digital mail scanning pilot program at the Federal Correctional Institution, Beckley, West Virginia, and the United States Penitentiary, Canaan, Pennsylvania, from March 2020 through June 2021, demonstrated effective interdiction technology and practices aimed at eliminating dangerous contraband arriving through the mail and served as an effective deterrent to smuggling attempts.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD56497E025684C49B919A6F422B88D78"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Apart from digital mail scanning, there is no widely deployed interdiction technology that has demonstrated a 100 percent efficacy to detecting fentanyl, and other synthetic drugs, arriving through the mail at Bureau of Prisons facilities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3B9F595EDD184E7C82326AD7872AD504"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Removing mail processing from Federal prisons and relieving Bureau of Prisons employees from mail sorting duties will result in an extensive budgetary relief to the Bureau and decrease the staffing shortages facing prisons.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H2DB9A8EB37ED4C59A936533041387D51"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="HADB4815EEB83482C996A5861A5E7763A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <quote>opioid</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 102 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/802">21 U.S.C. 802</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE03039874337405E95AA588B96BCE549"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <quote>synthetic drug</quote> means a controlled substance analogue (as such term is defined in section 102 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/802">21 U.S.C. 802</external-xref>), and includes any analogue of fentanyl.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HEE014012C2E547CA838FB6037B9C57B9"><enum>4.</enum><header>Strategy to interdict synthetic drugs in postal mail</header><subsection id="HFB03F4CC54A542B1A8A66A1370324E83"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director of the Bureau of Prisons (referred to in this Act as the <quote>Director</quote>) shall evaluate—</text><paragraph id="H91EFE85034FE4FD791414510E3979075"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Federal correctional facilities’ acquisition and deployment of synthetic drug interdiction equipment and technology;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3D57E117987B4C6D8F078980BDBFED14"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Federal correctional facilities’ use of technology services to scan mail; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H86EE8C02C4274FE69A2670074E54DF33"><enum>(3)</enum><text>whether any technologies used by other Federal agencies or State and local corrections facilities to intercept and interdict contraband in the mail may be used by the Bureau of Prisons.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCE7986A8E8A94063B86456587845D3C5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Strategy</header><text>Not later than 90 days after completing the evaluation under subsection (a), the Director shall submit to the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives a strategy to provide all Federal correctional facilities with capabilities necessary to—</text><paragraph id="H23CB8D6CEEDA4484B5D11662EFE76EAB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>protect staff and inmates from exposure to synthetic drugs and opioids introduced to facilities through the mail;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7FFD8F6236E34433818FF0B2AF717DA2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>ensure that—</text><subparagraph id="H3DD33F4EE19A4789BEE9B10CEF0D13B5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not later than 24 hours after a piece of mail is received at a Federal corrections facility or an appropriately contracted offsite location, each inmate receives a digital copy of any mail that is addressed to the inmate;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H56BBB476032140A5B71B236CF9A68EB4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not later than 30 days after receiving a digital copy of a piece of mail under subparagraph (A), the inmate receives the original physical copy of any mail that—</text><clause id="HD8A9ABA6678E49B19DBAD5100D5D05D4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>does not contain synthetic drugs or opioids; and</text></clause><clause id="H1AD562B78C18443981655DF2CE7DABE5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is addressed to the inmate; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6765C2BE32244516A3D3D0F55693DA72"><enum>(C)</enum><text>delivery to the inmate under subparagraphs (A) and (B) is documented; </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H24BCC1CBCCF74C00B316048F7C74430A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>ensure that a process is in place for the processing of legal mail that includes—</text><subparagraph id="H2195D024849D48CE9D65D024C604D7F4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the verification of the sender; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2350A90330F743B18666EB7AD11A955A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>maintains attorney client privilege as required by existing law; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7EB6DC454AE1495FA3FDAF8357F7C300"><enum>(4)</enum><text>achieve 100 percent scanning capacity of mail arriving at all Federal correction facilities.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7965D919C8DC40C9836C8DE8CD9E744C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The strategy required under subsection (b) shall—</text><paragraph id="H632EA7F951944427A0AE61BEDE0EA7A0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identify critical information technology, digital mail scanning equipment, and mail scanning services necessary to achieve the scanning capacity described in subsection (b)(4);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7BF0BA2605524C7D9025D98AB31B2122"><enum>(2)</enum><text>include an assessment of operational and logistical considerations, including—</text><subparagraph id="HCD3294B5DD6A4F72A8C75F71326DD664"><enum>(A)</enum><text>prioritization of high security and large inmate population facilities for digital mail scanning infrastructure and security technology deployment;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6E95A08E90A44A408EC40949B9D1392D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any need for additional personnel and technology training necessary to implement the strategy; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H22982A0544B7493EA494C2C4BAD2491F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>scanning equipment maintenance requirements and periodic digital technology upgrades; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAA581C9BF1B74E03ABBB8F32D18A7E3C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>include an equipment and technology budgetary proposal, for fiscal years 2025 though 2027, in order to fully implement the strategy described under subsection (b).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8847794DDFA34DD6A2174553075AF20E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Implementation deadline</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date on which the plan is submitted under subsection (a)(2), and subject to appropriations, the Director of the Bureau of Prisons shall complete implementation of the submitted plan.</text></subsection><subsection id="H30CD33E890184FC6B11B7ABF907E1478"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Annual progress reports</header><text>Beginning 1 year after the date on which the strategy is submitted under subsection (b), and each year thereafter, the Director of the Bureau of Prisons shall submit to the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives a report on the efficiency of the strategy and the total quantity of detected synthetic drugs and opioids.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

