<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE70450DCA7834D95988E2CC0E8499EF9" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1880 IH: Broadcast Freedom and Independence Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1880</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250305">March 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barrag&#225;n</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001227">Ms. McClellan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to clarify that the Federal Communications Commission may not take action against a broadcast licensee or any other person on the basis of viewpoint, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H338651724BDD48F597C0EAC32EF7D37B" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="HD98163A503A940F9861D615C7544C6A5"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Broadcast Freedom and Independence Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H7696D546C49E476184E2E255CAA7E914"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
<paragraph id="H7E076FA507AB46E8BA73BDA2F244D367"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Federal Communications Commission (in this section referred to as the <term>FCC</term>) was established as an independent agency by the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/151">47 U.S.C. 151 et seq.</external-xref>) for the purpose of <quote>regulating interstate and foreign commerce in communication by wire and radio so as to make available, so far as possible, to all the people of the United States, without discrimination on the basis of race, color, religion, national origin, or sex, a rapid, efficient, Nation-wide, and world-wide wire and radio communication service with adequate facilities at reasonable charges…</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC6E717EBB70A425DB5D1EC39166BB926"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Commissioners at the FCC, an independent agency, are confirmed by Congress for specified terms and the President does not have the power to remove them at will. </text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8B22D45473384D1899F34A5BA57230DF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The independence of the FCC is paramount to the FCC carrying out its mission without political pressure or intimidation.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H63147AC6F9B5462D8A3890EA45905E29"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The FCC’s priorities and agenda must be set by the FCC without undue influence from the President or any advisors to the President who do not work for the FCC.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC8934AD4B66A4E3EAB2D86EB80A36003"><enum>(5)</enum><text>As established in section 326 of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/326">47 U.S.C. 326</external-xref>), nothing in the FCC’s authority <quote>shall be understood or construed to give the Commission the power of censorship over the radio communications or signals transmitted by any radio station, and no regulation or condition shall be promulgated or fixed by the Commission which shall interfere with the right of free speech by means of radio communication</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF69D75094F954B0583142DF996164B9D" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Investigations and threats of Commission action or inaction must not be used to suppress certain viewpoints or intimidate broadcast licensees into aligning with any political agenda.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="HC480D771583E4A9BBA60A1D8BD961827"><enum>3.</enum><header>Viewpoint protection</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title I of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/151">47 U.S.C. 151 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB950FC87EC32405F947504B6503E9BDC"> <section id="HAD69596158844F92A282507A45A675FA"><enum>14.</enum><header>Viewpoint protection</header> <subsection id="HF163ACAD066B4355BC96DBCD1CA778EB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition against retaliation on basis of viewpoint</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission may not revoke any license or other authorization of, or otherwise take action against, any person on the basis, in whole or in part, of viewpoints broadcast or otherwise disseminated by that person or any person affiliated with that person.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HDB041C5398F54B32A7DA2DEB78029F98"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition against conditions on viewpoint in transaction review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission may not place on any approval under subsections (a), (b), and (c) of section 214 or section 310(d) any condition with respect to viewpoints broadcast or otherwise disseminated by the person seeking that approval, any successor of that person, or any person affiliated with that person or successor.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H47C91EC7AFC6467C998552908EF50143"><enum>(c)</enum><header>No effect on certain other authority of Commission</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to affect the authority of the Commission to take action on the basis of, or to place a condition on an approval described in subsection (b) with respect to—</text>
<paragraph id="H8DD061B6165F4220B75C4027831C0FE4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a violation of—</text> <subparagraph id="H1C76B4B5E6E54E10B64238C35EBF0A53"><enum>(A)</enum><text>section 1304 of title 18, United States Code, or conduct that would constitute a violation of that section if content disseminated by means other than radio or television broadcast were disseminated by means of radio or television broadcast;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H8B824ACE3D3A46E79D7E408030DE3A3F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>section 1343 of title 18, United States Code; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBFCAE4CE2C6C406D9FF75B54E846BC1A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>section 1464 of title 18, United States Code, or conduct that would constitute a violation of that section if content disseminated by means other than radio communication were disseminated by means of radio communication; or</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8C483800B56D41D1928080C3377C0DF2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the broadcast or other dissemination of content that constitutes incitement under the First Amendment to the Constitution of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> </legis-body></bill>

