<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE7ED69BBE8F0474487088DA3CDF3B6BE" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 777 IH: Commending the Council of Europe for its efforts in seeking justice for the people of Ukraine in response to Russian crime of aggression and other international crimes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 777</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250930">September 30, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Commending the Council of Europe for its efforts in seeking justice for the people of Ukraine in response to Russian crime of aggression and other international crimes.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, the Council of Europe, a prominent international organization dedicated to promoting democracy, human rights, and the rule of law, has played an essential role in addressing the ongoing humanitarian crisis and advocating for justice in the face of Russian aggression against Ukraine;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, since the beginning of Russia’s illegal annexation of Crimea in 2014 and the subsequent military incursions into Ukraine in 2022, the Council of Europe has consistently condemned these actions and their impact on the sovereignty and territorial integrity of Ukraine;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Council of Europe has actively worked to document and investigate reports of international crimes committed during the conflict, including violations of human rights, war crimes, and acts of aggression, ensuring accountability for those responsible;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Council of Europe has provided a platform for member states to collaborate in supporting Ukraine, including through the establishment of various initiatives aimed at providing humanitarian aid and support for the displaced;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Council of Europe has championed the need for a comprehensive approach to postconflict justice and reconciliation, recognizing that lasting peace in Ukraine requires accountability for those who perpetrate atrocities;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the efforts of the Council of Europe to mobilize international legal mechanisms for the prosecution of war crimes and to uphold the principles of justice serve as a critical deterrent against future violations of international law;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, under the leadership of the Council of Europe, a realistic and practical framework has been put in places to create a Special Tribunal on the Aggression against Ukraine;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Ukraine’s President Volodymyr Zelenskyy and the Secretary General of the Council of Europe have signed an agreement on the establishment of a Special Tribunal for the Crime of Aggression against Ukraine, including the Statue of the Special Tribunal; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the work of the Council of Europe aligns with the values and commitments of the United States to promote democracy, uphold human rights, and support the principle of accountability for international crimes: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H6A1F8D288B034D64804FE2C8993256CE"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HA114D3DA335E4319BF1E1151B763EB76"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> 
<paragraph id="HD089A3CE873946A6AE45758569A76CD2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>commends the Council of Europe for its unwavering commitment and ongoing efforts to seek justice for the people of Ukraine in response to Russian aggression and other international crimes;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H96372A45FEEA46CEA77955549F8A10DB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>encourages continued collaboration between the United States and the Council of Europe to support Ukraine in its pursuit of peace, justice, sovereignty, and democratic governance; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF41BB757A9264BD2947062DF909CA595"><enum>(3)</enum><text>reaffirms its commitment to stand with the people of Ukraine and to work alongside international partners to ensure accountability for those responsible for violations of international law.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

