<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="HB2FF465D1F6A4A5FAB18AAD76C6482ED" resolution-type="house-resolution"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 252 IH: Recognizing a century of broadcasting excellence from WOWO and celebrating the radio station’s 100th anniversary.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 252</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250325">March 25, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001188">Mr. Stutzman</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="Y000067">Mr. Yakym</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing a century of broadcasting excellence from WOWO and celebrating the radio station’s 100th anniversary.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas WOWO began in 1925 as one of the early radio stations in the United States and expanded into one of the strongest stations in the Midwest after joining CBS Radio Network in 1927;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in true Hoosier fashion, WOWO was the first radio station to ever broadcast a basketball game;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, by the 1950s, WOWO became a popular station for news, sports, and entertainment, ushering Fort Wayne into the rock and roll era and serving as a home to beloved radio personalities like Bob Sievers;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in the 1990s, WOWO evolved into the conservative talk radio powerhouse we know today;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas WOWO has been a consistent source of well-articulated conservative values, from the trusted and reliable voices of local commentators like Pat Miller, Charly Butcher, and Kayla Blakeslee, to nationally syndicated figures like Rush Limbaugh and Sean Hannity;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas WOWO has inspired and informed countless families in the United States about the issues that matter, and helped shape its community into a stronghold of conservative principles and common sense; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas WOWO has been affectionately known as “The Voice of a Thousand Main Streets”, a fitting tribute to its deep roots in the heartland of the United States and its role in delivering news, conversation, and connection to its listeners: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body id="H16932F3923894B149F9ACAB51B4277E3" style="traditional"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H0463080322C84FA88CF3F2BD44772FE6" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum/><text>That the House—</text><paragraph id="H216F1CC0F6E046A7B05BBB7FD55917EF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>celebrates WOWO’s 100th anniversary on air;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H575F388EDD7E4C06BF1304259D71E348"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes WOWO’s record of exemplary broadcasting, which has strengthened communities and educated countless families on the most important issues; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFF98C47E627C4C6890D313F7155680F0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>supports WOWO’s efforts to continue informing and inspiring generations to come.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

