<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H37BA09634E1D4B48952533AB4D5D977D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4652 IH: Preventing Fraudulent ICE Impersonation Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4652</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250723">July 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="C001110">Mr. Correa</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To enhance penalties for the unauthorized use and sale of Immigration and Customs Enforcement apparel and insignia, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H37E960D46F94485CBD2422C1431183FD" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HEACC6878E7FF4AB8A9A3F7F8192DD14A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Preventing Fraudulent ICE Impersonation Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="H9AC76815630340CFB28797D7B280C280"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HA2EADAE0D13740BCA9B06108799143E0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Unauthorized individuals have impersonated U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) officers, causing fear and distrust in communities.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0336BC46A4D3482EB50D85B38D17A979"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The unauthorized use of ICE insignia and apparel poses a significant risk to public safety, undermines trust in law enforcement, and facilitates fraudulent activities.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEA3A7097A9D8408CADF4C42A3118DE02"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Strengthening penalties and restricting the sale of ICE-branded apparel and insignia is necessary to protect communities from fraud and abuse.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HDD2AA35127894BDF8A9F4D8DD1657CDA"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibition on unauthorized use of ice apparel and insignia</header> <subsection id="H6E17F56FA0264B9A986047889B7AB830"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Unlawful Impersonation of an ICE Officer</header> <paragraph id="H0F5B1FDB0E9A40C9829937D24C17EFB5"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text>It shall be unlawful for any individual who is not an officer or employee of the Department of Homeland Security, acting within the scope of their official duties, to wear, display, or possess apparel, badges, insignia, or other items bearing the words <quote>ICE</quote> or <quote>Immigration and Customs Enforcement</quote> in a manner that could reasonably be interpreted as an attempt to impersonate a Federal law enforcement officer.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H70133BED31D944C7B4B5408BB5EC3A63"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Penalty</header><text>Any person who violates this subsection shall be fined under title 18, United States Code, imprisoned for not more than 7 years, or both.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H70E2AD6D7B934E45BD1E6E1BE7A96C45"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition on Sale of ICE Apparel and Insignia</header> <paragraph id="H185E537147894E45B9F7E24D9BCAE621"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>It shall be unlawful for any individual or entity to manufacture, sell, offer for sale, or distribute any apparel, badge, or insignia bearing the official marks, logos, or designations of the U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement without express authorization from the Department of Homeland Security.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD6FFBE70174745BF936BD950274B5079"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Civil penalty</header><text>Any person or entity who violates this subsection shall be subject to a civil penalty of not more than $100,000 per violation.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HFFA8D9DFCA5547AAAB9BB4C0E82B53BD"><enum>4.</enum><header>Seizure and forfeiture</header> <subsection id="HAD05AAE43B844C6497629886233C8001"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Seizure and forfeiture</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any unauthorized ICE apparel or insignia manufactured, sold, distributed, or possessed in violation of this Act shall be subject to seizure and forfeiture in accordance with <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/46">chapter 46</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H41196858DC15413DA61BEB1AD316D2BA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sentencing enhancement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States Sentencing Commission shall take such actions as may be necessary to provide that impersonation of an immigration official shall result in an enhancement of any term of imprisonment of no less than 6 months.</text></subsection> </section> <section id="HE29B1C7CDF5C40EEBA5826D7A74DC67D"><enum>5.</enum><header>Public awareness and reporting mechanism</header> <subsection id="HC288577B1B4248CDA923C0926A518148"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security shall establish a public awareness campaign to inform communities about the dangers of individuals impersonating ICE officers and provide resources for reporting such activities.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H59D49815093641DFB09047E5635A4AB5"><enum>(b)</enum><text>The Secretary shall also establish a national reporting mechanism, including a dedicated hotline and online portal, to facilitate the reporting of individuals impersonating ICE officers.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H5908769CCE8442879F6D125343E25F6D"><enum>(c)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act and every 180 days thereafter, the Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a study on the impersonation of immigration officials and the underlying factors that should be considered for any potential solution to the issue, and submit thereon a report to Congress.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HC34E6F1EBA8F47DEAE4B18E7EC92E8B6"><enum>6.</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security shall issue regulations necessary to carry out this Act not later than 180 days after the date of enactment.</text> </section> <section id="H5D2B4212423144CF8DE19D7A96B84730"><enum>7.</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act—</text> 
<paragraph id="H036A59AA205B4788A39F7746F514EA07"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>ICE</term> means U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF097CAE83CD641818D7A3C404BD07108"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>official</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HA95F558E753F4324A7D2DDAF8CFFB140"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a public official, as such term is defined in section 201(a)(1) of title 18, United States Code; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF00773BBA76440F6843CFF3534E342BA"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a person who has been selected to be a public official, as such term is defined in section 201(a)(2) of title 18, United States Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

