<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HAA07E187461B400BAB29E17824905900" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 321 IH: Supporting the goals and ideals of the Rise Up for LGBTQI+ Youth in Schools Initiative, a call to action to communities across the country to demand equal educational opportunity, basic civil rights protections, and freedom from erasure for all students, particularly LGBTQI+ young people, in K–12 schools.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 321</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250409">April 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001156">Ms. Sánchez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001200">Mr. Soto</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Supporting the goals and ideals of the Rise Up for LGBTQI+ Youth in Schools Initiative, a call to action to communities across the country to demand equal educational opportunity, basic civil rights protections, and freedom from erasure for all students, particularly LGBTQI+ young people, in K–12 schools.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas young people, teachers, school staff, families, and communities must be free from transphobia, homophobia, racism, sexism, and ableism in K–12 schools;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas K–12 schools must be safe and inclusive learning environments that include and affirm LGBTQI+ young people, especially those who are transgender, nonbinary, intersex, Black, Indigenous, people of color, and people with disabilities and those who are from communities that experience marginalization;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, for more than 2 decades, Congress has supported a resolution for a <quote>National Day of Silence</quote>, and for a decade, Congress has supported a resolution for <quote>No Name-Calling Week</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas advocates have designated 2025 to 2026 as a time for communities to support the Rise Up for LGBTQI+ Youth in Schools Initiative in support of LGBTQI+ young people in schools by building on the goals of <quote>National Day of (No) Silence</quote> and <quote>No Name-Calling Week</quote> to create a sustained call to action to demand equal educational opportunities, basic civil rights protections, and freedom from erasure for all students;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas LGBTQI+ young people frequently experience bias-based bullying and harassment, discrimination, and punitive discipline that increases the likelihood they will enter the school-to-prison pipeline;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas over 200 anti-LGBTQI+ education bills have been introduced each year in State legislatures across the country, the majority of which specifically target transgender and nonbinary young people, including—</text><paragraph id="H81AF26F60E16419E974BE880A1CB9F5F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the 26 States that have enacted policies between 2021 and 2025 that prohibit transgender students from playing alongside their peers on school sports teams; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0D6E8AC00A6B4F04AACE27B230502D5A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the 17 States that have enacted laws between 2021 and 2025 that prevent transgender students from using the school bathroom or locker room that corresponds with their gender identity;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas GLSEN’s 2021 National School Climate Survey found that LGBTQI+ students who experienced discrimination on the basis of their LGBTQI+ identity at school in the past year, including being prevented from using the restroom that aligned with their gender identity and being barred from playing on the school sports team that aligned with their gender identity, were nearly 3 times as likely to have missed school in the past month, had lower grade point averages, reported lower feelings of school belonging, and had higher levels of depression compared to LGBTQI+ students who had not experienced similar discrimination;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas LGBTQI+ young people are more likely than their non-LGBTQI+ peers to experience mental health concerns, including stress, anxiety, and depression;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas nearly half of LGBTQI+ young people seriously considered suicide in the last year, a trend that increases among Indigenous, Black, and multiracial LGBTQI+ young people;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the GLSEN’s 2021 National School Climate Survey found that, among LGBTQI+ students who said that they were considering dropping out of school, 31.4 percent indicated that they were doing so because of the hostile climate created by gendered school policies and practices;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas States have passed or attempted to pass legislation that erases or censors LGBTQI+ individuals, history, and contributions from classroom literature and curricula, including—</text><paragraph id="H7537DBD05ADD49A39E1B4CAC291A156F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in 9 States that enacted laws between 2022 and 2025 censoring instruction related to LGBTQI+ people; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H95F27059DC9E4F25A983F34FDB676711"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in 8 States that enacted laws between 2021 and 2025 that treat instruction related to LGBTQI+ individuals in history, science, the arts, or any academic class as a sensitive topic that requires parental notification and allows parents to opt their child out of such instruction;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas these laws harm students and force families to consider leaving their homes, as demonstrated in a Williams Institute report, which found that 56 percent of LGBTQI+ parents of students in Florida considered moving out of Florida, and 16.5 percent have taken steps to move out of Florida because of the passage of the Parental Rights in Education Act by the State in 2022;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas States have gone farther by specifically targeting transgender students and their families with policies that attack mental health counseling and gender-affirming care for transgender students, including the introduction of at least 35 bills in 18 States since the beginning of the 2025 legislative session that prohibit or create barriers to the social affirmation of transgender and nonbinary students in schools, such as using a student’s chosen name and pronouns, regardless of the risk to the student’s safety, health, and well-being;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 86 percent of transgender and nonbinary young people say that recent debates prompted by State legislation restricting the rights of transgender individuals have negatively impacted their mental health;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas data provided by the Department of Justice show that there were a reported 247 anti-LGBTQ hate crimes in schools in 2023;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas every young person must have equal educational opportunity and freedom from the fear that their basic civil and educational rights will be taken away from them;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas young people who develop in positive school climates, free from bullying, harassment, and discrimination, report greater physical and psychological safety, greater mental well-being, and improved educational and life outcomes;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas positive school transformation must recognize that safety is too low of a bar and that all communities deserve to be acknowledged and affirmed in schools;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas students and families, educators, and community members in every State and territory are advocating for safe and inclusive learning environments that affirm LGBTQI+ young people, particularly those who are transgender, nonbinary, intersex, Black, Indigenous, people of color, and people with disabilities;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas affirming policies such as enumerated antibullying protections, gender neutral dress code guidelines, and inclusive learning practices are proven strategies to address hostile learning environments for all students; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas we must all demand the best possible future for all young people in schools, particularly those who identify as LGBTQI+, without exception: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="OLC" id="HEA5181F21850402D886BCBE2EBAB8190"><section id="HF8DCF5CB22144BBD82965538FC60D184" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="H76D8C5F7D56B4714AF30D90D698D2C60"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supports the goals and ideals of the Rise Up for LGBTQI+ Youth in Schools Initiative in demanding the best possible future for all young people in schools, particularly those who identify as LGBTQI+;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4EF1B71CF327458285B052281C88ED0F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the contributions of students and families, educators, and community members participating in the <quote>National Day of (No) Silence</quote>, to draw attention to the bullying, harassment, assault, and discrimination faced by LGBTQI+ students; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3986A912879B41648611D6EE791A4BC7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>encourages each State, territory, and locality to support the Rise Up for LGBTQI+ Youth in Schools Initiative and adopt laws and policies that prohibit bias-based victimization, exclusion, and erasure. </text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

