<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9AF7233D40A44E5C82585E8FEA47F2FB" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3766 IH: To prohibit the District of Columbia from requiring tribunals in court or administrative proceedings in the District of Columbia to defer to the Mayor of the District of Columbia’s interpretation of statutes and regulations, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3766</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250605">June 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001096">Ms. Hageman</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the District of Columbia from requiring tribunals in court or administrative proceedings in the District of Columbia to defer to the Mayor of the District of Columbia’s interpretation of statutes and regulations, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE13D942E99554ED29B496BAD1DD63546" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HE8D002E6456C4798B52C50FEC22E650C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Prohibiting District of Columbia from requiring tribunals to defer to Mayor’s interpretation of statutes and regulations</header> 
<subsection id="H6C75B7DD5BA04786BEC7844CD6CE48DC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The District of Columbia may not require a reviewing tribunal—</text> <paragraph id="H6EEA58F5D18C40F898F715CE1E687BE2"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>in reviewing an order or decision of the Mayor of the District of Columbia or an agency of the District of Columbia in any court or administrative proceeding in the District of Columbia, including judicial review proceedings, to defer to the Mayor's or agency's interpretation of a statute or regulation the Mayor or agency administers; or</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDC1A802C1DC24F01BEB2333B48CE7B10">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>in reviewing a rule adopted by the Mayor or an agency, to defer to the Mayor's or agency's interpretation of a statute the Mayor or agency administers.</text>
        </paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFFC65532E0734169BDB38DAA55A8EFD9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Repeal of temporary emergency legislation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Review of Agency Action Clarification Temporary Amendment Act of 2024 (D.C. Law 25–290) is hereby repealed, and any provision of law amended or repealed by such Act is restored or revived as if such Act had not been enacted into law.</text> </subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

