<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-joint" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" slc-id="S1-OLL25A75-LFY-Y2-2M9"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SJ 75 IS: Terminating the emergency determined by the President on August 11, 2025, in the Executive Order titled “Declaring a crime emergency in the District of Columbia”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IIA</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. J. RES. 75</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250902">September 2, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S313">Mr. Sanders</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S426">Mr. Kim</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S428">Ms. Alsobrooks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S366">Ms. Warren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S327">Mr. Warner</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S422">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>) introduced the following joint resolution; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>JOINT RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Terminating the emergency determined by the President on August 11, 2025, in the Executive Order titled <quote>Declaring a crime emergency in the District of Columbia</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the President has failed to identify special conditions of an emergency nature that compel the use of the Metropolitan Police Department for Federal purposes in the District of Columbia;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas violent crime in the District of Columbia has declined for the past 2 years and currently stands at a 30-year low; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Federal Government, in 2025, has prevented the District of Columbia from spending $1,000,000,000 of its own locally raised revenues—money that was budgeted for essential public safety purposes, including law enforcement, fire and emergency response services, and schools: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="OLC" id="HA0A1A68108DF413F9D4DAD97D83E3562"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H3F6C12698E0E47588D46E5081E56B84E"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That pursuant to section 740(b) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act (sec. 1–207.40(b), D.C. Official Code), the emergency determined by the President on August 11, 2025, in the Executive order titled <quote>Declaring a crime emergency in the District of Columbia</quote> is hereby terminated. </text></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

