<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC6E5FCA192C2457596CD77E395421CF0" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4208 IH: Taxpayer Protection Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4208</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250626">June 26, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000474">Mrs. Torres of California</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the political punishment of donor States, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8F173F1A396145DDAA02EFC353AEEB8B" style="OLC"><section id="H1D62746EB6744894AFD070879F6FF592" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Taxpayer Protection Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H39A5D3DD51F24C8194D8DD1C14451AA5"><enum>2.</enum><header>No political punishment of donor States</header><subsection id="HCD20A241508E487495236A41A6F75AA9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>No general prohibitions on providing Federal funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the President, or any other member of the executive branch, may not target a donor State by imposing a general prohibition on awarding a grant to, or entering into a contract or other agreement with, the donor State (or a political subdivision of such donor State, or a public or nonprofit entity in such donor State).</text></subsection><subsection id="HEF77F65CABC14282907B2169AE986BFB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>No revocations or suspensions of Federal funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the President, or any other member of the executive branch, may not revoke or suspend any grant, contract, or other agreement awarded to, or entered into with, a donor State (or a political subdivision of such donor State, or a public or nonprofit entity in such donor State), unless the Comptroller General of the United States determines that the donor State (or such political subdivision or entity) has committed fraud, waste, or abuse with respect to such grant, contract, or agreement.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD993F40A0F1E4BE295B071DA744F1494"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section—</text><paragraph id="H0A4F3A3E1D64413EA008CA7D97F4951D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Donor State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>donor State</term> means any State the taxpayers of which have on average, over the 3-year period preceding the date of the enactment of this Act, paid a total amount in Federal income taxes that exceeds the average total amount of Federal funding provided to the State over such period.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA1AFDD9757EF43C69B235D98236E948E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Public entity</header><text>The term <term>public entity</term> includes public schools and public hospitals.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HDEFAD98E420E45CDA63C9819DB2A1F97" section-type="subsequent-section" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>3.</enum><header>Donor State Protection Trust Fund</header><subsection id="H4BD4FAD5D8744D7D84321A1106E2E385"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/98">Chapter 98</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H89D0C5EBDE394DCFA09034C23F5CF151" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="H99B13FC67DB640F08E3ABB4DAFC188B7"><enum>9512.</enum><header>Donor State Protection Trust Fund</header><subsection id="HF9E85AE87F6E45B09A1759582C1B0A8E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Creation of Trust Fund</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is hereby established in the Treasury of the United States a trust fund to be known as the <quote>Donor State Protection Trust Fund</quote>, consisting of such amounts as may be appropriated to such Trust Fund as provided in this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H205670D27D704C78990515394736A7CE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Transfer to Trust Fund of amounts equivalent to certain taxes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are hereby appropriated to the Donor State Protection Trust Fund amounts equivalent to the taxes received in the Treasury under subtitle A paid by the taxpayers of donor States. For each calendar year, if the unobligated amounts in such Trust Fund exceed $4,000,000,000,000 on December 31 of such year, such excess amounts shall be transferred to the general fund of the Treasury.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5704305066554B808BC8BDF704E4BA6A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Availability of and expenditures from Trust Fund</header><paragraph id="H1BC2EA70951844109A488A2E25F5B34F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts in the Donor State Protection Trust Fund shall be available, without further appropriation, to a donor State—</text><subparagraph id="H4ED01503704449F2B6FE35564BA36C73"><enum>(A)</enum><text>if, and only if, the President, or another member of the executive branch—</text><clause id="HC278EA17F7E040CCAFA5968CCF0585A7"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">imposes, in violation of section 2(a) of the Taxpayer Protection Act, a general prohibition on awarding a grant to, or entering into a contract or other agreement with, the donor State (or a political subdivision of such donor State, or a public or nonprofit entity in such donor State), or</text></clause><clause id="H6F722E530AD94C9E8A34C01E91CB7823"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">revokes or suspends, in violation of section 2(b) of such Act, a grant, contract, or other agreement awarded to, or entered into with, the donor State (or such political subdivision or entity), and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEB8A75100F6644EC9242F81964D7EC0F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for the purpose of making any expenditures determined necessary or appropriate by the donor State.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H65C9619CA33C42E89E40AB545EE803C5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any grant, contract, or other agreement that is revoked or suspended, as described in paragraph (1)(A)(ii), with respect to a donor State (or a political subdivision of such donor State, or a public or nonprofit entity in such donor State), the amounts in the Trust Fund available to the donor State shall be limited to the amount equal to the amount the donor State (or such political subdivision or entity) would have received under such grant, contract, or agreement but for such revocation or suspension.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE558A772DCA846ECBEB61D876649CFC1" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the terms <term>donor State</term> and <term>public entity</term> have the meaning given such terms in section 2(c) of the Taxpayer Protection Act.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HED2F8C1737B049B48E0E9CDCC7B44A2C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for subchapter A of chapter 98 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H005E2BDBFB674DA4A83ACB9DBB1C98DA" display-inline="no-display-inline"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry idref="H99B13FC67DB640F08E3ABB4DAFC188B7" level="section">9512. Donor State Protection Trust Fund.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HBB74B3E50BF14B589DDE17304BDB8832"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this Act shall apply to taxes received after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

