<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H747E8FF004BD413DBB7229833F67A785" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2047 IH: Pink Tariffs Study Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2047</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250311">March 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000468">Mrs. Fletcher</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="P000620">Ms. Pettersen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000560">Mr. Larsen of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require a study on the manner and extent to which the tariff rates assessed by the United States on imports are regressive or demonstrate a gender bias, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H48772E8CB2F043EAAE914F6215EB0B66" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H9413AE1AF0A1491A8BC5E7AE54F13C07" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Pink Tariffs Study Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H85FA71DFB0D04450991CD5DE7201FBCB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Study required</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Treasury, in coordination with the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection and in consultation with the United States International Trade Commission and the United States Trade Representative, shall submit to Congress the results of a study of the manner and extent to which the rates of tariffs and the revenues collected from tariffs assessed by the United States on articles imported into the customs territory of the United States—</text>
<paragraph id="H7A666805C45F40F0B189527E5B2C6D6D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>are regressive with respect to the degree to which the burden of such tariffs fall on consumers (such as tariffs that are higher on mass-market consumer goods as compared to analogous luxury goods), including an analysis of the manner and extent to which importation of the applicable goods is foregone to avoid the burden of the tariff;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3C594D0619A6451A814018C79EEB5D44"><enum>(2)</enum><text>demonstrate a bias with respect to the gender of consumer most likely to import such article (such as tariffs that are higher on clothing classifiable as women’s clothing as compared to men’s clothing);</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HFF78A3CEDC1849849FB9148F0D0F6242"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a disaggregation of the effects described in paragraphs (1) and (2) with respect to consumers based on gender and household type (single-parent families, double-parent families, other) and income level; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEC0AF532C8D34ACEB4178A6F391E1E28"><enum>(4)</enum><text>such other matters relating to the manner and extent to which the burden of tariffs assessed by the United States on imports falls unequally among certain categories of consumers or households in the United States as the Secretary may determine relevant.</text></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

