<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5CCA5A94FF014181AA7F3B782575D99B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1017 IH: Stop the Invasion of Women’s Spaces Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1017</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250205">February 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000194">Ms. Mace</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit an entity from receiving Federal funds if such entity permits an individual to access or use a single-sex facility on the property of such entity that does not correspond to the biological sex of such person, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD571F943A1F34AACB74195AAC7BEA6D8" style="OLC"><section id="HC58E31E40453402B8440FC91155D249B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop the Invasion of Women’s Spaces Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HB34EEFB195EB4B789A39BF3BDEA5032B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition</header><subsection id="H3C498A74299D48BDBAC0FE8AB7E45953"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law and except as provided in subsection (b), Federal funds may not be provided, directly or indirectly, to an entity if such entity permits an individual to access or use a single-sex facility on the property of such entity that does not correspond to the biological sex of such person, except as provided by subsection (c).</text></subsection><subsection id="HCF669054C434472FB08984D150BEF43A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Subsection (a) shall not apply with respect to an entity that permits an individual to access a single-sex facility on the property of such entity that does not correspond to the biological sex of such person in the circumstance of—</text><paragraph id="H40AEB2E48B71428BABFD9ED3114D371A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>emergency medical personnel responding to a medical emergency; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H869F0CC1B7A2490BAA0275E3ACCF3CD2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a law enforcement officer in active pursuit of a suspect, or as part of an active investigation.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDBF0E3F3298F408FB4B67808C503FFA9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H856F56EBBFBF45A8A35EE7F2C5FDFB5C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Biological sex</header><text>The term <term>biological sex</term> means the biological determination as to whether an individual is male or female.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF33FA1B3788149689338B769B3D041E8" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Entity</header><text>The term <term>entity</term> means any private entity, non-Federal Government agency or department, or State, Tribal, or local government (including a political subdivision, department, or component thereof). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4761FDFCA133408F849AE901FC8A3051"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Female</header><text>The term <term>female</term> means an individual who naturally has, had, will have, or would have, but for a developmental or genetic anomaly or historical accident, the reproductive system that at some point produces, transports, and uses eggs for fertilization.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE7C3F232585848D0B84FAE2E271496C4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Male</header><text>The term <term>male</term> means an individual who naturally has, had, will have, or would have, but for a developmental or genetic anomaly or historical accident, the reproductive system that at some point produces, transports, and uses sperm for fertilization.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HED1364E41D83495A99D3C66901007352"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Property</header><text>The term <term>property</term> means any building, land, or other real property owned, leased, controlled, or occupied by an entity.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAFCF722EC32345AAA3CD318E7EED8924"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Single-sex facility</header><text>The term <term>single-sex facility</term> means a space intended for the use of one biological sex (male or female), including a—</text><subparagraph id="HCDB31EE757134CAFA9CD6891A87072F9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>restroom;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA186274527AB454FB31970B56E3F6BD7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>locker room; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCF7CA9ACC74A4CA08FD3716445C930CB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>changing room.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

