<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-LIP25023-J67-LH-WPR"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S64 IS: To direct the United States Postal Service to designate a single, unique ZIP Code for Fairlawn, Virginia, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 64</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250109">January 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S327">Mr. Warner</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To direct the United States Postal Service to designate a single, unique ZIP Code for Fairlawn, Virginia, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H17BC06138B334E63AC9795F104130808"><section section-type="section-one" id="HB916648C273949B8B4CC556103D557C4"><enum>1.</enum><header>ZIP Code for Fairlawn, Virginia</header><subsection id="H096C15595E674005A7FE4F4C211E8940"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="HCAD06DA1EA564040A976F0B4C67969A7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Commonwealth of Virginia is the only State in the United States where all cities are independent from their surrounding counties;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4825ABF2C9C1490EB8D5204B9CB22F08"><enum>(2)</enum><text>these independent cities are not politically a part of the surrounding counties, even if they are located within their borders;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7EC22755016A4AE69617E409C5600979"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in Virginia these independent cities are subject to separate revenue collection and distribution practices related to roads, resources, and sales tax than neighboring counties;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB9B1DA5667F74CFEAA5F143E0C975388"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the sales tax collected from electronic commerce from the unincorporated community of Fairlawn, Virginia, located in Pulaski County, is often misallocated to the independent city of Radford, Virginia, because they share the same ZIP Codes; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6807B19C59B94424998F9C1827EFC3C3"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Fairlawn, Virginia, should be eligible to obtain a separate and unique ZIP Code from the neighboring independent city of Radford, Virginia, for tax purposes.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H894DA75D6AC641CDB7F5613CB6F5C346"><enum>(b)</enum><header>ZIP Code designation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the United States Postal Service shall designate a single, unique ZIP Code applicable to Fairlawn, Virginia.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

