<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF84FC250CD074C4BB46AD89DD3B5817D" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 399 IH: Congratulating Gregg Popovich, former Head Coach of the San Antonio Spurs and the winningest head coach in National Basketball Association history, on his retirement.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 399</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250508">May 8, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000594">Mr. Tony Gonzales of Texas</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Congratulating Gregg Popovich, former Head Coach of the San Antonio Spurs and the winningest head coach in National Basketball Association history, on his retirement.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, on May 2, 2025, Coach Popovich retired from his legendary career with the San Antonio Spurs, a franchise he helped lead and transform since joining in 1988;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, following a prior stint as an assistant coach with the Spurs, Coach Popovich returned to the organization as General Manager and Vice President of Basketball Operations in 1994, and in 1996, assumed the role of Head Coach—a position he held for 29 seasons;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Coach Popovich holds the record for the most wins of any head coach in National Basketball Association (NBA) history;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, during Coach Popovich’s tenure, he led the Spurs to five NBA championships in 1999, 2003, 2005, 2007, and 2014, and six Western Conference championships in 1999, 2003, 2005, 2007, 2013, and 2014;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Coach Popovich was named NBA Coach of the Year three times, in 2003, 2012, and 2014, and served as the NBA All-Star Game Head Coach four times, in 2005, 2011, 2013, and 2016;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Coach Popovich led the United States Men’s Olympic Basketball Team to a gold medal at the 2020 Tokyo Olympics;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2023, Coach Popovich was inducted into the Naismith Memorial Basketball Hall of Fame in recognition of his unparalleled contributions to the game;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas prior to Coach Popovich’s coaching career, he graduated from the United States Air Force Academy and served five years of active duty in the United States Air Force, including a tour through Eastern Europe and the Soviet Union with the United States Armed Forces Basketball Team; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Coach Popovich stated, <quote>I’m forever grateful to the wonderful players, coaches, staff and fans who allowed me to serve them as the Spurs head coach and am excited for the opportunity to continue to support the organization, community and city that are so meaningful to me</quote>: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="OLC" id="H2E8D10CDB3CC40B98AC08558D2F31E5C"><section id="H31D6D6463BE84C05A6A460CCF02FD531" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the House of Representatives— </text><paragraph id="H3E84E458E13F4C07BF15D86C6BDCD92B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>commends Gregg Popovich for his historic and record-setting career in the National Basketball Association, including five NBA championships and the most coaching wins in league history;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H42FB68C399E440C48A92A2D6E3342C58"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes his lasting contributions not only to the San Antonio Spurs organization but also to the broader San Antonio community and the sport of basketball;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6512D930EACF47579A351F59710ABD09"><enum>(3)</enum><text>congratulates Coach Popovich on his retirement and extends best wishes for continued success; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H61E444B99BC6475B927CEEA40B33EF62"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">directs the Clerk of the House of Representatives to transmit an enrolled copy of this resolution to Gregg Popovich, President of Basketball Operations, San Antonio Spurs.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

