<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC547F295DFD04BAE910490EFAB1F3394" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2730 IH: Military Moms Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2730</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250408">April 8, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000194">Ms. Mace</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S001196">Ms. Stefanik</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000804">Mr. Wittman</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000463">Mr. Turner of Ohio</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To include pregnancy and loss of pregnancy as qualifying life events under the TRICARE program and to require a study on maternal health in the military heath system, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HCE5C6ABADE044FB284DB780A365D9BC9" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HF792DF8901754F74A49D4C592941A925" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Military Moms Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H98F47E293C734069AC9018B06573C847"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
<paragraph id="H6AD5B71C45EA4C18A8EF5B3D21878CEC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered beneficiary; dependent; TRICARE program</header><text>The terms <term>covered beneficiary</term>, <term>dependent</term>, and <term>TRICARE program</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 1072 of title 10, United States Code.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H464A11C61A7C46DAA19A0374D3CB3807"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Maternal health</header><text>The term <term>maternal health</term> means care during labor, birthing, prenatal care, and postpartum care.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD505C55D7F394ED6924A9D9C43CE6014"><enum>(3)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Maternity care desert</header><text> The term <term>maternity care desert</term> means a county in the United States that does not have—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H073B574B78404BA8A1B70B2A94D17F4B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a hospital or birth center offering obstetric care; or </text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1AED7CF59B57442B83371B11A483CED5"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an obstetric provider.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H99D3A94035C540E39240FBFB9C8DB53B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Prenatal care</header><text>The term <term>prenatal care</term> means medical care provided to maintain and improve fetal and maternal health during pregnancy.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4534D15729DE4708B2F2A816F0387C9C" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(5)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Defense. </text></paragraph></section> <section id="H44D26A415ACE4FF2973D7D59A9ED9F0F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Modification of qualifying life events</header> <subsection id="H3B6760AF24C44922B3C0E4C3F20FC617"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall—</text>
<paragraph id="H7D6DE113970D439A93C8B2B48F4755E4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>update the list of qualifying life events under the TRICARE program to include pregnancy and loss of pregnancy; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H89A1F4C9B19447598E0B68E6F36D32CC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>issue guidance to covered beneficiaries describing the documentation required to make enrollment changes under the TRICARE program due to such qualifying life events, such as written confirmation from a medical provider confirming a pregnancy or loss of pregnancy.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H0216418981E64E0EAE145587C6EDAE24"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>This section shall not apply to a covered beneficiary who seeks to claim an abortion as a qualifying life event.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HA9E5AEE65BEA4BF8BA2C03B58F5131D4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text>
<paragraph id="H0518AA6F4C17427DB38D1729ADEC5C5F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Abortion</header><text>The term <term>abortion</term> means the use or prescription of any instrument, medicine, drug, or other substance or device to intentionally—</text> <subparagraph id="H736ED7FB482641A3A9A6BCC76C8B946D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>kill the unborn child of a woman known to be pregnant; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H12381E04A8E647859624DA74C7306136"><enum>(B)</enum><text>prematurely terminate the pregnancy of a woman known to be pregnant, with an intention other than to—</text> <clause id="H4C7E8756246042F3997F80E6578A9117"><enum>(i)</enum><text>increase the probability of a live birth or preserve the life or health of the child after a live birth;</text></clause>
<clause id="HBFB536F805A64A5DBA487870A5756D50" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>remove a dead unborn child; or</text></clause> <clause id="H16C202D8CDBF4C3F9017B34DE720E033"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>treat an ectopic pregnancy.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4D587B7D3958430EA3DF6D8263F05D9A"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Loss of pregnancy</header><text>The term <term>loss of pregnancy</term> means miscarriage or stillbirth.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H9A34D5D3EB7842999792F59E96B3D040"><enum>4.</enum><header>Report on access to maternal health care within the military health system</header> <subsection id="H0487CC8B661C4DA4BE9EA4558223081E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than two years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives a report on access to maternal health care within the military health system for covered beneficiaries during the preceding two-year period.</text></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1D599B41E5AB4798B47EE37222C7741B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report required under subsection (a) shall include the following:</text> <paragraph id="HDC179D9F171E4485839EDF0AF274A2E4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>With respect to military medical treatment facilities, the following:</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB6C5F95B01984E088112E5E2490BF529"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An analysis of the availability of maternal health care for covered beneficiaries who access the military health system through such facilities.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H31677439F16A4966B5505A5BCD4D89BE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An identification of staffing shortages in positions relating to maternal health and childbirth, including obstetrician-gynecologists, certified nurse midwives, and labor and delivery nurses.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H71BB8D3EA99D42CF889AC8C4F6E8E2C2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A description of specific challenges faced by covered beneficiaries in accessing maternal health care at such facilities.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H853CAB986BEB4B989116DE49898E9AF5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>An analysis of the timeliness of access to maternal health care, including wait times for and travel times to appointments.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD7A59C66BE284BF79177FE3AF6EA16B3"><enum>(E)</enum><text>A description of how such facilities track patient satisfaction with maternal health services.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE4357648885743769D3EF03E390AA6D9"><enum>(F)</enum><text>A process to establish continuity of prenatal care and postpartum care for covered beneficiaries who experience a permanent change of station during a pregnancy. </text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H34BDD1461AA54CB2815A33D560C3388F"><enum>(G)</enum><text>An identification of barriers with regard to continuity of prenatal care and postpartum care during permanent changes of station. </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3E1D2EFFDAF44F2C8221AA57ABDF5567"><enum>(H)</enum><text>A description of military-specific health challenges impacting covered beneficiaries who receive maternal health care at military medical treatment facilities, and a description of how the Department tracks such challenges. </text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HC49C0D61897D447E8898B93518109495"><enum>(I)</enum><text>For the 10-year period preceding the date of the submission of the report, the amount of funds annually expended—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD223CC509D7247F7855959F8B8678FE5"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by the Department of Defense on maternal health care; and</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB1D0F78FA81C47729E305B5D9DCF6B02"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by covered beneficiaries on out-of-pocket costs associated with maternal health care.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAB066CB22A5240B38E07031A57AA4B1A"><enum>(J)</enum><text>An identification of each medical facility of the Department of Defense located in a maternity care desert.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBB50C6B539FF400E857F85AB3FEA963D"><enum>(K)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Recommendations and legislative proposals—</text> <clause id="H2E00019B2EF347B39551CED25E25B219"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to address staffing shortages that impact the positions described in subparagraph (B);</text></clause>
<clause id="HFE76FC8B8D05462EA7A0F454E3F4B9D2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to improve the delivery and availability of maternal health services through military medical treatment facilities and improve patient experience; and</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H29A4621049C14473A51D03D40A27076F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to improve continuity of prenatal care and postpartum care for covered beneficiaries during a permanent change of station. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H363C8A06FCEB411A97A3DC18784309D0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>With respect to providers within the TRICARE program network that are not located at or affiliated with a military medical treatment facility, the following:</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8809B490DAEB4402BC4BE136EB2D05A9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An analysis of the availability of maternal health care for covered beneficiaries who access the military health system through such providers.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HDBE5E74609904DE2AF4775CF10B51101"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An identification of staffing shortages for such providers in positions relating to maternal health and childbirth, including obstetrician-gynecologists, certified nurse midwives, and labor and delivery nurses.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD5F0590F5F1A413EBE2C40237A51846D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A description of specific challenges faced by covered beneficiaries in accessing maternal health care from such providers.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HF6C59D735F2C4FBF842FFC704539826C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>An analysis of the timeliness of access to maternal health care, including wait times for and travel times to appointments.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0195E5C045204126A86689AE05C0BF9B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>A description of how such providers track patient satisfaction with maternal health services.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H9C7A6075A0EC44E5973CCB4562EFB57B"><enum>(F)</enum><text>A process to establish continuity of prenatal care and postpartum care for covered beneficiaries who experience a permanent change of station during a pregnancy. </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H32A2E3E2D25C43D6B6A011B1B9816ABD"><enum>(G)</enum><text>An identification of barriers with regard to continuity of prenatal care and postpartum care during permanent changes of station. </text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0C55124C399442B5BB52B81BE916E317"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number of dependents who choose to access maternal health care through such providers.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE2EB5F16A0234C75B9683BCFDE523A69"><enum>(I)</enum><text>For the 10-year period preceding the date of the submission of the report, the amount of funds annually expended—</text>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6BCCCCDC70E94249B7DDD6379181E3D2"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by the Department of Defense on maternal health care; and</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBAFFF7AA3F7B40FFA3E3D4CDB48B84D3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by covered beneficiaries on out-of-pocket costs associated with maternal health care. </text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HC169CBDD354C4863B27204D6C4E89474"><enum>(J)</enum><text>Recommendations and legislative proposals—</text> <clause id="HC04A1C5BBDE44C31A786464ACF13B100"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to address staffing shortages that impact the positions described in subparagraph (B);</text></clause>
<clause id="HDB7963F07E2747618024BEC9E4FB8F3C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to improve the delivery and availability of maternal health services through the TRICARE program and improve patient experience;</text></clause> <clause id="H719CE764D97E467FB42D96F8FB32589B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to improve continuity of prenatal care and postpartum care for covered beneficiaries during a permanent change of station; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H0C84E5F780A54D80854A08E4C6353E62" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>to improve the ability of contractors under the TRICARE program to build a larger network of providers for maternal health, including obstetrician-gynecologists, certified nurse midwives, and labor and delivery nurses. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H476DBD78C0124F4489B8408DB9F2250D"><enum>5.</enum><header>Updates to Military OneSource program</header> <subsection id="HB182F2ABE6F84698A140B2F3098E653D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall publish on a publicly available website of the Military OneSource program of the Department of Defense a dedicated webpage that includes a comprehensive guide of resources available to covered beneficiaries, including—</text>
<paragraph id="HF269F3516B9A45B684989886008EFA58"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a list of maternal health services that are available to covered beneficiaries under the TRICARE program and at military medical treatment facilities;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB42292D0856F4E97A6EB24EAD97367D6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>information on mental health counseling, pregnancy counseling, and other prepartum and postpartum services, including what services are reportable or non-reportable for members of the Armed Forces;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HAE6591824AEF421DA04D9A9F6770AFD1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>information on prenatal development, including anticipated prenatal appointments and available care for covered beneficiaries during prenatal development;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBC5F0214CB6047C19B51CBBC92265207"><enum>(4)</enum><text>information on—</text>
<subparagraph id="HF1B5C2C0BC8948D1BE9E72622DD2A9E4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>organizations that provide services and other resources to assist covered beneficiaries with maternal health needs and pregnancy support services located at, or in vicinity of, military installations; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7D21A7EAD4E84D33A1422DD4E22A8257"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Federal, State, and local maternal health care resources that are either covered by the TRICARE program or could otherwise be made available to a covered beneficiary;</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H3BD267DE5A9C4D4CBA059BEEA02A9FBC"><enum>(5)</enum><text>information on resources to assist covered beneficiaries who are pregnant with anticipated changes and health challenges that result from pregnancy, including information on anticipated postnatal appointments, available postnatal care for covered beneficiaries, and post-birth instructions specific to covered beneficiaries;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC82A83E718154A49AC244E704EDB725F"><enum>(6)</enum><text>information on financial assistance available to covered beneficiaries to support pregnancy needs; </text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0785CD32AE3548DFA1084B46CB921661"><enum>(7)</enum><text>a best practice guide for smooth continuity of pregnancy care during a permanent change of station; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H93F8358160CC4DE98FF9673AC596E3EE"><enum>(8)</enum><text>information specific to pregnant members of the Armed Forces, including leave options and regulations, career field specific information and restrictions, physical fitness requirements, and uniform resources and requirements.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HA5778ACCD39945F0B6F99A2AC4B93A7C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitations</header><text>The guide required by subsection (a) may not include information, references, or resources on abortion.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HA46F007579954E1482A7649FEA7D50ED"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Training</header><text>The Secretary shall provide training to military and family life counselors available through the Military OneSource program on addressing the non-medical needs of covered beneficiaries who are pregnant.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HCB60CBF34C4E4FCA90F6D8858C556BBB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Notification of pregnancy</header><text>The Secretary shall notify the head of the Military OneSource program when a covered beneficiary makes the Secretary aware of a pregnancy. </text></subsection> <subsection id="H48D1ACFB8F604534806CCE0F3772AE3B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Plan</header><text>Not later than 540 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall develop and submit to Congress a plan for the Secretary to disseminate to beneficiaries of the Military OneSource program the guide required by subsection (a).</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

