<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC4130ABAF2EC44D594AA9897F5BE9D89" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 863 IH: National Human Trafficking Database Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 863</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250131">January 31, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000401">Mr. Kiley of California</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001096">Ms. Hageman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a national human trafficking database at the Office for Victims of Crime of the Department of Justice, and to incentivize certain State agencies to report data to the database.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6118A113D93E4268BB0AB4377C5821F4" style="OLC"><section id="H56503D99E18B43A4ACE95C8FF24D2CF5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>National Human Trafficking Database Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H3D1525D1CBDC4F85AEB48851AD425FCD"><enum>2.</enum><header>National human trafficking database</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10101">34 U.S.C. 10101 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HB699E00D593D4931A3F89B41F924D47F" display-inline="no-display-inline" style="OLC"><part id="H2C3188A4F72343039B6F99E2812D94BD" style="OLC"><enum>PP</enum><header>National human trafficking database</header><section id="HF14748145AAB4F15BCBD1239C7C6002F"><enum>3061.</enum><header>National human trafficking database</header><subsection id="HF4A907A0ECF64E7BB2E669DCDF43D78E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H1069FAA185234D8FA69662C7956650A8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Anti-human trafficking organization</header><text>The term <term>anti-human trafficking organization</term> means an organization whose main objective is to address and combat human trafficking, including by—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAE0EBB0A68294C018DC6DB066653A2C1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supporting populations known to be at a higher risk of human trafficking;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAF1AF7345DD04ED482BA8D8C6BAD3F9C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">raising awareness of human trafficking; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD55F6F7307BC40389B6D5453CC2352D8"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">providing services to survivors of human trafficking.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7359EE866E284076A7DEB4CB9FCE843C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered State agency</header><text>The term <term>covered State agency</term> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0DACECB745E44BCC9E45085D4FFAE740"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a State bureau of investigation or equivalent State law enforcement agency; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9591689599B3492A8B8F0B2579EF06F8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a State agency other than an agency described in subparagraph (A) that is empowered by the State to coordinate a statewide human trafficking response, which may be the State public health agency or another agency as determined by the State.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4B7D09171DC24AD3BA8F24EA5428C8C8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Director of the Office</header><text>The term <term>Director of the Office</term> means the Director of the Office for Victims of Crime.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H36B26049FDD9450F947806D5FBF87DC5"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Human trafficking</header><text>The term <term>human trafficking</term> means labor trafficking or sex trafficking.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF34B422B066E48309821164E950AD19E"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Labor trafficking</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>labor trafficking</term> means conduct described in section 103(11)(B) of the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7102">22 U.S.C. 7102(11)(B)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H05EC005D860C4479A1B6E4308C1BBC5B"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Primary service</header><text>With respect to an anti-human trafficking organization, the term <term>primary service</term> means the essential function of the organization, which may be—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF110E5F2D4BD4B39BC925E49C62E2953"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">preventing human trafficking;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H02BD93C16B884DCE97726EBA34145783"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identifying survivors of human trafficking;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD318828CAA254A3C84696CC82278F763"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recovering survivors from human trafficking situations; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCED64BCE35EB4DDCAAC257BBEAFA468F"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">providing support for survivors to exit human trafficking situations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC65912674E6A49A78A298841DDE8AC9D"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Sex trafficking</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>sex trafficking</term> has the meaning given the term in section 103(11)(A) of the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7102">22 U.S.C. 7102(11)(A)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEE6F9CB0ADD440659B63A40F25070B2D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties of Office for Victims of Crime</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCFC1E0C726CF4AE293CF820E861C90E1"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Grants</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H17125C9F71AE48EB9DD9AF06D1A0E450"><enum>(A)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>For each fiscal year for which amounts are made available to carry out this section, the Director of the Office shall award grants to covered State agencies to collect and report to the Director of the Office human trafficking data, directly or by contract with a private or nonprofit organization with expertise and experience in the collection of human trafficking data, in accordance with subsection (c).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCC60E3D9E21948D19342C4DD3E3AF2F1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Application</header><text>A covered State agency seeking a grant under this subsection shall submit an application to the Director of the Office at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Director of the Office may reasonably require.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2E028C8ED46349DEA5B46941E506ACA0"><enum>(C)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Grant condition</header><text>A covered State agency may not receive a grant under subparagraph (A) unless the agency certifies to the Director of the Office that, not later than 180 days after the date on which the agency receives the grant, the agency will identify how the agency will collect or ensure the collection and reporting of human trafficking data described in subsection (c)(1)(A).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H98E7BCC33E014BE591A40A8DE627FE51"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Use of grant</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A covered State agency may only use a grant received under subparagraph (A) to collect and report the data described in section (c)(1)(A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC6D795D7115449E48E55A51DB2B4FA65"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Guidance for use of grant funds</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>National Human Trafficking Database Act</short-title>, the Director of the Office shall issue guidance that includes goals and guidelines for the use of grants awarded under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H09EF0D66DC4944058434656FBC86581A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Database</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H159872B15F2F468F8E1BBB63A7F3E915"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Establishment</header><subparagraph id="HC87002C7284442A899F518E11A09CE01"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Initial submission of State data</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of the <short-title>National Human Trafficking Database Act</short-title>, each covered State agency that has received a grant under subsection (b)(1) shall report to the Director of the Office, for the most recently ended fiscal year (as of that date of enactment) for the State—</text><clause id="HD24C568457E1457B8F44968E1560BED7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>where such data is available—</text><subclause id="H53F2535C200C41F6A8B0605F8524B38A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>with respect to each county in the State—</text><item id="H25896DBCE2774300AFD561B1DA515820"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the number of prosecutions, arrests, or convictions for human trafficking;</text></item><item id="H6EB30F05046D47D9A4F708272C431073"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>aggregated and anonymized data from State-level human trafficking hotlines;</text></item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2B42CA11C4A54EF89AD5194E9DD4BB8D"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>aggregated and anonymized data from the National Human Trafficking Hotline, operated by the Administration for Children and Families;</text></item><item id="H9F1FAAF1799D4F7A90BF4BD8D99929A4"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>aggregated and anonymized data from State-level children’s services agencies;</text></item><item id="H6B880BCF0AA240DC83B0166BC8545D52"><enum>(ee)</enum><text>aggregated and anonymized human trafficking data from the Office of Justice Services of the Bureau of Indian Affairs, including the Missing and Murdered Unit;</text></item><item id="HA9D546A8D5FD4D0DAFD0279E71009220"><enum>(ff)</enum><text>aggregated and anonymized human trafficking data from the Center for Countering Human Trafficking of the Department of Homeland Security;</text></item><item id="H893D7FCAE8F94FA5B245D1C813911E43"><enum>(gg)</enum><text>the presence and likelihood of criminal activity known to be correlated with human trafficking, including crimes of prostitution, drug distribution, sexual assault, and gang-related violence; and</text></item><item id="H83122DBADD854724B92DF381E1132352"><enum>(hh)</enum><text>the number of survivors of human trafficking who have been served by nongovernmental human trafficking victim service organizations;</text></item></subclause><subclause id="H285909C984D54213AD9186366F12F31C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the name and primary service of each anti-human trafficking organization operating in each county in the State; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HE2ADB96D50B742DDB67AE736B8F75217"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the total number of State-level human trafficking prosecutions, which the covered State agency shall compile by collecting the necessary information from the prosecutor's office for each county in the State, categorized by sex, race, citizenship, primary language, and prior convictions; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HD86CA3DF5ACC42FC80120A3F5BF4E0E6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if any data described in clause (i) is not available, a statement explaining why the data is not available.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2E51C2A613194DA4AA1C6DDAE1BB1869"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of the <short-title>National Human Trafficking Database Act</short-title>, the Director of the Office shall publish on the internet website of the Department of Justice a database that includes, for each State—</text><clause id="H1993DA4B7DC6490AB8CD5E7124263F3E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the data for each county in the State, as reported by the covered State agency under subparagraph (A)(i)(I), in accordance with subsection (d);</text></clause><clause id="H46DFE6FAF6B44D7996CBF1FACFCD15DB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the name and primary service of each anti-human trafficking organization operating in each county in the State, as reported by the covered State agency under subparagraph (A)(i)(II);</text></clause><clause id="H5D380F0198B94442A757439EF983FBA4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the total number of State-level human trafficking prosecutions, as reported by the covered State agency under subparagraph (A)(i)(III);</text></clause><clause id="H4321475E1F8D4F839E90FAB2587F25B3"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>any statement from the covered State agency of the State described in subparagraph (A)(ii);</text></clause><clause id="H15548E6F132F4729AAF2FD8AC38BFEB3" commented="no"><enum>(v)</enum><subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H1CE86A211AF748C996CD5535229847DD"><enum>(I)</enum><text>except as provided in subclause (II)—</text><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6B4BBC1AF36F474E90EF7EF97F3A9262" indent="up1"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the 10 counties in the State with the highest rates of human trafficking; and</text></item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="H7358B56039424B4DB038AC27376A185B"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the 10 counties in the State with the lowest rates of human trafficking; or</text></item></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="H5AF35A2C613241919ED2106C9300C9A1"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the State has fewer than 20 counties, a list of the counties in the State, ranked by rate of human trafficking from highest to lowest; and</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0C2E40FE423F4AAC9ECDAF7F580203EA"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the number of Federal prosecutions, arrests, or convictions for human trafficking occurring in the State.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0461B96BBADB492A899C02D47FAE0214"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Collection of data regarding anti-human trafficking organizations</header><text>In carrying out subparagraph (A)(ii), a covered State agency may coordinate with—</text><clause id="H349639C595B24D3C8D0DF98970B58412"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Administration for Children and Families, in its capacity as the operator of the National Human Trafficking Hotline;</text></clause><clause id="H342E7EEA5D6F4D5A811D6A371BF153A8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Office for Victims of Crime;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3F00AC0159214666B784437C7D5E86E0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Office on Violence Against Women;</text></clause><clause id="H0D707C9173A54DB78A891857295FBFD3"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the Bureau of Justice Statistics;</text></clause><clause id="H79E461FB3B6E441B98C70C27F0774BC2"><enum>(v)</enum><text>any office of the United States attorney in the State;</text></clause><clause id="H1091B4B8FBDA4803B92FA0BADDE8395D"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the Office of Justice Services of the Bureau of Indian Affairs;</text></clause><clause id="HC2E92B461B4F45A6AC19C81F4E003E98"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>the Center for Countering Human Trafficking of the Department of Homeland Security;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA3048D31203D4478BFED4D12CA1DDC7D"><enum>(viii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a relevant State-level human trafficking task force or Missing and Murdered Indigenous People task force; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H85D89BC6F8D94A348BF75AE2A31E3BFD"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>the Office of National Drug Control Policy, including the High Intensity Drug Trafficking Areas Program.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7B2FBBAA2E214CC1B1C286643EDE2F65"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administration</header><subparagraph id="HD2A47C4203B7438BABC0C24FA9E3002D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Submission of State data</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the last day of each fiscal year, beginning with fiscal year 2025, each covered State agency that received a grant under subsection (b)(1) for that fiscal year shall report to the Director of the Office the data described in paragraph (1)(A) of this subsection (and any statement described in clause (ii) of that paragraph, if applicable) for that fiscal year for the State.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4441ABAAF9974C70863E7988947370A9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Updating database</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the last day of each fiscal year, beginning with fiscal year 2025, the Director of the Office shall update the database established under paragraph (1)(B) using the data provided by covered State agencies for that fiscal year under paragraph (1)(A) (and including any statements described in clause (ii) of that paragraph, if applicable), as well as, for purposes of paragraph (1)(B)(iv), data provided by Federal law enforcement agencies.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBE367C690D3A4208BE6A42A83D47AD71"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the last day of each fiscal year, beginning with fiscal year 2025, the Director of the Office shall report to Congress the contents of the database established under paragraph (1)(B) for that fiscal year.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC62BF41D6C6E4D7F9CE962A9D4C509F0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Survivor confidentiality</header><text>In order to ensure the safety of survivors of human trafficking and their families, a covered State agency that receives a grant under subsection (b)(1), in collecting and reporting data under this section, shall protect the confidentiality and privacy of those survivors and their families.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H207086E880534E5AA4091C604C75B9BA"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Rules of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1A93295FAC9B4609A8C62BBF4A691BDD"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to permit the Department of Justice to make any funding decisions based on the collected data described in subsection (c); or</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD66B98906A874C1583001A81CB5A8EC7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to permit the Department of Justice, or any covered State agency that receives a grant under subsection (b)(1), to demand, access, or publicize personally identifying information about survivors of human trafficking from any source.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCF12CAAC1CE14B3780747126122087D1"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3647AEFC1E4D4402AE9BA6F4234F7BA0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Director of the Office for each of fiscal years 2025 through 2028—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H75AE34D90B754736AC0412E6F258CFB2"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$50,000,000 to carry out subsection (b); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H91ADCBDCFB1A4907ACA9FAA3A4BE7483"><enum>(B)</enum><text>$1,000,000 to carry out paragraphs (1)(B), (2)(B), and (3) of subsection (c).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDCEBC1E2E0A8432FBE9BA01114D020A8" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Availability of funds</header><text>The amounts authorized under paragraph (1) shall remain available until expended.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></part><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

