<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H39B5A16260614486B43AAD768485BDCE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3553 IH: Building Resiliency and Understanding of Shrublands to Halt Fires Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3553</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250521">May 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001241">Mr. Min</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="K000397">Mrs. Kim</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000593">Mr. Levin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000620">Ms. Rivas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000830">Mr. Whitesides</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001090">Mr. Harder of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="J000305">Ms. Jacobs</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Natural Resources</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Agriculture to carry out a study with respect to the effectiveness of available wildfire mitigation methods in reducing the risk of wildfire and the severity of damages from wildfire in communities within or adjacent to shrubland ecosystems, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC322DE0A49A54303B193951820B50555" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H22CAF0D9A3FC4676B1A4831660022C2C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Building Resiliency and Understanding of Shrublands to Halt Fires Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>BRUSH Fires Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H68E9969C28CF4D22B2FF1B4B44831BE9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Shrubland wildfire mitigation study</header> <subsection id="H9C32F5714FCB4C20A8E40EFE0F30E6CE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header> <paragraph id="HCD9E5C31DCCC45B8AE088F6DDDD1CB28"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall conduct a study to evaluate the effectiveness of wildfire mitigation methods available to the Forest Service as a means of reducing the risk of wildfire in covered ecosystems and the severity of damages from such wildfire in communities within or adjacent to covered ecosystems.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H49000861BAE849C09D0E27303217B609"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>In carrying out the study under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall, with respect to covered ecosystems—</text> <subparagraph id="HF8048729574849FB8093680024289675"><enum>(A)</enum><text>evaluate the effectiveness and longevity of—</text> 
<clause id="HD237815050C64B25A2BAAD381B5F79D5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>hazardous fuels management activities, including fuel modification through the use of strategic fuel breaks; and</text></clause> <clause id="H9D864FFA119B402A9BCDFEB559C49E65"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">practices for maintaining the health of native ecosystems, including—</text> 
<subclause id="H5D4AFDD775AB4AF6ABA752F597B60E59"><enum>(I)</enum><text>mitigating the development and spread of invasive species, including invasive weeds, grasses, and other vegetation; or</text></subclause> <subclause id="HA11D7BD2A6BF486C8D5A36A3C77EE705"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">improving the resprouting of native shrub species on lands affected by wildfire;</text></subclause> </clause> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H552A6DA09C9841DC8B3A379C7C6FA5EC"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">evaluate the effectiveness of policies and protocols of the Forest Service with respect to limiting unintentional ember ignitions attributable to the public or man-made structures, including electrical infrastructure;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA34A90B0BF614DC2B1B539461212A93E"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">study the conditions (including weather, seasonality, and topography) under which each wildfire mitigation method evaluated under the study is most and least effective in reducing the risk of wildland fire;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5E17C99823FB42FEA011D1FCD20D9768"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify administrative, operational, and budgetary factors that impede the ability of wildland fire managers and wildland firefighters to implement wildfire mitigation methods evaluated under the study; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9E9852D2BFCA49BC84435D9B8883C8B7"><enum>(E)</enum><text>evaluate the effectiveness of partnerships between the Forest Service and non-Federal entities in reducing the vulnerability of homes, roadways, and other high-risk structures to ember ignition.</text></subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7BE0773C63A14A1188BF98BB9EECFB00"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Coordination; consultation</header> 
<subparagraph id="H5C47F894F2CD4FBCBFCD98ABB022F7AB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Interagency coordination</header><text>In carrying out the study under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall, to the extent practicable and to avoid the duplication of research activities of the Federal Government, act in coordination with—</text> <clause id="H3C96624C33724BCE8DA9514215D104D8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>entities within the Forest Service with expertise in wildfire risk reduction and ecology in covered ecosystems, including the Shrub Sciences Laboratory and the Maintaining Resilient Dryland Ecosystems program; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HC54AB10DA4544EDBB855F7399EB2DAA6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the heads of Federal agencies conducting wildfire mitigation activities or hazardous fuels management activities in covered ecosystems, including the Secretary of the Interior.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE1B735824EA04B3EB709C2651B4834E5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In carrying out the study under paragraph (1), the Secretary may, and is encouraged to, solicit consultation from non-Federal public and private entities with relevant expertise in wildfire mitigation in covered ecosystems, as determined by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H9AE389D22ADB41D292E68B5BB1E0EB9B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date on which the study under subsection (a)(1) is complete, the Secretary shall submit to the relevant Congressional committees, and make publicly available, a report that includes—</text> <paragraph id="HC25F09C127B246CAACF09BEBB3DC24FA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a summary of the results of the study;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBCA75B2EA16A465E882DFD5016E2B97F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>based on the results of the study, identification by the Secretary of—</text> <subparagraph id="H0AC8BC6826D140B8A789F2DF67F14715"><enum>(A)</enum><text>best practices for land managers in reducing the risk of wildfire in covered ecosystems; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE60EFF5F10214B6B9C6C633FABDC0C8E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any areas implicated by the study that merit further research;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAA948E501B1643ADB411C1286C34FBB0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a comparison of the polices and protocols of the Forest Service with respect to reducing the risk of wildfire in covered ecosystems and the best practices identified under paragraph (2)(A); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9F9976651BB544B080D8874D08F85A91"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an evaluation by the Secretary of opportunities to improve coordination between the Forest Service and non-Federal entities on activities to improve wildfire resilience in covered ecosystems and reduce risks of harm from wildfire to the built environment, particularly in the wildland-urban interface.</text> </paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="H5464FF8AE66B40D395F0B008896B7811"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="HE4854B4B472F44639B54AC71D80A7822"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered ecosystems</header><text>The term <term>covered ecosystems</term> means shrubland ecosystems, including—</text> <subparagraph id="H069E3BA15F8C4913BB7FA16058FBF2D3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>chaparral;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1E9C1519589C41B99BB6934026E6AFF8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>coastal sage scrub;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF4F6A3F0BA4F41BE8C02ABAE8E41DB0D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>sagebrush;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H095817AB9E6749BAB6196C806BED7CA6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>shrub-steppe;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA670586F2AB648FD8AD034E21A667067"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">xeric shrubland; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0FE66996D8384BB09925EF5A15D7EC8F"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other dryland shrub ecosystem in which wildfire management presents a significant challenge, as determined by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H1CB12269B9C346AF868F6F837384CC36"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Hazardous fuels management activity</header><text>The term <term>hazardous fuels management activity</term> means an activity to manage vegetation to reduce the risk of wildfire.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H93AEAD3482854418BCA10CFBD2249B11"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Relevant Congressional Committees</header><text>The term <term>relevant Congressional committees</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H5B1DA53AD2D749DBAAE5D2633050F444"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the committees on Appropriations, Natural Resources, and Agriculture of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0195A6A844FC476D816C99947FC4D87C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the committees on Appropriations, Energy and Mineral Resources, and Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4FEFACF3BA324F58B9BA7B9C686989F5"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Chief of the Forest Service.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H24924D4F7D0B4097B42DFC5B9A9EA2ED"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Wildland-urban interface</header><text>The term <term>wildland-urban interface</term> has the meaning given such term in section 101 of the Healthy Forests Restoration Act of 2003 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/6511">16 U.S.C. 6511</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

