<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4AAC885D545343BB8F210139F8FEF629" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4335 IH: Abraham Accords Defense Against Terror Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4335</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250710">July 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001217">Mr. Moskowitz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Z000018">Mr. Zinke</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000230">Mr. Davis of North Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001213">Mr. Steil</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000168">Ms. Salazar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000392">Mr. Kustoff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001157">Mr. McCaul</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001212">Mr. Stauber</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000795">Mr. Wilson of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000596">Mrs. Luna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001322">Mr. Baumgartner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000193">Mr. Nunn of Iowa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000612">Mr. Rose</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000459">Mr. Fleischmann</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000246">Mr. Edwards</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001137">Mr. Crank</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001098">Mr. Hamadeh of Arizona</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001196">Ms. Stefanik</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000597">Mr. Garbarino</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000475">Mr. Finstad</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001233">Mr. Messmer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide authority to enhance security assistance with countries that are engaged in regional security cooperation efforts in the Middle East and North Africa, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HCB077AAD831E4F0A8E08A99710D2D821" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H3FC0459A0DD34E9F9EC825EAB9EF433E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Abraham Accords Defense Against Terror Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HEBCA626CBB91440E9EF0C515329E6194"><enum>2.</enum><header>Authority to enhance security assistance with countries that are engaged in regional security cooperation efforts in the Middle East and North Africa</header> <subsection id="HFE2FF29B9AF44B09BF237778AABB32F9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the policy of the United States to work with allies and partners to safeguard freedom of navigation, protect critical infrastructure, uphold basic principles of international law, and protect United States citizens from threats posed by Iran and Iran-aligned entities in the Middle East and North Africa.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD269852C37294BF0A74399569CA71F77"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authority</header><text>The Secretary of State shall—</text> <paragraph id="H96ECBE001E3C401F97DB4A56797303E8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identify countries that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H09B891122B20422E8751956B69EB24C3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>have normalized diplomatic relations with the State of Israel; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB1988E5C37A24775BE1253DD3ED080EB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>are engaged in regional security cooperation efforts in the Middle East and North Africa to combat threats posed by Iran and Iran-aligned entities; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H334297B383BD480FB1E86B90A7BC1ED4"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in order to meet the policy described in subsection (a), provide approval for the sale or lease, a license or other approval for the export, or the transfer of defense articles or defense services to countries identified by the Secretary under paragraph (1) in accordance with the expedited approval provisions of subsection (c).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H1348B5ABBB30415E84507151D023ECE0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Expedited approval provisions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a sale or lease of defense articles or defense services under section 3, 21, or 36 of the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2753">22 U.S.C. 2753</external-xref>, 2761, or 2776) to a country identified by the Secretary of State under subsection (b)(1), a license or other approval under section 38 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2778">22 U.S.C. 2778</external-xref>) for the export of defense articles or defense services to such a country (or of a commercial agreement that involves the manufacture in such a country of any item of significant combat equipment on the United States Munitions List in accordance with section 36(d) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2776">22 U.S.C. 2776(d)</external-xref>)), or a transfer of excess defense articles under section 516(c)(2) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2321j">22 U.S.C. 2321j(c)(2)</external-xref>) to such a country, the President shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H56ED6E6CE168448589743B0C09FE88CD"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">notwithstanding the time limitations described in any of such sections, submit to Congress a certification described in such sections, at least 15 calendar days before sale, lease, license or other approval, or transfer of the defense articles or defense services is approved; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1A57DE4910AB4B9C80CAFF9B8B51F112"><enum>(2)</enum><text>include in the certification—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB8F74650ED454687A29648446E1A849D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>information on why the provision of such defense articles or services is related to or in furtherance of the policy described in subsection (a); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H67754CAD2AB8454988FD36CF88AE4C76"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a summary of steps taken by the United States Government to ensure that any sensitive United States technology, information, or capabilities that may be provided to such a country by reason of the provision of such defense articles or services are not acquired by—</text> 
<clause id="H68050977B13C45819C2910E1C2D6D808"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the People’s Republic of China or any entity owned or controlled by the People’s Republic of China; or</text></clause> <clause id="H60BD8A8A0AB54F1DB4BEDF22E0ED595E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Russian Federation or any entity owned or controlled by the Russian Federation.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H143095F8538241E2B7B6214344E84575"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Strategy</header> 
<paragraph id="H515CB74EC5D84971AA933D631E631380"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and every 60 days thereafter, the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees, in writing, a strategy on the implementation of this section.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC550E2C67DAB485F91CFA0AE716C7EFC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Matters to be included</header><text>The strategy required by this subsection shall include the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HEE7C78656DD04417872EA9DCEDF78E64"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An overview of the security threats from Iran and Iran-aligned entities to both the United States and the countries identified by the Secretary of State under subsection (b)(1).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H645C93F7EE2E49219AB9D38C96E5D4AC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A description and assessment of the metrics and evaluation procedures used for implementing the policy described in subsection (a), including recommendations to improve multilateral cooperation between the United States and such countries and among such countries.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1BC689F3DDD1455F98A2AA7F05A58FB2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A description of the challenges to achieving full interoperability between the United States and such countries and the impact on progress to address the policy described in subsection (a), including efforts to address shared threats posed by Iran and Iran-aligned entities.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H480B34A89DD041DD8A8C07E09CE6B60F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A description of measures to provide such countries interim capabilities until the cases described in clauses (i) and (ii) are delivered.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H940D1E56BBE2491F90BB5F0688E6990F" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>A description and assessment of—</text> <clause id="H3B09F1DED51A41BF9B465564B23A535E" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the status of all pending sales of defense articles or defense services over $25,000,000, including Letters of Request and where applicable Letters of Offer and Acceptance, beginning 5 years prior to the date of the enactment of this Act, to such countries pursuant to the provisions of law specified in subsection (c);</text></clause> 
<clause id="HE1E3ADCE6C504801BCBC2C1C4D5D9C3A" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of the delivery time-frames for all pending sales of defense articles or defense services over $25,000,000 to such countries pursuant to the provisions of law specified in subsection (c) and any measures that could be taken to expedite their delivery; and</text></clause> <clause id="HD25D0A163D6A418693EE1690A5181B5C" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>recommendations to improve the process for authorizing the transfer of defense articles and services authorized under sections 36 and 38 of the Arms Export Control Act to such countries, including as it relates to delivery timeline.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAF0846636F2F43EC8B6FB76F340E235E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required by this subsection shall be submitted in unclassified form but may contain a classified annex.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1F08505572754A559349A8B32E70B548"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE0A273F6FA6A429B86C5F7051D819AF2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> <clause id="HAFC61AC7BB62439D824AE4DFECEFBACB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H91106AE43E1746BBA7F0470EA4F49FC6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7E16B488B4BD41EFA36D5FB818FC677D"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>Iran-aligned entity</term>—</text> 
<clause id="H0A76AA7A22C84CD78C0BC181DE5005FE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>includes an entity that—</text> <subclause id="H810F9EA1DCA644B48DF42E5AA10653BA"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is controlled or significantly influenced by the Government of Iran; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H2050D598124A442CA4914C9CFFF2DC74"><enum>(II)</enum><text>knowingly receives material or financial support from the Government of Iran; and</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H26A7C47341804AB5B4BE118F2DE12B95"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>includes—</text> 
<subclause id="HBAE6B91D7625472C84FD3398A29346A5"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Hezbollah;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H45B79D1C3C7B4A079FADEC9A194F08CC"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the Houthis; or</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H7A75228BF3224B4CB775F200B9BCC4F5"><enum>(III)</enum><text>any other proxy group that furthers Iran’s national security objectives.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HF5A9DB1E05CE4013870759E177F9A5C9"><enum>3.</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed as adversely affecting Israel’s qualitative military edge, as defined in section 36(h)(3) of the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2776">22 U.S.C. 2776</external-xref>).</text></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

