<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"
    slc-id="S1-MIR25619-MWP-MV-RFY">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1995 IS: FinCEN–SBA Coordination on Beneficial Ownership Registration Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>II</distribution-code>
        <congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session>1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. 1995</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action>
            <action-date date="20250609">June 9, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor
                    name-id="S366">Ms. Warren</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S316">Mr.
                    Whitehouse</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and
                referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSSB00">Committee on Small Business
                    and Entrepreneurship</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title>To require the Director of the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network and the
            Administrator of the Small Business Administration to enter into a memorandum of
            understanding to ensure the dissemination of covered information, and for other
            purposes.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"
        id="HDDDCC44B233D46A9A39D05CF3CD0B49C">
        <section section-type="section-one" id="H599A8ECE02BB440885A79FDCB37C672C">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>FinCEN–SBA Coordination on Beneficial Ownership Registration Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section id="H54EBAA65F994475A82C1CB69F4F3DF4C">
            <enum>2.</enum>
            <header>Sense of Congress</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text> <paragraph id="H91630D0F72CB4807847D6513548F6A49"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>malign actors seek to conceal their ownership of corporations, limited liability companies, or other similar entities in the United States to facilitate illicit activity, including money laundering, the financing of terrorism, proliferation financing, serious tax fraud, human and drug trafficking, counterfeiting, piracy, securities fraud, financial fraud, and acts of foreign corruption, harming the national security interests of the United States and allies of the United States;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H84097462D4DF4FB0AC4DAD0F90F53995">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>Federal legislation providing for the collection of beneficial ownership information for corporations, limited liability companies, or other similar entities formed under the laws of the States is needed to—</text>
                <subparagraph id="H1F3927221F36440CA4736135E82141FD">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>set a clear, Federal standard for incorporation practices;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB195003EE3AC4793A0D9E7261993E2E3"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>protect vital United States national security interests;</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H781FCF55323E49ECB02CC8549197A8B9">
                    <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>protect interstate and foreign commerce;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7B89F6C8B44E465F9B999AF94326A79D"> <enum>(D)</enum> <text>better enable critical national security, intelligence, and law enforcement efforts to counter money laundering, the financing of terrorism, and other illicit activity; and</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="HBE0A21DC0FEF45898FE4E7E6DF18DF8B">
                    <enum>(E)</enum>
 <text>bring the United States into compliance with international anti-money laundering and countering the financing of terrorism standards;</text>
                </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H6C514753DCE54972ACB51EEF0754FCE7">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>Federal legislation providing for the collection of beneficial ownership information is needed to protect critical law enforcement and national security efforts;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HD11C748F691E4C0F92BED4A7B90C995D">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>the Secretary of the Treasury and the Administrator should work with small business concerns and other reporting companies to provide clarity and minimize burdens on them while still generating a highly useful database;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph commented="no" id="H90E0F1AD9CE348C4BB4AF64E479C1CCA">
                <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an overwhelming bipartisan majority of Congress codified the provisions of paragraphs (1) through (4) in the enactment of the Corporate Transparency Act (title LXIV of division F of the William M. (Mac) Thornberry National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/283">Public Law 116–283</external-xref>; 134 Stat. 4604)); and</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H6612D2DB962C4B24813C0E121EAD1485" commented="no"
                display-inline="no-display-inline">
                <enum>(6)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">full implementation of the Corporate Transparency Act is critical to further the provisions of paragraphs (1) through (4).</text>
            </paragraph>
        </section>
        <section id="H993080FCAE60472F8BB8AAF5240CF79C">
            <enum>3.</enum>
            <header>Definitions</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H811A46F38E104376ABCFC6F878458AF6"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>Administration; Administrator</header> <text>The terms <term>Administration</term> and <term>Administrator</term> mean the Small Business Administration and the Administrator thereof, respectively.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H33F06BD51B1E4E51AD551A4DACF070D1">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <header>Beneficial ownership requirements</header>
 <text>The term <term>beneficial ownership requirements</term> means the requirements under section 5336 of title 31, United States Code.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H7C7F013131704EEB9FBC58C2842D3512">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
                <header>Covered agencies</header>
 <text>The term <term>covered agencies</term> means FinCEN and the Administration.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HC8F3106C20E54B4A90ED464A31DCBA2D">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
                <header>Covered information</header>
 <text>The term <term>covered information</term> means information developed by FinCEN regarding the beneficial ownership information reporting requirements under section 5336 of title 31, United States Code.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HFA8B4E9A76DD4472815A2E3D82D7335F">
                <enum>(5)</enum>
                <header>Director</header>
 <text>The term <term>Director</term> means the Director of FinCEN.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H4259A34B2F304D64A00098049AFF1AD3"> <enum>(6)</enum> <header>FinCEN</header> <text>The term <term>FinCEN</term> means the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network described in section 310 of title 31, United States Code.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H9776812675FF41659BE0DB5BF1192275">
                <enum>(7)</enum>
                <header>Reporting company</header>
 <text>The term <term>reporting company</term> has the meaning given the term in section 5336 of title 31, United States Code.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HC074D0D1F5934487879B9943705343BF">
                <enum>(8)</enum>
                <header>Resource partner</header>
 <text>The term <term>resource partner</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H1AA7C936292B4E0DAA6CD5F2388DE493"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>a small business development center;</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="HD43D3EC5FD7941298206B5BB130568CF">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>a women’s business center described in section 29 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/656">15 U.S.C. 656</external-xref>); and</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="HD1DE21CB5788470E92D10E0E8EB47B31">
                    <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>Veteran Business Outreach Centers described in section 32 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/657b">15 U.S.C. 657b</external-xref>).</text>
                </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H9F98155D4FC944F887949165E80454D7">
                <enum>(9)</enum>
                <header>Small business concern; small business development center</header>
 <text>The terms <term>small business concern</term> and <term>small business development center</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 3 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/632">15 U.S.C. 632</external-xref>).</text>
            </paragraph>
        </section>
        <section id="HCB759A7C025C4B94AA8C5757B85E09D9">
            <enum>4.</enum>
            <header>Memorandum of understanding to ensure the dissemination of covered
                information</header>
            <subsection id="HAC5310713B08430BB7723686C8566182">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>Meeting</header>
 <text>Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator and the Director shall meet to discuss the contents of the memorandum of understanding required by subsection (b).</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H84A45E4AC49C4C65BC48804AD023EB5D">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Memorandum of understanding</header>
 <text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator and the Director shall enter into a written memorandum of understanding to jointly carry out the following activities:</text>
                <paragraph id="HEE2BAE4B1FD746DDA6C39B3BB2ADE15D">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>Disseminating covered information to reporting companies and trade associations and other entities that represent small business concerns, including dissemination through resource partners of the Administration.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H71500AF213A94F2FA0BF7C49958AB74F">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>Ensuring covered information is made available in English, Spanish, and any additional languages as jointly determined by the Director and the Administrator.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HC013BAC7950B46CFB6F727233BDC5371">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>Ensuring that the homepage of the website of the Administration includes a link to the relevant webpages of FinCEN relating to beneficial ownership requirements and registration for reporting companies.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HE79D1354CEA74C36BD82D48BC379EFCC">
                    <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>Implementing a plan to identify and counter scams or other fraudulent schemes related to, or purporting to be, beneficial ownership reporting, and to educate reporting companies and trade associations and other entities that represent small business concerns about such scams or fraudulent schemes.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HB7CB965599AF40BFA06FA6AB6A3AC8E9">
                    <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text>Hosting in-person town halls and webinars—</text> <subparagraph id="H91D823C6DE534A2091A4D1A67CB110E5"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>organized by the Administrator, acting through national or regional offices of the Administration;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="HD3557643963043B79EF736C13F2E1D59">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>that feature presentations by FinCEN staff on compliance with beneficial ownership requirements; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H4E62DB3DEE534CE7A95CB30FA16B770D">
                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>that are advertised to reporting companies and trade associations and other entities that represent small business concerns.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H206ED2B9F6264849AF79101C8ABC4557">
                    <enum>(6)</enum>
 <text>Implementing a plan to use field offices of the Administration and Domestic Liaisons of FinCEN for the in-person town halls and webinars described in paragraph (5).</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H749CC213367B4D7B8EA96F437A275E22">
                    <enum>(7)</enum>
 <text>Any other activities the Director and the Administrator determine necessary to increase the number of reporting companies in compliance with beneficial ownership requirements.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H5C555A35639A439F889A5D916F143169">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Public availability of memorandum of understanding</header>
 <text>Not later than 7 days after the date on which the Director and Administrator enter into a memorandum of understanding under subsection (b), the Director and the Administrator shall each make the memorandum publicly available on a website of FinCEN and the Administration, respectively.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H33E1718135004FB3AD012C19F9D3F509">
                <enum>(d)</enum>
                <header>Meetings</header>
 <text>Not later than 6 months after the date on which the Director and Administrator enter into a memorandum of understanding under subsection (b), and every 6 months thereafter, the Director (or a designee) and the Administrator (or a designee) shall review the following:</text>
                <paragraph id="HD35E9259A989400F8848FACDD965F47B">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>Issues related to, and continued coordination on, the requirements of the memorandum.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H5D955D8E274E4BD09D5D7F530EA2D357">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>Challenges associated with increasing the number of reporting companies in compliance with beneficial ownership requirements.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H9F55820703C94D9DA37C1C1FBF97AEBC">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>Reasons provided by reporting companies to covered agencies for failing to comply with beneficial ownership requirements.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H336E9A1A352646DCBC76A9DC9D742F11">
                    <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>Strategies for collaboration to address the reasons described in paragraph (3).</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H10EF0C9783ED4C97AD9C48E18D3BD62E">
                    <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text>Any other topics the Director and the Administrator determine necessary.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="HD8FDE84412D245758FA3246C17E91BA3">
                <enum>(e)</enum>
                <header>Compensation</header>
 <text>The Director (or a designee) and the Administrator (or a designee) may not receive compensation for attending a meeting required by subsection (d).</text>
            </subsection>
        </section>
        <section id="HABB1CD539167402FB8E5B75E1B56BEEA">
            <enum>5.</enum>
            <header>Reports</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date on which the Director and Administrator enter into a memorandum of understanding under section 4(b), and every 30 days thereafter, the Director and the Administrator shall jointly submit to the Committees on Small Business and Entrepreneurship and Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and the Committees on Small Business and Financial Services of the House of Representatives a report that includes the following:</text>
            <paragraph id="HAA61D587C5CC4423805DEF2FFCE302C3">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>For the 30-day period preceding the date of the report—</text> <subparagraph id="HB11A6103C55C45168BD994167F8B3144"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>a description of the actions taken under the memorandum of understanding to provide outreach to reporting companies that are required to, but have failed to, comply with beneficial ownership requirements;</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="HD69EF9F4200147DAB22945A44E55B4BD">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>the estimated number of reporting companies that have received covered information or other assistance relating to beneficial ownership requirements from the Administration or FinCEN as a result of actions taken pursuant to the memorandum of understanding; and</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H3B0B8A84D5754DE7870F78D89BFBA591">
                    <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>the number of reporting companies in compliance with beneficial ownership requirements.</text>
                </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H9CBDEB0F5A274C7484D1B927FFC85A33">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>A description of the actions the Director and the Administrator plan to take under the memorandum of understanding during the 30-day period following the date of the report to provide covered information to reporting companies that have failed to comply with beneficial ownership requirements.</text>
            </paragraph>
        </section>
    </legis-body>
</bill>


