<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF96402889FDF47F18EA8FEEF7F8AF5C7" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1214 IH: To require the name of military installation under jurisdiction of Secretary of the Army located in Fayetteville, North Carolina, to be known and designated as Fort Bragg, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1214</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250211">February 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001224">Mr. Self</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the name of military installation under jurisdiction of Secretary of the Army located in Fayetteville, North Carolina, to be known and designated as Fort Bragg, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC75A280A84234E02A6360A4ED089B0E0" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H591F4659A32D4285ADAA18D9D512BE61" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Name of military installation under jurisdiction of Secretary of the Army located in Fayetteville, North Carolina</header> 
<subsection id="H7E400A07F4DF414BA960D8CF0E4E8CB6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The military installation under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Army located in Fayetteville, North Carolina, shall after the date of the enactment of this Act be known and designated as <quote>Fort Bragg</quote>. Any reference to such military installation in any law, regulation, map, document, record, or other paper of the United States shall be considered to be a reference to Fort Bragg.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H62A98D595C354BB5AC5EECAA83E8D375"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Military installation defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <quote>military installation</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 2801 of title 10, United States Code. </text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

