<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC63EEAFA61C542588CDB8A91526A801D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5729 IH: North Rim Restoration Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5729</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251010">October 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001132">Mr. Crane</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000565">Mr. Gosar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001228">Ms. Maloy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001302">Mr. Biggs of Arizona</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000578">Mr. LaMalfa</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000165">Mr. Tiffany</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize direct emergency acquisition flexibilities for the National Park Service for the purpose of retaining, vetting, approving, and expediting contractor approval for the clearing, rebuilding, maintenance, and improvement of the Grand Canyon grounds that have been impacted by the Dragon Bravo Fire.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H4DDCC15E06A6445FABFA558892D1E178" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H44D885DE79A64F47B73F8E5318611371" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>North Rim Restoration Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H75DF373E97F0487D883D41886F03DAA1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Emergency contracting authority</header> <subsection id="H86FAD08ACDAC4F87AF6AA77869ED1649"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary is authorized to use emergency acquisition flexibilities under part 18 of title 48, Code of Federal Regulations (and any successor regulations), in contracting for the following services within the covered area:</text> 
<paragraph id="H58D41E48A4A2448AA2F00FB9027BE70A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Forest management or restoration activities carried out in response to the Dragon Bravo Fire.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1DF65B1EB22747F5BA9ADAC49E29C5C2"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Rebuilding, planning, development, and design of structures affected by the Dragon Bravo Fire.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H40D6BA2FCB734685B9DD3C621DF16B57"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Improvements to the grounds and structures.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF628F8C0955746A280A90EE9ED82F1A6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Recovery efforts.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H01AEFA0440F040CEABF9839481F7E7B2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Process for other services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Unless otherwise provided by law or regulation, the authority granted under subsection (a) does not apply to contracts for services other than those described in paragraphs (1) through (4) of subsection (a).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H2C57E9D5C5AB41C7B20A88C6D73AED40"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the Secretary begins to use the authorization under subsection (a), and every 180 days thereafter until the date that is 180 days after the date described in subsection (e), the Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Natural Resources and Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives and the Committees on Energy and Natural Resources and Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a report on all expenditures related to the recovery efforts for the Dragon Bravo Fire, including the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H70C0CDC013EE46B8BBAC9A913E7E176D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The expected cost of recovery efforts.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFFD14C9CB0704F14AEC2A7A44634B5D1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Cost expenditures.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB29B1E7999BB4DE68B4A3AF23D3AB350"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Cost overruns.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDB0F755A5C3F42D8A3C30394692F8915"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Identification of contractors preforming the work associated with the recovery from the Dragon Bravo Fire.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE401E66667674C7D8F1C9D7C594D1A26"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Any affiliations or conflicts of interest between the contractor and the contracting office at the Grand Canyon National Park or the National Park Service.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0815E500B9FA4522BD64CA339D822F13"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Any waste fraud and abuse detected during the recovery efforts.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2C834110F52E418EA0A125ED15334601"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Any contracts that came in under expected expenses.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H82EA1BCB8A7943AC8AD11CD190AA09E3"><enum>(8)</enum><text>An estimated time of completion for all projects and full recovery efforts related to the Dragon Bravo Fire.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0E2BAD615B6047F991F313D01C2FEB0B"><enum>(9)</enum><text>If an extension is needed to this authority to complete projects associated with the Dragon Bravo Fire.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H113436B5C7C74697900D9D94B9FAF4C1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Extension</header><text>If, after the date of the enactment of this Act, a new wildfire ignites within the covered area and impacts recovery efforts related to the Dragon Bravo Fire, the Secretary may request a 12-month extension of the authority granted under subsection (a), subject to congressional approval.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE621F198F4F8471F8AFD5CD3180DA538"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Expiration</header><text>The authority granted under subsection (a) shall expire on the date that is the earlier of the following:</text> <paragraph id="HC7058763009A4323850F69A6AF3143DA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>5 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H99D26F89340F4173B660CD7F2DF9B7B2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Recovery efforts within the covered area are complete.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H8CCAFE6BC6A74C318A0717CE3EC69A7E"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="H367560AF7A1440F0B5F0F3180FB04EDF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered Area</header><text>The term <term>covered area</term> means the areas within Grand Canyon National Park impacted by the Dragon Bravo Fire.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HE7BFB36E09614AED911BCC11305D8356"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the National Park Service.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

