<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9C6D2C1D8AED4BCE84CD5E6C01E5B8C3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 440 IH: READY Accounts Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 440</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250115">January 15, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000597">Ms. Lee of Florida</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="M001217">Mr. Moskowitz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001260">Mr. Buchanan</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000472">Mr. Scott Franklin of Florida</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for Residential Emergency Asset-accumulation Deferred Taxation Yield (READY) accounts.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H303DB9B2A18442AB90BD33D2AE5CE5F0" style="OLC"><section id="H636D3BE636B74164ADD8A4E8AF38E5A2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>READY Accounts Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H438F535B1A1242DDB185200A6C8BF29F"><enum>2.</enum><header>READY accounts</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9EA66B6E72FE4F7BA051A63BDFA5E722"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Part VII of subchapter B of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by redesignating section 224 as section 225 and by inserting after section 223 the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC140C1AEC35A435C8AD4C100FEA551E4"><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEE11CD22D60546938017667816CE815A"><enum>224.</enum><header>Residential Emergency Asset-accumulation Deferred Taxation Yield (READY) accounts</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3B45431A39634523BD931007EC52D4D7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Deduction allowed</header><text>In the case of an individual, there shall be allowed as a deduction for the taxable year an amount equal to the aggregate amount paid in cash during such taxable year by or on behalf of such individual to a Residential Emergency Asset-accumulation Deferred Taxation Yield (READY) account such individual.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCEF3FBEA3AE14E248FE8CEC37AFD82E3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitation</header><paragraph id="HDC931D624A3343718327BF065FF085D5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The amount allowable as a deduction under subsection (a) to an individual for the taxable year shall not exceed $4,500.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H257A8F1532F5453F8A49D6615DDDC925"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Inflation adjustment</header><subparagraph id="HB662E430481742CEAD2D439BC24115C0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of any taxable year beginning in a calendar year after 2025, the $4,500 dollar amount under paragraph (1) shall be increased by an amount equal to—</text><clause id="HADB393129AE54DDC966BCF96D3D7E4F1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>such dollar amount, multiplied by</text></clause><clause id="H25073A2428A24927B0A1365694BF27AF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the cost-of-living adjustment determined under section 1(f)(3) for the calendar year in which the taxable year begins, determined by substituting in subparagraph (A)(ii) thereof <quote>calendar year 2024</quote> for <quote>calendar year 2016</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC1FE8847AB564DF28987EC4C3A0A8FFF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Rounding</header><text>If any amount as adjusted under paragraph (1) is not a multiple of $50, such dollar amount shall be rounded to the next lowest multiple of $50.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H280D50F441374C16B761B97972563FB2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Residential Emergency Asset-Accumulation Deferred Taxation Yield (READY) account</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text><paragraph id="H77ABD78B43DB4BA5B0F06ECB951DA883"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>Residential Emergency Asset-accumulation Deferred Taxation Yield (READY) account</term> means a trust created or organized in the United States as a Residential Emergency Asset-accumulation Deferred Taxation Yield (READY) account exclusively for the purpose of paying the qualified home disaster mitigation and recovery expenses of the account beneficiary, but only if the written governing instrument creating the trust meets the following requirements:</text><subparagraph id="H5721140EC7634DA19A193BE363515C4D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Except in the case of a rollover contribution described in subsection (e)(5), no contribution will be accepted—</text><clause id="HE0F5C2A28B774FACA9AC4EB3DFC5E03A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>unless it is in cash, or</text></clause><clause id="H0DBD742A5ABD48E9876C037701F05E2D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to the extent such contribution, when added to previous contributions to the trust for the calendar year, exceeds the dollar amount in effect under subsection (b)(1).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4E83D7119B774B9CB7E667139E82735E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The trustee is a bank (as defined in section 408(n)) or another person who demonstrates to the satisfaction of the Secretary that the manner in which such person will administer the trust will be consistent with the requirements of this section.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5F7C660F4AC44E7384FAB2C4F06C24F8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>No part of the trust assets will be invested in life insurance contracts.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB8142F1DC4FE42C4842792BFD95BACE3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The assets of the trust will not be commingled with other property except in a common trust fund or common investment fund.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB8748BCD49F34515AF6946B9E11379EE"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The interest of an individual in the balance in his account is nonforfeitable.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H144CD9E880294B5A85B478CFB85D5C3F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualified home disaster mitigation and recovery expenses</header><subparagraph id="H18BA2FF1AB4E423EBA835A3FED10A1E4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>qualified home disaster mitigation and recovery expenses</term> means, with respect to an account beneficiary, amounts paid by such beneficiary for—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEEDBFB2C101A4A29AE0727240C231CF5"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">qualified disaster mitigation measures, or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA50B32AABCB944D38FB149CB2F9E0557"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">qualified disaster recovery costs,</text></clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">with respect to a qualified home of the taxpayer.</continuation-text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0A62741AA29E4B2F839B5F5F52CE6A03"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Qualified disaster mitigation measures</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of subparagraph (A)—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCEA81432A1704F5FB0616740E5656EE4"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>qualified disaster mitigation measures</term> means any measure described in clause (ii) with respect to a qualified home of the taxpayer if—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCD486DFDD0D84E4BBE1B1DFA54648D71"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such measure meets such criteria as the Secretary, in consultation with the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, considers appropriate to mitigate damage from a natural or other disaster, and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H40F4B940A1184C64931988E82564CDDD"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is certified by a qualified industry professional as meeting such criteria.</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF2481D9B4AC24F388FA2EA9184962065"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Mitigation measures</header><text>The following measures are measures described in this clause:</text><subclause id="H28D75FA4F0A5448AB3CD0478A7FB1795"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Installing a roofing underlayment to sheathing.</text></subclause><subclause id="HC0BB6E2C7044486582E8B2684F86A4CA"><enum>(II)</enum><text>Replacing a roof covering.</text></subclause><subclause id="HE731E6D87EC64BB6B404E537EC1C0B57"><enum>(III)</enum><text>Applying a foam adhesive to reinforce the roof structure.</text></subclause><subclause id="H47317EDEFE3640AD862FB49D2E223021"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>Strengthening connection of roof deck to roof framing.</text></subclause><subclause id="H5B76A08091F84527AE45C3CEC0B3E54C"><enum>(V)</enum><text>Strengthening roof-to-wall connections.</text></subclause><subclause id="HDF9CE2559BCC48E491748D205057E5C9"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>Strengthening soffits.</text></subclause><subclause id="HBCB17343E07242AE8C5C41D4207FCC88"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>Strengthening attic ventilation openings.</text></subclause><subclause id="HD5DF9014DFC14CF8AEECE14706417034"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text>Installing impact-resistant windows.</text></subclause><subclause id="H0FC7544327C34EAF880385C8ED23F7E5"><enum>(IX)</enum><text>Installing impact-resistant entry doors.</text></subclause><subclause id="HE32745261B52449EBB32F5AC458D3B77"><enum>(X)</enum><text>Elevating the residential home.</text></subclause><subclause id="H44DA58C63B97499F8513B3FFC768540D"><enum>(XI)</enum><text>Installing ground anchors.</text></subclause><subclause id="H584EAC09202243D083CC5F46E6DE4AA4"><enum>(XII)</enum><text>If the qualified home was built according to a building code from a prior year, achieving the current building code standard in the applicable State or locality.</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H44CC865BF1114279B24C0C715E488178"><enum>(XIII)</enum><text>Such other measures determined by the Secretary, in consultation with the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, to be consistent with the purposes of this section.</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB7DCF479C2334B70B5548C08396909FA"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Qualified industry professional</header><text>The term <term>qualified industry professional</term> means an individual who meets such rules and standards as determined appropriate by the Secretary, in consultation with the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3F5ECB386BF94F5DAB645A392C89A0B6"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Qualified disaster recovery costs</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A), the term <term>qualified disaster recovery costs</term> means costs for repairing damage to the qualified home of the taxpayer if such damage arises from fire, storm, or other casualty and such costs are not compensated for by insurance or otherwise.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5AE630079EFC46BC8D5BFCAAEC785970"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Qualified home</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>qualified home</term> means, with respect to any taxable year, any structure which is—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE1CFDD0D44C441BAB6AFD15DAED44DB0"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">owned by the taxpayer, and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFD088957A2D74AC4B84E73F1E4B9B425"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">used by the taxpayer as the taxpayer's principal residence (within the meaning of section 121) for the taxable year.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3942599456E04DD8900D5D41F250B963"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Account beneficiary</header><text>The term <term>account beneficiary</term> means the individual on whose behalf the Residential Emergency Asset-accumulation Deferred Taxation Yield (READY) account was established.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H503F71ABCA9A43E7AA22D8EB05DD43C3"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Certain rules to apply</header><text>Rules similar to the following rules shall apply for purposes of this section:</text><subparagraph id="HF0D6EF1A34604935AE5942DE01098496"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Section 219(d)(2) (relating to no deduction for rollovers).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA7DCD9175C824C2DA0D5B919AA4876B2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Section 219(f)(3) (relating to time when contributions deemed made).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA7CDBA67F77C4BA6A48382FACFCAA61F" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Section 219(f)(5) (relating to employer payments).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFA91B18029724AFBA770C283E738B6D3" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Section 408(g) (relating to community property laws).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H813B745739F949BDA6BEBA3B78EF11EE" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Section 408(h) (relating to custodial accounts).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC9B7E929581A4801A78E3C6B30579368"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Tax treatment of accounts</header><paragraph id="H6F6B6678DC3E4280847576C859A13B01"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A Residential Emergency Asset-accumulation Deferred Taxation Yield (READY) account is exempt from taxation under this subtitle unless such account has ceased to be a Residential Emergency Asset-accumulation Deferred Taxation Yield (READY) account. Notwithstanding the preceding sentence, any such account is subject to the taxes imposed by section 511 (relating to imposition of tax on unrelated business income of charitable, etc. organizations).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDAC92FAD9480492096300984884717E0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Account terminations</header><text>Rules similar to the rules of paragraphs (2) and (4) of section 408(e) shall apply to Residential Emergency Asset-accumulation Deferred Taxation Yield (READY) accounts, and any amount treated as distributed under such rules shall be treated as not used to pay qualified home disaster mitigation and recovery expenses. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H145E6C7F93AD4B9B8709004441885CB5"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Tax treatment of distributions</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9A8042E4565F4A5DB9A235920C51B447"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Amounts used for qualified home disaster mitigation and recovery expenses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any amount paid or distributed out of a Residential Emergency Asset-accumulation Deferred Taxation Yield (READY) account which is used exclusively to pay qualified home disaster mitigation and recovery expenses of the account beneficiary shall not be includible in gross income.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H26E192DF689B4220802B8A9A197BF26B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Inclusion of amounts not used for qualified home disaster mitigation and recovery expenses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any amount paid or distributed out of a Residential Emergency Asset-accumulation Deferred Taxation Yield (READY) account which is not used exclusively to pay the qualified home disaster mitigation and recovery expenses of the account beneficiary shall be included in the gross income of such beneficiary.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA86114D217E44DEEB4B89673C3800FA0" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Excess contributions returned before due date of return</header><subparagraph id="H69FB67E14AEC4EC98D5F113F07BF49AB" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If any excess contribution is contributed for a taxable year to any Residential Emergency Asset-accumulation Deferred Taxation Yield (READY) account of an individual, paragraph (2) shall not apply to distributions from the Residential Emergency Asset-accumulation Deferred Taxation Yield (READY) accounts of such individual (to the extent such distributions do not exceed the aggregate excess contributions to all such accounts of such individual for such year) if—</text><clause id="H40326CC15DF24135A811508F78CA45DE" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>such distribution is received by the individual on or before the last day prescribed by law (including extensions of time) for filing such individual's return for such taxable year, and</text></clause><clause id="H0536C48D4F9F4DA3933A55F3858814AF" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>such distribution is accompanied by the amount of net income attributable to such excess contribution.</text></clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph" commented="no">Any net income described in clause (ii) shall be included in the gross income of the individual for the taxable year in which it is received.</continuation-text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCF16965C980E4C179F32CDCB6F449BB0" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Excess contribution</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A), the term <term>excess contribution</term> means any contribution (other than a rollover contribution described in paragraph (5)) which is not deductible under this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC6F0D85F50494875ADBBEAEF7A1A0159"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Additional tax on distributions not used for qualified home disaster mitigation and recovery expenses</header><text>The tax imposed by this chapter on the account beneficiary for any taxable year in which there is a payment or distribution from a Residential Emergency Asset-accumulation Deferred Taxation Yield (READY) account of such beneficiary which is includible in gross income under paragraph (2) shall be increased by 20 percent of the amount which is so includible.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE057EE2229204C589AE86C0CD5909ED8"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Rollover contribution</header><text>An amount is described in this paragraph as a rollover contribution if it meets the requirements of subparagraphs (A) and (B).</text><subparagraph id="H5418D8EB6DF342B8B6CBA1A2C5F4387F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Paragraph (2) shall not apply to any amount paid or distributed from a Residential Emergency Asset-accumulation Deferred Taxation Yield (READY) account to the account beneficiary to the extent the amount received is paid into a Residential Emergency Asset-accumulation Deferred Taxation Yield (READY) account for the benefit of such beneficiary not later than the 60th day after the day on which the beneficiary receives the payment or distribution.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD11968E8382948E9A2B25A27DCC2FAF9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>This paragraph shall not apply to any amount described in subparagraph (A) received by an individual from a Residential Emergency Asset-accumulation Deferred Taxation Yield (READY) account if, at any time during the 1-year period ending on the day of such receipt, such individual received any other amount described in subparagraph (A) from a Residential Emergency Asset-accumulation Deferred Taxation Yield (READY) account which was not includible in the individual's gross income because of the application of this paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H46774F2DE3F34E31A603A85B4A435CA8"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Transfer of account incident to divorce</header><text>The transfer of an individual's interest in a Residential Emergency Asset-accumulation Deferred Taxation Yield (READY) account to an individual's spouse or former spouse under a divorce or separation instrument described in clause (i) of section 121(d)(3)(C) shall not be considered a taxable transfer made by such individual notwithstanding any other provision of this subtitle, and such interest shall, after such transfer, be treated as a Residential Emergency Asset-accumulation Deferred Taxation Yield (READY) account with respect to which such spouse is the account beneficiary.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBCA747DF2CF14336B37CFB172A052991"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Treatment after death of account beneficiary</header><subparagraph id="H9994337532F64FA7A17A2E9E303C73F7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Treatment if designated beneficiary is spouse</header><text>If the account beneficiary's surviving spouse acquires such beneficiary's interest in a Residential Emergency Asset-accumulation Deferred Taxation Yield (READY) account by reason of being the designated beneficiary of such account at the death of the account beneficiary, such Residential Emergency Asset-accumulation Deferred Taxation Yield (READY) account shall be treated as if the spouse were the account beneficiary.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7FEE70B6D7F2416B9458524C203E254B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Other cases</header><text>If, by reason of the death of the account beneficiary, any person acquires the account beneficiary's interest in a Residential Emergency Asset-accumulation Deferred Taxation Yield (READY) account in a case to which subparagraph (A) does not apply—</text><clause id="HD6315D14E8E44C28B277DAC5796EE8DD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>such account shall cease to be a Residential Emergency Asset-accumulation Deferred Taxation Yield (READY) account as of the date of death, and</text></clause><clause id="H4CE8C8B4492141C48C97C37775D17622"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an amount equal to the fair market value of the assets in such account on such date shall be includible if such person is not the estate of such beneficiary, in such person's gross income for the taxable year which includes such date, or if such person is the estate of such beneficiary, in such beneficiary's gross income for the last taxable year of such beneficiary.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDDF6A603A56E48248199B6406ED52E26"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Reports</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDE40FB1570644385B78DD67AFB414329"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may require the trustee of a Residential Emergency Asset-accumulation Deferred Taxation Yield (READY) account to make such reports regarding such account to the Secretary and to the account beneficiary with respect to contributions, distributions, the return of excess contributions, and such other matters as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4FCA0A535E2F4E939E3BB0B293DB7C03"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Time and manner of reports</header><text>The reports required by this subsection shall be filed at such time and in such manner and furnished to such individuals at such time and in such manner as may be required by the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8E44A92AA6A04BE3B46E57C6BFFAD31A"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"> The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section and to prevent the abuse of such purposes.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HD227B19A95B543FC9F4471A0BF8A3C67"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Excess contributions</header><paragraph id="H18D2158FFB12449A83B9CFE67C73EF3E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/4973">Section 4973(a)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end of paragraph (5), by inserting <quote>or</quote> at the end of paragraph (6), and by inserting after paragraph (6) the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3BCA7ABE109E41B2B7E27B1CDC76B447"><paragraph id="HA531BDCD905A44728BB697E549616287"><enum>(7)</enum><text>a Residential Emergency Asset-accumulation Deferred Taxation Yield (READY) account (within the meaning of section 224),</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H2A8A123D0CE6409A8928303E192E5B0E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Excess contributions</header><text>Section 4973 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCDEC660FA4804445A04E58E2C18C1D53"><subsection id="H551BC7FD3015422F9470A7201C37A051"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Excess contributions to READY accounts</header><paragraph id="H616168D9F6E44EE1BD1F6FDAACEC0C12"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of this section, in the case of a Residential Emergency Asset-accumulation Deferred Taxation Yield (READY) account (within the meaning of section 224), the term <term>excess contributions</term> means the sum of—</text><subparagraph id="H9F8275D7BBF84C1CBB4A460A8E656D3D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the aggregate amount contributed for the taxable year to such accounts (other than rollover contributions described in section 224(e)(5)) which is not allowed as a deduction under section 224 fo such year, and, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H41869DB5738147D3BA66FE126A67B9D2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the amount determined under this subsection for the preceding taxable year, reduced by the sum of—</text><clause id="HC4D2998A93154CBABA5D3626EE1A9249"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the distributions out of the accounts which were included in gross income under section 224(e)(2), and</text></clause><clause id="HFF26AF5919724135B73ECE1D35BC6B67"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the excess (if any) of the maximum amount allowed as a deduction under section 224(b) for the taxable year over the amount contributed to the accounts for the taxable year.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H63C77F3AE0ED49D9858195E97E234410" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Special rules</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, any contribution which is distributed out of the Residential Emergency Asset-accumulation Deferred Taxation Yield (READY) account in a distribution to which section 223(e)(3) applies shall be treated as an amount not contributed.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEA91DF0623024E6A9D98B46894C42C9A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application of prohibited transaction rules</header><paragraph id="H6E117FB04B7B4002A981D86B28354C1C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/4975">Section 4975(e)(1)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end of subparagraph (F), by redesignating subparagraph (G) as subparagraph (H), and by inserting after subparagraph (F) the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA136002B6860472ABB21BC1A1935E085"><subparagraph id="H9B90BF926A594066AD7C3E2BB3944804"><enum>(G)</enum><text>a Residential Emergency Asset-accumulation Deferred Taxation Yield (READY) account described in section 224, or</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="HC1EAF2AF03EA40DABFE6D9C305CBB837"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Special rule</header><text>Section 4975(c) of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H286AE7EFBC9E4EF2ADC1536986586D05"><paragraph id="H5F9C6D8FEBE54C638F1BEFB6A20E4BE5"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Special rule for Residential Emergency Asset-accumulation Deferred Taxation Yield (READY) accounts</header><text>An individual for whose benefit a Residential Emergency Asset-accumulation Deferred Taxation Yield (READY) account (within the meaning of section 224) is established shall be exempt from the tax imposed by this section with respect to any transaction concerning such account (which would otherwise be taxable under this section) if, with respect to such transaction, the account ceases to be a Residential Emergency Asset-accumulation Deferred Taxation Yield (READY) account by reason of the application of section 224(d)(2) to such account.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE2EC4EB6C296490D8EC173BD5F017C81"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><paragraph id="H8767AA80C4A44DBBBFDBEBE746E755F7"><enum>(1)</enum><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/26">Section 26(b)(2)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of subparagraph (Y), by striking the period at the end of subparagraph (Z) and inserting <quote>, and</quote>, and by inserting after subparagraph (Y) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEC25A885763141959606114DDF787C2C"><subparagraph id="H58BB74FCDE4047FD969B4DC742A14C0D"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>section 224(e)(4).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H79A554A10EB34762B2A54ED67C33D49D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Section 62(a) of such Code is amended by inserting after paragraph (21) the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9784D4D216D540CB91CDA8279940256B"><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H57BEAA3257884338A5D722AE66A59A5B"><enum>(22)</enum><header>Residential Emergency Asset-accumulation Deferred Taxation Yield (READY) account</header><text>The deduction allowed by section 224.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA35B5A04080F4583AF1FF6713D58006B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Section 165(h) of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6C082B9A446D428DB6D69D6D26935EA8"><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDF6C2CD7D776424A8236E2CA1F86C3B1"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Coordination with expenditures from READY accounts</header><text>No deduction shall be allowed with respect to any loss described in subsection (a)(3) to the extent the taxpayer has made an expenditure from a Residential Emergency Asset-accumulation Deferred Taxation Yield (READY) account (as defined in section 224) which is taken into account under section 224(c)(2)(C) as a cost with respect to such loss.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H93A8F59D96E54B52B3D70BB73ABDD042" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Section 877A of such Code is amended—</text><subparagraph id="HA5F40917C4A9426FAD5A7AAF71AE6266" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (e)(2) by inserting <quote>a Residential Emergency Asset-accumulation Deferred Taxation Yield (READY) account (as defined in section 224),</quote> after <quote>a health savings account (as defined in section 223),</quote>, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAE0FD999E14744A7A6F40C88BAD88CE0" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (g)(6) by inserting <quote>224(e)(4),</quote> after <quote>223(f)(4),</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF1CDCDA4EFAD4C579124471AD03320DC"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Section 6693(a)(2) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of subparagraph (E), by striking the period at the end of subparagraph (F) and inserting <quote>, and</quote>, and by inserting after subparagraph (F) the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1E8A176456574DD28DEAD94F7E7B9260"><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA5065E0D30D24C22ABDFA549B201255D"><enum>(G)</enum><text>section 224(f) (relating to Residential Emergency Asset-accumulation Deferred Taxation Yield (READY) accounts).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H9DD5311FFB9549DDA95B92BDA37F4D54"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The table of sections for part VII of subchapter B of chapter 1 of such Code is amended redesignating the item relating to section 224 as relating to section 225 and by inserting after the item relating to section 223 the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H199FB4188AEC4ED299558EA45C0F9B83"><toc><toc-entry level="section" idref="HEE11CD22D60546938017667816CE815A">Sec. 224. Residential Emergency Asset-accumulation Deferred Taxation Yield (READY) accounts.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8311E5E253DA49BF91848656A2A916D0"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2024.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

