<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-TAM25025-8MS-GK-6WH"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S111 IS: Red Snapper Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 111</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250116">January 16, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S404">Mr. Scott of Florida</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To provide that the Secretary of Commerce shall not issue an interim or final rule or Secretarial Amendment that includes an area or bottom closure in the South Atlantic for species managed under the Fishery Management Plan for the Snapper-Grouper Fishery of the South Atlantic Region until the South Atlantic Great Red Snapper Count study is complete and the data related to that study is integrated into the stock assessment.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H444293EF13554194AAE5583654C4472A"><section section-type="section-one" id="H216BCA4E9AAB4CADA5FC6DAEFF2FF1F0"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Red Snapper Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H4BF1910C1F844701B6DCB3D2B09B7F5D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Conditions for rules and Secretarial Amendments related to certain area closures</header><subsection id="H38535CD711964791B2FDB8AD12709777"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H005F436DBA4C43B0BE9266203694A9A9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Fishing is a major economic driver in the South Atlantic. In Florida alone, recreational anglers provide $14,000,000,000 in economic output and support 119,000 jobs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HACD58385DB0E4BC48E54BF4E3CD7CE25"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Red snapper is a highly prized and sought after reef fish by both recreational and commercial fishermen.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HADC007E491E84D1C93380E5FA9380484"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The 6-day recreational red snapper season in 2018 added $13,000,000 to the gross domestic product of the South Atlantic region.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDE551C04A8234F9DA025ACDF4298F40B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Since 2010, fishery managers have successfully been working to rebuild the red snapper stock in the South Atlantic. There is currently record high abundance and strong recruitment within the stock.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA2D3504BC9E84B4F9CD9273DD2C1BB4F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>This record abundance has led to increased out-of-season encounters and discards which is driving red snapper mortality.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1645A460C6064F3FB3CE36A1E766AD7F"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Despite these increased discards, it is the overriding opinion of the South Atlantic Fishery Management Council’s Snapper Grouper Advisory Panel that based on members’ collective on-the-water experience, the red snapper fishery is recovered.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7E4E52887D2B4A9D96DA6E23515C1BA8"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">However, options for future consideration to reduce out-of-season encounters and red snapper mortalities include shorter seasons and broad area closures for the snapper-grouper fishery in the South Atlantic.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5807C4B2554C4811BD82C46CC18DCB80"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The State of Florida is concerned with the economic implications of area closures for the South Atlantic snapper-grouper recreational fishery.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9B021020C8284ABB938435CFB13F4719"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$8,700,000 has been invested in independent survey data over the last 3 fiscal years, including $3,300,000 for the South Atlantic Great Red Snapper Count to estimate the number of red snapper (Lutjanus campechanus) in the South Atlantic waters from North Carolina to Florida.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE120648B740A4A7DA32C19C6377E910C"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The National Marine Fisheries Service should incorporate data from this survey into the National Marine Fisheries Service stock assessments as expeditiously as possible to better inform fishery management decisions. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA760213B7F7843E0AC3CCA499EEFC429"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Condition on issuance of certain rule or Secretarial Amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Commerce shall not issue an interim or final rule or a Secretarial Amendment that includes an area or bottom closure in the South Atlantic for species managed under the Fishery Management Plan for the Snapper-Grouper Fishery of the South Atlantic Region until—</text><paragraph id="H0A99008194044B20B298E7034E8FFB0C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the South Atlantic Great Red Snapper Count study is complete; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFEF7B829A32644DF9043540C07A1EDB8"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the data related to that study is integrated into the first South Atlantic red snapper Southeast Data, Assessment and Review stock assessment that is carried out after the date of the enactment of this section.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

