<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-RYA25005-NDY-TW-1JS"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>108 S350 IS: Wildfire Emergency Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 350</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250130">January 30, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S375">Mr. Daines</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To direct the Secretary of Agriculture to select and implement landscape-scale forest restoration projects, to assist communities in increasing their resilience to wildfire, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="id8dece8102a134463af5ea992931b88a5"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header><subsection id="idC96720C91D1146EC8FB82781EE5E5D68"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Wildfire Emergency Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="idDB991EAB390A4571B2DF76183D3809E8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text><toc><toc-entry level="section" idref="id8dece8102a134463af5ea992931b88a5">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="title" idref="id09D12CB8F54E48D799858041B2590967">TITLE I—Landscape-Scale Forest Restoration</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id0b5e2fff6626474f9a23f0e9957c0663">Sec. 101. Definitions.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id90b0f5f62640456ba83e79f1c47237ce">Sec. 102. Purpose.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id980491a2a5854ace95c14a308b29cd19">Sec. 103. Conservation finance agreements.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id5ea83b82fb344f4ca552c976b6d7d938">Sec. 104. Report evaluating implementation.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="title" idref="id8BA8B951EB9A40E28D6074B0CF14A880">TITLE II—Increasing Community Resilience to Wildfire</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id7f33a550aad8486094e050912b1267b0">Sec. 201. Critical infrastructure and microgrid program.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id3A3B579719924015A0CAB60D587ECD3D">Sec. 202. Retrofits for fire-resilient communities.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id584D50D6FB0041739D7275A801482A27">Sec. 203. Wildfire detection, monitoring, and analysis equipment.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="title" idref="id33D6DD4D278A45E3A9E221B9C1FE5559">TITLE III—Research, Training, and Capacity Building</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id0A498BDF05114626A21CBB7D14243E24">Sec. 301. Western prescribed fire centers.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idA424938E3D6640A68001CACA2B43FF10">Sec. 302. Innovative forest workforce development program.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id00c837593e944fee96680e24021e4a34">Sec. 303. National community capacity and land stewardship grant program.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section><title id="id09D12CB8F54E48D799858041B2590967" style="OLC"><enum>I</enum><header>Landscape-Scale Forest Restoration</header><section id="id0b5e2fff6626474f9a23f0e9957c0663"><enum>101.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this title:</text><paragraph id="idb05da7d26f4049c2b9f6e1a119eb84f6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Conservation finance agreement</header><text>The term <term>conservation finance agreement</term> means a mutual benefit agreement (excluding a procurement contract, grant, or cooperative agreement described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/63">chapter 63</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code) for a conservation finance project—</text><subparagraph id="id4119F010C86B41F7B5DAD1CDF7C08244"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the term of which is not less than 2, and not more than 20, years;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd4a9082f7c3a4db2b343584c7d4c03ec"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that may provide that performance under the agreement during the second and subsequent years of the agreement is contingent on the appropriation of funds or receipt of collections; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0ca843bd824c491f8d6b16587498acde"><enum>(C)</enum><text>that may provide for a cancellation payment to be made to the conservation finance project developer if those appropriations are not made or collections are not received. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id52cf914d41e440bd86eeaa8f04a0fdfb"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conservation finance project</header><text>The term <term>conservation finance project</term> means a project—</text><subparagraph id="idD4BF3829F1FD4C9F80A867DC49A21EE8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>conducted on National Forest System land and may include land adjoining National Forest System land;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id395E1749DD19419092F2B3F50CE444B5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that would—</text><clause id="id0237E1398B5448C9ACE9610084AAAD7D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>protect, restore, or improve National Forest System land; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idBB2E57D154A94C21B356C8F9CA5E75AA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>use a conservation finance model that employs a debt financing approach that uses loaned capital from a conservation finance project investor to cover up-front project costs, with the loaned capital repaid over time by conservation finance project beneficiaries; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2EA058B542774FECACF85BD814F13F3B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the purpose of which is to conduct ecological restoration treatments that, at the time of selection for a conservation finance agreement under the pilot program established under section 103(a)—</text><clause id="id0c70647f36af4299802ede0cbfc1b295"><enum>(i)</enum><text>are conducted under the Collaborative Forest Landscape Restoration Program established under section 4003 of the Omnibus Public Land Management Act of 2009 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/7303">16 U.S.C. 7303</external-xref>);</text></clause><clause id="id9ECCBFA2BD98454EA312BFA608B61FFF"><enum>(ii)</enum><subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idA8669F9837CA4581B9380CC91D5C632F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>were previously conducted under the Program described in clause (i);</text></subclause><subclause id="idC28C3195A09E442CABD622F0BFC30ED5" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>are no longer eligible for funding under that Program due to a time limitation under subsection (b)(1)(B) or (d)(4)(B) of that section; and</text></subclause><subclause indent="up1" id="idCA46CB0AB2B14BAABD7BB4154C7D3FE4"><enum>(III)</enum><text>are otherwise eligible for funding under that Program;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id85f73d705b5c4048ae5b8eda2b1ceeb1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>are conducted by a water source investment partnership established under section 303(c) of the Healthy Forests Restoration Act of 2003 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/6542">16 U.S.C. 6542(c)</external-xref>); or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id283508ffd6174f53a46a2a6014bfca38"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>are conducted under the Joint Chiefs Landscape Restoration Partnership Program established under section 40808 of the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/6592d">16 U.S.C. 6592d</external-xref>). </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id85519266d76f4bd5949e62ae2e34eee6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Conservation finance project beneficiary</header><text>The term <term>conservation finance project beneficiary</term> means a nonprofit, for-profit, or Federal, State, local, or Tribal governmental entity or individual that—</text><subparagraph id="idE3A628D505F546FAAB5B6C36A3D4602C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>benefits from conservation finance project outcomes; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE64EF615C1684335A751107F3B29CA58"><enum>(B)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idDDB4A443E3724FD184FF99AA74D11F55"><enum>(i)</enum><text>provides capital directly to fund a conservation finance project; or </text></clause><clause id="idCB8471E4C76841ACB4F2CCB11ACAC889" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>repays to a conservation finance project investor up-front loaned capital for a conservation finance project at a rate of return agreed to by the entity or individual and the conservation finance project investor. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id3c7e8dc820bd42879913f50e8c3c6214"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Conservation finance project developer</header><text>The term <term>conservation finance project developer</term> means a nonprofit or for-profit intermediary that assists in developing, financing, funding, or implementing a conservation finance project. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id588a802f7e8446ceae0ef8459ecf146d"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Conservation finance project investor</header><text>The term <term>conservation finance project investor</term> means a nonprofit, for-profit, or State, local, or Tribal governmental entity or individual that provides up-front loaned capital for a conservation finance project.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idea9d5df5ab59401d8f95a9ef190ad496"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Ecological integrity</header><text>The term <term>ecological integrity</term> has the meaning given the term in section 219.19 of title 36, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6aefc000941f47a5afa278f478682eb7"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Low-income community</header><text>The term <term>low-income community</term> has the meaning given the term in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/45D">section 45D(e)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986. </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id63f99394c8714b8fab15763b06e2b18c"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Restoration</header><text>The term <term>restoration</term> has the meaning given the term in section 219.19 of title 36, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb4107a21e4754beba5dc97a332ce70bf"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Agriculture.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idFA728977050A48D9AE9C8C2706325173"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Wildland-urban interface</header><text>The term <term>wildland-urban interface</term> has the meaning given the term in section 101 of the Healthy Forests Restoration Act of 2003 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/6511">16 U.S.C. 6511</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section><section id="id90b0f5f62640456ba83e79f1c47237ce"><enum>102.</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purpose of this title is to increase the pace and scale of forest restoration and land management projects across the National Forest System by— </text><paragraph id="idc6889352fc194c8ba09c5ad624c6b884"><enum>(1)</enum><text>authorizing a pilot program with conservation finance agreement authority to leverage other Federal and non-Federal investment (in addition to funds appropriated to the Forest Service) in landscape-scale, multistakeholder land management activities and related natural and built infrastructure and associated local employment opportunities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6f43d5fe42234da89f18a255d1003c88"><enum>(2)</enum><text>encouraging project planning and analysis that effectively scale up to the landscape level of 100,000 acres or more;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd42e6b4baff8434a82d7032eb12cf1a7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>supporting projects that emphasize—</text><subparagraph id="idcfc1ab0cf40d41b3904b3ed91ab43ffc"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the reintroduction of characteristic fire, based on forest ecology and reference conditions, through the use of prescribed fire, wildfire managed for resource benefits, or both; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id56166232c06648d5b821feb051b8d5a0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>restoring terrestrial and aquatic areas that lack ecological integrity; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5623ad021f3b443e889079e97f6b566c"><enum>(C)</enum><text>reducing the risk of uncharacteristic wildfire and improving forest resiliency;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id3e517c11fc0a468a8a2b88fdd6a3d4eb"><enum>(4)</enum><text>requiring ecological standards and collaboration for landscape-scale projects; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5c02f32caad2430da940b69a4615fcc4"><enum>(5)</enum><text>coordinating with Federal, State, local, and Tribal entities to support the pilot program described in paragraph (1) by taking full advantage of existing interagency agreements and authorities. </text></paragraph></section><section id="id980491a2a5854ace95c14a308b29cd19"><enum>103.</enum><header>Conservation finance agreements</header><subsection id="ide5ad974065304fd582a0b2a2366d3dc6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Pilot program authority</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a pilot program under which the Secretary may enter into a conservation finance agreement with a public or private person, including a for-profit or nonprofit organization, to carry out a conservation finance project if the Secretary finds each of the following:</text><paragraph id="idc43b101e717a4d3d90712bd30db0e5af"><enum>(1)</enum><text>There is a reasonable expectation that, throughout the contemplated agreement period, the Secretary will request funding for the agreement at the level required to avoid agreement cancellation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id154fa659aa5e495398d97a2cbd053919"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The environmental analysis for the project demonstrates that there is a supply sufficient to support a conservation finance agreement of—</text><subparagraph id="id98FCA092A0554AB3A5365BC87AE2C2FB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>small-diameter material; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9FF6C0414B1A41F0A5372DC47AF466F8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>other hazardous fuels, the removal of which would reduce the risk of uncharacteristic wildfire.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idb8fe9e32684c4603b3f93f8c34737965"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The use of the conservation finance agreement will assist in achieving the purpose described in section 102.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id530d1b07e5424a30a9e7bbc86ab090e2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The project involves a conservation finance project developer.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idbb6da9f9e68541d9b321ba6b001ef91f"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limited delegation</header><text>The Secretary may not delegate the pilot program authority under subsection (a) to a Federal official that serves under the Chief of the Forest Service.</text></subsection><subsection id="idd7c24eb71ef646fbb5baf27a4b30aa8e"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Limitations</header><text>The pilot program authority under subsection (a)—</text><paragraph id="id6C55F4AFCC4C403AB2762EE2508B60D2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>may not be used to enter into more than 20 conservation finance agreements;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id478368cdbb614a45a8b2c8adfbc7477e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may be used for the obligation under conservation finance agreements of—</text><subparagraph id="ided1a7d5fe30642078712562490725137"><enum>(A)</enum><text>during the 10-year period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act, not more than $250,000,000 in the aggregate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida66c33e74c0f46338f4bb6798645fbe7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not more than $50,000,000 for any 1 conservation finance agreement; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id673ffbb7c6e1483f8231e984e75d10fa"><enum>(3)</enum><text>may not be used to reimburse for interest paid to any other entity providing funds for the applicable conservation finance project.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id6E9389BD75704A4FADFD016E227C0EF0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In entering into conservation finance agreements under subsection (a), the Secretary shall give priority to projects described in that subsection that are based on restoration strategies addressing larger landscapes, particularly landscapes of 100,000 acres or more.</text></subsection><subsection id="id07998b3aae2346a38b81300b0b52ab27"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Cancellation, termination, or modification for insufficient funding</header><paragraph id="idc3048cef376b4bf5a880546191b09cd8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><subparagraph id="id92c5a2db255144d9ae63892b61877289"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Insufficient funding</header><text>If funds are not made available for the continuation of a conservation finance agreement made under this section into a subsequent fiscal year, the agreement shall be canceled, terminated, or modified.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id60a6d7a1507c480cac1e6f91dc5e3052"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Payment of costs</header><text>If the Secretary determines that it is necessary to cancel or terminate a conservation finance agreement pursuant to subparagraph (A), and the conservation finance agreement includes a cancellation or termination provision as described in paragraph (2)(A), the Secretary may pay the costs of that cancellation or termination using any of the following amounts:</text><clause id="id593d0950e2e340f6959302a43d7bd85d"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Appropriations originally available for the performance of the applicable conservation finance agreement.</text></clause><clause id="id7b06856ba3624cbf99b11f90ef7a0ce0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Appropriations currently available for the type of services concerned under the applicable conservation finance agreement, and not otherwise obligated.</text></clause><clause id="ida881d665bdd24b9aa1da47747de2b60c"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Funds appropriated for payment of the costs of cancellation or termination.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idcef5b774456e4a47abee26be6a8ab633"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Provisions in agreements</header><subparagraph id="idd19249119b1e4eeab56221788a9b70a9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may include cancellation or termination provisions in conservation finance agreements under this section to the extent that those provisions are necessary and in the best interests of the United States.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5d995c9379a341fabbafba09bcbe63dc"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>The cancellation or termination provisions described in subparagraph (A) may include consideration of the recurring and nonrecurring costs of the conservation finance project developer under the applicable conservation finance agreement.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9A19B32C050C42F1BB9CA96B9047728A"><enum>(3)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Cancellation and termination costs</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H96D785C7AEF44977A5611E8892C8A014"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may obligate funds in stages that are economically or programmatically viable to cover any potential cancellation or termination costs related to the Federal share of the costs under a conservation finance agreement under paragraph (1)(B) and implement the agreement pursuant to this section.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H504161D45DE748B790596E115C2CCDD2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Advance notice to Congress of cancellation or termination costs in excess of $25,000,000</header><text>Not later than 30 days before entering into a conservation finance agreement under this section that includes cancellation or termination costs in excess of $25,000,000, but does not include proposed funding for the costs of cancelling or terminating the agreement up to the maximum cancellation or termination costs in the agreement, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources and the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives a written notice that includes—</text><clause id="HE9EC0349F90544DD92923523F710CB46"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a description of the cancellation or termination cost amounts proposed for each program year in the agreement;</text></clause><clause id="H93275212F6994FC8A37730A59D7EF059"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the reasons why the cancellation or termination cost amounts described under clause (i) were selected;</text></clause><clause id="H6024FC1A831440E3BC46F82B4C95C7DF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a description of the extent to which the costs of agreement cancellation or termination are not included in the budget for the agreement; and</text></clause><clause id="H399D3BE7D24144B19F615967ECF33B9F"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>an assessment of the financial risk of not including budgeting for the costs of agreement cancellation or termination.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6BDF52C1AAB846B39900234AF687034F"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Transmittal of notice to OMB</header><text>Not later than 14 days after the date on which written notice is provided under subparagraph (B), the Secretary shall transmit a copy of the notice to the Director of the Office of Management and Budget.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2adbd2ab3efe4a72a181f2f85715609f"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Determination of cancellation or termination costs specific to a conservation finance agreement</header><text>The Secretary may enter into a conservation finance agreement pursuant to this section that includes conservation finance project developer services in return for payments by the Secretary in future years that are contingent on the appropriation of funds, subject to the requirement that the Secretary shall pay the conservation finance project developer the Federal share of the cancellation or termination costs under the agreement pursuant to paragraph (1)(B) up to the limitation on cancellation or termination costs applicable to the agreement if funding for the completion of the agreement is not appropriated.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idccc2f86a9e86489da8f995412e7bf6c9"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Non-Federal cost share</header><paragraph id="id499F71B116994E908ED9B50F4CF03F41"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The non-Federal share of the costs of implementing a conservation finance agreement carried out using amounts made available under this title shall be not less than 40 percent of the costs of implementing the conservation finance agreement, of which, subject to paragraph (2)—</text><subparagraph id="id34D26585E1994D7C995EB215D41B857C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>up to 50 percent may be reimbursed by the Forest Service, subject to the availability of appropriations and subsections (c)(3) and (e); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id089D305309714ADEB8377DF4A399E5B0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not less than 50 percent shall be covered by non-Federal funding, which may include in-kind contributions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idB5F16DF27B1C41558AD8ACCB1D44AAB7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Cost share for low-income communities</header><text>In the case of a conservation finance project that the Secretary determines would primarily benefit 1 or more low-income communities and for which the non-Federal entities involved cannot meet the cost share requirement under paragraph (1)—</text><subparagraph id="id1B71EF6A1D694532845DC88E30E46948"><enum>(A)</enum><text>subparagraph (A) of that paragraph shall be applied by substituting <quote>75 percent</quote> for <quote>50 percent</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idFA9BD290D4AD4F4FAA2FDFCDFF155999"><enum>(B)</enum><text>subparagraph (B) of that paragraph shall be applied by substituting <quote>25 percent</quote> for <quote>50 percent</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id8e38f674b0554f9a86924bf02ba3f7a8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Savings provision</header><text>Nothing in this subsection limits additional non-Federal financing or funding for a conservation finance project above the 40 percent minimum non-Federal cost share described in paragraph (1). </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ide63225c3306d4595a064ea9052b68a4a"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Stewardship end result contracting project authorities</header><text>A conservation finance agreement developed under this section may incorporate the authorities provided to the Secretary and the Chief of the Forest Service to enter into stewardship contracting projects under section 604 of the Healthy Forests Restoration Act of 2003 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/6591c">16 U.S.C. 6591c</external-xref>). </text></subsection></section><section id="id5ea83b82fb344f4ca552c976b6d7d938"><enum>104.</enum><header>Report evaluating implementation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 4 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Natural Resources and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate a report evaluating the implementation of this title, including—</text><paragraph id="ide26a8dc27be04e899a26587a53cd8c0b"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a list of conservation finance agreements entered into under this title and the accomplishments under the projects carried out under those agreements; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id393af0cf95304563990fa0f12ed9efd6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an evaluation of the pilot authority for conservation finance agreements described in section 103, including whether that authority has—</text><subparagraph id="id879d0eb5c76940bfa09e4a157cb7020e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>increased the availability of non-Federal funding sources to assist in landscape-scale forest restoration projects; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8f0dc6787b034793899baf2d11f496e7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>promoted private or other non-Federal investment in—</text><clause id="id1448359759b24ee18b07852a92ebc87d"><enum>(i)</enum><text>new or existing infrastructure and related equipment that can make use of the byproducts of forest restoration;</text></clause><clause id="ida3be2e13438e492cbdb543898fcb3f57"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the use of prescribed fire at a greater scale;</text></clause><clause id="id67d50d1a086b4e74a0aa00d3c99363a1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>related economic development and workforce training and development;</text></clause><clause id="idb17acb630ab840bd91f4ac2d1bbd1680"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>land management activities enhancing natural infrastructure with benefits for downstream water users; or</text></clause><clause id="idbbcdc2b0c47f4deb86c3d88f7e868f73"><enum>(v)</enum><text>mitigating the risk of uncharacteristic wildfire; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idea1dc61e034844b19e2884e9bf0ce2e0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any barriers limiting the broader use or implementation of the pilot project authority to additional projects, including risks that may discourage further participation and investment by outside parties. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></title><title id="id8BA8B951EB9A40E28D6074B0CF14A880" style="OLC"><enum>II</enum><header>Increasing Community Resilience to Wildfire</header><section id="id7f33a550aad8486094e050912b1267b0"><enum>201.</enum><header>Critical infrastructure and microgrid program</header><subsection id="id285BF3364EA24B328B38A7CA9B0B3F25"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="id557116C654C94D0290C9065CFA39EA59"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Critical facility</header><subparagraph id="idC11E2FDA3FE84810AD615F3CA4C2A6CE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <quote>critical facility</quote> means a facility that provides services or may be used—</text><clause id="idB049B7AD27014C289CB49958251E5FF7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to save lives;</text></clause><clause id="idD8662D28ABA14AC4AF7279A7C1343B33"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to protect property, public health, and public safety; or</text></clause><clause id="id6D4FFC7E875F45F09A4C5EAE378D9FC9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to lessen or avert the threat of a catastrophe.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idF4D95B1BF27D47699FCCBB243CF54101"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text>The term <quote>critical facility</quote> includes—</text><clause id="id913398EE929149469CDA28A2BCEBDFC0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a hospital; </text></clause><clause id="idE3BCAB1E959F434EB6EE32DE35157ECC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an outpatient clinic; </text></clause><clause id="id4EA56A5256FD4384A2D8ED108131E8A5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a nursing home; </text></clause><clause id="idC34C15B48065402D80710F4EC95ADF15"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a police station; </text></clause><clause id="id951915BB53C1482680B218925D409A52"><enum>(v)</enum><text>an emergency operation center;</text></clause><clause id="id2832B7340D0B4B5699F1D117686C20D0"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>a jail or prison;</text></clause><clause id="id6FBA89B42378429789A102DE7C2B8124"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>a fire station; </text></clause><clause id="id4F040B8766A047B9A36855E15960241E"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>a facility in the communications sector, as determined by the Secretary;</text></clause><clause id="idE6FF1BE79B424798BCE35081A3B1E811"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>a facility in the chemical sector, as determined by the Secretary;</text></clause><clause id="id8a8ab2312ee14b03980fc02cb8c5e52a"><enum>(x)</enum><text>a school or other large building that may serve as a temporary gathering space; </text></clause><clause id="idFAA7531651D6468F9B430EA2AC56EB31"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>a utility station, such as a water station, wastewater station, community water system, or irrigation works;</text></clause><clause id="idC7721C9B316D452CADC4A6921F7998D9"><enum>(xii)</enum><text>a facility described in subparagraph (A) that is owned or operated by, or provides services to, an Indian Tribe (as defined in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>));</text></clause><clause id="id4ad88384e7f346f1a0fdea7c07bedb84"><enum>(xiii)</enum><text>a Federal facility, including a military base or installation; and</text></clause><clause id="id353a2c5e48054154b4ffb99dc947709b"><enum>(xiv)</enum><text>any other facility described in subparagraph (A), as determined by the Secretary. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id60101899AAB74FE5984CF529858AA451"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of Energy.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id7DF7048AA148476BAD8F28D6AD5A725C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Critical infrastructure and microgrid program</header><paragraph id="idD758A5615C2F483CB0E2222029FE6127"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a program—</text><subparagraph id="id2961B10B00A9479FA84D8940038055F0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to improve the energy resilience and power needs of critical facilities through the development and use of microgrids, renewable energy, energy efficiency, reduced electricity demand, and on-site storage;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idCA1A9717104C4278B21573F379F5F5CE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to improve the energy efficiency of critical facilities by decreasing the size and cost of generators;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2a5d04283c554106adec229464dcf3fb"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to provide technical assistance and facilitate the distribution and sharing of information to develop more resilient electricity systems (including bulk systems and localized systems); and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id15A7AAE7D0CC4845BA009752146024D2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to promulgate consumer-facing information and resources to inform the public on best practices and resources related to increasing resilience of electricity systems and reducing the impacts of extreme weather events on electricity systems. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id022d986c0bc64572b128fb08f4d7ecfc"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>In carrying out the program established under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall ensure, with respect to critical facilities—</text><subparagraph id="id759DC14F8941483D88F79AB8FF995C17"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provision of on-site back-up power with renewable resources, low-carbon liquid fuels, and on-site energy storage technologies; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id53DA335E72FD43469B24635C0C0EE0A6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>installation, at the transmission and distribution level, of interoperable technologies, advanced power flow control, dynamic line rating, topology optimization, and communications systems. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id2ac0567b5ce948dd8662ba9e741e6381"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Interested party input</header><text>In establishing the program under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall seek the input of State energy regulators, electric utilities (as defined in section 3 of the Federal Power Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/796">16 U.S.C. 796</external-xref>)), regional transmission organizations and independent system operators, electric utility customers and ratepayer organizations, local governments, community choice aggregators or regional energy collaboratives, and other interested parties. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id97cd12c97dde406fbcf99ac056f245b1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5254248E2E1E41CCA1A75EF6C8E73611"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary $100,000,000 to carry out this section, to remain available until expended.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5a89a676d58e40029cd2c9129311b942"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administrative costs</header><text>Of the amount used to carry out this section, not more than 10 percent shall be used for salaries and expenses, administrative management, and oversight of the program established under subsection (b)(1). </text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id3A3B579719924015A0CAB60D587ECD3D"><enum>202.</enum><header>Retrofits for fire-resilient communities</header><subsection id="idd17055aed8774eb492078e31b59e7214"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition of weatherization materials</header><text>Section 412(9) of the Energy Conservation and Production Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6862">42 U.S.C. 6862(9)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="idFC9494DEC1D143BAB31993F1F947413E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (I), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idC19F147CB045447FBDBA526D95EC1098"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (J) as subparagraph (K); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idEB371A505A164BFDB52DAD98F716FA76"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (I) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idF54D0A46E3614B28A557212FC63B7FBB"><subparagraph id="id5F2A98C1A4144E27903A8DC572C4ED2D"><enum>(J)</enum><text>materials that are resistant to high heat and fire; and</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id1d38ea85c3d74b29852319e55ef4f216"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Weatherization program</header><paragraph id="id08FB1BE0BD97464CB493030EE63837FD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 413(b)(6) of the Energy Conservation and Production Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6863">42 U.S.C. 6863(b)(6)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="id517687842ED64EB0A428B56F81F90B61"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id907C79A38BFE4635B481E24447E4F46C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idAD1447D25BB44E449691C43DB86D8095"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id265856F20C36451BBAC9AE768687285E"><subparagraph id="idCB7C416A277C40418E98FCAB94EDDD5F"><enum>(E)</enum><text>owners of such dwelling units shall use fire- and drought-resistant building materials, including mass timber, and incorporate wildfire and drought prevention and mitigation planning, as directed by the State.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id3f684a8c939d426aa2ffcb5e8811e6a0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitations</header><text>Section 415(c) of the Energy Conservation and Production Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6865">42 U.S.C. 6865(c)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="idB8D12E496D554F1EAAAD5B6E8024A1F5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text><clause id="idBDBE706F685F4A32873706FD51C21AA1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (A) through (E) as clauses (i) through (v), respectively, and indenting appropriately;</text></clause><clause id="id17472E45A3F54A069D7E1068DE2CB897"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the matter preceding clause (i) (as so redesignated), in the second sentence, by striking <quote>Labor</quote> and all that follows through <quote>to—</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idC346BBD4A70C45529DF32E125E101601"><subparagraph id="idC2F5F6F16B394B309E469E4C2450706E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Labor and weatherization materials</header><text>Labor, weatherization materials, and related matter described in subparagraph (A) includes—</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause><clause id="idA129499348FE4920B10A4266FC81E311"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(c)(1) Except</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9F2B7BB40BF54ABC8F6B235E0DC22A8A"><subsection id="id98BC9B246CCE4BE3A7C5BC7E133AA291"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Financial assistance</header><paragraph id="id099FF7CE7E9C4E59AA5B887DFC1EFBA2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Average cost</header><subparagraph id="id711A0F8F49EB49B0804BBE27F6AA2675"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause><clause id="idC60F2CE0AEBA4066BEE10B1B01B7CD22"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A) (as so designated)—</text><subclause id="idFD503D15B62F4512A3FA7B415E2D7606"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by striking <quote>exceed an average of $6,500</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idD2FAFCB43A7740D898BEB82229B2FF83"><text>exceed—</text><clause id="id212E95174B7E4C0098368A64B345C5D5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an average of $13,000 (adjusted annually for inflation)</text></clause><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subclause><subclause id="idC7B53E2746D8448D89B881D19757BF7D"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in clause (i) (as so designated), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text></subclause><subclause id="idB46C48A5596A4FE7BC7E8A66AF48A0A3"><enum>(III)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idA75E2F0B9DC74258B3FA038D81D20767"><clause id="idEF3FFB5C959246B6A24BEEE518C2F9C4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>another average amount that is greater than the amount described in clause (i), if the Secretary determines it necessary to waive or adjust the average amount established under that clause.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subclause></clause><clause id="idBF2AA440A7E14FD5B6ACB1684A637527"><enum>(v)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B) (as so designated)—</text><subclause id="id4489548AAFFF4C33AF29914625E8868C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in clause (iv) (as so redesignated), by striking <quote>, and</quote> and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id00B19A71C7244A1D8B3778B081BC7696"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in clause (v) (as so redesignated), by adding a period at the end; and</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id797ea3aa5a754b8f96683cb101e117e0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by striking <quote>$3,000</quote> and inserting <quote>$6,000 (adjusted annually for inflation)</quote>. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" id="id584D50D6FB0041739D7275A801482A27"><enum>203.</enum><header>Wildfire detection, monitoring, and analysis equipment</header><subsection commented="no" id="idB3E7AAA364A141118408985EEDB8B56B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title VI of the Healthy Forests Restoration Act of 2003 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/6591">16 U.S.C. 6591 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id10F9C7CB84B5435C8A9856A5F5845CBF"><section commented="no" id="iddf473f87ea15424b9385ba609516b416"><enum>607.</enum><header>Wildfire detection, monitoring, and analysis equipment</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">To the extent practicable, the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Interior shall—</text><paragraph commented="no" id="id9E2DD33989984D098D8080FDAF5CD0B2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">expedite the placement of wildfire detection equipment, such as sensors, cameras, and other relevant equipment, in areas at risk of wildfire;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idebeb2f8bdf874f98bf5c23b52489da85"><enum>(2)</enum><text>expand the use of satellite and remote sensing data and mobile technologies to assist wildfire response, management, and firefighter safety through improved situational awareness; </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id5839EB2E22424FF4A2904D0F252B3A3A"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">expedite any permitting required by the Secretary of Agriculture or the Secretary of the Interior for the installation, maintenance, or removal of wildfire detection equipment;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7ac3ef21e63345a3b9d7436eaa47a905"><enum>(4)</enum><text>review permitting described in paragraph (3) and procurement requirements for wildfire detection equipment within the context of modern and innovative technology;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf3e3e9ee0c0d4db08694ae0924e7617b"><enum>(5)</enum><text>pursuant to the OPEN Government Data Act (title II of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/435">Public Law 115–435</external-xref>; 132 Stat. 5534), the amendments made by that Act, and any guidance issued by the Director of the Office of Management and Budget under that Act or those amendments, support the disclosure to the public of nonconfidential data assets the disclosure of which does not pose security risks to the public so that wildland fire data is discoverable, understandable, and actionable; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5d80e3c93e3e4286b2a1a349d38a4932"><enum>(6)</enum><text>utilize new and existing technologies to analyze performance measurements and suppression effectiveness of wildland fire incidents.</text></paragraph></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="id008466A37F7543BCB9E2064420AF4015"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents for the Healthy Forests Restoration Act of 2003 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/6501">16 U.S.C. 6501</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/108/148">Public Law 108–148</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end of the items relating to title VI the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id18E39487BFFC43BB826BD420D5F68F8E"><toc><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 607. Wildfire detection, monitoring, and analysis equipment.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></title><title id="id33D6DD4D278A45E3A9E221B9C1FE5559" style="OLC"><enum>III</enum><header>Research, Training, and Capacity Building</header><section id="id0A498BDF05114626A21CBB7D14243E24"><enum>301.</enum><header>Western prescribed fire centers</header><subsection id="id0b430a02c8714e559f995ca0989f33cd"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Interior (referred to in this section as the <term>Secretaries</term>) shall establish 1 or more centers to train individuals in prescribed fire methods and other methods relevant to the mitigation of wildfire risk (referred to in this section as a <term>center</term>).</text></subsection><subsection id="id82EC61B3073C4F59B179068B8B373975"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Host institutions</header><text>The 1 or more centers shall be—</text><paragraph id="id05214495BA1E4951A1F2FBDA54008194"><enum>(1)</enum><text>located at 1 or more institutions of higher education; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id66CEF9D506094E348E6D37113C7B7249"><enum>(2)</enum><text>developed in collaboration with 1 or more institutions of higher education.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id74418D5F03BB4D73810321C424BA6670"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Goals</header><text>The 1 or more centers shall advance the following goals:</text><paragraph id="idb44b0a2b486649fa8c47e210bdc59b43"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Training individuals and conducting research on prescribed fire methods and other restoration methods relevant to the mitigation of wildfire risk.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida630f670b051475b964a02caea80aed8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Developing and advancing interdisciplinary science relating to wildfire, including social science and human dimensions of wildfire, in consultation with stakeholders who—</text><subparagraph id="idFF7148F9210F4A9FB97670B6DF9B3FF5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>need that science;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id27C273C954294215A4F1E5B950B49374"><enum>(B)</enum><text>will benefit from the outcomes of that science; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5D990EF739284D7B811716C43641D54E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>will coordinate with 1 or more other centers in developing and advancing that science.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id705839fe96be45998c068d7f41438b71"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Conducting ongoing and forward-looking needs assessments among stakeholders, including Federal and State agencies and Indian Tribes, to determine common need requirements and emerging challenges to reduce wildfire risk and adapt communities to increased risk from wildfire, including the following hazard-related focus areas: </text><subparagraph id="id96578671094747A89F4BB1157667748A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Increasing disaster resilience.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id456E4D9EBAD64CEDB1F1C24A52ADB2DB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Mitigation and management methods.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0AA78FAAC2DE4958943A4BB52B3FC7C5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Air quality.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id79B9B3305E4C4E18B264DE9A74877210"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Firestorm weather forecasting and burn-area debris flow forecasting, including empirical and modeling research.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idff2e1981464f484898770a8e3e0098fd"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Collaborating with Federal wildfire scientists at the Forest Service, the Department of the Interior, and other related agencies.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id154f9050bdef41b7a1441da63143dd01"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Identifying, through a detailed engagement process targeting defined end-users, the requirements and delivery mechanisms for products and services that are practical and will have an impact on mitigating wildfire risk.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id750289390ed74f51b4036e75114b1ded"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Promoting technology transfer with pathways for dissemination, implementation, and application of research results on the ground, using and enhancing previous research.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id19bde87d3dd647a4bc554dc7badbaf46"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Ensuring the connectivity and interoperability of distributed services to maximize synergies and benefits across services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0b90328d35b34d6baece85a92889db14"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Developing open digital infrastructure to make research data, science, and models open for all sectors to use.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7c0180a6fc5d4c3c857597a191c854d5"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Understanding the effectiveness of historical and current wildfire management and suppression strategies, including on wildfires that start in wilderness areas, wilderness study areas, or inventoried roadless areas. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id94a1c8b8d882422cab3eefb626aed67c"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Location</header><paragraph id="id4B6BABC9A7C145C182098A24E33D9118"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The 1 or more centers shall be located in any State the entirety of which is located west of the 100th meridian.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idae164a708c814709a2e9d64ab14d2b3a"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>The Secretaries shall consult with the Joint Fire Science Program to solicit and evaluate proposals for the location of the 1 or more centers.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idE89DFF3762A242C38273C541026FD4AA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Selection</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, based on the consultation under paragraph (2), the Secretaries shall select a location for the 1 or more centers.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idA424938E3D6640A68001CACA2B43FF10"><enum>302.</enum><header>Innovative forest workforce development program</header><subsection id="id13558bd94c52443c8be7ce7c1e4b5886"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="idDE02663AF3E34A6FBBD02D24308678F0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Career in forestry and fire management</header><text>The term <term>career in forestry and fire management</term> means a career in a field relating to forests and the restoration to the natural fire regimes of forests, including—</text><subparagraph id="id6FFAFEBD1FF64AE089F3004DF33F6F56"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in timber operations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id168F53AA0D8E4102B741B973ED0529CC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>as a registered professional forester;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id923FA2B5207C4A178DB0D12D8B21D945"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in vegetation treatment, including as a member of a hand crew, a machine operator, and in conducting prescribed fires as part of a fire restoration workforce that is capable of conducting large landscape restorative and maintenance prescribed fires;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE6407A2ECCCF463E9933F83054698B4A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in ecological restoration, including restoration of watersheds;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id25271ECF97614C24B6CAFF09F8005437"><enum>(E)</enum><text>in wildland fire fighting; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8095A699E6524EFDBEA61FCF455DCB11"><enum>(F)</enum><text>in community fire resilience, including workforce development projects.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1E5836E5938C4D0DA7A4015F8B1C09EC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Forestry and fire management</header><text>The term <term>forestry and fire management</term> includes the areas of fields relating to forests described in subparagraphs (A) through (F) of paragraph (1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2A7FD1D009F040B5B155ACA89CEA524B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Agriculture.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="iddacc50db523d4279a7bc3f64ecb5bddb"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grants authorized</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a competitive grant program—</text><paragraph id="id95267f6139044f43879651a692994537"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to assist in the development and utilization of innovative activities relating to workforce development in forestry and fire management and opportunities for careers in forestry and fire management; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbe1c2f27d68148fa80a43f1d31ae1fb1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to expand public awareness about forestry and fire management and connect individuals to careers in forestry and fire management.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ida8499654b0a1494aaac8aa506156627e"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Selection of grant recipients</header><text>In awarding grants under subsection (b), the Secretary shall, to the extent practicable, select nonprofit professional or service organizations, labor organizations, State agencies, community colleges, institutions of higher education, or other training and educational institutions—</text><paragraph id="id447247ab1fd747c28caf09bd13fd353e"><enum>(1)</enum><text>that have qualifications and experience—</text><subparagraph id="idc1da6020a3ad4d0aaa17a0d53c3d543a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the development of training programs and curricula relevant to the workforce needs of forestry and fire management;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idab2f56b7296442b7b7fc0ea20cb0043e"><enum>(B)</enum><text>working in cooperation with forestry and fire management; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf8f33cea1ee0457fb858c087408dc3c7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>developing public education materials appropriate for communicating with groups of various ages and educational backgrounds; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9929dd10aae5437e9e0e6cc53f103f5d"><enum>(2)</enum><text>that will address the human resources and workforce needs of forestry and fire management.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idd782af43ab1b4eddaf2ea6056ff1a3b5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>Grants awarded under subsection (b) may be used for activities such as—</text><paragraph id="id750a0acffc7940d5aded65cd4eff0aba"><enum>(1)</enum><text>targeted internships, apprenticeships, pre-apprenticeships, and post-secondary bridge programs for skilled forestry and fire management trades that provide—</text><subparagraph id="idfe934845c69041a3b7cd1afc46788b96"><enum>(A)</enum><text>on-the-job training;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id58dc14e2b468497593b7c339c858be92"><enum>(B)</enum><text>skills development;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id089e153682f1468d8023b3a1dccec038"><enum>(C)</enum><text>test preparation for skilled trade apprenticeships;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id87e879a6d09342d0ba262b50de03fb7b"><enum>(D)</enum><text>advance training in forestry and fire management relating to jobs as forest restorationists, members of hand crews, wildland fire fighters, machine operators, licensed timber operators, registered professional foresters, ecologists, biologists, or workers in construction in support of resilient infrastructure, including residential buildings; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5b560484cf944a909aa6b63679141ec7"><enum>(E)</enum><text>other support services to facilitate post-secondary success;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="iddc6bdfb6fc424cff9ac834855b366d0f"><enum>(2)</enum><text>education programs designed for elementary, secondary, and higher education students that—</text><subparagraph id="idec1ab921cd3c400a8af667bc4d4e13bd"><enum>(A)</enum><text>inform people about the role of forestry, vegetation management, and ecological restoration in the communities of those people;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id235f9a7192bc4a58952d59a7cb168c02"><enum>(B)</enum><text>increase the awareness of opportunities for careers in forestry and fire management and exposure of students to those careers through various work-based learning opportunities inside and outside the classroom; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc040026b44774d5899c5974a70d0d8f8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>connect students to pathways to careers in forestry and fire management;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idc4d8a7baaa664a0193b0c3c5d38858e4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the development of a model curriculum and related vocational programs to be adopted by community colleges, which, to the extent practicable and feasible, shall—</text><subparagraph id="ida9a52b6f9955443e8759162e33d71f45"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide professional training in implementing prescribed fire projects, including the knowledge and skills necessary to plan and implement broad-scale surface and ladder fuel treatments within the wildland-urban interface, wildlands, and urbanized areas, as appropriate;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3efc16e423dd49729defd10b3f5c86cd"><enum>(B)</enum><text>include a focus on the ecological concerns, economics, and practices necessary to improve community safety and forest resilience; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id29fdf6a9f0fb43c38d1395aa0aa2ab25"><enum>(C)</enum><text>train students in—</text><clause id="idE08ACB761C7B4B3485AFB81BEDB32A3F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the retrofitting of houses, including the use of fire-resistant materials and the maintenance of defensible space;</text></clause><clause id="id26ea73ece51c4e5d906db021a5bb339c"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>urban forestry; and</text></clause><clause id="idce4f18b922f04380bc7246ec30c490cd"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>policies or guidance relating to the management of vegetation near utility infrastructure and relevant portions of electric utility wildfire mitigation plans;</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id32c83f8e98f045af9dab07331cc839d0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>regional industry and workforce development collaborations, including the coordination of candidate development, particularly in areas of high unemployment;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id540c79d8dfe54fb282759ca883ec594a"><enum>(5)</enum><text>integrated learning laboratories in secondary educational institutions that provide students with—</text><subparagraph id="id5bc83069d1b642c79b5286040c991097"><enum>(A)</enum><text>hands-on, contextualized learning opportunities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd6b7988cf79446d5b3150965236f619d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>dual enrollment credit for post-secondary education and training programs; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb38ce347e4b04e3d82e577e54c69be0d"><enum>(C)</enum><text>direct connection to industry or government employers; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id70f446cbb0764e438425f85271fd2f3a"><enum>(6)</enum><text>leadership development, occupational training, mentoring, or cross-training programs that ensure that workers are prepared for high-level supervisory or management-level positions.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id00b0461c5b3341eb90fb849b5a7d779e"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this section such sums as are necessary. </text></subsection></section><section id="id00c837593e944fee96680e24021e4a34"><enum>303.</enum><header>National community capacity and land stewardship grant program</header><subsection id="ida7ccb59133134c00a1b20a44c6adb349"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="ide1df738a95794070b953bfda89e3614e"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Community capacity</header><text>The term <term>community capacity</term> means the ability of an eligible entity to carry out or assist in a land stewardship activity.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb1a0785e34b34b66918c0feadca2872f"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Disadvantaged community</header><text>The term <term>disadvantaged community</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="id851764eac5554ee4943acdbbd7b83cb0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a low-income community (as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/45D">section 45D(e)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2db5a4d9dac843cebe738e40b576d493"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a community that includes a significant population that has been systematically denied a full opportunity to participate in aspects of economic, social, and civic life based on a particular characteristic, such as Black, Latino, Indigenous, and Native American persons, Asian Americans, Pacific Islanders, and other persons of color.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idaef5c3b87e5649c39e4e89f61d83eae3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means any the following entities that is located in or represents a disadvantaged community:</text><subparagraph id="id04f3a2ac34774016a33efbb09de7f8f3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An organization described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and exempt from taxation under section 501(a) of that Code.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idDBA09CD6F9AB4A0BA2E676ECF002F674"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A collaborative group fiscally sponsored by an organization described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd143f076d9154abf8ab35f6a0fbffc95"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A unit of local government.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6d8b5b5ffda04139ae703d24965018e8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>An Indian Tribe.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3546fe090a8a4a21b18605d430df7a2b"><enum>(E)</enum><text>A special district government, as defined by the Director of the Bureau of the Census.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id11901030b8544c6c92f0b52045252df8"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Ecological integrity</header><text>The term <term>ecological integrity</term> has the meaning given the term in section 219.19 of title 36, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id18030732AF774A368D512CA06235DDE2"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Indian Tribe</header><text>The term <term>Indian Tribe</term> has the meaning given the term in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2866fe5cb8a7439ea0689f7ff27f64ed"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Land stewardship activity</header><text>The term <term>land stewardship activity</term> means any of the following activities, as applied to a qualifying project:</text><subparagraph id="id12d793325256466e963496f145afa9d2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Planning.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id083a4ba82d2747b2bd38fdc5912a8039"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Collaboration and building community support.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id98cbcfc5f21043848ba4edcbd51aa637"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Implementation on land other than National Forest System land.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf62e0b0275f749df9b169c69615edc80"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Monitoring, including multiparty monitoring, and adaptive management.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idbd884b9f7b6c42b4b436d377800469b0"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Qualifying project</header><text>The term <term>qualifying project</term> means any of the following activities that takes place at least in substantial part on National Forest System land or national grasslands:</text><subparagraph id="idca610227b3584da597b54a2f0186de4e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Restoration of the ecological integrity of a forest, meadow, grassland, prairie, or other habitat.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3372a2f9b19840eb91042192537589a1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Tribal management for aligned cultural and ecological values.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id110d543cdfd64ef8a662fffedce8c775"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Enhancing community wildfire resilience in the wildland-urban interface.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf9480b4f84314620ade25048941470c2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Increasing equitable access to environmental education and volunteerism opportunities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idf6a45d1477c04f45a48a78b8b8097c8c"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Restoration</header><text>The term <term>restoration</term> has the meaning given the term in section 219.19 of title 36, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0CF5149BF44243A49BC82534F0337D69"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through—</text><subparagraph id="id09E00EB8B5C04E1F9A286D8D9ED02A7A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the regional offices of the State and Private Forestry Deputy Area of the Forest Service; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id44D379B2F76F4045AFF393B3A12A84CA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>as appropriate, regional offices of other Deputy Areas of the Forest Service.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0e5f5f968486449ebd6a7bcb20732851"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of this section is to support increasing community capacity, partnerships, and collaborations within and involving disadvantaged communities for land stewardship activities and restoration of ecological integrity on—</text><paragraph id="id8761E2197FC44AD9B943AE9B745DF012"><enum>(1)</enum><text>National Forest System land;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8F284FAA6D4944F186E57AE794D78B41"><enum>(2)</enum><text>national grasslands; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="idF17C65D6AA5840B1A3868B1F5CBA74AA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>adjacent private, State, and trust land associated with the health and resilience of land described in paragraphs (1) and (2).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ida0c7a43e280643bd9c91c23456cf134b"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Administration</header><paragraph id="idbf760c451ec44aa9a177aac494df8f78"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may issue grants to eligible entities for increasing community capacity for land stewardship activities and related activities based on the criteria described in subsection (d).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf4fd180daa134c9ca5b3c0f506d739a6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federal cost-share</header><subparagraph id="idE32EEBCDEEE8428EBA5FC133F6F55448"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may fund up to 100 percent of the cost of land stewardship activities and related activities carried out using a grant issued under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id7FAE7C49F68B4AE18B18FF5351F58A14"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Matching eligibility</header><text>A grant issued under this section may be considered a non-Federal matching contribution from the eligible entity that received the grant towards other sources of Federal funding.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id822631ED14124C39A9A2EF02B1E687C4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>The Secretary may issue a grant under paragraph (1) for a period of 1 or more years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide1b47f07d998443fa7825debd766ac44"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Maximum grant amount</header><text>The amount of a grant issued under paragraph (1) shall be not more than $50,000 per year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id06364ee0c86b47cfb1a86b58ce5f00d7"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Applicable laws</header><text>The Secretary shall administer grants under paragraph (1) in accordance with all applicable Federal and State laws.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idb78492a486044428827372eb71d9cd6f"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Criteria for awarding grants</header><paragraph id="id5C0FDD10016146608A2A1DB9BA05F171"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2), the Secretary shall award grants to eligible entities under subsection (c)(1) on a competitive basis in accordance with the following criteria:</text><subparagraph id="id22edf8a378fb41bf901e1bbcb6089696"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The extent to which the proposed land stewardship activities benefit units of the National Forest System and national grasslands over the short and long term.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id451aabe391f74bb4a1ff4dc014ede301"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The extent to which valuable ecological, economic, and social benefits to disadvantaged communities, including job creation and business development or retention, are likely to result from the scope of the land stewardship activities.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide94501860e1a49fb9e574c30bcfca72d"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The extent to which the grant would benefit disadvantaged communities that have historically received less investment in collaborative capacity.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8ad078e97da94981873e21baa658f014"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The extent to which the proposal brings together diverse interests through planning, collaboration, implementation, or monitoring of land stewardship activities to benefit units of the National Forest System or national grasslands.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2b4e418e7dd648f7be9f024e2978fcdd"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The extent to which the grant funds appear to be critical for the success of the eligible entity and the identified land stewardship activities.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8b094c26e3884b83916dad0666887017"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The extent to which the budget for the land stewardship activities is reasonable given the anticipated outcomes.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id19DB28EF52F24418808745FC742A262A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Set-aside for Indian Tribes</header><text>The Secretary shall allocate not less than 10 percent of the funding awarded under this section to Indian Tribes or eligible entities representing Indian Tribes.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idcc5eefb9c6094697acfccc62250a560a"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Annual reviews</header><paragraph id="idcf18cc12cefb474bafcacb4392d7c1b8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall establish and maintain an advisory panel composed of not more than 15 members to provide feedback each year to each regional office of the State and Private Forestry Deputy Area of the Forest Service on the extent to which the implementation of this section by the regional office is fulfilling the purpose described in subsection (b).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id083f1d1d97f744e3bdef7967982fc898"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text>The advisory panel established under paragraph (1) shall include representation from a diversity of public land stakeholders from across interest groups, including—</text><subparagraph id="id2B0E81482E1B43EC9D142C0AEDA377C5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not fewer than 8 members representing the interests of a diversity of disadvantaged communities; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2D273284866F442082F06853412B4611"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not fewer than 2 members representing not fewer than 2 Indian Tribes.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idc14b176a08bf488483ce7a370486d2af"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exemption</header><text>The advisory panel established under paragraph (1) shall be exempt from <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/10">chapter 10</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code (commonly referred to as the <quote><act-name parsable-cite="FACA">Federal Advisory Committee Act</act-name></quote>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id7242c91eae674dd3adb03eeb415fdc77"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Report evaluating program implementation</header><paragraph id="idcdc6bbd8f53642c999d22d6b33263d53"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 4 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Natural Resources and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate a report evaluating the implementation of this section, including—</text><subparagraph id="id8f265bba555648edb430ae77e962a8dd"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a list of the eligible entities and land stewardship activities selected for funding under this section and the accomplishments of those activities; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0fdab19db29b417e86d19469fc88edc1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an evaluation of the extent to which the implementation of this section is fulfilling the purpose described in subsection (b).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id7e2176b20e6f448cab17ede52abe4b6d"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consultation; contracting</header><text>In preparing the report under paragraph (1), the Secretary—</text><subparagraph id="idA28319717A664C92A2D7F812D4B5583A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall consult with the advisory panel established under subsection (e)(1); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idddc88b4ad9ec455e984e9a1e2b24e22c"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may contract with a third party to complete an evaluation of the implementation of this section to inform the report. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id45575b2c886448bd861af32491ff5556"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><paragraph id="id611736b397ef4a92946fefaa59156d5d"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this section $50,000,000 for the period of fiscal years 2025 through 2029.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd9d9f9a625fc42fb9ef0573821d5702f"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Distribution</header><text>The Secretary shall distribute amounts made available under paragraph (1) to the regional offices of the State and Private Forestry Deputy Area and, as appropriate, regional offices of other Deputy Areas, of the Forest Service to administer the grants under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ideab723a675ea4421ab56eb343e4f1552"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Administrative costs</header><text>Not more than 10 percent of any amounts made available to carry out this section may be used for administrative management and program oversight. </text></paragraph></subsection></section></title></legis-body></bill> 

