<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" dms-id="H873B622885B74F15AA4731BA215BF162" public-private="public" key="G" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1048 : Defending Education Transparency and Ending Rogue Regimes Engaging in Nefarious Transactions Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code> 
<congress>119th CONGRESS</congress> <session>1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 1048</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber> 
<action>
<action-date date="20250331">March 31, 2025</action-date>
<action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to strengthen disclosure requirements relating to foreign gifts and con- tracts, to prohibit contracts between institutions of high- er education and certain foreign entities and countries of concern, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H5BD47D2E19AC452595B7E96E960DFAAC" style="OLC"><pagebreak/> 
<section id="HE6561074FD25446384B8C17467209927" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Defending Education Transparency and Ending Rogue Regimes Engaging in Nefarious Transactions Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>DETERRENT Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HCCD8409C14974C8881DD26701577F749" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Disclosures of foreign gifts</header> <subsection id="H673E58BD19AC460681ACF9C9D673C290"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 117 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1011f">20 U.S.C. 1011f</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBEB35B1CF1834D2C8D49CD44B55820E1"> 
<section id="H6913E1EDDE53493EBBA69A1F19BE9C71"><enum>117.</enum><header>Disclosures of foreign gifts</header> 
<subsection id="HE181E56D2EB84C8D8001798440C106B4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Disclosure reports</header> 
<paragraph id="H2F755F88DBAE4F7EAE353B699574CA32"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Aggregate gifts and contract disclosures</header><text>An institution shall file with the Secretary, in accordance with subsection (b)(1), a disclosure report on July 31 of the calendar year immediately following any calendar year in which— </text> <subparagraph id="H829F508139614CEE80E9AC6774C75E79"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the institution receives a gift from, or enters into a contract with, a foreign source (other than a foreign country of concern or foreign entity of concern)—</text> 
<clause id="H0FF78BF223E34556807EAB99F57597C7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the value of which is $50,000 or more, considered alone or in combination with all other gifts from, or contracts with, that foreign source within the calendar year; or</text></clause> <clause id="HAE59BDF648EB495CBC3EE7284E54242E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the value of which is indeterminate; or</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA66C5BFE6B84400FB5224C6B11015765" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the institution—</text> <clause id="H726C4515950C4691A828F8892949A7DE" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">receives a gift from a foreign country of concern or foreign entity of concern, without regard to the value of such gift; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="HD3967E8935AC4520996C8A3A4D9D9564" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>upon receiving a waiver under section 117A to enter into a contract with such a country or entity, enters into such contract, without regard to the value of such contract.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE64CCE55A0914F28A647D0FFA30D51E0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Foreign source ownership or control disclosures</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding paragraph (1), in the case of an institution that is substantially controlled (as described in section 668.174(c)(3) of title 34, Code of Federal Regulations) (or successor regulations)) by a foreign source, the institution shall file with the Secretary, in accordance with subsection (b)(2), a disclosure report on July 31 of each year.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3BC2B179D7E342DDA953160328170E01" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Treatment of affiliated entities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, any gift to, or contract with, an affiliated entity of an institution shall be considered a gift to, or contract with, respectively, such institution.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H299383A3CDA94A7AAF6D357829196369"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents of report</header> <paragraph id="H83AC3FFB7C994391980519DB3C827781"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Gifts and contracts</header><text>Each report to the Secretary required under subsection (a)(1) shall include the following: </text> 
<subparagraph id="H7AED36B4606A4E5DACEB4C8F1FAD999D" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to a gift received from, or a contract entered into with, any foreign source—</text> <clause id="HBDBC325FC983492985A75D1DCAC194D2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the name of the individual, department, or other entity at the institution receiving the gift or carrying out the contract on behalf of the institution; </text></clause> 
<clause id="H74528DEC1B4D4D81AC2BDEAE9E493F25" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any intended purpose of the gift or contract communicated to the institution by the foreign source, and, as of the date of filing such report, the manner in which the institution intends to use such gift or contract;</text></clause> <clause id="H6345DBC62ACA4DF2B42EB86DCDE8DB10" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a restricted or conditional gift or contract, a description of each restriction or condition that meets the definition of the term <term>restricted or conditional gift or contract</term> in subsection (f);</text></clause> 
<clause id="H5F8E0AC36929423289077EC96C2BB293"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>with respect to such a gift— </text> <subclause id="H2C436CC041DA440899B6D8E24060A336"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the total fair market dollar amount or dollar value of the gift, as of the date of submission of such report; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H34CFFE35A32145D683041DA4A3D82B3C"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the date on which the institution received such gift;</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HB96E6BC20C8B45059B9C17E953D329DC" commented="no"><enum>(v)</enum><text>with respect to such a contract—</text> 
<subclause id="HFEC98CDC917D40FEBD8D8A8B25888D39"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the total fair market dollar amount or dollar value of the contract, as of the date of submission of such report;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H60BC4E6501D243C8A06EB928C0AD455A" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the date on which the institution enters into such contract;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H7BDC3CBE2E4A48CFB3BFF9F2B8EBAC7A"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the date on which such contract first takes effect;</text></subclause> <subclause id="HCB34C291DC254A8BA654C0963FA9991F" commented="no"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>if the contract has a termination date, such termination date; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H9F06D3605B5048338EA488996FAF334D" commented="no"><enum>(V)</enum><text>an assurance that the institution will—</text> <item id="H8E4A0F8613C6433B86875B6006C86D6F" commented="no"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>maintain an unredacted copy of the contract until the latest of—</text> 
<subitem id="H281FE92603D9486484DCDE67EF7B29D3" commented="no"><enum>(AA)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the date that is 5 years after the date on which such contract first takes effect;</text></subitem> <subitem id="H826388BED1E04D97A10AC41A44BCAEF4" commented="no"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>the date on which the contract terminates; or</text></subitem> 
<subitem id="H278BBB89708D4B2281BF4BA2881A9A1B" commented="no"><enum>(CC)</enum><text>the last day of any period that applicable State law requires a copy of such contract to be maintained; and</text></subitem></item> <item id="H2C2DD546DC884B82ADC94DB5B723A0A0" commented="no"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">upon request of the Secretary during an investigation under section 117D(a)(1), produce such an unredacted copy of the contract.</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC34F07E065D14F639FF280477DA3D34E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>With respect to a gift received from, or a contract entered into with, a foreign source that is a foreign government (other than the government of a foreign country of concern)—</text> <clause id="H50263841E36C424CADD4C0445D89D8FF"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the name of such foreign government;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HC1D501D6E51A40009D358979D41C9548"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the department, agency, office, or division of such foreign government that approved such gift or contract, as applicable; and</text></clause> <clause id="H127DD5ECA0744E11BF759153ED03C4F2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the physical mailing address of such department, agency, office, or division.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H07884C421A7B4AF7A807EA9A82E29458" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to a gift received from, or contract entered into with, a foreign source other than a foreign government subject to the requirements of subparagraph (B)—</text> <clause id="H03FAF3EDEF9248D98A559401BEF70568" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum> <subclause id="HDBA2D04F8B8147F49861C3B2D235EF7F" display-inline="yes-display-inline" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the legal name of the foreign source; or</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HE6AD46DEC26D44EF90AEC6CC4CE808F8" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a gift received from a foreign source that awarded such gift to the institution as an agent described in subsection (f)(4)(G) on behalf of another foreign source—</text> <item id="H3869F5806FE341D5B19CA11838A35B4E" commented="no"><enum>(aa) </enum><text>the legal name of the foreign source that awarded such gift; and</text></item> 
<item id="H760DE829EBF5469B82D5CF292EB3C172" commented="no"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the legal name of the foreign source on whose behalf the gift was awarded, or a statement certified by a compliance officer in accordance with section 117D(c) that the institution has reasonably attempted to obtain such name;</text></item></subclause></clause> <clause id="HF3BB3C01F0BC4C44B5E9F7B0562497A7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case of a foreign source that is a natural person, each country of citizenship of such person, or, if no such country is known, the principal country of residence of such person;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HACD82FA944B848CFAFCEEDC364A5D587"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in the case of a foreign source that is a legal entity, the country in which such entity is incorporated, or, if such information is not available, the principal place of business of such entity; </text></clause> <clause id="HC2BE8C7224A84147BC133E089A588E49"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the physical mailing address of such foreign source, or, if such address is not available, a statement certified by a compliance officer in accordance with section 117D(c) that the institution has reasonably attempted to obtain such address; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H4E01AE0DBEE3467A993ECC173BBDDF33"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any affiliation of the foreign source to an organization that is designated as a foreign terrorist organization pursuant to section 219 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1189">8 U.S.C. 1189</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9467E5BDCB1341AAB4A5450430C40526"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to a contract entered into with a foreign source that is a foreign country of concern or a foreign entity of concern—</text> 
<clause id="H15B9833CFCD34D54BE2BCA41026B4ADC" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a complete and unredacted copy of the original contract, and if such original contract is not in English, a translated copy in accordance with subsection (c); </text></clause> <clause id="HB6C5C76257324E85BAF0E345292F56DF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a copy of the waiver received under section 117A for such contract; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H74A4BDB9DEA749058A2DA40AFDB8C558" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the statement submitted by the institution for purposes of receiving such a waiver under section 117A(b)(2).</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H438A73FDEB12474A9A947BC9F858CCF3" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to a gift received from a foreign source that is a foreign country of concern or a foreign entity of concern, an assurance that the institution will—</text> 
<clause id="H3E9F28A97E6D43C8B8ABDB8D5AEBEAC4" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in a case in which the institution received documentation relating to such gift, maintain such documentation until the latest of—</text> <subclause id="HD74C6376E67245B8AB1477C1238F8C10" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the date that is 5 years after the date such gift was received by the institution; or</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H7820946223CB49B9BD668C19BD90EBCA" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the last day of any period that applicable State law requires a copy of such documentation to be maintained; and</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H246A2139720F4FBAB50EA6DCA2CD2EFB" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">upon request of the Secretary during an investigation under section 117D(a)(1), produce such documentation;</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H63847877C9CD47F3B979D46C28D667FD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Foreign source ownership or control</header><text>Each report to the Secretary required under subsection (a)(2) shall contain—</text> <subparagraph id="H58ED8A6609F3499B8035D72E12DBDF98" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the information required under paragraph (1) of this subsection;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA150385ACA4C4EBFA0E40CA8719C1D79"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the legal name and the mailing address of the foreign source that substantially controls the institution as described in such subsection;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H31EE0F770EA942759F82125BA7532634"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the date on which the foreign source assumed such substantial control; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8A2105FD7CF04AFE82C07205F704336B"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any changes in program or structure of the institution of higher education resulting from such substantial control.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H2013DBEA044947FB8D487B1BFB762201" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header> Translation requirements</header><text>Any information required to be disclosed under this section, or requested by the Secretary pursuant to an investigation under section 117D(a)(1), with respect to a gift or contract that is not in English shall be translated into English, for purposes of such disclosure or such investigation, by a person that is not—</text> 
<paragraph id="H3E54EE8E93184AE49ED0F9F3DEBB558C" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a foreign source that awarded such gift or entered into such contract; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFA0E9C68849D47D4A5D1B88B107FA991" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any other foreign source from an attributable country of a foreign source referred to in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H06D4BDC4662A4321ACFDD66C13B5A050"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Public inspection</header> 
<paragraph id="H17C077BCF308428DA357BA81562ED31E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Database requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning not later than May 31 of the calendar year following the date of enactment of the <short-title>DETERRENT Act</short-title>, the Secretary shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H9022FA9F1EE94472AF06E8DD1BE22CB6"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish and maintain a searchable database on a website of the Department, under which all reports submitted under this section (including, to the extent practicable, any report submitted under this section before the date of enactment of the <short-title>DETERRENT Act</short-title>)—</text> 
<clause id="H66DC121E61754A87ADD95204D2BE3710"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are made publicly available (in electronic and downloadable format), including any information provided in such reports (other than the information prohibited from being publicly disclosed pursuant to paragraph (2));</text></clause> <clause id="HFEEB8B64E168432E895E219D44718FFD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>can be individually identified and compared; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H16996886FDC44D97B8D2C0A559992AE2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to the extent practicable, are searchable and sortable—</text> <subclause id="H843BBBAEA0BC409082419D78D5EF28B7"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by the institution that filed such report;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H49F91DAFB3394CAFA1D4403BBFAA3172"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by the date on which the institution filed such report;</text></subclause> <subclause id="HFD2070EA8FC44BBBB194D818A5750AAD"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by the date on which the institution received the gift which is the subject of the report;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HFA402C9274AF490F997782EF20278D5D"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>by the date on which the institution enters into the contract which is the subject of the report;</text></subclause> <subclause id="HB2BF646E6877457B91C4F3EE9D3A1ACB"><enum>(V)</enum><text>by the date on which such contract first takes effect;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H9E82ADDB584542C5A9926B27131BAA9D"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>by the attributable country of such gift or contract; </text></subclause> <subclause id="H0246C73DBD1B48B095F7E79F13026649" commented="no"><enum>(VII)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by the name of the foreign source; </text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HA034023BE8C4465E84648181E078E48A"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by the information described in subparagraph (C)(i); and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H4DDFB803F01047C9AB5735E1EEFA6EE0"><enum>(IX)</enum><text>by the information described in subparagraph (C)(ii);</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0155EB78BDDD436395B7123D80FEC1B3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not later than 30 days after receipt of a disclosure report under this section, include such report in such database;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H717F969F9962400383DA22E4A844D2CB" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>indicate, as part of the public record of a report included in such database, whether the report is with respect to a gift received from, or a contract entered into with—</text> 
<clause id="HCB3875DE6F6749F39F0496FB08BB6AA4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a foreign source that is a foreign government; or</text></clause> <clause id="H25367CBCD8CD40C7812784727262A04F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a foreign source that is not a foreign government; and </text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE7D19FB6572F4D3799E0D15B5CF2A14A" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to a disclosure report that does not include the name or address of a foreign source, indicate, as part of the public record of such report included in such database, that such report did not include such information.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB0F0C9EF5AFF4BDB966C8386C75B74E9" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application of Federal privacy law; protections for natural persons</header> <subparagraph id="H0BDCF256F291476281C65B9FC9889AEA" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Application of Federal privacy law</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), a disclosure report filed pursuant to this section is not subject to Federal privacy law (including any exemption from disclosure described in section 552(b) of title 5, United States Code)).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCCF9DB27118344168EDD19BB7DC62E26" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Protections for natural persons</header> 
<clause id="H446989DED27B42A0A7D458F9BB946BC2" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in clause (ii), with respect to a disclosure report filed under this section, the name or address (other than the attributable country) of a foreign source that is a natural person—</text> <subclause id="HBC019465E0E648FEBA7838DA2F9E72D7" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>may not be publicly disclosed; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H0B8996D9DBAA422D862449AF5DE2CBD4" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is exempt from disclosure under subsection (b)(3) of section 552 of title 5, United States Code (commonly referred to as the Freedom of Information Act).</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HB301C6023A4A409A9B1F7D66554F237D" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Exceptions for contracts with a foreign country of concern or foreign entity of concern</header><text>Clause (i) shall not apply to a disclosure report filed pursuant to this section that contains information with respect to a contract described in subsection (a)(1)(B)(ii) entered into with a foreign country of concern or foreign entity of concern.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB48B287ED46D4FFB91F5E5C1A7D3E6FB" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Interagency information sharing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, not later than 30 days after receiving a disclosure report from an institution in compliance with this section, the Secretary shall transmit an unredacted copy of such report (including the name and address of a foreign source disclosed in such report) to the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, the Director of National Intelligence, the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency, the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Defense, the Attorney General, the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Secretary of Energy, the Director of the National Science Foundation, and the Director of the National Institutes of Health. </text></subsection> <subsection id="HA5106F7F064B4A4CBB725E2F6CD2EA15"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="HC685ADE2C25846388AB443774E69D2BF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Affiliated entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>affiliated entity</term>, when used with respect to an institution, means an entity or organization that operates primarily for the benefit of, or under the auspices of, such institution, such as a foundation of the institution, or an educational, cultural, or language entity. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4FF1B9CA8C694D6CB9A1DBD13DCE48B6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Attributable country</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>attributable country</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H31AC3B9065804CA58AA9161FF86E6917" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the country of citizenship of a foreign source who is a natural person, or, if such country is unknown, the principal residence of such foreign source; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1EB8F657ECB24D2C86F226A636CB3010" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the country of incorporation of a foreign source that is a legal entity, or, if such country is unknown, the principal place of business (as applicable) of such foreign source. </text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H69525E47C792467FB3FBF73F2CDBC9F9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Contract</header><text>The term <term>contract</term>—</text> <subparagraph id="H3D2E71C0C56944198FED642505B2538F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means—</text> 
<clause id="H844F7D2A74EE4C09B6DD144D8DD9A14F"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any agreement for the acquisition by purchase, lease, or barter of property (including intellectual property) or services by the foreign source;</text></clause> <clause id="H1A1242BD28E04CDFBBEC6A2B1E98BF99" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">except as provided in subparagraph (B)(ii), any agreement for the acquisition by purchase, lease, or barter of property (including intellectual property) or services from a foreign source; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HCC39996A3F584E6AA62C476FD8272013"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any affiliation, agreement, or similar transaction with a foreign source that involves the use or exchange of an institution’s name, likeness, time, services, or resources; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF76A1C8A468E4A478997A8A238C8264C" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not include—</text> 
<clause id="HE4F55F4D4C4641F1A942886639B510B5" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an agreement made between an institution and a foreign source regarding any payment of one or more elements of a student’s cost of attendance (as such term is defined in section 472), unless such an agreement is made for more than 15 students or is made under a restricted or conditional contract; </text></clause> <clause id="H0D5F7DB5E6954B9D84F1962E534A2982" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an arms-length agreement for the acquisition by purchase, lease, or barter of property (including intellectual property) or services from a foreign source that is not a foreign country of concern or a foreign entity of concern; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="HC0D9B904B25246A7AB704352B5426C15" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any assignment or license of a granted intellectual property right (including a patent, trademark, or copyright) that is not associated with a category listed in the Commerce Control List maintained by the Bureau of Industry and Security of the Department of Commerce and set forth in Supplement No. 1 to part 774 of title 15, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6947D70E2E8943C6AC65C0F5B70D5479"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Foreign source</header><text>The term <term>foreign source</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H8DB5207F5C16481F8B21645EA980C009"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a foreign government, including an agency of a foreign government;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H61FEB9223AD7497092BA9A62E7DF8A0B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a legal entity, governmental or otherwise, created under the laws of a foreign state or states;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7FE2AF907F874DF88A13255FA07C4347"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a legal entity, governmental or otherwise, substantially controlled (as described in section 668.174(c)(3) of title 34, Code of Federal Regulations) (or successor regulations)) by a foreign source;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAE980C7808E94FDBB67F7A831C5C49B8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a natural person who is not a citizen or a national of the United States or a trust territory or protectorate thereof; </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA450A583304742E18429ACAB17B57422"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an international organization (as such term is defined in the International Organizations Immunities Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/288">22 U.S.C. 288</external-xref>));</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H190ABC33335E449C9B137F1BCFC8E7E8"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a person who is an agent of a foreign principal (as such term is defined in section 1 of the Foreign Agents Registration Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/611">22 U.S.C. 611</external-xref>)); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1FDC9D636EDE457FAEC84C09F8AF3520" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><text>an agent of any of the entities described in subparagraphs (A) through (F), including—</text> <clause id="HF6AC1F63F6874C6A90771BD7C35B860B" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a subsidiary or affiliate of a foreign legal entity, acting on behalf of such an entity; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HD3B6ACB599A643A585FE02863FB1B42D" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a person that operates primarily for the benefit of, or under the auspices of, such an entity, such as a foundation of such entity, or an educational, cultural, or language entity.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCB73D63563C54E8C87243B0FFF006A18"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Gift</header><text>The term <term>gift</term>—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H1365F1C7CB1F4DA29EA925D3DD062D3B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means any gift of money, property (including intellectual property), resources, staff, or services; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7232F85D813E4C5F8BE2554C0D7886C8"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not include—</text> 
<clause id="HC33A5463F6274B60B013F7A9653C61CC"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any payment of one or more elements of a student’s cost of attendance (as such term is defined in section 472) to an institution by, or scholarship from, a foreign source who is a natural person, acting in their individual capacity and not as an agent for, at the request or direction of, or on behalf of, any person or entity (except the student), made for not more than 15 students, and that is not made under a restricted or conditional contract with such foreign source;</text></clause> <clause id="H19D9189D447E4A89A3B39BD6AE4CF99D" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any assignment or license of a granted intellectual property right (including a patent, trademark, or copyright) that is not associated with a category listed in the Commerce Control List maintained by the Bureau of Industry and Security of the Department of Commerce and set forth in Supplement No. 1 to part 774 of title 15, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations); or </text></clause> 
<clause id="H35F277098A444E86A7FCEEAB862198A6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>decorations (as such term is defined in section 7342(a) of title 5, United States Code).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6629043BEF58400EB489338F9B3B5B66" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Restricted or conditional gift or contract</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>restricted or conditional gift or contract</term> means any endowment, gift, grant, contract, award, present, or property (including intellectual property) of any kind which includes provisions regarding—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H63C5208ABAE74FF8BED3C76E28CE833E" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the employment, assignment, or termination of faculty;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDD2425039FA74630908276FF2FD3B632" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the establishment of, or the provision of funding for, departments, centers, institutes, instructional programs, research or lecture programs, or new faculty positions; </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC66E6E705E1E4A8CBADF0150732DDAAF" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the selection, admission, or education of students; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H087ACE41DB1A480AB271E64DB7EFC091" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the award of grants, loans, scholarships, fellowships, or other forms of financial aid restricted to students of a specified country, religion, sex, ethnic origin, or political opinion.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HAD3871679B2C40FE8B6FBEFD940512C7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition on contracts with certain foreign entities and countries</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Part B of title I of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1011">20 U.S.C. 1011 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 117 the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE4F10B7A87894B22A5042A91FC316265"> <section id="H89CC4244FC524F939EAF5579763A2A97"><enum>117A.</enum><header>Prohibition on contracts with certain foreign entities and countries</header> <subsection id="HEB92F240797044A18C52B82A4554B263"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An institution shall not enter into a contract with a foreign country of concern or a foreign entity of concern.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3139447A4C554644B67685868FA6E646"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Waivers</header> 
<paragraph id="H05177F59B6CF460BBF8520F0BE7F7810"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A waiver issued under this section to an institution with respect to a contract shall only—</text> <subparagraph id="H0027600629A6440C853EF0230A9918CB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>waive the prohibition under subsection (a) for a 1-year period; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFE05ADD016684E2FAE95C5B9672B0361" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>apply to the terms and conditions of the proposed contract submitted as part of the request for such waiver. </text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6F74E0B104664ECEB76B7BE49D4B93E0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Submission</header> <subparagraph id="H0FE91B22A2FF41D5A088CD89F308D463"><enum>(A)</enum><header>First waiver requests</header> <clause id="H532986A048964BE5A744A421B2A15CEA"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An institution that desires to enter into a contract with a foreign entity of concern or a foreign country of concern may submit to the Secretary, not later than 120 days before the institution enters into such a contract, a request to waive the prohibition under subsection (a) with respect to such contract.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H99F99C82C81F45609737C906CB2794A3"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Contents of waiver request</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A waiver request submitted by an institution under clause (i) shall include—</text> <subclause id="HAFD6F52BA0C049949789484F758BF045" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the complete and unredacted text of the proposed contract for which the waiver is being requested, and if such original contract is not in English, a translated copy of the text into English (in a manner that complies with section 117(c)); and </text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HAA23A53806C34E2E9338F7D5BF903400"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a statement that—</text> <item id="HE020E49CA2424C2F962025DA2A7ABFA2"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is certified by a compliance officer of the institution designated in accordance with section 117D(c); and</text></item> 
<item id="HDBACBF9083484150BAC4B4BE93A22187"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>includes information that demonstrates that such contract—</text> <subitem id="HC7AA8B720D4341CEB930C7315A7D7F33"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>is for the benefit of the institution’s mission and students; and</text></subitem> 
<subitem id="H0B81C61F73FA4A4A9329ABA4E96239DF"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>will promote the security, stability, and economic vitality of the United States.</text></subitem></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HACBF541A629F4F6C8311418E3F6A6EDC"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Renewal waiver requests</header> <clause id="H2443D817ABA94336A180AE058B66B5C3"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An institution that, pursuant to a waiver issued under this section, has entered into a contract, the term of which is longer than the 1-year waiver period and the terms and conditions of which remain the same as the proposed contract submitted as part of the request for such waiver may submit, not later than 120 days before the expiration of such waiver period, a request for a renewal of such waiver for an additional 1-year period (which shall include any information requested by the Secretary).</text></clause> 
<clause id="H51FDAD573FEB4E3CA028BD37305DE42B"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>If the institution fails to submit a request under clause (i) or is not granted a renewal under such clause, such institution shall terminate such contract on the last day of the original 1-year waiver period.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4D98335799384B3A95A25C45D54F828B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Waiver issuance</header><text>The Secretary—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H55D4E98163BD48EDB374CC5B76E221C4"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 60 days before an institution enters into a contract pursuant to a waiver request under paragraph (2)(A), or before a contract described in paragraph (2)(B)(i) is renewed pursuant to a renewal request under such paragraph, shall notify the institution—</text> <clause id="H99ACFDE3CA8541A8AF713A18C2786B77"><enum>(i)</enum><text>if the waiver or renewal will be issued by the Secretary; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H865A451A3935478AA31E74F0F041CAA8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in a case in which the waiver or renewal will be issued, the date on which the 1-year waiver period starts; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAFE51558BEBF4ED1AA164013CCD5A1B8"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may only issue a waiver under this section to an institution if the Secretary determines, in consultation with each individual listed in section 117(e), that the contract for which the waiver is being requested—</text> 
<clause id="HE1B1E1B6F8A14C6899E7B0E7FCE5CF87"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is for the benefit of the institution’s mission and students; and</text></clause> <clause id="H2ED23C7E95AA47E8B94B05FEF5633C25"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>will promote the security, stability, and economic vitality of the United States.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H841EFBB7C9C14636B4F6D0DB9BBC54FC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Disclosure</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not less than 2 weeks prior to issuing a waiver under paragraph (2), the Secretary shall notify the authorizing committees of the intent to issue the waiver, including a justification for the waiver.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF1B27DDE883F46A3AA71677EBF169BE3" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Designation during contract term</header><text>In the case of an institution that enters into a contract with a foreign source that is not a foreign country of concern or a foreign entity of concern but which, during the term of such contract, is designated as a foreign country of concern or foreign entity of concern, such institution shall terminate such contract not later than 60 days after the Secretary notifies the institution of such designation. </text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC9511174B19741DBB6F9D751791C9334"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Contracts prior to date of enactment</header> 
<paragraph id="HB79985BBA67141A4B002F88F47E8392D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of an institution that has entered into a contract with a foreign country of concern or foreign entity of concern prior to the date of enactment of the <short-title>DETERRENT Act</short-title>—</text> <subparagraph id="H50F20879889D4E13B60FCF8C266197EF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the institution shall as soon as practicable, but not later than 30 days after such date of enactment, submit to the Secretary a waiver request in accordance with clause (ii) of subsection (b)(2)(A); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4F7E89C13AC74458803FDE5A9C1FE76A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary shall, upon receipt of the request submitted under such clause, issue a waiver to the institution for a period beginning on the date on which the waiver is issued and ending on the sooner of—</text> <clause id="HD6A1CC13063E4089A94A54A80290B7D3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the date that is 1 year after the date of enactment of the <short-title>DETERRENT Act</short-title>; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H6027B8A2EE4E4D95A7E703305F1789F9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the date on which the contract terminates.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE6C35C7DF2B04938989808A18EB11F9C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Renewal</header><text>An institution that has entered into a contract described in paragraph (1), the term of which is longer than the waiver period described in subparagraph (B) of such paragraph and the terms and conditions of which remain the same as the contract submitted as part of the request required under subparagraph (A) of such paragraph, may submit a request for renewal of the waiver issued under such paragraph in accordance with subsection (b)(2)(B).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF9AE9F9EE40C41FC864CE347960A9804"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Contract defined</header><text>The term <term>contract</term> has the meaning given such term in section 117(f). </text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HB6D2A6FF1E714048B980ECEE7B4BC439" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Interagency information sharing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Education shall transmit to each individual listed in section 117(e) of the Higher Education Act of 1965, as amended by this Act—</text> 
<paragraph id="HDFB7EF604D594906B8D731247CDB40F9" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an unredacted copy of each report (including the name and address of a foreign source disclosed in such report) received by the Department of Education under section 117 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1011f">20 U.S.C. 1011f</external-xref>) prior to the date of enactment of this Act); and </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4FFFC124B625411AB13409D1F1B3A1EE" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any report, document, or other record generated by the Department of Education in the course of an investigation—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H44B6E555507942B5903245B6AD9C3CFB" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>of an institution with respect to the compliance of such institution with such section; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE06C96EE6EDB4136B35161A1FCFA059D" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>initiated prior to the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HB6220E29216B4D5199CA837BDC0FA33A" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Policy regarding conflicts of interest from foreign gifts and contracts</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001 et seq.</external-xref>), as amended by the preceding section, is further amended by inserting after section 117A the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H83B32EAA6E7A47D1BF606D3EC1F640BA"> <section id="HE1608E35C6D64E40A0C3B4EC6D970507"><enum>117B.</enum><header>Institutional policy regarding foreign gifts and contracts to faculty and staff</header> <subsection id="HE84344F126CF4742B3D8AD706A363641"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement to maintain policy and database</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>DETERRENT Act</short-title>, each institution described in subsection (b) shall maintain—</text> 
<paragraph id="H0B10E94C200B43F4818C85B2F7560E9D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a policy requiring covered individuals at the institution and covered individuals at affiliated entities of the institution to disclose in a report to such institution by July 31 of each calendar year that begins after the year in which such enactment date occurs—</text> <subparagraph id="HFB0EAA97949E4245B50257152F8D8DE9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any gift received from a foreign source in the previous calendar year, the value of which is greater than the minimal value (as such term is defined in section 7342(a) of title 5, United States Code) or is of indeterminate value, and including the date on which the gift was received;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD224D238B39D476D9AAF770B47899632"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any contract with a foreign source (other than a foreign country of concern or foreign entity of concern) entered into or in effect during the previous calendar year, the value of which is $5,000 or more, considered alone or in combination with all other contracts with that foreign source within the calendar year, and including the date on which such contract is entered into, the date on which the contract first takes effect, and, as applicable, the date on which such contract terminates;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA325A631EB4F4C70AA8A6F3B863F1E95"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any contract with a foreign source (other than a foreign country of concern or foreign entity of concern) entered into or in effect during the previous calendar year that has an indeterminate monetary value, and including the date on which such contract is entered into, the date on which the contract first takes effect, and, as applicable, the date on which such contract terminates; and </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8F6FAF586E004E61B0EA6A8EF7A3A04F"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any contract entered into or in effect with a foreign country of concern or foreign entity of concern during the previous calendar year, the value of which is $0 or more or which has an indeterminate monetary value, and including—</text> <clause id="H12A75D37C62645A6A065B93769AA4569"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the date on which such contract is entered into;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H76B2920420F649EE8BCAA078D260C317"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the date on which the contract first takes effect;</text></clause> <clause id="H891510D402C444D49AE5AF7CC6CE265D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>if the contract has a termination date, such termination date; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H58FD37BB75B4454C919DD97DAB232AF1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the full text of such contract and any addenda;</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAA84AD970A2743DB9648C9890CA78960" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a publicly available and searchable database (in electronic and downloadable format), on a website of the institution, of the information required to be disclosed under paragraph (1) (other than the information prohibited from public disclosure pursuant to subsection (c)) that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HBB243B67B6F948E5AE9276BB88A02BB0" commented="no"><enum>(A) </enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">makes available the information disclosed under paragraph (1) (other than the information prohibited from public disclosure pursuant to subsection (c)) beginning on the date that is 30 days after receipt of the report under such paragraph containing such information and until the latest of—</text> <clause id="HD58BB374511B4BB08A1DC21CE9A8D42F" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the date that is 5 years after the date on which—</text> 
<subclause id="H6F47309D48A44AC1928B367760BE0356" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a gift referred to in paragraph (1)(A) is received; or</text></subclause> <subclause id="H195C855C69CC4F8FA54EDEF7AC19B1A4" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a contract referred to in subparagraph (B), (C) or (D) of paragraph (1) first takes effect; </text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="HEEB8229892034BA2BEBF97F861A72BD0" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the date on which a contract referred to in subparagraph (B), (C) or (D) of paragraph (1) terminates; or</text></clause> <clause id="H805C196E48934A83B72F185B51EE7435"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the last day of any period that applicable State law requires a copy of such contract to be maintained; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H21E115B233F44F34B4AF33DD72D26C60" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is searchable and sortable—</text> <clause id="HBC673BA7ED914C23A343AEF1BDF26088" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the subject of the disclosure is a gift, by the date on which the gift is received;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H4DCDB351166F49C4ABC06803F452AB64"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if the subject of the disclosure is a contract—</text> <subclause id="H5ECFF0C525F24AFC9ACE6EFF7E82910B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by the date on which such contract is entered into; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H771EFDED87C14260A7CCC5F4B4FF687F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by the date on which such contract first takes effect;</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H00E628F6379B4C58A2EB8756A8E183BA" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by the attributable country with respect to which information is being disclosed; </text></clause> 
<clause id="HBAC8CA65EE734651ABF9D609480F2B84" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum> 
<subclause id="H68A4540D751847CABB8A7BBE4E13BE56" display-inline="yes-display-inline" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>if the covered individual at an institution is making the disclosure, by the most specific division of the institution (such as the department, school, or college) that the covered individual is at; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HD69BAA31FE7B40E1B7ACF9B67E4A9356" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>if the covered individual at the affiliated entity of the institution is making the disclosure, by the name of such affiliated entity;</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="HEAD2E61175424DB18592038440A18CB1" commented="no"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by the name of the foreign source; and</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H27F2BE3688A14E91ABF19745CD25F67A"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an effective plan to identify and manage potential information gathering by foreign sources through espionage targeting covered individuals that may arise from gifts received from, or contracts entered into with, a foreign source, including through the use of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H35FF5D5624074D4FBAC324EB1035B1CA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>periodic communications;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H13F4406C18CA418E810A47A4F123D31F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">accurate reporting under paragraph (2) of the information required to be disclosed under paragraph (1); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD674360FBD3E46079E6686EC0E2E7D87"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">enforcement of the policy described in paragraph (1); and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF32637C52298443980D25F4424D467D4" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for purposes of investigations under section 117D(a)(1), a record of the name of each individual who makes a disclosure under paragraph (1) and each report disclosed under such paragraph. </text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3D8853001F7D401F9920ECD19BF48840"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Institutions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An institution shall be subject to the requirements of this section if such institution—</text> <paragraph id="H9BB8D84FCEAD4ADEBAF055072C51B724"><enum>(1)</enum><text>received more than $50,000,000 in Federal funds in any of the previous five calendar years to support (in whole or in part) research and development (as determined by the institution and measured by the Higher Education Research and Development Survey of the National Center for Science and Engineering Statistics); or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H24A67FA2AE3E4BE2B4800DD7FD5FED6C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>receives funds under title VI.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HAD910F13DA5241AA95FD00CF54843E75" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application of Federal privacy law; protections for natural persons</header> <paragraph id="HE03D0C9BA4C9494D892F223A71F123BF" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Application of Federal privacy law</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in paragraph (2), a disclosure made pursuant to this section is not subject to Federal privacy law.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFFCF97F3DB3D47BDA3CD01DBA9C78B2C" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Protections for natural persons</header> 
<subparagraph id="HFC60E426E9814DAE9D6E8DBBDFFF32C8" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), with respect to a disclosure made pursuant to this section, the following may not be publicly disclosed:</text> <clause id="H1A54B62645B249009D766C7CDCFC29F9" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The name or address (other than the attributable country) of a foreign source that is a natural person.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H27AF409813994E3F88A6DE3BBC708BA8" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The name or any other personally identifiable information of a covered individual making such disclosure.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H950C2394DAF54207B2FA792BA1F73EB6" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exceptions for contracts with a foreign country of concern or foreign entity of concern</header><text>Subparagraph (A) shall not apply to a disclosure made pursuant to this section that contains information with respect to a contract entered into with a foreign country of concern or foreign entity of concern.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H35D604B1364549E7A7BE86A65C0A00C5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text> <paragraph id="HEC31EE4F4D734BE6AA86979F682A5E3E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the terms <term>affiliated entity</term>, <term>attributable country</term>, <term>foreign source</term>, and <term>gift</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 117(f);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H10F45F840619427782B42F346205637B" display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>contract</term>—</text> <subparagraph id="HA259FDD0BBE0403EAD94ADC34E4351CF" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means—</text> 
<clause id="H12163DECF2544984BD2BD56F9AA80D0D" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any agreement for the acquisition by purchase, lease, or barter of property (including intellectual property) or services by the foreign source;</text></clause> <clause id="H2F215253D4B24AFB8A7438399C6C9BB1" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">except as provided in subparagraph (B), any agreement for the acquisition by purchase, lease, or barter of property (including intellectual property) or services from a foreign source; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HC884ABB2CE1B4E4EBDEF6F973883833B" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any affiliation, agreement, or similar transaction with a foreign source that involves the use or exchange of a covered individual’s name, likeness, time, services, or resources; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8D5BC8D35FD1427F918B2759748F895A" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not include—</text> 
<clause id="H344BF11BA17E48448F9E5CA64649A6DA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an arms-length agreement for the acquisition by purchase, lease, or barter of property (including intellectual property) or services from a foreign source that is not a foreign country of concern or a foreign entity of concern; and</text></clause> <clause id="H4CA7AF00E0AC4331B6EE19C49E6EFCE2" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any assignment or license of a granted intellectual property right (including a patent, trademark, or copyright) that is not associated with a category listed in the Commerce Control List maintained by the Bureau of Industry and Security of the Department of Commerce and set forth in Supplement No. 1 to part 774 of title 15, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations); and</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF0FED78CA65B4DC9B0EA86961631DFDF"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>covered individual</term>—</text> <subparagraph id="HE63158CD5EC44E6D944324BEDC6BCE25"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has the meaning given such term in section 223(d) of the William M. (Mac) Thornberry National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6605">42 U.S.C. 6605</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H284D082968854B3AABB1A2E1DA7B4821"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall be interpreted in accordance with the Guidance for Implementing National Security Presidential Memorandum 33 (NSPM–33) on National Security Strategy for United States Government-Supported Research and Development published by the Subcommittee on Research Security and the Joint Committee on the Research Environment in January 2022 (or any successor guidance).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section id="H5A35723205A340DCA632C84B0D54E122"><enum>4.</enum><header>Investment disclosure report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001 et seq.</external-xref>), as amended by this Act, is further amended by inserting after section 117B the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7C1074CA61CB4D03A390A781C80B2049"> 
<section id="H01C5EBFA610A4CE99EA7B7DCAB3310C3"><enum>117C.</enum><header>Investment disclosure report</header> 
<subsection id="HD7CCD24C2D1A48B3943F6C6DE43E6B8F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Investment disclosure report</header><text>A specified institution shall file a disclosure report in accordance with subsection (b) with the Secretary on each July 31 immediately following any calendar year in which the specified institution purchases, sells, or holds (directly or indirectly through any chain of ownership) one or more investments of concern.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H4E8316E56D4D439397EA8A7F597C85ED"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents of report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each report to the Secretary required by subsection (a) shall contain, with respect to the calendar year preceding the calendar year in which such report is filed, the following information: </text> 
<paragraph id="HC1AF03EB7243438DBC2DDDDB25EB5C2C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A list of the investments of concern purchased, sold, or held during such calendar year.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5C1E26B9E9564986BC7085488EA6014F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The aggregate fair market value of all investments of concern held as of the close of such calendar year.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H245C22413596444EBA6DF54DEFB1116F" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The combined value of all investments of concern sold over the course of such calendar year, as measured by the fair market value of such investments at the time of the sale.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0E990B9A6B44453CAFDE31AE3E8A1FC0" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The combined value of all capital gains from such sales of investments of concern. </text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6BDA4EE1DE3A43AEA6F2CC1C319DD92B" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Treatment of certain pooled investments</header> 
<paragraph id="H65584D64B5FF416D9033767EFB7AB46C" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Pooled investment classification</header> 
<subparagraph id="H7C154D0B49DA40B88372653E75AF6919" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of this section, except as provided in subparagraph (B), a specified interest acquired by a specified institution in a regulated investment company, exchange traded fund, or any other pooled investment that holds an investment of concern shall be treated as an investment of concern and shall be reported pursuant to paragraph (2)(A).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB1634440278F4A6D959E41622A0EE4F4" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Certification of pooled investment</header><text>Notwithstanding subparagraph (A), such specified interest shall not be subject to subparagraph (A) if the Secretary certifies, pursuant to paragraph (2)(B), that such pooled investment is not holding an investment of concern.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBB80AA5839CA4AD292D7B8B00CA236F9" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Procedures</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, after consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury and the Securities and Exchange Commission, shall establish procedures under which a pooled investment described in paragraph (1)—</text> <subparagraph id="H5CB8B2ED4ED94F1EB01E9EF5B768B16D" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall be reported in accordance with the requirements of subsection (b); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2F89E51753D74C93A66C595AEB648244" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may be certified under paragraph (1)(B) as not holding an investment of concern.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H3B1A5594BC00495E920F9D5308C1A813"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Treatment of related organizations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, assets held by any related organization (as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/4968">section 4968(d)(2)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986) with respect to a specified institution shall be treated as held by such specified institution, except that—</text> 
<paragraph id="H54F372E2E3D6423CB089FD8588C892C8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>such assets shall not be taken into account with respect to more than 1 specified institution; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAB089E78C7434673A3DC87336B750E77"><enum>(2)</enum><text>unless such organization is controlled by such institution or is described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/509">section 509(a)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 with respect to such institution, assets which are not intended or available for the use or benefit of such specified institution shall not be taken into account.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H76CFE37273CD419B9F40776A7D48B3D3" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Valuation of debt</header><text>For purposes of this section, the fair market value of any debt shall be the outstanding principal amount of such debt.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HDD8ED1E5A1084F3ABA321FE89BED043B" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, after consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury and the Securities and Exchange Commission, may issue such regulations or other guidance as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section, including regulations or other guidance providing for the proper application of this section with respect to certain regulated investment companies, exchange traded funds, and pooled investments.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA0D14A7E29C1427A9954F806A0800D4A" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Database requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning not later than May 31 of the calendar year following the date of enactment of the <short-title>DETERRENT Act</short-title>, the Secretary shall—</text> <paragraph id="HBFB9A73EC815482B86607D58FE2E4D9C" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish and maintain a searchable database on a website of the Department, under which all reports submitted under this section—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H26687912CEE343F78BC8F4C74E5A1FFB" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are made publicly available (in electronic and downloadable format), including any information provided in such reports;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H14F8B7A8E207458C9829249E6BA4EA8E" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>can be individually identified and compared; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA32BD91AB814456EA6E0EFD92CD7AFA4" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>are searchable and sortable; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H77945749F62644C3A4BFE366881E81D3" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not later than 30 days after receipt of a disclosure report under this section, include such report in such database.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HDCA8EAF76EA04A55B7D2FB51E6977038"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H1D4C6BD20DEF47EA8944C8C6AAABAEC6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Investment of concern</header> <subparagraph id="H15659B58C2CD4811AA144D17FC1D5B3D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>investment of concern</term> means any specified interest with respect to any of the following:</text> 
<clause id="H31AE74BDB90341F58D5C2BE45C093521"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A foreign country of concern.</text></clause> <clause id="H010C1EBEEC59419084AFE094EDDCF96F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A foreign entity of concern.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0FF7AD1F1BDF44428066CDFD851D2790"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Specified interest</header><text>The term <term>specified interest</term> means, with respect to any entity—</text> <clause id="HB49F6DCAE1534748856EF42E79BE08D7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>stock or any other equity or profits interest of such entity;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HF6296DA4221F47A79F378F211D347FAA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>debt issued by such entity; and</text></clause> <clause id="H64D25883A2984DF6B6CD4CA2E057E042"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any contract or derivative with respect to any property described in clause (i) or (ii).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD2001D15A64749328A8A60827AAFBF63"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Specified institution</header> 
<subparagraph id="H9EF2FD84A01E4FB7BABC4C5750DA2203" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>specified institution</term>, as determined with respect to any calendar year, means an institution that—</text> <clause id="HE99FAB073A7F4E1EB3C6251F1362DC69" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is not a public institution; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H06D86A119E1B462D8CC36191878963B9" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>at the close of such calendar year, holds—</text> <subclause id="H5AAB30522EE9493D97822D786A46951E" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assets (other than those assets which are used directly in carrying out the institution’s exempt purpose) the aggregate fair market value of which is in excess of $6,000,000,000; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HC7A750013F664AF282C2A0FDDBB3706B" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>investments of concern the aggregate fair market value of which is in excess of $250,000,000. </text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H287EC314A92C4E0688EA0528C73A481B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>References to certain terms</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purpose of applying the definition under subparagraph (A), the terms <term>aggregate fair market value</term> and <term>assets which are used directly in carrying out the institution’s exempt purpose</term> shall be applied in the same manner as such terms are applied for the purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/4968">section 4968(b)(1)(D)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
<section id="H31745F232FA4477894372190F5DBA871" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>5.</enum><header>Enforcement and other general provisions</header> 
<subsection id="HF3A354C328834A3DA982DD69CC700FDF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Enforcement and other general provisions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001 et seq.</external-xref>), as amended by this Act, is further amended by inserting after section 117C the following: </text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HFC5F9FD183DE460E87439656FDBE2409" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <section id="H41A9908D45044915ADE53B08756749BE"><enum>117D.</enum><header>Enforcement; single point-of-contact; institutional requirements</header> <subsection id="H6A74E96CA1ED43899512001EF540BEEC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Enforcement</header> <paragraph id="HFE9F87278EBB4F4B9C3E0DC568182DFE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Investigation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary (acting through the General Counsel of the Department) shall conduct investigations of possible violations of sections 117, 117A, 117B, 117C, and subsection (c) of this section by institutions and, whenever it appears that an institution has knowingly or willfully failed to comply with a requirement of any of such provisions (including any rule or regulation promulgated under any such provision), shall request that the Attorney General bring a civil action in accordance with paragraph (2).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H58C7BF79D27F4A6F86741541DA7BE679" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Civil action</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whenever it appears that an institution has knowingly or willfully failed to comply with a requirement of any of the provisions listed in paragraph (1) (including any rule or regulation promulgated under any such provision) based on an investigation under such paragraph, a civil action shall be brought by the Attorney General, at the request of the Secretary, in an appropriate district court of the United States, or the appropriate United States court of any territory or other place subject to the jurisdiction of the United States, to request such court to compel compliance with the requirement of the provision that has been violated.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1DE75C522FD542689CC7D17C858EE833" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Costs and other fines</header><text>An institution that is compelled to comply with a requirement of a provision listed in paragraph (1) pursuant to paragraph (2) shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H2021855CABAE475BB0F68A9E525E197F" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>pay to the Treasury of the United States the full costs to the United States of obtaining compliance with the requirement of such provision, including all associated costs of investigation and enforcement; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H770A441B2B9D44BB880B016CA7ABD92C" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if applicable, be subject to the applicable fines described in paragraph (4).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE83CFB87F91B4D9BBC2F59BABD767124"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Fines for violations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall impose a fine on an institution that is compelled to comply with a requirement of a section listed in paragraph (1) pursuant to paragraph (2) as follows:</text> <subparagraph id="HCC9ECBE860554BFFA7CA8A2487FCE7E2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Section 117</header> <clause id="HECEF8B85ED9A49908527E10A5DC12799"><enum>(i)</enum><header>First-time violations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an institution that is compelled to comply with a requirement of section 117 pursuant to a civil action described in paragraph (2), and that has not previously been compelled to comply with any such requirement pursuant to such a civil action, the Secretary shall impose a fine on the institution for such violation as follows:</text> 
<subclause id="H77FB307716534374A163038624F06F58"><enum>(I)</enum><text>In the case of an institution that knowingly or willfully fails to comply with a reporting requirement under subsection (a)(1) of section 117, such fine shall be in an amount that is—</text> <item id="H9CA6FA1103DE4B2E903066F57FD23787"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>for each gift or contract with determinable value that is the subject of such a failure to comply, the greater of—</text> 
<subitem id="H94D3492F0EBB4CAD9D7325C66B89EE4D"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>$50,000; or</text></subitem> <subitem id="HD294577514984E2E83F243A015EE1445"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>the monetary value of such gift or contract; or</text></subitem></item> 
<item id="H06D1B69333C9420E92231A5E5816D8EA"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>for each gift or contract of no value or of indeterminable value, not less than 1 percent and not more than 10 percent of the total amount of Federal funds received by the institution under this Act for the most recent fiscal year.</text></item></subclause> <subclause id="H961F2862CBE34406A957D2CE56ED4116"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an institution that knowingly or willfully fails to comply with the reporting requirement under subsection (a)(2) of section 117, such fine shall be in an amount that is not less than 10 percent of the total amount of Federal funds received by the institution under this Act for the most recent fiscal year.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="HFEBD94004DB34AABA4E5B1FB6C3A2414"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Subsequent violations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an institution that has previously been compelled to comply with a requirement of section 117 pursuant to a civil action described in paragraph (2), and is subsequently compelled to comply with such a requirement pursuant to a subsequent civil action described in paragraph (2), the Secretary shall impose a fine on the institution as follows:</text> <subclause id="HB1D11F1F7DE14E59979C797CB4B86DE9"><enum>(I)</enum><text>In the case of an institution that knowingly or willfully fails to comply with a reporting requirement under subsection (a)(1) of section 117, such fine shall be in an amount that is—</text> 
<item id="H2480ED029381461397306FBFD0DD81AA"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for each gift or contract with determinable value that is the subject of such a failure to comply, the greater of—</text> <subitem id="H97B0B6B18B4F4215A128C726290BE48C"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>$100,000; or</text></subitem> 
<subitem id="H7D4383264B2E4764A7F9D3726F1BA1C5"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>twice the monetary value of such gift or contract; or</text></subitem></item> <item id="H8C74F018582B4C34817313D55797F8A2"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for each gift or contract of no value or of indeterminable value, not less than 5 percent and not more than 10 percent of the total amount of Federal funds received by the institution under this Act for the most recent fiscal year.</text></item></subclause> 
<subclause id="H8D71D12623D34DDB93E0383852B91B8A"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an institution that knowingly or willfully fails to comply with a reporting requirement under subsection (a)(2) of section 117, such fine shall be in an amount that is not less than 20 percent of the total amount of Federal funds received by the institution under this Act for the most recent fiscal year.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4FF9E79202DC411C975F4FE24B682376"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Section 117A</header> <clause id="H0443E00AD5BA4D569E8441CA44E60962"><enum>(i)</enum><header>First-time violations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an institution that is compelled to comply with a requirement of section 117A pursuant to a civil action described in paragraph (2), and that has not previously been compelled to comply with any such requirement pursuant to such a civil action, the Secretary shall impose a fine on the institution in an amount that is not less than 5 percent and not more than 10 percent of the total amount of Federal funds received by the institution under this Act for the most recent fiscal year.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H1C557A03F71947B281AAEFEF91B6A854" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Subsequent violations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an institution that has previously been compelled to comply with a requirement of section 117A pursuant to a civil action described in paragraph (2), and is subsequently compelled to comply with such a requirement pursuant to a subsequent civil action described in paragraph (2), the Secretary shall impose a fine on the institution in an amount that is not less than 20 percent of the total amount of Federal funds received by the institution under this Act for the most recent fiscal year.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAB6E81738FC6465F8DC1EBC82404AA5F" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Section 117B</header> <clause id="HB5D65C579920474A9EE5045134694684" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>First-time violations</header><text>In the case of an institution that is compelled to comply with a requirement of section 117B pursuant to a civil action described in paragraph (2), and that has not previously been compelled to comply with any such requirement pursuant to such a civil action, the Secretary shall impose a fine on the institution for such violation in an amount that is the greater of—</text> 
<subclause id="H2B0983A6B9FD43E39E6209753D007C2F" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>$250,000; or </text></subclause> <subclause id="HF0EAD980DA9747A8AF21F12316B8481E" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the total amount of gifts or contracts that the institution is compelled to report pursuant to such civil action.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="HA222089878C64212891B3EBB072218EC"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Subsequent violations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an institution that has previously been compelled to comply with a requirement of section 117B pursuant to a civil action described in paragraph (2), and is subsequently compelled to comply with such a requirement pursuant to a subsequent civil action described in paragraph (2), the Secretary shall impose a fine on the institution in an amount that is the greater of—</text> <subclause id="H11B0D80B234C468EBE18BB8E127D5546" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>$500,000; or</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H648229AB65694AC083804513E525B2D4" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>twice the total amount of gifts or contracts that the institution is compelled to report pursuant to such civil action.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEE29086F6F6744F9A20FB9D61D6EA47C"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Section 117C</header> <clause id="H5971DF9C920A4173B2A688B3946E3D4A"><enum>(i)</enum><header>First-time violations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an institution that is compelled to comply with a requirement of section 117C pursuant to a civil action described in paragraph (2), and that has not previously been compelled to comply with any such requirement pursuant to such a civil action, the Secretary shall impose a fine on the institution in an amount that is not less than 50 percent and not more than 100 percent of the sum of—</text> 
<subclause id="HB1A4A6571EE0495882A43F76C63143E5"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the aggregate fair market value of all investments of concern held by such institution as of the close of the final calendar year for which the institution is compelled to comply with such requirement pursuant to such civil action; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HD83D11387CFC4C5DAB78F1AE03900988"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the combined value of all investments of concern sold over the course of all the calendar years for which the institution is compelled to comply with such requirement pursuant to such civil action, as measured by the fair market value of such investments at the time of the sale.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H5B4B5C09B58241BF922DA7595AAC3D1B" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Subsequent violations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an institution that has previously been compelled to comply with a requirement of section 117C pursuant to a civil action described in paragraph (2), and is subsequently compelled to comply with such a requirement pursuant to a subsequent civil action described in paragraph (2), the Secretary shall impose a fine on the institution in an amount that is not less than 100 percent and not more than 200 percent of the sum of—</text> <subclause id="H785A5F590C2545A59199B7A08A375BCC" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the aggregate fair market value of all investments of concern held by such institution as of the close of the final calendar year for which the institution is compelled to comply with such requirement pursuant to such subsequent civil action; and </text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HCB182AB644264CBF8D4DA5D05C5C8984" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the combined value of all investments of concern over the course of all the calendar years for which the institution is compelled to comply with such requirement pursuant to such subsequent civil action, as measured by the fair market value of such investments at the time of the sale.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H420F6CF1CBCD4EAF8D17358D156AB107" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Ineligibility for waiver</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an institution that is fined pursuant to subparagraph (A)(ii), (B)(ii), (C)(ii), or (D)(ii), the Secretary shall prohibit the institution from obtaining a waiver, or a renewal of a waiver, under section 117A.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H45AEDBB5C82D4A39A4447F716B36ADFB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Single point-of-contact at the Department</header><text>The Secretary shall maintain a single point-of-contact at the Department to—</text> <paragraph id="HDDF30B8781DA4998B215EAFF4D9D97E1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>receive and respond to inquiries and requests for technical assistance from institutions regarding compliance with the requirements of sections 117, 117A, 117B, 117C, and subsection (c) of this section; </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8214350A01914A25B751E9F43F59A5EA"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">coordinate and implement technical improvements to the database described in section 117(d)(1), including—</text> <subparagraph id="H8D1B019E3A004CEF831F128A0BA18146"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">improving upload functionality by allowing for batch reporting, including by allowing institutions to upload one file with all required information into the database;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBE552D1625A54E2E84FEBB18C2D64550" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">publishing and maintaining a database users guide, which shall be reviewed and updated as practicable but not less than annually, including information on how to edit an entry and how to report errors;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1BBA644BE3434825B5011C784270A202"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">creating a standing user group (to which <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/10">chapter 10</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, shall not apply) to discuss possible database improvements, which group shall—</text> 
<clause id="HB8AF58ECBE424717B85F404EA44B6969"><enum>(i)</enum><text>include at least—</text> <subclause id="H0D90A1A724B34EBEA4B3B80B78316865"><enum>(I)</enum><text>3 members representing public institutions with high or very high levels of research activity (as defined by the National Center for Education Statistics);</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H9F43B2A126BD4D1E8A63D5C3CF5B7EF8"><enum>(II)</enum><text>2 members representing private, nonprofit institutions with high or very high levels of research activity (as so defined);</text></subclause> <subclause id="HB4E43521DED84EB98512E431D642B293"><enum>(III)</enum><text> 2 members representing proprietary institutions of higher education (as defined in section 102(b)); and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H2B76DE3AFE7446B5A5F958A03F6F3BD2" commented="no"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">2 members representing area career and technical education schools (as defined in subparagraph (C) or (D) of section 3(3) of the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/2302">20 U.S.C. 2302(3)</external-xref>)); and</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H7A964050C5534D30B5A594226325F146"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>meet at least twice a year with officials from the Department to discuss possible database improvements;</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H82B339CBF3F64891B42BEF22B690FDEB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>publishing, on a publicly available website, recommended database improvements following each meeting described in subparagraph (C)(ii); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H28DF977B8315484DB0B9DF4F10A4D3EB"><enum>(E)</enum><text>responding, on a publicly available website, to each recommendation published under subparagraph (D) as to whether or not the Department will implement the recommendation, including the rationale for either approving or rejecting the recommendation;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H68420E55B5F54ABE8C52DFDC9029611A"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide, every 90 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>DETERRENT Act</short-title>, status updates on any pending or completed investigations and civil actions under subsection (a)(1) to—</text> <subparagraph id="H523EA51053264A509114DC7D37EF34B1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the authorizing committees; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H20DC14D97F184CC09A283E18C0CC59B0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any institution that is the subject of such investigation or action; </text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC09397D4F76A4E9D9BDF257BDB5B5C71"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">maintain, on a publicly accessible website—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HED07944A50CA415CAAE56111F8FF09AA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a full comprehensive list of all foreign countries of concern and foreign entities of concern; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFF65F1A8E07D4AD8AAB92E916C93E178"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the date on which the last update was made to such list; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H14F3C5C6341E45E4B3D9CB68C0EC4FC7"><enum>(5)</enum><text>not later than 7 days after making an update to the list maintained under paragraph (4)(A), notify each institution required to comply with the sections listed in paragraph (1) of such update.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HCE2B01867F1F44A2BB07161CA0DD488A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Institutional requirements for compliance officers and institutional policy requirements</header> <paragraph id="HAD89BD23C3FB429BA308403537F1B717"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An institution that is required to file a report under section 117 or 117C, that is seeking a waiver under section 117A, or that is subject to the requirements of section 117B, shall, not later than the earlier of the date on which the institution files the first report under section 117 or 117C, requests the institution’s first waiver under section 117A, or first fulfills the requirements of section 117B—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H98FB4D6CE5F54A78A0ACECAEF8A023C8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>establish an institutional policy that the institution shall follow in meeting the requirements of sections 117, 117A, 117B, and 117C; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF4513ABC61FF447D83EF3601DF250395"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">designate and maintain at least one, but not more than three, current employees or legally authorized agents of such institution to serve as compliance officers to carry out the requirements listed in paragraph (2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCC750DE430C44CB78389CA759373F282" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duties of compliance officers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A compliance officer designated by an institution under paragraph (1)(B) shall certify—</text> <subparagraph id="H0A53B1D937924DF781E5EFDC2A54BDCF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>whenever the institution is required to file a report under section 117 or 117C—</text> 
<clause id="HB6136213C6774B37ABD5CE5DB973F4CD" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the institution’s accurate compliance with the reporting requirements under such section;</text></clause> <clause id="H7701198AB7F34469AA073AAFE2AE1DE6" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that the institution, in filing such report under section 117 or 117C—</text> 
<subclause id="H8ADEBCDF6EC3400D87A33A4FFBCCB0B1" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>followed the institutional policy established under paragraph (1)(A) applicable to such section; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HDA74FD685A5A40DFB1D740F49DD9EC72"><enum>(II)</enum><text>conducted good faith efforts and reasonable due diligence to ensure that accurate information is provided in such report, including with respect to the valuations of any assets that are disclosed in a report submitted under section 117C; and</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H25F60DC47AAE4E3893F6B15F7C5D7AA7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in the case of a report under section 117, any statements by the institution required to be certified by such an officer under clause (i) or (iv) of section 117(b)(1)(C); and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF858120239F44971B13503C8FD4B0498"><enum>(B)</enum><text>whenever the institution requests a waiver under section 117A—</text> 
<clause id="HF8A1F8C04FC44C739A1FD44712493E13"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that the institution—</text> <subclause id="H024CF715B7704326A5919700889D2ADE"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is in compliance with the requirements of such section; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H2E6A3ECA978B4576975A634643D44857"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">followed the institutional policy established under paragraph (1)(A) applicable to such section; and</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H752234A9FB0F4669872C0C0DAD80CC02"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the statement by the institution required to be certified by such an officer under section 117A(b)(2)(A)(ii)(II); and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0F348072A76B42CD9421FBDCB4B25B16"><enum>(C)</enum><text>whenever the institution is subject to the requirements of section 117B, that the institution—</text> <clause id="HEDF1A93D98914E91A42E6470B2ECF870"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is in compliance with the requirements of such section; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H603F0E77ECBD4BC59A8B51E89B7C346E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">followed the institutional policy established under paragraph (1)(A) applicable to such section.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H6611AA5C1C8E458F9FC87B54340EA4BA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of sections 117, 117A, 117B, 117C, and this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="HC5439CE23D9B4B1C8CA64C311D2D0CC6" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Foreign country of concern</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>foreign country of concern</term> means the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H01A3587D333F4A6F926633393856434C" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any covered nation defined in section 4872 of title 10, United States Code, including any special administrative region within such a covered nation or any other territory that the United States recognizes as being under the control of such a covered nation on or after the date of the enactment of this subsection.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFB9FEB9792A8422C9A67C94C72B2EF84" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any country the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of State, and the Director of National Intelligence, determines, for purposes of sections 117, 117A, 117B, 117C, or this section, to be engaged in conduct that is detrimental to the national security or foreign policy of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6FE7B60BD5DA4CEE96487EAD8E006CDF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Foreign entity of concern</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>foreign entity of concern</term> has the meaning given such term in section 10612(a) of the Research and Development, Competition, and Innovation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/19221">42 U.S.C. 19221(a)</external-xref>) and includes—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HCB8CE2E1F5E140C19259079B5306C7B7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a foreign entity that is identified on the list published under section 1286(c)(9)(A) of the John S. McCain National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2019 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/4001">10 U.S.C. 4001</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/232">Public Law 115–232</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCCED000A41924F569A80799231FA37C2"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a Chinese military company that is identified on the list required by section 1260H of the William M. (Mac) Thornberry National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/113">10 U.S.C. 113</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/283">Public Law 116–283</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDAD9A3CDFD8445E980F2C6BCA21BA72F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Institution</header><text>The term <term>institution</term> means an institution of higher education (as such term is defined in section 102, other than an institution described in subsection (a)(1)(C) of such section) with a program participation agreement under section 487.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HCF030DCC83554D3EAE80D1563C977F31"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Program participation agreement</header><text>Section 487(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1094">20 U.S.C. 1094</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HD01B680E3973477094A941FA2CC71C9C" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="H9E483CCCC1E84821B8282AD3E86DD961"><enum>(30)</enum> 
<subparagraph id="HB20656D9771A48AFB6D14B3DC7452F69" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An institution will comply with the requirements of sections 117, 117A, 117B, 117C, and 117D(c). </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9C556685AEFA44C19BBDE463005BC62E" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>In the case of an institution described in subparagraph (C), the institution will—</text> 
<clause id="H5FE4078AE1A345FD9DB2A2031FC2EFD8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>be ineligible to participate in the programs authorized by this title for a period of not less than 2 institutional fiscal years; and</text></clause> <clause id="HBFB78A19C4E94F15BE93985D3EFD4AA1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in order to regain eligibility to participate in such programs, demonstrate compliance with all requirements of each such section for not less than 2 institutional fiscal years after the institutional fiscal year in which such institution became ineligible. </text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE3FD3D165DE644D9A14C8CBFB0A1D8A2" indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An institution described in this subparagraph is an institution—</text> <clause id="HB2E70CE6315241659B51B720AB36D65C"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">against which judgment has been granted in 3 separate civil actions described in section 117D(a)(2) that have each resulted in the institution being compelled to comply with one or more requirements of section 117, 117A, 117B, 117C, or 117D(c); and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H2530B8101F1C48D6B297EED1454FB3D0" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that pursuant to section 117D(a)(4)(E), is prohibited from obtaining a waiver, or a renewal of a waiver, under section 117A.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H757DBE9669A548358CBA7A778C682912" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>GAO Study and Report</header> <paragraph id="HD5BCC708F43A4073916AA0BBC902476F" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Study</header><text>Not later than January 31 of the second calendar year that begins after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall initiate a study to identify ways to improve intergovernmental agency coordination regarding implementation and enforcement of sections 117, 117A, 117B, 117C, and 117D(c) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1011f">20 U.S.C. 1011f</external-xref>), as amended or added by this Act, including increasing information sharing, increasing compliance rates, and establishing processes for enforcement.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9E4F18A9BADD487093EECBE898419F7F" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of the initiation of the study under paragraph (1), the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress, and make public, a report containing the results of the study described in <internal-xref idref="HD5BCC708F43A4073916AA0BBC902476F" legis-path="(c)(1)">paragraph (1)</internal-xref>.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20250325" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives March 27, 2025.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Kevin F. McCumber,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation> </bill> 

