<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="H2E4DB4C1E89649469F49487FF60C7DFD" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1049 RH: TRACE Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 7</calendar><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1049</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 119–13]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250206">February 6, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001314">Mr. Bean of Florida</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001230">Mr. Mackenzie</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250305">March 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="B001282">Mr. Barr</cosponsor> and <cosponsor name-id="H001093">Mrs. Houchin</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250305">March 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on February 6, 2025</action-instruction></action><action><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To ensure that parents are aware of foreign influence in their child’s public school, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HED00" reported-display-style="italic" id="HC35AEBC9CA8D4C03A54C6DB737C80354"><section id="H81A0945D11FC4149A9D36910DD662032" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Transparency in Reporting of Adversarial Contributions to Education Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote>TRACE Act</quote>. </text></section><section id="H47071BF9C9D54B9197BE01DAAB7D03BB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Parents’ right to know about foreign influence</header><subsection id="H714B68972F3C4AB2ACA422E19EB1F623"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subpart 2 of part F of title VIII of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7901">20 U.S.C. 7901 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H27B9DBFA4FF74CE3B3D19C620A32278B" style="OLC" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HED00"><section id="HF6C6F29E14FC43118F54CB9BE7B91414"><enum>8549D.</enum><header>Parents’ right to know about foreign influence</header><subsection id="H133D2043927D4576A9EB88B3E681BF33"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>As a condition of receiving funds under this Act, a local educational agency shall ensure that each elementary school and each secondary school served by such agency provides to each parent of a child attending the school, at a minimum—</text><paragraph id="H70FB54D41E9C4145A6299393F368C62B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the right (in a manner consistent with copyright law) to review, and make copies of free of cost, at least every four weeks and not later than 30 days after submission of a written request by the parent, any curricular material or professional development material used at the school that was purchased, or otherwise obtained, using funds received from the government of a foreign country or a foreign entity of concern;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9E96274E98854A3CBDE71760F6FCC544"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the right to know, by written response provided not later than 30 days after submission of a written request by the parent, how many personnel of the school are compensated, in whole or in part, using funds received from the government of a foreign country or a foreign entity of concern; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H665B596D614644C6BBA3622DE3328D40"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the right to know, by written response provided not later than 30 days after submission of a written request by the parent, of—</text><subparagraph id="H73F572A5C521410AA7E3E4F1F25C082E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any donation received by the school or local educational agency from a foreign country or a foreign entity of concern;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H008EB34FE49A4569836F34BF14BE3104"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any agreement in writing (such as a contract or memorandum of understanding) between the school or local educational agency and a foreign country or a foreign entity of concern; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3A9FF0BD3B1D460EB101AC21BC5F8012"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any financial transaction between the school or local educational agency and a foreign country or a foreign entity of concern.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0F57A5849A2F48B4B2CC7BB3C0664C51"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Donations, agreements, and financial transactions</header><text>The information described in subsection (a)(3) shall include, at minimum, the following:</text><paragraph id="H5844A95CF4F14CBD8F530D585A986366"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The name of the foreign country or foreign entity of concern.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8EA150DEAFB74113891FBD967DC4F738"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In any case in which funds were received by the school or local educational agency from a foreign country or a foreign entity of concern—</text><subparagraph id="HAC2E472F1B4A4347AEFF43550A8C6D76"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the amount of such funds; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HABC75929796840ADA2854D2689B766E5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any terms or conditions applicable to the receipt of such funds.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE66804962DBE48BA9F75DA03E71DB900"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Notice of rights</header><text>At the beginning of each school year, a local educational agency receiving funds under this Act shall ensure that each elementary school and each secondary school served by such agency posts on a publicly accessible website of the school or, if the school does not operate a website, widely disseminates to the public, a summary notice of the rights of parents described in subsections (a) and (b).</text></subsection><subsection id="HB7AC93398C05498D899F5CE3A0EEFFFA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Notification of requirements</header><text>At the beginning of each school year, the Secretary shall notify State educational agencies about the requirements of this section. As a condition of receiving funds under this Act, State educational agencies shall, at the beginning of each school year, notify local educational agencies of the requirements of this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H17CBC086DD4E4FE694CB8BB7F57EE006"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H775B819C00E045D3A15BADB9A165FC07"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <quote>foreign country</quote> means a foreign country or a dependent territory or possession of a foreign country. Such term does not include any of the outlying areas.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3F9ACBD44B344809B387D6B95F7FD517"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <quote>foreign entity of concern</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 10612(a) of the Research and Development, Competition, and Innovation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/19221">42 U.S.C. 19221(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H7FF027E91BD440F6AD0CE8CD2DF0298C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents in section 2 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 8549C the following:</text><quoted-block id="HEDF0E9D84E67413AB7957402646E9C05" style="OLC" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HED00"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HED00"><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 8549D. Parents’ right to know about foreign influence.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date date="20250305">March 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

