<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-NEW25094-Y71-F2-RT1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 80 ATS: Expressing gratitude to the Joint Congressional Committee on Inaugural Ceremonies, the Architect of the Capitol, the Sergeant at Arms, the Secretary of the Senate, law enforcement officers, emergency personnel, and volunteers for their support in making the Presidential Inauguration a success.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 80</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250213">February 13, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S381">Mr. Rounds</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S303">Mr. Thune</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S317">Mr. Barrasso</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S378">Mr. Lankford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S374">Mr. Cotton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S372">Mrs. Capito</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S365">Mr. Scott of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S357">Mrs. Fischer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S410">Ms. Lummis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S391">Mr. Young</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S384">Mr. Tillis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S437">Mr. Justice</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S423">Mr. Ricketts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S288">Ms. Murkowski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S174">Mr. McConnell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S343">Mr. Boozman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S347">Mr. Moran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S318">Mr. Wicker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S266">Mr. Crapo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S323">Mr. Risch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S419">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S293">Mr. Graham</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S385">Ms. Cortez Masto</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S363">Mr. King</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S408">Mr. Hickenlooper</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S432">Mr. Gallego</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S229">Mrs. Murray</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S426">Mr. Kim</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S259">Mr. Reed</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S430">Ms. Blunt Rochester</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S330">Mr. Bennet</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S270">Mr. Schumer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S409">Mr. Luján</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S316">Mr. Whitehouse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S415">Mr. Warnock</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S380">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S402">Ms. Rosen</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S406">Mr. Kelly</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing gratitude to the Joint Congressional Committee on Inaugural Ceremonies, the Architect of the Capitol, the Sergeant at Arms, the Secretary of the Senate, law enforcement officers, emergency personnel, and volunteers for their support in making the Presidential Inauguration a success.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, on January 20, 2025, the inauguration of the 47th President of the United States, President Donald J. Trump (referred to in this preamble as the <quote>Presidential Inauguration</quote>), took place under unique and challenging circumstances, requiring the relocation of certain events indoors due to unseasonably cold weather;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, during the Presidential Inauguration, the Joint Congressional Committee on Inaugural Ceremonies, the Architect of the Capitol, the Sergeant at Arms, the Secretary of the Senate, law enforcement officers, emergency personnel, and volunteers displayed exceptional dedication and professionalism in adapting to unforeseen challenges to guarantee the safety, security, and smooth operation of all inaugural events;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the tireless efforts of the Joint Congressional Committee on Inaugural Ceremonies, the Architect of the Capitol, the Sergeant at Arms, the Secretary of the Senate, law enforcement officers, emergency personnel, and volunteers during the Presidential Inauguration facilitated a historic and dignified transfer of power, reflecting the best traditions of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas the Joint Congressional Committee on Inaugural Ceremonies, the Architect of the Capitol, the Sergeant at Arms, and the Secretary of the Senate spent years planning and preparing for the events of the Presidential Inauguration and executed that plan flawlessly, even with unforeseen challenges;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the cold weather during the Presidential Inauguration presented additional logistical and operational difficulties, which were overcome through extraordinary commitment and teamwork; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the vigilance and preparedness of the Joint Congressional Committee on Inaugural Ceremonies, the Architect of the Capitol, the Sergeant at Arms, the Secretary of the Senate, law enforcement officers, emergency personnel, and volunteers allowed attendees of the Presidential Inauguration to celebrate the momentous occasion in a safe and secure environment: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id12c5ca30d2534f1ab17c37b7bc511cfb"><enum>(1)</enum><text>expresses its profound gratitude to the Joint Congressional Committee on Inaugural Ceremonies, the Architect of the Capitol, the Sergeant at Arms, the Secretary of the Senate, law enforcement officers, emergency personnel, and volunteers whose hard work and dedication made the inauguration of President Donald J. Trump on January 20, 2025 (referred to in this resolution as the <quote>Presidential Inauguration</quote>), a resounding success;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4216ae3801a648278fc8766f886fe729"><enum>(2)</enum><text>commends the professionalism and resilience of the Joint Congressional Committee on Inaugural Ceremonies, the Architect of the Capitol, the Sergeant at Arms, the Secretary of the Senate, law enforcement officers, emergency personnel, and volunteers in adapting to the unexpected challenges posed by the cold weather and the relocation of events during the Presidential Inauguration;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf1b8ec387a834178a411bb1625d5dd48"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recognizes the invaluable hard work of the Joint Congressional Committee on Inaugural Ceremonies, the Architect of the Capitol, the Sergeant at Arms, the Secretary of the Senate, law enforcement officers, emergency personnel, and volunteers in upholding the safety and security of all participants and attendees of the Presidential Inauguration;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id246d0e2fcea947479ee1532df5aae85c"><enum>(4)</enum><text>extends heartfelt thanks to the families and loved ones of the law enforcement officers, emergency personnel, and volunteers, whose support enables their service; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7fc55b256cab4c9c9a49c3bb9c3c606e"><enum>(5)</enum><text>calls upon all people of the United States to join in acknowledging the critical role played by the Joint Congressional Committee on Inaugural Ceremonies, the Architect of the Capitol, the Sergeant at Arms, the Secretary of the Senate, law enforcement officers, emergency personnel, and volunteers in ensuring the success of the Presidential Inauguration, a significant national event. </text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

