<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H41C058DDAAA3487EA53E2D86EBDF6BB5" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 751 IH: Healthy Equipping And Lending Technical Help Panel Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 751</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250128">January 28, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="E000298">Mr. Estes</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBU00">Committee on the Budget</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974 to codify the Panel of Health Advisors within the Congressional Budget Office, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE35966F703D44A898E39D76B97EC5E3D" style="OLC"><section id="H24B5FE3C6185486ABDD1CBE43F9A966A" section-type="section-one" commented="no"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Healthy Equipping And Lending Technical Help Panel Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>HEALTH Panel Act</short-title></quote> .</text></section><section id="H2FF85A798B7E4B868979FD5040A6EA21"><enum>2.</enum><header>Congressional Budget Office Panel of Health Advisors</header><subsection id="H0F125D530FE847F3AEF18AA57F69C641"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title II of the Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/601">2 U.S.C. 601 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HF11F9709CA554B72A715AEE6DABC82F9" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="HEE96538C69BE4E09A083661D6369794A"><enum>204.</enum><header>Panel of Health Advisors</header><subsection id="HB5F1F47836E1480089193868D88856AE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Panel of Health Advisors (in this section referred to as the <quote>Panel</quote>) shall be within the Congressional Budget Office.</text></subsection><subsection id="H3198949E087A488A927C6928DDC6CFAE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties and priority target areas</header><paragraph id="HA2E137E08C964060BB55C55CC1E7E8B4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Panel shall—</text><subparagraph id="H4A1FFF8EA4044F41B1FAEB940F74C87E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide technical and functional expertise and recommendations to the Congressional Budget Office to improve the office’s studies, analysis, and cost estimates related to health and health care issues and policies;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3E3FF4D3DA19425096F169FB79500339"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">meet at least once annually; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H98FA5661C4A14A048F15A3A533834223" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">issue an annual report to the chair and ranking minority members of the Committee on the Budget of the House of Representatives and the Committee on the Budget of the Senate which—</text><clause id="H587628B697384FC4A5B69872C72B89C3" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>details the work of the Panel and includes such recommendations as have been approved by a vote of at least 9 members of the Panel and provided to the Congressional Budget Office; and</text></clause><clause id="H9414A34FBCD844EE95F6BD307BB6A9F6" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>includes a description prepared by the Director of the Congressional Budget Office detailing how the office utilized any such recommendations provided under clause (i) and the extent to which any such recommendations were integrated into the office’s studies and cost estimates.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1973B5CDE8814341835CB75EB84C0EC4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Priority target areas</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purposes of this section, the Director of the Congressional Budget Office, in consultation with the chairs and ranking minority members of the Committee on the Budget of the House of Representatives and the Committee on the Budget of the Senate, as well as members on the Panel, shall determine priorities to address in meetings of the Panel, and the report detailed under paragraph (1)(C). The Panel shall provide expertise and recommendations under paragraph (1) with specific respect to the following areas: </text><subparagraph id="HFEF59FE54A9048408899CB73F0BF3D64"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Non-economic and economic studies on health and health care issues and policies developed by the Congressional Budget Office.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6D548D0248CA4102BEDDB4281051F052"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Official cost estimates prepared by the Congressional Budget Office for proposed health care legislation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEF67ABB4EC544D6ABF330D972017E9F9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Models developed and utilized by the Congressional Budget Office to project non-economic and economic impacts of health care policy changes and legislation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF6CC68450699432B9731E35C229AE5B5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Health care components of the Congressional Budget Office’s annual Budget and Economic Outlook publications, Federal Health Subsidies for Health Insurance reports, Health Insurance Coverage Projections, and other official publications related to health and health care by the Congressional Budget Office.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H21085FF354D141DBA0B1D4F4542A4AE0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Publication</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Congressional Budget Office shall publish, on the Office’s public website, the annual report prepared pursuant to paragraph (1)(C).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3555D288C45D46DCB132A03BE46B7397"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Ethical disclosure; confidentiality</header><text>The Director of the Congressional Budget Office may establish—</text><subparagraph id="H3C1436E1709E48FFA5A53F0FFDE79EE6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a system for public disclosure by members of the Panel related to potential conflicts of interest relating to such members; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC37D19A66A9C4B9BB0B9DD03307697DA"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">confidentiality agreements with members of the Panel to protect information obtained by the Government on a confidential basis to inform official work products and confidential congressional requests for analytical reports and budgetary scoring estimates.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1D4631B124BD4F58B79C9155447C981A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Membership</header><paragraph id="H3A6740F4DB10411CB4E401E1ECFA955B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Number and appointment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The membership of the Panel shall include 15 members appointed not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this section, of which—</text><subparagraph id="HF8874051BC824ECCAE29D4F869283FD4"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">3 members shall be appointed by the chair of the Committee on the Budget of the House of Representatives;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8A31C58D5D574D28A05BA5F8E54D30C9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>3 members shall be appointed by the ranking minority member of the Committee on the Budget of the House of Representatives;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1B5352A362764CFEBCFCC5ABD532C25D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>3 members shall be appointed by the chair of the Committee on the Budget of the Senate;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0809F6506D174169A265A2451A513086"><enum>(D)</enum><text>3 members shall be appointed by the ranking minority member of the Committee on the Budget of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8E7DFED720F344D0A1AB8C42D9962331"><enum>(E)</enum><text>3 members shall be appointed by the Director of the Congressional Budget Office.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H58EDC888ADD14EBAA6A09B6A207850A9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualifications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The membership of the Panel shall aim to include, but not be limited to, individuals with national recognition for their expertise in health finance and economics, actuarial science, health facility management, life sciences and drug development, investment in health care companies, health plans and integrated delivery systems, reimbursement of health facilities, allopathic and osteopathic physicians, and other providers of health services, Medicare, Medicaid, and other related fields.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9DED8095CD1A4039A4356179DEF2DDAD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Special Government employees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Members of the Panel shall serve as special Government employees (as defined in section 202(a) of title 18, United States Code).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFD650EC7DC574805859419C433C29611"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Terms</header><paragraph id="H6B1FCD14418F438AAAB7F867AF41D6A7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms of the members of the Panel shall be for 3 years, except that the Director of the Congressional Budget Office shall designate staggered terms of the members first appointed.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1B0F6644D107448D894C45C1657ED823"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Vacancies</header><subparagraph id="H5DB0F96B05E74B8F84538000591DE171"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A vacancy in the Panel shall be filled in the manner in which the original appointment was made.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H58E0CFECA5294F3698C74AD0AF5C19C4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Term of member appointed to fill vacancy</header><text>Any member appointed to fill a vacancy occurring before the expiration of the term for which the member’s predecessor was appointed shall be appointed only for the remainder of that term, except that a member may serve after the expiration of that member’s term until a successor has taken office.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H11EEE952EDA84C0B98B93428C8FD876A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Chair; vice chair</header><subparagraph id="H4DBEB262BBDA48B2A0901498123C0465"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director of the Congressional Budget Office shall designate a member of the Panel, at the time of appointment of the member, as chair and a member as vice chair for that term of appointment, except that in the case of vacancy of the chair or vice chair, the Director of the Congressional Budget Office may designate another member for the remainder of that member’s term.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H73466153FB374A92AA582D165606A28D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"> The chair and vice chair shall be appointed by the Director of the Congressional Budget Office—</text><clause id="HB9F73CB7D3D940FABDDF0B2828752C6A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>after considering recommendations received from the chairs of the Committees on the Budget of the House of Representatives and the Senate; </text></clause><clause id="H8B7C277B15114A4185BA69B4F38DE560"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>without regard to political affiliation; and</text></clause><clause id="H6CCAB8E20A624493A2976EFACEEF88D7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>solely on the basis of their fitness to perform their duties.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H03C796B680D742139DED8835B71CDCC6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Limits</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Members of the Panel shall be limited to two 3-year terms, for a total of not to exceed 6 years of service on the Panel. For purposes of this paragraph, any year of service on the Panel by a person appointed to fill a vacancy under paragraph (2) shall be included in determining the number of years that such person has served on the Panel.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HB3DB6F10256547159CAC919D1A9C5D0B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents of such Act is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 203 the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H55DFAE8639BB48AF99B3E94D69561805" style="OLC"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">204. Panel of Health Advisors.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

