<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3D34DA17EBD945E1B3253FD6611DBF08" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4920 IH: Bureau of Industry and Security Information Technology Modernization Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4920</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250808">August 8, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001121">Mr. Crow</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="K000398">Mr. Kean</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000400">Ms. Kamlager-Dove</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require modernization of information technology systems and applications of the Bureau of Industry and Security of the Department of Commerce.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H3E1154F7F0D0490FACE074566AA41535" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H69AD6CB9DB414826BD85BD13D3ED35BC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Bureau of Industry and Security Information Technology Modernization Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>BIS IT Modernization Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HA02A44237F5D4C43A4718053DDA7993C" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Modernization of information technology systems and applications of the Bureau of Industry and Security</header> <subsection id="H965C18A42C2447E191117F9C44AFCC17"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that the effective use of Bureau authorities requires that—</text> 
<paragraph id="HD85A63ECE9BA4A53BA6CD6D3460635C5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Bureau adopt and deploy cutting-edge data fusion, analytics, and decision-making capabilities, as well as supply chain illumination tools and additional commercial data sets, to streamline and standardize the export license adjudication process, better assess global industrial relationships, enhance the evaluation of information and communications technologies and services, identify dual use items of concern for control, and identify evasive trade patterns and shell companies being used by adversary militaries;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0397EE797E684B8C893C9F0E134D908D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Bureau expand and scale up the adoption and use of modern data sharing interfaces and capabilities to share data safely and efficiently with industry, Federal agencies, and international partners;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAAE8DAF9D35A48C3BAF5BE3B3D339CAE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Bureau information technology systems should over time enable the incorporation of artificial intelligence, machine learning, and other advanced tools as technologies evolve;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9E0024C785D641F4856F2CB5B83FBC03"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Bureau expedite Entity List, Military End User List, and Unverified List deliberations tied to countries of concern and enforcement activities related to tracking military end users and end uses in countries of concern, including the People’s Republic of China (PRC), Russia, and Iran;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5C01D9F83DF14048B320B76D46A497E4"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the Bureau work with relevant agencies to comprehensively map the PRC defense industrial base and its military civil fusion strategy; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB1B5537D1AA54A4791BA04D565CDA1A8"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Bureau work with relevant agencies to comprehensively map the commercial linkages between the industrial bases of the PRC, Russia, North Korea, Iran, and other countries of concern.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H27A7311925264F919FCE87BAD89E68E8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to the availability of appropriations, the Under Secretary of Commerce for Industry and Security shall, on an ongoing basis through fiscal year 2030, modernize the information technology systems of the Bureau.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H0E57D4875A9D4010B75F9175B9A2ACF9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>In carrying out subsection (b), the Under Secretary should—</text> 
<paragraph id="H62CC5C571D7A401589118A8B22EC4473"><enum>(1)</enum><text>replace the Bureau’s primary information technology systems with a unified environment that—</text> <subparagraph id="HCC7E7BD1DAA642D7A2ACD11F3354DE2E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>allows for deployment of a seamless case and customer relationship management information technology solution; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5617AE11B6FB44F48D1C71C7B81C83FB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provides analysis of data obtained from external data providers that is collected by trade transactions and other sources as appropriate;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF07B4EFFF99045399511F8B4F4F2149F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>adopt and deploy cutting-edge data fusion, analytics, and decision-making capabilities, as well as supply chain illumination tools, and additional commercial data sets to streamline and standardize the export license adjudication process, and better assess global industrial relationships;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0540FD3E59AA4548AA4011935632BAB4"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">enhance the processes that maintain a list of foreign persons determined to be a threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States, which support Entity List deliberations and, enforcement activities, such as tracking military end users and end uses and identifying evasive trade patterns and shell companies; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCFB565A0205E4A8FA8347E8A1CF46063"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">expand and scale up the adoption and use of modern data sharing interfaces and capabilities to share the appropriate data elements safely and efficiently with industry, Federal agencies, including the intelligence community, and international partners.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HEE1E09C3BD78421FAD078520F0646E9D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Objectives</header><text>Before any informational technology solutions are adopted with respect to the elements in subsection (c), such solutions should be analyzed based on their ability to—</text> <paragraph id="H54FDDEC16F2A43369ECDFFECEEBCA41A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>enhance productivity and efficiency, including by reducing the need for manual review and processing of data;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0092AA96785C4F24A725D033B24F9F32"><enum>(2)</enum><text>reduce redundancies and manage costs;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3184C5F7C5384ADCAC96B97B23A5DFEE"> <enum>(3)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">enhance the overall data and cyber security of Bureau systems and underlying information technology infrastructure;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7F81BDBDFC2F4AE4B56D117AA714940B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>facilitate seamless and safe sharing of appropriate data with relevant stakeholders and partners;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5A815AB0B36C44C687CA8D5795FBD60C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>facilitate seamless data sharing with relevant agencies and the intelligence community; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDF4F1971379E4A6F8BD425176BF282B3"><enum>(6)</enum><text>enhance the ease of access and user experience for United States parties that are utilizing Bureau systems.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H2771825091FA4D368A4B4EE8217629F2"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Personnel assessment</header><text>The Under Secretary should—</text> 
<paragraph id="HFA834A17FD9947AAB40CC8C7B6E08DD8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>reassess staffing and personnel needs across the Bureau throughout the modernization process described in this section; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H96AA6F7E6F274D5DAC964336950D23EF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>consult with Congress on whether additional or less personnel may be most effective for utilizing modern applications and systems.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3934E635C03A48C7AA337DF59AB9DE36"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated $25,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2026 through 2029 to carry out this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H4DF5E2264D4D4FFCBAFB1D18221CA03B"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="HCEE45BD9B8C54581A7EBAB2AA2BC7527"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HD688ED70E2EE41E49312588C28C96A95"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H84C347BEF1EF44D2910D8489DCDD085F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H031375615CB244E88D49D7A35A712062"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Bureau</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Bureau</term> means the Bureau of Industry and Security of the Department of Commerce.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H71A3AEE4E7884C31BC2D75BB2F336306"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Entity list</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Entity List</term> means the list maintained by the Bureau and set forth in Supplement No. 4 to part 744 of title 15, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H84E40BDBA8AE4F12809CF5FDF25067EF"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Under Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Under Secretary</term> means the Under Secretary of Commerce for Industry and Security.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

