<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H745DBE8210D14934A062933FC104E25A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2126 IH: Fair and Open Competition Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2126</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250314">March 14, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001077">Mr. Higgins of Louisiana</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001204">Mr. Meuser</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001129">Mr. Collins</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000175">Mr. Ogles</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001224">Mr. Self</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000467">Mr. Thompson of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000603">Mr. Gill of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000055">Mr. Aderholt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000605">Mr. Perry</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001132">Mr. Crane</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001118">Mr. Cline</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000250">Mr. Sessions</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000372">Mr. Allen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000235">Mr. Ezell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000806">Mr. Webster of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000194">Ms. Mace</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000026">Mr. Nehls</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001120">Mr. Crenshaw</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000459">Mr. Fleischmann</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001052">Mr. Harris of Maryland</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001177">Mr. McClintock</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001302">Mr. Biggs of Arizona</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000609">Mr. Palmer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000594">Ms. De La Cruz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001194">Mr. Moolenaar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001133">Mr. Ciscomani</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000668">Mr. Bentz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000471">Mr. Fitzgerald</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001309">Mr. Burchett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000301">Mr. Johnson of South Dakota</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000628">Mr. Dunn of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001257">Mr. Bilirakis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001096">Ms. Hageman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000871">Mr. Mann</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000825">Ms. Boebert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001325">Mrs. Biggs of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000059">Mr. Calvert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000190">Mr. Norman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000804">Mr. Wittman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000177">Mr. Onder</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000590">Mr. Green of Tennessee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001260">Mr. Buchanan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000740">Mrs. Bice</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000591">Mr. Guest</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001239">Mr. McGuire</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001212">Mr. Moore of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001314">Mr. Bean of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000558">Mr. Guthrie</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000565">Mr. Gosar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000603">Mr. Rouzer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000480">Mr. Timmons</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001095">Mr. Hunt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001172">Mr. Smith of Nebraska</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001316">Mr. Burlison</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000399">Mrs. Kiggans of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001228">Ms. Maloy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000165">Mr. Tiffany</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001099">Mr. Haridopolos</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001067">Mr. Hudson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000048">Mr. Pfluger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000405">Mr. Knott</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000795">Mr. Wilson of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001199">Mr. Smucker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000576">Mr. Grothman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001220">Mr. Strong</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000392">Mr. Kustoff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000609">Mr. Rutherford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000575">Mr. Rogers of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000032">Mr. Donalds</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001214">Mr. Steube</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000478">Mr. Fry</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000595">Ms. Letlow</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000626">Mr. Davidson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000450">Ms. Foxx</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001100">Mr. Hurd of Colorado</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001115">Mr. Cloud</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001093">Mrs. Houchin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001189">Mr. Austin Scott of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001072">Mr. Hill of Arkansas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001086">Mrs. Harshbarger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001039">Mrs. Cammack</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000589">Mr. Gooden</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000246">Mr. Fallon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001116">Mr. Clyde</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000809">Mr. Womack</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001108">Mr. Comer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001321">Mr. Barrett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000388">Mr. Kelly of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000816">Mr. Williams of Texas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001136">Mrs. McClain</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To preserve open competition and Federal Government neutrality towards the labor relations of Federal Government contractors on Federal and federally funded construction projects, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H25274A3AE09644B88E3B9434B6F1404B" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HF501A2E6D20B4E9ABA9CC466C5E7AAF1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Fair and Open Competition Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>FOCA Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section commented="no" id="H19634E54479A4CBF95516D7BDD5F5A75"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the purpose of this Act to—</text>
<paragraph commented="no" id="H13AA6770DD504620A75CC7827C4F7D06"><enum>(1)</enum><text>promote and ensure open competition on Federal and federally funded or assisted construction projects;</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H0D24B8D2397B4848921CEED39E257FC9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>maintain Federal Government neutrality towards the labor relations of Federal Government contractors on Federal and federally funded or assisted construction projects;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" id="HBAB1A34205974349B69402D4FD837A89"><enum>(3)</enum><text>reduce construction costs to the Federal Government and to the taxpayers;</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="HEA82CDBFA1864BD188A438FCE68DFF91"><enum>(4)</enum><text>expand job opportunities, especially for small and disadvantaged businesses; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" id="HA3FE60BB597342C3B7140595E478F316"><enum>(5)</enum><text>prevent discrimination against Federal Government contractors or their employees based upon labor affiliation or the lack thereof, thereby promoting the economical, nondiscriminatory, and efficient administration and completion of Federal and federally funded or assisted construction projects.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H596F75ED796C497E8B74C22038F417A3"><enum>3.</enum><header>Preservation of open competition and Federal Government neutrality</header> <subsection id="H55991230B0C24B5AA594C65C300AC2AB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header> <paragraph id="H07A348B27EE44A62A8199E2DF30A2C44"><enum>(1)</enum><header>General rule</header><text>The head of each executive agency that awards or enters into any construction contract or that obligates funds pursuant to such a contract, shall ensure that the agency, and any construction manager acting on behalf of the Federal Government with respect to such contract, in its bid specifications, project agreements, or other controlling documents does not—</text>
<subparagraph id="HBED21CD92FB74680B7775220C04AF28E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>require or prohibit a bidder, offeror, contractor, or subcontractor from entering into, or adhering to, agreements with 1 or more labor organizations, with respect to that construction project or another related construction project; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD4F584B738A24A1282BD513011A28E16"><enum>(B)</enum><text>discriminate against or give preference to a bidder, offeror, contractor, or subcontractor because such bidder, offeror, contractor, or subcontractor—</text>
<clause id="H19BE8989E3D746D0ABA675C15E83157D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>becomes a signatory, or otherwise adheres to, an agreement with 1 or more labor organizations with respect to that construction project or another related construction project; or</text></clause> <clause id="HD5D84108F3244CA488B70668ABA35A04"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>refuses to become a signatory, or otherwise adhere to, an agreement with 1 or more labor organizations with respect to that construction project or another related construction project.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA69FAEC5FC5A4D70933500ED4AF19820"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application of prohibition</header><text>This subsection shall apply with respect to—</text> <subparagraph id="H24D1325790BD46A7BD4837AE105C726E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>contracts awarded on or after the date of the enactment of this Act; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H54BDFFFE63404C7C9BE56797B89E73D7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>subcontracts awarded under such contracts.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H77CFE44317B34B41BA4B571FE249DFF0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in paragraph (1) may be construed to prohibit a contractor or subcontractor from voluntarily entering into an agreement described in such paragraph.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7ED683EFC1434524A883B706858958EE"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Federal acquisition regulation</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Federal Acquisition Regulation shall be revised to implement the provisions of this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H8A3ADE3F158A4207BEC2DF3E24985E4A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Recipients of grants and other assistance</header><text>The head of each executive agency that awards grants, provides financial assistance, or enters into cooperative agreements for construction projects after the date of the enactment of this Act shall ensure that—</text>
<paragraph id="H4633ABFB7D9C4F6F8C50575DE5D4A320"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the bid specifications, project agreements, or other controlling documents for such construction projects of a recipient of a grant or financial assistance, or by the parties to a cooperative agreement, do not contain any of the requirements or prohibitions described in subparagraph (A) or (B) of subsection (a)(1); or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H20AEDAF48E7741DE988BEA76DF48A89F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the bid specifications, project agreements, or other controlling documents for such construction projects of a construction manager acting on behalf of a recipient or party described in paragraph (1) do not contain any of the requirements or prohibitions described in subparagraph (A) or (B) of subsection (a)(1).</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HA72EC8C460344490B1716494E9A3B130"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Failure To comply</header><text>If an executive agency, a recipient of a grant or financial assistance from an executive agency, a party to a cooperative agreement with an executive agency, or a construction manager acting on behalf of such an agency, recipient, or party, fails to comply with subsection (a) or (b), the head of the executive agency awarding the contract, grant, or assistance, or entering into the agreement involved, shall take such action, consistent with the law, as the head of such agency determines to be appropriate.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HC4E89A36F49C4450BD89AB2DE2C8853A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Exemptions</header> <paragraph id="H8224264D768F47CEB60103387D6F42C2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The head of an executive agency may exempt a particular project, contract, subcontract, grant, or cooperative agreement from the requirements of 1 or more of the provisions of subsections (a) and (b) if the head of such agency determines that special circumstances exist that require an exemption in order to avert an imminent threat to public health or safety or to serve the national security.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HFDEFA3E7722543878D3E89D842E1A45A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Special circumstances</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (1), a finding of special circumstances may not be based on the possibility or existence of a labor dispute concerning contractors or subcontractors that are nonsignatories to, or that otherwise do not adhere to, agreements with 1 or more labor organizations, or labor disputes concerning employees on the project who are not members of, or affiliated with, a labor organization.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4E4DBD90573948B78302D617B8E1311E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Additional exemption for certain projects</header><text>The head of an executive agency, upon application of an awarding authority, a recipient of grants or financial assistance, a party to a cooperative agreement, or a construction manager acting on behalf of any of such entities, may exempt a particular project from the requirements of any or all of the provisions of subsection (a) or (b), if the head of such agency finds—</text>
<subparagraph id="HC0035D238C43469BB73228F550AEAE1E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that the awarding authority, recipient of grants or financial assistance, party to a cooperative agreement, or construction manager acting on behalf of any of such entities had issued or was a party to, as of the date of the enactment of this Act, bid specifications, project agreements, agreements with 1 or more labor organizations, or other controlling documents with respect to that particular project, which contained any of the requirements or prohibitions set forth in subsection (a)(1); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA1B4E1928DD048A8959AA36FDF506445"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that 1 or more construction contracts subject to such requirements or prohibitions had been awarded as of the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HB9EC952CA09A4996A4119DD98F1DFE0F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HFFEFEC80920647A2A5FF4958D1B827BE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Construction contract</header><text>The term <term>construction contract</term> means any contract for the construction, rehabilitation, alteration, conversion, extension, or repair of buildings, highways, or other improvements to real property.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2B10E9E5918944F594DBF5B304AB1176"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Executive agency</header><text>The term <term>executive agency</term> has the meaning given the term <term>Executive agency</term> in section 105 of title 5, United States Code, except that such term does not include the Government Accountability Office.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H57C6E684158B4DEB866C0A52F96145DB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Labor organization</header><text>The term <term>labor organization</term> has the meaning given such term in section 701 of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000e">42 U.S.C. 2000e</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

