<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-HEY25493-8R6-58-R53">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1951 IS: Retaining Essential Support for Combat and Unified Evacuation Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>II</distribution-code>
        <congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session>1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. 1951</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action>
            <action-date date="20250604">June 4, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S355">Mr. Cruz</sponsor> introduced the following bill;
                which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title>To ensure the preservation and operational integrity of the aeromedical
            evacuation capabilities of the Department of the Army within the Medical Service Corps
            and to maintain the role of the Medical Service Corps as the primary joint service
            provider for intra-theater aeromedical evacuation, and for other
            purposes.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body>
        <section id="S1" section-type="section-one">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Retaining Essential Support for Combat and Unified Evacuation Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>RESCUE Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section id="id92dab7057fea4b5d82f4d43fc6d59a0a">
            <enum>2.</enum>
            <header>Preservation of dedicated aeromedical evacuation capability of Medical Service
                Corps of the Army</header>
            <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1cd937ab98904bfd9e0e1ecdd0166824">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Medical Service Corps of the Army shall maintain a dedicated aeromedical evacuation capability, including personnel, training, doctrine, and aircraft specifically configured for aeromedical evacuation missions.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="ide84d61749f7741b18dd9d6ff4ae12d1b">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Clarification of authority</header>
 <text>The Secretary of the Army shall ensure that—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id55c15f1852454306b8ad78dcb216fbb4"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the aviation branch of the Army has the authority to organize, train, and equip aviation assets in accordance with operational requirements; and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idab389616236740cf9759258f00059411">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the medical department of the Army, under the authority delegated to such department by the Surgeon General of the Army, has the authority for medical command and control, patient care responsibilities, and clinical standards for aeromedical evacuation operations.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida9a23ab4fd5c4c0e93e8331552b86561">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Elements of capability</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Army shall maintain the capability required under subsection (a)—</text>
                <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9d58323511e0471088d408b7d5418c85">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in alignment with the sufficiency analysis of the Surgeon General of the Army;</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8649f8589486415386fc6b2c8b1ef371">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consistent with medical evacuation doctrine and operational planning assumptions of the Army; and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6d5ef72bda8c45afa469e511fdfb9fa3">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in support of—</text> <subparagraph id="id30fbda88f3cb4e70ba0c6516528aa690"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>the commanders of the combatant commands;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id43cd1a8528104816b67729a1bdf0a98b">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>contingency operations and operational plans;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idad8a3898d6f742afb1996ddced5104fc"> <enum>(C)</enum> <text>civil authorities;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id52093609ac9b49ed93ea30d4d6241c13">
                        <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">chemical, biological, radiological, and nuclear response force missions;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id2a0d3c8e29e14590b10c5808c0e80f75">
                        <enum>(E)</enum>
 <text>humanitarian assistance and disaster response operations; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id4ba73b4d6e31402f944e36a2030f86ca"> <enum>(F)</enum> <text>garrison emergency medical response operations at installations of the Department of Defense.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id217de4b9412a42f98de368db7cd87f96">
                <enum>(d)</enum>
                <header>Change in structure</header>
                <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id946c2dece1404e0d8d8c424396e52b73">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                    <header>In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The capability required under subsection (a) shall remain a distinct component within the Medical Service Corps of the Army and may not be restructured into general-purpose aviation elements or dual-use configurations without prior notification to the congressional defense committees (as defined in section 101(a) of title 10, United States Code), which shall—</text>
                    <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id71f547cc11404e969f6556e59bbc6be9">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be accompanied by a formal risk assessment on—</text>
                        <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id946c6e9957594883a731e342a97a12b2">
                            <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">operational medical readiness of the Medical Service Corps; and</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id165cf5e1206c459089fd40d81d2f26cb">
                            <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">readiness of the Medical Service Corps to support the joint force and missions specified under subsection (c)(3); and</text>
                        </clause>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5747b8fae1264543829c31aa73dc516b">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>contain a report that—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf1db98127bc34a0fa3a99611c90d7354"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is based on the force structure authorizations outlined in the most current Army Structure Message;</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5a63cb30d70f4963b2d70a170f145960">
                            <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is informed by the most current Total Army Analysis approved by the Secretary of the Army; and</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id37c455dc7eb446a88e963f2d83f1eb75">
                            <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not propose or assume any changes to the aircraft authorizations reflected in the documents specified in clauses (i) and (ii).</text>
                        </clause>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="idc24a5383794b4acba3d2bed6a9db850a">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Operational medical requirements and joint force needs</header>
 <text>Any adjustments made to the force structure of the aeromedical evacuation capability of the Army must account for operational medical requirements and joint force needs where the Surgeon General of the Army retains authority over the medical force structure, staffing, clinical oversight, and doctrinal development for aeromedical evacuation units.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id2210e6731fa84a008ce08d313c33056d">
                <enum>(e)</enum>
                <header>Change to allocations</header>
 <text>The Secretary of the Army may not make any changes to allocations for the Medical Service Corps of the Army that is inconsistent with the requirements of this section without prior consultation with the Surgeon General of the Army, who shall certify that the proposed changes are supported by a sufficiency analysis and that the revised platform levels remain adequate to support all mission categories requiring aeromedical evacuation, consistent with medical evacuation doctrine and operational planning assumptions of the Army.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbffec16a1df246718d00156cc1690968">
                <enum>(f)</enum>
                <header>Effective date</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section shall take effect on the date that is 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id686404f0fa0f48d6b491e0a3c39df120">
                <enum>(g)</enum>
                <header>Rule of construction</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall be construed to prohibit augmentation of military patient movement operations with combatant, commercial, or allied assets in contingency or humanitarian operations, as determined necessary by the Secretary of Defense.</text>
            </subsection>
        </section>
    </legis-body>
</bill>

