<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCAD144DA47874A4D86AB4A7D2B410E3C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5482 IH: Prevent Youth Suicide Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5482</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250918">September 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000193">Mr. Nunn of Iowa</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="P000614">Mr. Pappas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Education to issue a rule requiring schools to implement protocols for suicide prevention, postvention, and trauma-informed care.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H206504CBB43C45119CECEE06A13E2BDC" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H310376C3EE21484E9EA2329D85D18842" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Prevent Youth Suicide Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HAAEF5F3669C8451EB43BB8B97F9BB613"><enum>2.</enum><header>Rules on protocols for suicide prevention at any educational agency or institution serving students in grades 6 through grade 12</header> <subsection id="H7D881304620D4615B2AE00014A375224"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Rule</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 210 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Education shall issue a rule requiring, as a condition of receipt of funds under an applicable program, that an educational agency or institution carry out each of the following:</text>
<paragraph id="H9B84FCBDBECA43ED82B16869F45BE0BF" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><header>School-based suicide prevention protocols</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The development and implementation of evidence-based suicide prevention programs tailored to the needs of students, which shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="HCC29F7E76D8A4596A0917E9F308370DA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>biennial, evidence-based training for staff and faculty to—</text>
<clause id="H3FCA54141F7A475BA0BE21E0D330A3EF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>identify signs of distress and risk factors for suicide in students; and</text></clause> <clause id="H6A5E51D35D85403691AF14AB51EDDAC4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in a case in which a student has been identified as exhibiting such signs or risk factors, guidelines for reporting such identification to parents and guidance counselors, and responding to concerns from such parents and counselors;</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H606A852AF73D40C4872B432F0D2F0DBA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>establishing a referral system to connect students in need to appropriate mental health resources at school and outside of school; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H45881E2D07FA45F1B9EBF08EC085A47E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>conducting awareness campaigns and educational initiatives to reduce stigma associated with seeking help for mental health concerns.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4C82CC0F2475401AAF0A4AA906C6B9FC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Suicide postvention support</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The development and implementation of a suicide postvention plan to address the aftermath of a suicide, focusing on providing support to affected students, staff, and the broader community, which shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="H9EAB711943F6405894204DE539D9ECE3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>guidelines for communication, memorialization, and resources for grief counseling; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD220B643353C484D8109F473ADE85E5D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>collaboration with mental health professionals and community organizations to ensure comprehensive postvention support.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2FAB05E46C2C429CB7752CFAB73565E7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Trauma-informed care</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The adoption of a trauma-informed approach in policies and practices to create a safe and supportive environment for all students, which shall include the provision of biennial trauma-sensitive training for school staff to help such staff understand the potential impact of trauma on students and to promote appropriate responses.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H8D4C3D78602C43B9AD495D3F7FADADC3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Additional requirements for the Secretary of Education</header>
<paragraph id="H0092F0078D534E7DB2EB6A0966783722"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall provide each educational agency or institution subject to the rule issued under subsection (a) with the resources, guidelines, and technical assistance to comply with the requirements of such rule.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4DB86A20F62B4A42B60150ECE3188718"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Compliance monitoring</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish to ensure compliance with the rule issued under subsection (a), which shall include periodic assessments, evaluations, and audits of each such educational agency or institution.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H42C2377E167B41D0B582A8979D10BB4E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Feedback and improvement</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H3937E4A03148433CADDE41CD819FEB48" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text>encourage educational agencies and institutions to provide feedback to the Secretary on the effectiveness of the requirements issued under the rule; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HAF7C02DF31834875B56F21572B91D60A" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">review such feedback and make necessary revisions to such rule.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HA6238A5090BB47608A16360CF0971E15"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
<paragraph id="H5D18AA9A88394811903AE0712831E84D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Applicable program</header><text>The term <term>applicable program</term> has the meaning given the term in section 400 of the General Education Provisions Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1221">20 U.S.C. 1221</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H02DF27CF3AD44D339591238E55535FB8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Educational agency or institution</header><text>The term <term>educational agency or institution</term> means an educational agency or institution (as defined in section 444(a)(3) of the General Education Provisions Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1232g">20 U.S.C. 1232g</external-xref>)) that serves students in any grade from grade 6 through grade 12, as determined under State law.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2639AB4D5B384759A24FC7700B8DCCF1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Parent</header><text>The term <term>parent</term> has the meaning given the term in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H51394EF69F694B7C983B96E7EA0E4F23"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Education.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD8120F71258A410C9D5515D1B4B727DD"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Suicide postvention</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>suicide postvention</term> means activities and support provided after a suicide has occurred, designed to help individuals cope with the loss, minimize potential negative impacts, and prevent contagion.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4BCB551C320D423B94D326F31D1E7D47"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Suicide prevention</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>suicide prevention</term> means comprehensive strategies and actions aimed at identifying individuals at risk of suicide, providing appropriate interventions, and fostering a supportive environment to reduce the likelihood of suicidal behavior.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1C85C2C311C74EB5AE0C727E16140F32"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Trauma-informed care</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>trauma-informed care</term> means an approach based on an understanding of the vulnerabilities and triggers of individuals who have experienced trauma, recognize the role trauma has played in the lives of those individuals, recognize the presence of trauma symptoms and their onset, are supportive of trauma recovery, and avoid further traumatization.</text></paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

