<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MCC25446-LYJ-JF-N2J"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1233 IS: Keep STEM Talent Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1233</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250401" legis-day="20250331">April 1 (legislative day, March 31), 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S381">Mr. Rounds</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S363">Mr. King</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To provide lawful permanent resident status for certain advanced STEM degree holders, and for other purposes. </official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H29B4B266A3C14989A58EAC4BEE395A76"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Keep STEM Talent Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id2d16879bf4044727834dbd2a5d0b9e29"><enum>2.</enum><header>Visa requirements</header><subsection id="id4921457ff85a451a88f7f6520d117dbf"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Graduate degree visa requirements</header><text>To be approved for or maintain nonimmigrant status under section 101(a)(15)(F) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(15)(F)</external-xref>), a student seeking to pursue an advanced degree in a STEM field (as defined in section 201(b)(1)(F)(ii) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1151">8 U.S.C. 1151(b)(1)(F)(ii)</external-xref>)) (as amended by section 3(a)) for a degree at the master’s level or higher at a United States institution of higher education (as defined in section 101(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001(a)</external-xref>) must apply for admission prior to beginning such advanced degree program.</text></subsection><subsection id="id305beed280b74958b6b59eaa50af1ec6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Strengthened vetting process</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security and the Secretary of State shall establish procedures to ensure that aliens described in subsection (a) are admissible pursuant to section 212(a)(3)(A) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(a)(3)(A)</external-xref>). Such procedures shall ensure that such aliens seeking admission from within the United States undergo verification of academic credentials, comprehensive background checks, and interviews in a manner equivalent to that of an alien seeking admission from outside of the United States. To the greatest extent practicable, the Secretary of Homeland Security and the Secretary of State shall also take steps to ensure that such applications for admission are processed in a timely manner to allow the pursuit of graduate education.</text></subsection><subsection id="ide1caaefcaa494adca4d120d1d3778479"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reporting requirement</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security and the Secretary of State shall submit an annual report to the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives detailing the implementation and effectiveness of the requirement for foreign graduate students pursuing advanced degrees in STEM fields to seek admission prior to pursuing a graduate degree program. The report shall include data on visa application volumes, processing times, security outcomes, and economic impacts.</text></subsection></section><section id="ide149b4c22bfc4f54b5bdddf1a25433db"><enum>3.</enum><header>Lawful permanent resident status for certain advanced stem degree holders</header><subsection id="id500a648e28c4477ea22a17559ae95136"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Aliens not subject to direct numerical limitations</header><text>Section 201(b)(1) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1151">8 U.S.C. 1151(b)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb36d0fcd6e1b4b08b77b112df88e7fbf"><subparagraph id="id852a844fab16460c8fc298ae194f4814"><enum>(F)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idfa4bd878f7164fa4b27233598984b572"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Aliens who—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="idd20381534c484a31a7084f0f8b4cc3b4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>have earned a degree in a STEM field at the master’s level or higher while physically present in the United States from a United States institution of higher education (as defined in section 101(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001(a)</external-xref>)) accredited by an accrediting entity recognized by the Department of Education;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="idfaec4e8a5b414bccac62b80c92a98f28"><enum>(II)</enum><text>have an offer of employment from, or are employed by, a United States employer to perform work that is directly related to such degree at a rate of pay that is higher than the median wage level for the occupational classification in the area of employment, as determined by the Secretary of Labor; </text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="id47c11056be804596b13ad2855485ac95"><enum>(III)</enum><text>have an approved labor certification under section 212(a)(5)(A)(i); or</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="idf426c903c57846ceb5285c5fda80287e"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>are the spouses and children of aliens described in subclauses (I) through (III) who are accompanying or following to join such aliens.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="idec230ccc22ef4db6aeeaf964feadfe37"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>In this subparagraph, the term <term>STEM field</term> means a field of science, technology, engineering, or mathematics described in the most recent version of the Classification of Instructional Programs of the Department of Education taxonomy under the summary group of—</text><subclause id="idf1a68d15c41a435ea0447abf032c2b00"><enum>(I)</enum><text>computer and information sciences and support services;</text></subclause><subclause id="id61a12480694e476c8f29c9b27e41d4db"><enum>(II)</enum><text>engineering;</text></subclause><subclause id="id4ef8b72bcfd940fe8c8dc18e1cec9805"><enum>(III)</enum><text>mathematics and statistics;</text></subclause><subclause id="id3ee4e6ffa3b7420ab5430e4b79ccc093"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>biological and biomedical sciences;</text></subclause><subclause id="idf14f28bdb2024dfdb223a5604a48ede9"><enum>(V)</enum><text>physical sciences;</text></subclause><subclause id="ideae347013730488bbad5953ff35a7f8c"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>agriculture sciences; or</text></subclause><subclause id="id7bf49ab82b4a4286aee8b989eb6dd27b"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>natural resources and conservation sciences.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="id3ae352604f3c4150a5c9ba61c7378b4d"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Procedure for granting immigration status</header><text>Section 204(a)(1)(F) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1154">8 U.S.C. 1154(a)(1)(F)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>203(b)(2)</quote> and all that follows through <quote>Attorney General</quote> and inserting <quote>203(b)(2), 203(b)(3), or 201(b)(1)(F) may file a petition with the Secretary of Homeland Security</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="id7f04a699fa90427993b4ae39ac75d50e"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Labor certification</header><text>Section 212(a)(5)(D) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(a)(5)(D)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>section 201(b)(1)(F) or under</quote> after <quote>adjustment of status under</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="idaeefc04c632648f88350191dafe990b5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Dual intent for F nonimmigrants seeking advanced STEM degrees at United States institutions of higher education</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb8f3bae8324e488597060f0d36d56058"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding sections 101(a)(15)(F)(i) and 214(b) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(15)(F)(i)</external-xref> and 1184(b)), an alien who is a bona fide student admitted to a program in a STEM field (as defined in subparagraph (F)(ii) of section 201(b)(1) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1151">8 U.S.C. 1151(b)(1)</external-xref>)) for a degree at the master’s level or higher at a United States institution of higher education (as defined in section 101(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001(a)</external-xref>)) accredited by an accrediting entity recognized by the Department of Education may obtain a student visa, be admitted to the United States as a nonimmigrant student, or extend or change nonimmigrant status to pursue such degree even if such alien seeks lawful permanent resident status in the United States. </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9bf558468ad7480b8fb580c59e121240"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this subsection may be construed to modify or amend section 101(a)(15)(F)(i) or 214(b) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(15)(F)(i)</external-xref> or 1184(b)), or any regulation interpreting such authorities for an alien who is not described in this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

