<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4EDE9F03F14046499B8B0392BBFA31AA" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2085 IH: Mental Health Research Accelerator Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2085</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250311">March 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="K000376">Mr. Kelly of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for a credit against tax for expenses for translational research regarding neurodegenerative diseases and psychiatric conditions.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H1AF5EDD93271459FB3C29075B206C399" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H872518C31E03468BBA20F2797187DC6C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Mental Health Research Accelerator Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H8DAEDE0D6B6F4D6BA0EDA331FC3359E8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Expenses for certain translational research</header> <subsection id="HCC111EFBE8914F9088A3E87A69937968"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subpart D of part IV of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new section: </text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H3AAF7A7EE48249E5BE5D36B0930BD9A1" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="H51DA4D4269B74650BD127FA7C1FF650B"><enum>45BB.</enum><header>Expenses for certain translational research</header> 
<subsection id="HBC71E37BD0AF4A61A5E1E343F9162C2F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Allowance of credit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of section 38, the translational research credit determined under this section for any taxable year shall be an amount equal to 25 percent of the amounts paid or incurred by the taxpayer during such taxable year which are necessary for translational research regarding neurodegenerative diseases and psychiatric conditions.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HDBDFB3AC339B4D428BCF9E4506A2C3A3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitation</header> <paragraph id="H82ECBF049A8448D1BFBF70B41E3456B1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Taxpayer limitation</header><text>The credit allowed under this section to a taxpayer for a taxable year beginning in any calendar year shall not exceed the portion of the limitation amount allocated to the taxpayer under this subsection reduced by the amount of credit allowed to the taxpayer under this section for all prior taxable years.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H974FF48B95EE4BFBBF568242A6C0AA49"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Aggregate national limitation</header> 
<subparagraph id="H3AC5CD3080504387BF1E153C1EA57C59"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is a translational research credit limitation for each calendar year as follows:</text> <clause id="HDB85F1BB8972424F9E2BA9F43C766827"><enum>(i)</enum><text>$1,000,000,000 for 2026.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HACF1850FCE4A42E98E4B91F25FCD76D8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>$2,000,000,000 for each of years 2027 through 2030.</text></clause> <clause id="HCD713C94B3164EF7BBEB79CE56390563"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>$1,000,000,000 for 2031.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBA81CD6615234D3CB3F6725FBB3B2E81"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Allocation of limitation</header><text>As expeditiously as possible, the Secretary shall allocate among applicants selected by the Secretary the limitation under subparagraph (A) for all years.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0959F8013261486AB93C4E579B631692"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Carryover of unused limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the translational research credit limitation for any calendar year exceeds the aggregate amount allocated under subparagraph (A) for such year, such limitation for the succeeding calendar year shall be increased by the amount of such excess.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD1A3C383CF724EC8947F1AC6F0891BDE"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall (in consultation with the Secretary of Health and Humans Services, the Administrator of the Food and Drug Administration, and the Director of the National Institutes of Health) prescribe regulations as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this section, including establishing the application process and the criteria for allocation under subparagraph (B). Such regulations shall include the following:</text> <clause id="H7EBA5CBAFA854930845A37D22220E181"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts shall be allocated based on scientific merit.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HDB84D38268414470B60C70858C033A89"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Projects should include all phases of the research continuum.</text></clause> <clause id="H49A1E7ED82C74A1B83AF726D12DE8879"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An emphasis on new therapeutics and devices targeted at central nervous system disorders and in the neurological and psychiatric fields.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HC2AE2AF3A833401094FA86FF75FDF1E4"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Standards for repurposing existing drugs and devices for new purposes.</text></clause> <clause id="H017E55AA2FFC4F75BD78A04FD1779235"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Standards for public-private partnerships with priority given to collaborative efforts and sharing of intellectual property held by tax exempt entities involved in the project.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H85241F82949741F2BB8FBCCF8B7E4626"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Transfer of credit</header> 
<paragraph id="H3602674199CA4DA7899E8D426C4A94F9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If, with respect to a credit under subsection (a) for any taxable year—</text> <subparagraph id="H4DCAE39C47D24DD7B44725EDF62B268A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a tax-exempt entity would be the taxpayer (but for this paragraph), and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H551575428C42433E95202C4B6A7E2CEE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such entity elects the application of this paragraph for such taxable year with respect to all (or any portion specified in such election) of such credit,</text></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">the eligible project partner specified in such election, and not the tax-exempt entity, shall be treated as the taxpayer for purposes of this title with respect to such credit (or such portion thereof). </continuation-text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1AB89DE76DDF4E9CBC2AA481164493FF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this subsection—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H7FBC28790732423FBB6C7084E2C6BCF7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Tax-exempt entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>tax-exempt entity</quote> means— </text> <clause id="HA29FCD2F40B045C3BA5E4BC91398FB1F"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a Federal, State, Indian tribal government (as defined in section 7701(a)(4)), or local government entity, or any political subdivision, agency, or instrumentality thereof, and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HCC038E0AB2FC4F1BB20BD828598CC179"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an organization described in section 501(c)(3) and exempt from tax under section 501(a).</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1687E8043B2545F2864D253B20DDA268"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Eligible project partner</header><text>The term <quote>eligible project partner</quote> means any person who—</text> 
<clause id="H8A8A20113390455F903442A8B2C25EC6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is identified in the application for allocation of credit under this section as a project partner, and</text></clause> <clause id="H10CA43687608448986291E6D3D0E615A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>participates in, or provides funding for, the research with respect to which limitation was allocated by the Secretary under subsection (b).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF822182384A347AB99974E608B19FACF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Special rules</header> 
<subparagraph id="H1362C7D499D94A4DBE4F019E5C30FD38"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of a credit under subsection (a) which is determined at the partnership level—</text> <clause id="H8287EA9A58BF44EEA0699216244F98D4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for purposes of paragraph (1)(A), a tax-exempt entity shall be treated as the taxpayer with respect to such entity’s distributive share of such credit, and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H542E322E5C884313B614CD759999D007"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the term <quote>eligible project partner</quote> shall include any partner of the partnership. </text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2E32270B54B84ABA900374122A6C8178"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Taxable year in which credit taken into account</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any credit (or portion thereof) with respect to which an election is made under paragraph (1), such credit shall be taken into account in the first taxable year of the eligible project partner ending with, or after, the tax-exempt entity’s taxable year with respect to which the credit was determined.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1CD2A98025094560AC10463FEF544787"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Coordination with credit for increasing research expenditures</header> 
<paragraph id="HE1A0E99F2CB243EA8DBCF4BEAFBADDE9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in paragraph (2), any expenses taken into account under this section shall not be taken into account for purposes of determining the credit allowable under section 41 for such taxable year.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H706DDA1B4E344CDA951B1C89DAC3DF2C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Expenses included in determining base period research expenses</header><text>Any expenses taken into account under this section which are qualified research expenses (within the meaning of section 41(b)) shall be taken into account in determining base period research expenses for purposes of applying section 41 to subsequent taxable years.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0AD79B0D88764E33BDEC4B87B332DAE6"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>No credit shall be allowed under this section for any taxable year beginning after December 31, 2035.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HD41CEF81133B4DDB90DAA35678F780B9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Deduction disallowed</header><text>Section 280C of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H4E7EBAA2F6734F53AA6796B0951CFD7E" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="HA0B119BFF5D2492B920F0C490CEE05F8"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Credit for certain translational research</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No deduction shall be allowed for that portion of the expenses taken into account under section 45BB otherwise allowable as a deduction for the taxable year which is equal to the amount of the credit determined for such taxable year under such section.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="HF737590486A4447F903EF270F88D2005" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Credit made part of general business credit</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/38">Section 38(b)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking <quote>plus</quote> at the end of paragraph (40), by striking the period at the end of paragraph (41) and inserting <quote>, plus</quote>, and by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9A78BD026A9148B1AF65E418C10C237D" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="HA8FB15AA7BE34AC1A3C0940D1C6A8CC8"><enum>(42)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the credit determined under section 45BB.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="HD385BE89369441A284CA40CB441C5844"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections for subpart D of part IV of subchapter A of chapter 1 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text> 
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry level="section"><quote>Sec. 45BB. Expenses for certain translational research.</quote>.</toc-entry></toc></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFB2D8E0500AD43A5AC84FDF0BD4B622D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this subsection shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act. </text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

