<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA5A47DC4FC8C4E89A8743395789988B6" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3738 IH: Heat Management Assistance Grant Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3738</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250604">June 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001211">Mr. Stanton</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to provide for assistance to States and local governments in response to extreme heat events, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H261A933233B94D88B3535AFA449F86CB" style="OLC"><section id="HA140644D60204545A6250EEC1AC0B87E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Heat Management Assistance Grant Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>HMAG Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HA93E3BDF4EBD41699472C9269CC034C9" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Mitigation of extreme heat events</header><subsection id="H0200CCA98CC149B6BC19F5CE270AED75"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title IV of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5170">42 U.S.C. 5170 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H7D787B394BF5499A81AFA90E59000490" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="H8E0B691855ED4A21BC42F06FDFA136D7"><enum>431.</enum><header>Mitigation of extreme heat events</header><subsection id="HABE79959B05744C681B72DDAB8B8AF19"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President, acting through the Regional Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, may provide assistance, including grants, equipment, supplies, and personnel, to any State or local government for the mitigation, and management of an extreme heat event.</text></subsection><subsection id="HDB3B9CB955FF45FFA6A2B596933E5D26"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In providing assistance under this section, the President shall coordinate with the head of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</text></subsection><subsection id="H600E614802D1450C88DABF0A23F1CDB7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>To be eligible for assistance under this section, a State or local government shall submit to the President—</text><paragraph id="H46B74E34DEEB460F8FC834F0F1634E26"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an assessment of the potential loss of life due to the extreme heat event based on information on previous events, if such events have occurred;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H109B2271DE0C4D0B83499F0E054A9533"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an assessment of the potential loss of revenue to such State or local government due to the extreme heat event based on any such previous event;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H690FED980572412A9524039306258657"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of any other sources of assistance available to the State or local government, including potential sources that are not solely responsible for mitigation of extreme heat events; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA6B0B81EE4C6472B81F37A58CDD7E1B9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>any potential long-term impacts of the extreme heat events, including impacts to infrastructure.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H07CDF77ADAC24A18BD608E39E07EA56B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Essential Assistance</header><text>In providing assistance under this section, the President may use the authority provided under section 403.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB4794AD9281847DB96C5906197814F02"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Hazard Mitigation Assistance</header><text>Whether or not a major disaster is declared, the President may provide hazard mitigation assistance in accordance with section 404 in any area affected by an extreme heat event for which assistance was provided under this section, including—</text></subsection><subsection id="HE85AB4E67AF148ED8505FAEBD036CF66"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Rules and Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall prescribe such rules and regulations as are necessary to carry out this section, including—</text><paragraph id="HB99E78EC1D604CDD9F34D02F9FDF32E7"><enum>(1)</enum><text> requirements for an agreement entered into by the State or local government to receive assistance under this section;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA8AA268F07A943CE8A8B75E72F082704"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a procedure for an appeals process in the case of a denial of assistance requested under this section; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H77A749D025C04714A0B5064CC87A9FF8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a description of eligible costs for which assistance may be provided under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H1079BE396C5F40F7BC848E541C8D049F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Development of extreme heat event threshold</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, jointly with the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration and in consultation with the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, shall develop a threshold for the temperature and duration of a heat event to qualify as an extreme heat event under section 431 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act, as added by this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

