<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" slc-id="S1-NEW25103-83Y-CM-M75"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 79 ATS: Honoring the memories of the victims of the senseless attack at Marjory Stoneman Douglas High School on February 14, 2018.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 79</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250213">February 13, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S404">Mr. Scott of Florida</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S439">Mrs. Moody</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Honoring the memories of the victims of the senseless attack at Marjory Stoneman Douglas High School on February 14, 2018.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, on February 14, 2018, a mass shooting that took the lives of 17 teachers and students took place at Marjory Stoneman Douglas High School in Parkland, Florida;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the people of the United States continue to pray for the individuals who were affected by this tragedy;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Parkland community has shown strength, compassion, and unity over the past 6 years; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas February 14, 2025, marks 7 years since the horrific attack: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="S1"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="idb32478452a384843b5269f1c79f2c3e4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>honors the memories of the victims of the senseless attack at Marjory Stoneman Douglas High School on February 14, 2018, and offers heartfelt condolences and deepest sympathies to the families, loved ones, and friends of the victims;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf1a33f5ebd354842abb78252322245c2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>honors the survivors of the attack and pledges continued support for their recovery;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfff814a137094acdb1a284b8b40141ab"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recognizes the strength and resilience of the Marjory Stoneman Douglas High School community; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id661257da1d964ebbbc590408b24a81c7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>expresses gratitude to the emergency medical and health care professionals of the Parkland community for their efforts in responding to the attack and caring for the victims and survivors. </text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

