<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H35CC3FD8D3CF40529E09F2821A0E68C7" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4994 IH: Safe Air on Airplanes Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4994</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250819">August 19, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000476">Mr. Frost</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall update the regulations to issue regulations to phase out the use of bleed air systems in certain aircraft, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD179B3B50A82418DAA01506DC7226B5E" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H7D7179A9ECEE4DEE949AA1D40989ED81" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Safe Air on Airplanes Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H50F3773C74C347BABC55029285309924" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Regulations on bleed air systems in certain aircraft</header> <subsection id="H27D8D6B2459546EBA99759D38AB166A5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Regulations required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall update the regulations under part 25 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, and any other applicable regulations, to—</text>
<paragraph id="HCBA28B462DAD4878BA247E102C49FDDB"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prohibit new type certified turbine and turbo-prop aircraft designs from using bleed air systems;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HED080CA653EE451D92E606DA969CACC5"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">require that, beginning on the date that is 7 years after the date of enactment of this Act, any bleed air system in a newly manufactured aircraft is fitted with a filter or combination of filter and air cleaning device designed and demonstrated to remove gaseous and particulate components of oil fumes; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE100416CE08543F3B19BD301A04CC37E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provide for a phase-out of the use of bleed air systems in the manufacture of existing type designs of turbine and turbo-prop driven aircraft according to the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HD0FECF5DB8424CF6A28F6162E7CA1BEF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Not later than 10 years after the date of enactment of this Act, 25 percent of such aircraft shall be manufactured without bleed air systems.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HF5D9EAB94E73414882E678C35C26C850"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Not later than 20 years after the date of enactment of this Act, 50 percent of such aircraft shall be manufactured without bleed air systems.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H76BA8D9DFACE453E9F687469773BE858"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Not later than 30 years after the date of enactment of this Act, 100 percent of such aircraft shall be manufactured without bleed air systems.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H1289D69C291D4FFAB5EFFA34A962A837"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definition of bleed air system</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this Act, the term <term>bleed air system</term> means an air system that—</text> <paragraph id="H99B8AAE4A8F74731AFDD9DB2BE3098B5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>uses compressed air that is taken from an aircraft engine, or auxiliary power unite compressor stage, that is upstream of the combustion chamber or on a shaft driven by a turbine engine; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC142552EAE01492BBBD4191C8649A316"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provides pressurized air to the aircraft pneumatic system that passengers or crew could foreseeably inhale or come in contact with during the operation of the aircraft for applications including ventilation.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

