<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H685F1D3E0FA94AA894D0986631693F11" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2311 IH: Pakistan Democracy Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2311</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250324">March 24, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000795">Mr. Wilson of South Carolina</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the imposition of sanctions with respect to certain foreign persons who have knowingly engaged in the wrongful persecution and imprisonment of political opponents in Pakistan, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB22339DF92C44794A39734960373B6DB" style="OLC"><section id="HD9CE58424A004398BE0BB1CB37FF91F9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Pakistan Democracy Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="HDD1BBACECA504BC8AC172E77767605DB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the policy of the United States to support a democratic Pakistan, including free and fair elections, that is based upon civilian rule, restoration of judicial independence, rule of law, human rights, and due process of law for all of the people of Pakistan.</text></section><section id="H13118D6483D14CDB81A2D5F90BB4F124"><enum>3.</enum><header>Determination regarding General Asim Munir</header><subsection id="H4B027889BC474F96AC2852322154462E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sanctions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State, acting in conjunction with the Secretary of the Treasury, shall impose sanctions on General Asim Munir, Chief of Army Staff of Pakistan, the Global Magnitsky Human Rights Accountability Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/10101">22 U.S.C. 10101 et seq.</external-xref>). </text></subsection><subsection id="HF833426F14A7474D90EBAB28B09B3FB6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may waive subsection (a) if the President certifies to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs, and the Senate Committee on Foreign Relations that—</text><paragraph id="HD4D030B6D1354C37814C7B3016DE5AD2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">military rule has ended in Pakistan and rule of law and civilian-led democracy has been restored; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC0B57111675F4597BB20FF2EB1D0AFDF"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">all wrongfully detained political detainees have been released from detention.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HFDE7650DD91F40F4AAAC615CA534A9A6"><enum>4.</enum><header>Authorization of sanctions</header><subsection id="HA0339DB701E143F1AD916E008AFDBD8C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Inadmissibility of officials and individuals involved in the wrongful persecution and imprisonment of Imran Khan</header><paragraph id="HBFA2CA31EC774EE08F52D80DBDBD8133"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall identify key individuals who are knowingly engaged the wrongful persecution and imprisonment of political detainees in Pakistan including but not limited to former Prime Minister Imran Khan or significantly undermined democracy and furthered military rule for the people of Pakistan including—</text><subparagraph id="HF455E2D858B248CE871EE7E3DBE671F4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such individuals who have served as a member of the Government or military of Pakistan; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2BC207013D7B4E5BA89212CC01BDDE86"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such individuals who are serving as an official in a leadership position working on behalf of the Government or military of Pakistan, including law enforcement, intelligence, judicial, or local or municipal government.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD4883F0856B945C888D9922BB354C0EA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Ineligibility for visas, admission, or parole</header><subparagraph id="HBA73787D39A646E7915235C7DB9FB1D7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Visas, admission, or parole</header><text>An alien with respect to which the President has made an affirmative decision under paragraph (1) shall be—</text><clause id="H2E4CC7C3279C4BDEABAC589F8A2EEE9F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>inadmissible to the United States;</text></clause><clause id="H6E3B8552CF3E4BCCAC8CBDDE1C36468A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>ineligible to receive a visa or other documentation to enter the United States; and</text></clause><clause id="HA6BB86FE1FE841489EF97307C05BF981"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>otherwise ineligible to be admitted or paroled into the United States or to receive any other benefit under the Immigration and Nationality Act (8 U.S.C. 1101 et 16 seq.).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB8B788638CC0425A8A823DDF36A71766"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Current visas revoked</header><clause id="H09A91819C87F424887F0D6AC249E821C"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The visa or other entry documentation of any alien described in paragraph (1) is subject to revocation regardless of the issue date of the visa or other entry documentation.</text></clause><clause id="H3B2B237BC9F14F9CB2C45EE749B254F0"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Immediate effect</header><text>A revocation under subclause (I) shall, in accordance with section 221(i) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1201">8 U.S.C. 1201(i)</external-xref>) take effect immediately, and cancel any other valid visa or entry documentation that is in the possession of the alien.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H105B716B9A4A46AB8FC4FE9F8344D4B6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Briefing</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall brief the appropriate committees of Congress with respect to—</text><subparagraph id="HDCC9D7D136E94348863E2022DB83C769"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any foreign person with respect to which the President has made an affirmative determination under paragraph (1); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5429CB9F5F7840F882AC7B16B11243E9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the specific facts that justify each such affirmative determination.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA88BC150D63C41C281FE98C766C311D8"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>The President may waive imposition of sanctions under this subsection on a case-by-case basis if the President determines and certifies to the appropriate committees of Congress that—</text><subparagraph id="H91111229F8D94B4282EF8C575FE31CE5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such waiver would serve national interests; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H115D6A42CBEC469E88FC28BAD6C1EC04"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the circumstances which caused the individual to be ineligible have sufficiently changed.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6F77D9D5D9B8444F8C189B74E9F49A10"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HD57014911C5F4EAA87E830EF9AF0B4B9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Admission; admitted; alien</header><text>The terms <term>admission</term>, <term>admitted</term>, and <term>alien</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 101 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA4DF738C76E74750840E18BDBFB89CBE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of congress</header><text>The term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="HEFF8C0716D46414B80905B3A0AC802DE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on the Judiciary, and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD09E0F2091E54D158C028122FAD58B21"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on the Judiciary, and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H78FC8C4616614268B8BB1B3D01B11FA8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Foreign person</header><text>The term <term>foreign person</term> means any individual that is not a United States person.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H20FBD5175CAE41AD9946CAE363F50238"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Immediate family members</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>immediate family members</term> has the meaning given the term <term>immediate relatives</term> in section 1151(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1151">8 U.S.C. 1151(b)(2)(A)(i)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H390749A181FB4053BA35ECD5E072EC6F"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Knowingly</header><text>The term <term>knowingly</term>, with respect to conduct, a circumstance, or a result, means that a person has actual knowledge, or should have known, of the conduct, the circumstance, or the result.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0ADD01D7A9264B58ACDFD452A2F3CA87"><enum>(6)</enum><header>United states person</header><text>The term <term>United States person</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="HAD8A1623FA734EEBBDAC64F5AC3D19BC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a United States citizen or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence to the United States; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8D24A525A3344A4B981A0CB3CEB48466"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any person within the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

