<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HFE999C93BA414527A64BE1C094137EE1" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5470 IH: Route 66 National Historic Trail Designation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5470</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250918">September 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000585">Mr. LaHood</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="L000273">Ms. Leger Fernandez</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the National Trails System Act to designate the Route 66 National Historic Trail, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H04DAD4B46A124659AFC13F22E1CB9E0D" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HE8AD6DE648C04BAA8B6AFB9084A3553D"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Route 66 National Historic Trail Designation Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H49E61C0B35E247E6B04F2ADD78815712"><enum>2.</enum><header>Designation of Route 66 National Historic Trail</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 5(a) of the National Trails System Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1244">16 U.S.C. 1244(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H4D4C19712F0D45C096B10FF51DF40EBA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating the second paragraph (31) (relating to Butterfield Overland National Historic Trail) as paragraph (32); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD9DD19A357CB480590043184AEF7F9DE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HB78DCF9194974BA7892D298800B154DD" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="H864B0F12230D467E800A3B2871EC3122"><enum>(33)</enum><header>Route 66 national historic trail</header> 
<subparagraph id="H5A6D0B00253F4662A29A7BCD6DE641B6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Route 66 National Historic Trail, a trail that includes all the alignments of U.S. Highway 66 in existence between 1926 and 1985, extending along a route of approximately 2,400 miles from Chicago, Illinois, to Santa Monica, California, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Route 66 National Historic Trail, Proposed Route</quote>, numbered P26/141,279, and dated December 2017.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2AFB7D9E3F534557A6A43744C6317939"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Availability of map</header><text>The map described in subparagraph (A) shall be on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of the National Park Service, Department of the Interior.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB1E74BE664B24340960566419B880A8C"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Administration</header>
<clause id="HE6E85C51FC724279B2D06196F2A959C9"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Route 66 National Historic Trail shall be administered by the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the National Park Service. Such administration shall be conducted in a manner that respects and maintains the idiosyncratic nature of the Route 66 National Historic Trail.</text></clause> <clause id="H2E17A2B356C04D16BAFF8DEDE65A4991"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Tribal consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Consistent with Executive Order 13175 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5301">25 U.S.C. 5301</external-xref> note; relating to consultation and coordination with Indian Tribal Governments) and all other applicable Federal law, the Secretary of the Interior shall conduct active, meaningful, and timely consultation with all affected Indian Tribes prior to undertaking an activity with respect to the Route 66 National Historic Trail that would have substantial direct impacts on 1 or more Indian Tribes.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H09CA7DBF6B30401C9A519471F67551F0"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Land acquisition</header><text>The United States may not acquire for the Route 66 National Historic Trail any land or interest in land—</text> <clause id="HA71275B85BF3437993F7F8082A32D938"><enum>(i)</enum><text>outside the exterior boundary of any federally managed area without the consent of the owner of the land or interest in land; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H781DBF1245114347B8B4D100A49FA355"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that extends more than an average of one-quarter of a mile on either side of the trail.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA02B08CBC9B347789D6664D89433537B"><enum>(E)</enum><header>No buffer zone created</header><text>Nothing in this Act, the acquisition of the land or an interest in land authorized by this Act, or the management plan for the Route 66 National Historic Trail shall be construed to create buffer zones outside of the Trail. That activities or uses can be seen, heard, or detected from the acquired land shall not preclude, limit, control, regulate, or determine the conduct or management of activities or uses outside of the trail.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6402588ABC7D467CB8BDA0D1FC5242CB"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Energy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act, the acquisition of land or an interest in land authorized by this Act, or the management plan for the Route 66 National Historic Trail shall prohibit, hinder, or disrupt the current or future development, production, transportation, or transmission of energy, including the construction or maintenance of pipelines, renewable energy projects, or other infrastructure for the development, production, transportation, or transmission of energy.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5E68DC9157CD45E2976B8454D1C89A17"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Eminent domain or condemnation</header><text>In carrying out this Act, the Secretary of the Interior may not use eminent domain or condemnation.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8DEB3FA042B446CC9B53AA78AA616068">
              <enum>(H)</enum>
              <header>Not a designation of <quote>lands in the national park system</quote></header>
 <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the designation of the Route 66 National Historic Trail by this paragraph shall not have the effect of designating the Route 66 National Historic Trail or any land on which the Route 66 National Historic Trail is located as <quote>lands in the National Park System</quote> for purposes of section 28(b)(1) of the Mineral Leasing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/185">30 U.S.C. 185(b)(1)</external-xref>).</text>
            </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3AB951758C274AB3B1B9DD85BAD55067"><enum>(I)</enum><header>No new authorities or permit</header> 
<clause id="H10704BF306FD4DF3BB084AF1B4767C89"><enum>(i)</enum><header>No effect on authority to grant easements or rights-of-way</header> 
<subclause id="HE313A2DC767A4E3D96DBA9407E0B81BE"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the designation of the Route 66 National Historic Trail by this paragraph shall not alter or affect the existing authority of any Federal, State, or local agency or official to grant easements or rights-of-way over, under, across, or along any portion of the area designated as the Route 66 National Historic Trail.</text></subclause> <subclause id="H91EA0698C2AD4245B65C674F85D97219"> <enum>(II)</enum> <header>Authority of heads of federal agencies to grants easements or rights-of-way</header> <text>Notwithstanding the designation of the Route 66 National Historic Trail by this paragraph, the head of any Federal agency having jurisdiction over any Federal land on which the Route 66 National Historic Trail designated by this paragraph is located (other than land that is considered to be <quote>lands in the National Park System</quote> for purposes of section 28(b)(1) of the Mineral Leasing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/185">30 U.S.C. 185(b)(1)</external-xref>) as a result of a designation under any other law), shall have the authority to grant easements or rights-of-way over, under, across, or along any applicable portion of the Route 66 National Historic Trail in accordance with the laws applicable to the Federal land.</text>
                </subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H66388E62D54B4597A492DE49783E68AB"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>No new permits required</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the designation of the Route 66 National Historic Trail by this paragraph shall not subject the Route 66 National Historic Trail or any land on which the Route 66 National Historic Trail is located to any other Federal laws (including regulations) requiring a Federal permit or authorization that would otherwise be made applicable as a result of the designation of the Route 66 National Historic Trail as a component of the National Trails System.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

