<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H599C74A94E0F450BA737DC6EE753337E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3542 IH: CLEAR (Committee Leadership and Enhanced Accountability for Resilience) Defense Production Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3542</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250521">May 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001047">Mr. Himes</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="N000193">Mr. Nunn of Iowa</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Defense Production Act of 1950 to require the establishment of a DPA Registry, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H1C2AE3D0086242E1BD39D017BCE21092" style="OLC"><section id="H1188237BEBC545B89B168C6C3E1E2586" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>CLEAR (Committee Leadership and Enhanced Accountability for Resilience) Defense Production Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H52F101256FA84EA3832B0771F36B9C9E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Improvements to the Defense Production Act Committee</header><subsection id="H4D986F997AD145F39846116C532FD06F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 722 of the Defense Production Act of 1950 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4567">50 U.S.C. 4567</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H4296804528EB427489487E4FB681ED83"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>on the effective use of the priorities and allocations authorities under this Act</quote> and inserting <quote>the effective use of the authorities provided under this Act</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD0522B668E664295B32B1A5EB8AECEB1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text><subparagraph id="H98DDA869A1004F7695B2DBA1563C5A71"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text><clause id="HEC0203A5F0444225914DEE7CC3472DB0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></clause><clause id="HE2B8BFE2E94E4CC1A4377B26E5199101"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="H599A620BB3754C5E93B46D3B7E9C63A5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HAD33D69B32344D2A99E099E3582CAACE" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="H68DC12BD2B2F4D6A8F289D209B1264C4"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the chairperson of the Committee. </text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3E6635114FFD4F39B2F9D0B7CC288B73"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (2) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block id="H54C16EE695E046C7B3724F59AE55D811" style="OLC"><paragraph id="HFD06E89A00B9418BB09814C7E177CD28"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Chairperson of the Committee</header><subparagraph id="HD2E841414B21456689EE6BCDAA09E67F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Chairperson of the Committee shall be a senior, full-time employee of the Department of Commerce classified as a member of the Senior Executive Service, as defined in section 2101a of title 5, United States Code, selected by the Secretary of Commerce. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3E7231F3EBFF4D6780A6E091A13F178C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Reporting authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Chairperson of the Committee shall report directly to the Secretary of Commerce on all matters—</text><clause id="H1A734939F73042B28C9EE91461C34C08"><enum>(i)</enum><text>undertaken under this Act; and</text></clause><clause id="H3A856DF5AC524A92A5E613E93F7CDB0F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>relating to and the Committee.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB990F9EC33E84642B865FA2A442F0223"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Duties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Chairperson of the Committee’s primary job responsibility shall be to lead the Committee and help fulfill the responsibilities of the Committee under this section.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBBCC48C178F843A29FAF882B3B53A91E"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Provision of information</header><text>The Chairperson of the Committee shall provide information to each member of the Committee about—</text><clause id="HBC0745918732444295763F27CC6B7C86"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the frequency of the meetings of the Committee and the expected content of such meetings;</text></clause><clause id="H8D197FCD64DB497FA9418ADC9AFB32DE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the type and quality of information that needs to be shared with the Committee by Federal departments and agencies on the planned and actual use of authorities provided under this Act; and</text></clause><clause id="H085EE752F1534621A2ABE3CDC1F7EEC5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any other information necessary for the President, acting through the Committee, to coordinate and plan for the effective use of the authorities provided under this Act.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H49AA48F9230742288176766F145A75C2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking subsection (c) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H3E0E1432323946DE8F1BADD009AFF54D" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H872CF0CF67744901A212671EE77B2543" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Coordination of the Committee activities</header><paragraph id="H36234CA053894A368BE6D6136FD11E0F" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Commerce shall—</text><subparagraph id="H70527CA9137C478C8B4BC11E730713DD" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>ensure that the Chairperson of the Committee has the necessary staff and resources to carry out this section; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA3C9C27C42D04239B660DB1B0FAB8C83" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall submit funding requests on behalf of the Committee and the Chairperson for inclusion in the President’s budget of the United States;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9C481C6935E84E49B9B85A65648B35AA" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Coordinator</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The members of the Committee shall, not later than 90 days after the enactment of this subsection, designate one member of the Senior Executive Service, as defined in section 2101a of title 5, from each department, agency, or independent establishment of the Federal Government to which the President has delegated authority under this Act, to coordinate with the Chairperson of the Committee as required by the Chairperson on the effective use of the authorities provided under this Act. </text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="HECBE166CA02346FB9D3C01CC0A988D63"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (d)—</text><subparagraph id="HA385F01413B4436480EBD07C2EEB4BFC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking paragraphs (1) and (2) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block id="HC3394326EEF948FA951F7485506A49D0" style="OLC"><paragraph id="HE60BFC86337C40A299B1C840D0E82561"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a review of the use of the authorities provided under this Act by each department, agency, or independent establishment of the Federal Government to which the President has delegated authority under this Act; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE7050C4F73AC41409704EE2ED789D0DC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recommendations about how to effectively use the authorities provided under this Act in a manner that is consistent with the statement of policy set forth in section 2(b).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7ECA96835B9B46CD9049092DF617FFE6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>to support the effective use of the priorities and allocations authorities in this Act</quote> and inserting <quote>to support the effective use of the authorities provided under this Act</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H78ABE36ACF39429DAEAED25FC2B4B921"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by striking <quote>the use of the priorities and allocations authorities in this Act; </quote> and inserting <quote>the effective use of the authorities provided under this Act; and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H701522B7651348729F3EE5E069D0B2F0"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (5) and redesignating paragraph (6) as paragraph (5).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9302FEC704BE4485B59B9E9F738A686D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Comptroller general report</header><paragraph id="HBEFD8A400C504787A3C06EC528F0DCCD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this section, the Comptroller General of the United States shall issue a report to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing and Urban Affairs of the Senate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7DFE01633F9A4057A716B34B7ECE434D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report required under paragraph (1) shall include—</text><subparagraph id="H83EE53A97E8B4FE9BF38F371B487CF7D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an assessment of the quality of the coordination and planning relating to the effective use of the authorities provided under the Defense Production Act of 1950 completed by the Committee under section 722 of the Defense Production Act of 1950;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1D1344B35C6B45BBAE768124E2071870"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a review of the information provided by the Chairperson of the Committee to members of the Committee under section 722(b)(2) of the Defense Production Act of 1950;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H474F34BEA9624D96B20043DB60E8B543"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an identification of the authorities provided under the Defense Production Act of 1950 that may need additional attention from the Committee established under section 722 of the Defense Production Act of 1950; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCDFD86763E0C45C7964F84AD47F0AD5E"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other recommendations relating to how the Committee established under section 722 of the Defense Production Act of 1950 could improve its coordination and planning.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H39646321CD8645C2BE470CDBBA1F24EF"><enum>3.</enum><header>Transparency registry of uses of DPA authorities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title VII of the of the Defense Production Act of 1950 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4501">50 U.S.C. 4501 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HB64F07DAD66447D78264EEB8F5FA5F1B" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="H2F436FEB65D9422B88A8A08B0EE776F5"><enum>724.</enum><header>Registry of uses of DPA authorities</header><subsection id="H78B0E16CF8274A3F8BAB3DCB00515561"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Secretary of Commerce, acting through the Chairperson of the Defense Production Act Committee established under section 722 of this Act, shall, not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this section, establish a secure, electronic database that can include records about how each authority under this Act is used by the Federal Government (in this section referred to as the <quote>DPA Registry</quote>).</text></subsection><subsection id="HF820D74F02CA4FD9BDF1D5260D68C2B6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The DPA Registry established by the Secretary of Commerce under subsection (a) shall—</text><paragraph id="H4ADE067C4F6A487D836494C06181BCE4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identify each use of an authority provided under this Act by any Federal agency on or after the date that is 1 year before the date of the enactment of this section; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H59CF7EF050EC41C88C58F8150AB4E826"><enum>(2)</enum><text>describe, with respect to each use identified under paragraph (1)—</text><subparagraph id="HA9566FA826FE444D8F2867A89614BE9A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>why the authority was used; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4BF20A1A5E414397BE99129F2A5D9DEA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>how the authority was used to accomplish an objective in support of the national defense of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H369638E6DFAF4E26AF47C2B85491FE4B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Addition of information to the DPA Registry</header><paragraph id="H9E8D067877B346EB97E51C8EE06CAB44"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The head of each Federal agency that uses the authorities provided under this Act shall, not later than 180 days after the establishment of the DPA database under subsection (a), enter any data into the DPA database that the Chairperson of the Defense Production Act Committee may require, including information about each use of an authority provided under the Act by the Federal agency on or after the date that is 1 year before the date of the enactment of this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD3005CCCFED24BD3957382A022DF83AE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Update</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The head of each Federal agency that uses the authorities provided under this Act shall, each quarter, update the information in the DPA registry and submit any new information that the Chairperson of the Defense Production Act Committee may require.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3860E72F3C034825B54AA32685CD4B00"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Security of DPA Registry</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Commerce, acting through the Chairperson of the Defense Production Act Committee, shall ensure that the DPA registry is secure from cyber attacks and manipulation.</text></subsection><subsection id="H806A414CADCB423DB8617B8DA2C51275"><enum>(e)</enum><header>DPA Registry Access</header><paragraph id="H64611419906949B6A190BFC7EA9A9832"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Commerce, acting through the Chairperson of the Defense Production Act Committee, shall ensure that the DPA Registry is structured in such a way to allow access to varying information for different types of users, including—</text><subparagraph id="H351D761C92E04C00B90A5A01A40CB43A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>users employed by or contracted by Federal agencies or the Congress; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3FA77D93B9FA48D7B66FE0F82A541E0C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>users who are members of the public.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9A8F7F712EBE424FA95162AE0D9CE67A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sensitive information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Commerce, acting through the Chairperson of the Defense Production Act Committee, may limit access to certain types of information in the DPA Registry that may be sensitive to the national security of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3C35D96AB3DC4A7CAC53C5176F2AF97E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Promotion of transparency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Commerce, shall in carrying out this section, maximize transparency by providing as much access to information in the DPA Registry as is practicable while preserving the national security of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

