<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HAC457A80FE9A416C8F767232B1E0A93C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2879 IH: Prison Staffing Reform Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2879</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250410">April 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="O000019">Mr. Obernolte</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001112">Mr. Carbajal</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Director of the Bureau of Prisons to conduct a comprehensive review of understaffing across the Bureau, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H168C213E767F44F5AE78E2C3C677E4CD" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HD9CE5A5E653345BCB3B8A9BB265DFA81" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Prison Staffing Reform Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H597CF38D78CD47699384FC0BAA2A6F9B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
<paragraph id="H6D258D440D024F43B061985252CB174F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Bureau of Prisons has 121 institutions located throughout the United States and employs nearly 35,000 employees. Understaffing across the agency jeopardizes the health, safety, and well-being of staff and inmates alike.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H746CE24427164F248E56B3C882DB31E7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Understaffing at Bureau of Prison institutions poses a threat to inmates, who will consequently lack access to lifesaving medical care, efficient review of their casework, sanitary living conditions, access to vital recidivism reduction programming, and protections against abuse or sexual misconduct.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H33F2C1ECD8DC40BB89ECF121E240B9D3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Understaffing at Bureau of Prison institutions will also result in reduced staff safety, escalated workplace abuse, stressful work conditions, enhanced mental and physical health concerns, and unacceptably long work shifts for employees.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD4521A7F28644EBE87856D1A6A515291"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Mandated overtime, misuse of augmentation or reassignment, and overworked employees will reduce prison security and threaten public safety.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="H79E9A679C20D438CBD9FDEE0F7C427AC"><enum>3.</enum><header>Comprehensive review of understaffing across Bureau of Prisons</header>
<subsection id="HA55D7F14F2374BA4879C17D613D64ECB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Review</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of the Bureau of Prisons shall—</text> <paragraph id="H6C0A805246114AC9A3831CA5098E4D73"><enum>(1)</enum><text>complete a thorough external review, in accordance with subsection (b), of staffing across the Bureau of Prisons, as well as the impact of any understaffing on employees, individuals in the custody of the Bureau of Prisons, and overall agency spending; and </text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE4423CCBE72E45DE8714A96CDF1B9308"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submit to the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives, the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate, and the Council of Prison Locals C–33 within the American Federation of Government Employees Organization—</text> <subparagraph id="H656A8231AE304A05A82B74FF1F36409D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a plan for recruiting job applicants, filling vacancies, reducing mandated overtime and misuse of augmentation, and strengthening staffing across the Bureau of Prisons; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H6A7A6C3C008B4EE39E3F0FFD44F06E3B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a guideline for staffing requirements including—</text> <clause id="HEAE89A5DA7394953AA063A8E8DE88EF6"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of correctional officers needed per individual in the custody of the Bureau of Prisons for each housing unit, building, or location where individuals in the custody of the Bureau of Prisons are located; and </text></clause>
<clause id="H32DF253193ED417093CB89E1B00D4780"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of employees, including teachers, counselors, case managers, and medical staff, needed per individual in the custody of the Bureau of Prisons for non-correctional departments, disaggregated by the three primary shifts, security levels, and any special mission within the Bureau of Prisons.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H9D8D7D8F78584BF586A6C48710AE0021"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements of review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The external review completed under subsection (a)(1) shall be conducted by a non-Bureau of Prisons organization, in consultation with—</text>
<paragraph id="HE1FA3BDEE3CB489C889F9219C3E080BA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Council of Prison Locals C–33 within the American Federation of Government Employees Organization;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2FEB7B84E0FA4F34AC3E33B8A7C451E8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>civil rights organizations; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4B5611DC1A91440D85CF5F06D7749199"><enum>(3)</enum><text>organizations focused on reducing recidivism through educational, mental health, and substance use disorder programming.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H639F916D219E411997331283D1180F1C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The review required under subsection (a) shall—</text>
<paragraph id="HE7283AF933EC470F98682AF72F3055ED"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identify and address the effects of understaffing on—</text> <subparagraph id="H171314CD36F44CC7895E29B0AE52E268"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the length of time during which individuals in the custody of the Bureau of Prisons are placed on waiting lists to receive care or programming;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H13B1CE7A9E8742ADA3F876C493FB8FD2"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the availability of medical care for individuals in the custody of the Bureau of Prisons, including substance use disorder treatment programs, mental health programs, and maternal health programs;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAACF6D36A21C4C3F8622D959F27BAC63"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the processing of an individuals’ in the custody of the Bureau of Prisons application for compassionate release, home confinement, and time credits established under title I of the First Step Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/3631">18 U.S.C. 3631 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HDD39DC46CC2A4617A3D0DBBD06A55503"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the availability of teachers, therapists, and other support staff for evidence-based recidivism reduction programs and productive activities (as such terms are defined in section 3635 of title 18, United States Code);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF00CF3AB211342C39AE0F68C4EFD9491"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">adequate protections for staff and individuals in the custody of the Bureau of Prisons against violence, neglect, and sexual misconduct;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H6CBBA46D5A7148E19C4B1236ACB5CB59"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the availability of sanitary and efficient food services;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2A2754B73E5444D58C6B423741123183"><enum>(G)</enum><text>prison security, including the detection of contraband;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HBBE9B6BD3A1740B58AF8D41A9A6C03B9"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the efficient installation of security cameras and plans to remedy deficits in security camera systems;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H816C15E1A32149E19419136240B3FF48"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the conversion of existing analog radio systems to digital radios equipped with the man-down feature;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HED153B7454854B67B06141DA153BC48B"><enum>(J)</enum><text>stressful work environments, mandated overtime, augmentation, and other workplace conditions that may jeopardize employees’ mental and physical health; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4E9910ABEA7A48D096479325DF4ACAFA"><enum>(K)</enum><text>additional costs incurred by the Bureau of Prisons, including costs associated with augmentation and overtime; </text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H545849A7BAD142D8962B8A6DC44D2089"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include an independent review, conducted by the National Academy of Medicine, a nonprofit organization, or other type of organization determined by the Director to be capable of conducting such review, of the adequacy and quality of medical care available to individuals in the custody of the Bureau of Prisons;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H743A4F40E1364D6ABFCFDAF4745DE284"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include a comparison of the various methodologies used by the Bureau of Prisons to assess staffing levels, as well as any possible misalignments and inconsistencies in terminology between these methodologies; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC6AE03F9E68A47579374E1C18E820260"><enum>(4)</enum><text>include a 3-year strategic plan and cost projection for filling existing vacancies and maintaining staffing across the Bureau of Prisons. </text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H8373F8859D384E3EB2339449C7CCF238"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Implementation deadline</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date on which the plan is submitted under subsection (a)(2), and subject to appropriations, the Director of the Bureau of Prisons shall complete implementation of the submitted plan.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H9CF81D4563594CCC96F5A2E1AE399E26"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Annual progress reports</header><text>Beginning 1 year after the date on which the plan is submitted under subsection (a)(2), and each year thereafter until the end of the 3-year period described in subsection (c), the Director of the Bureau of Prisons shall submit to the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives, the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate, and the Council of Prison Locals C–33 within the American Federation of Government Employees Organization a report on the progress of the implementation of the plan submitted under subsection (a)(2).</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

