<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" dms-id="H5A9EF42917F242C59DC74CA05AE2293F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1107 EH: Protecting Veteran Access to Telemedicine Services Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1107</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to authorize certain health care professionals employed by the Department of Veterans Affairs to deliver, distribute, or dispense to veterans certain controlled medications via telemedicine under certain conditions, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HA600A9D1D9104F7FADF0515EC665FFC6" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HB608F759C23A4B5A82269DC81B9EBB76" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting Veteran Access to Telemedicine Services Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HB82842D8681B4C97B58F6CA8F4F9E186"><enum>2.</enum><header>Delivery, distribution, and dispensation of controlled medications by covered Department of Veterans Affairs health care professionals via telemedicine</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subchapter III of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/17">chapter 17</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new section (and conforming the table of sections at the beginning of such chapter accordingly):</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="HA7CCA921C2F44393A2F6F43FB4F070F4" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="H054B2AE3D6FB4FD88E13EAD7FD124AAB"><enum>1730D.</enum><header>Delivery, distribution, and dispensation of controlled medications via telemedicine</header> 
<subsection id="HC981A2A26B204158AE3ACE5990DCFD34"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Pursuant to section 1730C of this title and subject to the requirements of title II of the Comprehensive Drug Abuse Prevention and Control Act of 1970 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/801">21 U.S.C. 801 et seq.</external-xref>), a covered health care professional may use telemedicine to deliver, distribute, or dispense to a patient eligible to receive medical treatment under this chapter a controlled substance that is a prescription drug as determined under the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/301">21 U.S.C. 301 et seq.</external-xref>) regardless of whether such covered health care professional has conducted an in-person medical examination of such patient if—</text> <paragraph id="HD480F396DC144A03930DCB312E1B3C93"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such covered health care professional is—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H3DBA0A5B5FEF45009B519AB4CE3E287C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">authorized to prescribe the basic class of such controlled substance under an active, current, full, and unrestricted State license, registration, or certification; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H84F5A1719173414889CBFC682A7EF078"><enum>(B)</enum><text>acting in the usual course of professional practice; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC739C83D677745018FBDBA0A62FC1775"><enum>(2)</enum><text>such substance is delivered, distributed, or dispensed for a legitimate medical purpose.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HEC633A7327C4435EB94FD8EA1A153F2E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary shall establish in regulations guidelines and a process for the delivery, distribution, and dispensation of a controlled substance pursuant to subsection (a).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HEE745DBD1AAF45A5A8BFECF1D5FDA747"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section may be construed to remove, limit, or otherwise affect any obligation of a covered health care professional under the Controlled Substances Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HEA142ECCC85543B4B68130721AB56AAB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"> In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H4F309E5E4FB9477A8A1DC492C92BB262"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The terms <term>controlled substance</term>, <term>deliver</term>, <term>dispense</term>, and <term>distribute</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 102 of the Controlled Substances Act, respectively.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE63E519D878540F9965E79F64E990B9C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>covered health care professional</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB841B6AE3F91448CA4886AD1C8E3CD92"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a health care professional who—</text> <clause id="H8C5FF5B050974C5F83C5472C31FF5540"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is an employee of the Department appointed under section 7306, 7401, 7405, 7406, or 7408 of this title or under title 5;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H50ED7FCF5ED4473E97E3BEDBB27EC388"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is not a contractor of the Department;</text></clause> <clause id="H258794EA1C4240439714A4E4AD860914" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>is authorized by the Secretary to provide health care under this chapter;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HEFAAB3EA23014E308265CB9802BE78B2"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>is required to adhere to all standards for quality relating to the provision of health care in accordance with applicable policies of the Department; </text></clause> <clause id="HE520F7EC71B140B2AE5DABF7393B9132"><enum>(v)</enum><text>has an active, current, full, and unrestricted license, registration, or certification or meet qualification standards set forth by the Secretary within a specified time frame; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HE3F58B96D6974594AB2BBB01AB718961"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>with respect to a health care profession listed under section 7402(b) of this title, has the qualifications for such profession as set forth by the Secretary; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFA8FE0D5BF2D4338A518ACC884FE73CC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a health professions trainee who—</text> 
<clause id="H6E5B0C07D3484375B36749E084A5BA11"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is appointed under section 7405 of this title; and</text></clause> <clause id="HC7F4EE9D5408436B841BC715B5CAA65C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is under the clinical supervision of a health care professional described in subparagraph (A).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
</legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20250915" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives September 15, 2025.</attestation-date><attestor display="no">Kevin F. McCumber,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation>
<endorsement display="yes"></endorsement>
</bill> 


