<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HAF17B8CBDD0C43239CD65E8674BDD372" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2855 IH: Protecting Medical Research Funding Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2855</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250410">April 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000402">Mr. Kennedy of New York</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="W000788">Ms. Williams of Georgia</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To limit the impoundment, transfer, or reprogramming of Federal funds made available for the National Institutes of Health, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H38D26B494536455CB83672D3A0097D40" style="OLC"><section id="H8D6597009249445E98DFF4AC490D9C12" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting Medical Research Funding Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="HE507DF206C954A19A84B49FFF5F2C573"><enum>2.</enum><header>Limitation on deferral or transfer of Federal funds made available for NIH</header><subsection id="H608D7563F241418A8475A0B7A78C6FA5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, including the Impoundment Control Act of 1974, discretionary appropriations made available for the National Institutes of Health may not be impounded, transferred, or reprogrammed unless specific statutory authority is enacted into law after the date of the enactment of this Act, with express reference to this Act, permitting such an impoundment, transfer, or reprogramming.</text></subsection><subsection id="H9DA2AC4E7FD44D0A9852B595E2FBDE22"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Certification of compliance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall certify, to the Committee on Appropriations and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Appropriations and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor and Pensions of the Senate, that the Secretary and the Director of the National Institutes of Health is in compliance with the requirements of this Act. </text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

