<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4C69310FEF704044B345C24D07E1D6B5" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5739 IH: Italian Heroes and Heritage Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5739</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251010">October 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000619">Mr. Rulli</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit Federal funds from being provided to any State or local government that celebrates Indigenous Peoples Day instead of Columbus Day, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF586D26393384E7D82E7D0E3A8A4688F" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H5564545D176344EB8A701C0ABA957805" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Italian Heroes and Heritage Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HEB9E4BDCD5A54592B67239C048A46047"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings; sense of Congress</header> <subsection id="H0FA110A1BC664D31A4AE6C986EBF9BFB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H3128C4AF47D14112862189614078B831"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Christopher Columbus set sail 533 years ago in 1492 to bravely cross the Atlantic Ocean and discovered new land that would soon after become known as America.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H616209EBC20945699B7BCBBFAC523785"><enum>(2)</enum><text>President Benjamin Harrison founded Christopher Columbus day in 1892 to honor Christopher Columbus’s voyage and the 11 Italian-Americans murdered by a New Orleans lynch mob due to suspicion and hatred of Italian-Americans.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF205117367C74B2CA43E2BC0E931DE3B"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The 11 people brutally murdered were Italian-American cobbler Pietro Monasterio; fruit importer Joseph P. Macheca; fruit peddlers Antonio Bagnetto, Antonio Marchesi, Antonio Scaffidi; rice plantation laborer Charles Traina; stevedores James Caruso and Rocco Geraci; street vendor Emmanuele Polizzi; tinsmith Loreto Comitis; and ward politician Frank Romero.</text></paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="H8E3A60396FE546E9A999E25AB26DF29C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that October 13th should continue to be celebrated nationwide as Christopher Columbus Day, as it has been since 1892, to honor our Italian-American heritage and our forefather, Christopher Columbus, who helped to discover this great land.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H86B743742EFE49E3890BF228D952FC26"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibition on providing Federal funds to local governments that celebrate Indigenous Peoples Day instead of Columbus Day</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, during the 1-year period beginning after October 13, 2025, and each Columbus Day (as described in section 6103(a) of title 5, United States Code) thereafter, no Federal funds may be obligated, expended, or otherwise dispursed to any State or unit of local government that celebrates Indigenous Peoples Day in lieu of Columbus Day.</text> </section> </legis-body></bill>

