<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MDM25I33-WXR-G3-8NV">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2774 IS: Stop Greenlighting Driver Licenses for Illegal Immigrants Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>II</distribution-code>
        <congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session>1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. 2774</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action>
            <action-date date="20250911">September 11, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</sponsor> introduced the following
                bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title>To restrict certain Federal grants for States that grant driver licenses to
            illegal immigrants and fail to share information about criminal aliens with the Federal
            Government.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause">
        <section section-type="section-one" id="S1">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop Greenlighting Driver Licenses for Illegal Immigrants Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section id="id2C0CDCB60FD14EF4A14EFE16AB86A5AE">
            <enum>2.</enum>
            <header>Definitions</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="idAC8ABFF0566843088214B521D06DEC04"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>Edward Byrne Memorial Justice Assistance Grant Program funds</header> <text>The term <term>Edward Byrne Memorial Justice Assistance Grant Program funds</term>—</text>
                <subparagraph id="idA9B84DB26C8E4FA384F45347E8267762">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>means a grant under subpart 1 of part E of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10151">34 U.S.C. 10151 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="idBC5E18BA33394572B658044CCEA60A17">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>includes a grant made directly to a unit of local government within a State under section 505(d) of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10156">34 U.S.C. 10156(d)</external-xref>).</text>
                </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="id1F669CE69C77430A96F7E86C63422BB0">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <header>Immigration enforcement information</header>
 <text>The term <term>immigration enforcement information</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="idB0BD25736F55407CB744611644F46E6D"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>information relating to the citizenship or immigration status of any individual; and</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="id2BE1360C9724459383847710DACD2420">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>the date, time, and location of the release of any individual from detention, jail, or a prison facility.</text>
                </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="id5C2E760E248E49CAA49560DE8CF1DEB5">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
                <header>State</header>
 <text>The term <term>State</term> has the meaning given the term in section 901 of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10251">34 U.S.C. 10251</external-xref>).</text>
            </paragraph>
        </section>
        <section id="id8BE3C7C8A3A741599D96894D25C09B56">
            <enum>3.</enum>
            <header>Edward Byrne Memorial Justice Assistance grant restriction for States that fail
                to comply with Federal immigration law</header>
            <subsection id="idA30FF213F81E45578E0FF8D005ECE3C7">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>Prohibition</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State shall be subject to the penalties described in subsection (b) if the State—</text>
                <paragraph id="id451C89B5DCE74682ABA4F3AC74BB04B6">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">issues a driver license to an individual who does not have proof of United States citizenship or lawful presence in the United States; or</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id5F321290458F4FE1A97DA3F3F966B591">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prohibits or restricts a State or local government entity or official from collecting, sending to, or receiving from the Department of Homeland Security immigration enforcement information.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id161484C2B2AA47418A816EE43FECF5C3">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Penalty</header>
 <text>A State described in subsection (a) shall—</text> <paragraph id="idAB7513A0B72B4F02AF935ABDFA2F6516"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a State described in subsection (a)(1), not later than 30 days after the date on which a driver license is issued to an individual who does not have proof of United States citizenship or lawful presence in the United States, return to the Treasury of the United States any unobligated Edward Byrne Memorial Justice Assistance Grant Program funds;</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id74C35E61FC304214BB9AEB3C840C379D">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a State described in subsection (a)(2), not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, return to the Treasury of the United States any unobligated Edward Byrne Memorial Justice Assistance Grant Program funds; and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="idCF6623BBA2CA4549B31570875025D215">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>be ineligible to receive Edward Byrne Memorial Justice Assistance Grant Program funds until the date on which the State institutes a law or policy that—</text>
                    <subparagraph id="id46A3C012C34E4A76AC1FD662266FE15A">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>prohibits the issuance of a driver license to an individual who does not have proof of United States citizenship or lawful presence in the United States; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id7D14D72F1E914276BE30350B93D39BF2">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>permits a local or State government entity or official to collect and send to and receive from the Department of Homeland Security immigration enforcement information.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
        </section>
    </legis-body>
</bill>

