<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE310383E33C64A209F24A9822C228001" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4019 IH: Gio’s Law</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4019</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250617">June 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000602">Ms. Gillen</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="G000597">Mr. Garbarino</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to establish a grant program for provide access to, and training on the administration of, epinephrine products for law enforcement officers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H2AF1F810EFB64F0AA927E9C3D8CF943E" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HE6D5CAE3345F4CA2AF23152235A88DEC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as <quote><short-title>Gio’s Law</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HE4CE90CC0A834361BC80579F2E29539A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Law Enforcement Access to Emergency Epinephrine Grant Program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10101">34 U.S.C. 10101 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HA773CCE2BC75421AA43264112A6E7227" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <part id="H6545CED5B8AB494E918EEB52CD7ADB16"><enum>PP</enum><header>Law Enforcement Access to Emergency Epinephrine Grant Program</header> <section id="H34211ECF107B415F96F26D821131E223"><enum>3061.</enum><header>Grant authorization</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Attorney General is authorized to make grants under this part to States and units of local government to—</text> 
<paragraph id="H9F8574AEA4E84486A97D5453699C56C7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>purchase epinephrine products for use by State, local, and tribal law enforcement agencies;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H79FF7580755D406E9A7011B228A59BC3"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">train State, local, and tribal law enforcement officers, in accordance with the curricula developed or identified under section 3062.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H2EB17000FC044085828CB6473F794966"><enum>3062.</enum><header>Standardized training</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this part, the Attorney General shall develop a training curricula, or identify effective existing training curricula, to train law enforcement officer to—</text> 
<paragraph id="HE4141070F9AF473AABCA989C2CE0FE11"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recognize the symptoms of an anaphylactic reaction; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA8E4405B82A84E28BE77E6D022CBD692"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">correctly administer epinephrine products to any individual reasonably believed to be having an anaphylactic reaction.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HF592285D92074EE7AED6C80E8EFA2C5E"><enum>3063.</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The chief executive of a State or unit of local government seeking a grant under this part shall submit to the Attorney General an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Attorney General may reasonably require, including a certification of the State attorney general of the State, or the State in which the unit of local government is located, that a law enforcement officer who is authorized in that jurisdiction to administer epinephrine products to any individual reasonably believed to be having an anaphylactic reaction is protected from civil liability arising from administering such a product.</text></section> <section id="H93059AA142974F7C847248B5188FD476"><enum>3064.</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this part, the term <term>epinephrine product</term> means—</text> 
<paragraph id="H11B6C7B4476C458584F567C58CDC6A24"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an epinephrine auto-injector; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H004E842407C74290B6D970B833AE199A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a product that facilitates the administration of epinephrine other than by injection.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H169414D1AC9348D7A5E5598B7397604C"><enum>3065.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated $25,000,000 to carry out this part for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030.</text></section></part><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section id="H2716F10417E648C89066E7746325D7E5"><enum>3.</enum><header>Report on administration of epinephrine by law enforcement officers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">On an annual basis, the Attorney General, acting through the Director of the Bureau of Justice Statistics, shall submit to Congress and make publicly available, data on the frequency of the administration of epinephrine products (as such term is defined in section 3064 of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968) by Federal, State, local, and tribal law enforcement officers.</text></section> 
<section id="HCD38441CA5C142F5B7A161A08E478970">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <header>Interagency Public Awareness and Outreach Campaign</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline"> Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General, in collaboration with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, shall design and implement a public awareness campaign to educate members of the public about—</text>
      <paragraph id="H0212884D5ABA4B67840732E7CE76BFFD">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>the symptoms of an anaphylactic reaction; and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HB02C05BDAB01498F8D4C11245DF3DA22"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>the role of law enforcement officers and first responders in administering epinephrine products.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section> 
</legis-body></bill>

