<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="HAD3BD9F1F782451F8712DC942E89B497" key="H">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3826 IH: Expanding Access to Diabetes Self-Management Training Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3826</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20250606">June 6, 2025</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001216">Ms. Schrier</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="B001257">Mr. Bilirakis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to improve access to diabetes outpatient self-management training services, to require the Center for Medicare and Medicaid Innovation to test the provision of virtual diabetes outpatient self-management training services, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H03D4E6E10D874EDBB976B0E522BFE47F"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H792A2B085C754875B595B7943199FF9A"> <enum>1.</enum> <header>Short title</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Expanding Access to Diabetes Self-Management Training Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="H6CCFC04B1EB9463BBB27236FA553AFB7"> <enum>2.</enum> <header>Improving access to diabetes outpatient self-management training services</header> <subsection id="HED1D2983077B40AEB9ACC441B2C06BA8"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text>Section 1861(qq) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x(qq)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H32335A42F882499EAE1F7D20F038988F"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>in paragraph (1)—</text> <subparagraph id="H8DC7750F09B14025BC8223A6178803E3"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>by striking <quote>the Secretary determines appropriate</quote> and inserting <quote>specified in paragraph (3)</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBDA710931BB1403F998DDAFC8019AB93"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>by striking <quote>the physician who is managing the individual's diabetic condition</quote> and inserting <quote>a physician or qualified nonphysician practitioner</quote>;</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H33393A742C6A47BF83D6FE90C304FB09"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>in paragraph (2)(B), by striking <quote>paragraph</quote> and inserting <quote>subparagraph</quote>; and</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBE950A573C1F42DB93A16E5B420CBE3B"> <enum>(3)</enum> <text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB2177E89CD0E45EE96EECB5BA32937EE"> <paragraph id="H1A620EB9290B49F2958D3D784C9BDEF9" indent="up1"> <enum>(3)(A)</enum> <text>For purposes of paragraph (1) and subject to subparagraph (B), the times specified in this paragraph are the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H07302A2E8823491D83C08011351DB320"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>An initial 10 hours of individual or group educational and training services to remain available until used.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDB0D1D14460A46F4AC55BF1F935CB4FF"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>An additional 2 hours of individual or group educational and training services each year, beginning with the year in which the initial 10 hours described in subparagraph (A) are completed.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE0691063FED44472A1E5A9530BED85D3"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall not limit the quantity or duration of educational and training services furnished by a certified provider to an individual with diabetes if such services are deemed medically necessary by a physician or qualified non-physician practitioner.</text> </paragraph> <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block> </quoted-block> </paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="H942C791937454F538B0233C04E8B117E"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Medical nutrition therapy services</header> <text>Section 1861(s)(2)(V) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x(s)(2)(V)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H2D79EC1533F74A339AC725549682E433"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>by striking clause (i);</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H439FA10102224514BF14ECF16BE6A787"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>by redesignating clauses (ii) and (iii) as clauses (i) and (ii), respectively; and</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H922AFA12B0E24D259C85F98A3D43C44F"> <enum>(3)</enum> <text>in clause (ii), as so redesignated, by striking <quote>after consideration of</quote> and inserting <quote>consistent with</quote>.</text> </paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="H4D41BE88080F40AD85EBA009155DE254"> <enum>(c)</enum> <header>Cost-Sharing</header> <text>Section 1833 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395l">42 U.S.C. 1395l</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H532F7F3E665E4C0083ECB3994DB507EE"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>in subsection (a)(1)—</text> <subparagraph id="H4161AB33F6474C9F83EFB0571054EC0B"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>by striking <quote>and (HH)</quote> and inserting <quote>(HH)</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF4F6044607BD41AE82BD850F1C3E2052"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>by inserting the following before the semicolon at the end: <quote>and (II) with respect to diabetes outpatient self-management training services (as defined in section 1861(qq)), the amount paid shall be 100 percent of the lesser of the actual charge for the services or the amount determined under the fee schedule that applies to such services under this part;</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H8A88FA91195243F2918BF5BD9F1B056C"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>in subsection (b), in the first sentence—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H3CCF3CDBB55B412A868CFDC38B734F83"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>by striking <quote>, and (13)</quote> and inserting <quote>(13)</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6E1C78ECB26740C884B7A896661448B5"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>by striking <quote>1861(n)..</quote>and inserting <quote>1861(n), and (14) such deductible shall not apply with respect to diabetes outpatient self-management training services (as defined in section 1861(qq))</quote>.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H5A51D4B72EDD44C1BE60740AD423C0CA"> <enum>(d)</enum> <header>Application</header> <text>The amendments made by this section shall apply with respect to items and services furnished on or after January 1, 2027.</text> </subsection> </section> <section id="H07F06226E6144D0D8C73252A83667E2A"> <enum>3.</enum> <header>CMI testing of providing virtual diabetes outpatient self-management training services</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1115A of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1315a">42 U.S.C. 1315a</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HC338ABE91AB44FB6BE5A12E0EBAACAC9"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>in subsection (b)(2)(A), by adding at the end the following new sentence: “The models selected under this subparagraph shall include the testing of the model described in subsection (h).”; and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HC1DB684B2E3F49138C740735D0FCBA60"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H1884B364169B420E942EFCA4B41A3918" display-inline="no-display-inline" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="H9175BAB0E2624067BDEEB852D72B17E0"> <enum>(h)</enum> <header>Testing of providing virtual diabetes outpatient self-Management training services</header> 
<paragraph id="H32D1F27D5EC54ADDA64E7036711CFB9D"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>Establishment</header> <text>Not later than January 1, 2026, the Secretary shall implement a model to test the impact of providing coverage under title XVIII for virtual diabetes outpatient self-management training services furnished to applicable beneficiaries with respect to improved health outcomes for such applicable beneficiaries and reduced expenditures under such title XVIII.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HD791917717FF4AB286116EC9B9C48781"> <enum>(2)</enum> <header>Model design</header> <subparagraph id="H36C196DD62F3452CA631286D1AC32F2B"> <enum>(A)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text>The Secretary shall design the model under this subsection in such a manner to allow for the evaluation of demographic characteristics of applicable beneficiaries participating in such model and the extent to which such model accomplishes the following purposes:</text> 
<clause id="HC386F67CD8604B3AAAF74B900AB576B5"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>Improvement in health outcomes with respect to the diabetic conditions, including by reducing A1c levels.</text> </clause> <clause id="H979237A3B7AF4938B6E857D74AEBE463"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>Reduced hospitalizations due to diabetic-related complications.</text> </clause> 
<clause id="HE12079CED14441C1834684C0950DA443"> <enum>(iii)</enum> <text>Increased utilization of diabetes outpatient self-management training services as evidenced by, for example, Medicare beneficiary participation and utilization of covered hours during the first year and subsequent years or use of diabetes outpatient self-management training services in rural and underserved communities.</text> </clause> <clause id="HBA8871B3615F48D1B5A31BD54329D6B3"> <enum>(iv)</enum> <text>Improved medication adherence.</text> </clause> 
<clause id="H37327C8D548849099BD936B980325C98"> <enum>(v)</enum> <text>Reduced expenditures under this title attributable to the model.</text> </clause> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF78AE1F1416248CF99F9591C30CC0DE2"> <enum>(B)</enum> <header>Consultation</header> <text>In designing the model under this subsection, the Secretary shall, not later than 3 months after the date of the enactment of this subsection, consult with stakeholders in the field of diabetes care and education, clinicians in the primary care community, experts in digital health, and beneficiary groups.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H54A6D85B2CAA475A9D49DBE7318D4ECB"> <enum>(3)</enum> <header>Definitions</header> <text>In this subsection:</text> <subparagraph id="H114C3A5717F84D739BF6ACF842BE6908"> <enum>(A)</enum> <header>Applicable beneficiary</header> <text>The term <term>applicable beneficiary</term> means an individual with diabetes as described in section 1861(qq).</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H139AF7DC095A4900B8CFC18046D9E03C"> <enum>(B)</enum> <header>Qualified web-based program</header> <text>The term <term>qualified web-based program</term> means a web-based program—</text> <clause id="H74A91D608E2848FDBD5D221A7C79167D"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>designed to furnish educational and training services to an individual with diabetes to ensure therapy compliance with respect to the individual’s diabetic condition or to provide the individual with necessary skills and knowledge (including skills related to the self-administration of injectable drugs) to participate in the individual’s management of such condition; and</text> </clause> 
<clause id="H61C343C98AF744A5B04B4E57CA2D8F3C"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>that meets the quality standards described in section 1861(qq)(2)(B).</text> </clause> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC1ADED5C8EC64D1187879F249D4F6029" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <enum>(C)</enum> <header>Virtual diabetes outpatient self-management training services</header> <text>The term <term>virtual diabetes outpatient self-management training services</term> means any diabetes outpatient self-management training services (as defined in section 1861(qq)) furnished by a qualified web-based program for synchronous or asynchronous diabetes outpatient self-management training services.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> </subsection> <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block> </quoted-block> </paragraph> </section> 
</legis-body>
</bill>

