<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HAFC0993C97724A83BEC7AFC054DD2C8E" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 155 IH: Reaffirming the United States unwavering support for Ukraine’s sovereignty, independence, and territorial integrity as Russia’s illegal full-scale invasion of Ukraine hits its third year.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 155</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250224">February 24, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000874">Mr. Hoyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001296">Mr. Boyle of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000631">Ms. Dean of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001121">Mr. Crow</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Reaffirming the United States unwavering support for Ukraine’s sovereignty, independence, and territorial integrity as Russia’s illegal full-scale invasion of Ukraine hits its third year.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, on February 24, 2022, Russia launched an unprovoked and brutal full-scale invasion of Ukraine, violating Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity and subjecting the nation to acts of aggression that have threatened its independence and security;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, for three years, the people of Ukraine have demonstrated extraordinary resilience, courage, and determination despite relentless attacks on their homes, communities, sovereignty, and fundamental freedoms;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in the three years since the invasion began, Russia has engaged in widespread and systematic war crimes, including—</text><paragraph id="H67B6E5B702A8483697F307431D9161E1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>deliberate targeting of, including strikes on, residential buildings, schools, hospitals, and evacuation corridors; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2496F62E74BB41F7B66B5082E6A854AB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the forced deportation and kidnaping of at least 19,000 Ukrainian children to Russian-controlled territories in a deliberate attempt to erase Ukrainian identity; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H37D030DDDDD040FCB9629AF828AB6C4D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the destruction of Ukraine’s agricultural and energy infrastructure in an effort to create humanitarian crises and disrupt global food supply chains; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2EBA71369ADF4843B7EABAC97F3A5E66"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the use of torture, extrajudicial killings, and mass graves in occupied Ukrainian territories, as documented by the United Nations, the International Criminal Court, and leading human rights organizations;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, despite these atrocities, the people of Ukraine remain unyielding, proving that even in the face of relentless bombardment and unspeakable suffering, their spirit and commitment to self-determination will never be extinguished;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Russian Federation, despite its overwhelming use of force, has suffered catastrophic military losses, with estimates of over 800,000 killed, demonstrating that Putin’s war of conquest has become both a strategic failure and a humanitarian disaster for Russia;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Ukraine, despite facing an opponent with a far larger population, army, and military arsenal, continues to fight courageously for its sovereignty, proving that its resilience and determination remain unshaken;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Russia’s war has also destabilized global security, undermining the principles of sovereignty and nonaggression and emboldening authoritarian regimes seeking to redraw international borders by force; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States, North Atlantic Treaty Organization, the European Union, and allied nations have demonstrated historic unity in their support for Ukraine: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H5107D9B271B74679908384394723E94E"><section id="HB577983C102441E0AB52A67A30DBD07E" section-type="undesignated-section" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="HB9ED0D90AC504A6789B9DBEAF8D206DB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognizes that discussions surrounding the future of Ukraine must include Ukraine;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE22C5D9F646D4C12ACDDB375B84F0449"><enum>(2)</enum><text>condemns in the strongest possible terms the Russian Federation’s ongoing war crimes, its targeted destruction of Ukrainian society, and its blatant violations of international law;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0949631896A74354A8D1B4685D32C9D1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>reaffirms the United States commitment to the people of Ukraine and the principles of sovereignty, independence, and territorial integrity within internationally recognized borders;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD25D020D61354528967B0823709B5BD2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>urges the immediate and unconditional withdrawal of all Russian forces from Ukrainian territory, including Crimea and the Donbas, and affirms that any negotiations must be based on Ukraine’s sovereignty, not dictated by Russian ultimatums;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA26AD6E94AC6447FB80565CEAD97DA3A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>demands international institutions take decisive action to ensure the safe return of at least 19,000 kidnaped Ukrainian children, recognizing that their forced deportation is a war crime and an act of genocide under international law;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8CDB4CD6C70343D783323E2F4C1E3646"><enum>(6)</enum><text>supports the continued prosecution of Vladimir Putin and Russian political and military leaders for war crimes, crimes against humanity, and genocide, reinforcing that those who orchestrate such atrocities must be held accountable before the world; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD5155FA1D40C4FD897DFC9BE936061FE"><enum>(7)</enum><text>stresses that any sustainable peace deal must be built with Ukraine and our European allies at the table.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

