<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H55B430DEF6B24D898D20B02551C618BF" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2880 IH: To provide employment protections for, and reinstatement of, certain probationary Federal career employees, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2880</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250410">April 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="O000176">Mr. Olszewski</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000598">Mr. Garcia of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001103">Mr. Hernández</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000874">Mr. Hoyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="I000058">Mr. Ivey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000607">Mr. Liccardo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="U000040">Ms. Underwood</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000788">Ms. Williams of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000301">Ms. Elfreth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000110">Mr. Fields</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001066">Mr. Horsford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000309">Mr. Jackson of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000310">Ms. Johnson of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000402">Mr. Kennedy of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Lieu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000172">Ms. Ocasio-Cortez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000606">Mr. Raskin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000491">Mr. Tran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001324">Mr. Bell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001220">Mr. McGarvey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001157">Mr. David Scott of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001211">Mr. Stanton</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Veterans' Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide employment protections for, and reinstatement of, certain probationary Federal career employees, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HAB1830C915CC422D91B2763CF12C45A3" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HDAF73BE04057435D8E315D2566AACA77" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Employment protections and reinstatement of probationary career Federal employees</header> 
<subsection id="HB421B494C94C43CDA7F5F52809CBDB9A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Due process protections</header> 
<paragraph id="H29CD5572DDC949A4AEB94FEC71BDF942"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any Federal employee who is promoted to a position in the competitive service, a career position in the excepted service, or to a career appointee position in the Senior Executive Service and, after such promotion, is serving under a probationary or trial period shall be deemed to be covered by, and subject to the requirements of suchapter II or subchapter V (as the case may be) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/75">chapter 75</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5B316B2B580B45ED83CFE6889C2A78EF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>VA employees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any Federal employee who is promoted to a position at the Department of Veterans Affairs and, after such promotion, is serving under a probationary or trial period shall be deemed to be covered by, and subject to the requirements of, section 714 of title 38, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1F688213BEEE4825AEF4FFD0D220F69A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reinstatement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any individual who was a Federal employee serving under a probationary or trial status after a promotion and who was removed from the competitive service, a career position in the excepted service, or a career appointee position in the Senior Executive Service during the period beginning on January 20, 2025, and ending on the date of the enactment of this Act shall, at the election of the individual, be reinstated to the same position or an equivalent position with backpay in accordance with section 5596 of title 5, United States Code.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H126059501AA34E1E8FCC288A78E7F308"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Subsection (a) shall not apply to any individual promoted to a political position and subsection (b) shall not apply to any individual removed from a political position.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4717BF48C81F4D6CB3D9BB1D87B3E992"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text> <paragraph id="H9C0A8A84DCA94729996786A53F971E62"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <quote>career appointee</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 3132(a) of title 5, United States Code;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF46191FF19284DA1B5D76FAB0186238A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the terms <quote>civil service</quote>, <quote>competitive service</quote>, and <quote>excepted service</quote> have the meaning given those terms in section 2101, 2102, and 2103, respectively, of such title; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD2023F10E6DC4F1F86B5CDD55D708FF3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <quote>political position</quote> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H6C3D48922E75462CA2C00C56BC01FE47"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a position described under sections 5312 through 5316 of such title 5 (relating to the Executive Schedule);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8C05459C4AE64C1483251A8BD35023F3"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a noncareer appointee (as that term is defined in such section 3132(a)); or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1F5A94D86229407191F8DF282A7ECF82"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a position in the executive branch of the Government of a confidential or policy-determining character under schedule C of subpart C of part 213 of title 5, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

