<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H90BF3BB4D6A54B2CBF32BC0C2F3A1C89" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 660 IH: Women Involuntarily Separated Earning Remittance Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 660</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250123">January 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="H001085">Ms. Houlahan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="O000173">Ms. Omar</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Veterans' Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs and the Secretary of Defense to carry out programs to provide to certain veterans who are women a compensation benefit and an upgrade to the discharge status of such veterans, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H5D24797BC4234204917CD3204C78E318" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H8609D030F43647AF972E9426351A63D3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Women Involuntarily Separated Earning Remittance Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>WISER Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HD40868B9CD7F41139108F3ADBD213163"><enum>2.</enum><header>Programs to provide compensation benefit and discharge status upgrades for certain veterans who are women discharged pursuant to Executive Order 10240</header> <subsection id="H4FDA1EC03D5B4611BD4C0B6B0641ABAD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Discharge status upgrade program</header> <paragraph id="HC11127C869AA43B288E9B88C841C1C2B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to the availability of amounts made available in advance in appropriations Acts, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, in coordination with the Secretary of Defense, shall establish and carry out a program to, subject to the eligibility criteria under subsection (c) and conditions to be prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, upgrade the discharge status of covered veterans.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA17F6D9B6F34473689A15116CABD57F6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applications</header><text>A covered veteran desiring to participate in such program shall submit to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs and the Secretary of Defense an application in such form, at such time, and containing such information and assurances as such Secretaries determine appropriate.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H474C62F41A6C4F36A1ED836BDFF3E6C4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Treatment of certain covered veterans</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to the provision of benefits under the laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, such Secretary shall treat a covered veteran who receives a discharge status upgrade pursuant to such program as if such covered veteran completed the duty to which such covered veteran was assigned at the time such covered veteran was separated from active military, naval, air, or space service.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HDFBA8996A24A4B358E934B586470AF90" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Compensation benefit program</header> 
<paragraph id="H22D744CCCA4F4A80A60F53EE226BB17B" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Defense shall establish and carry out a program to provide to covered veterans, subject to the eligibility criteria under subsection (c) and paragraph (2), a one-time compensation benefit in the amount of $25,000.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6D631A9EDC654110B38FE3B6D41C6881" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Surviving spouse eligibility</header><text>If a covered veteran who satisfies the eligibility criteria under subsection (c) dies after the date of the enactment of this Act, the surviving spouse of such covered veteran shall be eligible for participation in the program under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF11E9432015E4E5BA65AFA3A9EF560C5" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Applications</header><text>A covered veteran, or the surviving spouse of a covered veteran, desiring to participate in such program shall submit to the Secretary of Defense an application in such form, at such time, and containing such information and assurances as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEC1DF5726BD843E7924AF34770E61A33" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of Defense such sums as may be necessary to carry out this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB615B1DB3D38422FA0752694E11BF71C" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligibility criteria</header> 
<paragraph id="H54E50744A65B4F918FC7971638306BC3" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Irrebuttable presumption</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is an irrebuttable presumption of eligibility for participation in the programs under subsections (a) and (b) for a covered veteran who was involuntarily separated from active military, naval, air, or space service pursuant to Executive Order 10240.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H41430CECA4CE431B90102D1B9C0D987A" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rebuttable presumptions</header><text>There is a rebuttable presumption for eligibility for participation in such programs for a covered veteran who—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HC21B05B713CE4973A2AFF1EDC5D2D994" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">gave birth to a child, obtained legal or physical custody of a child, or adopted a child during the 10-month period beginning after the date the veteran was separated from active military, naval, air, or space service; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H28B214E2D89E4B43B1FA9969BC1A0DF4" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>experienced an incomplete pregnancy (including due to an abortion or miscarriage) during such 10-month period.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9D27CB855CE14F7B9102587CC88CF367"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HC1534449B7584617A17753BC2D03A1B9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <quote>active military, naval, air, or space service</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 101 of title 10, United States Code.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6FEF53084137479A8A00C1F0BCAE5813"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <quote>covered veteran</quote> means a veteran who—</text> <subparagraph id="HA010B1521751479D812C6DA824DC5482"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is a woman; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA9CFE51C5CD0450498ECA4CD18DEC0FC"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">performed active military, naval, air, or space service during the period beginning on April 27, 1951 and ending on February 23, 1976.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

