<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-WAL25405-R0Y-5K-F1N"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 218 IS: Condemning any acceptance of Presidential aircraft, or any other substantial gift, from a foreign government.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 218</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250513">May 13, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S353">Mr. Schatz</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S270">Mr. Schumer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S364">Mr. Murphy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S414">Mr. Ossoff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S313">Mr. Sanders</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S229">Mrs. Murray</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S402">Ms. Rosen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S327">Mr. Warner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S275">Ms. Cantwell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S330">Mr. Bennet</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S380">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S430">Ms. Blunt Rochester</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S436">Ms. Slotkin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S363">Mr. King</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S428">Ms. Alsobrooks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S426">Mr. Kim</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S406">Mr. Kelly</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Condemning any acceptance of Presidential aircraft, or any other substantial gift, from a foreign government.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the aircraft commonly referred to as <quote>Air Force One</quote> is a symbol of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Air Force One is one of the most recognizable symbols of the Office of the President of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Air Force One is equipped with some of the most sensitive technologies designed to transmit some of the most highly classified national security information of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the acceptance of Presidential aircraft from a foreign government— </text><paragraph id="idffc67bd043024795b74e9d39bc8ba111"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">constitutes a substantial gift; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide9bf9de810d04e1ebc165a95483da2dd"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">poses counter-intelligence and other national security concerns;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the acceptance of a substantial gift from a foreign government could unduly influence the foreign policies of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the acceptance of Presidential aircraft from a foreign government would establish a concerning precedent for the acceptance of substantial gifts from foreign governments without the consent of Congress;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Foreign Emoluments Clause contained in clause 8 of section 9 of article I of the Constitution of the United States states that no present, emolument, office, or title, of any kind, may be accepted by the President of the United States from a king, prince, or foreign state without the consent of Congress;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the President of the United States has a constitutional and statutory obligation to uphold the public trust; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the violation of the Foreign Emoluments Clause of the Constitution of the United States undermines public trust and the integrity of public office in the United States: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate— </text><paragraph id="id76b641fce64c4533bb6cdf5474930e6e"><enum>(1)</enum><text>condemns any acceptance of a Presidential aircraft, or any other substantial gift, from a foreign government as a grave national security threat to the Office of the President; </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id600c9c68afd643a8a7ccec0718406577"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">demands that any such gift may only be accepted by the President with the explicit consent of Congress; </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9d8b2d1bc130497c8f64ef131cf8a6e0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>urges the executive branch to reject compromising the national security of the United States by operating an aircraft not built under the security specifications or supervision of the Department of Defense as Air Force One; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3da8ed13535f453ab2e07c85a2d841f6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>condemns any acceptance of a Presidential aircraft, or any other substantial gift, from a foreign government if such acceptance violates any law. </text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

