<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Laid-on-Table-House" public-private="public" dms-id="H1BC9CC27F13B43A49DA10C8847B31E81" key="H" resolution-type="house-resolution"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 537 : Impeaching Donald J. Trump, President of the United States, for high crimes and misdemeanors.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 537</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250624">June 24, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Green of Texas</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>; which was laid on the table</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Impeaching Donald J. Trump, President of the United States, for high crimes and misdemeanors.</official-title></form><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H0467B49C3D80408FA052799AD01E321B"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HC7FE7D7983C94D1BA56168F0CD448E65"><enum/><text>That Donald J. Trump, President of the United States, is impeached for high crimes and misdemeanors, and that the following articles of impeachment be exhibited to the Senate: </text><subsection id="HC7FE7D7983C94D1BA56168F0CD448E64"><enum/><text> Articles of impeachment exhibited by the House of Representatives of the United States of America in the name of itself and of the people of the United States of America, against Donald J. Trump, President of the United States of America, in maintenance and support of its impeachment against him for high crimes and misdemeanors. </text></subsection></section><section section-type="undesignated-section" id="HC7FE7D7983C94D1BA56168F0CD448E54"> <enum/> <header>Article I: Abuse of Presidential Powers by Disregarding the Separation of Powers—Devolving American Democracy into Authoritarianism by Unconstitutionally Usurping Congress’s Power to Declare War</header> <subsection id="HC7FE7D7983C94D1BA56168F0CD448E34"> <enum/> <text>In his conduct of the office of President of the United States, Donald J. Trump, in violation of his constitutional oath faithfully to execute the office of President of the United States and, to the best of his ability, preserve, protect, and defend the Constitution of the United States, and in violation of his constitutional duty to take care that the laws be faithfully executed, abused the powers of the presidency when he disregarded the doctrine of separation of powers by usurping Congress’s power to declare war and ordered the United States military to bomb another country without the constitutionally-mandated congressional authorization or notice to Congress—cognizant of the fact that should another country’s military bomb a facility within the United States of America, it would be a de facto declaration of war against the United States of America. </text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HC7FE7D7983C94D1BA56168F0CD448E24">
        <enum/>
 <text>On June 12, 2025, the State of Israel initiated attacks on Iran, ostensibly to target sites and individuals of importance to Iran’s nuclear program. Iran retaliated, and the conflict has escalated between Israel and Iran, though at no point did Iran pose any imminent threat to the United States. </text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HC7FE7D7983C94D1BA56168F0CD448E14">
        <enum/>
 <text>On June 21, 2025, President Trump announced “successful” attacks on three nuclear sites in Iran: Fordow, Natanz, and Estahan via his social media network, Truth Social. President Trump failed to seek prior congressionally-mandated authorization for the use of military force. Congressional leaders were not appropriately briefed or notified of the attack plans despite foreign leaders being given advance notice of the planned U.S. military action. </text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HC7FE7D7983C94D1BA56168F0CD448E85">
        <enum/>
 <text>President Trump’s unilateral, unprovoked use of force without congressional authorization or notice constitutes an abuse of power when there was no imminent threat to the United States, which facilitates the devolution of American democracy into authoritarianism, with an authoritarian president who has instigated an attack on the United States Capitol, denied persons due process of the law, and called for the impeachment of Federal judges who ruled against him—making Donald J. Trump a threat to American democracy. </text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HC8FE7D7983C94D1BA56168F0CD448E65">
        <enum/>
 <text>Article I, Section 8, Clause 11 of the United States Constitution grants Congress the sole power to declare war: “[The Congress shall have the Power...] To declare War...” At the time, the Framers of the Constitution emphasized the goal of limiting the monarchical power of any single individual person to take a country to war over personal whims and preferences—no constitutional exception exists for a successful military action. </text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HC2FE7D7983C94D1BA56168F0CD448E65">
        <enum/>
 <text>In starting his illegal and unconstitutional war with Iran without the constitutionally-mandated consent of Congress or appropriate notice to Congress, President Trump acted in direct violation of the War Powers Clause of the Constitution. President Trump has devolved and continues to devolve American democracy into authoritarianism by disregarding the separation of powers and now, usurping congressional war powers. </text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H1AC095382EBD4E7A8E1DA15878085C48">
        <enum/>
 <text>In all of this, Donald J. Trump has abused the powers of the presidency in a manner contrary to his trust as President, has become a threat to American democracy, subverted our constitutional government, and devolved democracy into authoritarianism, to the great prejudice of the cause of law and justice, and to the manifest injury of the people of the United States. </text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HC7FE7D7983C84D1BA57168F0CD448E65">
        <enum/>
 <text>Wherefore Donald J. Trump, by such conduct, warrants impeachment and trial, and removal from office. </text>
      </subsection>
    </section></resolution-body></resolution>


