<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H530DC50BC1CD4FA2A4EA96A070E66530" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5780 IH: Federal Emergency Management Continuity Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5780</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251017">October 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001217">Mr. Moskowitz</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency to continue to obligate and disburse covered funds in the Disaster Relief Fund during a lapse in appropriations, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD6F3B026B2234D36BAE24982363BF4D2" style="OLC"><section id="H217BEEEDDE064D80A60E0955817B274D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Federal Emergency Management Continuity Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H96EA47015B85448BBBC53F022C811946" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Continuity of operations of FEMA</header><subsection id="H5CACB1E8BE6946C8A98AFBB18E708210"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, during a lapse in appropriations to the Federal Emergency Management Agency, the Administrator of the Agency shall continue obligating and disbursing covered funds available in the Disaster Relief Fund for covered programs.</text></subsection><subsection id="H18681ECDF85A4B578DE225E8FB8D2689"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Employees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Employees necessary to carry out disbursements or related program activities under subsection (a) shall be treated as excepted employees under section 1341 of title 31, United States Code (commonly referred to as the ‘Anti-Deficiency Act') and such employees may not be subject to furlough or reduction in force due to the applicable lapse in appropriations.</text></subsection><subsection id="H4D1B6D0EE8AF4E19AC7A7DC9881CF1DE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph id="H57B6668A9A3E49FD849B6A5A7C0A26BA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered funds</header><text>The term <quote>covered funds</quote> means any funds in the Disaster Relief Fund that have been appropriated before the applicable lapse in appropriation and remain available to be expended.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF17DA4CD5DEC4E7E89B32F4D6836384E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered programs</header><text>The term <quote>covered program</quote> means any disaster relief, emergency assistance, and recovery program authorized under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5121">42 U.S.C. 5121 et seq.</external-xref>), including individual assistance under section 408 of such Act, public assistance under sections 403, 406, 407, and 502, and other disbursements and obligations made from the Disaster Relief Fund for programs or activities necessary to protect life and property during a lapse in appropriations.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

