<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" slc-id="S1-HLA25095-Y27-2W-TCV"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 96 ATS: Designating the week of February 24 through February 28, 2025, as “Public Schools Week”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 96</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250225">February 25, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S252">Ms. Collins</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S259">Mr. Reed</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S363">Mr. King</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S388">Ms. Hassan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S432">Mr. Gallego</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S288">Ms. Murkowski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S313">Mr. Sanders</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S422">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S430">Ms. Blunt Rochester</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S380">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S229">Mrs. Murray</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S275">Ms. Cantwell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S354">Ms. Baldwin</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Designating the week of February 24 through February 28, 2025, as <quote>Public Schools Week</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas public education is a significant institution in a 21st-century democracy;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas public schools in the United States educate students about the values and beliefs that hold the individuals of the United States together as a nation;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas public schools prepare young individuals of the United States to contribute to the society, economy, and citizenry of the country;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 87 percent of children in the United States attend public schools;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Federal, State, and local lawmakers should—</text><paragraph id="id6a23aeb59a4041ecbd8a2d268bf7e7fd"><enum>(1)</enum><text>prioritize support for strengthening the public schools of the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5fd2bdc8f4584dcdafa95437738dea15"><enum>(2)</enum><text>empower superintendents, principals, and other school leaders to implement, manage, and lead school districts and schools in partnership with educators, parents, and other local education stakeholders; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9862e737cb8144bdbf0b641b97212abd"><enum>(3)</enum><text>support services and programs that are critical to helping students engage in learning, including counseling, extracurricular activities, and mental health support;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas public schools should foster inclusive, safe, and high-quality environments in which children can learn to think critically, problem solve, and build relationships;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas public schools should provide environments in which all students have the opportunity to succeed beginning in their earliest years, regardless of who a student is or where a student lives;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Congress should support—</text><paragraph id="id24f34ecece0b409386ce5f738c84d2b3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>efforts to advance equal opportunity and excellence in public education;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id68fea581a1b74549ab819442cfd6f341"><enum>(2)</enum><text>efforts to implement evidence-based practices in public education; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9d961b1297414a578ac01165eced2828"><enum>(3)</enum><text>continuous improvements to public education;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas every child should—</text><paragraph id="id1f0d690121504aaa8b0d6ff7f017a2f7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>receive an education that helps the child reach the full potential of the child; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idcb0d14d714b546ec94adebf789c44e82"><enum>(2)</enum><text>attend a school that offers a high-quality educational experience;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Federal funding, in addition to State and local funds, supports the access of students to inviting classrooms, well-prepared educators, and services to support healthy students, including nutrition and afterschool programs;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas teachers, paraprofessionals, and principals should provide students with a well-rounded education and strive to create joy in learning;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas superintendents, principals, other school leaders, teachers, paraprofessionals, and parents make public schools vital components of communities and are working hard to improve educational outcomes for children across the country; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the week of February 24 through February 28, 2025, is an appropriate period to designate as “Public Schools Week”: Now, therefore, be it </text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="S1"><text>That the Senate designates the week of February 24 through February 28, 2025 as <quote>Public Schools Week</quote>.</text></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

