<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA28083043D9B42B4B75CE306A1657BC8" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 545 IH: Supporting the designation of Guam War Survivors Remembrance Day.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 545</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250625">June 25, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001219">Mr. Moylan</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Supporting the designation of Guam War Survivors Remembrance Day.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas Guam is an unincorporated territory of the United States in the Mariana Island chain and has been an integral part of the United States since December 10, 1898;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Guam was invaded by Imperial Japanese forces on December 8, 1941, hours after the attack on Pearl Harbor;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the CHamoru people of Guam endured nearly 3 years of harsh occupation and atrocities by Imperial Japanese forces during World War II until it was liberated in 1944 by American forces;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the survivors of this occupation demonstrated extraordinary courage, resilience, and unwavering loyalty to the United States despite facing unimaginable hardships;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas survivors endured forced labor, torture, beatings, executions, and forced marches to concentration camps, including the notorious Manenggon camp where approximately 18,000 CHamoru people were imprisoned without adequate food, shelter, or sanitation;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas survivors risked their lives to hide and protect members of the Armed Forces, including George Ray Tweed, who evaded capture for 31 months with CHamoru assistance;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas families were torn apart as survivors watched loved ones die during forced marches, lost children during birth, and were compelled to leave deceased family members behind without proper burial;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas an estimated 1,170 CHamoru civilians died during the occupation, representing nearly 10 percent of the population;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas survivors maintained their faith, cultural identity, and hope for American liberation while preserving crucial testimony of Imperial Japanese war crimes committed on American soil;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the United States recognized the loyalty of the people of Guam and passed the Guam World War II Loyalty Recognition Act in 2016;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Government of Guam has awarded over $38,000,000 in combined Federal and local war reparations to survivors and descendants;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas survivors provided intelligence and support that contributed to American liberation forces reaching Guam on July 21, 1944;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the resilience and unwavering loyalty of survivors represent the indomitable spirit of the CHamoru people;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas survivors and their families deserve continued recognition for their sacrifices and ongoing support for their needs;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the legacy of these survivors reminds us of our obligation to protect human rights and prevent such atrocities from occurring again;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas honoring survivors ensures that their experiences will not be forgotten and that their courage will inspire future generations; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas June 28, 2025, marks the 10th anniversary of Guam War Survivors Remembrance Day, commemorating the courage and resilience of Guam’s survivors and honoring their unwavering loyalty and sacrifices: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H40EEE977190E4F0D865E1A0485537729"> <section id="H21D147D110D948D687614AE6B6AF64E4" section-type="undesignated-section" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text> 
<paragraph id="H64F95A23C696436B8D3BA8C215EF135F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the designation of <quote>Guam War Survivors Remembrance Day</quote> to honor the resilience and extraordinary courage of CHamoru survivors who endured nearly three years of Imperial Japanese occupation while maintaining their loyalty to the United States; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA7F0800681714EA68432F65362A7DF3E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>calls upon the people of the United States to observe Guam War Survivors Remembrance Day with appropriate ceremonies and activities to honor the memory of survivors who have passed, support those still living, and ensure their stories of courage and sacrifice continue to inspire future generations.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

