<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-BAG25291-6LH-6P-XG1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 S1068 IS: Putting Veterans First Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1068</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250313">March 13, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S313">Mr. Sanders</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S331">Mrs. Gillibrand</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S432">Mr. Gallego</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S402">Ms. Rosen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S385">Ms. Cortez Masto</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S406">Mr. Kelly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S359">Mr. Heinrich</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S316">Mr. Whitehouse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S409">Mr. Luján</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S408">Mr. Hickenlooper</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSVA00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend title 5 and title 38, United States Code, to put veteran and military families first and to provide protections for employees, benefits, and programs of the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idde71248da78b44d5a7f8243ba9addc24"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Putting Veterans First Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id406f07c8c7c54ffe9cad5a4466682f5e"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text><toc><toc-entry level="section" idref="S1">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id34be2b2acb454c92b37415c7a6d14cd1">Sec. 2. Definitions.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="title" idref="id4261B1FE589945CF8584B0578363F443">TITLE I—Putting veteran and military families first</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id42629ce1bc3641b5b3c36e8ce206a883">Sec. 101. Reinstatement of members of the military community who were Federal employees.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id6ea1683f367d422393f4605d7d580de7">Sec. 102. Protection for members of the military community who were Federal employees.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id603bd6b23f2c4dd788ad60d10cc96864">Sec. 103. Report on members of the military community in the civil service.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idaf6fd061039e4c019894631194615dd7">Sec. 104. Comptroller General report on military community employment.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="title" idref="idfa63374c364544e098c64b27b950afeb">TITLE II—Department of Veterans Affairs employees</toc-entry><toc-entry level="subtitle" idref="idc5503777cbc64370abe6e8c960369dfb">Subtitle A—Protections</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id45b904941ba14cb896870c4df31acb50">Sec. 201. Limitations on hiring freezes at Department of Veterans Affairs.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idbca210c73de043b4a899b219bba5f9d2">Sec. 202. Limitations on closing offices at Department of Veterans Affairs.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id53819063cefd482197ba0dfbb79518ed">Sec. 203. Limitations on changes to telework and remote work at Department of Veterans Affairs.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id1abb1d76945f436186f82d61656098e2">Sec. 204. Limitations on changes to final job offers at Department of Veterans Affairs.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="subtitle" idref="idddf993028df3450fba8256d7e1dff972">Subtitle B—Reporting</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idea70accba89d4d819d570d6d4a3b71f0">Sec. 205. Notice and justification required before reduction in force at Department of Veterans Affairs.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id89c50ce3cd3f4d4eabe13ce827a267d5">Sec. 206. Department of Veterans Affairs personnel reporting.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id1f5399a111894f30a7e27882337f096d">Sec. 207. Department of Veterans Affairs research personnel reporting.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id6145d2e24c114482a42addafd2298898">Sec. 208. Prohibition on individuals serving as Secretary of Veterans Affairs from also serving as heads of other Federal agencies.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idb935147165ff49789c7019d46fa448d6">Sec. 209. Office of Special Counsel.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idedb32c356d7743a282822c04b04d664d">Sec. 210. Office of Government Ethics.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="subtitle" idref="idc7e1d768da954a2a82ad9fe5c5662553">Subtitle C—Restoring accountability and services</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id47c75674decf4b02af020eedbbb8d1d8">Sec. 211. Report on effects of removing essential programs, offices, and services from Department of Veterans Affairs.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idec0acac1e16f4ae088c5321186fa898e">Sec. 212. Restoring Department of Veterans Affairs programs, offices, and services affected since the beginning of the second Trump Administration.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="title" idref="id6b0c6f5d4a1043ddb9b69faed129c00e">TITLE III—Protections for civil servants</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="ide8b12a0bedd84ea9912f6e4a0c4bca97">Sec. 301. Nominations to Merit Systems Protection Board.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id025626e7e1554e69ba58101c3252e657">Sec. 302. Modifications to appeal rights for probationary employees.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idfad76359ead348da98b1c136cb5019c9">Sec. 303. Authority to retract offers and contracts relating to deferred resignations.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id011ae6387fc1417bb8c5ebc74f6eb692">Sec. 304. Limitation on changes to competitive service categories of positions.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="title" idref="iddabd0be26f114ed0bf438ced67ceff89">TITLE IV—Mental health care for civil servants</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id6358d6261571470bbdd3188dfc30532b">Sec. 401. Mental health services.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="ide863c1b7a9794d738d32dd2f848e8fbe">Sec. 402. Mental health services for current civil servants.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="title" idref="id5aa2bdf1843e4c619e1c44363612fbb8">TITLE V—Employment assistance for civil servants</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id7848434a039b4e72b98864450d3f687f">Sec. 501. Employment assistance.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idea9690974bd54281bca9d32783342ff9">Sec. 502. Office of Personnel Management and the Department of Labor work on employment opportunities for members of the military community.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="title" idref="id27ac53159dea40cda65f50939cff7662">TITLE VI—Department of Government Efficiency</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id4E79EACA1CAE4C0DBA40C48286A0C7BE">Sec. 601. Limitation on access to veteran and department information, systems, and data.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idf73d9f054a724276b3016909b822c8d3">Sec. 602. Limitation on application of certain Executive Orders relating to Department of Government Efficiency at Department of Veterans Affairs.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id482814c8730b48bfa9f6c9f3d1e8d696">Sec. 603. Report on compliance with limitation on access to veteran and Department of Veterans Affairs information, systems, and data and Inspector General review.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="title" idref="idF86FC0F6052B4EAC9F091EC617D137D4">TITLE VII—Financial needs of the Department of Veterans Affairs</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id22522d485fd74fcc80ccf69de1bd9e88">Sec. 701. Definition; rule of construction.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id66e7f1ff42924538838b3e3c18efe103">Sec. 702. Report on financial effect of the Department of Government Efficiency on the Department of Veterans Affairs.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idf90ad2c373ff41269b28120aabdf7453">Sec. 703. Reinstatement of contracts and review of mass contract cancellations.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id8a4702f4463445da9523dd62aca6d07a">Sec. 704. Limitations on mass contract cancellations.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idb5abecd92e794d428cfd908c29b58957">Sec. 705. Charge card program of the Department of Veterans Affairs.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="title" idref="id5335240d0ee5452ab539e4a9bb4a4851">TITLE VIII—Reporting requirements</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="ide8da65d3836247a3a8431873189562d7">Sec. 801. Requirement for Veterans Benefits Administration Monday Morning Workload Report.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id26a726ff0f0343ca9405c6e9b9144e1d">Sec. 802. Improvements regarding periodic publication of metrics relating to processing of appeals.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idb1d4281e5c3743ebb84e9b0ee7726110">Sec. 803. Publication of wait times for community care from Department of Veterans Affairs.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id3216343bf63745ac8ae6528451a75814">Sec. 804. Period for Secretary of Veterans Affairs to respond to questions submitted by members of certain congressional committees.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section><section id="id34be2b2acb454c92b37415c7a6d14cd1" commented="no"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act: </text><paragraph id="id2483b31064fb4f41a1147b958cc5647c" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agency</header><text>The term <term>agency</term> has the meaning given that term in section 3330d of title 5, United States Code. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id09a5f7f5df5e41158f53258af0a93a14"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Caregiver</header><text>The term <term>caregiver</term> means an adult family member or other individual who has a significant relationship with, and who provides a broad range of assistance to, a wounded, ill, injured, or disabled member of the Armed Forces or veteran or a dependent of such a member or veteran with a chronic or other health condition, disability, or functional limitation. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4994b25c40b0424f96d7bdecadde8faf" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Civil service</header><text>The term <term>civil service</term> has the meaning given that term in section 2101 of title 5, United States Code. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7d29dc55d88f444abe77bba7dae06350" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Demotion</header><text>The term <term>demotion</term> means a reduction in grade (as defined in section 7511(a) of title 5, United States Code). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3ff530fa9bc04a97a2794e1d212143f7" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Member of the armed forces</header><text>The term <term>member of the armed forces</term> has the meaning given that term in 315.612(b)(4) of title 5, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor thereto. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb0e42599e0804e54a6415d44d4f64fb9" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Military spouse</header><text>The term <term>military spouse</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="ida03fd4b2c98243a990daf27778e4c0d6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the husband or wife of a member of the armed forces;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6a150469fadb45fc9b2e4de13853374f"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the husband or wife of a retired, totally disabled, or separated member of the armed forces; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id09250eb6af684a7ca361dc220670e27a"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the widow or widower of a member of the armed forces killed while performing active duty or who died from a service-connected injury or illness.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idf9c136072f8f4ae0bff2266f41edd18c" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Removal</header><text>The term <term>removal</term> means removing an individual from the civil service.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4e7810fcc1af4bcfa1c92b6ab0a9b1f5"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Reserve component</header><text>The term <term>reserve component</term> has the meaning given that term in section 101 of title 38, United States Code. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id618149adc11b438bbcc567dff3c24b16" commented="no"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Suspension</header><text>The term <term>suspension</term> means the placing an individual in a temporary status without duties and pay for a period of longer than 7 days. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id03dc359fbb444aab9ac8c81dcd434b14"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Survivor</header><text>The term <term>survivor</term> means a family member of a member of the armed forces or veteran who died while on active duty or after military retirement or of a service-connected injury or illness. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id445afafc420041ea8de1e457757a94d0" commented="no"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Veteran</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide5c70bef5b81443c83a03bd01757e424"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the term <term>veteran</term> means a person who served on active duty as a member of the armed forces, regardless of length of service, and who was discharged or released therefrom.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf0719533b88d4f62a417d8cecad04e92" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusions</header><text>The term <term>veteran</term> does not include a person who—</text><clause id="id9f061e7738164bfcbaad84fd99a3193c" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>received a dishonorable discharge from the Armed Forces; or</text></clause><clause id="id0f90e95fbe10403c9e530b3dd10ef7b6" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>was discharged or dismissed from the Armed Forces by reason of the sentence of a general court-martial. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></section><title id="id4261B1FE589945CF8584B0578363F443" style="OLC"><enum>I</enum><header>Putting veteran and military families first</header><section id="id42629ce1bc3641b5b3c36e8ce206a883"><enum>101.</enum><header>Reinstatement of members of the military community who were Federal employees</header><subsection id="ideb9da91a6251402aaf8a964a45c7caba"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any removal, demotion, or suspension of a veteran, military spouse, caregiver, survivor, or member of a reserve component who was serving in a position in the civil service that occurred during the period beginning on January 20, 2025, and ending on the date of enactment of this Act shall have no force or effect.</text></subsection><subsection id="idecc989dba4bb4314bfd404972b49dc41"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Back pay and resumption of benefits</header><text>Any person whose removal, demotion, or suspension is rendered without force or effect under subsection (a) shall—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id40685df2aadd44a792061acb907226f2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">receive back pay for any pay not received by the person during the period beginning on the date of the removal, suspension, or demotion and ending on the date of enactment of this Act; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id88f01cca0da54c26bc58919d7aa376ae"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have benefits restored, retroactive to the date of the removal, demotion, or suspension.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id65e69a4fa4cf40c6a3311a6541bc2e9a" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Election To resign</header><text>At the election of a person whose removal, demotion, or suspension is rendered without force or effect under subsection (a), at any time after the date of enactment of this Act, the person may resign from the position of the person in the civil service, which shall not affect the obligation to provide back pay or the resumption of benefits with respect to the period beginning on the date of the removal, demotion, or suspension and ending on the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="id6ea1683f367d422393f4605d7d580de7"><enum>102.</enum><header>Protection for members of the military community who were Federal employees</header><subsection id="idb803e88b821d47a2ad88e46dc1927b9c"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any veteran, military spouse, caregiver, survivor, or member of a reserve component who is in a position in the civil service may not be removed, demoted, or suspended—</text><paragraph id="idf7a8224a6efc4a789794270f53a7185d"><enum>(1)</enum><text>as a part of a group of more than 5 persons who are being removed, demoted, or suspended on the same day by the agency employing the persons;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id968072a69b7f4f5c939bcae33163c2fe"><enum>(2)</enum><text>without providing a notification to the direct supervisor of the veteran, military spouse, caregiver, survivor, or member of a reserve component not less than 10 business days before the removal, demotion, or suspension, unless the supervisor advises or approves the removal, demotion, or suspension;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2bc4358d62d145a28229c71ff9198936"><enum>(3)</enum><text>on the basis of performance, unless the veteran, military spouse, caregiver, survivor, or member of a reserve component has received at least 1 performance rating at or below level 2 or minimally satisfactory (or a similar equivalent level) during the 1-year period ending on the date of the removal, demotion, or suspension; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd12606e4c0a64e498616013ee9d66e64"><enum>(4)</enum><text>if the removal, demotion, or suspension would result in a greater than 50 percent vacancy rate for the office or position of the veteran, military spouse, caregiver, survivor, or member of a reserve component or a significant reduction or elimination of the duties being carried out by the veteran, military spouse, caregiver, survivor, or member of a reserve component, without approval by the direct supervisor of the veteran, military spouse, caregiver, survivor, or member of a reserve component.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id811d0df145dd4089bdb8e31ea1b31acb" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Review</header><text>Not later than 10 days after the date of the removal, demotion, or suspension of any veteran, military spouse, caregiver, survivor, or member of a reserve component in a position the civil service, the removal, demotion, or suspension shall be referred to the Merit Systems Protection Board or the Office of Special Counsel, unless the individual agrees to waive the right to such a referral. </text></subsection></section><section id="id603bd6b23f2c4dd788ad60d10cc96864"><enum>103.</enum><header>Report on members of the military community in the civil service</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, and not later than 90 days after the end of each fiscal year thereafter, each agency shall submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs, the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Appropriations, and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs, the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Appropriations, and the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives the following information:</text><paragraph id="idc78115bbe1ae498aadc21d3c5e1c6085"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The number of veterans, military spouses, caregivers, survivors, and members of a reserve component who, during the prior fiscal year—</text><subparagraph id="idead7a38ab9774694b00f2898cb21287e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>were hired by the agency, disaggregated by those who were serving at a different agency immediately before being hired by the agency and those hired from outside the Federal Government;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7218fbcf2c384245a6352bfd2fce7063"><enum>(B)</enum><text>separated from service with the agency, disaggregated by those who were hired by another agency and those who were not hired by another agency; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ided104ffbf48d4c3f9f6a43cb79033e65"><enum>(C)</enum><text>were removed by the agency.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide19028851ac64570add7db16178b3dde"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The number of veterans, military spouses, caregivers, survivors, and members of a reserve component who, as of the end of the prior fiscal year, were employed by the agency.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd096ce0d4ac14439b333edcbfcf20561"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Data regarding any directed efforts or incentives utilized to recruit or retain veterans, military spouses, caregivers, survivors, and members of a reserve component during the prior fiscal year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8e5c2a71959d49a29c932e6ddda19600" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(4)</enum><text>For the second report under this section, and each report thereafter, data on changes to the number of veterans, military spouses, caregivers, survivors, or members of a reserve component hired by, separated from, or were employed by the agency, as compared to the most recent report. </text></paragraph></section><section id="idaf6fd061039e4c019894631194615dd7"><enum>104.</enum><header>Comptroller General report on military community employment</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than April 1, 2027, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs, the Committee on Appropriations, the Committee on Armed Services, and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs, the Committee on Appropriations, the Committee on Armed Services, and the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and publicly issue a report regarding employment of military community members by the Federal Government, which shall—</text><paragraph id="idd49e2ee07c1e4bbe81fdf31ef381824a"><enum>(1)</enum><text>include a review of employment of veterans, military spouses, caregivers, survivors, and members of a reserve component by the Federal Government during fiscal years 2024 and 2025;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id33fc2aaa8fac4ad682004ff66a0477e1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>review the period of service in positions in the civil service by veterans, military spouses, caregivers, survivors, and members of a reserve component and the rate of removal, suspension, or demotion of veterans, military spouses, caregivers, survivors, and members of a reserve component from positions in the civil service, as compared to other individuals in positions in the civil service; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id44a8cd23e5a2499a9c593b409a7e59c7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>describe any changes in employment of veterans, military spouses, caregivers, survivors, and members of a reserve component across agencies between the end of fiscal year 2024 and the end of fiscal year 2025.</text></paragraph></section></title><title id="idfa63374c364544e098c64b27b950afeb" style="OLC"><enum>II</enum><header>Department of Veterans Affairs employees</header><subtitle style="OLC" commented="no" level-type="subsequent" id="idc5503777cbc64370abe6e8c960369dfb"><enum>A</enum><header>Protections</header><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id45b904941ba14cb896870c4df31acb50"><enum>201.</enum><header>Limitations on hiring freezes at Department of Veterans Affairs</header><subsection id="idfc5dbf5d3c6846c5b4b5e870c7eab92c"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Neither a position nor an employee at the Department of Veterans Affairs may be subject to a hiring freeze, hiring prohibition, or similar policy—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id646bd69a797e4b5f96cef6e52354a8c5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">unless the Secretary determines that unfilled positions or lack of staff subject to such a freeze will not result in increased costs to the Department; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7286fa4114804f3c96fca73a13a69a19"><enum>(2)</enum><text>until the date that is 90 days after the date that the Secretary of Veterans Affairs submits a report regarding the hiring freeze pursuant to subsection (b).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idddaa37dbb76f47e1b9ad4d7a622ddc19" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Before issuing any hiring freeze, hiring prohibition, or similar policy, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on the hiring strategy of the Secretary and budgetary proof that such a freeze, hiring prohibition, or similar policy will not cause increased costs to the Department.</text></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbca210c73de043b4a899b219bba5f9d2"><enum>202.</enum><header>Limitations on closing offices at Department of Veterans Affairs</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id90e01eefeb654fcf87f014376ec405ce"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs may not remove, close, or realign any office or program of the Department of Veterans Affairs except pursuant to a provision of law that specifically authorizes such removal, closure, or realignment.</text></subsection><subsection id="id37f016dccf3e444083c9a9e80b6b37b4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Notification required</header><text>Whenever the Secretary removes, closes, or realigns an office or program of the Department, the Secretary shall, not later than 1 year before the date on which the Secretary commences such removal, closure, or realignment, submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives notice of the intent of the Secretary to carry out such removal, closure, or realignment. </text></subsection><subsection id="ide885d9eaf33b476b960c9db5d342bec8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Assistance for displaced employees</header><text>In any case in which an employee of the Department is displaced by the removal, closure, or realignment of an office or program of the Department, the Secretary shall make a significant effort to find another employment opportunity for the employee within the Department.</text></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id53819063cefd482197ba0dfbb79518ed"><enum>203.</enum><header>Limitations on changes to telework and remote work at Department of Veterans Affairs</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8fb843d7328b43149b3510e22628bc78"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notice required</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs may not take any action to change to a telework or remote work policy of the Department of Veterans Affairs until after the date that is 1 year after the date on which the Secretary—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id855ad3e0855a4ab0b2def934eb296138"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submits to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives notice of the intent of the Secretary to take such action or make such change; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida75f91e80229440f9c3b1e20e6ce9e68"><enum>(2)</enum><text>transmits notice of such intent to the following:</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc8213399023d485c98bf94bc17762726"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Labor organizations that represent employees of the Department.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id89317906ab9d4ab0bf89dbe36746c2fb"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The employees of the Department who would be affected by such action or change.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id1580d05e64c24afa96a88746d053eff3" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text>A violation of subsection (a) against an employee of the Department of Veterans Affairs shall be treated, under section 505 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/794a">29 U.S.C. 794a</external-xref>), as a violation of section 501 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/791">29 U.S.C. 791</external-xref>) against an aggrieved employee described in subsection (a) of that section. </text></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1abb1d76945f436186f82d61656098e2"><enum>204.</enum><header>Limitations on changes to final job offers at Department of Veterans Affairs</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7ecbacf5e8644efda546a0db67accbba"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Limitations</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs may not rescind or make any change to a final offer of employment with the Department of Veterans Affairs for any reason that is not directly related to an action or quality of the individual to whom the offer of employment was extended.</text></subsection><subsection id="id61d2ab016ab346aebedbabbab1ac7b8b" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Remedies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A rescission or change made in violation of subsection (a) may be appealed to the Merit Systems Protection Board in accordance with the procedures under section 7701 of title 5, United States Code. </text></subsection></section></subtitle><subtitle id="idddf993028df3450fba8256d7e1dff972" style="OLC"><enum>B</enum><header>Reporting</header><section id="idea70accba89d4d819d570d6d4a3b71f0"><enum>205.</enum><header>Notice and justification required before reduction in force at Department of Veterans Affairs</header><subsection id="id46631beee95c4387bd6acbdc88f2ce68"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days before commencing any effort to carry out a reduction in force, or similar action under a different name, at the Department of Veterans Affairs, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit a justification for the reduction in force or similar action to the following:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id77ac67602b7a4f8891d324b9739a03a2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Committee on Veterans’ Affairs and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5c40062fecb94333b461e49fc3ef58eb"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Committee on Veterans’ Affairs and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4a20703d8dbb4644934a64b58697f5af"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The labor organizations that represent employees of the Department.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id18a75c17696844d19ec24c35ee363e43"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Each employee of the Department who will be affected by the reduction in force or similar action.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id6747defdd8f94e52a4de4ae994a3fa60"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Each justification submitted pursuant to subsection (a) for a reduction in force or similar action shall include the following:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idad9c31a41f134f7eb72d20db5a6abde3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For each employee or position that will be terminated pursuant to the reduction in force or similar action, the following:</text><subparagraph id="id52f05f2c6d9c4027b05fe72b1a229138"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Documentation and analysis used to determine that the termination will not reduce or negatively affect delivery of care or benefits for veterans.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida8966a4f77374c79be86082c65094bc6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Documentation and analysis used to determine that the termination will not cost the Department or the Federal Government more than if the Department were to retain the position or employee.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9ee08f95e5ff497ba95a810b156a41bc"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Cost estimate, strategic plan, analysis, and any other relevant information or documentation the Secretary used to determine the need to terminate the employee or position. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id7cce682019554c9aaf56317491efe81d"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The planned timeline for the reduction in force or similar action and the methodology the Secretary will use to track the actual effects of the reduction in force or similar action.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idaf4c3d9e2a1b4156b2f4091880dc8aed"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Options for changing the plans of the Secretary and a strategy should an unexpected negative impact to veterans occur from the planned actions.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id89c50ce3cd3f4d4eabe13ce827a267d5"><enum>206.</enum><header>Department of Veterans Affairs personnel reporting</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9757fb08a9a8495bae4b8e32cba94046"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>Section 505 of the John S. McCain III, Daniel K. Akaka, and Samuel R. Johnson VA Maintaining Internal Systems and Strengthening Integrated Outside Networks Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/182">Public Law 115–182</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/301">38 U.S.C. 301</external-xref> note) is amended—</text><paragraph id="ide35f4aac326f4ffb9b61ca9f794bec17"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id526a4164e88f4a0d8c9d139fda19d9af"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (1)—</text><clause id="id4ebfcc0fb5904d8fa50df3192045a9ab"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the matter before subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>information,</quote> and all that follows through <quote>facility:</quote> and inserting <quote>information:</quote>;</text></clause><clause id="idee6398772a7d4c27a27fd160e96aa88f"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id89bb6fd4fec7425db3df4efd821ba899"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting <quote>(i)</quote> before <quote>The number</quote>; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd83b0dee0ca64821873f3441dfecd29b"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new clause:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0B65BF74C2424C1394037D22F7AEC090"><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb10b8ed726ca440b95198e6d915fca3c" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Information made available under this subparagraph shall be updated not less frequently than once each quarter to account for delays in data processing and shall reflect the most recently available data.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subclause></clause><clause id="id9eadfda8d03944008aab80bd78378e20"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>vacancies, by occupation.</quote> and inserting <quote>positions currently undergoing a recruitment action, disaggregated by occupation and by stage of recruitment, including Manager Request Initiation Stage, recruitment stage, onboarding stage, and waiting to start stage, or successor stages if modified.</quote>;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idde023f73bfe54b0ebf12b877d473d08d"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (E)(iii), by striking <quote>potential hires or</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="id5ad1007f266e43339ae4e02826a44595"><enum>(v)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8166A0657BB14B51B6201952BC1D02EA"><subparagraph id="id620AABE1024A4968B0EC82407E42153B"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The number of positions vacated during the quarter for which the Department has not initiated a recruitment action, including the date the position was vacated, disaggregated by occupation.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id682fef20bdce4aeebe77171846d0c499" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (5) as paragraph (6);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id734de5a782d549cb8aa20eb6dbf10de9"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting after paragraph (4) the following new paragraph (5):</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4310aef6df4b40fdb55802a5cbcf29d3"><paragraph id="id12e3590db97049b4ac2cffb548f3cd57"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Display of information</header><text>The display of information made publicly available on an internet website of the Department pursuant to paragraph (1), shall be disaggregated—</text><subparagraph id="id8d0f3a2312da4aefabf438e4d8a284ba"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by departmental component;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id17dec0b0692c470998834e81162ab99b"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of information relating to Veterans Health Administration positions, by medical facility; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id67decb743ebe44868c7532f2abd2f233"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in the case of information relating to Veterans Benefits Administration positions, by regional office.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idee18d7c3b0f84a2594c153c4e144efda"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in paragraph (6), as redesignated by subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>shall</quote> and all that follows and inserting “shall—</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2C5A710D9C6D43109E9BE97E5EEDB08C"><subparagraph id="idb735ad2d37674a0da1da7e67ee62d3df"><enum>(A)</enum><text>review the administration of the website required under paragraph (1);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7b052dfb277b41a3abd41c32c63ce579"><enum>(B)</enum><text>develop recommendations relating to the improvement of such administration; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id09e4566088904c0290167a968e724b4b"><enum>(C)</enum><text>submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a report containing—</text><clause id="id12e725ffb7a148f881968f2a1453c6f0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the findings of the Inspector General with respect to the most recent review conducted under subparagraph (A); and</text></clause><clause id="id11a99c373d444d2cb4e641a1e16ff392"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the recommendations most recently developed under subparagraph (B).</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id52f90da6050a434289cb3fe5661f21c3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by amending subsection (b) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idFF8650FBAD8740368E33F876CF07759D"><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id579e5e162074479b93962ac22283f351"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>Each year, the Secretary shall submit to Congress an annual report that includes the following:</text><paragraph id="idf1d9005d21ec4b21a1d82163b7eff234"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A description of the steps the Department is taking to achieve full staffing capacity.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id108bca82a505452bac0c89d654a64857"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A description of the actions the Department is taking to improve the onboard timeline for facilities of the Department, including—</text><subparagraph id="id059E4567710144658D6BFA6DD1D4E194"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case of facilities of the Veterans Health Administration, for facilities for which the duration of the onboarding process exceeds the metrics laid out in the Time to Hire Model of the Veterans Health Administration, or successor model; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc70232772da14e08b28afd5bf887f442"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of the Veterans Benefits Administration, for regional offices that exceed the time-to-hire target of the Office of Personnel Management.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id95afddbbd82745a8a7861934ae9747f7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The amount of additional funds necessary to enable the Department to reach full staffing capacity.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id54092c98c3c84e889eac47b74e457895"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Such recommendations for legislative or administrative action as the Secretary may have in order to achieve full staffing capacity at the Department.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id71af9441faf14e6bb46350a6c6353d6c" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by subsection (a) shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act and shall apply with respect to the first update under section 505(a)(3) of such Act beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act and each update thereafter. </text></subsection></section><section id="id1f5399a111894f30a7e27882337f096d"><enum>207.</enum><header>Department of Veterans Affairs research personnel reporting</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit to Congress a report that includes—</text><paragraph id="id2874c15ef1214cfeb6cfdbee1d0bc0d8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the number of Department of Veterans Affairs research employees who were terminated from the Department since January 20, 2025;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2b348fc88c0a491d9f94494f63c62014"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the number of Department research employees who had their term limits shortened since January 20, 2025; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1f569d96a0ca4d71a558e8ec95ce7c2e"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a list of the research studies the employees described in paragraphs (1) and (2) were working on.</text></paragraph></section><section id="id6145d2e24c114482a42addafd2298898"><enum>208.</enum><header>Prohibition on individuals serving as Secretary of Veterans Affairs from also serving as heads of other Federal agencies</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide2f7ed22628a4fd4a07ad2a2e593a6e7"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>Section 303 of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0768a13704894913a660683cd78f2ba7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>There is</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id34F641E38AB746C4931893C2FDCCB013"><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide839b8b3038c435e8eeee379883fae17"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id355fcf3cc30a41018a00c54afbb3c713"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsections:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5AA02B18FEF2476F83A400C0274458E1"><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc4ea82a7091248ccbf03a849bf142a28"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id394f94704bfd4b33952e4403ef6d5a73"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, including any provision of subchapter III of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/33">chapter 33</external-xref> of title 5, an individual who is serving as the Secretary, regardless of whether such service is pursuant to an appointment made by and with the advice and consent of the Senate or such service is in an acting capacity, may not serve as the head of any other Executive agency, either pursuant to an appointment made by and with the advice and consent of the Senate or in an acting capacity, while serving as the Secretary.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide4b802820fb7416c84c681c654d21fe3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effect of noncompliance</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddc1a82edaf6b4cc094a2cbc50ed97acf"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Removal from office</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual serving as the Secretary who is not in compliance with subsection (a) is hereby removed from the position of Secretary.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0b1a772485ef46ac80dc7bca77e52f64"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Prohibition on certain actions</header><text>An individual removed from the position of Secretary by subparagraph (A) may not issue orders, guidance, direct any people or resources, or in any other manner carry out any of the functions of the Secretary.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id19cc65c170cc46a19e312908b97cdd97"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Treatment of orders, guidance, and direction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any order, guidance, or direction of people or resources or any other leadership action issued by an individual who was removed from the position of Secretary by subparagraph (A) and that was issued on or after the date of such removal shall be considered unlawful.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id17f66fccee2a4b6da3ebb71f9af3d08e"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definition of Executive agency</header><text>In this section, the term <term>Executive agency</term> has the meaning given such term in section 105 of title 5 and includes the Office of Government Ethics and the Office of Special Counsel, but does not include any advisory committee (as such term is defined in section 1001 of title 5).</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd75c5f1b463c4f349ad6534da0ff76ad"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>Subsections (b) and (c) of section 303 of such title, as added by subsection (a), shall take effect on the date that is 7 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id18ca50f7da5f4b71ac7c28d2400813f2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcb5a529483b345c7a37e5feed39116a4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date specified in subsection (b), the most senior career individual in the Office of the General Counsel of the Department of Veterans Affairs shall submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on compliance with the provisions of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2eb76d37bceb4ac3b592e8e27c779d19"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report submitted pursuant to paragraph (1) shall include the following:</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idebb8b6dbeb584c939805a80dca398ebc"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Documentation as to whether the Secretary of Veterans Affairs is in compliance with section 303(b) of title 38, United States Code, as added by subsection (a).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3268202405ba43d8b62e493545053eaa"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of the procedures in effect to reestablish firewalls, conflict of interest protections, and independence requirements at the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4e6b88016c4945e8937df36e54dd2354"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An affirmation that the Department of Veterans Affairs will comply with and respect the independent oversight and investigative power of the Office of Special Counsel, the Office of Government Ethics, the Merit Systems Protection Board, the Government Accountability Office, the Office of Inspector General of the Department of Veterans Affairs, the Federal Labor Relations Board, and all other relevant investigatory and audit bodies. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idb935147165ff49789c7019d46fa448d6"><enum>209.</enum><header>Office of Special Counsel</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1211(b) of title 5, United States Code, is amended by striking the sixth sentence and inserting the following: <quote>The Special Counsel, including any individual serving as the Special Counsel in an acting capacity, may not hold another office or position in the Government of the United States while serving as the Special Counsel. Notwithstanding any provision of subchapter III of chapter 33, if the Special Counsel dies, resigns, or is otherwise unable to perform the functions and duties of the office, the most senior career attorney serving in the Office of General Counsel of the Office of Special Counsel, as of the date of the death, resignation, or beginning of inability to serve, shall serve as the Special Counsel until an individual is appointed by the President as the Special Counsel in accordance with this subsection.</quote>. </text></section><section id="idedb32c356d7743a282822c04b04d664d"><enum>210.</enum><header>Office of Government Ethics</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 13121(b) of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="idf98f2d102d6245788544a4e080e4ffe0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>There shall</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idC33AE47B6C804E8AA38BA3403978C956"><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id35c0225119c04d69bc5f84dff4070017"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There shall</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2792a4965df84022996ff0601cbcb0b6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6235cff11b164b35bfe2c9fcd69bca1e"><paragraph id="idad82edd638444a30b8ce416844b50603"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Removal or transfer</header><text>The Director may only be removed from office by the President for inefficiency, neglect of duty, or malfeasance in office.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id312130b985834746ac9ddcd1383b4084"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Restriction on holding other offices</header><text>The Director, including any individual serving as the Director in an acting capacity, may not hold another office or position in the Government of the United States while serving as the Director. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb9cef1873045488eb6213f5836a8754b"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Absence or unavailability of Director</header><text>Notwithstanding any provision of subchapter III of chapter 33, if the Director dies, resigns, or is otherwise unable to perform the function and duties of the office, the most senior career individual serving in the office of the Chief of Staff of the Office of Government Ethics, as of the date of the death, resignation, or beginning of inability to serve, shall serve as the Director until an individual is appointed by the President as the Director in accordance with this subsection.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></subtitle><subtitle id="idc7e1d768da954a2a82ad9fe5c5662553" style="OLC"><enum>C</enum><header>Restoring accountability and services</header><section id="id47c75674decf4b02af020eedbbb8d1d8"><enum>211.</enum><header>Report on effects of removing essential programs, offices, and services from Department of Veterans Affairs</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id07d1cc0b331240a3896d6e6a2b0b5ad3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the effects of removing essential programs, offices, and services from the Department of Veterans Affairs during the period beginning on January 20, 2025, and ending on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide1f852e6921145e588f44b78e11980bf"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report submitted pursuant to subsection (a) shall include, for the period covered by the report, the following:</text><paragraph id="idde00afeed0f2494f94cdb735125a5aa7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A description of all offices or programs either reorganized, renamed, shut down, or reduced.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf67c273b79534d6a8dfd6e9507104101"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Position titles of individuals either terminated or placed on leave, disaggregated by which office they were housed in.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id12cd1515fe3841f5b4d334c1f5da31ec"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A list of all websites, pamphlets, fliers, reports, photographs, or other public-facing documents removed.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf6688308f5e6434ba41dcf0882ca4b1a"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A detailed description of how accessibility of Department facilities and websites has been affected, for both veterans and Department employees.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6eebbd73e42d426d893bfa86b082a2a3"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A list of any Department research projects cancelled or postponed.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id05bda8ebe264445a83ddae400b64e11b"><enum>(6)</enum><text>A list of all Department employee-facing documents or trainings removed from intranet sites.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc88fca9a97e648b795175b6cce79ba04"><enum>(7)</enum><text>A list of all events cancelled or postponed by the Department.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id57c4499e4199414a9b71fadcff871788"><enum>(8)</enum><text>For each of paragraphs (1) through (7), a justification for why each action was taken.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idec0acac1e16f4ae088c5321186fa898e"><enum>212.</enum><header>Restoring Department of Veterans Affairs programs, offices, and services affected since the beginning of the second Trump Administration</header><subsection id="idb80a5e255b2643f7816ff80c2731ee08"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Restoring Department of Veterans Affairs</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida6ae515f2c8f4fde94aad626114c6b21"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any removal, demotion, or suspension of a Department of Veterans Affairs employee during the period beginning on January 20, 2025, and ending on the date of the enactment of this Act shall be considered null and void.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1c6ce9f3ecd241039f27c5cb46b43d5a"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Backpay and resumption of benefits</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person subject to a removal, demotion, or suspension described in paragraph (1) shall be eligible for backpay and resumption of benefits.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf3f6622e56f44013807529587c6fc307"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Resignations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person described in paragraph (2) who does not wish to be restored to a position from which the person was removed, demoted, or suspended as described in paragraph (1) may resign from the position as they so choose.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ide29ddbccd5fe40379d1b89f96518385a"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Publication of certain materials and websites</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall commence publishing all materials and websites described in section 211(b).</text></subsection><subsection id="id4541eb1a53b64d479b29f1575ab5ff82"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Nullification of cancellation or postponement of certain research projects</header><text>The cancellation or postponement of any research projects during the period beginning on January 20, 2025, and ending on the date of the enactment of this Act shall be considered null and void.</text></subsection><subsection id="id4fc825ad8a6947678e4295f6542df20b"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Withdrawal of certain directive relating to flags</header><text>The Secretary shall withdraw the February 12, 2025 directive of the Secretary entitled <quote>Public Display or Depiction of Flags throughout Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) Facilities</quote>.</text></subsection></section></subtitle></title><title id="id6b0c6f5d4a1043ddb9b69faed129c00e" style="OLC"><enum>III</enum><header>Protections for civil servants</header><section id="ide8b12a0bedd84ea9912f6e4a0c4bca97"><enum>301.</enum><header>Nominations to Merit Systems Protection Board</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/12">chapter 12</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended in section 1202, by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="id5C0A6C14001B470CB2CD5843999C3516" style="OLC" act-name=""><subsection id="idB7FF59A99B994CAB9832ABAAB34FDCF1"><enum>(e)</enum><text>Not later than 30 days after the date on which a vacancy on the Merit Systems Protection Board occurs (whether before or at the end of a term of office of a member), the President shall appoint an individual to fill that vacancy.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="id025626e7e1554e69ba58101c3252e657"><enum>302.</enum><header>Modifications to appeal rights for probationary employees</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 7701(a) of title 5, United States Code, is amended, in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by inserting <quote>(including, notwithstanding any other provision of law, an employee who is in a probationary period)</quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfad76359ead348da98b1c136cb5019c9"><enum>303.</enum><header>Authority to retract offers and contracts relating to deferred resignations</header><subsection id="id5a27b8aba4f34a47acaf324c0643a562"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority</header><text>Any offer or contract relating to deferred resignation commitment accepted or entered into by an employee in a position in the civil service may be nullified by the employee (without penalty) at any time until the close of business on the last day of the employment of the employee by the agency employing the employee.</text></subsection><subsection id="id36c1f74bd5694b729cbe1e830afbca42" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Remedy</header><text>A violation of subsection (a) may be appealed to the Merit Systems Protection Board in accordance with the procedures under section 7701 of title 5, United States Code, or challenged in a court of competent jurisdiction. </text></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id011ae6387fc1417bb8c5ebc74f6eb692"><enum>304.</enum><header>Limitation on changes to competitive service categories of positions</header><subsection id="id1c14a04ca98f4cc4855549afea60a6e1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>A position in the civil service may not be shifted, realigned, or removed from a competitive service category to an excepted service category—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd106b9683d48433d8093caefa73eadc7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>unless—</text><subparagraph id="idd0c793c8203a43e0b700a0d300ba122d"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the employee who current fills the position agrees to such a shift; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb80c8323f01f40909b61ddb166699472"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the position is vacant; or</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id3f89f009f0bf4ed699406a9e43c228b4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>until the date that is 2 years after the date on which the head of the agency employing the employee has given notice to the employee and submitted to Congress notice of such a shift, realignment, or removal.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id31533cbafb8447e8b41e0f44a3e1ef8f" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Remedy</header><text>A violation of subsection (a) may be appealed to the Merit Systems Protection Board in accordance with the procedures under section 7701 of title 5, United States Code, or reviewed by a court of competent jurisdiction. </text></subsection></section></title><title id="iddabd0be26f114ed0bf438ced67ceff89" style="OLC"><enum>IV</enum><header>Mental health care for civil servants</header><section id="id6358d6261571470bbdd3188dfc30532b" commented="no"><enum>401.</enum><header>Mental health services</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The agency that currently employs, or most recently employed, a veteran, military spouse, caregiver, survivor, or member of a reserve component serving in a position in the civil service who is removed, demoted, or suspended on or after January 20, 2025, shall reimburse the veteran, military spouse, caregiver, survivor, or member of a reserve component for the cost of all mental health services provided during the 90-day period beginning on the date of the removal, demotion, or suspension.<italic></italic></text></section><section id="ide863c1b7a9794d738d32dd2f848e8fbe"><enum>402.</enum><header>Mental health services for current civil servants</header><subsection id="id2edc37d5b0254fcba1f82ff157db4784"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Vet Centers</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall deploy a mobile Vet Center to the office of any agency that, on or after January 20, 2025, removes, suspends, or demotes a group of more than 5 veterans, military spouses, caregivers, survivors, or members of a reserve component on any day, for use by any current or former employees of the agency who are a veteran, military spouse, caregiver, survivor, or member of a reserve component.</text></subsection><subsection id="ide179b9b3954f4034b4a0bcb6a25a0a9a" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>Subject to the availability of appropriations, until February 1, 2030, an agency may not reduce the amount of funds spent, contracts, staff, or programming related to mental health counseling services, financial and legal services, dependent care services, workplace conflict resolution services, cultural competency services, substance use treatment services, crisis intervention services, or employee assistance programs below the levels as of January 5, 2025.</text></subsection></section></title><title id="id5aa2bdf1843e4c619e1c44363612fbb8" style="OLC"><enum>V</enum><header>Employment assistance for civil servants</header><section id="id7848434a039b4e72b98864450d3f687f" commented="no"><enum>501.</enum><header>Employment assistance</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The President shall order measures to provide employment assistance and opportunities for veterans, military spouses, caregivers, survivors, and members of a reserve component who are removed, demoted, or suspended from civil service on or after January 20, 2025.</text></section><section id="idea9690974bd54281bca9d32783342ff9" commented="no"><enum>502.</enum><header>Office of Personnel Management and the Department of Labor work on employment opportunities for members of the military community</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Director of the Office of Personnel Management and the Secretary of Labor shall—</text><paragraph id="ide68b2e7b32e34de29ec8ee0fd0dce2a0" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>work with the heads of other agencies to expand and facilitate the use of Federal programs, hiring and training opportunities, and retention incentives for veterans, military spouses, caregivers, survivors, and members of a reserve component;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6ad30d5c9e5c496195cbe36c60f4708b" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>seek to develop partnerships with firms in the private sector to enhance employment opportunities for veterans, military spouses, caregivers, survivors, and members of a reserve component, including to provide for improved job portability for such individuals;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id108333986aab4741b80f29b14e095a3b" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>work with the United States Chamber of Commerce and other appropriate private-sector entities to facilitate the formation of such partnerships; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id744172568b844ce68832ef6c69dbdd6f" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(4)</enum><text>examine and seek ways for incorporating hiring preferences for veterans, military spouses, caregivers, survivors, and members of a reserve component into contracts between an agency and 1 or more private sector entities. </text></paragraph></section></title><title id="id27ac53159dea40cda65f50939cff7662" style="OLC"><enum>VI</enum><header>Department of Government Efficiency</header><section id="id4E79EACA1CAE4C0DBA40C48286A0C7BE" commented="no"><enum>601.</enum><header>Limitation on access to veteran and department information, systems, and data</header><subsection id="id4A781ACF035C4BC0B7E45844CCDD7E39" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Limitations</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idDF0EE326B682478BB855F56A3C95B4E7"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>Subchapter III of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/57">chapter 57</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end of the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id938D4D5DF3324B31A9CE98A635A7BE93"><section id="idCF8D486CF89D411B9E87BE61DD497D0C" commented="no"><enum>5729.</enum><header>Limitations on access to certain information, systems, and data</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idCDDA580BB96548718F1534C5CBD27B5B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may not allow any individual to use, exercise administrative control over, or otherwise access any Department information technology system, health or benefits data repository, contracting information, financial system, record system, or other relevant system, or any data from any such system, unless—</text><paragraph id="idC8B65457E1EF4BA3B33833F1DD774A76" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>such individual is an officer, employee, or contractor of the Department; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8295B3CCC3874053976C53967036F260"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of an individual not described in paragraph (1)—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0C80BC5018D24488947127A71EDAFFAD"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such individual holds a security clearance at the appropriate level with respect to such system or data and such clearance was granted pursuant to the procedures established under section 801 of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3161">50 U.S.C. 3161</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id605D8B815DBC43389342FF7315C139F7"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such individual’s access to such system or data, or use thereof, does not constitute a violation of section 208 of title 18 (determined after the application of subsection (b));</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9B1ECF8B9C8F4A95A9FFCA515913D7F4"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such individual is not a special Government employee (as defined in section 202 of title 18);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5CA0EC87A07649A2AC9417514B722043"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such individual’s current continuous service in the civil service (as that term is defined in section 2101 of title 5) as of the date of such access is for a period of not less than one year;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idD5EAC1E1CFFC43BDAB5598319E35FA74"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such individual has completed any required training or compliance procedures with respect to privacy laws, cybersecurity regulations, national security regulations, and best practices; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4D606CDF817441D998443FFECC5C237E"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has signed a written ethics agreement with either the senior career Designated Agency Ethics Official of the Department, or the most senior career official within the Office of Government Ethics.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id80A471B18D8C4A4BB89AD3BAA69BF8A6" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Treatment of individuals who are not officers or employees of executive branch of Federal Government</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idF7D4D243CAF2472C913A1C7BC5E5A558"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Any individual who accesses any system or data described in subsection (a) who is not otherwise an officer or employee of the executive branch of the Federal Government shall be treated as an employee of the executive branch of the United States Government for purposes of section 208 of title 18.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idE7CE900CC4D74002B35E24A7DD0FBE26" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>For purposes of such section 208, exercise of administrative control or stopping, canceling, adjusting, holding, rejecting, changing, or otherwise impacting any payment or data in any Department system, data repository, or other similar location, shall be considered personal and substantial participation as a Government officer or employee in a particular matter.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id64A7748CDFDE422E958F9992BF596917" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definition of other relevant system</header><text>In this section, the term <term>other relevant system</term> means any data, system, connection, database, repository, or any other tangible thing of the Department that stores information of the Department, veterans, surviving spouses, caregivers, or other recipients of health care or benefits under laws administered by the Secretary, including health data, personally identifiable information, protected health information, burial data information, contract data, the Corporate Data Warehouse of the Department, data regarding benefits provided to veterans, financial transaction and bank information, Department of Veterans Affairs Integrated Enterprise Workflow Solution system and data, payroll information, research and development data, and data that is part of the Million Veteran Program.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5551804BEA3E41D392C7B5CFA2193CC0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of chapter 57 of such title is amended by inserting after section 5728 the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6FA06CDC58294AC4A82715777E8C42E4"><toc><toc-entry level="section" bold="off">5729. Limitations on access to certain information, systems, and data.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id61BE7EB8D44744AC82AB9FEF744D56C4" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Deletion of improperly obtained data</header><text>In any action brought against the Department of Veterans Affairs or a recipient agency or other recipient in a court of competent jurisdiction for a violation of subsection (b) or (e) of section 552a of title 5, United States Code, the court may order the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, the recipient agency, or other recipient to delete records improperly disclosed or maintained in a system of records in violation of the rules and regulations set out pursuant to such section.</text></subsection><subsection id="id8BB0AC4E0289488C8BABC8B9AA97E0B9" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Removal of connections</header><text>Not later than 15 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall remove any information technology connection between the Department and any entity not in compliance with the provisions of this section or section 5729 of title 38, United States Code, as added by subsection (a). </text></subsection></section><section id="idf73d9f054a724276b3016909b822c8d3" commented="no"><enum>602.</enum><header>Limitation on application of certain Executive Orders relating to Department of Government Efficiency at Department of Veterans Affairs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Executive Order 14158 (90 Fed. Reg. 8441; relating to establishing and implementing the President’s Department of Government Efficiency), Executive Order 14210 (90 Fed. Reg. 9669; relating to implementing the President’s <quote>Department of Government Efficiency</quote> workforce optimization initiative), Executive Order 14219 (90 Fed. Reg. 10583; relating to ensuring lawful governance and implementing the President’s <quote>Department of Government Efficiency</quote> deregulatory initiative), and Executive Order 14222 (90 Fed. Reg. 11095; relating to implementing the President’s <quote>Department of Government Efficiency</quote> cost efficiency initiative) shall not apply as it relates to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs or the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text></section><section id="id482814c8730b48bfa9f6c9f3d1e8d696" commented="no"><enum>603.</enum><header>Report on compliance with limitation on access to veteran and Department of Veterans Affairs information, systems, and data and Inspector General review</header><subsection id="idBA8F9A667EB04FB7BDDAAE321E9F7548" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report on compliance</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on the compliance of the Department of Veterans Affairs with the provisions of this section and section 5729 of title 38, United States Code, as added by section 601(a), including with respect to removal of connections pursuant to section 601(c) and the removal of relevant employees and their credentials from all Department systems, premises, and networks consistent with the such sections.</text></subsection><subsection id="id3233EB0F8EBE4865A0FC875D5148E5B0" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Inspector General review</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB2762B9D40F8462481C717ADD61A7AEC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 10 days of after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Inspector General of the Department of Veterans Affairs shall initiate a review on any instance of unauthorized use or other access of systems described in section 5729(a) of title 38, United States Code, as added by section 601(a), that has occurred during the period beginning on November 6, 2024, and ending on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idADE4334EB8C54CEC99E6570CBCD797B5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Preliminary briefing</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Inspector General shall provide the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a preliminary briefing on the findings of the Inspector General with respect to the review initiated pursuant to paragraph (1).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idC751E124B8FB49A2B8001B623AC566C6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Final report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Inspector General shall submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a final report on—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id77EF62B23F4543FA918C4E95BE61A982"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the findings of the Inspector General with respect to the review initiated pursuant to paragraph (1); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB31AF915EF024D259296A7566107CDDC"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such recommendations for administrative or legislative action as the Inspector General may have as a result of such findings.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idF6F6B436851F4AA18930C64DD38246AC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each report submitted under this subsection shall include the following:</text><subparagraph id="idEBFD6252708A4752911E7C2DCB09F845" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a detailed description of the unauthorized use or access, including any actions the individual or individuals carried out;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1C85BB2BB9344F7D9D11669B92FDA461" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a risk assessment of any threat to privacy, contracting and financial information, protected veteran health and disability information, national security, cybersecurity, or the integrity of the applicable system as a result of such unauthorized use or access; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4C30C020F98348E3AD2881F921AE0F85" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a detailed description of any stopped benefits, health care delivery, or other services of the Department of Veterans Affairs during the unauthorized use or access. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></title><title id="idF86FC0F6052B4EAC9F091EC617D137D4" style="OLC"><enum>VII</enum><header>Financial needs of the Department of Veterans Affairs</header><section id="id22522d485fd74fcc80ccf69de1bd9e88"><enum>701.</enum><header>Definition; rule of construction</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3335DDA8A5674DB6A072313C6E5BCD38"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Mass contract cancellation defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this title, the term <term>mass contract cancellation</term> means the termination by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs of—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id84b2f1857f2b418dadedec4c2e4e72ea"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">five or more contracts in a single business day; or</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf7c03fb3ef434685ad1631251b910d14"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ten or more contracts in a five-business-day period. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5C81276FFD7B44DDBE0F0831A7A7AB26"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this title shall be construed to prevent the Secretary of Veterans Affairs from cancelling individual contracts for poor performance, fraud, breach of contract, or other reasons in accordance with applicable law, including the Federal Acquisition Regulation. </text></subsection></section><section id="id66e7f1ff42924538838b3e3c18efe103"><enum>702.</enum><header>Report on financial effect of the Department of Government Efficiency on the Department of Veterans Affairs</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id40ab5ab97bb645a0bbd6d8476b419d98"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not less frequently than once each quarter until September 30, 2029, the Secretary of Veteran Affairs shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report detailing the estimated costs associated with or attributed to policy changes prompted by the Department of Government Efficiency or the President since January 20, 2025. </text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb8439f818e50422fb75a8a38d5bab2a2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Costs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each report required by subsection (a) shall account for the following: </text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id381e12d863cf49f2b062fb31acd0ecbe"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The cancellation of any contracts and potential litigation to resolve related matters. </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3aa14bb871c749f29d8fa6d6e5d15088"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The wrongful termination of employees and any settlements.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id73e33b4039f143089a355c0cc2279e16"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The need to hire contracted providers or staff to backfill vacant roles. </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id929a7f5ad2454a7ba503211109d06221"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Such other matters as the Secretary of Veterans Affairs considers appropriate. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1b4857a0dc0244d4b718853813f78dfa"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of Congress defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida5a816a88f6142218cdea953f11eefaf"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate; and </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf977e0fdb91f4b5f8294bb395a9e0977"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives. </text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idf90ad2c373ff41269b28120aabdf7453"><enum>703.</enum><header>Reinstatement of contracts and review of mass contract cancellations</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd44ece9e5444463392c8669bb5367b6c"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reinstatement; pause; review</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idedbee7b1f6ce4a539be792552c6ede3b"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd6178912daf54c208531b9ad7d412ef6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall reinstate each contract cancelled in a mass contract cancellation during the period beginning on January 20, 2025, and ending on the date of the enactment of this Act; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idef2014a929724a4a92a4fb71221c1a68"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall pause any mass contract cancellation in progress as of the date of the enactment of this Act; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0a8769fc5f6048e59503a34d2986d618"><enum>(C)</enum><text>shall not commence any mass contract cancellation unless—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfc1cc0793da546968a26aa2eff02fc41"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">each condition described in paragraph (2) is met; and </text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id37e35f06cf43462dacedfe011f26c54f"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the requirements of section 704 are fulfilled. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd860c13ad1c5454c9229a108c609dca9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conditions</header><text>The conditions described in this paragraph are the following: </text><subparagraph id="id4da5f38b02334182b40e92881696a591"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs has reviewed all contracts cancelled or proposed to be cancelled during the period beginning on January 20, 2025 and ending on April 30, 2025.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6987fac69b9444a7aa4d68373e4ab8c5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Secretary has submitted to Congress a report on the reviews conducted under subparagraph (A), including, for each contract reviewed, a certification by the Secretary and career head of each relevant administration or office of the Department of Veterans Affairs that canceling the contract has not or will not affect any of the following: </text><clause id="id72699080AB0B446D9759CC8C6C79DA98"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The delivery of health care, benefits, and memorial services to veterans.</text></clause><clause id="id369A79EE24364122BE4746C8753F210D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Safety and cleanliness of any facility of the Department, including surgical suites.</text></clause><clause id="idD2BCA713C6914FF281865B99BF77946F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The ability of the Department to prevent and detect waste, fraud, and abuse.</text></clause><clause id="idE7F864ED4AD54C5B9741B02E9B12809D"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Medical research carried out by the Department. </text></clause><clause id="idE9F194D3C63743D3A92867A9D157EBCD"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Cyber and information security.</text></clause><clause id="idE5357962AC974447908545A120ABD892"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Planning, delivery, and maintenance for infrastructure, leasing, and construction.</text></clause><clause id="id0252F809DE4F45619F1790A2A6981313"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>Homelessness services, including prevention and housing.</text></clause><clause id="id9A359B7700E248BE9526AA6953760D34"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>Cancer research and care.</text></clause><clause id="idA057957AA3424A9B92D1D1A9703A96F6"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>Memorial services.</text></clause><clause id="id56D2ACA7F3CC4EBA85562F2AEF1C62AD"><enum>(x)</enum><text>Claims processing and retrieval and digitization of records.</text></clause><clause id="idD872932226384CEB9971C550175C4E81"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>Veteran-directed care.</text></clause><clause id="id9698FFA7D04C4C3AA93C982C31536BF5"><enum>(xii)</enum><text>Payments and program oversight for educational assistance under laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs.</text></clause><clause id="id52916CE3AE15431184DFA0FBAD7EA0AB"><enum>(xiii)</enum><text>Medical supplies.</text></clause><clause id="id0DF21C71C2B14D4E91C2C05FA5B18370"><enum>(xiv)</enum><text>Mental health and suicide prevention.</text></clause><clause id="id95DFDC31589C4FCE95DD99ED535F4EBF"><enum>(xv)</enum><text>Implementation of the Sergeant First Class Heath Robinson Honoring our Promise to Address Comprehensive Toxics Act of 2022 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/168">Public Law 117–168</external-xref>) (commonly known as the <quote>PACT Act</quote>). </text></clause><clause id="id2BD592DF91B24A68A081A8ACA95D2A76"><enum>(xvi)</enum><text>Radiology services.</text></clause><clause id="idCAF54AAC990640A1A296764B6B5F2A9D"><enum>(xvii)</enum><text>Pharmacy services.</text></clause><clause id="id69E213CBD67642D082CBF5FCAE68AD49"><enum>(xviii)</enum><text>Prosthetics services.</text></clause><clause id="id5817C3EEF3004C7DBF43A7183CF671E3"><enum>(xix)</enum><text>The Transition Assistance Program.</text></clause><clause id="id6DD090F6C63741D5AAB3202FB3D1F874"><enum>(xx)</enum><text>The Home Loan Guaranty Program of the Department.</text></clause><clause id="id250B9483AF0E4DD195014093506603F0"><enum>(xxi)</enum><text>Police and security services provided by the Department.</text></clause><clause id="id3061F4AB4BD6430CB3C093596A29679F"><enum>(xxii)</enum><text>Emergency response, including the <quote>Fourth Mission</quote> of the Department.</text></clause><clause id="id3CEBCB8782DF43418B253025B93DCA8C"><enum>(xxiii)</enum><text>Veterans employment.</text></clause><clause id="id8FC91DC65D7940C2AA41CF1A9D317EA7"><enum>(xxiv)</enum><text>The disposal of waste, including hazardous waste.</text></clause><clause id="id52092A6AFC974E818D0951A7C95CA55D"><enum>(xxv)</enum><text>Any other critical service, function, or operation of the Department, including those required by statute. </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id28804f9c35024bb3a79644a03c340c2d"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Secretary has submitted to Congress a report that sets forth a day-by-day timeline of how the effort to carry out mass contract cancellations was initiated, led, and unfolded, including the following: </text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc14d7ea6571741aca1858d838184e6e6"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An identification of each of the following: </text><subclause id="id9568FD2F2B924A81AC89379DA9681491" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Who directed the effort to begin and the date on which such direction took place.</text></subclause><subclause id="idC6C79BDE820D4AA18E2B28FAAEA7C2EE" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>The parameters of the effort.</text></subclause><subclause id="id1FD040D84D6541658C319551B5ADB1F2" commented="no"><enum>(III)</enum><text>Whether the Department was provided with a dollar number target to meet for <quote>savings</quote> or whether officials of the Department determined the amount of savings desired.</text></subclause><subclause id="idBE6AC63C8B454DC58816B9D7D39F0CB5" commented="no"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>The search terms used to select contracts for cancellation.</text></subclause><subclause id="idE8B9942BD47942108F36A7C09A7CCD9D" commented="no"><enum>(V)</enum><text>Who led the contract review process.</text></subclause><subclause id="idBF758F7CE2B0478CA063DA2550866425" commented="no"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>The specific individuals who reviewed the justifications to defend the merits of each contract.</text></subclause><subclause id="idF2EAB0451A8E4AE79DF9950C14C9BC20" commented="no"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>The data and fact-based criteria used to decide which contracts should be cancelled based on the review of the defense of those contracts prepared by career officials.</text></subclause><subclause id="id2BD9BDC33B06476B9D45E5BCDBE8CF1C" commented="no"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text>Whether any contracts were removed from the initial list of contracts to be cancelled prior to that list being finalized.</text></subclause><subclause id="idDF9549E85A044B4E863F412FB183B410" commented="no"><enum>(IX)</enum><text>The criteria used to develop the list of contracts announced for termination on March 3, 2025.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id8298663B82964BBEA392BA4B6545E263" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>An estimate developed by the Chief Financial Officer or the Assistant Secretary for Management of the Department of the cost expended by employees of the Department to respond to data calls and contract justification exercises during the period beginning on January 20, 2025 and ending on April 30, 2025.</text></clause><clause id="idC64317623135491BA732A51D030BC9A2" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>A list of contracts cancelled during the period described in clause (ii) that were subsequently restored, and any costs paid by the Department to the contractor to mitigate the temporary cancellation, including legal fees.</text></clause><clause id="id1FE24D122B3842F580123EE13A071071" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>For each contract that was cancelled, an estimated cost for the work to be performed by government personnel and an identification of the part of the Department those personnel will come from considering the ongoing partial hiring freeze and reduction in force efforts of the Department, including those outlined in the Departmental memorandum dated March 4, 2025, and entitled <quote>Department of Veterans Affairs Agency Reduction in Force (RIF) and Reorganization Plan (ARRP)</quote>. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idDA4C079AF0294895AA2558EFAA6C66A3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Inspector General review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date on which the reports required by subsection (a) are submitted to Congress, the Inspector General of the Department shall—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id081f724febe64ccc8710e920d77c52da"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">review the reports for accuracy and completeness; and </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id145e30f74c984982bc246dc503b5afbc"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submit to Congress and make publicly available a report that includes—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id63d044ef59af4565a2fac0732d6e147b"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">findings regarding whether the process for mass contract cancellations was consistent with public statements of Department officials; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id72ab9a750af7466ea16f8d3ea30127bc"><enum>(B)</enum><text>recommendations for areas for improvement for future contract management and oversight; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5602cb51f7324a77aff486b593238129"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such other matters as the Inspector General considers appropriate, including actions the Department may take to improve oversight and use of Federal resources in order to improve efficiency in contracting by the Department and prevent and detect waste, fraud, and abuse. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id8a4702f4463445da9523dd62aca6d07a"><enum>704.</enum><header>Limitations on mass contract cancellations</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB317CF90808345B180779D30694E0CD5"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Submission required</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id28d72ef170894b92bf225146b44547e0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After the conditions described in section 703(a)(2) are met, if the Secretary of Veterans Affairs decides to carry out a mass contract cancellation, the Secretary shall, before carrying out such cancellation, submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives the following: </text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idE07B793EB1F34874AC597B02A5E740F8"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A list of contracts proposed for cancellation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idD7A1BC575D5A4F66AC1CC1A124E80B18"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For each contract included in the list described in subparagraph (A), a certification described in section 703(a)(2)(B).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idA1779ADE0B6947D1B9F3FBB0CCE6E762"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number of contracts included in such list that are held by a service-disabled veteran-owned small business or a veteran-owned small business.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idFDF71BD1073B4F9B88909073B103C715"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A description of how the work proposed to be cancelled would be absorbed by the existing workforce of the Department or whether hiring of additional staff will be needed to perform that work, and a cost benefit analysis comparing the contracting and staffing approaches. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7e3650d09e194e838b6758c95bf452af"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall not commence a mass contract cancellation until the date that is 30 days after the date on which the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives receive the submission for such cancellation under paragraph (1). </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1958f936094941139bc3166bfa6ffcb7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><paragraph id="id1903886d9bc548b4a0e656d7da66901d"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 7 business days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit to Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a report that includes the following:</text><subparagraph id="id194bd2700e7048a7a540e5aca80a99dc"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A list of the contracts cancelled or proposed for cancellation developed by the Department and announced by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs on February 25, 2025, and, for each contract included in such list—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8e5bd61464cf47e2938b05ce0b833b17"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the justification for the need for the contract, if submitted, as written by career employees of the Department; and </text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id89f00d7e33f048f6ad02116ad2732f6e"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an indication of whether the entity holding the contract is a service-disabled veteran-owned small business or a veteran-owned small business. </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id36d726b06ae046bf895016fba387f4c6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A list of contracts announced for cancellation by the Department of Veterans Affairs on March 3, 2025, and, for each contract included in such list—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc714179dbbdd4cc8976f39197715a05e"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"> the justification for the need for the contract, if submitted, as written by career employees of the Department; and </text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcfe3246bb19849c3a636394e2c17241b"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an indication of whether the entity holding the contract is a service-disabled veteran-owned small business or a veteran-owned small business. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida4249c860e5742e3b83c6fc4fae8c512"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Data fields</header><text>Each list described in paragraph (1) shall contain, at a minimum, the following fields: </text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6876ec8e2bfb49c98e9629044d122d16"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Contract/Order #/PIID. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idadb7a8be0d4444c0a1cf68fc750bc3b8"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Vendor. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id257b1ea0aee34c88aeedd5f1ea83e69a"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Category of contract using relevant North American Industry Classification System (NAICS) terminology. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7baed5de10a74904bfeb0f1256be6840"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Contract description. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id74fe3a9ce1b7471fba6b08fee8d0baba"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Date of termination or contract action. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id92fdf1fbd3854ca4af41591d5f044f59"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Contracting Unique Entity Identifier.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4e6f39324c7e4e7392070af140620c8d"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The headquarters city and State of the vendor.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idb5abecd92e794d428cfd908c29b58957" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>705.</enum><header>Charge card program of the Department of Veterans Affairs</header><subsection id="id8251a02ac5754996b2fcbb5d813161aa"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 60 days before making any change to the charge card program of the Department of Veterans Affairs, including any change reducing the total number of charge cards authorized for use, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall notify the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives in writing of the proposed change. </text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id940b34059fec443ea85b43886366241a"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>Any notification required by subsection (a) shall include the following: </text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7f315fb0cc774feda2ca1db440e864a1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The justification for the change concerned.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf976f0da67b644ef826330e099e76c3e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The timeline for the change to occur. </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf6179ef4209e464c97abc5e95e9ef2ed"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A description of how the Secretary of Veterans Affairs intends to monitor for any negative effects on health care or benefits delivery. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id3691210cac6445e59e8bf0bd63e74bcc" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>This section shall terminate on the date on which President Trump is no longer President. </text></subsection></section></title><title id="id5335240d0ee5452ab539e4a9bb4a4851" style="OLC"><enum>VIII</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide8da65d3836247a3a8431873189562d7"><enum>801.</enum><header>Requirement for Veterans Benefits Administration Monday Morning Workload Report</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7bf1b45bb421485e842c7b6d2c0c64bd"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/53">Chapter 53</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idCE894DD205CB45D0A138B26404D26E11"><section id="idfb1cc00fec7b4faaac98db1f1452bd6a"><enum>5322.</enum><header>Monday Morning Workload Report</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfed099fd444544e8967cd6ebb76241a9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not less frequently than once each week, the Under Secretary for Benefits shall publish on a publicly available website of the Department, a report providing a snapshot of the workload of the Veterans Benefits Administration.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idac972cd28b4a45dc9f27a255c637a5e7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each report published pursuant to subsection (a) shall include the following:</text><paragraph id="id4231b3add9074cb5839c92e3070daed1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>National totals for pending and backlogged compensation, pension, appeals, and education workloads of the Veterans Benefits Administration.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idec6ef652eb144dfea9388812b3aad47a"><enum>(2)</enum><text>National, district, and regional office-level data, disaggregated by the following:</text><subparagraph id="idb5803dcd7584453086d2502a67dcb295"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Station of jurisdiction.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id75d55164d8dc4f9589922ea916e37695"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Station of origination.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1454fd2b180e4c03ae140976d002856f"><enum>(C)</enum><text>State.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0c495e9fe06e44a09f143898a62ec7ec"><enum>(D)</enum><text>National Work Queue, or successor queue, including—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4a24b37ee4374db2a63fd0a62cab5636"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of claims pending at stage of the claims life cycle; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5962419b86c84c7dbc433d1b847900b5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">average time claims are pending at each stage of a life cycle.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id22c55f542a57473d8873eb2944543c40"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Data for groups of claims, disaggregated by national, district, and regional office or State level, including non-rating bundle, entitlement bundle, award adjustments bundle, program review bundle, other bundle, burial claims, accrued claims, appeals, number of claims and appeals with duty to assist errors, and such other groups as the Secretary considers appropriate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida2efca4c0f1f4ce6a1a1ce9f42dc7749"><enum>(4)</enum><text>National level data on claim and appeal inventories, disaggregated by end product code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7c9fa18a3d6b4438a9077ecfc8a70ecf"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Regional office level data on claim and appeal inventories, disaggregated by traditional aggregate groups.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2538c90f95fb4f059eecda58e892a005"><enum>(6)</enum><text>National level data on the future volume of work of which the Under Secretary is aware.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id52ae0454f3c24df0806f20e01a1ae5b7"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Average age of claims that have maintained continuous pursuit.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6706cd2f1af249178781758f05d5b64a"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Factors contributing to the increase or decrease in workload and the claims backlog.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id384f564ee5f44408bd45dc200e594f17"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Such additional data as the Under Secretary considers appropriate. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idde92a9b76c4c4c65bd82b3a12e7aa741"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Publication requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each report published pursuant to subsection (a) in a week shall be published on the Monday of that week, except as follows:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5a0a3887352b49c89e62bf9b3045dad9"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In a case in which the Monday of the week of publication is a Federally recognized holiday, the report shall be published on the Tuesday of that week.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id963a39aa648d455d8f30b7c3ab95a4c8"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In a case in which the Secretary is publishing the report required by subsection (a) more than once in a single week, any publication after the first publication may be made on any day of the week at the discretion of the Under Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5db852399d0f468e9f011bbb1a48138a"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of chapter 53 of such title is amended by adding after the item relating to section 5321 the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id674DCEBD84EB4AFBAE09923303AC5BA1"><toc><toc-entry level="section" bold="off">5322. Monday Morning Workload Report.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id26a726ff0f0343ca9405c6e9b9144e1d"><enum>802.</enum><header>Improvements regarding periodic publication of metrics relating to processing of appeals</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 5 of the Veterans Appeals Improvement and Modernization Act of 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/55">Public Law 115–55</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block id="id275960682810492F8BEEFCA85E73DFD9" display-inline="no-display-inline" style="OLC"><paragraph id="id74d667e8695e4f8b8756d68e6cd11c4b"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A summary of the outcome of appeals under the new appeals system, including appeals reviewed by the Board of Veterans’ Appeals, disaggregated by—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5670eda288ac409d8c825a056ebaec1c"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the type of review;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id47f15bbd091442d996d2115375b9e350"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">station of origination;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id26e4229be76f4c758233bccd26473bbe"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">type of appeal; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddc04201dd30f41e2b57d2d4029fe743a" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">diagnostic codes.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="idb1d4281e5c3743ebb84e9b0ee7726110"><enum>803.</enum><header>Publication of wait times for community care from Department of Veterans Affairs</header><subsection id="idbedb11151b6d4f1d86d94974cca37c4c"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall publish on a publicly accessible website of each medical center of the Department of Veterans Affairs the wait times for scheduling an appointment for a veteran to receive care from a non-Department provider in the community for that medical center and each of the clinics of the Department in the catchment area of that medical center.</text></subsection><subsection id="id7cd9dba96bd74f1093d3de87447ed388"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Data To be included</header><text>The Secretary shall include in the publication under subsection (a) wait times for the following care:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc569ec5e96d04b7f97c81e2849740ad7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Primary care.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id04c2aaffca5b4c86b0b6299a7eff05e1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Specialty care.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id24a88408049147a2b95874443d61edb7"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Inpatient care.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id24d228c8899c4988af61bc841ecd31eb"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Mental health care.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb2f18c383c6247c9b94e68428b5bb4d9"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such other types of care as the Secretary considers appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb7a7f52195fe43fca3b1e5d87637da50"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Update</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall update the wait times published under subsection (a) not less frequently than weekly.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1954949940ea414c9fc127686e4699d8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Metrics used</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall calculate the wait times published under subsection (a) based on similar metrics as the metrics used to calculate wait times for care at facilities of the Department. </text></subsection></section><section id="id3216343bf63745ac8ae6528451a75814"><enum>804.</enum><header>Period for Secretary of Veterans Affairs to respond to questions submitted by members of certain congressional committees</header><subsection id="idD53D6FF1A2C848DE997CCFDC0531EC68"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>To the maximum extent practicable, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall provide—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4a043560ef8547d8a18b81b5689fd055"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an answer to a question submitted for the record to the Department of Veterans Affairs by a member of the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate or the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives, on or before the date that is 45 business days after the date on which the Department receives the question;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idef6840479dea486bbe1e76527a41c788"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an answer to a request for information submitted by a member of the staff of the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate or the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives or a member of either committee, on or before the date that is 15 business days after the date on which the Department receives the request from the member of the staff or the member of the committee, as the case may be; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1af5abe0e05d488485b48646412b90b3"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an answer to a letter sent by a member of the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate or the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives, on or before the date that is 15 business days after the date on which the Department receives the letter.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idB039A63F380649ABBE1811E188CCCAF6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Delayed responses</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id122447f2c3214d5d89ea7f4365cef718"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Notice required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary anticipates being unable to provide an answer to a question, request for information, or letter described in subsection (a) that was submitted to the Department by the date specified in such subsection, the Secretary shall, before such date, submit to the member and the relevant Committee a notice that the Secretary anticipates being unable to provide the answer by such date.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3952b4f64e6c4102b828d6807bcc4c18"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notice submitted under paragraph (1) shall include the following:</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddcea4f438e4a45cd940cf2ef7718c4f1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A justification for the inability of the Secretary to meet the deadline set forth in subsection (a).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1434e0b47dc544b388c07c62affa8bb4"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An estimate of when an answer will be provided by the Secretary to the question, request for information, or letter submitted.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id44e9267eea7a446b96748b84c1dcc703"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A description of the steps the Secretary needs to take in order to provide the response, including steps required to obtain any information required of another Federal agency.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></title></legis-body></bill> 

