<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H8F0C7C6A3A9146D9AA670FF163DA1BA2" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5585 IH: Equal Detention Standards Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5585</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250926">September 26, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000403">Mr. Kennedy of Utah</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for the applicability of the Federal Performance Based Detention Standards to any immigration detention facility.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H1BD87272F95E4572BE49E23AA723AA8B" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H577A1A7A77084411B8FA9355ED63A7E3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Equal Detention Standards Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H2357F3D104474E2CBF808E7BEA2D0FBF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Applicability of Federal Performance Based Detention Standards</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Beginning on the date of enactment of this Act, in the case of any agreement entered into or renewed between the Secretary of Homeland Security and any entity for the operation of a facility where, pursuant to any contract or agreement, any individual is detained pursuant to the immigration laws (as such term is defined in section 101 of the Immigration and Nationality Act), in addition to any standards for the operation of immigration detention facilities applicable pursuant to the terms of such contract or agreement, the Federal Performance Based Detention Standards published by the United States Marshal Service shall apply to the operation of such facility.</text></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

