<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-AEG25326-D1M-1F-3X2">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1895 IS: Mental Health Excellence in Schools Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>II</distribution-code>
        <congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session>1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. 1895</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action>
            <action-date date="20250522">May 22, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S391">Mr. Young</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S398">Mr.
                    Cramer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and
                referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health,
                    Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title>To establish the Mental Health Excellence in Schools Program to increase the
            recruitment and retention of school-based mental health services providers, and for
            other purposes.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HD6E3D43E23E4455FA59E1DD4CBFBB05E">
        <section section-type="section-one" id="H99F06F9A3EE5455FB44D8EB950041304">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Mental Health Excellence in Schools Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section id="HAE0DC4DC7AED4909AFC2AF81C829ACBB">
            <enum>2.</enum>
            <header>Program to establish public-private contributions to increase the available
                workforce of school-based mental health service providers</header>
            <subsection id="H4F72FE38BB37402384EED39A1D141BAB">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>Program authorized</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall carry out a program under which eligible graduate institutions may enter into an agreement with the Secretary to cover a portion of the cost of attendance of a participating student, which contributions shall be matched by equivalent contributions towards such cost of attendance by the Secretary.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection commented="no" id="HB37B0E54FD784944B7E15447AE38FA0E">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Designation of program</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The program under this section shall be known as the <quote>Mental Health Excellence in Schools Program</quote>.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H3A9F425706A840608465EC31523D3653">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Agreements</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall enter into an agreement with each eligible graduate institution seeking to participate in the program under this section. Each agreement shall specify the following:</text>
                <paragraph id="H927DCB512C4F4B50B98539AA69728D5C">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The manner (whether by direct grant, scholarship, or otherwise) in which the eligible graduate institution will contribute to the cost of attendance of a participating student.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H952938E3B42F4623A81B0789383E4FDC">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The maximum amount of the contribution to be made by the eligible graduate institution with respect to any particular participating student in any given academic year.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HAEC65A9DB28B4B50AF7486EDEBE304E4">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The maximum number of individuals for whom the eligible graduate institution will make contributions in any given academic year.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph commented="no" id="H3DAE83191AAA43C8816EE0C4B11B5EFF">
                    <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>That the eligible graduate institution, in selecting participating students to receive assistance under the program, shall prioritize the participating students described in subsection (d)(2).</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HA395664A41B9402A8C929F2252945448">
                    <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such other matters as the Secretary and the eligible graduate institution determine appropriate.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="HB0596361AD3A4B998206DF77344BE800">
                <enum>(d)</enum>
                <header>Outreach</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall—</text> <paragraph id="H638B4E0E7EF74C2FBBD15D1C34F69D0E"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>make publicly available and periodically update on the internet website of the Department of Education a list of the eligible graduate institutions participating in the program under this section that shall specify, for each such eligible graduate institution, appropriate information on the agreement between the Secretary and such eligible graduate institution under subsection (c); and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H44F5A4F31D54488193CE044BC993E229">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>conduct outreach about the program under this section to participating students who, as undergraduates—</text>
                    <subparagraph id="H7007A89BBE394789B7745E4799D2AF86">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">received a Federal Pell Grant under section 401 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070a">20 U.S.C. 1070a</external-xref>); or</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="HD9508DC9BA414018B12752AE657D3C5E">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>attended an institution listed in section 371(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1067q">20 U.S.C. 1067q(a)</external-xref>).</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H1A331EC220484939B1E215CBA7CAB51E">
                <enum>(e)</enum>
                <header>Matching contributions</header>
 <text>The Secretary may provide a contribution of up to 50 percent of the cost of attendance of a participating student if the eligible graduate institution at which such student is enrolled enters into an agreement under subsection (c) with the Secretary to match such contribution.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id8011a32938084c419244c36b9f841d89">
                <enum>(f)</enum>
                <header>Monitoring and evaluation</header>
 <text>As a condition of participation in the program under this section, each eligible graduate institution shall agree to submit an annual report to the Secretary describing—</text>
                <paragraph id="idD176F773DDFD4DC59E7CE12047A13264">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>the number of students served by the program;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="idAFFE9CBEBB374366BA6D314D0169DE72"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>the percentage of tuition cost covered by the program;</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="idCD9272EF607E49C0AB6BAE5682721D3C">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>the number of participating students who were also recipients of a Federal Pell Grant; and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id957758603EF94AF9A508F006789E2FBD">
                    <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>as applicable, the graduation rates and post-graduate employment of participating students.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id3db0a72752d444b1b89276a6ec732ca9">
                <enum>(g)</enum>
                <header>Interim report</header>
 <text>Not later than 2 years after the first contributions are provided under this section, the Secretary shall submit an interim report to Congress based on the annual reports required by subsection (f).</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="ide9ef47d0aba1444d81683b29edbc23f4">
                <enum>(h)</enum>
                <header>Independent national evaluation</header>
                <paragraph id="id71f69254acdb436999413fb1bdeb56b9">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                    <header>In general</header>
 <text>Not later than 4 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall provide for the commencement of an independent national evaluation of the outcomes and effectiveness of the program under this section.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id06bcb6772fc040688fb3a96fd220bd02">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Report to congress</header>
 <text>Not later than 90 days after receiving the results of such independent national evaluation, the Secretary shall submit a report to Congress containing the findings of the evaluation and the Secretary’s recommendations for improvements to the program.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="idD957319D7FD74223AC6DF49DA7DC1BCB">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
 <text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act—</text> <paragraph id="id63CAB2CB2EFE4C33B9D79717F04F3A44"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>$20,000,000 for fiscal year 2026;</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id9181512487B143039F9DCF5ABB84C55F">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>$30,000,000 for fiscal year 2027; and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="idF3D5078C538D48F4900FC57C52207C3F"> <enum>(3)</enum> <text>$50,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2028 through 2030.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
        </section>
        <section section-type="subsequent-section" id="H58575A035107442CA4346A364F1C0B06">
            <enum>3.</enum>
            <header>Definitions</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="HC4BA03FB52914CBE8907B1F08F8BC75C"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>Cost of attendance</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>cost of attendance</term> has the meaning given the term in section 472 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087ll">20 U.S.C. 1087ll</external-xref>).</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph commented="no" id="H4EC803CC455848E0804F8C0BEA9DF0DA">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <header>Eligible graduate institution</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible graduate institution</term> means an institution of higher education that offers a program of study that leads to a graduate degree—</text>
                <subparagraph id="H622E624360A7433191AFE67D95686DFE">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in school psychology that is accredited or approved by the National Association of School Psychologists' Program Accreditation Board or the Commission on Accreditation of the American Psychological Association and that prepares students in such program for the State licensing or certification examination in school psychology at the specialist level;</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H61D1C32B1CAA44048F25BFFB18E90E45">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in an accredited school counseling program that prepares students in such program for the State licensing or certification examination in school counseling;</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="HFA236BD7C89644188DB030D94FB21043">
                    <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in school social work that is accredited by the Council on Social Work Education and that prepares students in such program for the State licensing or certification examination in school social work;</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="HEF651F49DC8641608B3DB10C181418CE">
                    <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in another school-based mental health field that prepares students in such program for the State licensing or certification examination in such field, if applicable; or</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H0301F9FF81CB4F30A9CB902AF9F4EB36">
                    <enum>(E)</enum>
 <text>in any combination of study described in subparagraphs (A) through (D).</text>
                </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HDF8C7E4ABDE34589933D074A12280D24">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
                <header>Institution of higher education</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given such term in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>).</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H71F641FB93AB40B1854664D95CE62EE7">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
                <header>Participating student</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>participating student</term> means an individual who is enrolled in a graduate degree program in a school-based mental health field at a participating eligible graduate institution.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HA6D2E033D92D4775A206C9FFE5013A2C">
                <enum>(5)</enum>
                <header>School-based mental health field</header>
 <text>The term <term>school-based mental health field</term> means each of the following fields:</text>
                <subparagraph id="HB63214CEB35D44668D9E239ECC2A082E">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>School counseling.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAFD4F90B11F640FFAFCD44334C0EEAA3"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>School social work.</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="HFF3757E62A8D4072BD5B0546EE6E8464">
                    <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>School psychology.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE35EFA3A6A8142D9A6F80AD2D5392051"> <enum>(D)</enum> <text>Any other field of study that leads to employment as a school-based mental health services provider, as determined by the Secretary.</text>
                </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H6CC260E309BC494EB92B5E50AE0F997A">
                <enum>(6)</enum>
                <header>School-based mental health services provider</header>
 <text>The term <term>school-based mental health services provider</term> has the meaning given the term in section 4102 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7112">20 U.S.C. 7112</external-xref>).</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HEB5DC317246446D4B476AD909E76850F">
                <enum>(7)</enum>
                <header>Secretary</header>
 <text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Education.</text> </paragraph> </section> </legis-body> </bill>

