<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H63CC6E527A5B4E56A02D7769199E57D0" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1150 IH: Sturgeon Protected and Exempt from Absurd Regulations Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1150</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250207">February 7, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000829">Mr. Wied</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000576">Mr. Grothman</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000165">Mr. Tiffany</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Endangered Species Act of 1973 to exclude certain populations of the lake sturgeon from the authority of such Act.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0C65B03F89F84CB5BFA2E57D92DF3B6A" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H822AEF0DBAB74ED1B78639C5A2EA9D34" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Sturgeon Protected and Exempt from Absurd Regulations Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SPEAR Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H95079B679AC94E249886B311AD8A6C61" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Exclusion of certain populations of lake sturgeon under Endangered Species Act of 1973</header> <subsection id="HF9DF1881C784431FB70D13973EB41F2A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H4B24476A5405496683604416EE9090AD"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The lake sturgeon (Acipenser fulvescens) holds a special place in the cultural fabric of Wisconsin, especially for the communities located on Lake Winnebago and the Winnebago System.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFCDEEA810C2649B087F502E8D1F1258A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Through the staunch dedication and close public-private collaboration of the Wisconsin Department of Natural Resources, Sturgeon for Tomorrow, the Sturgeon Advisory Committee, the Sturgeon Guard, and local fishing, sportsmen, and conservation groups, Wisconsin has become the global leader in lake sturgeon management.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7C70440427F54F77A5D21240F80AF9D4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>As a result of these efforts and the development and implementation of a comprehensive management plan, the Lake Winnebago system is home to a thriving lake sturgeon population, one of the largest in North America, and the most successful sustainable sturgeon fisheries in the world.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB429D080D33F47D7A2E61D36A930B04D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An integral component of this management plan is the annual sturgeon spearing season that is meticulously managed and provides the data necessary, along with data from detailed spawning assessments, to maintain an accurate account of population levels needed and allowable maximum harvest rates to ensure the health and sustainability of the species.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H77094C3179564314AD03FE278ABE0F04"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Mandatory registration stations are established to collect detailed data on the length, weight, sex, and tag status of each harvested fish and ensure strict seasonal harvest caps are followed.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5BAE394C5B8146BCB68A6A730D0D2C42"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The spearing season has grown into a unique cultural event filled with strong traditions and community ties, drawing participants from throughout Wisconsin and many other States, and is crucial to the livelihoods of local communities and small businesses near the Winnebago System who rely on the annual season.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9EE14BB61CFA4ADAB77D934D64CEA4F9"><enum>(7)</enum><text>It is vital that this long-standing and cherished tradition be protected and that Wisconsin is allowed to continue its successful Winnebago System and statewide management of lake sturgeon.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H547886C86B824EA5B5E98AD63BEE8F75"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exclusion from listing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 4(a) of the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1533">16 U.S.C. 1533(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H196470EB0C04433AA428BFD161848099"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>The Secretary shall by regulation</quote> and inserting <quote>Except as provided in paragraph (4), the Secretary shall by regulation</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9A263C80A96D4B96B06DBBA7AD754AF0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H7E6B222F3E404731AB43CB2C7ACCC4E9" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="H4AA634E8AB8B4A8F84A1F7A84D9ACFD5" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Applicability to lake sturgeon</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may not make a determination under this subsection that any population of the lake sturgeon (Acipenser fulvescens) in Wisconsin is threatened or endangered.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

