<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3FE6BABF7F364BA2B2830C6C0F397BE5" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3994 IH: Understanding Student Parent Outcomes Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3994</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250612">June 12, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000305">Ms. Ross</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="M001208">Mrs. McBath</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To improve data collection related to student parents pursuing higher education, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H2F2638BF07FB42DD91116C2AD16F9897" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H2730B34CFDDA467EBF8BA7A16FD59A2E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Understanding Student Parent Outcomes Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H056A4A90B1A144EC84587AE5282B0538"><enum>2.</enum><header>Data on student parents pursuing higher education</header> <subsection id="H9D85C82E600F4BD39F083DED10998D7F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>IPEDS data elements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commissioner of Education Statistics shall carry out the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H7FDB1B12ED47474DA43ED8A5C2669FEF"><enum>(1)</enum> 
<subparagraph id="H5B4593A1033B4070829B968A831463A6" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To ensure consistency of the data collected pursuant to paragraph (B), establish a common definition of the term <term>parenting student</term> that covers any student who identifies as a parent or caregiver of a dependent child, in consultation with groups that include—</text> <clause id="H30926441E34B4BD59123253B5D64F73D" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">students who are parents or caregivers of dependent children;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H8B3104C822194D999997FA39B5C11DEC" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">experts in data collection related to such students;</text></clause> <clause id="HBF4DBF6047E14801B8D6FB7C9C0294D1" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>support staff at institutions of higher education for such students;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H0351A4B7D0B34EBBBB8C43123106E9C9" indent="up1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>financial aid administrators at institutions of higher education; and</text></clause> <clause id="H6A6598B597414BBB876A010ABE3760D9" indent="up1"><enum>(v)</enum><text>research staff at institutions of higher education.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFB0940EA77AA4F4FB8447F5FE4F3892A" indent="up1" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum> 
<clause id="HC18882F844CB423B84D8DC2D9B2D8640" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, develop data elements related to parenting students (as such term is defined pursuant to subparagraph (A)) attending institutions of higher education for the surveys conducted as a part of the Integrated Postsecondary Education Data System (IPEDS) or any other Federal postsecondary institution data collection effort, to collect data related to such parenting students that shall be disaggregated in accordance with clause (ii), and which includes data elements on—</text> <subclause id="HC33064AC72EA4EC78410237D2DD42B46" indent="up1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the number of parenting students;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HE7287C95A9404B3EA691780F3CA325D9" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the enrollment, retention, and completion rates of parenting students;</text></subclause> <subclause id="HC7FFFD994D97465584CBEB1211D6BE25" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the average individual net price charged to parenting students by institutions of higher education (as determined based on the calculation of the individual net price of an institution of higher education for a student under section 132(h)(2) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1015a">20 U.S.C. 1015a(h)(2)</external-xref>));</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H39BB6DB2DBAE4E38B2843D55872F8611" indent="up1"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the marital status of such students (reported in aggregate by marital status categories);</text></subclause> <subclause id="HF5013BFA5B0F44538348A24771555810" indent="up1"><enum>(V)</enum><text>the number of such students who are employed for all or part of the academic year while enrolled;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H7DD35D0DAFFE4F5CAA16CC1F8898716E" indent="up1">
                                <enum>(VI)</enum>
 <text>the median income of such students, and the number of such students in each income category (determined in accordance with section 132(i)(6) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1015a">20 U.S.C. 1015a(i)(6)</external-xref>));</text>
                            </subclause> 
<subclause id="H433B4BACBA364A76B154851A526027B1" indent="up1"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>the number of such students who are enrolled in an associate, baccalaureate, or graduate degree program, or a certificate program;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H9AFF54D2A72941B9A6618B0604C6AF57" indent="up1"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text>the number of such students who are enrolled full-time, part-time, or less than part-time;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H5974BDEE26234B43A31C5E3E92812271" indent="up1"><enum>(IX)</enum><text>the number of such students who are Federal Pell grant recipients;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H5AA271553B6F4F57B4C0D7A662D48EEC" indent="up1"><enum>(X)</enum><text>the number of such students who use campus-based childcare services;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H803FEA3572F8424AB66692A807A8F64A" indent="up1"><enum>(XI)</enum><text>the number and age of dependent children of such students;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H6F16EC2FD5B54AA1AD8EE4D87A41EFCE" indent="up1"><enum>(XII)</enum><text>the disability status of dependent children of such students; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HD0AE5EBAFB084C87943C60941B360899" indent="up1"><enum>(XIII)</enum><text>the transfer status of such students (without regard to whether such students were admitted as a transfer student or not).</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HF93DB208B4304DE1AA295A283E40DD5A" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Any data collected using the data elements developed pursuant to clause (i) shall be disaggregated—</text> 
<subclause id="HEE3EA0AA900645868EA762C2CCAE5A66"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by students who identify as a parent of a dependent child; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HA7A6DD1B597C4482A7FFF323C7BE2888"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by students who identify as a caregiver of a dependent child.</text></subclause></clause> </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8DF929C03FC64EDE9FE3376B4457291A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, include the experts described in paragraph (1)(A)(ii) in the technical and scientific peer-review groups and scientific program advisory committees authorized under section 114(g) of the Education Sciences Reform Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/9514">20 U.S.C. 9514(g)</external-xref>) to advise, on a continuous basis, the Commissioner on best practices related to data collection on parenting students (as such term is defined pursuant to paragraph (1)(A)).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3DC324267B7D4E01BB9EF1BF2AB0CCEF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Beginning with academic year 2026–2027 and annually thereafter—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE03406A50B60433781A84F11A1C3BC66"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">collect information on the data elements described in paragraph (1)(B) with respect to, at a minimum, the institutions of higher education required to complete, pursuant to section 487(a)(17) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1094">20 U.S.C. 1094(a)(17)</external-xref>), the surveys described in paragraph (1)(B); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD8E09C8DE3F74B4E9CCD1FAB183C6102"><enum>(B)</enum><text>disaggregate the information collected—</text> 
<clause id="H9BCB7679B70A4EC698960FDF64F6E474"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by race and ethnicity; and</text></clause> <clause id="HFD68D3D4FFDF4BE5AE069FE6F829C02C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by gender.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HCFCBA766793F48F384A018768BBF5E52"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text>The Secretary of Education, in consultation with the Commissioner of Education Statistics, shall provide technical assistance to States and institutions of higher education related to developing and carrying out State and institutional data collection mechanisms for data on the parental status of students collected in accordance with <internal-xref idref="H9D85C82E600F4BD39F083DED10998D7F" legis-path="2.(a)">subsection (a)</internal-xref>, including—</text> <paragraph id="H27A36F5CA45F4D6E8A4D879D7F01AAEF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>how to leverage existing systems, surveys, and other data collection mechanisms to collect and report such data, and examples and best practices related to data collection and privacy;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H259118E2C5DA45CD83DBD818BC2F516C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>integration and reporting of such data with State information systems, including statewide longitudinal data systems;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC6CE6ACB0E7E4BFCA9F5721BD81318F9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>how to account for data elements that change over time; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBA903C8AEDF144BA9A2C7876C4ACD52E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>recommendations of best practices to institutions of higher education related to communicating with students about data use and privacy, including how data will be used to help students who are parents or caregivers of dependent children.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HE42E755D50014CAF99086044F3487157"><enum>3.</enum><header>Study on improving student parent outcomes</header> <subsection id="H53812335932B4AA89451FB049A385A2E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Education shall conduct a study of a demographically and geographically representative sample of institutions of higher education (as determined by the Secretary) on best practices of institutions of higher education that improve outcomes for students attending institutions of higher education who are parents or caregivers of dependent children. Such study shall include qualitative and quantitative research on—</text> 
<paragraph id="H1BDD96512A9E4BBBB9001ABEA40AF24E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the enrollment, persistence, and retention of students attending institutions of higher education who are parents or caregivers of dependent children, disaggregated by race, ethnicity, gender, income, and the type of program in which such students are enrolled (such as an associate, baccalaureate, or graduate degree program, or a certificate program);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H60A5C89FD233462C86B8AE70C9D295CE" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the effects of the availability of campus-based childcare services on such outcomes of students who are parents or caregivers of dependent children, including a comparison of students whose children are served by the campus-based childcare services with students whose children are not served by campus-based childcare services;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDBBB072D61584BF48C08A45E85448B5C">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>enrollment trends of students who are parents or caregivers of dependent children to attend certain institutions or types of institutions, and whether such trends and preferences are based on the availability of institutional support services for such students, such as campus-based childcare, student parent centers, and grants under the Child Care Access Means Parents in School Program under subpart 7 of part A of title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070e">20 U.S.C. 1070e</external-xref>);</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE0A49E5F78404B00A3309EA9275D1C59" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the percentage of children served by campus-based childcare services who are the children of students, compared to the percentage of such children who are children of faculty, staff, and other community members, disaggregated by—</text> <subparagraph id="HDFE54FA02F354146B3F7741CE6789D8D" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>race, ethnicity, gender, employment or student status (including faculty, staff, community member, and student status), and family income of the parent of such children; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF97679E35FF345BE86AE09EFB5341771" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>only with respect to students who are parents of such children, the type of program in which the student is enrolled (such as an associate, baccalaureate, or graduate degree program, or a certificate program); and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H62A01B0346A14A5687C9685DB6F73163"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the strategies used by institutions of higher education for integration of on-campus services for students who are parents or caregivers of dependent children with other State and institution-provided services, such as the supplemental nutrition assistance program established under the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2011">7 U.S.C. 2011 et seq.</external-xref>), the program of block grants for States for temporary assistance for needy families established under part A of title IV of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/601">42 U.S.C. 601 et seq.</external-xref>), the special supplemental nutrition program for women, infants, and children under the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1786">42 U.S.C. 1786</external-xref>), workforce programs including adult education and literacy activities (as defined in section 203 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3272">29 U.S.C. 3272</external-xref>)), and Head Start and Early Head Start programs carried out under the Head Start Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9831">42 U.S.C. 9831 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1FC1DF683A30464385F61DE8A2E45B02"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report and dissemination of findings</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Education shall report the findings of the study conducted under <internal-xref idref="H53812335932B4AA89451FB049A385A2E" legis-path="2.(c)(1)">subsection (a)</internal-xref> to Congress, and make such findings publicly available. Such findings shall include information on the best practices identified by the Secretary to be most effective at improving outcomes for students attending institutions of higher education who are parents or caregivers of dependent children.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H3EF9DEEF44424CD48A1C56B095765957"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="H4C33EA55348B480F980D277E4020CF46"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text>The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given the term section 102 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1002">20 U.S.C. 1002</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H91C195DBABC546DA94C97C8E68A12602"><enum>(2)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> has the meaning given the term in section 103 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1003">20 U.S.C. 1003</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

