<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD28B2B5284E6494C934A311F52F2A6D1" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 339 IH: Supporting the Second Amendment’s guarantee that the right of the people to keep and bear arms shall not be infringed, and commending President Trump and his administration as they work to protect Second Amendment freedoms by reviewing and eliminating any of the Biden administration’s infringements on American’s constitutional freedoms.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 339</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250417">April 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000816">Mr. Williams of Texas</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001291">Mr. Babin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001325">Mrs. Biggs of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001118">Mr. Cline</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001115">Mr. Cloud</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001132">Mr. Crane</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001120">Mr. Crenshaw</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000634">Mr. Downing</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000246">Mr. Fallon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001099">Mr. Haridopolos</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001067">Mr. Hudson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000596">Mrs. Luna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001240">Mr. McDowell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001228">Mr. Schmidt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000490">Mr. Taylor</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000829">Mr. Wied</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Supporting the Second Amendment’s guarantee that the right of the people to keep and bear arms shall not be infringed, and commending President Trump and his administration as they work to protect Second Amendment freedoms by reviewing and eliminating any of the Biden administration’s infringements on American’s constitutional freedoms.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the Second Amendment to the Constitution safeguards the right of the people to keep and bear arms, declaring that such right shall not be infringed;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas James Madison, the father of the Second Amendment, stated, <quote>Americans have the right and advantage of being armed—unlike citizens of other countries whose governments are afraid to trust the people with arms.</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas it has nonetheless been a stated goal of the Biden administration to restrict, burden, and undermine the ability of ordinary law-abiding citizens to exercise their right to keep and bear arms, by encouraging Federal, State, and local lawmakers to pass gun control measures that self-evidently violate the spirit and letter of the Second Amendment despite the understanding of the Second Amendment as an important protection against crime, tyranny, and oppression;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas there have been an increased number of rules issued by the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives (ATF) in recent years aimed at restricting Americans’ right to keep and bear arms;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Bureau of Industry and Security (BIS) has restricted the fundamental Second Amendment right enumerated in the Bill of Rights by implementing policies that limit commercial firearm exports without providing adequate reasoning to why such a prohibition is necessary; </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas President Trump has vehemently defended the constitutional right to own and purchase firearms by peeling back the Biden administration’s flagrant gun-control measures;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas President Trump is protecting law-abiding gunowners from the infringements of ATF and BIS policies; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas President Trump continues to empower law-abiding gunowners and firearm manufactures to ensure the Second Amendment remains secure: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H894C5208B6B648B18F2BC59C66E1BD8D"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H2CA2F5112535456798E8E2156B09CAE3"><enum/><text>That the House of Representatives— </text><paragraph id="H88C05C206A0E4E25A8BF6562C0F3416B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>reaffirms the support for the Second Amendment and the constitutional guarantee that the right of the people to keep and bear arms shall not be infringed;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H87997BB824624734BE1EEFC7EB6BDB08"><enum>(2)</enum><text>disapproves of the Biden administration’s gun control agenda and hostility towards the lawful gun industry;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H68C1107366AD4DB18D9274997C79472C"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">disapproves of rule and policy changes by the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives under the Biden administration to restrict citizen’s Second Amendment right;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD7BC5CBBCAF845D79905B4387F481884"><enum>(4)</enum><text>disapproves of the Bureau of Industry and Security policies to limit lawful firearm exports and bad-faith attacks on civilian gun ownership;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H30CECEBE843C48C0AD8E6F36C85D823C"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supports President Trump’s actions to repeal harmful policies imposed by the Biden administration on law-abiding gunowners; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAFA1767C45E84560A12A6CD4544FE377"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">commends President Trump’s commitment to upholding the Constitution and defending the constitutional right to bear arms.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

