<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD84A13A8AB4F4D19A6277CBB62BA15BA" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 715 IH: Expressing support for the designation of the week of September 15, 2025, as “National Latino Gastronomic Cuisine Week”, and celebrating the vibrant and diverse culinary traditions of Latino gastronomy.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 715</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250915">September 15, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001226">Mr. Menendez</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001200">Mr. Soto</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000599">Mr. Ruiz</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of the week of September 15, 2025, as <quote>National Latino Gastronomic Cuisine Week</quote>, and celebrating the vibrant and diverse culinary traditions of Latino gastronomy.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas Latino cuisine is an integral part of the cultural heritage of the United States and reflects a wide range of culinary traditions originating in Latin America and the Caribbean;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Latino cuisine, characterized by its diverse ingredients, techniques, and flavors, has contributed to the development of new culinary trends and fusion cuisines in the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Latino cuisine incorporates centuries of Indigenous, European, African, and other culinary influences;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Latino chefs, home cooks, and culinary entrepreneurs play a vital role in the innovation, preservation, and sharing of Latino culinary traditions;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Latino gastronomic sector significantly contributes to the United States economy, including through restaurants, Latino-owned businesses, food markets, agricultural producers, and culinary tourism, providing employment and entrepreneurial opportunities for millions of Americans;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas celebrating Latino cuisine promotes cultural understanding and appreciation among all Americans, highlighting the importance of food as a cultural expression and fostering greater inclusivity and respect for cultural diversity;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas celebrating Latino gastronomic cuisine can support the allocation of funding and resources to Latino culinary initiatives, including educational programs and community projects; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas supporting educational initiatives can foster greater awareness and appreciation of Latino cuisine among students on college campuses: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H8CEF4E30022C42EBB39BF4F358AA2CD4"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HA964DEB7C2EE463CAE04DEDB2629848E"><enum/><text>That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="H71CDE865C7DA4C06AEB0FE27F4D56E1A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the designation of <quote>National Latino Gastronomic Cuisine Week</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1908BC3C57C44F958E68A486B588DC64"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the culinary influences of Latino cuisine that bring together a vibrant tapestry of traditions, technique, and flavors, creating a gastronomic experience celebrated worldwide;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H59F3F8D3618F4E2BA9A49CB6F67BBDAD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>supports the goal of bringing awareness to Latino gastronomy and cultivating an appreciation for innovative culinary practices in Latin cuisine; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8EB9382717ED4DE29A4EBA435332090D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>encourages Federal agencies, local governments, and community organizations to collaborate in supporting initiatives that promote Latino gastronomy, including funding for culinary education, food festivals, and cultural exchange programs, to enhance the visibility and appreciation of Latino culinary heritage across the Nation.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

