<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H80C2FFC11CC14BD884F98C523B63F033" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4525 IH: Right to FDA-Approved Medicines Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4525</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250717">July 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000305">Ms. Ross</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S001216">Ms. Schrier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001066">Ms. Castor of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000482">Mrs. Trahan</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000468">Mrs. Fletcher</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To protect an individuals ability to access medicines approved by the Food and Drug Administration to protect a health care providers ability to provide such medicines, and information related to such medicines.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE2DAD425F51D448881F91419A26AB44D" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H7245F776A52245909F193894FB986DF6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Right to FDA-Approved Medicines Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H07E47A8BB42E405BB59DF14FBAC431A6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
<paragraph id="HC56D4C8FA1614B61883F44F7EBAE3503"><enum>(1)</enum><header>FDA-approved medicine</header><text>The term <quote>FDA-approved medicine</quote> means any drug approved under section 505 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/355">21 U.S.C. 355</external-xref>) or licensed under section 351 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/262">42 U.S.C. 262</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H93199A66A47A4A0AA2CBE255BD5135C2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Government</header><text>The term <quote>government</quote> includes each branch, department, agency, instrumentality, and official of the United States or a State.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB0D35002BBFB42008F9ABBD5A2EFD165"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Health care provider</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>health care provider</quote> means any entity or individual (including any physician, certified nurse-midwife, nurse, nurse practitioner, physician assistant, and pharmacist) that is licensed or otherwise authorized by a State to prescribe FDA-approved medicines.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC9BAE2BCDEBB44AF8C9B59E542953460"><enum>(4)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <quote>State</quote> includes each of the 50 States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, and each territory and possession of the United States, and any political subdivision of any of the foregoing, including any unit of local government, such as a county, city, town, village, or other general purpose political subdivision of a State.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="HF3011EBCE72E4E6684646BA531B32F8F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purposes of this Act are—</text> <paragraph id="HB6C1BEFF3D284433AFD27C392F44F6C8"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to provide a clear and comprehensive right to FDA-approved medicines; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H077C6BAE3B7D4B6F89A00A0D5A03E8CE"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to permit individuals to seek and obtain FDA-approved medicines and to permit health care providers to facilitate prescribing such medicines.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HD97B61CFB368492C8C7FB1C81BD2B8F5"><enum>4.</enum><header>Permitted services</header> <subsection id="HF30B33A4E7414FA0B6A0E7DB6814C3F3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual has a statutory right under this Act to obtain FDA-approved medicines free from coercion, and a health care provider has a corresponding right to provide FDA-approved medicines, and information, referrals, and services related to such medicines.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H09D83646D724425AB970FE86C648C28E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitations or requirements</header><text>The statutory rights specified in subsection (a) shall not be limited or otherwise infringed through any limitation or requirement that—</text> <paragraph id="HA60DE9A385B94DBDB5A074C0F78974E7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>expressly, effectively, implicitly, or as-implemented singles out—</text>
<subparagraph id="H42FC6A96A5A943CB9DF6EE7D16D4F9DE"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the provision of FDA-approved medicines, or information related to such medicines;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB9666D6B638E44829208D457D1F975B8"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">health care providers who provide FDA-approved medicines or information related to such medicines; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HEAF20623881643F0A051F131F52965EB"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">facilities in which FDA-approved medicines or information related to such medicines; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6409A1C4E7E544989FA45524CB1C34A0"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">impedes access to FDA-approved medicines or information related to such medicines.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HEF2D8DE0653E455A8EA6794FA1910955"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>To defend against a claim that a limitation or requirement violates a health care provider’s or individual’s statutory rights under subsection (b), a party must establish, by clear and convincing evidence, that—</text> <paragraph id="H0591991A02B745E4944565BB5549EBD1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the limitation or requirement significantly advances access to FDA-approved medicines, and information related to such medicines; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H96B338821D08455E9C9DE00F3683F16B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">access to FDA-approved medicines and information related to such medicines or the health of patients cannot be advanced by a less restrictive alternative measure or action.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H48086ED308BF40929ADE82D14DD65A14"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit the authority of the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Commissioner of Food and Drugs, to approve a drug under section 505 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/355">21 U.S.C. 355</external-xref>) or license a drug under section 351 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/262">42 U.S.C. 262</external-xref>), or for the Federal Government to enforce such approval or licensure.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="HC12C78C31E654E298F90F948A46156F2"><enum>5.</enum><header>Applicability and preemption</header>
<subsection id="H20040E3FE3C94452806FE0F3FCB94070"><enum>(a)</enum><header>General application</header>
<paragraph id="HD419950387A4486B9B9C33BEA9C9D7B9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (c), this Act supersedes and applies to the law of the Federal Government and each State, and the implementation of such law, whether statutory, common law, or otherwise, and whether adopted before or after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2F67F087F69E4183B81D966C1DC01907"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>Neither the Federal Government nor any State may administer, implement, or enforce any law, rule, regulation, standard, or other provision having the force and effect of law in a manner that—</text>
<subparagraph id="H149CB4A566EE4168BF19D7075191CD1F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prohibits or restricts the sale, provision, or use of any FDA-approved medicines (as defined in section 2(2));</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2F40C526CE6C4E2BA32CDA4FA66D5044"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prohibits or restricts any individual from aiding another individual in voluntarily obtaining or using any FDA-approved medicines; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H26315FABC7234ABEAE4A2088721EF758"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">exempts any FDA-approved medicines from any other generally applicable law in a way that would make it more difficult to sell, provide, obtain, or use such medicines.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFB86A0E4BB9F4F958042E720FC3973EB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Relationship with other laws</header><text>This Act applies notwithstanding any other provision of Federal law, including the Religious Freedom Restoration Act of 1993 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000bb">42 U.S.C. 2000bb et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H24E5007F80B0417E911D3FECB48507AA">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Subsequently enacted Federal legislation</header>
 <text>Federal law enacted after the date of enactment of this Act is subject to this Act, unless such law explicitly excludes such application by reference to this Act.</text>
      </subsection>
<subsection id="HC3A88AF9F364467E9250DCC59943E545"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Limitations</header><text>The provisions of this Act shall not supersede or otherwise affect any provision of Federal law relating to coverage under (and shall not be construed as requiring the provision of specific benefits under) group health plans or group or individual health insurance coverage or coverage under a Federal health care program (as defined in section 1128B(f) of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 1320a–7b(f))), including coverage provided under section 1905(a)(4)(C) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396d">42 U.S.C. 1396d(a)(4)(C)</external-xref>) and section 2713 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg-13">42 U.S.C. 300gg–13</external-xref>).</text></subsection> <subsection id="HDEED3EAE03DE4340BFBA3AA46F0B8976"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Defense</header><text>In any cause of action against an individual or entity who is subject to a limitation or requirement that violates this Act, in addition to the remedies specified in section 7, this Act shall also apply to, and may be raised as a defense by, such an individual or entity.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H7B0CD3B8236B484B84C8C02C13792E64"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This Act shall take effect immediately upon the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H53ADA3C637A445A29CD2B7590BE1F902"><enum>6.</enum><header>Rules of construction</header> <subsection id="H531F8202B08F40DFB4CE2B073E7B1813"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In interpreting the provisions of this Act, a court shall liberally construe such provisions to effectuate the purposes described in section 3.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H4EEACB19BCF040CF95B73143FEFD98B7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed to authorize any government to interfere with a health care provider’s ability to provide FDA-approved medicines or information related to such medicines or a patient’s ability to obtain such medicines.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H5E073AD5335C40869D088495AFD259E5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Other individuals considered as government officials</header><text>Any individual who, by operation of a provision of Federal or State law, is permitted to implement or enforce a limitation or requirement that violates section 4 shall be considered a government official for purposes of this Act.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="H0AD6389D95E94342AEE999F4634CBF47"><enum>7.</enum><header>Enforcement</header>
<subsection id="HA17D8919AB8840538B5D7D77DCFD838B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Attorney general</header><text>The Attorney General may commence a civil action on behalf of the United States against any State that violates, or against any government official (including an individual described in section 6(c)) that implements or enforces a limitation or requirement that violates, section 4. The court shall hold unlawful and set aside the limitation or requirement if it is in violation of this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H70294EB6F3A94769B3F80A72504877F4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Private right of action</header> <paragraph id="H8BE8747D10C64B34B9E5D468B02498BF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any individual or entity, including any health care provider or patient, adversely affected by an alleged violation of this Act, may commence a civil action against any State that violates, or against any government official (including an individual described in section 6(c)) that implements or enforces a limitation or requirement that violates, section 4. The court shall hold unlawful and set aside the limitation or requirement if it is in violation of this Act.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5B84837AA1DB440496FD3EF0BF000AB3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Health care provider</header><text>A health care provider may commence an action for relief on its own behalf, on behalf of the provider’s staff, and on behalf of the provider’s patients who are or may be adversely affected by an alleged violation of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H4B7A2244AEBA4361873FF5266B5E3B5A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Equitable relief</header><text>In any action under this section, the court may award appropriate equitable relief, including temporary, preliminary, and permanent injunctive relief.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H5A3130D8D9B8447C97FA836AAC097AF2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Costs</header><text>In any action under this section, the court shall award costs of litigation, as well as reasonable attorney’s fees, to any prevailing plaintiff. A plaintiff shall not be liable to a defendant for costs or attorney’s fees in any nonfrivolous action under this section.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H1573BCAC38964BEB96B8CCB8F7B20F6A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Jurisdiction</header><text>The district courts of the United States shall have jurisdiction over proceedings under this Act and shall exercise the same without regard to whether the party aggrieved shall have exhausted any administrative or other remedies that may be provided for by law.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H3CAF8340C65C4E988D6524DD2E7F08F0"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Abrogation of state immunity</header><text>Neither a State that enforces or maintains, nor a government official (including an individual described in section 6(c)) who is permitted to implement or enforce any limitation or requirement that violates section 4 shall be immune under the Tenth Amendment to the Constitution of the United States, the Eleventh Amendment to the Constitution of the United States, or any other source of law, from an action in a Federal or State court of competent jurisdiction challenging that limitation or requirement.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H0994D9A7A40F46BEAD0F9999338EFA30"><enum>8.</enum><header>Severability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any provision of this Act, or the application of such provision to any individual, entity, government, or circumstance, is held to be unconstitutional, the remainder of this Act, or the application of such provision to all other individuals, entities, governments, or circumstances, shall not be affected thereby.</text></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

