<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC25F408F8E3049B0B7AB90F0728492F3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5507 IH: Hidden Foster Care Transparency Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5507</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250919">September 19, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001224">Mr. Moran</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require States to measure and publicly report on the separation of children from parents by hidden foster care arrangements, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H3977D4C6160B4915A8A57B965F2BA488" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H6EB4C30F5AE840B2A18999DBF55A2D48"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Hidden Foster Care Transparency Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H23CA4C239C5F4DD69B541C5030D47728"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="HABE8EC02C54742D3B6933C35D60E688D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>CPS agency</header><text>The term <term>CPS agency</term> means the State agency responsible for the administration of the State plans under parts B and E of title IV of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/621">42 U.S.C. 621 et seq.</external-xref>, 671 et seq.) and any State, county, local, or tribal child protective services agency.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1CE5B18F3D0F4059974FA82FA8E75982"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Hidden foster care arrangement</header> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE6C65C0AE88D493D82BAC70ABC75051C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>hidden foster care arrangement</term> means any separation of a child from the child’s parents or primary caregivers that occurs without the State taking responsibility for the care or placement of the child and without a court order or the involvement and oversight of a court of law, whether voluntary or involuntary. Such term includes a separation of a child that occurs—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4B71843F0566438C9138926D9DEAC19D"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">following a child protection hotline call or during an investigation by a CPS agency; or</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9548C2FB44F8414483C68B23DF664DA5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>while a CPS agency has any involvement with a child’s parents or primary caregivers but without the State taking responsibility for the care or placement of the child and without a court order or the involvement and oversight of a court of law, whether voluntary or involuntary.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0A42500C1BD14C74897ABEF636C38B04"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Included arrangements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such term includes—</text> 
<clause id="H8CD180A44EB3434AA994869AFE0504DF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any arrangement in which a CPS agency suggests, implies, or insists that a parent should or must permit the parent’s child to live with someone else in response to an investigation of allegations that the parent, or a spouse, partner, or other individual who resides with the parent, has neglected or abused the child; and</text></clause> <clause id="H967930F93DAD4677B065395912A16525"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any arrangement commonly referred to as <quote>kinship diversion,</quote><quote>foster care diversion,</quote><quote>safety planning,</quote><quote>informal family planning,</quote> or <quote>hidden foster care</quote> to the extent that such arrangement occurs without a court order or court oversight.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCFA97C6EDDDC467FABF263C50C21889D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBB85C164EFA044FDBAC01663E4969950"><enum>(4)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> has the meaning given that term in section 1101(a) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1301">42 U.S.C. 1301(a)</external-xref>) for purposes of parts B and E of title IV of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/621">42 U.S.C. 621 et seq.</external-xref>, 671 et seq.).</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H5D577F63253947C5923CBAD80883FC28"><enum>3.</enum><header>State reports on hidden foster care arrangements</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">As a condition for payment of funds under a State plan approved under part E of title IV of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/671">42 U.S.C. 671 et seq.</external-xref>), a State shall submit to the Secretary as part of the Adoption and Foster Care Analysis and Reporting System (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/679">42 U.S.C. 679</external-xref>) data that specifies, for each such fiscal year—</text> <paragraph id="H79CDB0F26B11420AA6BBF103595BAB84"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the number of children separated from their parents by a hidden foster care arrangement;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB6695DB39F4A4D21946D8DC2D7034052"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the number of hidden foster care arrangements that ended without the child entering the formal foster care system;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA5B41AFE0C334BEC945B3E75D4CE0A35"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the number of hidden foster care arrangements that ended through the placement of the child into the formal foster care system;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H970F1D1484F4487393A920A7F5A53EC7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the category or type of allegation raised in each case which resulted in a separation of a child from their parents by a hidden foster care arrangement;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H26EFE473E92D4CB4B28DC71B78DB8B57"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to the extent data is available, the number of caregivers in a hidden foster care arrangement who received additional services including referrals to kinship navigator programs, prevention services programs funded under part B or E of title IV of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/621">42 U.S.C. 621 et seq.</external-xref>, 671 et seq.), services provided by an entity or organization other than a CPS agency, or to legal counsel;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCDDD0E0D30E8442DA2ECA13C1B94F54F">
                <enum>(6)</enum>
 <text>the result of any investigation leading to a hidden foster care arrangement (whether an allegation is substantiated or indicated or not substantiated or indicated);</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF4F9029122F64DFCAF132CD1FD6C597F"><enum>(7)</enum><text>how many parents—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1C89516B02254288A97102DDF2056D7B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">were—</text> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H523B048A264E466EBF06C25F713D332C"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provided legal counsel; or</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H218B6EEA99E34445B7BD18800F6A9B14"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">referred to a legal services provider before a hidden foster care arrangement began or within 72 hours of such an arrangement; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H493AB77161F74009AC03F2349411F0B3"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">were actually represented by legal counsel within 72 hours of such an arrangement;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5DD9700774AD485C9D18D3D291620FCF"><enum>(8)</enum><text>the length of time children were in a hidden foster care arrangement, including the number of children in a hidden foster care arrangement for more than 90 days without any court orders addressing custody;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H02150625FB4E452E87844DBD32A4D63B"><enum>(9)</enum><text>the number of children who left hidden foster care arrangements—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H389392719DE2440B8BCEE871A65CD3C3"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by reunification with the parent or guardian from whom they were initially separated;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H705D77F744954DEAB0F0071AA51F4D4E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by returning to a different parent or guardian; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8F7D83C1413D4F72A27DFFAF7E7F5BC9"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">through—</text> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H55FF5F94D3AE442293D5AE48387599D4"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a kinship caregiver obtaining legal custody or guardianship outside of the foster care system;</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H13A63EF1585B4CA3A2C8226EE8419B8B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">entry in the foster care system and placement with kin; and</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5C5D532D604C4431A81C386C66243096"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">entry in the foster care system and placement with someone else;</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFE619E9B51DC4A33ABD799C1F132D38F"><enum>(10)</enum><text>a list of specific services provided to parents, children, and kinship caregivers affected by a hidden foster care arrangement and, for each such group, the number and specific services provided; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDB9D5D0776874D1CB864902A0BCAC6CD" commented="no"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a list of reports of substantiated abuse or neglect made to a CPS agency within 3, 6, 9, or 12 months after a child is identified as being in a hidden foster care arrangement, where the child was living at time of report.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HEBA4A6B393FD45F4A55B21FB47601DC8"><enum>4.</enum><header>Secretarial responsibilities</header> <subsection id="H61149289A5C5455690F2053BBDA02715"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Annual report to Congress on hidden foster care arrangement practices</header><text>The Secretary shall submit an annual report to Congress based on the most recent State reports submitted under section 3. Each annual report shall include the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H461F24967E7E44B69DEE10459C2CAC55"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The total number of children for whom a hidden foster care arrangement ended during the fiscal year reported on, and of that number—</text> <subparagraph id="H64343466C79241B7B34C88ECC609933D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>how many of the hidden foster care arrangement ended without the child entering the formal foster care system; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE76A17A7200D4BC1892390ED38C29772"><enum>(B)</enum><text>how many of the hidden foster care arrangement ended through the placement of the child into the formal foster care system.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4F46DAB7C2774471B214E004B4AC0AA4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The total number of each category or type of allegation raised in a case which resulted in a separation of a child from their parents by a hidden foster care arrangement.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF22B8DAAE30046F0AC8AE9F31C968CD1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>To the extent data is available, the number of caregivers in a hidden foster care arrangement who received additional services, including referrals to kinship navigator programs, prevention services programs funded under part B or E of title IV of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/621">42 U.S.C. 621 et seq.</external-xref>, 671 et seq.), services provided by an entity or organization other than a CPS agency, or legal counsel.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4F012AFE10894768BA1F1F506CF48523"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The number of States that submit a report under section 3 for the fiscal year involved and a summary of such reports that includes a summary of the ways in which States address hidden foster care arrangements within the most recent State plan reports submitted part B or E of title IV of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/621">42 U.S.C. 621 et seq.</external-xref>, 671 et seq.).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD08BFE046C6E4DA7952F57880DD1887E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Implementation</header> 
<paragraph id="H2EFAAA882DA3429BB0F9906953A203C4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Consistent data</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that, to the extent practicable, the data and information required to be reported under section 3—</text> <subparagraph id="HDF6E1FFF22D94AA9B8038AEDE48D3F51"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is collected and reported in a reliable and standardized manner by all States;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1D399C2F12744700B16038DD639AF304"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provides a comprehensive, national picture of the practice of hidden foster care arrangements; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H19FC5513D7B5468DA709837A7F183E8E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>draws upon and does not duplicate other required child welfare data collection and reporting regarding children for, or on whose behalf, prevention services are offered, including under section 471(e)(5)(B)(x) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/671">42 U.S.C. 671(e)(5)(B)(x)</external-xref>), section 479 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/679">42 U.S.C. 679</external-xref>), and subparagraphs (C) and (D) of section 103(c)(1) of the Child Abuse Prevention and Treatment Act and 106(d) of the Child Abuse Prevention and Treatment Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5103">42 U.S.C. 5103(c)(1)</external-xref>, 5106a(d)).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H70AE08FBF3E748F38BF5BBCE62BB0A1B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Guidance; technical assistance</header><text>The Secretary may use funds made available to carry out part E of title IV of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/671">42 U.S.C. 671 et seq.</external-xref>) to issue guidance or provide technical assistance to States with respect to the data and information required to be reported under section 3.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDD360762658F45429795153ED0CF7017"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Publication and manner of submission</header><text>The Secretary—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HC3BE6784CA1B4860B98BD08BA1428E13"><enum>(A)</enum><text>may include the report required by subsection (a) in the annual compilation of State reports required to be submitted to Congress under section 479A of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/679b">42 U.S.C. 679b</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFEAE49FEE270426190AE5E2F34396CDF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall make each report submitted to Congress in accordance with subsection (a) publicly available.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

