<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H29DCAD850AB14A30A323330E79B1E761" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5462 IH: Michelle Alyssa Go Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5462</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250918">September 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001120">Mr. Crenshaw</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001226">Ms. Salinas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001159">Ms. Strickland</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to revise the definition of institution for mental diseases under the Medicaid program to exclude from such definition institutions having 36 beds or less if such institutions meet certain standards.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9FD9ACDE9C744929BCE502323C4B1B77" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HFE1338E752134DF39897FFD5FF4CCA54" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Michelle Alyssa Go Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H6CC6EA445391495B8DD0F0BFE0C7349B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Revising the definition of institution for mental diseases under the Medicaid program to exclude from such definition institutions having 36 beds or less if such institutions meet certain standards</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1905(i) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396d">42 U.S.C. 1396d(i)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HAC4A1FAE0E734288B8A2275085023927" display-inline="no-display-inline">
<subsection id="HE7989C767ED8440DADFD5295A64D5801"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Institution for mental diseases</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>institution for mental diseases</quote> means a hospital, nursing facility, or other institution that is primarily engaged in providing diagnosis, treatment, or care of persons with mental diseases, including medical attention, nursing care, and related services, unless such hospital, facility, or other institution—</text> <paragraph id="HF28B9ED47C8F40FAB4D86EFC1D59F831"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has 36 beds or less; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF40FD0AFF9F349E7BB593FAD6A83C027"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">meets nationally recognized, evidence-based standards for mental health programs (and, in the case of an institution for mental diseases that provides treatment for substance use disorders, meets nationally recognized, evidence-based standards for substance use disorder programs, such as the latest standards set forth by the American Society of Addiction Medicine) approved by the Secretary, including standards that establish the types of services offered, hours of clinical care, and staffing credentials for such an institution, and any other standards as the Secretary may require.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section id="H45D4E6471FAC40E1B0472C66FEFEAE09"><enum>3.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The amendments made by this Act shall take effect 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act and shall apply to State plans beginning on such date.</text></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

