<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-HEN25016-J1T-XJ-WJW"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S88 IS: No Budget, No Pay Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 88</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250114">January 14, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S404">Mr. Scott of Florida</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S402">Ms. Rosen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S416">Mrs. Britt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S417">Mr. Budd</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S355">Mr. Cruz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S375">Mr. Daines</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S420">Mr. Schmitt</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To provide that Members of Congress may not receive pay after October 1 of any fiscal year in which Congress has not approved a concurrent resolution on the budget and passed the regular appropriations bills.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No Budget, No Pay Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idec74b5e155a049ceb6e788330098a58f"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act—</text><paragraph id="id3E44C5B7E30241FCBA92082B6119BF6C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>Budget and Appropriations Chairs</term> means the House Budget and Appropriations Chairs and the Senate Budget and Appropriations Chairs; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2B40532BA9D14FD5AC3841FC197DB2A6"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>House Budget and Appropriations Chairs</term> means the Chair of the Committee on the Budget of the House of Representatives and the Chair of the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7A5320D383EE41A7B8F02B067A7A243E"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>Member of Congress</term>—</text><subparagraph id="idf8469d9d0c754f35b2bc796875215a6f"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has the meaning given that term under section 2106 of title 5, United States Code; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide04754fa53be49f49f3c8211dda24e3b"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include the Vice President; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idBC4D74503A1243E3B847A78AEDCD63D9"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>Senate Budget and Appropriations Chairs</term> means the Chairman of the Committee on the Budget of the Senate and the Chairman of the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate. </text></paragraph></section><section id="idd6b0cc61098c4365a2ef8c0764a89c80"><enum>3.</enum><header>Timely approval of concurrent resolution on the budget and the appropriations bills</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than October 1 of each fiscal year, both Houses of Congress shall—</text><paragraph id="idB9EB31398CC54740B542E995B51DCC90"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">approve a concurrent resolution on the budget as described under section 301 of the Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/632">2 U.S.C. 632</external-xref>) for that the fiscal year; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="idF8BFD22029A64AECBA963955C061721B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">pass all the regular appropriations bills for that fiscal year.</text></paragraph></section><section id="idf2873e1e7ab24b7b95a0a9890b41e7a1"><enum>4.</enum><header>No pay without concurrent resolution on the budget and the appropriations bills</header><subsection id="id2d2dcfb287db495e91ad233c44a36673"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no funds may be appropriated or otherwise be made available from the Treasury of the United States for the pay of any Member of Congress with respect to any period during which Congress is not in compliance with section 3, as determined by the Budget and Appropriations Chairs under section 5.</text></subsection><subsection id="idcf3ddc58b1ce48a8803fcd2015991d3c"><enum>(b)</enum><header>No retroactive pay</header><text>A Member of Congress may not receive pay with respect to any period during which Congress was not in compliance with section 3, as determined by the Budget and Appropriations Chairs under section 5, at any time after the end of that period.</text></subsection></section><section id="id28f66a47ec514653bf47aea4941683a0"><enum>5.</enum><header>Determinations</header><subsection id="id2dc7a4eae89b4507b746c9e0727bec36"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Senate</header><paragraph id="idc7da3d640688426a9ebd25cfd93cf4e3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Request for certifications</header><text>On October 1 of each year, the Secretary of the Senate shall submit to the Senate Budget and Appropriations Chairs a request for certification of determinations made under subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id36084d8ea8d9486cbe87f1aded067fa6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Determinations</header><text>The Senate Budget and Appropriations Chairs shall—</text><subparagraph id="id4e053f75a9db473b9e175ff2a51c430c"><enum>(A)</enum><text>on October 1 of each fiscal year, make a determination of whether Congress is in compliance with section 3 with respect to that fiscal year and whether Senators may not be paid under section 4;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9ba7246bc5b845b3ab12734c13050810"><enum>(B)</enum><text>determine the period of days following each October 1 that Senators may not be paid under section 4; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd6d587d2af0a46c3840a143897e9d9ae"><enum>(C)</enum><text>provide timely certification of the determinations under subparagraphs (A) and (B) upon the request of the Secretary of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id89a2fb248c01485aa191b4988598363d"><enum>(b)</enum><header>House of Representatives</header><paragraph id="id4fce731653e14c19b9d721a027c31603"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Request for certifications</header><text>On October 1 of each fiscal year, the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives shall submit to the House Budget and Appropriations Chairs a request for certification of determinations made under subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida306df4d0e6244b7900b703d95c78188"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Determinations</header><text>The House Budget and Appropriations Chairs shall—</text><subparagraph id="id5a810be776654ad6b11c4071ea771ff6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>on October 1 of each fiscal year, make a determination of whether Congress is in compliance with section 3 with respect to that fiscal year and whether Members of the House of Representatives may not be paid under section 4;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0d00a6142f024de186730555da452894"><enum>(B)</enum><text>determine the period of days following each October 1 that Members of the House of Representatives may not be paid under section 4; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id99bc179f284f4dd29fc25a5163e81c9a"><enum>(C)</enum><text>provide timely certification of the determinations under subparagraphs (A) and (B) upon the request of the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id9e6b282eecf8462a8900d4db2728ce72"><enum>6.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act shall take effect on September 29, 2027.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

