<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB1D1222A6A7B47CA80C0680041E6026B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>101 HR 848 IH: Voluntary Food Climate Labeling Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 848</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250131">January 31, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001117">Mr. Casten</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to establish a voluntary food climate labeling program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE814DA1639414BDFA3482C8E2B059874" style="OLC"><section id="H006E9C0F14EA4D37B4C19B8687796360" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Voluntary Food Climate Labeling Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="HDB81D034C1D4411196E5FF690EA3ADA4" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Voluntary food climate labeling program</header><subsection id="H0D0676D613B44C9B9044381D67E3418E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><paragraph id="H994E9F04BCFC44D19BD2B92B6E7A7BD6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency shall carry out a voluntary food climate labeling program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB0D5164938DA4306831FEFBD51C3E8A3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall establish and operate the labeling program in consultation with the Secretary of Agriculture and the Federal Trade Commission.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9622597C22D040268B4D16741706AC77"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Administration of Program</header><paragraph id="HAD0F9C01ED744D75B38C0CA23A0FD0BF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person manufacturing, importing, distributing, or selling food may not place the food climate label developed under subsection (c) on the food or its labeling unless the Administrator has authorized such person to do so under paragraph (3).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2EA2472B0D36401896A5E2E53E6AF66E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applications</header><text>An applicant shall submit to the Administrator an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Administrator may require.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0C23D323111F49AA806A43E30D82AABE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Review of applications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall review all applications submitted under paragraph (2) and approve any such application—</text><subparagraph id="HAA5EB261547645DD970191F09A8F85E6"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">on the basis of whether the applicant provides assurances satisfactory to the Administrator that the applicant will adhere to the requirements of the labeling program; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDF2F5D22630F47A780CC0F2DCC2EABA9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not on the basis of an assessment of the benefits to the environment associated with the food.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEC9883954BAC4D43B39ECF7A4F83A2EA" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Placement of label</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Administrator approves an application under this subsection with respect to a food, the Administrator may specify where on the food or its labeling the food climate label shall be placed.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE068C416007D45CC8C09A31536247A86"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Development of food climate label</header><paragraph id="H49F25020439640BF9B6EA6769C2DCA63"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall specify—</text><subparagraph id="HF080A7C205944421A27C741E9F801475"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the visual form of the food climate label, as described in paragraph (3);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCA940A846C5E4300857DE87D91362566"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the information to be included on the food climate label, as described in paragraph (4); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H14BBFC6BDF6F4CC58402525BCBDE6E13"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the method by which the information to be included on the food climate label shall be verified, as described in paragraph (5).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB5A9B4EC00F7408DBF51CAF47ACF269A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In specifying the visual form, information to be included, and method for verification referred to in paragraph (1), the Administrator—</text><subparagraph id="H0069DE8379DF4CAE8112B20198281E9D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall consult with food industry stakeholders; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H164EC5C77D454A82A10789569680167A"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may perform such consultation—</text><clause id="HD0FA88601A7945219C794ADEFB7B1C8D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by establishing a Federal advisory committee under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/10">chapter 10</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code (commonly referred to as the <quote>Federal Advisory Committee Act</quote>); or</text></clause><clause id="H902EE03E794A4290992A42E41AA15E42"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>through a negotiated rulemaking under the Negotiated Rulemaking Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/101/648">Public Law 101–648</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H09E63B38B7A54A6C8B1413EEBEA8DC2A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Visual form</header><text>The visual form of the food climate label shall—</text><subparagraph id="H8EFD5DE52CA8451ABAA3D7764B443B71"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">convey the information described in paragraph (4) to the consumer in a manner that is determined by the Administrator to be most useful to the consumer at the point of sale in making food purchasing decisions;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H790802A8024B4263A3949BF791BED87D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not convey that any given food is acceptable or unacceptable, but instead provide to the consumer a numerical quantification of the information described in paragraph (4);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H09059D93FF274107B7E0E6C3CC52D27D"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">employ words, numbers, and imagery, as specified by the Administrator;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8F9B41B36ECC49AAB89604D71D990DFF"><enum>(D)</enum><text>convey that the information on the food climate label has been verified under requirements established by the Environmental Protection Agency;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC19DF944858F483CBDFDB70CAB1558F8"><enum>(E)</enum><text>include a logo (or other identifier) to help the consumer identify the food climate label; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H13953B15C53E436DA926645230899951"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include a quick response code (commonly known as a <quote>QR code</quote>) or similar mechanism that provides electronic access to the consumer at the point of sale to the information described in paragraph (4)(B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0A0607403EC84DDABE45059335376AFD"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Information to be included</header><subparagraph id="H112D5B055D5A4595AF03508FCB5C6E98"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Label</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The food climate label shall include two numerical summaries of the best available information regarding the total greenhouse gas emissions released throughout the lifecycle of the food and its input materials as follows:</text><clause id="HB10DEAB0E9164F138E4A2BBF2CE228E5"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The first numerical summary shall include the information on the greenhouse gas emissions released during—</text><subclause id="H5A6C3DC1D68E49468E22D83CB02B48E0"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the growing of ingredients;</text></subclause><subclause id="HB66A47D730124FF1892C98978BCD7A6F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the manufacture of the nonfood input materials;</text></subclause><subclause id="HEFB4E95B3975417DBBB291499E0FAEA7"><enum>(III)</enum><text>processing;</text></subclause><subclause id="HBA4C48EA2FD048FB85C95AF17C94EFB0"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>packaging; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H05F886E9C59643CF957DEFBF13054DF0"><enum>(V)</enum><text>distribution.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H9C30A43AAFCD47B4BCCE93BA4BB7A57F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The second numerical summary shall include the information on the greenhouse gas emissions released during—</text><subclause id="H7483DE41A12D470B9AF862D204DD186B"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">storage;</text></subclause><subclause id="H8B625743A82E4297AF9D3136F2C4AC8A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>presentation in a retail food establishment;</text></subclause><subclause id="HEB2278F3A2964CDBB299F719E7DBB83C"><enum>(III)</enum><text>consumer use, including the energy used to store the food after purchase;</text></subclause><subclause id="H060B937EF42B48C4AE3011DD28E6A622"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">end-of-life reuse, recycling, composting, treatment, and disposal of the food and its packaging; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H3821D1BBA3064331B0900D05FCB742F2"><enum>(V)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other aspect of the lifecycle of the food and its input materials.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H58911211C4DA4D0EBFB3D8A18E229AD9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Validation of summaries</header><clause id="H8C7C097C8BBA4463BD36C8215F8CE13D"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Validity of first numerical summary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The participant shall be responsible for the validity of the numerical summary required by subparagraph (A)(i).</text></clause><clause id="H1A8E29EF72E04D34A51CF6A0F5E9084A"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Validity of second numerical summary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall—</text><subclause id="H98B6AA8419394F29BFD99AA207ACC7BF"><enum>(I)</enum><text>be responsible for the validity of the numerical summary required by subparagraph (A)(ii); and</text></subclause><subclause id="H7898532285734A2F84227D0A794C6527"><enum>(II)</enum><text>develop such numerical summary in consultation with the participant referred to in clause (i) and the advisory committee established under paragraph (2)(B).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1F92CB37D00C4493B6CDA157A12E1974"><enum>(C)</enum><header>QR code</header><text>The QR code (or similar mechanism) referred to in paragraph (3)(F) shall provide access to the following information:</text><clause id="HC7A9256436064CC693D66C9E92249349"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the food is subject to a voluntary commitment under subsection (d), an indication that such food is subject to such commitment and a summary of the information reported pursuant to such commitment under such subsection.</text></clause><clause id="H884793A63FCE4AEA8A4FB0E8BCCE8FC6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The database established under subsection (e).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5E162AEA7937458092058C409CC4EF8C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Method of verification</header><subparagraph id="H12DD6B422FB944DEB9C45E7D228F887A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator shall specify the method by which the information included on the food climate label shall be verified. Such method shall include—</text><clause id="H9243B31734BA4854ACE35D4F11559673"><enum>(i)</enum><text>adhering to uniform standards for the collection and analysis of such information;</text></clause><clause id="H2B01E9F95A684387BF5F04E5EA27751C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>adhering to requirements for entities (certified by the Administrator for such purpose) to measure, monitor, verify, and report such information; and</text></clause><clause id="HD12B933A70B8411C90743E97C39F5A6D" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>using the best available scientific information.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H339BF0C30BB34BC4AAB51AE09C8BF4D0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>International standards</header><text>In developing the method under subparagraph (A), the Administrator shall consider the established international standards for carbon accounting for product lifecycle assessment, including—</text><clause id="H3995EE2E79434A34A9B09653E42D5387"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the ISO 14040 and ISO 14044 standards of the International Organization for Standardization; and</text></clause><clause id="HC626F915DA464947B7B8B98BB892AA76"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>protocols established under the Greenhouse Gas Protocol (commonly known as the <quote>GHG Protocol</quote>) program of the World Business Council for Sustainable Development and the World Resources Institute, including—</text><subclause id="H0B1AA601BBE14026A8AB4B5D5F5380F3"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the GHG Product Life Cycle Accounting and Reporting Standard; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H56C8E4E48686467EA68118201761BA22"><enum>(II)</enum><text>Publicly Available Specification 2050 (commonly known as <quote>PAS 2050</quote>).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1346EFFF711B452AA21230A553FF86D5"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Alignment with current best practices of food industry</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall ensure that the method under subparagraph (A) is informed by, and generally aligned with, the current best practices of the food industry for validating the information included on the food climate label.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDAA8D13C08C744E8AA483498CD8E769A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Voluntary commitments</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this section, the Administrator shall establish a program under which a manufacturer, importer, distributor, or seller of a food bearing the food climate label may, on a voluntary basis—</text><paragraph id="H4CC517D658A94E249976263298343E87"><enum>(1)</enum><text>make and report a voluntary commitment to reduce the greenhouse gas emissions associated with such food; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H893AEB2C73C64555BEC11ADE076A674E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>report sustainability information pertaining to the food based on the best available scientific information.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5B4B58FB4BB649A3B10D1B843C6927A4" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Database</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this section, the Administrator shall establish and make publicly accessible a database under an open license to provide consumers with easy access to information pertaining to the labeling program, including—</text><paragraph id="H15B5CAD003D946DFA3D8C7A5E14E271E" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">explanations of the objectives and the methodologies of the Administrator in developing the food climate label and in specifying the visual form, information to be included, and method for verification referred to in subsection (c)(1);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA926AD74F74843B5A1318567F9F17915" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the information described in clauses (i) and (ii) of subsection (c)(4)(B) with respect to each food in the labeling program;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H578CA34030DA48678583A3F9BC6FF5A7" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the voluntary commitments and sustainability information reported under subsection (d); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H619C006B222B41E89DC30A8C62E88AAF" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">as the Administrator determines appropriate, any sustainability information pertaining to food bearing the food climate label, based on the best available scientific information.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6F576672531B4F9F80F4BD6979A7840B" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 7 years after the date of enactment of this section, and every 5 years thereafter, the Administrator shall—</text><paragraph id="HEF9FF9D6402F4FD8AB58C4037FD59CD8" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>publish a report on the labeling program’s effectiveness in—</text><subparagraph id="H79F914415A3B48C6BB38EA1C0A7C6382" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>providing consumers information that consumers find useful; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H01BA7FC257E14C028F1EE37FE374F9FB" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reducing the greenhouse gas emissions associated with food throughout the lifecycle of the food and its input materials, as described in subsection (c)(4)(A); and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0444F8781C6942A3A5317F2FF9E67AA2" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submit to Congress a report containing any recommendations for legislative action that would improve the labeling program’s effectiveness in achieving the objectives described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H29AF71EEF9F14F19B39F10C162002239" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Regulations</header><paragraph id="H080C13CF1A9343C99597689F2EC88785"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this section, the Administrator shall finalize regulations to carry out the labeling program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H79AAD54FF59549129D269914725E3C45"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Updates</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 7 years after the date of enactment of this section, and every 5 years thereafter, the Administrator shall update the regulations for carrying out the labeling program to increase the labeling program’s effectiveness, as determined by the Administrator with regard to the objectives described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of subsection (f)(1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H86E53B3FA9B44D0C82F1B3A9872DF578" commented="no"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><paragraph id="H29AF9596CE00479ABF9247674F9B46FB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Administrator shall establish a technical assistance advisory board within the Environmental Protection Agency to provide technical assistance to—</text><subparagraph id="H0962BC30445448EE8D6A9835A165BE34" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>entities participating in or seeking to participate in the labeling program;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF659AEA430B7491AAC6D955A26692AEA" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>entities certified or seeking to become certified under subsection (c)(5)(A)(ii);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H22437AF9093D46EFAE9CF181B4D4021F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>entities making a voluntary commitment or seeking to make such commitment under subsection (d); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H17122AD7239F4F9D8B9E844F154DC01B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>retail food establishments.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC1BFD62BD57B435E859F3F943E2B5DEC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Composition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The technical assistance advisory board under paragraph (1) shall be comprised of subject matter experts and academics, trade associations, consultants, leaders of the Department of Agriculture, and representatives of industry and appropriate organizations.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8383AFE0E3634DF691AD9FEF76C5E2F2"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Consumer outreach</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this section, the Administrator shall establish a program to inform consumers about the labeling program by—</text><paragraph id="H3DCCDC04A7E94B7785064B0087D60504"><enum>(1)</enum><text>providing retail food establishments educational materials and other information to be conveyed to consumers regarding the labeling program, which materials and information shall display the logo (or other identifier) described in subsection (c)(3)(E); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H89A5149A5C7C463CA1D3F5C3B7383C64"><enum>(2)</enum><text>reaching the public through a wide range of venues, including public service announcements and advertising.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD6E1B53F80EC4AE7A119CDFA228341C6"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Penalties for fraudulent use of label</header><paragraph id="H3D0C62FA9DA547E9944397A75514ACE7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any person that violates a requirement of this section shall be subject to a civil penalty of not more than $10,000 for each such violation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H214101834B1B4343B67A62BB1DA6F56F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Separate violations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each separate violation of a requirement of this section with respect to a given type of food shall be a separate offense, except that in a case of a violation through continuing failure to obey or neglect to obey an order by the Administrator under this section, each day of continuance of such failure or neglect shall be deemed a separate offense.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H48522C3133AE48108FCF47A18CD75CA2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Equitable relief</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In a civil action brought under this section, the United States district courts are empowered to grant mandatory injunctions and such other equitable relief as such courts deem appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H32F59A20C16A4A47B0C98707D46767F4"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HEADD011B23A74C5898F6B3E9595AB405"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF87D75DE58EE4933ABC58A8D4D914060"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applicant</header><text>The term <term>applicant</term> means a person that—</text><subparagraph id="H1FD2E5D2DB944D75B245C79AB109FDE9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">manufactures, imports, distributes, or sells food; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H23742C4B9DE048C4B423C86932E0F8BA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has an application pending under subsection (b) to participate in the labeling program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0803CD0A334143B8AEBBDCAA6A62DA93"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Food industry stakeholders</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>food industry stakeholders</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H8235BFE7AFEC4395B28BC9EEF91FF06C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>entities that—</text><clause id="HBA5654F144A644F6AEA861008B39FF3D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>grow, raise, process, prepare, manufacture, or otherwise add value to a food product;</text></clause><clause id="H1FC198F490D042CD978132EA34377F1C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>store, package, repackage, transport, or distribute a food product for wholesale;</text></clause><clause id="H7FD1F1DE01384952A1623BDBB9FC160F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>sell a food product directly to consumers;</text></clause><clause id="H0E4BB2118A99477E9BDF5F9B9A498841"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>provide a food-related service to entities that engage in any of the activities described in clauses (i) through (iii);</text></clause><clause id="H3739B710C30F40E0AD50C3BF74F0C469"><enum>(v)</enum><text>measure, monitor, verify, and report the type of information to be included on the food climate label under subsection (c)(4); </text></clause><clause id="H44DEDB31FD4E43739F341D0F0B58831F"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>represent consumers of food products; or</text></clause><clause id="H67D4D8467E60481CB5B80BC762FE453D"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>study and analyze the food industry; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCA36AEF3C5544D69953646B929ED30D7"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">other relevant stakeholders, as determined by the Administrator.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H681CB5C9FC0442BB910553EBD0F4C54C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Greenhouse gas</header><text>The term <term>greenhouse gas</term> includes—</text><subparagraph id="H5D47A5262E1D4D90B93D416EA37DFF17"><enum>(A)</enum><text>carbon dioxide;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBD4C809BCC344A23B5435DC8F413C2B8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>methane;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0E6397FAA71145C49A47B839CF796320"><enum>(C)</enum><text>nitrous oxide;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H11171E4963194F8BB678D8795F359787"><enum>(D)</enum><text>sulfur hexafluoride;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7DCA21B1A1B341C6A8EC91E760B21A8C"><enum>(E)</enum><text>any hydrofluorocarbon;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H38B3CA3B0A5041E1AC4ECAF8B440BD1D"><enum>(F)</enum><text>any perfluorocarbon;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF66F11C69FD74076BE867CFF2283FC66"><enum>(G)</enum><text>nitrogen trifluoride;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H706D3BF1931846808A81AC949E394A2E"><enum>(H)</enum><text>any fully fluorinated linear, branched, or cyclic—</text><clause id="H363179DACCF34B03AE807AD38BC78AA8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>alkane;</text></clause><clause id="HD040F0D56FC54C158618CF1A0D4B713E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>ether;</text></clause><clause id="H6F1F86B0E88445B3BF5306FFB2A0D150"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>tertiary amine; or</text></clause><clause id="H193683778D3C4CD193C51112EFE450EB"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>aminoether;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H519A3A0049634D2F9BF4D3CB637A4277"><enum>(I)</enum><text>any perfluoropolyether;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAF39903117114D94A0B6A8E6AEC1165E"><enum>(J)</enum><text>any hydrofluoropolyether; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAB9F0AB3817F4643BB5C1233E7EEF4F6"><enum>(K)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other fluorocarbon, except for a fluorocarbon with a vapor pressure of less than 1 millimeter of mercury absolute at 25 degrees Celsius.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF4E5FFDF539649D0A1CE5A5CD8599D63"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Greenhouse gas emission</header><text>The term <term>greenhouse gas emission</term> means the release of a greenhouse gas into the ambient air.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H422492A875F54ACC87B7DDC44A382E97"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Labeling program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>labeling program</term> means the voluntary food climate labeling program established under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H21E3DCC132634DDD99F9CFFA227C0764"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Open license</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>open license</term> means any legally binding instrument that grants permission to access, reuse, and redistribute a work with few or no restrictions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBBFBE163982A4EDB881B864935C10C59"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Participant</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>participant</term> means, with respect to food, the person authorized pursuant to subsection (b) to place the food climate label developed under subsection (c) on the food or its labeling.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

