<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF3DAF7D6FEDF46EC8EE58E2BA950BDCA" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5267 IH: American Franchise Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5267</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250910">September 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001082">Mr. Hern of Oklahoma</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="D000230">Mr. Davis of North Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000134">Ms. Van Duyne</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001221">Ms. Scholten</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000246">Mr. Edwards</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000379">Mr. Alford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000605">Mr. Gray</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000048">Mr. Pfluger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001063">Mr. Cuellar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001224">Mr. Moran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001287">Mr. Bera</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000581">Mr. Vicente Gonzalez of Texas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001230">Mr. Mackenzie</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To preserve the franchise business model.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H4E3992B020AA4A579A9F775250CD1C0F" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H1A85BDBE06C04DBA88BB577BE2041D59" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>American Franchise Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HAD4DAD08CFAD467FBA02BD3990D3723D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
<paragraph id="H21D69287902E45C39F414D425642747B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A franchise is a commercial relationship under which a franchisee acquires the right to operate an independent business that offers, sells, or distributes goods or services using a franchisor’s system of operations, which typically includes the franchisor’s business system and marketing plan, and its service mark, trademark, trade dress, or trade name.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2F1B7FC63A8A41698E9D583421ED99C8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>To protect the integrity of its system of operations, a franchisor must set and enforce uniform quality, marketing, and operational standards that govern its use. Doing so helps maintain consistency and uniformity in the nature and quality of the goods and services distributed under the franchisor’s trademarks. That consistency and uniformity, in turn, help ensure that consumer expectations are satisfied, increase the value of the franchisor’s brand, and enhance the recognition and profitability of individual franchises.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8A7D6EEA03984CBA98494FA0A9076C39"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Although franchisees must comply with these standards, franchisees are independent business owners. It is the franchisee who determines how to implement the franchisor’s standards, controlling on a day-to-day basis the operations of its franchise and its labor relations.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE4668A6D18DB417C99384600EE5D3220"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The economic impact of this business model has been profound. According to a September 2023 report from Oxford Economics, in 2022, the economic output of franchise establishments in the United States was approximately $825,000,000,000. During that year, franchises employed approximately 5 percent of all workers in the United States, which was approximately 8,400,000 workers.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2F0F032F802246CE867098C33548C119"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Inconsistent and expansive views of what constitutes a <quote>joint employer</quote> have impacted the viability of franchising by creating joint employer liability based on the franchisor’s exercise of control that is inherent in franchise relationships.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H9EDD4C58EFC64BDCA6ED6F41BE4DF59B"><enum>3.</enum><header>Clarification of joint employment for franchising</header> <subsection id="HE409D6B9190043879CB504F119808CFB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>National Labor Relations Act</header><text>The National Labor Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/151">29 U.S.C. 151 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H428A43B55E3B40CEACE8BF81C33D3489">
<section id="H0D9B74799E6D43239803258EBDB56456"><enum>20.</enum><header>Clarification of joint employment for franchising</header>
<subsection id="HF773F250E2E34E3EB8CB9D5F032EAF24"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H68A46F6B9C384AB7BB151BB886E5276A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Direct and immediate control</header><text>The term <term>direct and immediate control</term> means the following with respect to each respective essential term and condition of employment:</text>
<subparagraph id="H72695665EB294F23AECC87DC022B4A1C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Wages</header><text>A franchisor exercises direct and immediate control over wages if it actually determines the wage rates, salary, or other rate of pay that is paid to individual employees of a franchisee or job classifications of employees of a franchisee.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF7E92463C3284647BB76EF47F4FBA424"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Benefits</header><text>A franchisor exercises direct and immediate control over benefits if it actually determines the fringe benefits to be provided or offered to a franchisee’s employees. Such direct and immediate control—</text>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H082B762524A144D8BADA5B096D099B39"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes selecting the benefit plans (such as health insurance plans and pension plans) or level of benefits provided to a franchisee’s employees; and</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H30288CB8F1A949DC8D9E71770398FA88"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not include permitting a franchisee, under an arm’s-length contract, to participate in a benefits plan of the franchisor.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H9A890635F91442CEA8838A10D60486A0"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Hours of work</header><text>A franchisor exercises direct and immediate control over hours of work if it actually determines work schedules or the work hours, including overtime, of a franchisee’s employees. Such direct and immediate control does not include—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE900776F9C61453DBF6AF11FD68F2D0C"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establishing a franchisee’s operating hours; or</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8549CA736C9F468BB018F3CE2EDEF870"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establishing minimum staffing levels to satisfy the franchise’s service standards.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAEAB4EB30B5144AEA737DE56635751A4"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Hiring</header><text>A franchisor exercises direct and immediate control over hiring if it actually determines which particular employees will be hired or which employees will not be hired. Such direct and immediate control does not include—</text>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCE446BC738E549CD8BA8AFADE52DA425"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">encouraging, recommending, or requesting changes in staffing levels to accomplish tasks; or</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9D103D2FAC044D53A3FEBC0CBF495D0C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">setting minimal recruiting and hiring standards, such as those required by law, for consumer or employee safety, or for brand protection.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HBAC10220302C4E52804FA379DECF14D2"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Discharge</header><text>A franchisor exercises direct and immediate control over discharge if it actually decides to terminate the employment of an employee of a franchisee. Such direct and immediate control does not include—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H90D482FD9A3A4E41B5C2EE51E16248B8"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">bringing misconduct or poor performance to the attention of a franchisee that makes the actual discharge decision;</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFAE60BA4659E4ECEA6AAA69EEEB2D634"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">expressing a negative opinion of a franchisee’s employee; or</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H66C3B618A25146589171859CB1976260"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">setting minimal standards of performance or conduct, such as those required by law, for consumer or employee safety, or for brand protection.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HEB5F98419A57449486E060276B1A4A1C"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Discipline</header><text>A franchisor exercises direct and immediate control over discipline if it actually decides to suspend or otherwise discipline a franchisee’s employee. Such direct and immediate control does not include—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE44B09FABE2149A29BA2EE109358347A"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">bringing misconduct or poor performance to the attention of a franchisee that makes the actual disciplinary decision;</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H26A129535A5446DAAB93E0BC73CB15EA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">expressing a negative opinion of a franchisee’s employee;</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFB94BF2E260A4F5198F131E9ED6121B4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">refusing to allow a franchisee’s employee to perform work under a franchise offer or contract; or</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCE057FADAB1447FDBB52F89FC1707072"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">setting minimal standards of performance or conduct, such as those required by law, for consumer or employee safety or for brand protection.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBF56D21C6DE94CBBB64414732BFA834F"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Supervision</header><text>A franchisor exercises direct and immediate control over supervision by consistently and directly instructing a franchisee’s employees how to perform their work or by actually issuing employee performance appraisals. Such direct and immediate control does not include—</text>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H72D8A19AB12A40FC92A6E16B15F49927"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">providing instructions to a franchisee's employees that—</text> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD05C44DD949B4EC3B2329B0E637B4C22"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are limited and routine; and</text></subclause>
<subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE56EB4F6A88A4B1BA66EBEE7A16C2A0C"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consist primarily of telling a franchisee’s employees what work to perform, or where and when to perform the work, but not how to perform the work;</text></subclause></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBC22FE14AA6D4E569B17CE27BC9D073E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">setting brand standards for the performance of the work;</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8B134291E5F0453DA814794F34899ED4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">offering training materials (including training demonstrations) for a franchisee to use to train the employees of the franchisee; or</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H65F6DECCDD564C35814B70FBD9DA28FB"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establishing minimum training requirements for the employees of a franchisee.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H07CF5EA9BF8C44CB8C61698A0C207C2B"><enum>(H)</enum><header>Direction</header><text>A franchisor exercises direct and immediate control over direction by assigning particular employees of a franchisee their individual work schedules, positions, and tasks. Such direct and immediate control does not include offering resources and tools for a franchisee to consider using to direct the work schedules, positions, and tasks of the employees of the franchisee.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDA472DC438874669A73DCEC6DC63249D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Essential terms and conditions of employment</header><text>The term <term>essential terms and conditions of employment</term> means wages, benefits, hours of work, hiring, discharge, discipline, supervision, and direction.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HED996743AC264BCBAC394A91BADF6C8C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Franchise; franchisee; franchisor</header><text>The terms <term>franchise</term>, <term>franchisee</term>, and <term>franchisor</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 436.1 of title 16, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on the date of enactment of this section.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H927684D189BB44549879FAE1C03ED407"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Substantial direct and immediate control</header><text>The term <term>substantial direct and immediate control</term>—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA786196690F3458C8BC06338943624F0"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means direct and immediate control that has a regular or continuous consequential effect on an essential term and condition of employment of a franchisee’s employees; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDE875CFBA063478DB84F0A14C9F33E8C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not include direct and immediate control that is only exercised on a sporadic, isolated, or de minimis basis.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HDD6A482FDF014C8D83242C20217BC72E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Joint employment</header><text>For the purposes of this Act, a franchisor may be considered a joint employer of the employees of a franchisee only if the franchisor possesses and exercises substantial direct and immediate control over one or more essential terms and conditions of employment of the employees of the franchisee.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HC70E9249067D4BC796AEFB05E58959A5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938</header><text>The Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/201">29 U.S.C. 201 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end of the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD3612302772643E0852D8F1FC665A1A7">
<section id="H88D06D30811C4D2AB586EF4A2661D4A0"><enum>20.</enum><header>Clarification of joint employment for franchising</header>
<subsection id="H3A7D404CB3A246CFB8F1910204B3F9F3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of this Act, a franchisor may be considered a joint employer of the employees of a franchisee only if the franchisor meets the criteria for a joint employer with a franchisee under section 20 of the National Labor Relations Act, except that, for purposes of determining joint-employer status under this Act, the terms <term>employee</term> and <term>employer</term> referenced in section 20 of the National Labor Relations Act shall have the meanings given such terms in section 3 of this Act.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3A474FE84DCC4F2583909CC9793FB56A"> <subsection id="HF8A3AB5B768648A5ADB43EA9F828A1A6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section, the terms <term>franchisor</term> and <term>franchisee</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 20(a) of the National Labor Relations Act.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section>
<section id="HD182DE40E1D44724A1FF3882E5204687"><enum>4.</enum><header>Applicability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act, and the amendments made by this Act, shall not apply to any proceeding that is commenced before the date of enactment of this Act.</text></section> </legis-body></bill>

