<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-GAI25931-H39-C1-1PW"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2638 IS: Energy Efficiency for Affordable Housing Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2638</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250731">July 31, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S366">Ms. Warren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S394">Ms. Smith</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to increase the low-income housing credit for rehabilitation expenditures for buildings achieving enhanced energy performance, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="id63439cf7219b496c96c232186f607dd7"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Energy Efficiency for Affordable Housing Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section section-type="subsequent-section" id="id043F7AC4B9974204AC1FCDB6F4690613"><enum>2.</enum><header>Increase of credit</header><subsection id="id8084543B05D541648B578167E79F868F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (2) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/42">section 42(e)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida01d53daaf6148c68fb3323aa4ffc8ab"><subparagraph id="id8bb065ee60494ed1b380e0904bb88311"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Increase in credit for buildings achieving enhanced energy performance</header><clause id="ida3605bd4907647ff92fdeed44e336ef2"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of any existing building to which subsection (b)(2) does not apply which achieves enhanced energy performance, the rehabilitation expenditures taken into account under subparagraph (A) shall be 130 percent of such expenditures determined without regard to this subparagraph.</text></clause><clause id="idcce4b470272248f18c941c2131541152"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Enhanced energy performance</header><text>For purposes of clause (i), a building achieves enhanced energy performance if it meets either of the following:</text><subclause id="id8902d774bb914162ae74a1362c06dd2b"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The minimum requirements of an advanced building construction standard which shall be determined by the Secretary of Energy using prescriptive or performance methods of calculation and promulgated by the Secretary of Energy within 180 days of the date of the enactment of this subparagraph.</text></subclause><subclause id="ide2040c11ab6345c986d35613bd484ea6"><enum>(II)</enum><text>In the case of a taxpayer which elects (at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may provide) the application of this subclause with respect to the building, a qualified retrofit plan.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id47ff5a82d2284c47b5a4600ab479a2e7"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this subparagraph—</text><subclause id="id74e2c42db6f24f47b22c529d6a4735b2"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Qualified retrofit plan</header><text>The term <term>qualified retrofit plan</term> means a written plan prepared and stamped by a qualified professional which specifies modifications to a building which, in the aggregate, are expected to reduce such building’s site energy usage intensity by 50 percent or more in comparison to the baseline energy usage intensity of such building. Such plan shall require a qualified professional to certify—</text><item id="ida0faed1d7dc0458f8a85d2fda2549a36"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the baseline energy usage intensity of the building,</text></item><item id="id69050aa3edd745afa422da9807dac1ff"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>that the modifications are expected to reduce such building’s site energy usage intensity by 50 percent or more in comparison to the baseline energy usage intensity of such building, and</text></item><item id="id7c954033abe74f7091e8578ed162f6d6"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>as of any date following installation of building modifications, that such modifications have been installed.</text></item></subclause><subclause id="id5315cd8526d54872b9533b559190aaa3"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Baseline energy usage intensity</header><text>The term <term>baseline energy usage intensity</term> means the site energy usage intensity as of any date during the 24-month period immediately preceding the building modifications described in the qualified retrofit plan.</text></subclause><subclause id="id94c1132df6bb4b64a160bfa0c96176ec"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Site energy usage intensity</header><text>The site energy usage intensity shall be determined for the entire building in accordance with such regulations or other guidance as the Secretary may provide and measured in British thermal units per square foot per year.</text></subclause><subclause id="idd8f10f27ad404095b7e4bdff7f71f782"><enum>(IV)</enum><header>Qualified professional</header><text>The term <term>qualified professional</term> means an individual who is a licensed architect or a licensed engineer or meets such other requirements as the Secretary of Energy may provide.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="id43940E8985CF461EBD29738C6D66B315"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Increase for buildings in high-Cost areas</header><text>Paragraph (2) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/42">section 42(e)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as amended by subsection (a), is further amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id981f5bdbbbe34285ab9dca5629780382"><subparagraph id="idc4db7e177db94c0d88c4b0371f41e27c"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Special rule for buildings in high-cost areas which achieve enhanced energy performance</header><text>In the case of an existing building to which both subparagraph (C) and subsection (d)(5)(B) apply (but for this subparagraph)—</text><clause id="idBD019E4459DE466AA9EE4480CB2F7DB7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>subsection (d)(5)(B)(i)(II) shall not apply, and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB1063EB6637D49EDBF8F41C92EBA5F8D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the rehabilitation expenditures taken into account under subparagraph (A) shall be 160 percent of such expenditures determined without regard to this subparagraph.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="id20E1DB454A9A4A11893714DB17BA4444"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><paragraph id="id8E9C1A31077F4377B16EA86FFD2E8E8C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the amendments made by this section shall apply to buildings with respect to which housing credit dollar amounts are allocated after December 31, 2025.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id65D8E86C6EC94A36B67A44897B6E1974"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Bond-financed projects</header><text>In the case of any building some portion of which, or of the land on which the building is located, is financed by an obligation which is described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/42">section 42(h)(4)(A)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, the amendments made by this section shall apply to any such building financed by such an obligation which is part of an issue the issue date of which is after December 31, 2025.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

