<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" slc-id="S1-HEN25376-YPK-1P-SRP"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 121 IS: Establishing the Senate Human Rights Commission.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 121</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250310">March 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S384">Mr. Tillis</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSRA00">Committee on Rules and Administration</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Establishing the Senate Human Rights Commission.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the Senate Human Rights Caucus, which was founded in 2014, and is currently co-chaired by Senator Tillis and Senator Coons, has created an outlet and opportunity to establish a formalized forum for human rights discussion and engagement in the Senate;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Senate Human Rights Caucus has brought together critical thinkers and first-hand experts on issues affecting human rights throughout the world to better inform the actions of Congress; </text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas, by establishing a commission in the Senate to put testimony regarding human rights in the record, all of the Federal Government and the public can access this information and insight; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Senate Human Rights Commission would continue the work of the Senate Human Rights Caucus and elevate the need to sustain and support the fundamental access to human rights across the world: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section section-type="section-one" id="id38f3640a793b4884bdba890bb3f8eed4"><enum>1.</enum><header>Senate Human Rights Commission</header><subsection id="id6b192cda32fa456ba7e2152f8fc9b244"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Commission establishment</header><paragraph id="id692643c85f4e4fe1b5903f4bed7299ad"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is established in the Senate the Senate Human Rights Commission (in this section referred to as the <quote>Commission</quote>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5c0061e69d7a4e2eb2041bbebc58a9cf"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Commission shall—</text><subparagraph id="iddc84ace9f1f8472eacb08f1338873249"><enum>(A)</enum><text>serve as a forum for bipartisan discussion of international human rights issues and promotion of internationally recognized human rights as enshrined in the United Nations Universal Declaration of Human Rights;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida57be83719364750a9e4567dcb09bf25"><enum>(B)</enum><text>monitor the state of human rights across the world and raise awareness on critical human rights violations through conducting regular briefings, hearings, and private roundtables;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8ce4580ad2fb4435b417f60ddd492a33"><enum>(C)</enum><text>maintain records of all meetings and activities; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc3adcaa0230046a6aed12931387645a1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>collaborate with congressional committees and other congressional entities (including the Tom Lantos Human Rights Commission), the executive branch, human rights organizations, civil society organizations, nongovernmental organizations, and think tanks to promote human rights initiatives within the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9021451898b6458797db0a762702c903"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitations</header><text>The Commission shall not—</text><subparagraph id="id5a0af1851d984cf6861808715400bde7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>have legislative jurisdiction;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide3ff169ca11e4da69e99f168c58f36c3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>have authority to take legislative action on any bill or resolution; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida326ecaa86b542cabf7d0d3ee33fa137"><enum>(C)</enum><text>encroach upon the jurisdiction of any standing, select, or special committee of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id67202cbef59d48439af126419626ed1c"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Membership</header><subparagraph id="id1e791b94d59040079022f7c590cf9c09"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission shall be composed of 10 members of the Senate, who shall be appointed, and may be removed, by the President of the Senate.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id80f13a2f5b0445cca9fe9bb83efdebae"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Selection</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President of the Senate shall— </text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb4fbbc489363471dbe8b244f4883455c"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">after consultation with the majority leader, select 5 members from the majority party of the Senate, 1 of whom shall be designated as a co-chairperson in accordance with paragraph (5)(A)(i); and </text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddf5af2b68cc242d489f4015e3c4e53fd"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">after consultation with the minority leader, select 5 members from the minority party of the Senate, 1 of whom shall be designated as a co-chairperson in accordance with paragraph (5)(A)(ii).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4b4e8134d90146bdbb549859315606a7"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Term</header><text>The term of a member shall end on the last day of the Congress during which the member is appointed by the President of the Senate, unless the member ceases being a member of the Senate, leaves the Commission, or is removed.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id344a782ca22e44ff801f56e152cc6fc4"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Vacancy</header><clause id="id56b0d28acb7a4fb1b6ae36ff9737a00a"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A vacancy on the Commission shall be filled in the same manner in which the original appointment was made.</text></clause><clause id="id60b9c37dd101492cbef3b86b24568640"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Resignation</header><text>A member of the Commission wishing to resign from the Commission shall submit a written notification to the President of the Senate.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idd6b82c2747ad40c9b170ed088ca10e69"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Co-chairpersons of the commission</header><subparagraph id="ide0926bf07d674548a0c14d7ebed81fa7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Two members of the Commission shall be appointed to serve as co-chairpersons of the Commission, as follows:</text><clause id="ide4ed2168242640ada64e4aa3560bce3f"><enum>(i)</enum><text>One co-chairperson shall be appointed, and may be removed, by the majority leader of the Senate.</text></clause><clause id="idf9e811c16b884080be789bf696f59095"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>One co-chairperson shall be appointed, and may be removed, by the minority leader of the Senate.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9b5b9d0f0ba54bad9fae0dfedab4bb11"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Term</header><text>The term of a member as a co-chairperson of the Commission shall end on the last day of the Congress during which the member is appointed as a co-chairperson, unless the member ceases being a member of the Senate, leaves the Commission, resigns from the position of co-chairperson, or is removed.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0e09e6f851d24bd2810eeef0a929e758"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>Appointments under this paragraph shall be printed in the Congressional Record.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7a6ea1bdbd2b4c0f8ed817f8b519aad5"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Vacancies</header><text>Any vacancy in the position of co-chairperson of the Commission shall be filled in the same manner in which the original appointment was made.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id1499feb6bc0a4c2a94c7b3208a82c2f4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Commission staff</header><paragraph id="id4f4dbe0d8e3943889a575a63117ff7ab"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Compensation and expenses</header><subparagraph id="id84effafbe0754fd79bc895d2c3b1508d"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission is authorized, from funds made available under subsection (c), to—</text><clause id="id02ade2c164c64c298ebd6abc3f9466b1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>employ such staff in the manner and at a rate not to exceed that allowed for employees of a committee of the Senate under section 105(e)(3) of the Legislative Branch Appropriation Act, 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/4575">2 U.S.C. 4575(e)(3)</external-xref>); and</text></clause><clause id="id71b3e80999ab4768a09d91aca696073f"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>incur such expenses as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out its duties and functions.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ideaf9b9c60db04457b5be2422b42a4bf3"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Expenses</header><clause id="id6f1057649aef4db990648cb03b78f734"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Payments made under this subsection for receptions, meals, and food-related expenses shall be authorized only for actual expenses incurred by the Commission in the course of conducting its official duties and functions.</text></clause><clause id="idd0f225faf6c54ca69b8e0527a800bd8b"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Treatment of payments</header><text>Amounts received as reimbursement for expenses described in clause (i) shall not be reported as income, and the expenses so reimbursed shall not be allowed as a deduction under the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id666f081d23b142a0850318634c467eef"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Designation of professional staff</header><subparagraph id="id109d3272d70b48ecb9fa713ba6dc082f"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each co-chairperson of the Commission may designate 1 professional staff member.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id07e69d20577e40e1ae2f04d8a6830f8b"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Compensation of Senate employees</header><text>In the case of the compensation of any professional staff member designated under subparagraph (A) who is an employee of a Member of the Senate or of a committee of the Senate and who has been designated to perform services for the Commission, the professional staff member shall continue to be paid by the Member or committee, as the case may be, but the account from which the professional staff member is paid shall be reimbursed for the services of the professional staff member (including agency contributions when appropriate) out of funds made available under subsection (c).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id666422ab759d44c29bdfba79dde21741"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>Each professional staff member designated under subparagraph (A) shall—</text><clause id="id43005705d9f54f0b8bfb11add6449d39"><enum>(i)</enum><text>serve all members of the Commission; and</text></clause><clause id="id510e7e6b9a7d46e2bd385946825d55ef"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>carry out such other functions as the co-chairperson designating the professional staff member may specify.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id8793c1ef1ee745ab8ec9d3a8696f607a"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Payment of expenses</header><paragraph id="idffea37595d5048a5b931c57a1bea8d98"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The expenses of the Commission shall be paid from the Contingent Fund of the Senate, out of the account of Miscellaneous Items, upon vouchers approved jointly by the co-chairpersons (except that vouchers shall not be required for the disbursement of salaries of employees who are paid at an annual rate of pay).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6a60b248c3f24c9db05b8cc6e3d1bfff"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Amounts available</header><text>For any fiscal year, not more than $200,000 shall be expended for employees and expenses. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id206e329dd4ad4dd0b52b81bc9f572f29"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>This section shall cease to have force or effect on January 1, 2029. </text></subsection></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

