<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HBDD0D31EFDC54812ACCD7B3FB71269A4" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2593 IH: Making Any Reimbursement Against the Law for Guarding Overnight Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2593</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250402">April 2, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the President from personally profiting from Secret Service protection.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD69A5CFF81BB4E2C8CE481D41301A471" style="OLC"><section id="HEC2AD71C56224AD88A25E5F0A8D372D6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Making Any Reimbursement Against the Law for Guarding Overnight Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>MARALAGO Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="HFB3FDA6C237B4F5581597A332CDD59C1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Limitation on use of funds by United States Secret Service</header><subsection id="HC5FA10FF312F4F539F32DB58E49104E9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No Federal funds may be used by the Director of the United States Secret Service to purchase, rent, lease, or otherwise procure from a President or any entity owned or controlled by a President, or to reimburse a President or any entity owned or controlled by a President for, lodging, meals, office space, or any other expense incurred by the United States Secret Service during the course of protecting a President at the President’s residence. </text></subsection><subsection id="H696DF95B8DAA407284BDBD3C5BBA2BF5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Gifting permitted</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a President or an entity owned or controlled by a President, may gift to the United States Secret Service lodging, meals, office space, or any other expense incurred by the United States Secret Service during the course of protecting a President at the President or former President’s residence.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5E8B3F5DC383468DAE9642E294E577B7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>President</term> includes a former President. </text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

