<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC0D513ECEE6D47A392025A9507C4816C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2589 IH: Consensual Donation and Research Integrity Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2589</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250402">April 2, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001257">Mr. Bilirakis</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="F000468">Mrs. Fletcher</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Public Health Service Act to ensure the consensual donation and respectful disposition of human bodies and human body parts donated or transferred for education, research, or the advancement of medical, dental, or mortuary science and not for use in human transplantation, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H610A40734D954FEFBEAB2DCFC95DB27D" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H4A886A5C0F5F40E1825BA6504FFD7842"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Consensual Donation and Research Integrity Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H5B4EFE90E48445A0B747FD144CC39383"><enum>2.</enum><header>Human bodies and human body parts donated or transferred for education, research, or the advancement of medical, dental, or mortuary science and not for use in human transplantation</header> <subsection id="H12C2A00EA5704B45AC1BCBAC5C24D965"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Title III of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/241">42 U.S.C. 241 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 373 the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0BA9BFFB414C4E559927DBB400CD7A63"> 
<section id="HBE8DA7256C144146B224A829474B69B9"><enum>373A.</enum><header>Human bodies and human body parts donated or transferred for education, research, or the advancement of medical, dental, or mortuary science and not for use in human transplantation</header> 
<subsection id="H46F63407EBE64B7CADB748BD3CFF6EA7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Registration</header> 
<paragraph id="HBE1C0710AE29441494BAE5E5D47D4258"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A person who acquires human bodies and sells for profit a whole human body or human body part in or affecting interstate commerce shall register with the Secretary at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may require.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H930E4F2436714D3EB4FEC2C465B3BF40"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Paragraph (1) does not apply to the Organ Procurement and Transplantation Network under section 372 and any entity that is a member of the Network pursuant to section 121.3 of title 42, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulations), funeral service professionals in regard to the preparation, transportation, and final disposition of the human body or body parts, and schools of medicine, dentistry, and mortuary science and research, training organizations, and other entities that do not sell for profit a whole body or body part.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4A98A14332EF40768A0E08FA58957D63"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Contents of application</header><text>An applicant for registration or renewal of registration under this section shall submit an application to the Secretary containing such information as the Secretary may by regulation require on the activities to be carried out pursuant to the registration. Unless the Secretary specifies otherwise by regulation, an application shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="HD57FACF99E3B4D88B28332D17AA1E532"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the name of the applicant, including all trade names under which the applicant conducts business;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDA016B5735A34B2598962523B2C02814"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the date on which the applicant first began or will begin commencing activities described in paragraph (1);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBA0DAB4D318543A5B832DA26A3A4F74B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a list of all addresses at which the applicant conducts business;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF2FF2D1155D24F49B2C224B306735BDA"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a description of the premises and equipment used by the applicant;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H77F73557D4714D88AFC9BFF0696BC296"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a description of the types of service provided by the applicant;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7C1602D93D564314943A09B127FA8C4B"><enum>(F)</enum><text>an identification of a representative of the applicant who has attained the age of 18 and has the authority to ensure that the applicant complies with this section;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA88DB8CE2B3D4AC8A57C396B5C23E178"><enum>(G)</enum><text>an assurance that the Secretary will be permitted to inspect the premises and records of the applicant at the times and in the manners prescribed under subsection (b);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA8AA3BB38EDB4F71B6EDECDC3987ED39"><enum>(H)</enum><text>an assurance that the applicant will keep records in accordance with subsection (c);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3D3C7F1AE0954E66B7249E373980B25B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>an assurance that the applicant will label and package all human bodies or human body parts in accordance with subsection (d); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2D5F845393054479A113AF02A47E6506"><enum>(J)</enum><text>an assurance that the applicant will limit the use and disclosure of information in accordance with the regulations promulgated pursuant to subsection (e).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE1CC5BABC16C4EFFA56988531A5B61DC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Fees</header> <subparagraph id="HA3B1E12035764653A827F6EA0F9A6476"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Authority</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a fee for registration under paragraph (1) and renewal under paragraph (5) in an amount in accordance with subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAB563FE6E93D4442B9A3439031D07DBB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Amount</header><text>The Secretary shall determine the amount of the fees authorized by subparagraph (A) on an annual basis based on the projected cost of implementing and enforcing this section, including the cost of inspections under subsection (b).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC06C677D26554E2FBD225E6A51EE888F"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Collections and appropriations acts</header><text>The fees authorized by subparagraph (A) shall be available for obligation only to the extent and in the amounts provided in advance in appropriations Acts.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFA0C01F8E6D84C6ABED769FFA1FBDBB7"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Registration renewal</header><text>The Secretary shall require that the registration of a registrant be renewed by such registrant at such intervals as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0E94E481387241F28AE7FDC4383A7BE2"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Change of information</header><text>Not later than 30 days after any change of any information listed in paragraph (3), an applicant or registrant shall notify the Secretary of such change in writing as prescribed by regulation by the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H54AEDB6498204BC08F83872B9EFA67E0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Inspections</header><text>The Secretary shall inspect at regular intervals (to be prescribed by the Secretary) the premises described in subsection (a)(3)(D).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H31BA843A9254480F8BD7F401E75B374E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Record keeping</header> <paragraph id="H86628168DD82419F898EB276EA20B918"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A registrant shall maintain a record for each case in which the registrant acquires a human body or human body part.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB824AF6323814513BF5E92FE0D0A0858"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Record requirements</header><text>A record under paragraph (1) shall contain such information as the Secretary may by regulation require. Unless the Secretary specifies otherwise by regulation, a record under paragraph (1) shall include the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H230F7807C65E4AB8AB8C7DEEC5150227"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Documentation that the donor has knowingly consented to the transfer of the human body or human body part (not for use in transplantation) involved for education, research, or the advancement of medical, dental, or mortuary science in accordance with all applicable laws pertaining to the disposition of human remains.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HABEE0544F734483BA0D53EF0F29F3798"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Documentation that the donor has been informed of the obligation of the registrant under subsection (e) to dispose of the human body or human body part.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7C3D77BB5BE34FB294B74EF9E81868F0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The date and time of the donation or transfer from the donor.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8AE4CF7A7DCA42D380C94870598B3B96"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The name of the person, including any trade or business name, who transferred the human body or human body part to the registrant, if applicable.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC03D2CC5505A4087857F6FA96EDF7C6B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The full name and most recent address of the donor.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE059CD7891BF42789A29C84D23BC88CF"><enum>(F)</enum><text>A description of the human body or human body part being acquired or transferred.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H21B0BD1C89874ECCB48BA5A43F9A94F5"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The medical history of the donor, including the autopsy report if an autopsy was conducted.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0423FF704EE1400FA5D644EC72C5012E"><enum>(H)</enum><text>The identity and address of each person that has been in possession of the human body or human body part prior to the registrant, including any funeral home, coroner, hospital, organ procurement organization, or tissue bank.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0EF617F5479240BC85D8EEE6CB30AE2A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Documentation of the use and disposition of each human body or human body part by the registrant.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4944BCA4BE1B4425A2D5EB3B2EDFB81C"><enum>(J)</enum><text>Documentation of the name and address of each person to whom the registrant transfers such human body or human body part.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H8995199A60F6479DAF188492FACFF6DE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Labeling and packaging</header> <paragraph id="HFAB4D0944CFC42BCB3455C53B327895D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A registrant shall ensure that all human bodies and human body parts in the possession of, or transferred by, a registrant are labeled and packaged in accordance with paragraphs (2) and (3) and that a proper chain of custody is maintained.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H45091CB9C7504B53857F0ABDFDF7130C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Labeling requirements</header> 
<subparagraph id="H56356129E9254182B22698835B7D786A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Placement</header><text>The labeling required by paragraph (1) shall be affixed beneath the outer packaging.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE7355E576D694518B214A569620DB652"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The labeling required by paragraph (1) shall contain such information as the Secretary may by regulation require consistent with any applicable Federal privacy provisions. Unless the Secretary specifies otherwise by regulation, a label under paragraph (1) shall include the following:</text> 
<clause id="H277B8A637FDA4A2D8EB9639214D8F138"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The proper name of the donor.</text></clause> <clause id="H000BED46A61547C6B9E3CB23DCCB0622"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A description of the contents of the packaging, indicating whether it is a human body or human body parts, including a list of all such parts.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HAE2430CBEF434500821A5905E5731161"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The name, address, and any applicable license or registration number of the person transferring the human body or human body part.</text></clause> <clause id="HB763C46B67374E5C8C8811BC8B332597"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The tissue types of the human body or human body part.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H88884243AF3649A78FF08D2803756B66"><enum>(v)</enum><text>The cause of death of the donor, if applicable and known.</text></clause> <clause id="H8EF93D1EA12C4582B0A36E31270D04F6"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Serological test results, if any such results exist.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H15C33E5EA9604B51893804EE4A282993"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>Record of the presence of radioactive materials or implants.</text></clause> <clause id="H715B5B77EF6F4AC195D1E827431C09B0"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>Any known infectious disease agents of such human body or human body part.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HADF309A9F4AE42C1970F18CEAA7EB0D7"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>A statement about the use of personal protective equipment and universal precautions when handling a human body or human body part as required by law.</text></clause> <clause id="HD7CAA01D0E6E46DA8B19712D6834753F"><enum>(x)</enum><text>The statement <quote>not for transplantation</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2BD3F2DE44E04D82BB22EF10475573D3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Packaging requirements</header><text>Each human body or human body part described in paragraph (1) shall be wrapped and packaged in such manner as the Secretary may by regulation require. Unless the Secretary specifies otherwise by regulation, each such human body or human body part shall be wrapped and packaged in a manner that—</text> <subparagraph id="H610B404BBAF4485695B35805D67895CD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>mitigates potential contamination and cross contamination;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAD1B07E5C9BD4F54BBF44F98349F1B59"><enum>(B)</enum><text>mitigates potential safety hazards;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0A07695B341F4BE7B20DFB13D6766CD4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is sealed to prevent leakage; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7FE4B95E20CD4E678995BCC98947E657"><enum>(D)</enum><text>ensures the integrity of the human body or human body part.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H4635BC37922749BD88AFF03B74DBB3E4"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Limitations on use and disclosure of information</header><text>Individually identifiable information relating to the donor of a human body or human body part acquired or transferred pursuant to a registration under this section shall be used and disclosed only for such purposes (including the return of remains for burial) as the Secretary may explicitly authorize by regulation.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC056A7B8E09E41AA8AEDC3C96978627C"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Disposition</header><text>The registrant shall ensure the proper disposition of a human body or human body part, in accordance with applicable Federal and State law, by—</text> <paragraph id="H6AAFABBD4D474413908F9DB5F91A579E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>returning the human body or human body part to a relative or personal representative of the donor or carrying out the disposition of such human body or human body part in accordance with the written instructions of the person or persons with the right to control the disposition of the human body or body parts; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5536AE356A8D475A9F92438FE184ED64"><enum>(2)</enum><text>if the registrant is transferring the human body or human body part to another person, contracting with such person to assume the obligation described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H9711B4303B1140828765C0AD43D95656"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Violations</header> <paragraph id="HBCE7BB36D8124F038B2DDD86116FEED9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any person who violates a requirement of this section shall be fined in accordance with title 18, United States Code.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAE5A7F9C68444A9CACEBA5EC870E3628"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Revocation of registration</header><text>The Secretary may suspend or revoke the registration of any registrant found to be in violation of this section.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6135687A67404FEDBF11CE4C6609F585"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Alteration or falsification of label</header><text>It shall be a violation of this section for any person to alter or falsify any information in a label required by subsection (d).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HAD8690CDA8594741B94580036A3F25EC"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HE46B2B0BC3944284A29CA6B3288437DE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Donor</header><text>The term <term>donor</term> means a person who has knowingly consented in accordance with applicable law to the transfer of such person’s deceased body or deceased or living body part (not for use in transplantation) for education, research, or the advancement of medical, dental, or mortuary science.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H41FB68BBD8B346C6A24404D60A7BD65D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Education</header><text>The term <term>education</term> means the use of a human body or body parts for teaching or training individuals, including medical, dental, or mortuary science students or professionals, with regard to the anatomy and characteristics of the human body, disease detection, and such other uses as may be specified by the Secretary by regulation.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H40D6DBFC969F4733BA7F78EF6526C7B8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Human body</header><text>The term <term>human body</term> means a deceased human body.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2D39B3A2D9FF45F28BE21C23F85ADC83"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Human body part</header><text>The terms <term>human body part</term> or <term>body part</term> mean an organ, tissue, eye, bone, blood vessel or any other portion of a deceased or living human body that is subject to an anatomical gift or other transfer made pursuant to State law, but do not include—</text> <subparagraph id="HF0A2FA9F5760495397C1825F9E50C82A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>blood drawn for medical purposes; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9C1825B673BB4A0A90CB0BCC6A8B4F6A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a growing cell line.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA9629BE4BE344C3E944615DFEFFBA26A"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Research</header><text>The term <term>research</term> does not include an autopsy or examination, conducted as part of a criminal investigation.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD210676F5E3E4EE1AC81BBDB7A38FE05"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rule of applicability</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply with respect to any acquisition or transfer of a human body or human body parts after the date that is 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act. </text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

