<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDA6980879E6E4D35B4B784F96D113B96" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2888 IH: Stopping a Rogue President on Trade Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2888</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250410">April 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001156">Ms. Sánchez</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="N000015">Mr. Neal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000399">Mr. Doggett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000557">Mr. Larson of Connecticut</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001296">Mr. Boyle of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001190">Mr. Schneider</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000585">Mr. Gomez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001066">Mr. Horsford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000610">Ms. Plaskett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001201">Mr. Suozzi</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000605">Mr. Gray</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Rules</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To terminate certain tariffs imposed pursuant to emergency authorities and require congressional approval for the imposition of similar tariffs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H67AEC216E53D4B9297E820116DD55D97" style="OLC"><section id="H93D4F4AA859A4030A53C2A1136104067" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stopping a Rogue President on Trade Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H25B840BC7A2B40C3AEA3D4284475EA61"><enum>2.</enum><header>Termination of certain executive orders imposing tariffs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Duties imposed by the following Executive orders, and any successor or substantially similar Executive orders, shall have no force or effect on and after the date of the enactment of this Act:</text><paragraph id="HAF41C9578E19413D87978DB733DFAF97"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Executive Order 14257 (90 Fed. Reg. 15041).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H15BDB93550604EAA9048DB0001C6E64C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Executive Order 14193 (90 Fed. Reg. 9113).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8AC5E1736C184107889BEB1292F81876"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Executive Order 14194 (90 Fed. Reg. 9117).</text></paragraph></section><section id="HE3E1509A906B46609C8278DC56F0AF1E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Approval required for imposition of duties, quotas, or tariff rate quotas or suspension, withdrawal, or prevention of the application of trade agreement concessions</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFB5BB21000F645709D99D1AE920E49D6"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congressional approval required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided by subsection (b), the President may not impose or increase a duty, quota, or tariff-rate quota with respect to an article imported into the United States or suspend, withdraw, or prevent the application of trade agreement concessions with respect to an article unless there is enacted into law a joint resolution of approval with respect to the duty, quota, tariff-rate quota, or concession.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H91E33FBA80984FC6ADCE1C46E9E72135"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exclusions</header><text>The requirement under subsection (a) shall not apply with respect to—</text><paragraph id="HBCB0281538FB4501BA67D998296A216E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>antidumping and countervailing duties imposed under title VII of the Tariff Act of 1930 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1671">19 U.S.C. 1671 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6075B785EF9E434F984BBB46D544D247"><enum>(2)</enum><text>duties, quotas, and tariff-rate quotas imposed under chapter 1 of title II of the Trade Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/2251">19 U.S.C. 2251 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA7D3B02757794F5881CB3E5EF6122C99"><enum>(3)</enum><text>duties imposed consistent with a ruling authorizing the suspension of benefits or concessions on the part of the United States issued by—</text><subparagraph id="H23C29C0F450340B18EB02EC9C03DC589" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a dispute settlement panel constituted under a bilateral or plurilateral free trade agreement for which explicit congressional approval pursuant to the requirements of section 151 of the Trade Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/2191">19 U.S.C. 2191</external-xref>) has been enacted before the date of the enactment of this Act, before which the United States is a party; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2B66CD4EF71C4F708B466D0949E6D97F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a dispute settlement panel described in section 123 of the Uruguay Rounds Agreement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/3533">19 U.S.C. 3533</external-xref>) before which the United States is a party.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HF3ACE31FB02D4E2F8D8F0A1A6C2CF2B8"><enum>4.</enum><header>Joint resolution procedures</header><subsection id="H7A2139BBBE574AEBBF2EC01DD49A5DCD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Joint resolution of approval defined</header><text>For purposes of this Act, the term <term>joint resolution of approval</term> means only a joint resolution, the sole matter after the resolving clause of which is as follows: <quote>That Congress approves ___ imposed with respect to ___.</quote>, with the first blank space being filled with a description of the proposed action with respect to the article and the second blank space being filled with a description of the article.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5C19AA0B3ECE461AB94AA45AAEA3A2E7" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Introduction of joint resolution of approval</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A joint resolution of approval may be introduced in either House of Congress by any Member.</text></subsection><subsection id="HBC8E9C3D587E4F0BA6B9E5DE2E7EE13F" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Expedited procedures</header><text>The provisions of subsections (b) through (f) of section 152 of the Trade Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/2192">19 U.S.C. 2192</external-xref>) apply to a joint resolution of approval described in subsection (a) to the same extent that such subsections apply to joint resolutions under such section 152.</text></subsection><subsection id="H6125DE65D031446089E3435A3A2DB329" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rules of the Senate and the House of Representatives</header><text>This section is enacted by Congress—</text><paragraph id="HE58D3F85CB1141E69932333BB8AA70F0" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>as an exercise of the rulemaking power of the Senate and the House of Representatives, respectively, and as such is deemed a part of the rules of each House, respectively, but applicable only with respect to the procedure to be followed in that House in the case of a joint resolution of approval, and supersedes other rules only to the extent that it is inconsistent with such rules; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC1C688CA6929456C9E287190586BFF9D" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>with full recognition of the constitutional right of either House to change the rules (so far as relating to the procedure of that House) at any time, in the same manner, and to the same extent as in the case of any other rule of that House.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

