<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H8CE7F8650DBE4A9B90F68D5FCC087CC7" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 686 IH: Supporting the designation of the week of September 14, 2025, through September 20, 2025, as “Telehealth Awareness Week”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 686</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250909">September 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001183">Mr. Schweikert</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Supporting the designation of the week of September 14, 2025, through September 20, 2025, as <quote>Telehealth Awareness Week</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas telehealth allows health care practitioners to provide services to patients or other practitioners in different physical locations;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas telehealth significantly supported access to quality health care for millions during the COVID–19 public health emergency and remains essential postemergency;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2024, about 6,700,000 unique Medicare fee-for-service (FFS) beneficiaries received at least 1 telehealth service, with one-quarter of Medicare FFS beneficiaries utilizing telehealth;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the number of Medicare FFS telehealth users in 2024 is 24 percent higher than in 2019, prepandemic;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the percentage of Medicare FFS beneficiaries using telehealth has remained relatively stable in 2024;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas increased access to telehealth over the past 5 years has positively shifted patients’ and providers’ perceptions, with study findings indicating greater openness to using telehealth services;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas telehealth is now fully integrated into our health care system and patients’ care journeys, and it is essential that these flexibilities be preserved beyond September 30, 2025;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas legislative efforts to increase telehealth access have garnered broad bicameral bipartisan support in both the Senate and the House of Representatives;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas data from the Medicare Current Beneficiary Survey and the Census Bureau’s Household Pulse Survey indicate that individuals with disabilities are more likely to use audio-only services, with the highest usage among Medicare beneficiaries with multiple disabilities (41.8 percent);</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States has the opportunity to improve broader access to health services for all individuals, including members of rural and underserved communities; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas <quote>Telehealth Awareness Week</quote>, September 14, 2025, through September 20, 2025, unites the efforts of patients, caregivers, health care providers, policymakers, and other stakeholders to advance the role of telehealth in health care: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HBF6D2DC5BBB244B09FD4BEAF2BBDA490"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HF17F17FC07FA4CE3AB3D39CEB1ABBDFA"><enum/><text>That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="H56BE01172CAC4EAFB600DD8CDC451E73"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the designation of <quote>Telehealth Awareness Week</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE8300AB230BA4024A857537BFF46EAEF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the impact of telehealth in delivering health care services to patients across the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0D3D4558279B487C9343E653D1808DCA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>urges that steps be taken to—</text><subparagraph id="H87CB8C723B764833802B939D04153DC4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>continue the telehealth flexibilities beyond September 30, 2025;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H815489DA652D4407AEC308E2B1D72D7F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>raise awareness about the benefits of expanding telehealth;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB19A9ABE7A6A4897987C4F94296D09B4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>highlight resources for health care providers and patients regarding telehealth;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF8912F32062D42C1A2674427B8716F11"><enum>(D)</enum><text>collect and analyze data on the impacts of telehealth; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBED7166E800D4F49A8D512E45A8824F2"><enum>(E)</enum><text>promote continued access to telehealth for all communities and across settings permanently.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

