<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H065083570037443F8C6735068D22F2C9" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1509 IH: Accelerating Kids’ Access to Care Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1509</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250221">February 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000482">Mrs. Trahan</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="M001215">Mrs. Miller-Meeks</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend titles XIX and XXI of the Social Security Act to streamline the enrollment process for eligible out-of-state providers under Medicaid and CHIP.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE11D4587C7AF4627A2095865D7601684" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HCB9D0DF7EF124FE787C29524E0ABB128" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Accelerating Kids’ Access to Care Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="H9939C3BD4417421EBC8BEB98346C2ACD"> <enum>2.</enum> <header>Streamlined enrollment process for eligible out-of-state providers under Medicaid and CHIP</header> <subsection id="HE4CFF95A56094D63AC694170B6F88897"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text>Section 1902(kk) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396a">42 U.S.C. 1396a(kk)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H03931CBFCF8E41848C2ACDE0C3BD4FAF"> 
<paragraph id="H6AAC3BAAA10D41C99C5107C696BE4479"> <enum>(10)</enum> <header>Streamlined enrollment process for eligible out-of-state providers</header> 
<subparagraph id="HDE85BF34BAD14F31954D09AB47B36223"> <enum>(A)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text>The State—</text> <clause id="H815041F9DC684E129FE7B212AC4CD361"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>adopts and implements a process to allow an eligible out-of-State provider to enroll under the State plan (or a waiver of such plan) to furnish items and services to, or order, prescribe, refer, or certify eligibility for items and services for, qualifying individuals without the imposition of screening or enrollment requirements by such State that exceed the minimum necessary for such State to provide payment to an eligible out-of-State provider under such State plan (or a waiver of such plan), such as the provider's name and National Provider Identifier (and such other information specified by the Secretary); and</text> </clause> 
<clause id="HA657DCBC60CD421588CDF8AA54879F5D"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>provides that an eligible out-of-State provider that enrolls as a participating provider in the State plan (or a waiver of such plan) through such process shall be so enrolled for a 5-year period, unless the provider is terminated or excluded from participation during such period.</text> </clause> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5C373F5EB6AB49BCA6ABB5043E1AB4E5"> <enum>(B)</enum> <header>Definitions</header> <text>In this paragraph:</text> 
<clause id="HC1A77264769E42249CF34CB6A7B89BE2"> <enum>(i)</enum> <header>Eligible out-of-state provider</header> <text>The term <term>eligible out-of-State provider</term> means, with respect to a State, a provider—</text> <subclause id="HC0ABF32A6B13468CB4B11179D49A4D06"> <enum>(I)</enum> <text>that is located in any other State;</text> </subclause> 
<subclause id="HB2FC3D9BA06246DFB6A580A1ADF87C97"> <enum>(II)</enum> <text>that—</text> <item id="H909496D38FDF4276BEBFB4A85CCA3767"> <enum>(aa)</enum> <text>was determined by the Secretary to have a limited risk of fraud, waste, and abuse for purposes of determining the level of screening to be conducted under section 1866(j)(2), has been so screened under such section 1866(j)(2), and is enrolled in the Medicare program under title XVIII; or</text> </item> 
<item id="H851C0262093041FF9107842F6C592386"> <enum>(bb)</enum> <text>was determined by the State agency administering or supervising the administration of the State plan (or a waiver of such plan) of such other State to have a limited risk of fraud, waste, and abuse for purposes of determining the level of screening to be conducted under paragraph (1) of this subsection, has been so screened under such paragraph (1), and is enrolled under such State plan (or a waiver of such plan); and</text> </item> </subclause> <subclause id="H26CFD2D535B8446093389E3845B34263"> <enum>(III)</enum> <text>that has not been—</text> 
<item id="H0BEC18DC95294E8AAF960D2D090D8071"> <enum>(aa)</enum> <text>excluded from participation in any Federal health care program pursuant to section 1128 or 1128A;</text> </item> <item id="H495F6CBD423144DDB60FF8E70974F4AF"> <enum>(bb)</enum> <text>excluded from participation in the State plan (or a waiver of such plan) pursuant to part 1002 of title 42, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation), or State law; or</text> </item> 
<item id="H36471347771948938F32146EAAB7F599"> <enum>(cc)</enum> <text>terminated from participating in a Federal health care program or the State plan (or a waiver of such plan) for a reason described in paragraph (8)(A).</text> </item> </subclause> </clause> <clause id="H9C9BF6477CD94C4D83E74BAE8EB385DA"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <header>Qualifying individual</header> <text>The term <term>qualifying individual</term> means an individual under 21 years of age who is enrolled under the State plan (or waiver of such plan).</text> </clause> 
<clause id="HBE7F18B490674015B29B7B7D008C8779"> <enum>(iii)</enum> <header>State</header> <text>The term <term>State</term> means 1 of the 50 States or the District of Columbia.</text> </clause> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block> </quoted-block> </subsection> <subsection id="HBE98EF4D51844ABE82D3DF3D9DFE626A"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Conforming amendments</header> <paragraph id="H164BBE7492AB46FD9C6A8405504F49F4"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>Section 1902(a)(77) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396a">42 U.S.C. 1396a(a)(77)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>enrollment,</quote> after <quote>screening,</quote>.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2180F625707147528DE4D948F57AA688"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>The subsection heading for section 1902(kk) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396a">42 U.S.C. 1396a(kk)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>enrollment,</quote> after <quote>screening,</quote>.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H9AF7162AD2B34FFF96B8EB1DAA78BC86"> <enum>(3)</enum> <text>Section 2107(e)(1)(G) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1397gg">42 U.S.C. 1397gg(e)(1)(G)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>enrollment,</quote> after <quote>screening,</quote>.</text> </paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H6E9E6C8591444E7098290E43EC413F62"> <enum>(c)</enum> <header>Effective date</header> <text>The amendments made by this section shall take effect on the date that is 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act.</text> </subsection> </section> </legis-body></bill>

