<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3520ACA642A24C91949B8ED2DB59CCE8" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1999 IH: Disclose Getting Involved in Foreign Transactions Act </dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1999</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250310">March 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000307">Mr. James</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="F000450">Ms. Foxx</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require staff and faculty to report foreign gifts and contracts, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HEA7D0F55B9174DD1BD5352164C8155BF" style="OLC"><section id="H3E85A8A9AE3546CCA7640BE2490EFA45" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Disclose Getting Involved in Foreign Transactions Act </short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Disclose GIFT Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HC2DAE51BA1994419B0DAB1E16ECD4A9B" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Policy regarding conflicts of interest from foreign gifts and contracts</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 117 the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4601600DAF1743F0AC92A99546B98DD1"><section id="HF7F653A7024D45A9A88789561646677C"><enum>117A.</enum><header>Institutional policy regarding foreign gifts and contracts to faculty and staff</header><subsection id="HA50D8ECE8AB345DFBEAD92687B2DF8CF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement To maintain policy and database</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Disclose GIFT Act</short-title>, each institution described in subsection (b) shall maintain—</text><paragraph id="H71789C7F4B8644BBA98B22F592E4C177"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a policy requiring covered individuals employed at the institution to disclose in a report to such institution on July 31 of each calendar year that begins after the year in which such enactment date occurs—</text><subparagraph id="H32D4C1664041475DA47D545A17C4C395"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any gift received from a foreign source in the previous calendar year, the value of which is greater than the minimal value (as such term is defined in section 7342(a) of title 5, United States Code) or is of undetermined value, and including the date on which the gift was received;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC9C9D1CA2E684700BF06ECD2167D68CC"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any contract with a foreign source (other than a foreign country of concern or foreign entity of concern) entered into or in effect during the previous calendar year, the value of which is $5,000 or more, considered alone or in combination with all other contracts with that foreign source within the calendar year, and including the date on which such contract is entered into, the date on which the contract first takes effect, and, as applicable, the date on which such contract terminates;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7930AA0701D648258691BA19C82DBBA1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any contract with a foreign source (other than a foreign country of concern or foreign entity of concern) entered into or in effect during the previous calendar year that has an undetermined monetary value, and including the date on which such contract is entered into, the date on which the contract first takes effect, and, as applicable, the date on which such contract terminates; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H30374DF66667418EB32DAAD150118FE0"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any contract entered into or in effect with a foreign country of concern or foreign entity of concern during the previous calendar year, the value of which is $0 or more or which has an undetermined monetary value, and including—</text><clause id="H58D869F8D32C42B6A6EF4534F9BF68F2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the date on which such contract is entered into;</text></clause><clause id="HA0F7574D83BF450AA40C56B5ECE4A7D8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the date on which the contract first takes effect;</text></clause><clause id="H2532329E5E4A4F08B996703178C98FA7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>if the contract has a termination date, such termination date; and</text></clause><clause id="H68785260964D4E558F2D2468C284E299"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the full text of such contract and any addenda;</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC42DB3EEDC9D405B9B51AFCA091386BC" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a publicly available and searchable database (in electronic and downloadable format), on a website of the institution, of the information required to be disclosed under paragraph (1) (other than the name or any other personally identifiable information of a covered individual) that—</text><subparagraph id="HC1FB9DD3738C4275A992B503C0097DD1" commented="no"><enum>(A) </enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">makes available the information disclosed under paragraph (1) (other than the name or any other personally identifiable information of a covered individual) beginning on the date that is 30 days after receipt of the report under such paragraph containing such information and until the latest of—</text><clause id="HA7DEE34E448540B8BE83F4E39A14E6E7" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the date that is 5 years after the date on which—</text><subclause id="H0D5FF71024B84FA39C8C8CB798C877AF" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a gift referred to in paragraph (1)(A) is received; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H716F71E1AF3D40E0B50D8E9971621828" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a contract referred to in subparagraph (B), (C) or (D) of paragraph (1) first takes effect; or</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H71A6ACC670694FE68041CC39299CFAA0" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the date on which a contract referred to in subparagraph (B), (C) or (D) of paragraph (1) terminates; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7CC93095218A42BE966C7289609FD76B" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is searchable and sortable—</text><clause id="H5EBEA5049B664EB69FF8E2E5D60D16A4" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the subject of the disclosure is a gift, by the date on which the gift is received;</text></clause><clause id="HE99B7DC7C1A24AB1A8C2449FCE6BA383"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if the subject of the disclosure is a contract—</text><subclause id="H4C51DD8D5B304BD19722D3F9A4754F12"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by the date on which such contract is entered into; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H610C7B1EF42B40C1A1E85F97C29B7687"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by the date on which such contract first takes effect;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H4A9FFDBB41434F54BD6EFB743CF3D079" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by the attributable country with respect to which information is being disclosed; </text></clause><clause id="HA41384E7F4124C39860A08FCA01B4738" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by the narrowest of the department, school, or college of the institution, as applicable, for which the individual making the disclosure works; and</text></clause><clause id="H14D3451ECE4F44068A98BC93FAC892AE" commented="no"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by the name of the foreign source (other than a foreign source who is a natural person); and</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H781E7B2B500C451E9FD14FB9CBB65FF3"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an effective plan to identify and manage potential information gathering by foreign sources through espionage targeting covered individuals that may arise from gifts received from, or contracts entered into with, a foreign source, including through the use of—</text><subparagraph id="HD0CA93895043435CBA60DC6045820CFF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>periodic communications;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7AE79C91763D4802B612B992CAF733C1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">accurate reporting under paragraph (2) of the information required to be disclosed under paragraph (1); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF51830B9F53949E598D77B04D52F47BC"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">enforcement of the policy described in paragraph (1); and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAA482CDDCD9446D09B6E1FFECC6BC97A"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for purposes of investigations under section 117B(a)(1) or responses to requests under section 552 of title 5, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Freedom of Information Act</quote>), a record of the names of the individuals making disclosures under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2FDFFA2071F64B7FA61795C923984B8A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Institutions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An institution shall be subject to the requirements of this section if such institution—</text><paragraph id="H76BE0E17FD034F6BAA0CE55786F71D5B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is an eligible institution for the purposes of any program authorized under title IV; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H18140AD97E3F45D78291A0D4D7AB36C8"><enum>(2)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H6E5F249DB841481CBB4222FE084981FE"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">received more than $50,000,000 in Federal funds in any of the previous five calendar years to support (in whole or in part) research and development (as determined by the institution and measured by the Higher Education Research and Development Survey of the National Center for Science and Engineering Statistics); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDC08E5ADB6BD4917B8DF36030E502ED8" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">receives funds under title VI.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC20B194831FF4357BCF317D0B4FD456D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text><paragraph id="H25074B5B6B5B4999BB1704D0482A598F" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>attributable country</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="HC8CAC05510E74ED99125B9825E0FD5C8" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the country of citizenship of a foreign source who is a natural person, or, if such country is unknown, the principal residence (as applicable) of such foreign source; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H42AE9AB21F5D44EE83598045AD6B6349" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the country of incorporation of a foreign source that is a legal entity, or, if such country is unknown, the principal place of business (as applicable) of such foreign source. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC34CFDF5F4E84FE9849241854940FFD4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>contract</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H0042AC68BCBC4B84BBE66BFE5B64CD40"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any agreement for the acquisition by purchase, lease, or barter of property or services by the foreign source; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAE5A6FA83E334B50B2005BA3E2CB14A2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any affiliation, agreement, or similar transaction with a foreign source that involves the use or exchange of an institution’s name, likeness, time, services, or resources; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H665FF255C3454B6B9F7061D0A15239A6"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any agreement for the acquisition by purchase, lease, or barter, of property or services from a foreign source (other than an arms-length agreement for such acquisition from a foreign source that is not a foreign country of concern or a foreign entity of concern); and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7B988ABE9E9843BD9CADD3748B947245"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>covered individual</term>—</text><subparagraph id="H5EDDC1FA554C4460B17510E6C7D8F734"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has the meaning given such term in section 223(d) of the William M. (Mac) Thornberry National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6605">42 U.S.C. 6605</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H16FFA48B6BAB4D19982FEC15AF19EC69"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall be interpreted in accordance with the Guidance for Implementing National Security Presidential Memorandum 33 (NSPM–33) on National Security Strategy for United States Government-Supported Research and Development published by the Subcommittee on Research Security and the Joint Committee on the Research Environment in January 2022 (or any successor guidance).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7D715CCFABE44CA6AD499E0BC4D10CD6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the term <term>foreign source</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="HBFB4057E2EAD4798A66862231140D9D9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a foreign government, including an agency of a foreign government;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF69550E5323A4A6B8821A5EE37860C9B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a legal entity, governmental or otherwise, created under the laws of a foreign state or states;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H12B07D1B38744ECDA7984D03F3C8A411"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a legal entity, governmental or otherwise, substantially controlled (as described in section 668.174(c)(3) of title 34, Code of Federal Regulations) (or successor regulations)) by a foreign source;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF3370DDBE6844E24B057DFD35839F187"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a natural person who is not a citizen or a national of the United States or a trust territory or protectorate thereof; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB36054235CE74880A63C8791955A2DE0" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>an agent of a foreign source, including—</text><clause id="HCDCFBD9D583C49528781F08F2ACDB046" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a subsidiary or affiliate of a foreign legal entity, acting on behalf of a foreign source; </text></clause><clause id="H334A30F1E7A142EB9C6B9880D2FB5C5F" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a person that operates primarily for the benefit of, or under the auspices of, a foreign source, including a foundation or a related entity (such as any educational, cultural, or language entity); and</text></clause><clause id="HD55E0E3CCCE942449CE59A6D3CBF6036"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a person who is an agent of a foreign principal (as such term is defined in section 1 of the Foreign Agents Registration Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/611">22 U.S.C. 611</external-xref>); and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H87D2031CB1A645398006725CFE6081DD"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an international organization (as such term is defined in the International Organizations Immunities Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/288">22 U.S.C. 288</external-xref>)).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3B27FFF7DC324F3A86AE0796FE92938F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the term <term>gift</term>—</text><subparagraph id="H4DEF8D6CD2A24DF89ADA4F4A372A35C9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means any gift of money, property, resources, staff, or services; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8E6937ED1FBF41CABD3F4294CB2D964D"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not include—</text><clause id="H7EB7842BA3EF4F84AE5DDD877CBB5D82"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any payment of one or more elements of a student’s cost of attendance (as such term is defined in section 472) to an institution by, or scholarship from, a foreign source who is a natural person, acting in their individual capacity and not as an agent for, at the request or direction of, or on behalf of, any person or entity (except the student), made for not more than 15 students, and that is not made under a restricted or conditional contract with such foreign source;</text></clause><clause id="HE496FA63AA9C4C369241EFFB0C0D61D0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assignment or license of registered industrial and intellectual property rights, such as patents, utility models, trademarks, or copyrights, or technical assistance, that are not associated with a category listed in the Commerce Control List maintained by the Bureau of Industry and Security of the Department of Commerce and set forth in Supplement No. 1 to part 774 of title 15, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations); or</text></clause><clause id="H6696047BFF454E22A6ADBB06BE353EBF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>decorations (as such term is defined in section 7342(a) of title 5, United States Code).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="HA8760D3580BD4BF0A7F16820FB8C5A49" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Enforcement and other general provisions</header><subsection id="H06C701A5365A47E9BD20706CA6068EA9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Enforcement and other general provisions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001 et seq.</external-xref>), as amended by this Act, is further amended by inserting after section 117A the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H55D02E53E389413ABF8B7DC3CF840587" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="H24DFFC76630448FE88BF68306BB1FA5C"><enum>117B.</enum><header>Enforcement; single point-of-contact; institutional requirements</header><subsection id="H37D9614E825B4AF0BDC8EFB67602F0D6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><paragraph id="HFD50709CB1EB4570848A8F3CF28D198E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Investigation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary (acting through the General Counsel of the Department) shall conduct investigations of possible violations of section 117A and subsection (c) of this section by institutions and, whenever it appears that an institution has knowingly or willfully failed to comply with a requirement of any of such provisions (including any rule or regulation promulgated under any such provision), shall request that the Attorney General bring a civil action in accordance with paragraph (2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5EF6FBFFB91B4C4E8692A49EA1544556" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Civil action</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whenever it appears that an institution has knowingly or willfully failed to comply with a requirement of any of the provisions listed in paragraph (1) (including any rule or regulation promulgated under any such provision) based on an investigation under such paragraph, a civil action shall be brought by the Attorney General, at the request of the Secretary, in an appropriate district court of the United States, or the appropriate United States court of any territory or other place subject to the jurisdiction of the United States, to request such court to compel compliance with the requirement of the provision that has been violated.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDF5926203B8E42D188D403CF8047D642" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Costs and other fines</header><text>An institution that is compelled to comply with a requirement of a provision listed in paragraph (1) pursuant to paragraph (2) shall—</text><subparagraph id="H184FE912A66F4635B6AFD21C6221E5B6" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>pay to the Treasury of the United States the full costs to the United States of obtaining compliance with the requirement of such provision, including all associated costs of investigation and enforcement; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H481693B2B867425F89409729387C8A25" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if applicable, be subject to the applicable fines described in paragraph (4).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4FE8B57948004315A542007E498A7FD2" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Fines for violations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall impose a fine on an institution that is compelled to comply with a requirement of section 117A pursuant to paragraph (2) as follows:</text><subparagraph id="H90E9E5EE52F7401D9CAEC7BE23013F1C" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>First-time violations</header><text>In the case of an institution that is compelled to comply with a requirement of section 117A pursuant to a civil action described in paragraph (2), and that has not previously been compelled to comply with any such requirement pursuant to such a civil action, the Secretary shall impose a fine on the institution for such violation in an amount that is the greater of—</text><clause id="HDCF20E4F594E43D3B2C6235E5565DE43" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>$250,000; or </text></clause><clause id="HDEF4F29F9E324AD689EAE0C8D0851457" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the total amount of gifts or contracts that the institution is compelled to report pursuant to such civil action.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7DBF1BB55939419CAAF4E169377FC3D9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Subsequent violations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an institution that has previously been compelled to comply with a requirement of section 117A pursuant to a civil action described in paragraph (2), and is subsequently compelled to comply with such a requirement pursuant to a subsequent civil action described in paragraph (2), the Secretary shall impose a fine on the institution in an amount that is the greater of—</text><clause id="HF3A6964C25D7494DB5959D5CECC12E74" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>$500,000; or</text></clause><clause id="HA9BE67A8359D48F897EFCEB26D236711" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>twice the total amount of gifts or contracts that the institution is compelled to report pursuant to such civil action.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3BA0F69E96F544CA84E9F2D29E8CA57A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Single point-of-Contact at the Department</header><text>The Secretary shall maintain a single point-of-contact at the Department to—</text><paragraph id="HE7B39A559F93411685E42576FB4B5EE9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>receive and respond to inquiries and requests for technical assistance from institutions regarding compliance with the requirements of section 117A and subsection (c) of this section; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4C5A8A0AFFD34B8BAB054818F880B4EB"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide, every 90 days after the date of enactment of the status updates on any pending or completed investigations and civil actions under subsection (a)(1) to—</text><subparagraph id="HF94C71092C2249E2A2334779C9D7A7F6"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the authorizing committees; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H35DA66C7B38B4806A81B67ED31ADFBA7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any institution that is the subject of such investigation or action; </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H14EF6D1DCD3749AE85173EE3EED7F6C3"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">maintain, on a publicly accessible website—</text><subparagraph id="H09603C9B0C3E48AA8C51DE476B51E259"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a full comprehensive list of all foreign countries of concern and foreign entities of concern; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3E863F19E6094D5F99E0B1C8311E091C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the date on which the last update was made to such list; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF67713A28FEC4E10B972358BF062B5DB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>not later than 7 days after making an update to the list maintained under paragraph (3)(A), notify each institution required to comply with the section listed in paragraph (1) of such update.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBBB8B82D997341A39EBE1863B5B43DC6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Institutional requirements for compliance officers and institutional policy requirements</header><paragraph id="HCD1E359F46A7454ABE8B3B524E3F904C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An institution that is subject to the requirements of section 117A shall, not later than the date on which the institution first fulfills the requirements of such section—</text><subparagraph id="HF17CB46137724114A82DECEC0071A81F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>establish an institutional policy that the institution shall follow in meeting the requirements of such section; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H09FC69DDF8E04D0F901A21CFB66BB714"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">designate and maintain at least one, but not more than three, current employees or legally authorized agents of such institution to serve as compliance officers to carry out the requirements listed in paragraph (2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H19E684E6E466407CA962D74CA16EA83C" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duties of compliance officers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A compliance officer designated by an institution under paragraph (1)(B) shall certify, whenever the institution is subject to the requirements of section 117A, that the institution—</text><subparagraph id="HD4BAEA80FE554CD6B294A049607D333C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is in compliance with the requirements of such section; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H96359FFDA8754793AC794A5F0765ADFE"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">followed the institutional policy established under paragraph (1)(A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H45959E9C78354F7181EFAC4D9C093F41"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of section 117A and this section:</text><paragraph id="HE0D6C3770A7245C198F5F2D1B56504B6" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Foreign country of concern</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>foreign country of concern</term> means the following:</text><subparagraph id="HD1A1EBA5FDB24CC281593E2A5AFA907A" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Any covered nation defined in section 4872 of title 10, United States Code.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H62A06A7157D14DB2A61D0B990F228476" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any country the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of State, and the Director of National Intelligence, determines, for purposes of section 117A or this section, to be engaged in conduct that is detrimental to the national security or foreign policy of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5EA7D03F7678483594ED60110FB683A4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Foreign entity of concern</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>foreign entity of concern</term> has the meaning given such term in section 10612(a) of the Research and Development, Competition, and Innovation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/19221">42 U.S.C. 19221(a)</external-xref>) and includes a foreign entity that is identified on the list published under section 1286(c)(8)(A) of the John S. McCain National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2019 (10 U.S.C. 22 4001 note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/232">Public Law 115–232</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H50F9AA7373884854897F811D715345AC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Institution</header><text>The term <term>institution</term> means an institution of higher education (as such term is defined in section 102, other than an institution described in subsection (a)(1)(C) of such section).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H2E62C1BA75954A4695BF9293C9A8F250"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Program participation agreement</header><text>Section 487(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1094">20 U.S.C. 1094</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HEA9929FAC4604F1E8CD34D519166E011" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H6992BC36B3E042C7A5D16594563121CF"><enum>(30)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HB90E507C960D4A338F8CF68C957B89E3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An institution will comply with the requirements of sections 117A and 117B(c). </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9A5D98C7CEC5408397848FAD80EC6A57" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>In the case of an institution described in subparagraph (C), the institution will—</text><clause id="H2F598468A92545B789291722ACB65C57"><enum>(i)</enum><text>be ineligible to participate in the programs authorized by this title for a period of not less than 2 institutional fiscal years; and</text></clause><clause id="H7324326EDC8B43998D613055FA4114D6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in order to regain eligibility to participate in such programs, demonstrate compliance with all requirements of each such section for not less than 2 institutional fiscal years after the institutional fiscal year in which such institution became ineligible. </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H276BE91EA6A24D189B572C7D13621618" indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An institution described in this subparagraph is an institution that has been subject to 3 separate civil actions described in section 117B(a)(2) that have each resulted in the institution being compelled to comply with one or more requirements of section 117A or 117B(c).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H05D93C9BCB0641629CB2414BD1370614"><enum>(c)</enum><header>GAO Study and Report</header><paragraph id="HDC494A2B8D244F9EB922FDF8F75E0C77"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Study</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall initiate a study to identify ways to improve intergovernmental agency coordination regarding implementation and enforcement of sections 117A and 117B(c) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1011f">20 U.S.C. 1011f</external-xref>), as added by this Act, including increasing information sharing, increasing compliance rates, and establishing processes for enforcement. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDD1BD01504D44CB78D6CFCC1925699AE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress, and make public, a report containing the results of the study described in <internal-xref idref="HDC494A2B8D244F9EB922FDF8F75E0C77" legis-path="(c)(1)">paragraph (1)</internal-xref>.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

