<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H36E2BC10ADA345C6AB238ED0832CB728" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5762 IH: New York-New Jersey Watershed Protection Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5762</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251014">October 14, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M000317">Ms. Malliotakis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000602">Ms. Gillen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000398">Mr. Kean</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000606">Mr. Latimer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001231">Mr. Mannion</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001229">Mrs. McIver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001226">Mr. Menendez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000188">Mr. Norcross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000172">Ms. Ocasio-Cortez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000034">Mr. Pallone</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000621">Ms. Pou</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000622">Mr. Riley of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000579">Mr. Ryan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001207">Ms. Sherrill</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001201">Mr. Suozzi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000486">Mr. Torres of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000133">Mr. Van Drew</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish the New York-New Jersey Watershed Restoration Program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC87469B38C96482491EBBC4D09855C4C" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HCA335F88CF60413886A63E120F5FD092" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>New York-New Jersey Watershed Protection Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H1305C9CA225A4515A15D1E43F20FA948"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="HA7F9F28C5EA44C34BA82C65A305EEB73"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Approved plan</header> 
<subparagraph id="H77860E687F494A25824454CCDEF750B2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>approved plan</term> means any plan for management of the Watershed—</text> <clause id="HF053C22B040D445EBD0149A2DB045BE1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that has been approved by a Federal, regional, State, Tribal, or local governmental entity, including State Wildlife Action Plans, Comprehensive Conservation Management Plans, and Watershed Improvement Plans; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H6F0A6AC2BEC44DCFB8C0B002B006FDBF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that is determined by the Secretary, in consultation with the entities described in clause (i), to contribute to the achievement of the purposes of this Act.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7035F51DEB8649F099A3E44218BB3CC3"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text>The term <term>approved plan</term> includes—</text> 
<clause id="H90DB119559A743248019F44FAB853323"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the New York-New Jersey Harbor &amp; Estuary Program (HEP) Action Agenda;</text></clause> <clause id="HB88C33A6AC834D03ABCEB3D69D6C3507"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Hudson Raritan Comprehensive Restoration Plan;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HF138161ED3B34D3584D28FDF3441A49A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the Hudson River Comprehensive Restoration Plan;</text></clause> <clause id="H976B8B0C19CD453988FBC3D52B4E0950"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the Hudson River Estuary Program Action Agenda;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H3EF4F3B4B9E34014958CA6028D3A6388"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the Mohawk River Action Agenda;</text></clause> <clause id="H844D21F2B04643F8A902C170879D95C6"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the Sustainable Raritan River Initiative Action Plan;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H4E70E593FE9D49189C2D05223A963C6C"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>the Lower Passaic and Bronx &amp; Harlem Federal Urban Waters Partnership Workplans;</text></clause> <clause id="H2DE7D53AE08D4CE3A6D56D3245A56E45"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>the New Jersey Sports and Exhibition Authority Meadowlands Restoration Plan; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HB81ABD9EC93C4CEA8112C792D397DEC3"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>such other conservation projects in the region that achieve the purposes of this Act, as determined by the Secretary.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2F519310C9ED4530B96273538D6AF1D3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Environmental justice</header><text>The term <term>environmental justice</term>, with respect to the development, implementation, and enforcement of environmental laws, regulations, and policies, means the fair treatment and meaningful involvement of all people, regardless of race, color, national origin, or income.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBCA17F9237EA4098A4CB927870FC5E2C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Foundation</header><text>The term <term>Foundation</term> means the National Fish and Wildlife Foundation.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9238683D913742578DBEBD45E568B77F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Grant program</header><text>The term <term>grant program</term> means the voluntary New York-New Jersey Watershed Restoration Grant Program established under section 4(a).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC239198BFB0B4857B9173634AD66EFFE"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Program</header><text>The term <term>program</term> means the New York-New Jersey Watershed Restoration Program established under section 3(a).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEF44B5396A4546DC950499173906B1D7"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Restoration and protection</header><text>The term <term>restoration and protection</term> means the conservation, stewardship, and enhancement of habitat for fish and wildlife, including water quality—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE09C971B49564B32BDC3FA1B1CD6870D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to preserve and improve ecosystems and ecological processes on which those fish and wildlife depend; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7ECECFECFB824BC8B993EA704E9E94AD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for use and enjoyment by the public.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFD1F5020B9C54EF1A0A1F49DA49D53FF"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEF577446B92A43D18C0DED2E903AA2FA"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Watershed</header><text>The term <term>Watershed</term> means the New York-New Jersey Watershed, which is composed of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H6DC52C9BC3F04E228A4127919E9649A8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>all land area the surface water of which drains into the New York-New Jersey Harbor;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H97ECE39BC9754AA5BBC3BC2273E4E154"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the waters contained within that land area; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H43E5070C7A8F419F9E27335A34400AA2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the estuaries associated with those watersheds.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> <section id="H1E59BF6781BA4552B776EF8CCE844E29"><enum>3.</enum><header>New York-New Jersey Watershed Restoration Program</header> <subsection id="HC3E90690B45845399036ACE730928860"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall establish a nonregulatory program, to be known as the <quote>New York-New Jersey Watershed Restoration Program</quote>.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5F3A407EABEC4E888CA800CF175EC8C0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of the program shall include—</text> <paragraph id="H6714DA68D57A46149022A1000AD7374F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>coordinating restoration and protection activities among Federal, State, Tribal, local, and regional entities and conservation partners throughout the Watershed;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HADEA2B349A744D4B8A6EC4C0DC164028"><enum>(2)</enum><text>carrying out coordinated restoration and protection activities, and providing for technical assistance for those activities, throughout the Watershed—</text> <subparagraph id="H0D7220022DAF426CB958A6DD64EA71A5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to sustain and enhance fish and wildlife habitat;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H99AE7003808A422C8F311A4B78F0B6AE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to improve and maintain water quality to support fish, wildlife, and their habitats, as well as to improve opportunities for public access and recreation in the Watershed consistent with the ecological needs of fish and wildlife habitats;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H212FFFA3997C4F30A71A7E5A65ECC362"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to advance the use of natural climate solutions and natural infrastructure, including living shorelines and other green infrastructure techniques, to maximize the resilience of communities, natural systems, and habitats experiencing the impacts of climate change;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCD3B0906371D4A2C9A46D79505836B93"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to engage the public, particularly communities experiencing environmental injustice, through outreach, education, and community involvement to increase capacity, support, and workforce development for coordinated restoration and protection activities in the Watershed;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDB648A6D19614BA6A8265BF8712AFB52"><enum>(E)</enum><text>to increase scientific capacity to support the planning, monitoring, and research activities necessary to carry out coordinated restoration and protection activities in the Watershed;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2F0FF70C80A34243BF6C9617AE50E33F"><enum>(F)</enum><text>to provide for feasibility and planning studies for green infrastructure projects that achieve habitat restoration and stormwater management goals;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA8F034E7D5E14B13A8497407EE9A7E08"><enum>(G)</enum><text>to support land conservation and management activities necessary to fulfill the Watershed-wide strategy adopted under subsection (c)(3);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCC935F5E7F6845B08D0A723BBB045F9F"><enum>(H)</enum><text>to monitor environmental quality to assess progress toward the purposes of this Act; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA4ED508A187B498C970A79D53065AA8C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to improve fish and wildlife habitats, as well as opportunities for personal recreation, along rivers and shore fronts within communities experiencing environmental injustice; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1923FBDCD3764D83809CB5D7062F5832" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><text>carrying out restoration and protection activities necessary, as determined by the Secretary, for the implementation of approved plans.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H6420C541C8894A4E88F5E17DC7E1FFC5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>In carrying out the program, the Secretary shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H4CDFAA0764944687906D78E0C00EF5D1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>draw on existing and new approved plans for the Watershed, or portions of the Watershed;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB6E501468879476BBA60E087159F3556"><enum>(2)</enum><text>work in consultation with applicable management entities, including representatives of the New York-New Jersey Harbor and Estuary Program (HEP), the Hudson River Estuary Program, the Mohawk River Basin Program, the Sustainable Raritan River Initiative, the Federal Government, other State and local governments, and regional and nonprofit organizations, including environmental justice organizations, as appropriate, to identify, prioritize, and implement restoration and protection activities within the Watershed; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8EC041750BE546C99F915310A3131493"><enum>(3)</enum><text>adopt a Watershed-wide strategy that—</text> <subparagraph id="H3681ABF24CCF4B60A17BE9C6410AC6AA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>supports the implementation of a shared set of science-based restoration and protection activities developed in accordance with paragraph (2);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9ABEECEF19EE41ED95C746F46F27A088"><enum>(B)</enum><text>targets cost-effective projects with measurable results;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H37BE74CBE2FA47D28A359879CD81407E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>maximizes conservation outcomes;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB9B36BB7A41345B78A856D0507CED7A6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>prioritizes the needs of communities experiencing environmental injustice; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDC79838BB21B432FBEE2DAE25335E9AF"><enum>(E)</enum><text>implements the grant program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA0C378DDCB414D0297BE4B28B55A8008"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In establishing the program, the Secretary shall consult with, as appropriate—</text> <paragraph id="H554D8EE194F246B288BEB0B2F953C6FE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the heads of Federal agencies, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HCE3FE6B0C21D42109B0AEEFE91F6198A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H884EEB3BD0FF48B89ED4B6389C1E783D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0BAE11C39B3D42879BD23FF2B58E152F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Secretary of Agriculture;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB3DEDB950E0C4663AF7DA2BD2DC7DE79"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Director of the National Park Service; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H29F9B6508D0B45CEA4DB2CAABABDA208"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the heads of such other Federal agencies as the Secretary determines to be appropriate;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5A8DAD65292941108A1AD4F30A90CAFE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Governor of New York;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1B4552600279410F83F4AA8E8A0FDE65"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Governor of New Jersey;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6F893E98070D4677B47E97D905F41DFA"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the Commissioner of the New York State Department of Environmental Conservation;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7B99A22BC607425A8424ECD745741FF4"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the Director of the New Jersey Division of Fish and Wildlife;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5E34F083AC014DFD85098C37E4461622"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the New York-New Jersey Harbor &amp; Estuary Program; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0FDDD97DDE9A4C17A9B7C2835B90E36C"><enum>(7)</enum><text>other public agencies, Indian Tribes, and organizations with authority for the planning and implementation of conservation strategies in the Watershed, as determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H57413617B98F4519AC7A1AAD126FA807"><enum>4.</enum><header>New York-New Jersey watershed restoration grant program</header> <subsection id="H0FB44C13D1264692BCA3AE6A286B6D1A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall establish a voluntary grant and technical assistance program, to be known as the <quote>New York-New Jersey Watershed Restoration Grant Program</quote>, to provide competitive matching grants to State, Tribal, and local governments, nonprofit organizations, institutions of higher education, and other eligible entities, as determined by the Secretary, to carry out the coordinated restoration and protection activities described in section 3(b)(2).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H56A07FFFAFAC42C78D5275CAE4E782BA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Criteria</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with the individuals and entities referred to in section 3(d), shall develop criteria for the grant program to ensure that activities funded under the grant program—</text> <paragraph id="HF413302531254CCD874A1EAD9EBD81F4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>accomplish 1 or more of the purposes identified in section 3(b)(2); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDBDAEBF74B6242178A6A8FD0431E003B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>advance the implementation of priority actions or needs identified in the Watershed-wide strategy adopted under section 3(c)(3).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF138F20484D34B9FB1949B601829FB34"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Capacity building</header><text>In carrying out the grant program, the Secretary shall seek to increase the effectiveness of organizations that carry out restoration and protection activities described in section 3(b)(2) within the Watershed by addressing organizational capacity needs.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H60AA53E90246428FA0E2DF097FD449B2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Cost-Share</header> 
<paragraph id="HAFDA2D59088840E782C498AFE376B530" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Federal share</header> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H6C182342589246D1BB6C8C0DD963AFC2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the Federal share of the total cost of a restoration and protection activity carried out under the grant program shall be not more than 50 percent, as determined by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HDE326A2BB6C6466DAB29C0D40DDC6CE8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Small, rural, and disadvantaged communities</header> <clause id="H578D24277152416DA60EE6401AC3CFAA"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to clause (ii) the Federal share of the total cost of a restoration and protection activity carried out under the grant program that serves a small, rural, or disadvantaged community shall be 90 percent, as determined by the Secretary.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H778807830B544242B2069F25D83E3468"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>The Secretary may increase the Federal share under clause (i) to 100 percent of the total cost of the restoration and protection activity if the Secretary determines that the grant recipient is unable to pay, or would experience significant financial hardship if required to pay, the non-Federal share.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H53F22A076033439AA4FFF343E22FCE24" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Non-Federal share</header> <subparagraph id="H3C7B555704894C6395F98962CE9E22D1" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The non-Federal share of the total cost of a restoration and protection activity carried out under the grant program shall be not more than 50 percent, as determined by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF44E9711D06444E6A28501C50541B52F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Form of payment</header><text>The non-Federal share described in subparagraph (A) may be provided—</text> <clause id="HAA2F122994014BB987D8DFBB67465945"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in cash; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="HBCFEA430008848C8A730C22E87CF1EDF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the form of an in-kind contribution of services or materials.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H8E162E805D9D44ED865632B9C095CC65"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Administration</header> <paragraph id="H0448A294E16B4E6582D011BBD94A6E88"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may enter into an agreement to manage the grant program with—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HAA9D28F82D514E13A7D12AB832F12FCB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Foundation; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8A189BB1884241AEAB98184E6D608D92"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a similar organization that offers grant management services.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9DABC9C2C3884648B6EF35DC684D5067"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>If the Secretary enters into an agreement under paragraph (1), the Foundation or similar organization selected, as applicable, shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H0D117FD5C94A42FBA51BCC75D965EC91"><enum>(A)</enum><text>receive the amounts made available to carry out the grant program under section 7 for each applicable fiscal year in an advance payment of the entire amount on October 1 of that fiscal year, or as soon as practicable thereafter;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFA539D74E7D24C84A477F0E068CA4DAB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>invest and reinvest those amounts for the benefit of the grant program; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H82FB9791E1E94146B0873133055A2E19"><enum>(C)</enum><text>administer the grant program to support partnerships between the public and private sectors in accordance with this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HECD050CD6295453EB2DE6BBE8C973A88"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>If the Secretary enters into an agreement with the Foundation under paragraph (1), any amounts received by the Foundation under this section shall be subject to the National Fish and Wildlife Foundation Establishment Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/3701">16 U.S.C. 3701 et seq.</external-xref>), excluding section 10(a) of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/3709">16 U.S.C. 3709(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H3763BED1DB55476D8773349B002A5277"><enum>5.</enum><header>Annual report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the implementation of this Act, including a description of each activity that has received funding under this Act in the preceding fiscal year.</text></section> 
<section id="HD26D8D0E5044439392FEE2234BAF4EA9"><enum>6.</enum><header>Prohibition on Federal land holdings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Federal Government may not maintain ownership of any land acquired under this Act except for the purpose of promptly transferring ownership to an entity described in section 4(a).</text></section> <section id="H97BA40A732D143D28F2917F173F766DD"><enum>7.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header> <subsection id="H6B517F6A70DA4097BD654DA1CE976D7E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this Act $20,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2031, of which not more than 5 percent shall be used for administrative costs of carrying out this Act.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE604D96E72EE48FBA23CC43F3E01802A" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grant program</header><text>Of the amounts made available to carry out this Act for each fiscal year, the Secretary shall use not less than 75 percent to carry out the grant program, including for technical assistance relating to the grant program.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H97B4CF95A469445B88C516A4BC9404BF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Supplement, not supplant</header><text>Amounts made available to carry out this Act for each fiscal year shall supplement, and not supplant, funding for other activities conducted by the Secretary in the Watershed.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HA6F7A7521D224189B69E11F9579FD7E2"><enum>8.</enum><header>Sunset</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act shall cease to have force or effect on October 1, 2031.</text></section> </legis-body></bill>

