<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF128BD991CE24A7D8F3883D7FEC1CB10" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1369 IH: President Jimmy Carter Congressional Gold Medal Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1369</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250214">February 14, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B000490">Mr. Bishop</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001189">Mr. Austin Scott of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000188">Mr. Norcross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001208">Mrs. McBath</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000788">Ms. Williams of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000311">Mr. Jack</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000399">Mr. Doggett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To award posthumously a Congressional Gold Medal to former President Jimmy Carter in recognition of his service to the Nation.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE65013734323479C8D8A5FDBD389E110" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H1843193C6B8D45978E64583BF1AF7465" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>President Jimmy Carter Congressional Gold Medal Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H57FA3D8527834BF1B74B1140F34AD90F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HAAA52786FBCB46C8B71A1C413FB5960B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>President Jimmy Carter served as the 39th President of the United States from 1977 to 1981.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAC55C7BA4A6D450DBEFEF3A33E595EDA"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">President Jimmy Carter, whose full name is James Earl Carter, Jr., was born on October 1, 1924, in Plains, Georgia, a small farming town.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H21D61780D70442A69C59A2674FF1CBF5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>President Carter graduated from the United States Naval Academy in Annapolis, Maryland in 1946 and actively served as a submarine officer for 7 years. He served in the Navy Reserve for another 8 years, separating from the Navy with the rank of Lieutenant in 1961.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H339FA2C4763947C1AAE3178784DC1499"><enum>(4)</enum><text>President Carter married his wife and life partner of 77 years, Rosalynn Smith, on July 7th, 1946, in Plains, Georgia.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3F94844490EF4442941715DE1C817A95"><enum>(5)</enum><text>President Carter entered state politics in 1962 and was elected to the Georgia State Senate from the 14th District in 1963. He was sworn in as the 76th governor of Georgia in 1971. During his tenure, he emphasized government efficiency and removing racial discrimination.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC461EB4BA25E41F99A00536C46FDEDE9"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Guided by his moral values and deep religious faith, Jimmy Carter’s presidency was characterized by a commitment to championing civil and human rights around the world. His foreign policy accomplishments include the Panama Canal treaties, the Camp David Accords, the normalization and treaty of peace between Egypt and Israel following the Fourth Arab-Israeli War, the SALT II nuclear limitation treaty with the Soviet Union, and the establishment of United States diplomatic relations with the People’s Republic of China.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDF42239F4AD342F9B8083CB21A14315F"><enum>(7)</enum><text>President Jimmy Carter’s domestic legacy includes the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/3101">16 U.S.C. 3101 et seq.</external-xref>), one of the most significant pieces of environmental legislation ever approved by Congress; the Nation’s first national energy policy; and the creation of the Departments of Education and Energy.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA4E9D68BB4C74930A47010A2ED6BC52C"><enum>(8)</enum><text>After his presidency, he founded the Carter Center along with his wife Rosalynn, which is dedicated to conflict resolution, supervising democratic elections abroad, and combating neglected tropical diseases.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFB0ECB9A7B9C4466A20C8B5292209891"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Through their work with the Carter Center, Jimmy and Rosalynn Carter are credited with the near eradication of the painful parasitic infection known as Guinea worm disease, reducing cases from an estimated total of 3,500,000 in 1986 to just 14 in 2023.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H77C25EA001864202A9F894D5A71E8DDA"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Through a partnership with Habitat for Humanity known as the Carter Work Project, Jimmy and his wife Rosalynn led and worked alongside over 100,000 volunteers across 14 countries to build, improve, and repair over 4,400 homes.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H971DF145923847F7906BF2AABEBFAACE"><enum>(11)</enum><text>In 2002, Jimmy Carter became the third American President to win the Nobel Peace Prize for his <quote>decades of untiring effort to find peaceful solutions to international conflicts, to advance democracy and human rights, and to promote economic and social development</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD30F1D6A4DE44B0A8DD46646B41A3A91"><enum>(12)</enum><text>President Carter exemplifies American voluntarism through his countless service activities in his home State of Georgia, throughout the United States, and across the world.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H43A287ADE5024E46A6772352D0EAD839"><enum>3.</enum><header>Congressional gold medal</header> 
<subsection id="H4513DBEC26E4468AA927636003CEEB9A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Presentation authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President pro tempore of the Senate shall make appropriate arrangements for the posthumous presentation, on behalf of Congress, of a single gold medal of appropriate design to former President Jimmy Carter in recognition of his service to the Nation.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HD67BFAA0B2364B6B8E32FC5119810D19"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Design and striking</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of the presentation referred to in subsection (a), the Secretary of the Treasury (referred to in this Act as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall strike a gold medal with suitable emblems, devices, and inscriptions, to be determined by the Secretary. The design shall bear an image of, and inscription of the name of Jimmy Carter.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H42418A45E4D7425B8BCF0998BE34C5D7" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Disposition of medal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Following the award of the medal under subsection (a), the gold medal shall be given to the Carter Center in Atlanta, Georgia.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HBADBE1B2A319468DA7382759DF25093E"><enum>4.</enum><header>Duplicate medals</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary may strike and sell duplicates in bronze of the gold medal struck under section 3, at a price sufficient to cover the costs thereof, including labor, materials, dies, use of machinery, and overhead expenses.</text></section> 
<section id="HF392BCEB3B9549728437C93241DD36FC"><enum>5.</enum><header>Status of medals</header> 
<subsection id="HD5768F79F64A4401A6FC2EA7AE1C7062"><enum>(a)</enum><header>National medal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Medals struck pursuant to this Act are national medals for purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/51">chapter 51</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H605E54C13D314D4D9F355BAE8D6CA7BA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Numismatic items</header><text>For purposes of sections 5134 and 5136 of title 31, United States Code, all medals struck under this Act shall be considered to be numismatic items.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HA627FAA0F6A344C7802CFB3168C0C0AA"><enum>6.</enum><header>Authority to use fund amounts; proceeds of sale</header> 
<subsection id="H964AE42C77404CD589B9C867D240CCE5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority To use fund amounts</header><text>There is authorized to be charged against the United States Mint Public Enterprise Fund such amounts as may be necessary to pay for the costs of the medals struck under this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HE11252B748D948D198C72D34CBD83442"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Proceeds of sale</header><text>Amounts received from the sale of duplicate bronze medals authorized under section 4 shall be deposited into the United States Mint Public Enterprise Fund.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

