<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5EF251C6FED147388CD86D72C8273E93" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5512 IH: No Shari’a Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5512</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250919">September 19, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000484">Mr. Fine</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S001224">Mr. Self</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the application of Shari’a in the United States where such application would violate constitutional rights, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC3E02A7480CA449E8C2DB9BF02569F09" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H9128F81A4D69458D9154D9D9C94D3677" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No Shari’a Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H369F577C7E6E49E5B5224EC4C3CBDAF3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text> 
<paragraph id="HA87248E13A784ACB9BF58122F5D1FA84"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Constitution of the United States is and must remain the supreme law of the land, and no foreign law or legal system may be permitted to undermine it;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H62B07B60B5BB4043AC4D7E89CA231F3D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>attempts to apply foreign law, including religious or international codes, in American courts risk eroding constitutional protections, particularly in matters of family law, contract law, and civil rights;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H79094F04A32D4602AA0F0ADC9CB50FBB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>safeguarding constitutional rights is especially urgent in cases involving women, children, and vulnerable populations who may face coercion or unequal treatment under foreign legal systems;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCDD8A52D7D58485BADDAF0E12D96D807"><enum>(4)</enum><text>while individuals are free to practice their religion and observe personal codes voluntarily, United States courts must never enforce or give effect to laws that conflict with fundamental liberties guaranteed by the Constitution; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3108FB487374466E89FE2617B14AE323"><enum>(5)</enum><text>this Act is necessary to reaffirm and protect the rights of all citizens by ensuring that only American laws govern American courts.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H901F6EC8866F4971BC06C746ED781F44"><enum>3.</enum><header>Findings and purposes</header> <subsection id="HF1680D16C48548F3BDD4BBAA50970C57"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HFFD3E6AFAFBF4B718DDCB061F017EF80"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Supremacy Clause of the Constitution requires State and Federal courts to apply United States law above Shari’a or any foreign law.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3CAA0F36A5F049BB92854F45C94FE335"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In certain judicial and arbitration cases, parties have sought to apply foreign law contrary to United States constitutional guarantees.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFFD1945887F8471F8D8B2FDDF808A408"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Clear and uniform rules are needed to prevent erosion of constitutional protections in all jurisdictions.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H018D74EA27EC4E64812BEDB46B8B5C9E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>It is the purpose of this Act to—</text> 
<paragraph id="HB9BB19F3C1674A35A981C193BC7D2967"><enum>(1)</enum><text>prohibit the enforcement of Shari’a or any foreign law that infringes on constitutional rights;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6AFD98E9D52348B6B1C67A3E64A1A6DA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>affirm that American courts must rely solely on Federal and State law; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3770F29FC1B5498999F4E3D07A77D4DB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provide certainty and clarity in the application of constitutional protections nationwide.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H521FF8706D86417D8F836FEB8B48EC2B"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For the purposes of this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="HB7B79DC36E784C6BA249BE44BF884229"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <quote>foreign law</quote> means any law, legal code, or system derived from a jurisdiction outside the United States or its territories, including religious law when invoked as a substitute for State or Federal law.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD4E0B0578F0F4DDAAC6ED6C1AF87AFBD"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>court</quote> means any Federal, State, or territorial court, including arbitration tribunals when decisions are subject to judicial enforcement.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3DBACEB4CAEB49C9B06B16C403900150"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>fundamental rights</quote> means rights guaranteed by the Constitution of the United States and by State constitutions, including due process, equal protection, freedom of religion, freedom of speech, and rights related to marriage, child custody, and property.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H8FB24CAA44CF4C229711D8429952C3CE"><enum>5.</enum><header>Application of Shari’a</header> <subsection id="H3E9D79A909984E589C893C8F4DFB64EC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>No court shall enforce a judgment, decree, or arbitration decision if it relies, in whole or in part, on Shari’a or any foreign law that violates the constitutional rights of any party.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H265297E91371447C810C882517429BAE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contracts</header><text>A contract provision choosing foreign law shall be valid unless enforcement would result in a violation of constitutional rights.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HC81E109BD3FC491B9859B8CFBCABDC28"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Family Law</header><text>In matters involving marriage, divorce, child custody, adoption, or inheritance, no court shall apply or enforce foreign law if inconsistent with fundamental rights or public policy.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H2ED9E149FF91486BB6C910DD292E4643"><enum>6.</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Attorney General of the United States, in consultation with the Administrative Office of the U.S. Courts, shall issue regulations and provide judicial education to ensure uniform application of this Act.</text></section> <section id="HCA46790B656E473289146B371592D597"><enum>7.</enum><header>Severability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any provision of this Act is held invalid, the remainder of the Act and its application shall not be affected.</text></section> 
<section id="HD874CE5135F240C08AA63083AF6E30BC"><enum>8.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act shall take effect 180 days after enactment of this Act.</text></section> </legis-body></bill>

