<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ROS25029-TRC-95-DD8"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S411 IS: Flight 293 Remembrance Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 411</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250205">February 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S229">Mrs. Murray</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S383">Mr. Sullivan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To develop a database of members of the Armed Forces who died in non-combat military plane crashes and to provide support to the families of such members, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Flight 293 Remembrance Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id9220decf94634800bfc6b76c9ca0d29c"><enum>2.</enum><header>Program to support families of members of the Armed Forces who died in non-combat military plane crashes</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1bb1856090654f4794fded1595616e4f"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Identification</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, shall—</text><paragraph id="id174498484bd7494688491d4dd8c911fc"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identify and document all non-combat military plane crashes categorized as <quote>Operational Loss/Non-War Loss</quote>—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide85d00ba77c44d09ac3a686765582de0"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">based on a thorough review of records of the Department of Defense starting with calendar year 1984; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6ba71c279e044dee9a97fddd41888329"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for such crashes that occurred before calendar year 1984, using information obtained from other organizations; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide9501b92274644ef896e99a9fe160a08"><enum>(2)</enum><text>develop and maintain a publicly accessible database of the names, ranks, and service details of all members of the Armed Forces who died in such crashes. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id7dab564d65ad4761989fdb79e782feac"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Assistance to families</header><text>The Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, shall provide assistance to the families of members of the Armed Forces who died in crashes described in subsection (a)(1)—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id30a30829d2b94d72aefe33771b3828fe"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to ensure that those families are aware of and have full access to the benefits, resources, and support services available from the Department of Defense;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc22554331873486fba45603d185ca4dc"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to offer personalized guidance on navigating and applying for those benefits, resources, and services, including financial assistance, counseling services, and survivor benefits tailored to non-combat losses; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id69a4789950074942b0cc9bbc66fa1ffa"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to connect those families with community and peer support networks that allow them to meet and share experiences with others who have faced similar losses.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id41e9e89b04fc4727b137f43ba9cdcb91"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Designated point of contact</header><text>The Secretary of Defense shall establish a designated point of contact within the Department of Defense—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id34de23b2f33a4a168d7034e2674d04cd"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to be responsible for guiding families of members of the Armed Forces who died in crashes described in subsection (a)(1) through the benefits process;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb196f52ccac64a7dbdb646224e432259"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to provide those families with updates on—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4a1352efc9a5435b88dae80b18df5baf"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the availability of new programs, services, and benefits; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id754fc779247c42dcbfcca3b261ff796c"><enum>(B)</enum><text>changes to law that may affect the eligibility of those families for support; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida890eaae3b6e429bb65b808b43d0b91a"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">advancements in efforts to recover members who died in crashes described in subsection (a)(1); and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id10f575607e934a3984dc679ae8a80d1e"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to liaise with relevant agencies, such as the Department of Veterans Affairs, and local support organizations to ensure those families receive coordinated, streamlined assistance.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id9e3c4312a5f346438f50b9e6e79e1000"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Consultations</header><text>In carrying out this section, the Secretary of Defense may consult with organizations with knowledge of and expertise relating to crashes described in subsection (a)(1).</text></subsection><subsection id="idc0f185a72a8b4a4ea9afb4a82c07b6a3"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report required</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to Congress a report on efforts carried out under this section that includes—</text><paragraph id="id9482a12ef36f417c9b57f09a763dbc22"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the number of families receiving support under subsection (b) and a description of the types of support those families received;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd9c1fbf603544858b4c82e2453ffac33"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an assessment of progress made in developing the database required by subsection (a)(2) that includes an estimate of the percentage of crashes described in subsection (a)(1) that have been included in the database as of the date of the report;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id29513fc174d5468c8dc0c5a9acf7cf08"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an assessment of the effectiveness of efforts carried out under this section and the satisfaction of the families of members of the Armed Forces who died in crashes described in subsection (a)(1); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id529d5433571c4d48b0b02fca5b6ba7c9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>any recommendations for legislative changes to improve efforts carried out under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id9c4492e844094351a87c11e60f58920a"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Nondiscrimination provisions</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id855c9ad4f66f4ea68600e3572b52fca0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purpose of applying the prohibitions against discrimination on the basis of disability under section 504 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/794">29 U.S.C. 794</external-xref>), on the basis of sex under title IX of the Education Amendments of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1681">20 U.S.C. 1681 et seq.</external-xref>), or on the basis of race, color, or national origin under title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d">42 U.S.C. 2000d et seq.</external-xref>), programs and activities funded or otherwise financially assisted in whole or in part under this section to provide assistance to families under this section, even if carried out directly by the Department of Defense or the Department of Veterans Affairs, are considered to be education programs and activities receiving Federal financial assistance. </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc65370d8cc264735bbe15f3cb709ff41"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall effectuate the provisions of paragraph (1) by issuing regulations, applicable to officers or employees of the Department of Defense or Department of Veterans Affairs, respectively, who provide assistance under this section directly, including provisions specifying how the corresponding Secretary shall enforce the regulations.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

