<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-HLA25598-J0D-XS-J2F"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 S2381 IS: Preventing Recurring Online Abuse of Children Through Intentional Vetting of Artificial Intelligence Data Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2381</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250722">July 22, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S287">Mr. Cornyn</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S426">Mr. Kim</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00" added-display-style="italic" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology to develop a framework for detecting, removing, and reporting child pornography in datasets used to train artificial intelligence systems, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Preventing Recurring Online Abuse of Children Through Intentional Vetting of Artificial Intelligence Data Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>PROACTIV Artificial Intelligence Data Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddea70f8083d04deabd802d62dedbbfd6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb338a83b815d4e2399ea6a0b4de4838a"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Artificial intelligence</header><text>The term <term>artificial intelligence</term> has the meaning given that term in section 238(g) of the John S. McCain National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2019 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/232">Public Law 115–232</external-xref>; 10 U.S.C. note prec. 4061).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida886459243fc49fdb32ec1f5527616d8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Artificial intelligence developer</header><text>The term <term>artificial intelligence developer</term> means a person who designs, codes, or produces an artificial intelligence system and makes such system commercially available, whether for profit or not.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id676eadf122c34d568d88db463c5dd64f"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Artificial Intelligence Deployer</header><text>.The term <term>artificial intelligence deployer</term> means a person who integrates an artificial intelligence system into the products or services of the person and makes those products or services commercially available, whether for profit or not.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3c1fbabaaf98494e98e43fccfa34d8d7"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Artificial intelligence user</header><text>The term <term>artificial intelligence user</term> means a person who uses an artificial intelligence system for a purpose other than personal noncommercial activity.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id51a9a8fe682a4882bfad0e702ba91703"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Child pornography</header><text>The term <term>child pornography</term> has the meaning given that term in section 2256 of title 18, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3fd7135e9d4f44dfa2a22f67b92f60e0"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Covered dataset</header><text>The term <term>covered dataset</term> means a set of data that—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide402776680054113b07652c4c3c67400"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is collected for the purpose of training an artificial intelligence system; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id04f4687eed4e4c0ba57c3f1170a7ad90"><enum>(B)</enum><text>was created using automated data crawlers or data scraping tools, whether or not directed by a human operator.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida9a32d20d7114d368d6f8aa3600f8d6e"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Data collector</header><text>The term <term>data collector</term> means any person who specializes in collecting, preparing, cleaning, labeling, transforming for algorithmic compatibility, and organizing large amounts of data for the purpose of training an artificial intelligence system.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6c2db62c60e545ae98bc6f16ffe77627"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The term <term>Director</term> means the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology.</text></paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7664832ec110417bbc3eed98ed02ecf4"><enum>3.</enum><header>Development of framework on detecting, removing, and reporting child pornography in certain datasets</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaed05a73fd174d1b9e22f2d360d024ab"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director shall, in collaboration with such other Federal agencies and public and private sector organizations as the Director considers appropriate, including the National Science Foundation, the National Center for Missing and Exploited Children, and the Department of Justice, develop and publish a voluntary framework for detecting, removing, and reporting child pornography in covered datasets.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd271eea659044993819ab1f989bef91c"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The Director shall ensure that the framework published under subsection (a) provides to artificial intelligence developers and to data collectors guidelines, best practices, methodologies, procedures, and processes—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4a5a5fe2fd0943c9aa6f057d06e03ff7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to detect any child pornography in covered datasets;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id93ce261938ac4bcbbf0a5eac08b8adec"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to remove any child pornography from covered datasets; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8df3b635391c4be09a119857d0185e7d"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to regularly report to Federal, State, or local law enforcement and the National Center for Missing and Exploited Children any child pornography detected in covered datasets.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc647d39a46c34db69f553911bcfd5234"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The framework published under subsection (a) shall apply to persons who are artificial intelligence developers and to data collectors, and not to persons who are solely artificial intelligence deployers or artificial intelligence users.</text></subsection><subsection id="id7b2dd92f89d540ceac40864aca6b6dff"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Stakeholder outreach</header><text>In developing the framework issued under subsection (a), the Director shall—</text><paragraph id="id48b98602ec7847b5a2158c5edfdb99aa"><enum>(1)</enum><text>solicit input from—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3edb8341f2b14c6b927b4cd5bd261c26"><enum>(A)</enum><text>institutions of higher education (as defined in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>));</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6bae64e0c8874a228eaea3e34bcd66e9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any Federal agency the Director considers relevant;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida79fda32644d460898dce029ad59ea40"><enum>(C)</enum><text>civil society and nonprofit organizations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id453089e26a714071aec49a052a591321"><enum>(D)</enum><text>artificial intelligence developers and artificial intelligence deployers;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide48c745c4eb14788b000e7b6b6d1b9a6"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Federal laboratories (as defined in section 4 of the Stevenson-Wydler Technology Innovation Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/3703">15 U.S.C. 3703</external-xref>)); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id26086d868d0742018ae8f650e66da75e"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other such stakeholder the Director considers appropriate; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9d861b06ab9e40aca253d898b00c3e2c"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide an opportunity for public comment on the guidelines, best practices, methodologies, procedures, and processes developed as part of the framework.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idbc5a59fb6d814554900e3935e4c9b382"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Research</header><text>The Director of the National Science Foundation, in coordination with the heads of other relevant Federal agencies, as determined by such Director, shall support research into innovative approaches to detecting, removing, and reporting child pornography from covered datasets, including research conducted through the Directorate for Technology, Innovation, and Partnerships.</text></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="id68bbdd6d3a6143589da9e9cbac3edaa4"><enum>4.</enum><header>Limited liability for detecting, removing, and reporting child pornography</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id07105b3dc2f6422783ecaa1531a7bb08"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (b), no cause of action shall lie or be maintained in any court against an artificial intelligence developer or data collector, and such action shall be promptly dismissed, for the detecting, removing, or reporting of child pornography in covered datasets that is conducted in accordance with the framework issued by the Director under section 3(a).</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc45c4664bd0b4519bedd11ef979f69e5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Intentional, reckless, grossly negligent, or other misconduct</header><text>Subsection (a) shall not apply to a cause of action for detecting, removing, or reporting child pornography in covered datasets if the artificial intelligence developer or data collector—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaab772d449e2429b83eff6b147421418"><enum>(1)</enum><text>engaged in intentional misconduct;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7f42d4133de14cb9b7f66ce8c135de47"><enum>(2)</enum><text>acted, or failed to act—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida5b6a5dce2f747709f5e0b37bcfe4b3b"><enum>(A)</enum><text>with actual malice;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida07f4a879e9d46919360e4d66d9bf937"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with reckless disregard to a substantial risk of causing injury without legal justification; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfed3306c3b054258bc2ab9cb2d0611af"><enum>(C)</enum><text>with gross negligence; or</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6dc0ac6022e248c885f42da5e3c00736"><enum>(3)</enum><text>engaged in any activity that violates section 2251 of title 18, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4899d446b1a44a70b4277be159b6089e"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to affect the protections and obligations of section 2258A of title 18, United States Code.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

