<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-FLO25436-N00-1K-XST"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1453 IS: University of Utah Research Park Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1453</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250410">April 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S346">Mr. Lee</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S431">Mr. Curtis</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To confirm the use of certain non-Federal land in Salt Lake City, Utah, for public purposes, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>University of Utah Research Park Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idD5BFCFA5C5D04AD2A3566075ADE1016B" changed="not-changed"><enum>2.</enum><header>Confirmation of use of certain non-Federal land in Salt Lake City, Utah, for valid public purposes</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4d443d84134048fb90de085bc464c363" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Confirmation of uses</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc07f8bde21bd448a8815929d39a4b2ab" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The use by the University of Utah of the land described in subsection (b) as a University research park, as approved by the letter from the Secretary of the Interior to the University of Utah dated December 10, 1970, and any modifications of the approved plan of development and management approved by the Department of the Interior prior to the date of enactment of this Act, is confirmed as a valid public purpose consistent with the requirements of the Act of June 14, 1926 (commonly known as the <quote>Recreation and Public Purposes Act</quote>) (44 Stat. 741, chapter 578; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/869">43 U.S.C. 869 et seq.</external-xref>), subject to the terms and conditions included in the letter and approvals.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5ce3e8511fbb4a4a84981e4f7e6e8c17" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Other uses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any other uses of the land described in subsection (b) by the University of Utah that are consistent with use as a University research park and related university purposes (including development of student housing and a transit hub) are confirmed as valid public purposes consistent with the requirements of the Act of June 14, 1926 (commonly known as the “Recreation and Public Purposes Act”) (44 Stat. 741, chapter 578; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/869">43 U.S.C. 869 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id5f763d1e5b4d4ab6921511601c605854" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Description of non-Federal land</header><text>The land referred to in subsection (a) is the approximately 593.54 acres of land conveyed to the University of Utah under the Act of June 14, 1926 (commonly known as the <quote>Recreation and Public Purposes Act</quote>) (44 Stat. 741, chapter 578; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/869">43 U.S.C. 869 et seq.</external-xref>), by patent numbered 43–99–0012 and dated October 18, 1968, and more particularly described as tracts D (excluding parcels numbered 1, 2, 3, 4, and 5), G, and J, T. 1 S., R. 1 E., Salt Lake Meridian. </text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

