<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HFA5B6E1C86D14F5090DEC0DDEF5F0530" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5458 IH: Child Care Access Means Parents In Schools Reauthorization Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5458</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250918">September 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001101">Ms. Clark of Massachusetts</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000585">Mr. Gomez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000620">Ms. Pettersen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001227">Ms. McClellan</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Child Care Access Means Parents In School Program under the Higher Education Act of 1965.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF52FD7F68E1640389928A2B06FBD110F" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H8D957A62FFE54762BF0C69C18AC36881" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Child Care Access Means Parents In Schools Reauthorization Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>CCAMPIS Reauthorization Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H17AD2C60FC7743279D40A97A3B448760"><enum>2.</enum><header>Child care access means parents in school</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 419N of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070e">20 U.S.C. 1070e</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAE70050EF75F41B6A3265B07A38B7764">
<section id="H4A591B8C99C84C0A99B5BCE146B69B52"><enum>419N.</enum><header>Child care access means parents in school</header>
<subsection id="H9B549A76192A413C980B24C0871F9E14" commented="no">
            <enum>(a)</enum>
            <header>Purpose</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The purpose of this section is to facilitate the success of eligible student parents in postsecondary education through the provision of child care services, including campus-based child care services.</text>
          </subsection>
<subsection id="H9C550913427C49CDB321E9011259CF52"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Program authorized</header>
<paragraph id="HAF49201255414502B22EAD17111155AE">
              <enum>(1)</enum>
              <header>Authority</header>
 <text>The Secretary may award grants to eligible institutions to assist the eligible institutions in providing child care services to eligible student parents.</text>
            </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF67336CC22B64C65A13B386753F8CC08"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Amount of grants</header>
<subparagraph id="HB7791BF401004E198A6C9558F933EBFF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Minimum grant amount</header><text>A grant under this section shall be awarded in an amount that is not less than $75,000 per year.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6FBED93434864C468D8B54E72CFF2F33"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Maximum grant amount</header><text>A grant under this section shall be awarded in an amount that is not more than $2,000,000 per year.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H94EFFCDFB9A54BF7BAE9301350D6E9D0" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Ratable increases and decreases</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount specified in subparagraph (A) shall be ratably increased or decreased to the extent that funds available under subsection (i) exceed or are less than (respectively) the amount required to provide the amount specified in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0CBDB1344BE94F52933C2CDF911D4B06"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Duration and payments</header> <subparagraph id="H788606EEA3604D48A9F21AA9EBE310F2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>The Secretary shall award a grant under this section for a period of 5 years.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HECF74BBA68F54EED84F0F24A344BBA52"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Payments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to subparagraphs (C) and (D), the Secretary shall make annual grant payments under this section.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCD7A0D8A803141A39F33C6A7F3CADA95" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Supplemental grants</header><text>The Secretary may consider applications from an eligible institution that receives grant funds under this section for additional funds in any subsequent fiscal year, if such institution demonstrates the need for such additional funds, subject to the maximum grant amount under paragraph (2)(B) and the duration of the original grant under subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H1873FA59A78B4AD9AED98882E907C6BE" commented="no">
                <enum>(D)</enum>
                <header>Continuation awards</header>
 <text>The Secretary shall make continuation awards under this section to an institution of higher education only if the Secretary determines, on the basis of the reports submitted under subsection (g)(1), that the institution is making a good faith effort to ensure that eligible student parents at the institution have access to affordable, quality child care services.</text>
              </subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB973032FA8924A1C834513DEE9C2BB48"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Definition of eligible institution</header><text>In this section, the term <term>eligible institution</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H98FD5F8288F94657BBBAB27FC9E03511"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an institution of higher education, as defined in section 101, with respect to which, the total number of students eligible for a Federal Pell Grant enrolled at the institution of higher education in the most recently completed award year was equal to or greater than 150; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H922C260BEEDB4B7BB6017212693B023F" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a consortium of institutions of higher education described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H296BF089878649A1ABFD3432CF6FA881"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of funds</header> <paragraph id="HDC23E17544044806AEF969FB6A604967"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>In General</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible institution receiving a grant under this section shall use such grant funds to support access to child care services for eligible student parents enrolled at such institution by carrying out 1 or more of the following activities:</text>
              <subparagraph id="HB998624B72044388B952C6DE8ED08FFF">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>Establishing or supporting a campus-based child care program.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H03488AA873604953B325935D36D1ADE3"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Providing subsidized child care using a sliding fee scale.</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="HE8121ABAD6D04150A7BBA6A662343661">
                <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Providing subsidized and accessible before and after school services.</text>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9CA7B489885543A0B95982D2BAD74C62" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Permitted uses</header><text>In addition to the required activities described in paragraph (1), an eligible institution receiving a grant under this section may use such grant funds to carry out 1 or more of the following activities:</text> <subparagraph id="H085393AE4938442CBB80BE499A192BFC" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Providing support services for eligible student parents.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H6C69625F1AC6490DB20D434C48E580CA" commented="no">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Enhancing the quality of the campus-based child care program supported under this section, including to meet at least one of the purposes described in subparagraphs (A) through (C) of subsection (d)(15).</text>
              </subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H808704C0119E414E80FADFBBA1A5FB38"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Prohibitions</header>
<subparagraph id="H7343DA69C1F545D1859C4F7C3A714114"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Use of funds prohibition</header><text>Funds under this section shall not be used for construction, except for renovation or repair to meet applicable State or local health or safety requirements.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC6D3D1581D964B1792CABB3EA17BA5E9" commented="no"> <enum>(B)</enum> <header>Prohibition on additional eligibility requirements</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No eligible institution receiving a grant under this section may require a student parent to meet requirements (such as requirements related to work, academic progress, or enrollment intensity) to be eligible for child care services under this section other than the requirements listed in paragraph (5).</text>
              </subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5AD5A6DBCD8840E1AD18FC7B270A9379" commented="no">
              <enum>(4)</enum>
              <header>Rule of construction</header>
 <text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to prohibit an institution of higher education that receives grant funds under this section from serving the child care needs of the community served by such institution.</text>
            </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H85BD282D31B74EC68B8A3523FDBF9736"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Definition of eligible student parent</header><text>For the purpose of this section, the term <term>eligible student parent</term> means a student who—</text> <subparagraph id="HC5936D05FFF346B1ACA86CB797B1BAE2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is the parent or guardian of 1 or more dependent child;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H3CE4A403A6B34BE9A469DCCC2EFDB7F0"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is enrolled at an eligible institution; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0B94490756AE4D9FBE33140CED199745"><enum>(C)</enum><text>for the award year for which the determination is made—</text>
<clause id="H17621201A87340849ABB9924CEB469FE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is eligible to receive a Federal Pell Grant; or</text></clause> <clause id="H6E65AEE08F054B97A1C8D6F3790A523D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>meets the financial eligibility criteria for receiving a Federal Pell Grant under section 401, but is not eligible for a Federal Pell Grant for such award year because—</text>
<subclause id="H84042EE243ED400D87F57655357849A9"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the student has not completed the Free Application for Federal Student Aid described in section 483;</text></subclause> <subclause id="HB62E3CAE2CAA4A508F581148C9900228"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the student does not meet the eligibility requirements of section 484; or</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H18B9E3EB422C4418ABAC59A99957FF4D"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the student is enrolled in a graduate or first professional course of study.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAAF56DC888514EE3A0AEB097C8DF29AB"> <enum>(6)</enum> <header>Publicity</header> <text>The Secretary shall publicize the availability of grants under this section, in addition to publication in the Federal Register, and shall inform appropriate educational, nonprofit, and child care organizations of such availability.</text>
            </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HEE1FDDB74B7B417799DB3D5091B22AC3"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Special rule</header><text>Any assistance provided to eligible student parents from grants provided under this section shall not be treated as other financial assistance for the purposes of section 471(3).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H8CD8F27D1B1B49069A5E0D7E0217937F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Applications</header><text>An eligible institution desiring a grant under this section shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and accompanied by such information as the Secretary may require. Such application shall—</text>
<paragraph id="H3C9C630650D141719645B649524AD759"><enum>(1)</enum><text>demonstrate that the institution is an eligible institution described in subsection (b)(4);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC754D46900F94175BC077472AEC62B3E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>specify the amount of funds requested;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9B79F3A7F917482ABA087FCCA78A3941">
              <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>demonstrate the need of eligible student parents at the institution for accessible and affordable child care services by including in the application—</text>
              <subparagraph id="H502788CB14B5416BA8235509F8CFCACC">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>information regarding student demographics;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7198E37C0A97499D915423F567379E21"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>an assessment of child care capacity on or near campus;</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="HF9682C9561A8408783BBD787B2064579">
                <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>information regarding the existence of waiting lists for child care services on or near campus;</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H55FDD34151694A62A04A07ACF5DFF486">
                <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>information regarding additional needs created by concentrations of poverty or by geographic isolation; and</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H399A56CBD29441EC97B2981B309CCB09">
                <enum>(E)</enum>
 <text>other relevant data;</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HC3D85502276E4E0BBF7B8E30030BF696"> <enum>(4)</enum> <text>contain a description of the activities to be assisted, including whether the grant funds will support an existing child care program or a new child care program;</text>
            </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H92EB7A177BA94E54A9A15AEC1A8CD5AF">
              <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text>identify the resources, including technical expertise and financial support, the institution will draw upon to support the child care program and the participation of eligible student parents in the program (such as accessing social services funding, using student activity fees to help pay the costs of child care, using resources obtained by meeting the needs of parents who are not eligible student parents, and accessing foundation, corporate, or other institutional support) and demonstrate that the use of the resources will not result in increases in student tuition and fees;</text>
            </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5B15EF3BF83B4ADD935DF73E77A68D24">
              <enum>(6)</enum>
 <text>contain an assurance that the institution will meet the child care needs of eligible student parents through the provision of services, or through a contract for the provision of services;</text>
            </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HBF8261DF0BD7410AB51364BC6C46AC15">
              <enum>(7)</enum>
 <text>describe the extent to which the child care program will coordinate with the institution’s early childhood education curriculum, to the extent the curriculum is available, to meet the needs of the students in the early childhood education program at the institution, and the needs of the parents and children participating in the child care program assisted under this section;</text>
            </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H88B329E68AD049A09280745C0F091310">
              <enum>(8)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of an institution seeking assistance to establish a campus-based child care program—</text>
              <subparagraph id="H8D98BBCB8F084E59BF152281CBEDE8FF">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>provide a timeline, covering the period from receipt of the grant through the provision of the child care services, delineating the specific steps the institution will take to achieve the goal of providing eligible student parents with child care services;</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H07013408CC53406A99F069DF164DC2E0">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>specify any measures the institution will take to assist eligible student parents with child care during the period before the institution provides child care services;</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H4E782F0EA12E4285A56B96ED1A75322E">
                <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>include a plan for identifying resources needed for the child care services, including space in which to provide child care services, and technical assistance if necessary; and</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H088167DA224844BDA414F2FDCD8876AF">
                <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>include plans to assure quality of campus-based child care facilities;</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H2938CF3EB37642FB85C448C4A549646F"> <enum>(9)</enum> <text>in the case of an institution seeking assistance for a campus-based child care program in existence on the date of the application—</text>
              <subparagraph id="H502FC3E5871F45278BB41CC8636CF618">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>provide information regarding the number of eligible student parents served through campus-based child care on such date;</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="HB92640A2E3544E2BA65F6A34417B2E99" commented="no">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>provide information on the age groups of children to be served;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC684493937994CDAA01DE551E6DAEED4"> <enum>(C)</enum> <text>specify any measures the institution will take to assist eligible student parents who are waitlisted for the campus-based child care program;</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H3F96D9DA5B0F42FCA93906FD193A2983">
                <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>provide information regarding the application of subsidies or a sliding fee scale for child care services;</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="HA40C9E5CF73647B18740020FFF8F92DF">
                <enum>(E)</enum>
 <text>specify what staff positions will be supported by funding under this section, and how those staff positions support the purpose under subsection (a);</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H6ECB3971B32246BE9F672A6855C1BC98">
                <enum>(F)</enum>
 <text>provide information on the total number of children served by the campus-based child care program, and number of children of students served; and</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="HB8BD47C889684470920C7E6CC65E37F3">
                <enum>(G)</enum>
 <text>specify if funding will be used to enhance program quality as described in subsection (c)(2)(B);</text>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC8F95FFBC70944488F4FE7D6654C2209">
              <enum>(10)</enum>
 <text>in the case of an institution seeking assistance that will contract for the provision of child care services—</text>
              <subparagraph id="HF575F7B8BFD34452B9FE65CD62BC5489">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>provide information on the age groups of children to be served;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HABB2BE2D8EB647B895D386082760DAE0"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>provide information regarding the application of subsidies or a sliding fee scale for child care services; and</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H1A1082DA2DC54CB8891515AB2C888AD1">
                <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>provide information regarding parameters the institution will use in selecting child care providers in contracting for the provision of services, including—</text>
                <clause id="HADDEA422202C4725928119A9F04D13F9">
                  <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>assessment of program quality; and</text> </clause> <clause id="HDE23EB235952407DA20C9B00730C294E"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>geographic location;</text>
                </clause>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8B6F7B7A7A884581B770219B438B6AD0">
              <enum>(11)</enum>
 <text>contain an assurance that any child care facility assisted under this section will meet the applicable State and local government licensing, certification, approval, or registration requirements;</text>
            </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H190825881D48434E9EE1398161A77101">
              <enum>(12)</enum>
 <text>describe how information regarding the availability of subsidized child care will be provided to students;</text>
            </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9CF6FB4BE814480899E71F9178501FC0">
              <enum>(13)</enum>
 <text>contain an assurance that the institution will assist student parents receiving child care services provided under this section in enrolling in Federal, State, Tribal, or local means-tested benefits programs for which they may be eligible, including—</text>
              <subparagraph id="H92398B68B220432BB8B25FA757D3762F" commented="no">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>the supplemental nutrition assistance program established under the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2011">7 U.S.C. 2011 et seq.</external-xref>), a nutrition assistance program carried out under section 19 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2028">7 U.S.C. 2028</external-xref>), or a nutrition assistance program carried out by the Secretary of Agriculture in the Northern Mariana Islands;</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H896405813A1F425FAEB02775F8F5C1E1" commented="no">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>the supplemental security income program under title XVI of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1381">42 U.S.C. 1381 et seq.</external-xref>);</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H86E9C397562143A3A55FAB453DF94A1F" commented="no">
                <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>the program of block grants to States for temporary assistance for needy families under part A of title IV of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/601">42 U.S.C. 601 et seq.</external-xref>);</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H639914121103480D8231FA89A7440947" commented="no">
                <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>the special supplemental nutrition program for women, infants, and children established by section 17 of the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1786">42 U.S.C. 1786</external-xref>);</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H090EDC8A817D45B1A2D77EF30B160DF4" commented="no">
                <enum>(E)</enum>
 <text>the Medicaid program under title XIX of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396">42 U.S.C. 1396 et seq.</external-xref>);</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H36763C67B6734E3C97D2A9981C0845A5" commented="no">
                <enum>(F)</enum>
 <text>Federal housing assistance programs, including tenant-based assistance under section 8(o) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437f">42 U.S.C. 1437f(o)</external-xref>), and public housing, as defined in section 3(b)(1) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437a">42 U.S.C. 1437a(b)(1)</external-xref>);</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H7942E8AA48D347AA825544F2CDCBCB12" commented="no">
                <enum>(G)</enum>
 <text>Federal child care assistance programs, including assistance under the Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9857">42 U.S.C. 9857 et seq.</external-xref>);</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H59F2853D87CA42F3AB995FD141178320" commented="no">
                <enum>(H)</enum>
 <text>the free and reduced price school lunch program established under the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1751">42 U.S.C. 1751 et seq.</external-xref>);</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H4476876B9FAD40B3AF46F668F9922A45" commented="no">
                <enum>(I)</enum>
 <text>refundable credit for coverage under a qualified health plan under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/36B">section 36B</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986;</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H245EBBF08A0344B182D09FB98D4C0A99" commented="no">
                <enum>(J)</enum>
 <text>the earned income tax credit under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/32">section 32</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986;</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H4E4D967C258C4AE680FA77CA764594D1" commented="no">
                <enum>(K)</enum>
 <text>the child tax credit under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/24">section 24</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986; and</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H2EC9061286CB4600B850E70A8654DF87" commented="no">
                <enum>(L)</enum>
 <text>any other means-tested Federal program determined by the Secretary to be appropriate;</text>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6A7157D0A7A94AFDABF11377EDF5DB1E"><enum>(14)</enum><text>contain an abstract summarizing the contents of such application and how the institution intends to achieve the purpose under subsection (a);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB20C886F8CE14B79A6C6094A21AB99C9" commented="no"> <enum>(15)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">contain a plan for any child care program assisted under this section to, not later than 3 years after the date the institution first receives assistance under this section—</text>
              <subparagraph id="H66837D37247B408C9600D01C544E5711">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">meet the Head Start performance standards described in section 641A(a)(1)(B) of the Head Start Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9836a">42 U.S.C. 9836a(a)(1)(B)</external-xref>) or other equivalent evidence-based standards approved by the Secretary;</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H45F50BABE6A040E08639C3C6C5BE874F">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>be in the top tier of the quality rating improvement system for such facilities used by the State in which the facility is located; or</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="HA12FCB2206EB4BA19165778ECEF637FB">
                <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>be accredited by a national early childhood accrediting body with demonstrated valid and reliable program quality standards; and</text>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H40013D1AACB14B3D9C784609A6C94656" commented="no"><enum>(16)</enum><text>contain an assurance that the institution will comply with the prohibitions described in subsection (c)(3).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H522F2D3D3F74493BA0716AE4F9BD30DC"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text>The Secretary may provide technical assistance—</text>
<paragraph id="H6A50F09C2D994EB0840E815CD06BFAD4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to eligible institutions to help such institutions qualify for, apply for, and maintain a grant under this section; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H88FDB0478521404490CD7FB6B71F667C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to institutions receiving grants under this section to help such institutions meet the reporting requirements described in subsection (g).</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HA8E7319F58B64133B6CF9A90775F1282"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Priority</header>
<paragraph id="H35EB4D3519824EDAA486EC3208FDA75F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall give priority in awarding grants under this section to eligible institutions that submit applications describing programs that—</text> <subparagraph id="HCDAED1370CA2411399B47D4E0AEEA3BD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>leverage local or institutional resources, including in-kind contributions, to support the activities assisted under this section;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HCE284FB08541472C9D71ED262972238D">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>utilize a sliding fee scale for child care services provided under this section in order to support a high number of eligible student parents pursuing postsecondary education at the institution; and</text>
              </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H688D69868FDA4A35A748A7FFE6E11EE9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>provide additional resources or supports to students who are single parents.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD4536854E3AD481089AA7A9EBE88B43C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The Secretary may not establish a priority in awarding grants under this section to eligible institutions that—</text>
<subparagraph id="H48C40C1273EF4ED2A0526C7D632C7F52">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>propose projects solely with off-campus child care providers; or</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2A5C33535A35414599B1BDAE5C147B43"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>that are designed to support 2 or more child care providers.</text>
              </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H9F319D03DE044018A80DF831ED2C06EC"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Reporting requirements; continuing eligibility</header>
<paragraph id="H48640C513F794AF7ADB34A4E0F51B4BB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header><text>Each eligible institution receiving a grant under this section shall report to the Secretary annually information on—</text> <subparagraph id="HA9463D525D954F8F8B390DCF0AB138AA"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>the population of eligible student parents who received child care services under this section, including—</text>
                <clause id="H0AF9BFCE1FC54FB0A4D0646D9FD537E5">
                  <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>the number of such eligible student parents, disaggregated by full- and part-time status;</text>
                </clause>
                <clause id="H07B2B567D5DC46D2820C090DE8B4098E">
                  <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>information on such eligible student parents, including demographic information disaggregated by—</text>
                  <subclause id="HBBAC8797AB554B16AD85715549B0F4A8">
                    <enum>(I)</enum>
 <text>sex;</text> </subclause> <subclause id="H9417BAAA47AB4C1D80DDB1271652E113"> <enum>(II)</enum> <text>status as a single parent;</text>
                  </subclause>
                  <subclause id="H8B08809C10E54B538EF6420D0D82E2C2">
                    <enum>(III)</enum>
 <text>race and ethnicity;</text> </subclause> <subclause id="H85316F5616344867A2B1F1AFA13B2EFA"> <enum>(IV)</enum> <text>age groups of the dependents of such student parents;</text>
                  </subclause>
                  <subclause id="H3C6195EC89D142FB8872A57DFEABEF26">
                    <enum>(V)</enum>
 <text>classification as a student with a disability;</text> </subclause> <subclause id="HEF2DE6412D3E463790C4F0E4C8458F5D"> <enum>(VI)</enum> <text>recipients of educational assistance under laws administered by the Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of Veterans Affairs;</text>
                  </subclause>
                  <subclause id="H706B807B93BF40F599E0C176B2E46F9C">
                    <enum>(VII)</enum>
 <text>status as a first-generation college student; and</text> </subclause> <subclause id="HF179C8A49AE74BD5B022C4FC3C84621E"> <enum>(VIII)</enum> <text>levels of degree or credential pursued by such eligible student parents; and</text>
                  </subclause>
                </clause>
                <clause id="HB3549D8C56384931AF5E872D34CE655D">
                  <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>the number of such eligible student parents who—</text> <subclause id="HAB440ADF821D4D87BD257EEAC57FF14C"> <enum>(I)</enum> <text>remain enrolled at the institution during the academic year for which they received such services;</text>
                  </subclause>
                  <subclause id="H2C694AE407C042FF9697CF5C4B2B7F10">
                    <enum>(II)</enum>
 <text>remain enrolled at the institution during the subsequent academic year after which they first received such services;</text>
                  </subclause>
                  <subclause id="H57C46B5BB845484D97D711E440E8D1B6">
                    <enum>(III)</enum>
 <text>graduate from the institution during the academic year for which they received such services;</text>
                  </subclause>
                  <subclause id="H265E53979F5E40F89CDB18B6A8B8B278">
                    <enum>(IV)</enum>
 <text>transfer to a different institution during the academic year for which they received such services; or</text>
                  </subclause>
                  <subclause id="HABB7F9FFA9654DA4AAB9DD15F85AFCC8">
                    <enum>(V)</enum>
 <text>withdrew from the institution during the academic year for which they received such services;</text>
                  </subclause>
                </clause>
              </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H7A8C73251D81453483BA29DD2D0854DF">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>the fee structure for eligible student parents to receive child care services under this section, including any sliding scale;</text>
              </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H53BE4CB65B864006BB23541BF6C36C3D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the percentage of the institution’s grant that was used directly to subsidize any fees charged for—</text> <clause id="H3FC4B97581F049F0AD85824055908BDF"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>campus-based child care services for eligible student parents; and</text>
                </clause>
<clause id="HC275CCB8CDE741AFB0DEE76963624E0A">
                  <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>off-campus child care services for eligible student parents;</text> </clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCC8EAA4E515E47519546E30DDACA39F0"> <enum>(D)</enum> <text>information on institutional or local resources, including in-kind contributions, leveraged to help eligible student parents access child care services; and</text>
              </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H125EB81145E54BBD8D87564FDEE8D5DB">
                <enum>(E)</enum>
 <text>the relevant quality information of the child care services supported by a grant under this section, including—</text>
                <clause id="HEE220BD9C08641C8A05EEE5A2E244277">
                  <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>the name of the accrediting agency or association that is providing accreditation to such child care services, if applicable; and</text>
                </clause>
                <clause id="H57638CA80FC8433B918F2488142265E7">
                  <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>the tier or level of the State tiered and transparent system for measuring the quality of child care providers that is associated with such child care services, if applicable.</text>
                </clause>
              </subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC9F1680B51304B0D9DD59FA704802AC2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header>
<subparagraph id="H581B61CEB35946E681D7A1C69C10046A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Report required</header><text>On an annual basis, the Secretary shall make publicly available a report that includes a summary of the information described in paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE61BFB3BF30348509AB84517B171EAB1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Stakeholder consultation</header><text>The Secretary shall work with relevant stakeholders to determine the manner in which the data described under paragraph (1) and summarized under subparagraph (A) is collected.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H999E383E139545A4A66E34417EBE7C53" commented="no"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Nondiscrimination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No person in the United States shall, on the basis of actual or perceived race, color, religion, national origin, sex (including sexual orientation, gender identity, pregnancy, childbirth, a medical condition related to pregnancy or childbirth, or sex stereotype), or disability, be excluded from participation in, be denied the benefits of, or be subjected to discrimination by any program funded, in whole or in part, with funds made available under this section or with amounts appropriated for grants, contracts, or certificates administered with such funds.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HDD9A604D7F5A49E5960510C176CE417A"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $500,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2031.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

