<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9849B5BADAB447A19848CCAD2CA7404D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5635 IH: Veterans Healthcare Equality Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5635</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250930">September 30, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000402">Mr. Kennedy of New York</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001318">Ms. Balint</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000617">Mrs. Ramirez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000788">Ms. Williams of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000831">Mr. Walkinshaw</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000172">Ms. Ocasio-Cortez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001119">Ms. Craig</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to prohibit discrimination on the basis of gender identity in connection with the furnishing of health care under laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD1E04909E56B401D83A2702853919A4E" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H470BC70660C14CDEB0A1993AB1D9B769" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Veterans Healthcare Equality Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HF56BD5F7C47F467CB277E0B704AC92F4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> <paragraph id="HFE75EEBCA06A4FCFB0BA3DF3433E07B9"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Transgender veterans have served our country with honor and deserve to receive the health benefits such veterans are entitled to free from discrimination, including free from intentional and repeated misgendering.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0F6FC80618294AF3BFF1B987F97FA8E4"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Treatments for gender dysphoria are medically necessary and supported by every major U.S. medical association.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H018F8F2F79FC49308C9D0532C75EA9B9"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Prohibitions on sex discrimination, including in Section 1557 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/10822">42 U.S.C. 10822(b)</external-xref>), prohibit discrimination on the basis of gender identity.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3E288BA245BA4528B66E6AEC38EDDDF8"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Despite these protections, the Department of Veterans Affairs has taken steps to discriminate against transgender veterans in the provision of health care, including by the rescission of the transmittal sheet of the Veterans Health Administration published on May 23, 2018, titled <quote>Providing Health Care for Transgender and Intersex Veterans</quote> (VHA Directive 1341(4)) and phasing out treatments for gender dysphoria.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H95CA57D668B74D3F923A86904CDE9DC2"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Explicit nondiscrimination protections for transgender veterans in healthcare services will ensure the Department fulfills its legal obligation to provide health care services, including treatments for gender dysphoria, free from discrimination.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HDFDDA4BAFF6244A5A6BAF0C68F606AFB"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibition against discrimination on the basis of gender identity in connection with furnishing of health care under laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs</header> 
<subsection id="H99B5E36A2FAA4808A3F0B8DA3C9AD2C6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/17">chapter 17</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code is amended by adding at the end the following new section (and conforming the table of contents at the beginning of such chapter accordingly):</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="H18D5C07AD9C340808C4B7C9D64912EC2" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <section id="H196F2AB9A77D41289B73FB962BD0CDC1"><enum>1709D.</enum><header>Prohibition against discrimination on the basis of gender identity</header> <subsection id="HCEA395D0DDFD4723AA617296903FFA24" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In carrying out this chapter, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs—</text> 
<paragraph id="H364F65F7705548908029281A1AC0585E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>may not—</text> <subparagraph id="HCA76550643BB44099FE9D1C43600A0B2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>discriminate on the basis of gender identity; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H815CBA4EE2994401BB27606F5F833706">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>deny a person a medically-necessary treatment for gender dysphoria prescribed to the individual by a health care provider; and</text>
                </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H93EDAC934DD94A78B07720787E250960"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall ensure that no person is discriminated against on such basis in connection with the furnishing of hospital care, medical services, or extended care services under this chapter.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC92FF1A95023464D877A0C39EC6FB59F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Quarterly briefings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of the Veterans Healthcare Equality Act of 2025, and not less frequently than on a quarterly basis thereafter, the Secretary shall provide to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Senate a briefing with respect to the furnishing of hospital care, medical services, and extended care services under this chapter to transgender veterans during the period covered by the briefing.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8632C761476B4191A5AE8C5B3ED21570"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Briefing required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall provide to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Senate a briefing with respect to the implementation by the Secretary of the amendment made by subsection (a).</text></subsection> </section> </legis-body></bill>

