<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE30F7CDFC3D4413A91292F8ABE9BC49F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3806 IH: New World Screwworm Preparedness Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3806</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action display="yes"> 
<action-date date="20250606">June 6, 2025</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000594">Ms. De La Cruz</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="B001291">Mr. Babin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000614">Mr. Roy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000048">Mr. Pfluger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000594">Mr. Tony Gonzales of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000589">Mr. Gooden</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001120">Mr. Crenshaw</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001157">Mr. McCaul</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000816">Mr. Williams of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000026">Mr. Nehls</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000375">Mr. Arrington</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000603">Mr. Gill of Texas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name></action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Agriculture to study and report on strategies to combat the New World screwworm and enhance the United States' preparedness and response capabilities against potential outbreaks.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H8FAF0B3814EB4F0EA9710EDF0A47787C" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H56C86E24A2644D52A1B6DFB39E803B50" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>New World Screwworm Preparedness Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H9F70A010FB4C42F2A2510C04A466D83F" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HBEF32BF573044E5398B0781CE50DA29F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The New World screwworm (Cochliomyia hominivorax) (in this section referred to as <quote>NWS</quote>) is a parasitic fly whose larvae infest and feed on the living tissue of warm-blooded animals, including livestock, wildlife, and, in rare cases, humans.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H06A7A832D32F4F8C83B6F4CEB7884A12"><enum>(2)</enum><text>NWS infestations can lead to severe damage, secondary infections, and often death in affected animals, posing a significant threat to agricultural economies, wildlife populations, and public health.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H31B8126CC8AD416690D058645C04010C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The United States successfully eradicated NWS in the 1960s through significant efforts, primarily utilizing the sterile insect technique, which involves releasing sterile male flies to disrupt reproduction in wild populations.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H04FDB75C6C484528978275A8E525F058"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Recent outbreaks and confirmed detections of NWS in neighboring countries, particularly Mexico, indicate an increasing risk of reintroduction and establishment of NWS within the United States.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2B9A2D981AE8470FAD61F85EB6596F30"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Proactive measures, including enhanced surveillance, rapid response capabilities, and continued research into innovative control methods, are critical to preventing a widespread NWS outbreak and mitigating its potential economic and ecological impact.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HE23C9E652EA4454383A52EE37264ACDD"><enum>3.</enum><header>Study and report on New World screwworm preparedness</header> <subsection id="HD6F67D109E4842DEBD6F9F2F649A1DA0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Administrator of the Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service (in this section referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall conduct a comprehensive study on the current State of United States preparedness and response capabilities to combat the New World screwworm (in this section referred to as <quote>NWS</quote>).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF37815F96DE54AE18AF3BC07D399EF17"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Components of the study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The study under this section shall include the following:</text> <paragraph id="HCFB41CBD2725460580F1D8C71DAB131F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Current threat assessment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An analysis of the current threat posed by NWS to the United States, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HDD7D1ABA6E6E4BEE98172CD91D922D66"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the migratory patterns and confirmed detections of NWS in countries bordering the United States;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H13035F574C5E4C69AEDAFB4A0CAAF93A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the potential pathways for NWS introduction into the United States;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H670E903699A349C29660164D11997CC9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the economic impact of a potential NWS outbreak on the United States livestock industry, including cattle, swine, and other susceptible animals; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H16F18C571F0F4D1A8E03A6D3B33023A9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the ecological impact of a potential NWS outbreak on domestic wildlife populations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7CCFAE1E51B14CC6A2C1F450ADF33C64"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sterile insect technique capabilities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A review of the United States capacity to produce and deploy sterile NWS flies, including—</text> <subparagraph id="HDB01059A9A184A67B1AE7CC10AECB17B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the current status and capacity of existing NWS sterile fly production facilities;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H363B4A146B8A418885F557C615D04A09"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the feasibility and cost-effectiveness of establishing new or expanding existing modular NWS sterile fly rearing facilities within the United States, including potential locations based on risk assessment; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H13F91ADF3A7C478AB053F195C88C251A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the logistical requirements for effective dispersal of sterile flies in areas at risk of infestation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H655299019DA849868EC39AEF34157D7D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Surveillance and detection systems</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An evaluation of current NWS surveillance and detection systems, including—</text> <subparagraph id="HCC8BE03A20A145898AD446BD2CE8D433"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the effectiveness of border inspection protocols for live animals;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFDFFEA6F7F94435AAAD13FD3963BF7EB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the adequacy of diagnostic capabilities and laboratory infrastructure; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDAA92673DDBB4F8887870058984C3AB8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the integration of public and private sector reporting mechanisms for suspected NWS cases.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF566F7017EAE42AC98346B98E35B5130"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Emergency response plans</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An examination of existing emergency response plans for NWS outbreaks, including—</text> <subparagraph id="H32FF47A85CA8433882FA354E044AC8F5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the coordination mechanisms between Federal, State, and local agencies;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H246640CCA396426AA11EDC68850551F5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the availability of resources for rapid containment and eradication efforts; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2F58ED6C64184B369CEA950A5B19D644"><enum>(C)</enum><text>protocols for animal movement restrictions and public outreach during an outbreak.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5EF7D52226A44CDC8C8B41EEA3663950"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Research and development needs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Identification of critical research and development needs to enhance NWS prevention, control, and eradication, including—</text> <subparagraph id="H797DBE598CBB4866863757D10D501CBF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>new diagnostic tools;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H46502E4809C641F6842B65808D4E0098"><enum>(B)</enum><text>improved sterile insect techniques;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC4F9D6A761A84E46AB246508AA67D1F1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>alternative control methods; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H402AB5032C7B4C76BB94DE8640ABF57F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>genetic research into NWS vulnerabilities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB71227BE3E4E4AEEB6B1B9C9618217B2"><enum>(6)</enum><header>International cooperation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of the effectiveness of current international co-operation efforts with affected countries and recommendations for strengthening such partnerships to establish and maintain biological barriers.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H61D919DE729B4F4B9458E121C79DB453"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Stakeholder consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In conducting the study under this section, the Secretary shall consult with relevant stakeholders, including—</text> <paragraph id="H9CDA3C8830C44F8792629E3119A7C072"><enum>(1)</enum><text>livestock producers and industry associations;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H209B81FCB43A49A1B5C44ABEC8A706F8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>wildlife management agencies;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H02DFD4A0B1594D0F9C4062883A1F2C2D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>veterinary professionals;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE7C0F23E7BCD43C8AC76B1BD74467B50"><enum>(4)</enum><text>scientific experts in entomology, epidemiology, and animal health; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3C711FA162FF4E979B224A5649A3B450"><enum>(5)</enum><text>State and local agricultural and public health officials.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8EA30DB1E8EC47E8BAD35B96490564BE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate, and make publicly available, a report—</text> <paragraph id="HB799D718FAF94D4FA53EA8545352558A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>detailing the findings of the study under this section; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5AECB2376AF14CD18C8AA3D16FED7FFA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>providing recommendations for legislative and administrative actions to improve the United States' ability to combat NWS.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

