<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" dms-id="HF0DE5D3283DF4C36B86A5E7CF6CD84C2" public-private="public" key="G" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3937 : Wabeno Economic Development Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3937</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250723">July 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for the conveyance of certain Federal land in Chequamegon-Nicolet National Forest, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" style="OLC" id="H707F6AB5A5774E91A3FBC250C8D0189B"><pagebreak></pagebreak><section id="HEE11DC806A934332B27C6914EBBE806C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Wabeno Economic Development Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HA3931E6341E84A269F1AAD0FE74A1213"><enum>2.</enum><header>Conveyance of certain National Forest System land in the Chequamegon-Nicolet National Forest to Tony’s Wabeno Redi-Mix, LLC</header><subsection id="H6254AABC2160464C9C67809314128653" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Conveyance required</header><text>If, during the 180-day period beginning on the date of Federal approval of the appraisal under subsection (d), Tony’s Wabeno Redi-Mix, LLC submits to the Secretary an offer to acquire the property described in subsection (b) for market value, as determined by such appraisal, the Secretary shall, not later than 180 days after receiving such offer, convey to Tony’s Wabeno Redi-Mix, LLC all right, title, and interest of the United States, including mineral rights, in and to the property described in subsection (b).</text></subsection><subsection id="H633BA6D19E6548C9BDD70CC5897BF070"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Description of property</header><paragraph id="HDD12998BE58447809D71176885C9C289"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The property referred to in subsection (a) is the parcel of real property, including all land and improvements, generally depicted as <quote>Federal Parcel to be Conveyed</quote> on the Map, consisting of approximately 14 acres of National Forest System land located in the Chequamegon-Nicolet National Forest in Wisconsin.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H61D1EE7423A041B2ACFBF11F77BED642"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Map</header><subparagraph id="H1CCA6E0EF40142B8BAF8FA1A724AE17F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Minor errors</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may correct minor errors in the Map.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H129E3498AC6A44AEB270465BD876BF27"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>A copy of the Map shall be on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate office of the Forest Service.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8317C95248E146D992EB81098BCBF546"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Survey</header><text>The exact acreage and legal description of the National Forest System land to be conveyed under subsection (a) shall be determined by a survey satisfactory to the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H32AFD476BE2A43EBA862DFEDEF36C4AC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Terms and conditions of the conveyance</header><paragraph id="H54591CFF646B42999B94B0044CB883E8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The conveyance under subsection (a) shall be—</text><subparagraph id="H164623DB0EFA4D0380F07A08EE048B62"><enum>(A)</enum><text>subject to valid existing rights;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H66582C36B47846CB97AE4E5805684DB0" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>made by quitclaim deed; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7B899BC20E25473DB0E0EC8043CF3D4B" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>subject to such other terms and conditions as the Secretary considers to be appropriate to protect the interests of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDCD182876924485486355C7A87597424"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Costs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As a condition of the conveyance under subsection (a), Tony’s Wabeno Redi-Mix, LLC shall pay to the Secretary—</text><subparagraph id="H84E89C1AB1334F4DBDD573F5F6D86817"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an amount equal to the market value of the land to be conveyed under subsection (a), as determined by the appraisal under subsection (d); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2645D0326A1C4C14AA4F3997232AE2F0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>all costs associated with the conveyance, including the cost of—</text><clause id="H53004A67FCFE4B2297D0F8E145E10B2A" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a survey, if necessary, under subsection (b)(3);</text></clause><clause id="HD2BCBAB9A8B044AA8F88F592A2F9BC69"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>conducting the appraisal under subsection (d); and</text></clause><clause id="HC56D25B7AAB34B87A995250A5585FFB8" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any environmental analysis or resource survey required under Federal law.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H87B916BE527943628E4E52EF2B2996ED"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Appraisal</header><paragraph id="H96D93D1F1EFA48F39E0FDEBEFCE62860" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 300 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall complete an appraisal to determine the market value of the land to be conveyed under subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEA5E87836BA84FC282A3DFD41B1C0638"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Standards</header><text>The appraisal under paragraph (1) shall be conducted in accordance with—</text><subparagraph id="H7A26BFA1029D48038C5EF60551815733"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Uniform Appraisal Standards for Federal Land Acquisitions; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA5846C88E86A4130932F605FA7D9F9A8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Uniform Standards of Professional Appraisal Practice.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0E3EFA6BA74F49D983C1F74C82661939"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph id="H919797958E4E4211A845BE06F112A810"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Map</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Map</term> means the map entitled <quote>Conveyance of Federal Parcel Chequamegon-Nicolet National Forest</quote> and dated September 27, 2023.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9A718B5F9D344D4595BF9239D1628B31"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Chief of the Forest Service.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H59ED8E9A2BAE4F93A533B13B86BED9D1"><enum>3.</enum><header>Comprehensive review of Federal permitting processes for stone, sand, and gravel development on Federal lands</header><subsection id="HF0204F07251847A3A5921317A16C05D1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Interior, in consultation with the heads of other relevant Federal agencies, industry stakeholders, and State permitting authorities, shall conduct a comprehensive review of the Federal permitting processes for the development of stone, sand, and gravel on Federal lands.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE8F66C87841444669758587F19CC6D9C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Interior, in consultation with the entities referred to in subsection (a), shall submit to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate, and make publicly available on the website of the Department of the Interior a report that includes—</text><paragraph id="H4E8070794C644207B1D1D3372459DF1C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a detailed description of the current Federal permitting process for stone, sand, and gravel development, including average timelines from initial application to final approval;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H603ACFDE60CD468896F404368A851FE3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an analysis identifying potential inefficiencies and duplicative steps in such permitting process and the impact of such inefficiencies and duplicative steps on project timelines;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H952F9FFBC95F4157A347B7CE5A1126E1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Secretary’s recommendations for legislative or administrative actions to streamline such permitting process; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC1981A0EA5DC4C38AD2F24BB61C3E659"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a summary of the economic impacts associated with current permitting timelines under such permitting process, specifically focusing on the stone, sand, and gravel sectors.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20250722" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives July 22, 2025.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Kevin F. McCumber,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation></bill> 

