<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC8C3E685ED494503A1119A4571DFC8A3" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 627 IH: Celebrating the 100th anniversary of Pratt &amp; Whitney.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 627</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250801">August 1, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000557">Mr. Larson of Connecticut</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="D000216">Ms. DeLauro</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001069">Mr. Courtney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001047">Mr. Himes</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001081">Mrs. Hayes</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Celebrating the 100th anniversary of Pratt &amp; Whitney.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas 2025 marks the 100th anniversary of the founding in 1925 of Pratt &amp; Whitney by Frederick Rentschler, whose vision revolutionized aviation with the creation of the dependable air-cooled Wasp engine; </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Pratt &amp; Whitney, headquartered in East Hartford, Connecticut, has since become a global leader in the design, manufacture, and service of aircraft engines and auxiliary power units for commercial, military, and business aircraft, and helicopters; </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Pratt &amp; Whitney has contributed to every major advancement in powered flight over the past century, helping to drive innovation, support national defense, and enable safe, efficient air travel around the world; </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, for the 100 years since 1925, the people of Connecticut have been at the heart of the success of Pratt &amp; Whitney, including machinists, engineers, technicians, veterans, and countless other skilled employees whose dedication and ingenuity continue to power the future of aviation; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the continued investment of Pratt &amp; Whitney in workforce development, manufacturing, sustainability, and community partnership has strengthened the economy and aerospace leadership of Connecticut: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HAA964AF96F484B518B08126245794DC7"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H381901E60CF141C9A7B7EB1E1C56B3EA"><enum/><text>That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="H04C64561C4784B14B9F5CCF5DBCB733E" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>proudly celebrates the achievements and legacy of Pratt &amp; Whitney, recognizing a century of excellence in engineering, innovation, and public service;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFBC5E4278FCB4154B99D83C4383DC716"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">commends and thanks the countless skilled employees, past and present, who have been the bedrock of Pratt &amp; Whitney’s success, including machinists, engineers, technicians, and veterans; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB36B914DDFFF4E148E4367A7AFC571FF" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><text>encourages all citizens to join in honoring the extraordinary contributions of this iconic company to the State of Connecticut, the United States, and the world.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

