<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-BUR25764-268-24-H6L">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2424 IS: Tracking Hostile Industry Networks and Kit while Thwarting Weapons Imports from Chinese Entities Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>II</distribution-code>
        <congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session>1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. 2424</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action>
            <action-date date="20250723">July 23, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S423">Mr. Ricketts</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S330">Mr. Bennet</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was
                read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on
                    Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title>To require a report of, and a strategy to combat, arms sales of the
            Government of the People’s Republic of China, and for other purposes.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body>
        <section id="S1" section-type="section-one">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Tracking Hostile Industry Networks and Kit while Thwarting Weapons Imports from Chinese Entities Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>THINK TWICE Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9956d499072e48919d2eb4fd0b9c3016">
            <enum>2.</enum>
            <header>Findings</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc8513a3691b248bfa2f87185bdb89ced"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The People's Republic of China is the fourth largest arms exporter behind the United States, the Russian Federation, and France.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9e47d4d39fde4be185396cb9acef2e26">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Arms sales by entities in the People's Republic of China are an important element of the country's growing military power and geopolitical influence.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6ab3cf781e2b40f8a62a3c7e616d4b10">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The People's Republic of China uses arms sales to promote strategic interests, including—</text>
                <subparagraph id="id14a1da421f9f4452a64047cdc222c095">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>improving the image and reputation of the People’s Liberation Army;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id569a5dc4ebc048a4bcfab9d5b3d8d7bb"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>acquiring performance data of Chinese-made weapons in contested environments, which can be utilized by the People's Liberation Army;</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="idaf71c6dce04546899e363dd2d93ffa07">
                    <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>exacerbating tensions between the United States and traditional security partners;</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="ide5feaaf693924cb49d01359a79eba51d">
                    <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>gaining a foothold for further defense and security cooperation with certain countries;</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="id5970deab914b4744a484451111c0d3de">
                    <enum>(E)</enum>
 <text>building relationships with senior political and military leaders in other countries, further expanding the diplomatic and strategic influence of the People’s Republic of China;</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="id62a545dd42974495b70d7a558ca7e374">
                    <enum>(F)</enum>
 <text>protecting economic interests of the People's Republic of China by ensuring the security of foreign partner governments to safeguard Chinese investments and Chinese workers;</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="iddf90824d3bf54b1e81f48d2c6a9c9449">
                    <enum>(G)</enum>
 <text>exerting influence over the progression of conflicts to serve the broader geostrategic aims of the People's Republic of China;</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="id7721feb8857b43a5b4ff1d0bb249fa14">
                    <enum>(H)</enum>
 <text>improving military operations and capabilities of partner states, thereby stabilizing regions of interest by addressing local issues, such as disturbances near the border of the People's Republic of China; and</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="idddb0456eaa71450dab7338a6156a80ba">
                    <enum>(I)</enum>
 <text>subsidizing the research and development and production costs of weapons systems of the People's Republic of China.</text>
                </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
        </section>
        <section id="idcf6d9dc5db39499db030a5ec551156b2">
            <enum>3.</enum>
            <header>Report on arms sales of the People's Republic of China</header>
            <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8b086cefc19543f4982bec453177a520">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header>
 <text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Secretary of Defense, in coordination with the Secretary of State, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on arms sales facilitated by entities in the People’s Republic of China.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7bff265268f64c5ab55e93f8cbda1f30">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Contents</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report required by subsection (a) shall include an analysis of—</text>
                <paragraph id="idba26b45672b54c2f972f6926188f03fe">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>the weapons systems and defense equipment originating from the People's Republic of China available for purchase;</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id8f3399baa22441a298ee56b88a12c6ee">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>the technical aspects and capabilities of such weapons systems and defense equipment;</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="idcfda70ec82d445618d0c58d99652860a">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>how such weapons systems and defense equipment may impact the balance of power in the area of responsibility of each United States Combatant Command, when applicable;</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id68b4e3b7c7214445965fa2172cf90197">
                    <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>the weapons systems and defense equipment originating from the People's Republic of China that are considered direct alternatives to weapons systems and defense equipment originating from the United States;</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="idee53ee8c02bc42309efd0ff4ae4438e1">
                    <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text>the weapons systems and defense equipment originating from the People’s Republic of China that present the greatest security risks regarding the potential to collect intelligence on or compromise assets, weapons, or platforms of the United States;</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="ida207a00525e64cccbd83d6d102691233">
                    <enum>(6)</enum>
 <text>the countries mostly likely to procure weapons systems and defense equipment originating from the People's Republic of China, including the specific type, quantity, and estimated value in United States dollars of weapons, during the 1-year period following the date of the submission of the report;</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id66f52cfb025c47e7a6507090e8f9a432" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline">
                    <enum>(7)</enum>
 <text>the weapons systems and defense equipment in development as of the date of the submission of the report by entities in the People's Republic of China that could be available on the global market not later than 5 years after such date;</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id01c7e7fa993349238bf33452bd9e6252">
                    <enum>(8)</enum>
 <text>the factors that incentivize countries to procure such weapons systems and defense equipment, including costs, flexible payment conditions and financing, a lack of end-user agreements, and speed of sale and delivery; and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id820fbf1dcdbf4928912950b7adcaf14f">
                    <enum>(9)</enum>
 <text>the strategy of the People's Republic of China regarding arms sales and variables that could influence such strategy.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ideb5d2e3a47cf45e38d1b609705f1082f">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Form</header>
                <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf8d5be75bd3a4807b846de54c79cbae1">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                    <header>In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report required by subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but shall include a classified annex.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id9d9992b58bf041eb8648510bffcb2e7e">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Classified annex</header>
 <text>The classified annex required by paragraph (1) shall contain—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide06952d04bd9409faf99c5925931c2af"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an assessment by the National Intelligence Council of the contents required by subsection (b); and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idebaa28470ab746f98dd604d44ebaf074">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>an assessment by the Director of National Intelligence of the counterintelligence risks and risks of onward proliferation of technology and defense systems originating in the United States and created through the purchase, deployment, and use of weapons systems and defense equipment originating from the People’s Republic of China by United States allies and partners.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id2f635138d8da42d895d30f033c6244da">
                <enum>(d)</enum>
                <header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header>
 <text>In this section, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text>
                <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id10835f384ccd4505949f6c04555b77df">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Foreign Relations, and the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate; and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="idafab00eb3bf2456ab86a44c041cb519e" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
        </section>
        <section id="id1c60cbea6cca4e2497f50d3c985d8e27">
            <enum>4.</enum>
            <header>Strategy to combat arms sales of the People's Republic of China</header>
            <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaaabc9937d3a4cebb77e023b3ee5dc7d">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State, in coordination with the Secretary of Defense, shall develop a strategy to dissuade purchases of new weapons systems and defense equipment, excluding spare parts or parts for maintenance of previously procured weapons, originating from the People's Republic of China.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0cab546310264eb0b5a19419e2728f1c">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Elements</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The strategy shall include the following elements:</text>
                <paragraph id="id13315a464e384aa28ce8cd3f97c28191">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>An information campaign targeting countries interested in procuring weapons systems and defense equipment originating from the People's Republic of China to warn such countries about—</text>
                    <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb441f822944e4c7387f63b36dd9aa2d1">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">potential risks, including the lack of a proven track record in combat, insufficient training on the operation of the weapon or weapons system, reliability issues, and the lack of maintenance and spare parts available;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id4cf1f6cbd51b4f5b82806b528569dee3">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>the inability to integrate such weapons systems and defense equipment with weapons systems and defense equipment from the United States; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id93f342d8059848099c03088720388ad2">
                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>the potential limitation of future security cooperation with the United States that could arise if such weapons are acquired.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="idbe1b733f04ae4834b22e73f337156204">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>A description of actions the United States can take, including reforms to the foreign military sales, direct commercial sales, and foreign military financing processes, to make weapons systems and defense equipment from the United States more attractive to prospective buyers of weapons systems or defense equipment originating from the People's Republic of China.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id44414be18d354dafb66b8d727fefd47a">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>A description of actions defense firms of the United States can take to provide competitive alternatives to prospective buyers of weapons systems and defense equipment originating from the People's Republic of China.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="idfd9423fcea3747efb942c38a2d73931a">
                    <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>An analysis of whether the use of sanctions, export controls, or other economic restrictions targeting buyers of new weapons systems or defense equipment originating from the People’s Republic of China could serve as an effective deterrent.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id885ef18b741c4e7bb854dee7181497c0">
                    <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text>A plan to ensure sufficient representation of defense firms of the United States, or trusted allies, at defense expositions where defense firms of the People’s Republic of China are also attending.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id4f243f4cb28943ae9309d165deb60b68">
                    <enum>(6)</enum>
 <text>A plan to combat Chinese disinformation campaigns targeting the performance of weapons or platforms produced by the United States or trusted allies.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id0b8816329f2e4e868b1e4a120d6038aa">
                    <enum>(7)</enum>
 <text>A plan to ensure close coordination with Congress to prevent disjointed engagement with countries.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb663a79a62764ecb8a316e14711cd6ba">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Report and implementation plan</header>
 <text>Not later than the date on which the strategy required by subsection (a) is completed, the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report detailing the strategy and a plan for implementation.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2c884218fba54234b88df8a1e5073c9e">
                <enum>(d)</enum>
                <header>Form</header>
 <text>The report required by subsection (c) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="idd80c1e2eb4504d49a97ef2681be2587d">
                <enum>(e)</enum>
                <header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header>
 <text>In this section, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text>
                <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8d4bb06c463f468cb458363de02f305f">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate; and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id73c558036c6f4c65b3593d3cda2a7015" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
        </section>
    </legis-body>
</bill>

