<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" dms-id="HE3A2F96EB1F94127AEB88B6E124B1684" public-private="public" key="G" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3494 : VA Hospital Inventory Management System Authorization Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>H. R. 3494</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250916">September 16, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSVA00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to carry out an information technology system and prioritize certain requirements to manage supply chains for medical facilities of the Department of Veterans Affairs.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H29BA375E746F4015B1F92DCA94A3F68F" style="OLC"><pagebreak></pagebreak><section id="H846A5204AE1E49FBBF127F183725C5EB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>VA Hospital Inventory Management System Authorization Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H1B8320C896F84879AEA31EB23E409856"><enum>2.</enum><header>Management of supply chains for medical facilities of Department of Veterans Affairs</header><subsection id="H9B2D08B78EB9426C9C096D346BDE9284"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs is authorized to—</text><paragraph id="H5BF3D7151BD94AFCA58980BBC4E92BE2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>purchase or develop for the Veterans Health Administration a cloud-based information technology system for the management of inventory, including expendable and nonexpendable items; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H43506C63E17A4E4A8C63FE528683900C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>implement such system.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8089C25F8F274B1894B3EC09B2B6A897"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Pilot</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary purchases or develops a system under subsection (a), the Secretary shall carry out a pilot program at one Veterans Health Administration facility before implementing the system throughout the Veterans Health Administration. The pilot program shall be designed to determine whether the functions of the system are satisfactory.</text></subsection><subsection id="H12815C91B80947DB91BF61665FA0185D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Deadline</header><text>If the Secretary purchases or develops a system under subsection (a), the Secretary shall complete the implementation of the system by not later than three years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1DD50FAC6CEF4EF8983C617939011205"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may not exercise the authority under subsection (a) or subsection (b) until the date on which the Secretary submits to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Senate a report that includes—</text><paragraph id="H61B8E023A09D485B908E691DECFF2779"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a comprehensive supply chain strategy to guide enterprise-wide implementation, as recommended in the report of the Comptroller General of the United States titled <quote>VA Acquisition Management: Comprehensive Supply Chain Management Strategy Key to Address Existing Challenges</quote> (GAO–21–445T; published March 24, 2021), which includes success metrics, a plan for data standardization, and staffing models;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6137CE9A2ED148DCB5058C1B51B08E5B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a cost estimate and implementation schedule for the supply chain modernization program of the Department;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H95C67F3BC20141198C3D8DAF308037CF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a comprehensive staffing assessment of the supply chain and information technology modernization workforces of the Department that includes—</text><subparagraph id="H65FF0AD5E9B040D183A05BA8E643DDC1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>monthly staffing gains and losses since October 1, 2022;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF96E4BBBFD0543AE92EDCE7D3856A87C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the current staffing level of each such workforce as of the date of the enactment of this Act; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9AAD9F7183CD4A4A8593A206F833101F"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an estimate of future staffing requirements for the implementation of the supply chain modernization program, disaggregated by each such workforce; and </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCAC14B48962F4083AE640534F38BA4A7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>an independent assessment of the review carried out by the Secretary with respect to failures of the supply chain modernization program of the Department. </text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H214E117002DB43378B94A96BE9363E20"><enum>3.</enum><header>Extension of certain limits on payments of pension</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 5503(d)(7) of title 38, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>November 30, 2031</quote> and inserting <quote>December 31, 2032</quote>.</text></section></legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20250915" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives September 15, 2025.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Kevin F. McCumber,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation></bill> 

