<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6261A041F4F14CA3888FE866BC2B4FAA" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2428 IH: Wildfire Homeowner Relief Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2428</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250327">March 27, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000483">Ms. Friedman</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Lieu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001225">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Comptroller General of the United States to conduct a study regarding a Federal buyout program available to homeowners with properties in high-risk catastrophic wildfire disaster areas, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC1F728A250224DB5BAD8F3B5E7307939" style="OLC"><section id="H41C27B2F82374039B86790488BA374A1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Wildfire Homeowner Relief Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HB2EB5832B06E4A68BE4ECBF164C4FB15"><enum>2.</enum><header>GAO study on a federal buyout program for high-risk wildfire areas</header><subsection id="H71036756833D403499C95CE3AB816BBB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a study to analyze the feasibility of using Federal grant programs to purchase property from homeowners, voluntarily selling such properties, before and after a catastrophic wildfire disaster.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE10B0099BF124B9A9A88450484FE5C70"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Existing covered buyouts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In conducting the study under subsection (a), the Comptroller General shall compile recommendations on—</text><paragraph id="H14EBA8AB9489442C854697ABAF93EEBB"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how to develop a national database on covered buyouts, existing on the date of enactment of this Act, with information on what grant program was used to purchase each respective property under such buyouts, what entity is responsible for maintaining such property, and any development on such property following the covered buyout; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6B1001FE92834161A76BF2E1186D3212"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how the Federal Emergency Management Agency and the Department of Housing and Urban Development can exchange information about any covered buyout in process as of the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA6E6701078714C6B89062FBCFF7E53B1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>New wildfire buyout program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In conducting the study under subsection (a) of this Act, the Comptroller General shall—</text><paragraph id="H3BFAC10C86D745299C8BC56964382003"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">analyze how a program for the buyout of properties endangered or impacted by catastrophic wildfire disasters would compare to covered buyout programs existing on the date of enactment of this Act, including any floodplain disaster buyout programs; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H125B6625E8084C0694BA4777A673E5EB"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide recommendations on which department, agency, or program should house a program for the buyout of properties endangered or impacted by catastrophic wildfire disasters; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBCD4CAA24DD64DDDB4FBEA42E0794D21"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide land use recommendations for properties after a covered buyout, including—</text><subparagraph id="HA46822DE230846E48FC23BEED0C2FCCA"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how to ensure specific purchases and future land uses will reduce catastrophic wildfire risk, loss of life, and loss of property during catastrophic wildfires;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7FB4B575B5B0479EBF1ECE576A6F4F5B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how land use may be different for rural compared to urban communities and for disadvantaged compared to high-income communities; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4FC02863244649669F6104B8E1896C1F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>how to allow flexibility for communities to decide how to use the land following a covered buyout; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H112DBFF4D19D47FBA2F21D262F357EA0"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to properties in high-risk areas prior to catastrophic wildfire disaster and for properties impacted after a catastrophic wildfire disaster, eligibility requirements, including—</text><clause id="HD3119A0DA4C24255B3012ED5D098EEE5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>recommendations for mapping which areas are at the highest risk for catastrophic wildfire; and</text></clause><clause id="HF70A089FFED84A65BAD257E614F3D038"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>methodology for determining which areas would be most effective for implementing a Federal buyout program, including consideration for where the greatest benefit would be derived as a result of evacuating individuals in efforts to avoid loss of life. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H44F65D2C50E24753B1878F11B9C9AFAE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authority To define terms</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In conducting the study under subsection (a), the Comptroller General shall develop definitions for the terms <term>development</term>, <term>disadvantaged community</term>, <term>high-income community</term>, and <term>catastrophic wildfire</term>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H079AFA00F3E544F9825B3C1C000DA74C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 12 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General shall submit to Congress a report identifying findings and conclusions, including—</text><paragraph id="H1CA1083C578346D5B06128BE76C6A42F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the results of the study conducted pursuant to subsection (a);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H633DB8C4AA194C1DBFE6A1D33FCF98CD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any recommendations made under subsection (b);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD92A0964E4AE4C8FB9D1CF4875E0DAAF"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommendations on ways to incentivize participation in the program described in subsection (c);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H00A680164E724AC785756E906F6598F5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>analysis of the economic impacts of the program described in subsection (c) and the cost of the program to the Federal Government; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC7558B6FB44240728158A5AE67CE5F84"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the definitions developed under subsection (d).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H029B59252D4144B6AD0EA852E8AD1CA1"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Covered buyout defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this Act, a <quote>covered buyout</quote> means a purchase of property by the Federal Government from a homeowner who voluntarily sold such property because such property was recognized by the Federal Government to be in an area endangered or impacted by a catastrophic natural disaster.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

