<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="constitutional-amendment" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" slc-id="S1-HEN25030-1S8-Y6-XPM"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SJ 1 IS: Proposing an amendment to the Constitution of the United States relative to limiting the number of terms that a Member of Congress may serve.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IIA</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. J. RES. 1</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250107">January 7, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S355">Mr. Cruz</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S346">Mr. Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S404">Mr. Scott of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S420">Mr. Schmitt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S348">Mr. Paul</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S391">Mr. Young</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S375">Mr. Daines</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S407">Mr. Hagerty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S410">Ms. Lummis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S416">Mrs. Britt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S411">Mr. Marshall</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S411">Mr. Banks</cosponsor>) introduced the following joint resolution; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>JOINT RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Proposing an amendment to the Constitution of the United States relative to limiting the number of terms that a Member of Congress may serve.</official-title></form><resolution-body style="constitutional-amendment"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="S1"><text>That the following article is proposed as an amendment to the Constitution of the United States, which shall be valid to all intents and purposes as part of the Constitution when ratified by the legislatures of three-fourths of the several States within seven years after the date of its submission by the Congress:</text><quoted-block style="constitutional-amendment" id="id723589076583038736"><constitution-article id="idAE7509260972467264092629"><enum> —</enum><section section-type="section-one" id="id746584869376347636034"><enum>1.</enum><text>No person who has served 3 terms as a Representative shall be eligible for election to the House of Representatives. For purposes of this section, the election of a person to fill a vacancy in the House of Representatives shall be included as 1 term in determining the number of terms that such person has served as a Representative if the person fills the vacancy for more than 1 year.</text></section><section commented="no" section-type="section-one" id="id7465848693763476360341"><enum>2.</enum><text>No person who has served 2 terms as a Senator shall be eligible for election or appointment to the Senate. For purposes of this section, the election or appointment of a person to fill a vacancy in the Senate shall be included as 1 term in determining the number of terms that such person has served as a Senator if the person fills the vacancy for more than 3 years.</text></section><section commented="no" section-type="section-one" id="id74658486937634763603411"><enum>3.</enum><text>No term beginning before the date of the ratification of this article shall be taken into account in determining eligibility for election or appointment under this article.</text></section></constitution-article><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

