<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H81BE7A45E8FE4A098415F48B899464E3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4952 IH: Ensuring Coast Guard Readiness Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-08-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4952</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250812">August 12, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000403">Mr. Kennedy of Utah</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize an exception to the prohibition on the construction of Coast Guard vessels in foreign shipyards, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H2C3E496D0A144FDCB8BFFC8FB09CE7E5" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H0D762229B4834126AE410D086D98FEDF"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Ensuring Coast Guard Readiness Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H4F746E8713594A35AB8487DCD94BCC04"><enum>2.</enum><header>Exception to prohibition on construction of Coast Guard vessels in foreign shipyards</header> <subsection id="HBEDF1996408448E597C2BBC41F23DE6E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (b) of section 1151 of title 14, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4A7506ACDB7245398AE5434B5DCD9149">
<subsection id="H59227E022D964EE1A7A83AE457610D1C"><enum>(b)</enum>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H9A8DF8C9D3254236A444799259F7DBC7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The President may authorize exceptions to the prohibition in subsection (a) when the President determines that it is in the national security interest of the United States to do so, provided that—</text> <subparagraph indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H762FEF5B76A34B749E57481F5B96B265"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the foreign shipyard concerned is located in a North Atlantic Treaty Organization member country or a country in the Indo-Pacific region that is party to a mutual defense treaty with the United States; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H68E350A8612942349620F63551CD38F1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the cost of the construction concerned is less than the cost would be if such construction occurred in a domestic shipyard.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H319A6EC32EAB415BA2FB317DFF174E07"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The President shall transmit notice to Congress of any such determination, and no contract may be made pursuant to the exception authorized until the end of the 30-day period beginning on the date the notice of such determination is received by Congress.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF2BCE4DF817044D7B7BBE5DBC7BB5096"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Before the construction of a Coast Guard vessel, or a major component of the hull or superstructure of a Coast Guard vessel, may commence at a foreign shipyard pursuant to this subsection, the Commandant shall submit to Congress a certification that the foreign shipyard is not owned or operated by a Chinese company or a multinational company domiciled in the People’s Republic of China.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HCBED1756D57140AA8310092871BB5E44"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 8679(a) of title 10, United States Code, is amended by inserting <quote>and section 1151(b) of title 14</quote> after <quote>in subsection (b)</quote>.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

