<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H8739AF662BFB4B98915F5AB1DD34491A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><form><distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5320</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250911">September 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="W000795">Mr. Wilson of South Carolina</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To strengthen United States relations with certain countries of Central and Southeast Europe and develop a comprehensive strategy to strengthen democracy, rule of law, and civil society, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H36C75F8A0879451A87D5E2265C8F74BB" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H582A9CA518AA4044AC003E620B6B4F81" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
            <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the
                        <quote><short-title>Transatlantic Growth Enterprise
                    Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H69D458D77AC54D9F871C9DC7B992759D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text> 
<toc container-level="legis-body-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"> 
<toc-entry idref="H582A9CA518AA4044AC003E620B6B4F81" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H69D458D77AC54D9F871C9DC7B992759D" level="section">Sec. 2. Table of contents.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H8CE3E51BDA1A446DA98CE76CC755D19A" level="section">Sec. 3. Findings.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HE0E7ED4F895B4F2D98A5588E3D1BC494" level="section">Sec. 4. Sense of Congress.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H41255DBE9D4F4D06BC793579B587977A" level="section">Sec. 5. Establishment of Transatlantic Growth Enterprise.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H3E86A8F5B35743CDAFFC9C01452DE122" level="section">Sec. 6. Definitions.</toc-entry> </toc></section> 
<section id="H8CE3E51BDA1A446DA98CE76CC755D19A"><enum>3.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H2175DC0E45BA4DDAAC07867B7649D491"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States has a strong and unwavering interest in promoting peace, security, democracy, good governance, and rule of law in Central and Eastern Europe.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE354E0C37D4D4E1B97CFC92F5ECF0E93"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Many countries in Central and Eastern Europe are strong and reliable NATO partners that serve as indefensible allies to the United States and transatlantic security.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H27751C315D4B48148404DE7777EE88C2"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In recent years, de-democratization in Central and Eastern Europe, particularly in Hungary, has greatly undermined the United States bilateral relationship with those countries and have enabled malign actors like China and Russia to gain a foothold in the transatlantic alliance.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7388A56FED63434182265F22404670D0"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Russia’s illegal war of aggression in Ukraine and China’s significant support for Russia’s war of aggression pose a significant economic and security threat to the European continent.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1CCE1DC4A5F84A90BC895AFEA138E341">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Strengthening the United States security and
          economic relationship with Central and Eastern Europe while countering malign action in
          the region is in the vital interest of the United States.</text>
      </paragraph></section> 
<section id="HE0E7ED4F895B4F2D98A5588E3D1BC494" commented="no"><enum>4.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text> 
<paragraph id="H8C3E580936D34E079C4E50C6E15ED504" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a strong security and economic relationship between the United States and countries in Central and Eastern Europe is vital to United States national security;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H860F7FCB0906492D93FAA85601436021" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Central and Eastern European countries play an important role in NATO and the transatlantic security architecture and serve as a bulwark against Russian malign influence and aggression;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9667AC5245D54F84BB1D5C1BF08BE2E7" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the United States can better counter the influence of the People’s Republic of China around the world through transatlantic cooperation including with countries in Central and Eastern Europe; and; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4424090FAD214000B2FA952804F1EEB6" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">United States investments in Central and Eastern Europe and strengthened business to business ties between the United States and Central and Eastern Europe strengthen the economic security of the transatlantic relationship and contribute to increased prosperity and energy security around the world.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H41255DBE9D4F4D06BC793579B587977A"><enum>5.</enum><header>Establishment of Transatlantic Growth Enterprise</header> 
<subsection id="H54518A303A3C48E6B1C3C47656A798A0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Enterprise authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State shall, in coordination with the Chief Executive Officer of the Development Finance Corporation, and other relevant Federal agencies, carry out a program, to be known as the <quote>Transatlantic Growth Enterprise</quote>, in support of strengthening United States relations with participating Enterprise countries, with a particular focus on strengthening business to business ties and fostering a robust investment environment in participating Enterprise countries as well as expanding energy security and security cooperation within Enterprise countries.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8D0DF1FEF154433C83A07DA1330D5774"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Objectives</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The objectives of the Enterprise shall be the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H3F379D2932BF4171B4B63C3B2500CB47"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Strengthen United States relationships with like-minded participating countries.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC15EEB0450C249EFAC78AE2A3BDE23E0"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Expand business-to-business ties, including by working with relevant Chambers of Commerce, between United States industry and important economic and security sectors in participating countries.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF4AEA7F7EE5C4F92B861136358A0FED2"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Expand energy sector cooperation between the United States and Enterprise countries, including in the nuclear energy sector.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7B08EA2B5F344B15A78E83E22D237576"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Strengthen people-to-people ties between the United States and participating countries.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFC0091B207EE4BB69A95BDF7705BA873"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Strengthen security cooperation and efforts to counter Russian malign influence and aggression on the European continent.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDFA14CC43FC844199EADF7A4A13D058A"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Counter the People’s Republic of China’s growing private sector footprint in Enterprise countries;</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA76DBC281576467E876EE7E7CFB3F89B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall seek to convene appropriate stakeholders of participating Enterprise countries at least twice per calendar year to discuss shared goals and priorities for the Enterprise. Such stakeholders shall include, as practicable, government officials, business leaders, and civil society representatives.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5606FCFE124649F1BEB70222009D2F06"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To the extent that projects or activities are undertaken or supported by the Secretary, the Enterprise may only engage with counterpart government officials of Enterprise countries that the Secretary has determined are not undermining United States interests in the region—</text> 
<paragraph id="HC85FE82A143047BA9A2B3BC05695E516"><enum>(1)</enum><text>through cooperation with Russia or China; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H494C945CB5BC43F4B140FA9DA53168B9"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by undermining democracy in the region including through the conclusion of a bilateral agreement with the People’s Republic of China or the Russian Federation that enables the stationing of that country’s police or military forces on the enterprise country’s territory.</text> </paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3A5C38C3C1544A37AA3F1DCFC729DB52" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reports</header> 
<paragraph id="H8C2A7B2C7A34421BADE77BE61B02CBEC" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Implementation report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Secretary, in coordination with the heads of the Federal agencies described in subsection (a), shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report detailing the activities of the Enterprise, which shall also include—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H0E249B95FF7D41B9B22771BDBA454FAD" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an overview of the diplomatic engagements undertaken in the Enterprise;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H55B119F2A60F430A9DDF195DCF8FBF65" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an assessment of the progress of achieving the objectives described in subsection (b); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF298F0E0F9CC46978A33F98B39D7A962" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>recommendations for future initiatives for the Enterprise to undertake.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2C98B0B2182C408B9F1AFBE10B3CEBC5" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Form</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report required by paragraph (1) shall be submitted in unclassified form but may contain a classified annex.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9ACB6E3F13DF47B29E945C86C2FA2186"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Energy strategy</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State, in consultation with the heads of the Federal agencies described in subsection (a), shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that includes the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H7D4B64865EA64EF9BF378ACDDC4A6257"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An overview of ongoing energy cooperation between the United States and participating Enterprise countries.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H98D5841B12D14689B77AACC88405F693"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An overview of the dependency of enterprise countries on the Russian and Chinese energy sectors and the impacts of these dependencies on United States and transatlantic trade and energy security.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEFD8F4EF488F4CA4A968E0F3B2664F8A"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A list of opportunities in the energy sectors of participating countries, including in energy infrastructure, that would enhance the work of the Enterprise, further United States national security, support decoupling from energy sector dependencies on Russia and China, and strengthen United States bilateral relations with enterprise countries.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5A47A112AA0E479B9538BF4F3836733F"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of required appropriations or additional needed authorities for the United States to carry out public sector opportunities listed pursuant to subsection (c).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H13E5927366A744919123D2F71D7DD1F7"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of actions required by the private sector and opportunities for the United States to provide support to the private sector to carry out private sector opportunities listed pursuant to subsection (c).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H3E86A8F5B35743CDAFFC9C01452DE122" commented="no"><enum>6.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="HE0C78B8FB65742A39FBFCD5B3C5844C2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HED00EF8E7AA64BD59CB07E4BE29DD894"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Enterprise country</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Enterprise country</term> means the Czech Republic, Poland, Slovakia, Hungary, Romania, Moldova, Ukraine, or Bulgaria, and may include any other country in Central and Eastern Europe that the Secretary of State determines appropriate to participate in the Enterprise authorized by <internal-xref idref="H41255DBE9D4F4D06BC793579B587977A" legis-path="5.">section 5</internal-xref>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA255500F7F3C4C689F85A6545C1623C0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>North Atlantic Treaty Organization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>NATO</term> means the North Atlantic Treaty Organization.</text></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>
