<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H73248A1547E34A93B94CB45F1712553C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4114 IH: Ensuring Veterans’ Smooth Transition Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4114</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250624">June 24, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to automatically enroll eligible veterans in the patient enrollment system of Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H619553A2437648D7B98741A75A678D83" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H3B29827DB2714B2DB8E8AC16BC16D28E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Ensuring Veterans’ Smooth Transition Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>EVEST Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HB75161FFB709449FBCE0EC21A4004884" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Automatic enrollment of eligible veterans in patient enrollment system of Department of Veterans Affairs</header> <subsection id="H86C7145CFBC44D85A6FC4BA1FE19F285"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1705 of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="HF7691B468670430EAF16025BA708C69B" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="HC3E867FE6FBA48BBAC01088168F63406"><enum>(d)</enum> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H21D35ACBE29D4EDBBAD33AB23AF43E5F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Secretary shall enroll each veteran described in subsection (a) in the patient enrollment system under this section not later than 60 days after receiving the information described in paragraph (2) regarding the veteran.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFD31A9D93E4842B0BA8EE061D7E18FBF" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The information described in this paragraph is the information—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H3AEB624A1E524350881B335C31A52C60"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">regarding a veteran that the Secretary determines is necessary to so enroll a veteran; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3940AFD347F54BF3AE71369DF2722EE8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>transmitted to the Secretary under section 1142(e) of title 10.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7342E60721914BD08C198307EC74AF71" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after enrolling a veteran under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall provide to the veteran—</text> <subparagraph id="HED6FC2CBB9154D5BB0FD31170FE3C4D4"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">notice of such enrollment;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H43960240DDFD45F2BAAB30BA6A6550A9"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">instructions regarding how the veteran may opt out of such enrollment;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE7FE09F9D51F4E3FB57DA3DFC6755B00"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">instructions regarding how the veteran may elect to enroll at a later date.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFB8B611C9EA948BDB5850DED6C503BB6" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out paragraph (3), the Secretary shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HAAE7671E7181416C97DCC0FFF93C48A9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide a notice or instructions in the form of a physical copy delivered by mail and, to the extent practical, in the form of an electronic copy delivered by electronic mail; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H67374E6B10A54FD7832A49C6559A186E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>consider using, to the extent practical, mass texting capabilities through mobile telephones.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HC29B98130BA64FD1A56E39E6F9F3AE86"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>Subsection (d) of section 1705 of title 38, United States Code, as added by subsection (a), shall apply to a veteran—</text> 
<paragraph id="H1BFF6FAE29304C1897AC22D80BA945B0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>who is discharged or separated from the Armed Forces on or after the date that is 90 days before the date of the enactment of this Act; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H87A068F1BA0E4AC08178B06D43D5D902"><enum>(2)</enum><text>with respect to whom the Secretary receives the information described in paragraph (2) of such subsection on or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HADD8702E805540698BFA751CA06478C7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Electronic certificates of eligibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than August 1, 2026, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall ensure that any veteran who is eligible for automatic enrollment in the patient enrollment system under subsection (d) of section 1705 of title 38, United States Code, as added by subsection (a), is able to access—</text> <paragraph id="H064AD8206D1B42C1B5C917A912FEA567"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an electronic version of the veteran’s certificate of eligibility for such enrollment; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7A03AC5893ED4EFCAFF796668D0AFC16"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an electronic mechanism by which the veteran may opt out of such enrollment.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H6930BD692F734D96BC84F9553B7B40D9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report on automatic enrollment</header> <paragraph id="H5FBF2CE442D8475F8113455A48F1CBBD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the first veteran is enrolled in the patient enrollment system of the Department of Veterans Affairs under subsection (d) of section 1705 of title 38, United States Code, as added by subsection (a), the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and House of Representatives a report on the enrollment process under such subsection. Such report shall include each of the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H0D33E8B0C5B04C4EB1B80AB9532341EC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A discussion of any anticipated challenges that occurred in implementing such subsection, the strategies used to address such challenges, and the effectiveness of such strategies.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9438E935A41D4EBA9CA99DC46A8E03DB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A discussion of any unanticipated challenges that occurred in implementing such subsection, the strategies used to address such challenges, and the effectiveness of such strategies.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9434FDB272964199895535E0C510812E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Any additional information the Secretary determines appropriate, including information that may be useful to other Federal departments and agencies considering the implementation of similar automatic enrollment programs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4D4437ED07BF481CB9547C996363A6E2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Form of report</header><text>The report required under paragraph (1) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H4F66BB9E0295456F97CE2DA5CB2E0D66"><enum>3.</enum><header>GAO report on notice of automatic enrollment in patient enrollment system of Department of Veterans Affairs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and House of Representatives a report containing the results of a study to determine the best methods for the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to provide notice under paragraph (3) of subsection (d) of section 1705 of title 38, United States Code, as added by section 2. In making such determination, the Comptroller General shall consider the needs of a veteran based on—</text> <paragraph id="HA50E3D0F96184FCEA9E8C5D806EFFA14"><enum>(1)</enum><text>age;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA0D2E738A0E6481A8ED63B4B73FD1F99"><enum>(2)</enum><text>residence in an urban area; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3C86D9F006EA436BBEEEDE4832A9F996"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">residence in an rural area.</text></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

