<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-EHF25579-CGX-47-RVG"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1525 IS: Common Cents Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-04-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code>II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1525</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250430">April 30, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S410">Ms. Lummis</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S331">Mrs. Gillibrand</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To direct the Secretary of the Treasury to stop minting the penny, to
            require cash transactions to be rounded up or down to the nearest 5 cents, and for other
 purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HA22120092E1344D499EEE8C0BD51C931"><section section-type="section-one" id="H341550C24D0E49408F714CB0C7F18F2E"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Common Cents Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HC6CA9512C4234F85869789D4D030CD64"><enum>2.</enum><header>Elimination of production of one-cent coin</header><subsection id="HE1153F3C3B8E4A5981A1DBFD2C7E94FD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Elimination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subsection (b), and notwithstanding any other provision of law (including section 5112(a)(6) of title 31, United States Code), beginning on a date that is not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Treasury shall cease minting and issuing one-cent coins.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE92470D899C2425FAD1CA21553986E44"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exception</header><paragraph id="H0C222CD2F27545EE98C114C668C368A8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On and after the date described in subsection (a), the Secretary of the Treasury shall continue to mint and issue one-cent coins as appropriate solely to meet the needs of numismatic collectors of the one-cent coin.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HABE156CD20DD42288105277DFBB27CD1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sale</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any one-cent coin minted and issued under this subsection shall be sold in accordance with section 5132(a) of title 31 United States Code, and any other provisions of law governing numismatic coins.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA72C19B6FDCF4FD2A93E4EDBCF321033"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Net receipts</header><text>The net receipts from the sale of a one-cent coin minted and issued under this subsection shall equal or exceed the total cost of production, including variable costs and the appropriate share of fixed costs of production, as determined by the Secretary of the Treasury.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE67AD0DE9F704DEC9EF7E7F9D4E80A20"><enum>(c)</enum><header>No effect on legal tender</header><text>All coins and currencies of the United States, including one-cent coins, regardless of when coined, printed, minted, or issued, shall continue to be legal tender for all debts, public and private, public charges, taxes, duties, and dues, in accordance with law.</text></subsection></section><section id="H2FBEF60DE6B747B69354062F634B4B40"><enum>3.</enum><header>Cash transaction rounding</header><subsection id="HFC7FE86B5DB541D58AA888FF1E3A81D3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any person selling goods or services in a cash transaction, entering into any other transaction that results in a payment or transfer of cash between the parties to the transaction, or paying cash wages to an employee as compensation shall round the payment in the following manner:</text><paragraph id="HA704BECA8ED04A5E8A6F07F54057B3BA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Rounding down</header><text>In any case in which the total transaction amount, including any taxes, ends with 1 cent, 2 cents, 6 cents, or 7 cents as the final digit, the amount of cents in the sum shall be rounded down to the nearest amount divisible by 5 for any person seeking to make payment with legal tender.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6DC76D54D3D44B9F8BF39F9DCF67FDE7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rounding up</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In any case in which the total transaction amount, including any taxes, ends with 3 cents, 4 cents, 8 cents, or 9 cents as the final digit, the amount of cents in the sum shall be rounded up to the nearest amount divisible by 5 for any person seeking to make payment with legal tender.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6E9DF8E8B3DC4099AF007C7B471536DC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Subsection (a) shall not apply to a transaction—</text><paragraph id="H28C6EFC060CA41D28C96476F44C09CB1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in which the total transaction amount, including any taxes, totals $0.01 or $0.02, in which case that transaction amount shall be rounded up to $.05 for any person seeking to make payment with legal tender; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0D6421BB930D40B9AA3274212344380B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for which payment is made by any demand or negotiable instrument, electronic fund transfer, check, gift card, money order, credit card, or other similar instrument or method.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H006CB4BC21B84C7096A23698456C5572"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section shall take effect on the date that is 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


