<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H28B0D1BD1C814350A722AB1ABE229DEF" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>118 HR 390 IH: Advanced Capabilities for Emergency Response Operations Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-01-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 390</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250114">January 14, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000480">Mr. Fong</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001227">Ms. McClellan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To utlitize the Advanced Capabilities for Emergency Response to Operations project of NASA to improve aerial responses to wildfires, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8901DE23392A4E138D42FB2071EFEA71" style="OLC"><section id="H4BD965C331AE4C1DA09C2B7B07098656" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Advanced Capabilities for Emergency Response Operations Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>ACERO Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H50973BC19865421E8550333A14EAB3D3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Advanced capabilities for emergency response operations</header><subsection id="H07ED9E8A4A154906A091F11F1FBE4688"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator shall leverage NASA-developed tools and technologies to conduct research and development activities under the Advanced Capabilities for Emergency Response Operations (ACERO) project to improve aerial responses to wildfires.</text></subsection><subsection id="H8A4BAB6EF83047DEBBEF6F0D3C117F90"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Goals</header><text>The research and development activities conducted under subsection (a) shall, to the extent practicable, address the following:</text><paragraph id="HEE1E9C38502E4EBBAD8E16BDA640E5E7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Advanced aircraft technologies and airspace management efforts to assist in the management, deconfliction, and coordination of aerial assets during wildfire response efforts.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H880346DDB24E4268B14AB7F83F083DC3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Information sharing and real-time data exchange for wildfire response teams.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA81B12642D3D4F2ABF2C82636800F0DA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Development of an interoperable platform to provide situational awareness of aerial assets during wildfire response.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2690481E45F44DCF8C88AAAC11477EBF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Establishment of a multi-agency concept of operations, which may involve Federal, State, and local government agencies, to enable coordination of aerial activities for wildfire response.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC28C859885E04C4D915ED007C94D72D4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Collaboration</header><text>In carrying out this section, the Administrator—</text><paragraph id="H8AA6C04A2BDE419EBE2B8250BD9988F6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>may coordinate and collaborate with other Federal, State, and local government agencies, regional organizations, and commercial partners and academic institutions involved in wildfire management; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H594A0AF696B240CFA282C35B129A8B28"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall, to the maximum extent practicable, consult with the heads of other Federal departments and agencies to avoid duplication of activities.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H022ABEDC119F46F78ECC5AD4920319B5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><paragraph id="H89A6C79BB59B4C21869BC06B521A9DD8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in this subsection, the Administrator may not procure an unmanned aircraft system to conduct activities described in this section if such unmanned aircraft system is manufactured or assembled by a covered foreign entity.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC00C6FD0AFC84C21B769E99AF6C0B1FD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exemption</header><text>The Administrator may waive the prohibition under paragraph (1) on a case-by-case basis if the Administrator—</text><subparagraph id="HB5A4ADF589EC49D4956B9E4D3BA15E30"><enum>(A)</enum><text>determines that the procurement of an unmanned aircraft system is—</text><clause id="H57A46F2C2D9F44F782D0870BFAD70856"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the national interest of the United States; and</text></clause><clause id="H8F69BF992E5045D7819D90D716462888"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>necessary for the sole purpose of improving aerial responses to wildfires; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAD2D8720951C4A9089417849635D5A17"><enum>(B)</enum><text>notifies the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate not later than 30 days after a determination in the affirmative under subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4C5A15FC064B434FBD0CDD75E2568F06"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Annual reports</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act and annually thereafter until December 31, 2030, the Administrator shall submit to the Committee on Science, Space and Technology of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a report describing the activities, including results, carried out pursuant to this section. Each such report, at minimum, shall contain the following:</text><paragraph id="H0F01F2325347470AAE9D1E334BE18A81"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A description of any research and development activities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB138EEE9D9304DB8917C901638664147"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A description of the Administrator’s activities pursuant to subsection (c).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF1BC4618076447C18CEFED6A1B006BCD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>An assessment of the effectiveness of such activities in preventing injuries and loss of life, protecting property, and reducing economic damage.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5E63D24B89A743B2885D389169F56A37"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An identification of any topics related to improvement of aerial responses to wildfires that could benefit from further research.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H40F1FDF6D3914D7AB57E387EDEE18F86"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A description of any continuing efforts under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H61F7675D3A274E8CA4C554801EE100F5"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Any other information determined appropriate by the Administrator.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8AA65C5F02354EB9AEAF43CE3870BF48"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated $15,000,000 for fiscal year 2026 to carry out this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC1FBAB62653B4059AA86E1CD5ECFC4DE"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HE7BC53B96A8547A8A644B2A166C14827"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <quote>Administrator</quote> means the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1E4658C9CD6C46FBBBC3E0D306DF7C7B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered foreign entity</header><text>The term <quote>covered foreign entity</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 1822 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2024 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/118/31">Public Law 118–31</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H76FFC62D327F48618D6E19170F594953"><enum>(3)</enum><header>NASA</header><text>The term <quote>NASA</quote> means the National Aeronautics and Space Administration.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3B5E868B3849417F83F7FA63340CE685"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Unmanned aircraft system</header><text>The term <quote>unmanned aircraft system</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 44801 of title 49, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

