<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDEAB807DCE7140868E26B694BD21E65C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1531 IH: Pressure Regulatory Organizations To End Chinese Threats to Taiwan Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1531</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250224">February 24, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000491">Mr. Lucas</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="G000581">Mr. Vicente Gonzalez of Texas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct certain financial regulators to exclude representatives of the People&#8217;s Republic of China from certain banking organizations upon notice of certain threats or danger, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6EA2EE8F5FB742AA9234C0118C9B922C" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HAE9E99207AB5457CAE315E93E6BCB185" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Pressure Regulatory Organizations To End Chinese Threats to Taiwan Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>PROTECT Taiwan Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HBA261A24FA18473D89BE1F9C2195B619"><enum>2.</enum><header>Statement of policy regarding the exclusion of representatives of the people’s republic of china from certain banking organizations upon notice of certain threats or danger</header> <subsection id="HDB2C32063AA948F4BCF68081E8CE112C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the President, pursuant to section 3(c) of the Taiwan Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/3302">22 U.S.C. 3302(c)</external-xref>), informs the Congress of any threat to the security or the social or economic system of the people on Taiwan and any danger to the interests of the United States arising therefrom resulting from actions of the People’s Republic of China, it is the policy of the United States to seek to exclude representatives of the People’s Republic of China, to the maximum extent practicable, from participation in meetings, proceedings, and other activities of the following organizations:</text> 
<paragraph id="HCDE481D94DD14B3296B9638204F59977"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Group of Twenty.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8BB5FA4551874657BB17936E9D7D84DD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Bank for International Settlements.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H774BCB460A3E42A0800B274CB42CD7C0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Financial Stability Board.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5D1545CDFCCC4FC9B6EF1BF927C52D65"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Basel Committee on Banking Supervision.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC16EC54945F94CBAA2A8C347F801746B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The International Association of Insurance Supervisors.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7393BBB11C4F44518489B0210A0C3D7E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The International Organization of Securities Commissions.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6235B1B02AA740C48CE8302EED12D941"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Policy advancement</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury, the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, and the Securities and Exchange Commission, shall take all necessary steps to advance the policy set forth in subsection (a).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H9B71100F37D84059BC4B832E7A028B4F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>The President may waive the application of subsection (a) with respect to an organization upon submission of a report to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate—</text> 
<paragraph id="HE77886262FB141AFABBC7E004A74CD44"><enum>(1)</enum><text>that such waiver is in the national interest of the United States; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H038C8F02295341A58B3DB228624FC07A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>that contains an explanation of the reasons therefor.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HDB3E76B12E334B18818DCF982FFF47BE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>This Act and the requirements of this Act shall have no force or effect on the date that is the earlier of—</text> <paragraph id="HAEA06BD5D5994A81B7381191F038ED2F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>5 years after the date of the enactment of this Act; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF77F7D8F4AB14E79978974AC35ECDE4A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">30 days after the date on which the President notifies Congress that the termination of this Act is in the national interest of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

