<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-SIL25896-8J2-LT-K0D"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2487 IS: Buffalo Soldiers Congressional Gold Medal Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-07-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code>II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2487</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250728">July 28, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S426">Mr. Kim</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S365">Mr. Scott of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S363">Mr. King</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms.
                    Klobuchar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>, and
                    <cosponsor name-id="S402">Ms. Rosen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill;
                which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To award a Congressional Gold Medal collectively to the Buffalo Soldier
            regiments, authorized by Congress in 1866 to serve in the United States Armed Forces, in
            recognition of their superior, dedicated, and vital service to the United
 States.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HCBD003FD39D149BBAD84516584921E43"><section section-type="section-one" id="H9218D075AECE4731B493796521E729D6"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Buffalo Soldiers Congressional Gold Medal Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H98011A414B8B4269A3F9C629C1F74884"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H62ADC245F78B47B3AD1BF474D9CEEB2D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In 1866, Congress passed the Act entitled <quote>An Act to increase and fix the military peace establishment of the United States</quote>, approved July 28, 1866 (14 Stat. 332; chapter 299), which authorized the creation of 6 all-Black cavalry and infantry regiments. These regiments remained active until the Army was desegregated in 1951.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H337F87500D0F43A693D5BB3AB3E6EB33"><enum>(2)</enum><text>According to legend, American Indians called the Black cavalry troops <quote>Buffalo Soldiers</quote> because of their dark, curly hair, which resembled a buffalo’s coat.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD66CFFF9C80745408A0F3FFB32F48EF6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The African-American troops accepted the name with pride and honor, as they were aware of the fierce bravery and fighting spirit of the buffalo.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H923ED51B51954E8692BE30949B39D594"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The original 6 regiments melded into the following 4 regiments:</text><subparagraph id="HCC2208E44BD54467A6AC54D8CE7CC580"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The 9th Cavalry Regiment assembled in New Orleans, Louisiana, in August and September of 1866. They were ordered to San Antonio, Texas, in April 1867, with the mission to maintain order and to secure the road from San Antonio to El Paso.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H496720A03F164BDA87F47614BAFC9B0A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The 10th Cavalry Regiment gathered in Fort Leavenworth, Kansas, during the summer of 1867. In August 1867, they were ordered to Fort Riley, Kansas, with the mission of protecting the Pacific Railroad.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H396FB8A04D9B4A33875A43B1FA0A0D67"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The 24th Infantry Regiment was organized in 1869, forming from the 38th and 41st Colored Infantry Regiments. They served throughout the Western United States, with the mission to protect frontier posts and secure roadways.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDD14C03305B645978C88B9D61F183927"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The 25th Infantry Regiment assembled at Camp William Penn, Pennsylvania, beginning in January 1864. They were assigned to numerous districts within the Department of the Gulf with the mission to maintain security.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8BDE76DC32C64675A279BF94C7FCE061"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Buffalo Soldiers also assisted in the protection of National Parks. They helped fight wildfires and poachers in the Yosemite and Sequoia National Parks and served as park rangers in the Sierra Nevada.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H78633E4A8F424063B81A706C5289EC61"><enum>(6)</enum><text>In the Spanish-American War, all 4 regiments played key roles and fought with distinction, despite facing severe discrimination from the locals.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H032B10E2EC394ED78099164571398E8C"><enum>(7)</enum><text>At the start of World War I, the Buffalo Soldier regiments were dispatched to locations throughout the central United States and into the Pacific, offering logistics and support behind the front lines in the American Expeditionary Forces.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H91D019972499444BA35C8CE46FD83CDC"><enum>(8)</enum><text>During World War II, African-American soldiers and units continued to serve proudly under the name <quote>Buffalo Soldier</quote>, including the 92nd Infantry Division, which was the only Black division that saw combat in Europe.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3BF85E80C36A41D188A907C887A720B3"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the Korean War, Buffalo Soldier regiments fought throughout the Korean peninsula, from the defense of the <quote>Pusan Perimeter</quote> to the counteroffensives which resulted in the end of armed hostilities and the creation of the Demilitarized Zone.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H25EB3B69E1AF4B9C8A46116D8D3AA734"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Buffalo Soldiers had the lowest military desertion and court-martial rates of their time. In recognition of combat valor and their actions beyond the call of duty, many were awarded the Congressional Medal of Honor.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id08b771325ec1443d8652c6f2475dacd8"><enum>(11)</enum><text>On November 15, 2024, the Reverend Robert W. Dixon Sr., the last known living member of the 9th and 10th Cavalry Regiments, passed away at the age of 103.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H143088B51EF94F40BDEFE298A87182DD"><enum>(12)</enum><text>The Congressional Gold Medal would be an appropriate way to shed further light on the service of the Buffalo Soldiers and the instrumental role they played in instilling an approach to inclusivity within our military and the way of life in the United States.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H9F943828FCB94ED185762EEB13E17111"><enum>3.</enum><header>Congressional gold medal</header><subsection id="H04D78D8F0D2F4B82ADBE6877B94A930F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Award authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President pro tempore of the Senate shall make appropriate arrangements for the award, on behalf of Congress, of a gold medal of appropriate design to the Buffalo Soldier regiments, authorized by Congress in 1866 to serve in the United States Armed Forces, in recognition of their superior, dedicated, and vital service to the United States.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF6539C1EA5824B92B6E76C0943134DDA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Design and striking</header><text>For purposes of the award described in subsection (a), the Secretary of the Treasury (in this Act referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall strike a gold medal with suitable emblems, devices, and inscriptions, to be determined by the Secretary.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE5FB9AE109684E22A8A6DC06A356D30F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Smithsonian institution</header><paragraph id="H3C8853CB7827437F9ADF851363C420E9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Following the award of the gold medal under subsection (a), the gold medal shall be given to the National Museum of African American History and Culture of the Smithsonian Institution, where it shall be displayed as appropriate and made available for research.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H065A7966ACD848398BA8F2E8D7EC8588"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that the Smithsonian Institution should make the gold medal received under paragraph (1) available for display elsewhere, particularly at other locations and events associated with the Buffalo Soldiers.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HADAE398973CB4163BE992A1F0A6E7C78"><enum>4.</enum><header>Duplicate medals</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary may strike and sell duplicates in bronze of the gold medal struck pursuant to section 3, at a price sufficient to cover the costs thereof, including labor, materials, dies, use of machinery, and overhead expenses.</text></section><section id="HA6E997F9C70F47F794DD5759A53C0A60"><enum>5.</enum><header>Status of medals</header><subsection id="H4F91A5C2553E4E789B7560540B7D1E10"><enum>(a)</enum><header>National medals</header><text>Medals struck under this Act are national medals for purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/51">chapter 51</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code.</text></subsection><subsection id="H7B21148B5D614AE1A705E65A14EAD680"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Numismatic items</header><text>For purposes of sections 5134 and 5136 of title 31, United States Code, all medals struck under this Act shall be considered to be numismatic items.</text></subsection></section><section id="H363628A2955C4E578E34A3244D1324E3"><enum>6.</enum><header>Authority to use fund amounts; proceeds of sale</header><subsection id="H2FA9B9B2197E4A159B6D02A0C41C3755"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority To use fund amounts</header><text>There is authorized to be charged against the United States Mint Public Enterprise Fund such amounts as may be necessary to pay for the costs of the medals struck under this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H20726F57BA2D48D4B6FA44D75FA23A51"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Proceeds of sale</header><text>Amounts received from the sale of duplicate bronze medals authorized under section 4 shall be deposited into the United States Mint Public Enterprise Fund.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


