<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-HEN25753-YT4-5K-JKT"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2192 IS: Clean Hands Firearm Procurement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2192</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250626" legis-day="20250624">June 26 (legislative day, June 24), 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S364">Mr. Murphy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S366">Ms. Warren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S426">Mr. Kim</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Attorney General to make publicly available a list of federally licensed firearms dealers with a high number of short time-to-crime firearm traces, and to prohibit Federal departments and agencies from contracting with such dealers.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H9C78AA5BF59A46DF9FA6DFBF8D9979F7"><section section-type="section-one" id="HEA93286737F546CCB0C7C80AD1BA6918"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Clean Hands Firearm Procurement Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H725E53A2536446388D58D262F7CEBF38"><enum>2.</enum><header>Federal gun tracing notifications</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Attorney General, acting through the Director of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives, shall publish or make publicly available a list of covered firearms dealers.</text></section><section id="H39BF0FED0B914B1D86651944A56EA421"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibition on Federal contracts with certain Federal firearms dealers</header><subsection id="H554080D76FCF4A40B58D8BEEC5C141DD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>A Federal agency may not enter into a contract with a licensed dealer that has been listed as a covered firearms dealer during the current calendar year or either of the preceding 2 calendar years. </text></subsection><subsection id="H44401C19F079458F8B0DFB6482CB4808"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Waiver authority</header><paragraph id="idDD3B5949BE6E4547BA3FED8CD2E9F685"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon a request by the Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Attorney General may waive the applicability of subsection (a) to a contract, to protect the national security of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id826DA209EECF487A86F60658772B5E95"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notice</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General shall immediately notify the Chair and Ranking Minority Member of the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and the Chair and Ranking Minority Member of the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate of any waiver granted under paragraph (1). Notice under this paragraph may be submitted in classified form.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCA544DC4F17F46E59E17FABD7B789D93"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section shall take effect 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act. </text></subsection></section><section id="HEF7237546257422D901FF4F8E0707195"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="HA6C443A11AE8436195F73664B91965ED"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered firearms dealer</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered firearms dealer</term> means a licensed dealer with respect to whom, during not less than 2 of the 3 calendar years before the publication of the applicable list under section 2, the National Tracing Center of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives has traced to the firearms business of the licensed dealer not less than 25 firearms with a time-to-crime of not more than 3 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8FF4797E1A0B4A6E83AE7A9D09E1A0AB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federal agency</header><text>The term <term>Federal agency</term> means a department, agency, office, or other establishment in the executive, legislative, or judicial branch of the Government of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H888DE36A2B9047438C2309AB4B0A94B0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Firearm</header><text>The term <term>firearm</term> has the meaning given that term in section 921(a) of title 18, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idAA77E9666D6341B680E3F9A03217712B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Licensed dealer</header><text>The term <term>licensed dealer</term> has the meaning given that term in section 921(a) of title 18, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2CE1B484269E46A48C9C8A30C21727CE"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Time-to-crime</header><text>The term <term>time-to-crime</term> means, with respect to a firearm, the period between the date of the last known retail sale of the firearm and the date a law enforcement agency recovers the firearm as a result of an actual or suspected purchase, use, or possession of the firearm in, or that constitutes, a crime.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

