<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MIR25123-LFF-VR-4X5"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S970 IS: Helping More Families Save Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-03-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 970</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250311" legis-day="20250310">March 11 (legislative day, March 10), 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S259">Mr. Reed</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S416">Mrs. Britt</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To establish a pilot program to improve the family self-sufficiency program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="id46afe1bf888141a09d5b8486b81a483d"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Helping More Families Save Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="ida2368eeb44dd4021937c083c7efd4078"><enum>2.</enum><header>Family self-sufficiency escrow expansion pilot program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 23 of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437u">42 U.S.C. 1437u</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0EB257307A1B4EDFB439CE597F88530A"><subsection id="id4fb108801378489ebf53a43a7e4fbdaa"><enum>(p)</enum><header>Escrow expansion pilot program</header><paragraph id="id2ed602e3f977454bb37cb2dcbd1d55fe"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text><subparagraph id="id6cfaa77f314f43368ae9c2d02b5d20c3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Covered family</header><text>The term <term>covered family</term> means a family that receives assistance under section 8 or 9 of this Act and is enrolled in the pilot program.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3fdaeb13481549d1b588dd953df216ac"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means an entity described in subsection (c)(2). </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idadc741c36b2e4f2ab377c145a1d51c0b"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Pilot program</header><text>The term <term>pilot program</term> means the pilot program established under paragraph (2).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbf3bd635f35f4e66b8c836b9a475255c"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Welfare assistance</header><text>The term <term>welfare assistance</term> has the meaning given the term in section 984.103 of title 24, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor regulation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id94e8429aba9448f78772fe1079ef19c5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a pilot program under which the Secretary shall select not more than 25 eligible entities to establish and manage escrow accounts for not more than 5,000 covered families, in accordance with this subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbf24d1d911344ca0b0bfc6234a584267"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Escrow accounts</header><subparagraph id="ida772acfe8ac749d2a699f432f12d779b"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An eligible entity selected to participate in the pilot program—</text><clause id="id478c79dbbf97496cb48844d2e3d8ae48"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall establish an interest-bearing escrow account and place into the account an amount equal to any increase in the amount of rent paid by each covered family in accordance with the provisions of section 3, 8(o), or 8(y), as applicable, that is attributable to increases in earned income by the covered families during the participation of each covered family in the pilot program; and</text></clause><clause id="id041131d8913347eb8a38354deeddbbf9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>notwithstanding any other provision of law, may use funds it controls under section 8 or 9 for purposes of making the escrow deposit for covered families assisted under, or residing in units assisted under, section 8 or 9 of this title, respectively, provided such funds are offset by the increase in the amount of rent paid by the covered family.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb3ca9d2ac0094bd39ab5fa52968ca84c"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Income limitation</header><text>An eligible entity may not escrow any amounts for any covered family whose adjusted income exceeds 80 percent of the area median income.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idca0eb189d55b4ac9ad53987cb2f8b044"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Withdrawals</header><text>A covered family shall be able to withdraw funds, including interest earned, from an escrow account established by an eligible entity under the pilot program—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9209ffc038b54a8e91df23c6eb78f918"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">after the covered family ceases to receive welfare assistance; and </text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idee960177b0554f85856156f72c77a914"><enum>(ii)</enum><subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idd12dad439afa48fbac21e31739c78a0b"><enum>(I)</enum><text>not earlier than the date that is 5 years after the date on which the eligible entity establishes the escrow account under this subsection;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="id0e47e58ce62c4e97aac73af482fc79af"><enum>(II)</enum><text>not later than the date that is 7 years after the date on which the eligible entity establishes the escrow account under this subsection, if the covered family chooses to continue to participate in the pilot program after the date that is 5 years after the date on which the eligible entity establishes the escrow account;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="id6404399e7ff14da39e6849704f068349"><enum>(III)</enum><text>on the date the covered family ceases to receive housing assistance under section 8 or 9, if such date is earlier than 5 years after the date on which the eligible entity establishes the escrow account; </text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="iddb91e67962424fbf93ffca1c451266c8"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">earlier than 5 years after the date on which the eligible entity establishes the escrow account, if the covered family is using the funds to advance a self-sufficiency goal as approved by the eligible entity; or </text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="id09ee33379e7041b9bb08aa82c1dd8ec0"><enum>(V)</enum><text>under other circumstances in which the Secretary determines an exemption for good cause is warranted.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id66354cf6d2134a938c54f93540be8b2b"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Interim recertification</header><text>For purposes of the pilot program, a covered family may recertify the income of the covered family multiple times per year, as determined by the Secretary, and not fewer than once per year.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idce371f58799348a48038ae44be87419b"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Contract or plan</header><text>A covered family is not required to complete a standard contract of participation or an individual training and services plan in order to participate in the pilot program. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1c36643c0ddd41048c04cd06e3c9ad65"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Effect of increases in family income</header><text>Any increase in the earned income of a covered family during the enrollment of the family in the pilot program may not be considered as income or a resource for purposes of eligibility of the family for other benefits, or amount of benefits payable to the family, under any program administered by the Secretary.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idde3acf4c5f7f480192102b80c8ffc08f"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Application</header><subparagraph id="ide3f19613ac4c4aaa98487a548fe16948"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An eligible entity seeking to participate in the pilot program shall submit to the Secretary an application—</text><clause id="id75f306a6f9f344ff93d30105042f2aef"><enum>(i)</enum><text>at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require by notice; and</text></clause><clause id="id35993e34cfad4c318b514926da9f5ec2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that includes the number of proposed covered families to be served by the eligible entity under this subsection.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida5fb24a56a21420cb3a6d574704a2641"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Geographic and entity variety</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that eligible entities selected to participate in the pilot program—</text><clause id="idb1ebaf0fa03a4de2876ef1b499370dcf"><enum>(i)</enum><text>are located across various States and in both urban and rural areas; and</text></clause><clause id="id1f25ee9997ca44629115260552e1c129"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>vary by size and type, including both public housing agencies and private owners of projects receiving project-based rental assistance under section 8.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id646eab071e2445e2a67a462fc96372f0"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Notification and opt-out</header><text>An eligible entity participating in the pilot program shall—</text><subparagraph id="ide6fc725ee9c948c0b99094f8b55a0c06"><enum>(A)</enum><text>notify covered families of their enrollment in the pilot program;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd4cbbec1f9be4eb3ba6b7e35465bf442"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide covered families with a detailed description of the pilot program, including how the pilot program will impact their rent and finances; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id112484796f96410b807036ed72549481"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">inform covered families that the families cannot simultaneously participate in the pilot program and the Family Self-Sufficiency program under this section; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2a9e0d2e6376446590c7b07eca96511a"><enum>(D)</enum><text>provide covered families with the ability to elect not to participate in the pilot program—</text><clause id="id4998939c633545c19ddf452938f313c5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>not less than 2 weeks before the date on which the escrow account is established under paragraph (3); and</text></clause><clause id="id552c992ff69949bc88d3d0fda6d115ea"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>at any point during the duration of the pilot program.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id16992bc047b74cf3b193c90baa6971bd"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Maximum rents</header><text>During the term of participation by a covered family in the pilot program, the amount of rent paid by the covered family shall be calculated under the rental provisions of section 3 or 8(o), as applicable.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8ac9340049424b438408f732b441a3bf"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Pilot program timeline</header><subparagraph id="idf93ae99037bd4a98929d0ee4b8ce6b90"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Awards</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this subsection, the Secretary shall select the eligible entities to participate in the pilot program.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb419fd507525490db8fe94d08d95bd3c"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Establishment and term of accounts</header><text>An eligible entity selected to participate in the pilot program shall—</text><clause id="id352fdb29dbd34d6cb9dfa69c23e59ff9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>not later than 6 months after selection, establish escrow accounts under paragraph (3) for covered families; and</text></clause><clause id="id165f028a875f41b0b55b7ee980ea58ca"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>maintain those escrow accounts for not less than 5 years, or until the date the family ceases to receive assistance under section 8 or 9, and, at the discretion of the covered family, not more than 7 years after the date on which the escrow account is established.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id44b373a0e9ca46658c99952aedbac4ad"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Nonparticipation and housing assistance</header><subparagraph id="id48a0bfaf30024f1bad3ace6e3d8bffba"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Assistance under section 8 or 9 for a family that elects not to participate in the pilot program shall not be delayed or denied by reason of such election.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id56faf80bb0334782ae7d42f4f674b43b"><enum>(B)</enum><header>No termination</header><text>Housing assistance may not be terminated as a consequence of participating, or not participating, in the pilot program under this subsection for any period of time.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id0454bbc0b06743dcb5677d0cab94c380"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Study</header><text>Not later than 8 years after the date the Secretary selects eligible entities to participate in the pilot program under this subsection, the Secretary shall conduct a study and submit to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives a report on outcomes for covered families under the pilot program, which shall evaluate the effectiveness of the pilot program in assisting families to achieve economic independence and self-sufficiency, and the impact coaching and supportive services, or the lack thereof, had on individual incomes.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2c92c4890666473497c2e9204340bf2c"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Waivers</header><text>To allow selected eligible entities to effectively administer the pilot program and make the required escrow account deposits under this subsection, the Secretary may waive requirements under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id57c7a86999364136816379091052c962"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The pilot program under this subsection shall terminate on the date that is 10 years after the date of enactment of this subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idaf7672febbab427aa8ca80f923a8ee78"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><subparagraph id="id6d726ad43ccb453d97cf0eaa498f1891"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary for fiscal year 2026 $5,000,000—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id666120c7a7414a5db23cc41aa2a9656f"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for technical assistance related to implementation of the pilot program; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbdb5b068d7d44316ae3797ad20146858"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to carry out an evaluation of the pilot program under paragraph (10).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida69df3e3c54b49428100d9c7eaf94c35"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>Any amounts appropriated under this subsection shall remain available until expended.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

