<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF5799F3387494D62BCF744360D9DE109" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3772 IH: Defense Shipyard Workforce Housing Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3772</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250605">June 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000399">Mrs. Kiggans of Virginia</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000621">Ms. Randall</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Defense to conduct a study on the feasibility, costs, and benefits of providing housing for civilian workers at certain naval shipyards, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H5C9EF616BDDA48DBB6BF35C80514A497" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HA757121672A74858A61B064DBA537F20" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Defense Shipyard Workforce Housing Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HE82D164CE9204EF5837FCD1CEEF4CE45"><enum>2.</enum><header>Department of Defense study on feasibility, costs, and benefits of providing housing for civilian workers at certain naval shipyards</header> <subsection id="HFA2E16BD64FC412FB522925E342BBA34"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense, in coordination with the Secretary of the Navy and the Director of the Office of Industrial Policy of the Department of Defense, shall conduct a study to assess the feasibility, costs, and benefits of providing apartment-style or dormitory housing for civilian workers at covered naval shipyards. Such study shall include each of the following:</text>
<paragraph id="H1E7B2054642443629EEE3B5A883C635F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of the estimated costs of constructing, maintaining, or leasing apartment-style housing units for shipyard workers.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4DAF23CA1E2046CCABA167FECF4093C7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An assessment of the potential economic and workforce benefits, including recruitment and retention rates.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H78F334425728437AAC07109CB1FF162E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>An assessment of the feasibility of implementing housing solutions at various public shipyard locations.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H15522F5EF2C7495793905B245627E11C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An assessment of the operational effects of providing housing, including on worker availability, morale, and commuting burdens.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF8E967A9F7A74103A9C8E4E2FFD14331"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Options for deducting fair-market rent or below-market housing fees directly from employee paychecks, including administrative, legal, and contractual implications.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB6951B44A77346C39D52FCD70869FA39"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Comparisons with similar workforce housing models used by the Department of Defense or other Federal agencies.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6B1AA0D8A14B44AEA7473DA24FF3393A"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Case studies of at least two covered naval shipyards that include specific data on the potential effectiveness of workforce housing solutions.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H47467F8CDCEF432F9321BB0C5EB317CA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the results of the study conducted under subsection (a).</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H5FB9A93E759A43E3AF8428408D4801C6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Covered naval shipyards</header><text>In this section, a covered naval shipyard is any of the following:</text> <paragraph id="HCDD2F53D1EA544308BD4BD55195C5F90"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Norfolk Naval Shipyard, Virginia.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7F3D003FDA6C4B1D822F5CFCB7BC3593">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>Pearl Harbor Naval Shipyard and Intermediate Maintenance Facility, Hawaii.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HE3ACE894DEEA4B96AF591596E16A0CBD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Portsmouth Naval Shipyard, Maine.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H59F757B26635430CBB54B8A198CA21AE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Puget Sound Naval Shipyard and Intermediate Maintenance Facility, Washington.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

