<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-FLO25145-R4Y-WX-MM3"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S525 IS: To transfer the functions, duties, responsibilities, assets, liabilities, orders, determinations, rules, regulations, permits, grants, loans, contracts, agreements, certificates, licenses, and privileges of the United States Agency for International Development relating to implementing and administering the Food for Peace Act to the Department of Agriculture.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 525</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250211">February 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S347">Mr. Moran</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S411">Mr. Marshall</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To transfer the functions, duties, responsibilities, assets, liabilities, orders, determinations, rules, regulations, permits, grants, loans, contracts, agreements, certificates, licenses, and privileges of the United States Agency for International Development relating to implementing and administering the Food for Peace Act to the Department of Agriculture.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H6509FE637E2C432B8324EECE28344316"><section section-type="section-one" id="HC64BDBD4B50C45D3B72EE508DD3859F0"><enum>1.</enum><header>Transfer of functions</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5119e5f2d97441b39e2708a9c9944f87"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning on the date of enactment of this Act, the functions, duties, responsibilities, assets, liabilities, orders, determinations, rules, regulations, permits, grants, loans, contracts, agreements, certificates, licenses, and privileges of the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development relating to carrying out any authority under the Food for Peace Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1691">7 U.S.C. 1691 et seq.</external-xref>) shall be transferred to the Secretary of Agriculture. </text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id73dcace2ef524c8da0c8ee90afaa291f"><enum>(b)</enum><header>References</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any reference in any provision of law or regulation to the Administrator or Agency referred to in subsection (a), as applicable, shall be deemed to be a reference to the Secretary of Agriculture or to any department or office of the Department of Agriculture to which the Secretary assigns the functions, duties, or responsibilities transferred pursuant to this Act, respectively.</text></subsection><subsection id="id88a8f3b3d74146ad91daf1b95003e196"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary of Agriculture may implement amendments to a regulation referred to in subsection (a), which shall be published as an interim final rule and may be made effective immediately on publication, to ensure continuity of the applicable program as a result of a transfer under this Act. </text></subsection><subsection id="id318988a7980444808d0968ec7c5372a9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any existing statutory authorities available to the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development that have or could have been used by the Administrator to implement the functions, duties, or responsibilities of the United States Agency for International Development relating to implementing or administering the Food for Peace Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1691">7 U.S.C. 1691 et seq.</external-xref>) may be exercised by the Secretary of Agriculture. </text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4e2a58407ca84cc6827e43a9c2c92b83"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Famine Early Warning Systems Network</header><text>Notwithstanding subsection (a), the Secretary of Agriculture shall continue to carry out the Famine Early Warning Systems Network or a successor program, 1 of the purposes of which is to provide objective, evidence-based analyses with respect to potential or existing famine and flood situations to assist the Secretary of Agriculture in mitigating food insecurity. </text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd72864205731410790ec260e8fd35975"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>The Secretary of Agriculture shall consult with the Secretary of State from time to time in carrying out the authorities under title II of the Food for Peace Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1721">7 U.S.C. 1721 et seq.</external-xref>). </text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

