<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Engrossed-in-House" dms-id="H9851E8AB89FA40739F2F4F9BEF228AC3" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 519 EH: Condemning the attacks on Minnesota lawmakers in Brooklyn Park and Champlin, Minnesota, and calling for unity and the rejection of political violence in Minnesota and across the United States.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-06-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">IV</distribution-code> 
<congress display="no">119th CONGRESS</congress> 
<session display="no">1st Session</session> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 519</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="yes">In the House of Representatives, U. S.,</current-chamber>
<action>
<action-date date="20250625">June 25, 2025</action-date>
</action> 
<legis-type display="yes">RESOLUTION</legis-type> 
<official-title display="no">Condemning the attacks on Minnesota lawmakers in Brooklyn Park and Champlin, Minnesota, and calling for unity and the rejection of political violence in Minnesota and across the United States.</official-title> 
</form> 
<preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, on June 14, 2025, a gunman entered the home of Minnesota State Senator John Hoffman and shot and critically injured him and his wife, Yvette Hoffman;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the gunman then entered the home of Minnesota State House Speaker Emerita Melissa Hortman and assassinated her and her husband Mark Hortman;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the gunman had documents that listed dozens of lawmakers targeted for assassination;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the law enforcement officers of Brooklyn Park and Champlin saved additional lives by intervening with their bravery and rapid response to the attack;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Speaker Emerita Hortman was a formidable public servant who served her community and the people of Minnesota with deep devotion, compassion, and strength;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas acts of political violence have no place in the United States of America and represent a grave threat to our nation;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas swift condemnation of political violence by elected officials is necessary to preserve and protect American democracy;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas when these violent acts expose division, we must persevere in the pursuit of democratic principles, resolving our differences through debate and civil discourse; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas political violence not only attacks the life and liberty of our representatives, it also attacks the right of the people to be represented: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble> <resolution-body style="traditional" id="HAE2FF174DB9C4C2A93F3C07D528E4A7E"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H1A6D460A397B4BD7963021F18D700AA2"><enum/><text>That the House of Representatives, in this moment of tragic loss—</text> 
<paragraph id="H046B31EC0A8F444DBBFE2138A8287363"><enum>(1)</enum><text>strongly condemns and denounces the attacks on Minnesota state legislators in Brooklyn Park and Champlin, Minnesota on June 14, 2025;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H99932232B77B437F8E3F02A4B93E3BCF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>honors the life of Speaker Emerita Melissa Hortman for her devotion to public service and her tireless efforts to serve the people of Minnesota, and the life of her husband, Mark Hortman;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCC7DA55D639C42DDBA770220FD610FAF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>honors Senator John Hoffman and his wife, Yvette Hoffman, who were shot and critically injured, and wishes their full and speedy recovery;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC939D4EA05D84706A11A4FD98BA41276"><enum>(4)</enum><text>honors the courageous law enforcement officers who saved additional lives with their rapid response to the attack and successfully apprehended and charged the suspected perpetrator on June 15, 2025;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6EFDC55FCC1C4112B66006B7D6B299FC"><enum>(5)</enum><text>calls on all community leaders and elected officials to publicly and unequivocally denounce acts of political violence; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA34CB89E506A4B98ADDB0084C8FB4578"><enum>(6)</enum><text>calls on all people in the United States to unite in this moment of pain and tragedy and reaffirm our commitment to a safe, civil, and peaceful democracy where violent rhetoric and acts are not tolerated.</text></paragraph> </section> 
</resolution-body> 
<attestation><attestation-group><attestor display="no">Kevin F. McCumber,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation>
</resolution> 


