<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H26542AF026FD4569BDEA2B024C71A0CF" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1485 IH: Alien Removal Not Resort Stays Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-02-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1485</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250221">February 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000194">Ms. Mace</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="B000825">Ms. Boebert</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000806">Mr. Webster of Florida</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAP00">Appropriations</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To terminate the Shelter and Services Program of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF103C576E5964F0FA5B93F4F4FD8052C" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H9A0EB1FA12EC4AA49C600DECAAAB047A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Alien Removal Not Resort Stays Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HFC10E951167545EBA22CFE1E07EE52FE" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Termination</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Beginning on the date of enactment of this Act, no Federal funds are authorized to be appropriated or otherwise made available to the Shelter and Services Program of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, as in effect on the day before such date of enactment, or to any successor or similar program.</text></section> 
<section id="H41B0A4527EA3498FA65F4C1F1AA98A5C"><enum>3.</enum><header>Transfer of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The unobligated balances of all amounts appropriated or otherwise made available to the Shelter and Services Program of the Federal Emergency Management Agency as of the day before the date of enactment of this Act shall be transferred to and merged with amounts otherwise made available to U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement under the <quote>U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement—operations and support</quote> account for necessary expenses for enforcement, detention, and removal operations.</text></section> </legis-body></bill>

