<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="HE0E9C3784F304640AAC51FCED8796852" resolution-type="house-resolution"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 805 IH: Recognizing October 2025 as “American Pharmacists Month” in honor of the contribution of pharmacists to provide safe, accessible, affordable, and beneficial patient care services and products to all residents and protect the public health of our communities.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 805</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251014">October 14, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="H001086">Mrs. Harshbarger</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing October 2025 as <quote>American Pharmacists Month</quote> in honor of the contribution of pharmacists to provide safe, accessible, affordable, and beneficial patient care services and products to all residents and protect the public health of our communities.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas pharmacists are some of the most accessible health care providers delivering critical services to patients and contributing to the health and well-being of all people;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas pharmacists are best positioned to be the health care provider that ensures optimal medication therapy outcomes, and helping to ensure patients are adherent to their medications;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, with a community pharmacy located within 5 miles of nearly all Americans, pharmacists and pharmacy personnel are best suited to work collaboratively with other health care providers and are making an impact helping patients overcome illness and live healthier lives through chronic disease management and the full, effective use of their medicines; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, today, there are over 330,000 licensed pharmacists, over 400,000 pharmacy technicians, and 47,000 student pharmacists providing care and serving as patient advocates to ensure access to the best and safest therapy to the patients they serve: Now, therefore, be it </text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body id="H9BCCA59DE54C4CC9AC8B75EDFE1C53C5" style="traditional"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HD69207B63BED47AB881793846FA6A47E" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum/><text>That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="HB015F1882CDC493F9675682D352F040B"><enum>(1)</enum><text> recognizes “American Pharmacists Month” in honor of the contribution of pharmacists to provide safe, accessible, affordable, and beneficial patient care services and products to all residents and protect the public health of our communities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD67435D9A5284C34B65C9000DFE071A2"><enum>(2)</enum><text> pledges to celebrate contributions of pharmacists to the health and well-being of all people in each State;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H403AB7DBE1D648829B4C580BF1E7DBBB"><enum>(3)</enum><text> recognizes pharmacists as one of the most accessible health care providers delivering critical services to patients and contributing to the health and well-being of all people; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6D3145BC6A2D496199D5F6E3A31AB626"><enum>(4)</enum><text> commits to working collaboratively with pharmacists and other health care providers to help patients overcome illness and live healthier lives through chronic disease management and the full, effective use of their medicines.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

